yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for another episode of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation let's write up here a new
grower if you're a professional grower
if you're a new smoker or a dedicated
dabber if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who is just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me this episode of the podcast
is brought to you by my friends at the
hella dank seed company if you need new
genetics for your gardening I highly
recommend the hella dank seed company
you can find them at dank seed dot store
ladies and gentlemen roll up a fat joint
pack up the bomb or start heating up
that daybreak because it's time for
another episode of the glow from your
heart a podcast
[Music]
welcome podcast world it's time for
episode 310 of the girl from heart
podcast thanks again for joining me this
episode was a lot of fun to record for
this episode I took white mic up to
Colorado Springs and we went to the
green faith ministries cannabis Church
and we were joined by Deb and Grammy
Reverend Brendan Baker and a dude who
calls himself I rock watts you guys I
don't want to ramble on too long in this
intro so let's just get right to it
ladies and gentlemen davon granny white
Mike hi Rock watts
Reverend Brandon Baker and myself at the
green faith ministries cannabis church
all right podcast world we're here live
at green faith ministries in Colorado
Springs I am joined on microphone by the
always beautiful dab and Granny welcome
to the show sweetheart thank you for
having me Rasta Jeff thanks for putting
this together for us we're at a pretty
cool place this I'm kind of impressed we
walked in a young lady checked my ID she
told me to have a good time and I am set
up recording a podcast I've had about 37
dabs smoke some insert dabs I smoked
some hot nail dabs this is a great place
thanks for introducing me to this place
well I'm meeting the Rev for the first
time myself so well then let's introduce
the Rev to the show ladies and gentlemen
joining us on microphone number three
over there is the Rev they call him Rev
Brandon Baker thanks for joining me on
the show bro thanks for having me thanks
for having me thanks for inviting me to
your church would you like to take a
second and tell my audience about the
church we're kin of a sacrament Church
all denominational and sit a
non-denominational I think it sounds
better Rastafarian based believe
cannabis is the healing of the nation's
tree life and our mission is to get all
other churches no matter their path or
faith to believe that whatever their God
is that cannabis is the holy nail the
Holy healing sacrament put here by him
or her Rastafari
well thanks for uh representing cannabis
for us and having a place where we can
consume safely and not feel like we're
in any danger I'm totally comfortable
here this is cool thank you I appreciate
it nice and secure glad to have you here
thanks man we'll definitely be back here
also on the microphone a repeat offender
I brought him all the way to Colorado
Springs we got him out of the house
ladies and gentlemen white Mike is on
the show with me
everybody thanks for coming dude thanks
for taking some time away from the
family to come be on the show dude if
you're gonna get out once every six
months get out to this place yeah this
is a good time here I feel like I'm
tapped out and I'm hanging out with a
bunch of new friends and old friends
it's a good time right here on
Constitution and Academy is there a
social media page for this place green
flag green faith Supply Company on
Facebook pretty much our main thing
where we keep people updated daily
perfect checking out you guys if you
were 21 and over and you're not an
[ __ ]
you can come here and you can
participate in the church you can be
part of the crew it's a really cool vibe
everybody's here super serious super
friendly eyes for an extension cord like
I took off running for an extension cord
so we have emails they have everything
here to Medicaid everything is a
donation basis is that well what we do
is people regular donating members we
give them reward points to cash in for
Church merchandise whether it be
sacraments or buy shirts drinks whatever
beautiful I like the artwork on the wall
I like the Native American by painting
in front of me lots of great color super
chill vibe I just noticed the people in
the clouds that is super cool great
great painting in front of me nice
Indian smoking a peace pipe they're
super cool vibe it's not too hippie
doubt which is something that I like a
lot of places over hippie Phi the place
so it's super chillier yeah all
hand-painted by a patron actually can
you give them a shout out they can you
can say their name if you'd like on the
show go ahead I rock uncle Steve uncle
Steve is a savage great painting much
respect that guy that just jumped in as
a guy called I rock watts on Instagram
check him out troll him he'll troll you
back don't worry he may jump in once in
a while he said he didn't want to be on
the show but I needed you gotta Mari
he's podcast adjacent three minutes we
got him in he's just chilling out he's
keeping the bad nail hot he's keeping us
going so welcome to show everybody I
think we've introduced everybody
properly white Mike's here the reference
here granny's here josh is here I'm here
we're all hanging out getting red eyed
getting I re getting medicated granny we
wanted to talk about some of your
adventures let's start with your injury
okay
there's two injuries now two of them
well the first one was in Michigan
and if you notice my glasses are out
whomp eyed on my face I'm starting not
to pay too much attention to your
injuries or feelings I can laugh at
myself because I've always said I'm a
hazard to myself here we go in Michigan
it was so cold oh it was freezing cold
it was colder than Colorado and we're
going to this Hash bash cup and we
couldn't park close so I got out and I'm
running and guys if you know me I am an
Amazon so if I'm running there's a lot
of force and I look out of my eye and I
see the door is open to my left I look
in front of me and the door is open
wrong bump bounced right off a huge
plate glass window my glasses went flat
and there's people all around the only
person is mama bear dab she run up to me
and she was like oh I'm so glad that was
you because I would have done the same
thing we go in I fix my glasses I'm not
injured too badly had some bruises we go
in we party we come back out the party
somebody goes oh my god gale there's
your face on the window I hit that plate
glass window lips and like a pillow in
the morning it was hilarious
about my second are you okay from the
first one good so lasting damage from
the first one just pry dirt stitches no
nothing thank God that window didn't
break what but you actually heard some
cuz I was running so fast that was your
riding the window I bounced probably two
feet back off that window that's how
hard I hit it in Michigan over injury we
go to DC last weekend a week after my
Michigan injures Kevin and I decide to
go exploring
no problem right fair enough navigation
what's your photo GPS we're good forgot
to check the battery life of the phone
we're 20 minutes into the walk have no
idea where we're at and I have 1%
battery power I said Oh Kevin we're
[ __ ]
I don't know where we're at he goes
hurry up find long-term on your phone
where we gotta go I'm looking at my
phone not at my feet there is a big tree
thing that grew up into the sidewalk I
literally bounced my lips on your hand
it's why I kind of sprained my hand but
I knew it was bad because Kevin come
running and he said are you okay I said
I am and then he said well you should
have been watching your feet I said I'm
trying to figure out where the hell
we're at we're staying in the Airbnb
this is a really great story checked out
the keep going yeah injuries something
really good we are lost there you go we
are lost as can be and I don't know how
we're gonna get back to the Airbnb
phone's dead and I'm looking around and
I'm not getting a vibe that I can ask
you how do I get back to my place
finally I see a young urban professional
probably early 30s with the baby on his
back and I say I hate to bother you but
I am so lost can you help me and he says
I will walk you as far as my brownstone
and then I'll tell you how to get from
there very nice young man five minutes
into the walk he goes I can't help but
notice your earrings she's gotten pot
leaf earrings you guys and I said yeah I
guess is the earrings were the only
cannabis related item of clothing you at
the moment I think probably the only
thing you could really see okay I had
like a vest on cuz it was kinda chilly
there in DC as well there was no there
was no pot nothing visible like I
usually have on nothing glass or
anything but these were visible and I
said
yes I'm a marijuana advocate and he says
I I don't like this whole legalization
thing I have a lot of questions and I
said she got the perfect lady right here
and he was like what do you mean and I
said I'm kind of known for talking a lot
of [ __ ] about marijuana so we get
talking I learned quite a bit about this
young man
I learned his father is a cardiologist
his brother is a surgeon in one of the
branches of the military he is a
financial planner his wife is a CEO of a
company and they're not there they're
frightened about cannabis the cartels
are gonna come in and everything
stereotypical is what he is frightened
about we get to his brownstone and he's
asked me questions about how I feel
about legalization and I say for a
family like yourself legalization is the
way to go in Colorado it's track seed to
sale there's no funny business going on
we got to his brownstone and he says I'm
enjoying our conversation so much I'm
going to walk you to your Airbnb Lipton
I did flip him that's awesome
by the time we got to the Airbnb he was
convinced I told him Kevin's story I
told him I said I said you know I really
like you I'm not gonna say his name
although I did know it I said what makes
Kevin and I sitting down and smoking a
joint or me doing a DAB what makes that
any different than you and your wife
consuming a glass of wine when your
children are in bed I said I bet you do
that don't you and he said I never
thought about it that way
and most people don't so he told me he's
not so frightened now about legalization
and that may be controlled marijuana is
the way to go good he brought him to the
green side do you think he's gonna go
talk to his parents who were ideal
educated and teach them about cannabis
also he's gonna go a step farther he
said he would talk to people in the
financial institutions around there what
is the what is the reason we can't work
with reputable cannabis companies that's
awesome now kevin says gale you know you
as much as a goofball as I am and you
all know I am a goofball when I need to
be I can be articulate and I can be
personable and I think I think maybe
that was my whole mission there just
that one interaction that one
interaction set places just to be that
angel because I knew the next day would
all be a bunch of people like us
everybody medicated my word wasn't gonna
mean anything there maybe you're
changing cannabis there right now maybe
he's putting something into action
they're getting a bank going and they
won't have the struggles that we have
here in Colorado I would like I would
love that
a little angel moment that you have
provided there so that was like that
that was my big moment from beautiful DC
I'm sorry that you hurt yourself but I'm
glad you were able to spread some
knowledge and turn some people onto our
side yes well thank you for doing that
do you want to keep going with stories
or do you want to I don't know let me
ask Mike Mike here he he knows a lot
about the laws that is what I would say
your biggest part of the industry is
that's the part of the industry that I
have locked down more than anyone else I
know that's why we call him white Mike
right he's the guy that follows the
rules and he does follow the rules and
you knows what the rules that try what
I'm trying to do something when I'm
getting a little too out of hand I'm
trying to break three rules at once
Michael say break one law at a time bro
ever been given is if you get a break or
a ruler Allah break one ruler law at a
time I said this morning when young kids
were asking me about you know the
weekend and doing this or that I was
like the best advice I could give you is
do one illegal thing one stupid thing at
a time don't be doing all kinds of dumb
[ __ ] at what you're gonna get in trouble
it's when you start combo and [ __ ] up
that all the shenanigans really good
and everybody needs a friend like Mike
around sometimes you got to have a guy
to pull the reigns ago hey you're going
[ __ ] crazy you just need a guy to
remind you that you're slipping
especially some of us that are very
impulsive we don't think so one of my
concerns is people say that I do a lot
of boneheaded things and one of them
they think I'm terrible for being so
transparent traveling from state legal
state to legal state with as I say my
medicine it's a real real gray area and
basically you're putting yourself at the
mercy of every law enforcement agency
whose jurisdiction you happen to travel
through on the ground so just because
the TSA and Denver doesn't give a [ __ ]
doesn't mean that a stewardess won't
radio ahead and have the local PD for
wherever you're landing
ruin your trip okay advice there when
it's from legal state to legal state or
medical state to medical state you're
lowering lowering your odds of having a
shitty trip when you land and having law
enforcement we're waiting to ruin your
day but right now as far as I can recall
there's only one state with what they
call reciprocity meaning they consider
your state's medical marijuana card is
valid and that's Nevada but they don't
say explicitly that it's kosher to fly
into Nevada with product you picked up
in another legal state so it's an
incredibly gray very close to the called
you are transporting yep federal the
feds don't care unless it's enough to
distribute though that seems to be more
of the issue TSA will tell me their
mission is more bombs and things that
are going to do it other paths
if you can't hurt somebody with it right
now GSA doesn't have time to care Metro
in Vegas because I've been I
pushed it to the limits they told me
what I bring is nothing leave me alone
they are looking for people that are
transporting large amounts trafficking
there's one business right now in Alaska
their production facility in one of
their shops are like well we would
consider half the country away because
it's an Alaskan one side of the state
can be days travel from the other side
and they're flying product back and
forth right now and it's a major news
story that comes up every two months
another news outlet I'll hear about it
go holy [ __ ] they're putting weed on a
plane but in Alaska those little jumper
planes are like those little jumper
planes is just like driving a bus from
Springs to Denver you know I mean
there's just it's such a rural place
that's so far apart that [ __ ] is normal
for them they drive to the plane they
get on the plane to drive to other
landing they get in the other truck and
drive that to their spot yep just what
they do in Alaska
don't you think as advocates or
activists sometimes we do have to push
things in those grey areas because I
will say why do I have to follow the
rules when they're not even concrete all
the time that's where the change comes
from and that's how we end up with
actual rules like right now you can take
booze on a plane I think if you follow
very specific rules I'll sell it to you
there but you can't open it on you have
to follow very specific if you're drunk
at altitude all sorts of crazy [ __ ]
happens because there's not a flood yeah
Lange yeah they won't let you board if
they think you're drunk but so far we
haven't had anybody freak out up in the
on canvas please keep that streak going
people as advocates or activists or
whatever you'd like to title us is there
our responsibility to follow the rules
and play fair so we don't [ __ ] it up or
is it our responsibility to push the
limit so that things change the way we
need it it's both okay like is that why
there's a white mic version of activism
the dab and granny version of activism
the Rebs version of activism which we
can see here
situation that arises introspect it
takes all kinds like when I first heard
we were coming to a legit cannabis
Church I was like Jeff where are you
taking me and I walked in and I was like
oh he's taking me home like but it's not
my type of activism it's not something
that I would wake up on Monday morning
and say today I'm going to found and I
have a feeling that the Rebbe here would
be substantially less comfortable than I
am going in front of City Council in
Lobby lobbying for a specific zoning
change or something of that nature
probably it's just a guess but well yeah
I have legal schooling I'm actually a
law student on hiatus and I'm more or
less the counsel for the church so I
have to deal with all our zoning and
stuff but exactly what I'm talking about
the time when I bring it up people look
at me like I'm talking gibberish or a
language they've never heard before no I
do consulting on the side I don't raise
revenue for the church I worked a law
office for like four years
so saves me a lot of attorney fees for
the church absolutely that's how I found
you is your facebook posts everybody was
like if you're following cannabis
activism check out this guy and I found
you through your legal actions and
Facebook posts yeah I used to post a lot
of great things that would educate me
keep me on top of stuff yeah being a
religious guy anytime I get politically
active I have to run on the Republican
ticket but I did I actually did delegate
all the way to the state level this year
it's got a lot of them to flip their
stance on cannabis because they're
scared they don't have voters in
Colorado it's like third of the
unaffiliated third Democrat 30%
Republican 3030 and then 10% third
parties the only way to win is the
flipped unaffiliated and so I told the
Republicans only way that's happening is
to support our state rights for cannabis
because you're Republican you stand for
state rights that's what we're seeing
naturally right now is a bunch of
Republicans really standing up for
cannabis specifically as the states
rights issue I never thought I'd find
myself agreeing with Cory Gardner on
anything it's amazing isn't it
yep and all of a sudden I'm like I'm
kind of a court garter fan and just
saying that out loud might give me
ostracized at holidays but like he's
really standing up for Colorado on the
state's Rice's she won really went to
battle for us and that's what we need
and we have to keep open minded like you
said I never thought I would be agreeing
with certain people either hmm but
you're out there changing people's minds
granny you're the one out there doing
the mind changing well that's just
because I mean finding those little
seeds of mine change you're so much
easier - you're not intimidating you
don't have your non-threatening people
can listen to this beautiful older lady
that's already got a life that has
nothing to prove that's got nothing to
prove anything
but that and that's the best part you're
having fun with cannabis while
advocating it you've got a reason for it
he's not so grumpy but dabbin grandpa
now what are we calling him out is there
Colin I'm Kevin and he's having a yeah
Kevin is enjoying life because they said
are you her security and he said no I'm
her husband yeah he is shut up Kevin I
hope you get to listen to this come next
time dude you can be on the show if
you'd like you're always invited I'll
bring them yeah he can come it's fun
when we go hang out at events because a
lot of times things get uh people like
to come say hi to you and I sometimes I
just look over at Kevin and he this is
this is my wife
yeah sometimes I'll sneak away and go
hang out with him somebody made me proud
in my life the other day they said that
in DC that I was mobbed that people were
taking my picture and that he was
standing to the side and somebody said
to him when did you know gale was a rock
star and he said the day I married her
he's absolutely right I knew the moment
I met you he gave me a big old hug
it was like we'd known each other
forever yep yeah we'd been talking on
social media for so long it was just
like old friends that hadn't seen each
other in a while hey Mike what do you
think these three states that I've been
into Michigan California and DC what do
you think they're in store for with
legalization the long fight they're all
in different stages none of them
acquired obtained what yes
having I call it the Wild West Michigan
I went to a dispensary I walked in the
owner came out strapped smoking a blunt
around
that's 2009 right there 50 strains on
the shelf
none of them grown in his dispensary not
one hot one just buy it and flip it as
fast as I can
no edibles Colorado nowadays 100 plus or
minus plus or minus so you might be
getting 50 you might be getting every
state's gotta smell their own lab
testing infrastructure and that takes a
while
do you see doesn't have an industry
everything I found it doesn't surprise
me that there's a lot of out-of-state
product goes straight to the East Coast
but they don't allow growing in DC right
like you got a car you can grow it but
you can't buy it but you can possess it
like Wyoming where you have to go out of
state to get it to possess it I don't
know the rules in each state but I think
the places we are not allowed to buy it
at a store and you're not allowed to
cultivate but you can have it I think
that's completely silly right you can't
sell it in DC it's all traded donated
but it was again it was like a flea
market at the National Mall washable on
the mall they're gonna really soon
because with legalization comes taxation
and regulation well the the DC I want to
say it's City Council is legally
prevented from spending money to draft
the rules for the legalization law that
the voters pass but the employees
working on marijuana stuff kind of like
at Wyoming
with the CBD the political rules in DC
are very odd they live in a tiny portion
of the country that's not like the rest
of the country and so some of the rules
and some of their rights are a little
bit different but they're so close to
like people from Maryland came people
from all these places outlying they all
came to buy their medicine there it's
it's weird game front like I'm from
Colorado and so to me to travel to
another state like that's something you
need to plan in pack a lunch for and
you've got to stop for gas a couple of
times before you get it done and there
are fully parts of the country on the
east coat that Gail's looking to be like
I just said I could fly know where these
borders are tiny it's like driving you
know ten blocks away you're in another
state yeah but you should still have it
available in your state this is why it
should be legal those invisible lines
should be yes and you just change how
you want it legal in each state like
alcohol yep like there can be a Utah of
pot where you have to join the bar as a
member to come in and pay your monthly
probably be Utah like at a church that's
how we run the church is kind of how
they run the yep bars and it works
there's no riffraff here get about
higher co2 standard as far as patrons
than any other Church I heard something
today on the news that just amazes me
and this is more government they just
released the first synthetic CBD why why
do we need CBD half of it is like it's
way easier to synthesize and then grow
to grow it you really need some Jeff and
they don't want that and that's why the
federal grow is so sad but I'm worried
that is what we have to keep fighting or
it will come to that yeah it's that's
what
is coming to and I'm like damn we fought
for this it's what we wanted but look at
the cost it was one of my biggest
frustrations in Colorado it's like the
last season a weed so when they take the
Big O garden and it's just chopped up
through a lab and put out in fields yeah
what's coming one of my biggest
disappointments in the community in
Colorado is we all took four years off
after legalization pass to celebrate and
enjoy and build an industry and like I
remember feeling like we won I remember
laying off and then I started seeing
that they were gonna get us through
zoning and they were gonna turn it just
back or back into exactly what we had
before legalization and start blocking
us and fighting us out and routing us
out that way and getting a vote for
legalization having that vote passing
that's the beginning like that's that's
just yeah that's like maybe the middle
of the beginning like you haven't
reached the middle yet or even come
close to the end the fight is long and
we all have to gear up for it and keep
it going I've been seeing where
Californians want to repeal 64 is that
an option I don't think so it would be
crazy hard to do but a lot of the people
in the black market or the gray market
have a vested interest against
legalization of course as soon as
legalization shows up the people that
have been doing it for 25 years in the
mountains are out unless what happened
here unless they can convert honestly
how many people couldn't convert here
everybody vent so I feel like everybody
that could grow that had heart for a
grow they got pushed out and all the
people that had a bunch of money they
took over and now they're hiring people
that have heart to grow and not paying
them worth of [ __ ] and they're kind of
ruining the industry yeah everything is
alarming audit products are subpar
because owners are from corporations and
they just want returned at large yes
they don't care about quality product
and then they hire a guy like me they're
just being hypothetical they can grow
[ __ ] his ass off and then they don't
give you the resources and they restrain
you and restrict you and that's what
this industry does I've consulted for a
couple of businesses now for years that
their problem is they will
invest in talent they keep hiring their
brother-in-law or their cousin or a guy
that came in and said he was a master
grower and was down for 13 an hour like
talent is what produces high quality
products talent skill and support and if
you don't have all three of those going
in your business you can't produce a
quality product but it you know I used
to when I first came into this scene I
really did believe it was patience over
profit I really did believe that I
thought oh yeah we're doing a great
thing it is not that it is not that
anymore it is profit over anything model
is disappearing yeah the soul got sucked
out of this industry when it became
recreational legal creation illegal I
feel like that's when the soul got
ripped out of it one of the first things
kind of the stay in local governments
did was raise the bar of entry into the
industry first they said no felonies and
then okay no felonies for five years no
drug felonies for ten and so just with
every whack they could take they made it
harder and harder and harder for people
in the the industry before legalization
to participate in the industry after and
the hurdle that really fixed it was
saying all right
like in Aurora you need four hundred
thousand dollars just in a duffel bag in
a safe in the back of your store to
apply for a license you need to have
four hundred cash liquid on hand in case
you get sued or in case taxes come up
they wanted you to have that on hand
just webelo tried to bring it up and
when they added it to their list of
rules their reasoning for doing so was
well Aurora does it and when I pointed
out just City Council that we're not
allowed to use banks when we invest
money in this industry it has to come
from bank account in Colorado for money
generated in Colorado we have to
withdraw that as cash and then we can
invest it in the business requiring us
to have four hundred grand or and then
they lower well maybe we'll only do two
hundred here I was like even two hundred
grand you're requiring me to put 200
grand in a duffel bag and just keep that
in the bottom of the gun safe in the
back of my store like think about what
you're doing just
little bit super target they immediately
pulled that rag once they realized what
it meant but before I really like grab
them by the collar out and drag them to
reality
not all of them thought it was a great
idea because you know if we want
responsible business owners to be the
only people running these businesses no
responsible business owner should have a
lot of money on hand just cash sound
like a drug dealer it sounds like a
wildly responsible business owner and
they did it because somebody else did it
yeah because somebody else did it it's
the same reason we have five nanograms
as the limit for your your blood draw in
Colorado five nanograms was what they
had in some other state and we were like
well Georgia does it in it's like well
they just picked the [ __ ] number like
there's no science do you think ever so
much they've got to be able to come up
with something they're not even allowed
to do the research right okay that's
that's how the web and I had this
conversation they could pull me over and
I'm always good I might not even have
smoked or consumed at all that day but
my blood is gonna say I'm high yes I
will I've been tested too and I was way
over five the next morning at 11:30 1400
or 14,000 whatever the test was they
could test for 1,400 or 14,000 nanograms
per particle or whatever this doctor
called me back and he's like you want a
prescription from Aaron all and I was
like no and he goes how did you do this
your blood your urine is as high as we
can test and I was like I've been
practicing for that test
he's like didn't you know you were
getting a test as like nope that [ __ ]
was a surprise
people like us when they say it takes 30
days for to clean your system out for a
drug test for us it takes months yeah I
win sixty three full days before I took
a pee test it still feels Josh had 72
days over there in the corner of flush I
haven't taken one of years like I could
even guess ya gonna do my best now but
hold you over if they pulled me over
right now I mean I was it's been a while
since I've been pulled over but I mean
you hit on what the evening officer how
can I help you this evening and they
start looking for a business card Tonya
have a baby
good evening usually before they even
get to the
no look as long as my car doesn't reek
I'm good to go I'm trying to think I
don't think I've been pulled over no
I've definitely been pulled over since I
had my badge it's been at least four
years I got pulled over and the cop
could smell the herb I roll down the
window got my license registration proof
of insurance in my hand the cop could
smell the herb from 25 feet away from my
car and he just a straight-up
marijuana in there I was like yeah
yes sir I do it is my job do you have a
lot and I go no I just got my personal
and I reached from my backpack and
tapped I just got my personal bag in
here and I go oh hey like dawns on me
and I showed him I got my badge on my
shoulder on my my chest here and I was
like sorry I've worked gonna grow I run
a really big commercial grow so I'm just
rubbing up against it he goes oh my
daughter's a trimmer he's like smells
pretty ripe in there and he's like I'm
gonna give you a warning because you
were honest with me you were going 92 in
a 75 let's slow it down it's like I see
you got a new car you're probably just
seeing how fast it goes let's not go so
fast today go wouldn't you say that
staying calm and being articulate goes a
long way yes
take off your sunglasses look them in
the eye call them sir yes sir no sir you
don't need to say a lot more no uh and
if you're in a place where cannabis is
legal and they ask you if you have
cannabis don't [ __ ] lie it's legal
there's no reason to lie when I said yes
I feel real the first time you do it
don't get me wrong that was the first
time I admitted yes sir I got weed in
the car
he was you kind of like smiled at me
like I don't he knew like it was the
first time you ever said yes to that
question because his shoulders went down
and so did mine at the same time like
this is tense do you have weed yes
certainly cuz it's okay he's just like
patted me on the head basically like you
can have your weed sir it's okay and
since I told him I had it he didn't go
through my car he didn't give me a
[ __ ] sobriety test he didn't [ __ ] me
worried about your weed yeah I had a
quarter bag of [ __ ] Rudeboy OG is
what I think I had because I remember
where I was going mm-hmm yeah and just
stunk up the whole [ __ ] neighborhood
yeah if you thought you were intoxicated
he would I had you out on some car doing
roadsides clearly you didn't was 11:00
in the morning at 11:00 on i-25 I forget
the smell we take home from the grow
until I'm changing my laundry from
washer to dryer and I flipped that
washer open
start it again go to go to that King
Soopers or something to get some
ingredients for dinner on the way home
and everyone and their gives you a dirty
look like I was asked we ordered dinner
at a restaurant in Springs and after we
it was a walk up in order and then you
go sit away in the eat your food at the
table there you seat yourself after we
ordered the guy said so we'll bring that
outside to you
we're like no bro it's like snowing
we're gonna eat inside he's like no not
you guys reek of marijuana you must go
outside he wouldn't let you eat in there
so at that point I turned around and
asked him for my money back I was like
if I can't eat in here I don't want the
food there's a restaurant here in this
town the deal was a chair to sandwich at
the moment when you just said that you
made me smiley I want to hear about your
diva moment at that last festival I
wanted so badly to go up on stage with
the group that was playing do we want to
say the name Clini who they were it was
Cypress Hill and be real oh I so wanted
to go up there and meet him I wanted to
tell his story it's required so bonhomie
said gale I asked they said no and I was
like oh come on we got all access let's
try it so we go over and the security
guy was so sweet he goes granny I can't
I can't let you up there and Chris crazy
goes where his tour manager bring him
over and Chris
he goes no nobody can go up on stage and
Chris crazy goes just davon granny she
damn near got a million fans you let her
go up on stage and he was like no
nobody's going up on stage and so I
looked at them too and I was like while
we tried and we start walking away and
Chris goes look he's up there talking to
him now and we keep walking away the
tour manager come running back
and said they said you can come and meet
them after the set when they come
offstage and I said no and he said
excuse me and I said no you wouldn't let
me go up on stage and have fun with the
people they sure as hell ain't getting a
photo-op with me thanks anyway
bye I like your style granny I'm glad
you've a moment that is a big diva
moment I think anybody else in this room
would have would have stuck around for
the photo op yeah do you see where I was
coming from yeah yeah they didn't want
you the first time why don't they want
you the second time I'm gonna take this
dab somebody find something good to
ramble about Oh what are you dabbing
there gee it's supposed to be the hdfs
see but it's real mushy would his monkey
blood it's got terms and he's taking a
hot dab as usual it's not red it's not
ready so I hope some day be real I meet
you I've been enjoying one of his new
projects but was never much a fan of the
old just said that oh the podcast you
know Mike there's no hatred that's not
your type of music nope it's just
outside of my rent and that's just not
your thing you were allowed to like and
dislike music I think that's why there's
so much of it America yeah
if anybody like a dab of that Charlie
Sheen I might recommend it that was uh
I'm roasted I'm gonna wait till a couple
other people dad before I go again all
right well it's sitting on the table
granny's got the huge flame going on
granny can you teach us about insert
dabs granny's gonna do an insert dab I
will discuss this freaks me out earlier
I had to ask questions so
well I talked about dabs a lot on the
show and I try to keep people updated on
what's going on the new way that we're
dabbing to use a banger it looks a lot
like the old banger but it's bigger it's
much wider so it is use a small I like a
small rig a small bubbler then this
piece fits where your bowl would go it
is comes up at a 90 degree angle then it
looks like it's got a giant glass symbol
on it to tell you the truth and granny
is about to burn her arm with it there
we go that was damn near a dad brand
yeah it's got a giant symbol and then
there is a smaller thimble you take the
smaller glass thimble and you load it
with your dab granny's put a nice tab
with this Charlie Sheen og in there like
a nice little insert you dropped that
one piece of glass into the other piece
like it's hot so you got one piece of
glass that you heat then you put your
dab inside of another you drop it in
there then you put a carbon cap on it
you want that bubble cap I think yes you
need a bubble cap you need a nice bubble
rotation as soon as it starts bubbling
granny starts dabbing it and smoking it
now you're gonna say that sounds like a
lot of [ __ ] work you're not wrong
it's it's really yeah it is a little
extra work but I like the ritual it
gives me one more step to participate in
my dab smoking maybe it'll slow me down
one little step that's one of the things
we have in common we both enjoy the
ritual taking a DAB and doing it just
feels nice one more thing is beautiful
that's why I don't like an email there's
no ritual all right I can agree with
that but now the reason for the insert
dab it's so much easier to pull that
little insert out of there and drop that
into the cup of alcohol that she brought
to clean it up and then now it's fresh
and clean the Scourge part of the dab
didn't just burn the inside of her nail
my nail is black and funky it tastes
like poop her dad tastes like turps and
fresh and there we go on I did one the
other night always 2 minutes and 27
seconds ago with it though it's not
required because she's got multiple
inserts and you could clean them off if
there's any rolls and stuff
granny granny is a spoiled Hache brat
and I'm all about it I'm very spoiled
and I I thank the powers that be every
day that I live in this life I do not
take it for granted we're smoking the
best ash on the planet in a cannabis
Church in Colorado Springs with our best
friends burger and a milkshake I'd never
lose we're gonna do that when we leave
so don't worry I would never leave
I think the chairs are comfortable the
people are good so this is a good call
grannies thanks for putting this
together
insert dad you guys if you're trying to
up your your dad level I was wondering
how you're gonna get that out of there
she brings little tweezers with yes
she's got the whole kid it's beautiful
whole set up they're not little tweezers
these look like they're the size of like
a heavy-duty letter opener yes yes and
she's got a jar of its ISO but it's
starting to look like cannabis moonshine
at this point it was clean when we
started well just kind of color to it
now it's kind of look like a piece was
crystal clear it looked like water for a
second I thought it was shine when I
first saw it I realized quickly that's a
jar of alcohol granny's gonna keep your
[ __ ] clean this has been an excellent
podcast has been a good fun time if you
want to grab that Mike brother you could
definitely jump on that one since uh the
Rev got busy come you're so smiley Josh
he's enjoyed the conversation is
watching the sausage get made we are
honored because we've got a winner this
guy's known as I rock watts he was a
winner of the Adam Dunn show
Invitational one year he's over there
shaking his head no but this kid grows
fire ask cannabis he knows what he's
doing if you need some work done this
guy is not afraid to put in [ __ ] work
he's one of those guys that puts in
hours he gets up before the Sun and he
goes to bed late at night and he's also
an Instagram troll so he's always put
weird [ __ ] turn and chickens should
we just title this one donkey show was
that the name of this episode oh I
wonder give the wrong impression
we can't have an insane sexual reference
every time granny's on the show the last
episode was about boof and hash fire
remember yes we did
I had used one of them suppositories
today are you okay I probably hurt
myself somehow some way and forgot how I
get you a security guard and like a
medic after I after I did this fall that
same night we're in that air B&amp;B and it
was on the third floor if you have ever
been to DC those brownstones are very
high and the railing only came to my
knee
well Kevin said order GrubHub so I
ordered us dinner but he had to go to
the gate to meet him so he text me I'm
here and I said I'll go get it and Kevin
said no if anybody could fall out this
thing and hurt themselves it's nighttime
I'll go get the food Kevin no thank you
that's a couple that should stay
together that's some [ __ ] my wife would
say we take care of one another
I want the french fries to survive the
drive yeah the fries never make it well
we've been together 45 years well he
should be on the show next time I want
to hear some of those stories I want to
hear about some of that oh he told he
told one he told about me dancing on
tables Kevin doesn't tell a lot of
stories but he told one so I didn't
write down the word twerk because I was
trying to dodge it but would you like to
tell us about your torque adventure miss
granny don't ever give me Hennessy I
like stories hit start with a stern
lucky to the Hennessy a stern look she's
never given me a look that serious book
don't ever give me Hennessy bonhomie
said will you do your party trick on my
it's called the slab our on W l sv radio
and I said sure I didn't know he is
giving me Hennessy and
I got drunk on the slab our and they had
a wrapper up there and I jumped up
onstage and I didn't know it but I seen
the video and I'm twerking want to see
that video it's on YouTube I'm going to
find that video project for tonight were
you doing the granny's party trick I did
the traditional I try to describe the
party trick but I don't know if I get
the steps in the correct order okay will
you teach us about I will so they didn't
have a bong so I had to get out of a
spoon Bowl but normally it'd be a bong
it would be a bong a do a bong rip and
then I threw back that shot of hennessey
and what would your normal shot be she's
still holding the pipe rip yeah take a
take a rip hold it in then do the shot
yes then I take the shot usually it'll
be like one of them fruity like they're
kind of like wine cooler shots because
when I equivocate them I can't even talk
but there's your fruity shot 150 we're
called porn stars and it's it's like
raspberry vodka it's not very strong
could you just get a stream so then I
take the shot then I do a DAB and then I
chug a beer a pint of beer and then I
exhale so I did that on Rico show but
then I went back and did another dab and
then I just drank out of the Hennessy
that part is what did it that is what
did it yeah so can you tell me part of
the story that you told earlier about
what happened in that damn studio about
my friend losing control you know it's a
cannabis radio show and Kris crazy and I
we just lost control we were crazy we
were we were we were just out of control
doing crazy stuff you didn't ever want
Mike with you well my husband was out in
the audience watching me
the poor guy that's phone homie is the
host of the radio show stands up and
says oh my god I just lost control I
lost control and he poured a beer over
his head and Kris crazy so that's the
first he's never lost I'm not one for
losing control I did eat edibles and try
to fly away on one episode that was
different I needed a damn seat belt I'm
sure that wasn't they sent 350
milligrams in that peanut butter bar it
was more than that it was plus 125 knows
that Mountain medicine peanut butter bar
it was labeled at 350 and as soon as I
bit into it I was like that tastes just
like pure weed I was like biting into a
brick of Mexican brick weed I ate it
about 20 minutes later I was like that
was way more than 350 milligrams to hit
me like twenty or thirty minutes you can
hear it in the podcast because I'm
talking I'm talking when they're so over
medicated like that half the time when
you bite into it you get this was before
those days this was when everything was
cannabutter and it just tasted like it's
anyway edibles hit me right away like 20
minutes later I was just wrecked I had
to be 500 milligrams it may be six I
don't know [ __ ] me up so quickly I'm
looking at you cuz it takes about a
thousand milligrams for me to even feel
anything Josh said how much is too much
for you 500 is too much what's your
normal dose if you're gonna eat edibles
he said a hundred he gave me the that
thing you do with your hands like no
[ __ ] more I'm out he gave me that
hand motion we're gonna give Josh a mic
and let him talk for a little bit if
you're pushing it how often do you eat
edibles though oh [ __ ] okay and you
still haven't built up a tolerance there
you go there's no reason to build it up
that's true stay a cheap date stay a
cheap date so maybe one weekend you're
gonna try like three or five hundred for
us one weekend you're gonna throw down
to three or five hundred and to see what
you could do are you a Ferrari guy deep
inside bro you need to grow a mole and
get a Ferrari yeah I've seen your
collection limo you gonna jump it on
some ramps jump over the alpaca all
right this guy weird pretty quick
explain that sense a little more
extension cord guy you guys over there I
see you double company 500 milligrams
funk juice there's an N in there right
sorry gonna funk you up is where did
that come from DC from DS oh okay
everything's imported everything well
there's a little bit of local stuff here
in front of us do you find that the
drinks hit you more quickly
I'm I just I think I'm high all the time
I know that's true your class saturated
I you know I don't think I know what yes
I do I wake up for about an hour and
then then I start dabbing okay
sometimes I won't to have until the
first break yeah yeah oh wait till the
first break it's good to go in and get
[ __ ] figured out and see what's going on
for the day and then get it all set I'm
past that I'm reaching yeah yeah I gotta
make a list of what to do and get my
rhythm on and then take a couple of dabs
what's about you and I run a large
commercial grow so there's always this
game of the first thing you do the class
yeah the first thing you do is go find
out what [ __ ] up laugh how big is a
large commercial grow there's one other
for what room has 55 lights and we have
seven rooms total seven flower rooms two
bedrooms that's there's a lot of stuff
going on and it's it's not understaffed
but it's barely staffed there's got days
precision staffing yes yeah we we could
use yeah but we don't want to pay you so
we're just gonna keep going like we are
as long as I've known you you've never
lost your passion for cannabis there's
always something new to spark it in me
it started to kind of I got overwhelmed
with this with these grows and then they
gave me a brand new one look at all
these new lights you get in all these
new tables and this new irrigation and
they brought me new strains and work
it's working you still have compassion
it I don't know who the hell would I be
without cannabis what would I be a
musician and it wouldn't be a happy life
that'd be on the road I'd be on the road
addicted to drugs that's not a future
for me this is the way to be would you
be a politician without cannabis yeah
psychologist oh boy when I graduated
college I was gonna go put broken
teenagers back together
teenagers okay
so write it right is there truly broken
and then you get to try to learn the
hard way that that's way too late to
intervene yeah I've got a 15 year old
girl and I was gonna say that's they're
not gonna change anything about them
after that when I went worked with the
the much younger kids the five six seven
year olds in social service care Dave
Blake broke my psyche like that's why I
was [ __ ] up when we met
it was cuz I was still coming off that
job and hadn't recovered yet no I don't
think I could deal with that yes no it's
everyday they'd be like here there's a
new kid coming in and then they would
hand you a notebook with the world's
most horrible story in it and that
happened like twice a week for three
years
that's like emotionally that's more than
one person even think about it in
serious terms and I don't like to draw
your eye look like you're distant yeah
job for surely can I had my aunt was a
social worker in Cedar Rapids Iowa and
she loved it it was her passion but I
was like that's too emotional for me I
can't deal with that the only positive
part was working with the older kids was
I had a little bit of an ability to yank
the occasional kid out of the meat
grinder before the system fully treat
them to death but once I went to work
with the younger kids just like that
level of [ __ ] up at this yeah it's
just it takes a certain type of person
who's just left yep
well you have to roll with it and then
you've got to do like therapy sessions
with the family and it's just seriously
I didn't have them invested nope yeah
way too young for that yeah because it's
so underfunded they can't afford people
who actually know what they're doing or
care so me right out of college they
were like here's a bunch of gang kids
good luck good yo yeah wait Mike
take care all these gang kids do you
guys feel that I'm just asking because I
am definitely doing this do you guys
feel like you go through phases where
sometimes you can smoke all the hash and
you don't get properly medicated or high
enough for where you want to be within
like four or five days later you'll open
up your jar and you'll try to take it
dab in as soon as you hit it so I'm so
high and it'll last for maybe an hour
yeah yeah yeah I'm going through into
those phases where just little tiny dads
have just been wrecking me I'm not
complaining I just wondered if other
people experienced it did you have you
taken a tolerance break or anything I
don't do that Gail neither I feel like I
had a natural pass dr. weir
talking about things like that it's dive
stomach problems and stuff they were
just talking they're a friend of mine
and they actually ran the holistic
clinic in the town I'm from she's past
now so this is a long time ago but uh
we're talking and she's like so what are
you doing for that stomach pain and
stuff and I was gonna just smoke like
this much hash and I do this and she's
like you better not ever stop smoking
cuz if you do whatever is really wrong
with you is gonna show I believe that
cannabis is what's keeping him alive and
that's been true for like 25 years
and I would myself they the doctors that
he's working with convinced him to get
off cannabis completely it just like
give it 30 days old man see what happens
and he did it and on day 15 they were
like please for the love of God go smoke
a joint like you're gonna die Jeff do
you take CBD on the Reg - I do not take
CBD I don't like the way CBD makes me
feel CBD got me through my head injury
at certain times and then I feel like
once I got past a certain point with the
head injury the CBD wasn't doing what I
wanted it to were you only smoking it or
were using identity I was taking pills
and I was smoking dabs of it I had when
I first hit my head it felt like I had
so you guys just a just a reminder or
update or whatever I had a traumatic
brain injury in April of back in the day
it was a couple years ago
in a doorway a low doorway I got the low
doorway knocked myself clean at the top
of some stairs knocked myself out fell
down the stairs woke up at the bottom of
the stairs a couple friends were pulling
me up the stairs had a traumatic brain
injury
I'm subdural hematoma and I'm treated
well let's let's move forward Mike I had
a few problems but anyway my head hurt
[ __ ] bad and I was at Maddy and
Spence's house and Spitz was making CBD
concentrates for a cannabis cup and he's
like dog you need that CBD and I was
like sure it's the stuff that ended up
winning the Cup so I took a couple of
big dabs of that and each dab felt it
felt like I had a belt too tight around
my head like you'd put a belt around my
head and stomped on it and tried to get
a ratchet clam
and when I took that CBD dad it feel
like you just took it off half a notch
and everybody in the room could see a
difference in me maddie was like are you
feeling better and I was like dude I'm
coming back cuz when I hit my head I
knocked the [ __ ] out of myself I
couldn't do math like I'm not even
kidding I couldn't do math probably
couldn't remember simple words like the
and I could but instead I would say
pickle or like yeah yeah I had really
weird symptoms I had other physical
symptoms I talked about my nervous boner
I would get a raging erection for no
reason if I got nervous or anxious just
get a huge boner which would just make
me more uncomfortable have an adult I
can't have a boner in public that's
[ __ ] horrible but so I smoked then
Spence was like Dawg you need more of
the CBD we can see a difference in you
so I was smoking the CBD with Spence and
he gave me a little bit of it and it got
me through it and then I got past the
dark times I call it of my head injury
there were terrible things going through
my mind I didn't know that I was gonna
make it through that if I didn't have
friends like Mike and a few other people
that were around my mom probably granny
a few other people that took good care
of me and they knew I had a brain injury
that would if I started saying weird
[ __ ] they just come hang out and I'd be
like it's like 3:00 in the morning why
are you still here it's cool bro I'm
just gonna hang out I'm talking strange
or something's going on I could tell
that that's why they're here but I
wasn't cognizant to figure out exactly
why but I knew I was like subconscious
is like you're just keeping it I mean he
do you think I might hurt myself or my
trying to microwave the batteries or
something I don't know because I was
doing weird and saying weird [ __ ] so
eventually the CBD got me through the
dark times and I realized that the high
THC was what I needed now cuz the pain
was gone the thoughts scrambling and the
word disassociation so you guys I
clearly was asking my mom to pass me a
banana to put in a smoothie and I kept
calling it a [ __ ] burrito and was
getting angry at my mom forget him
understand what you were give me the
goddamn burrito she's like there's not a
burrito over here I'm [ __ ] pointing
at a burrito mom I want that burrito why
are you [ __ ] with me is making me
really mad like why would my mom do this
to me I want that burrito I can see it I
want to touch I want to eat it
I meant banana she was really having my
back so things were weird but that was
coming back all my my signals were going
to the right path but my thoughts would
I don't know they would scatter it would
feel like I got a filing cabinet in my
brain and somebody just dumped out the
files and they were still
there I just couldn't get to him as
quickly I'd be like oh you want to know
my name hold on and I'd have to shuffle
through all the papers and then we'd
find it here's my birthday I know what
it is I can tell you then I started
smoking the high THC stuff and it
started putting it back together the
puzzle pieces when I start getting that
like I can't remember [ __ ] the high THC
the limonene and T you still get that I
don't know because I stay so long I
don't know I had brain farts before I
hit my head I'm trying to think too many
things I'm responsible for 15 employees
to grows a daughter the friends whatever
else Facebook Instagram Twitter podcast
driving putting on my shoes you know I
got so many things there's gonna be a
[ __ ] brain fart in there somewhere I
think I can tell the difference between
the brain injury brain farts and the
natural you're just thinking too many
things or you had too many tabs brain
farts so now what does the CBD do make
you feel like it makes me
Gumby like it makes me not feel like
I've got complete control of my fingers
in my hands like if I go to try to you
ever been in the cold and your thumbs
are too cold and you have texts that's
what CBD does to my thumbs
I just I feel like I'm missing instead
I'm hitting the Pete that's strange yeah
yeah it just makes my my dexterity goes
funky but and so I don't smoke it when
people like this is mad CBD I'm like oh
give that to granny who it works for or
Mike who it works for because it's a
waste on me it just doesn't do what I
want it to do
we're on tinctures and it ruins my THC
high if I get it takes me because it
takes me a little bit I'm medicating I'm
not smoking the first three dads are
medicine the fourth and fifth one that's
probably recreational but it takes me a
minute to get where I need to be
medicinally I got a smoke to get my to
build it up it's like if you take
whatever 250 milligram pills I got to
get my 250 milligrams or whatever in my
body by consuming it before I start I
would like to dab yeah just go in just
beautiful and I don't want to [ __ ] that
up with CBD I don't want to just I I run
into that all the time because I eat a
lot of well not a lot for the people at
this table but a lot for civilians CBD
every day and if I've been hurting all
day and we've been running around really
hard and like my knees my harvest 165
plants
in one day on days like that I'll end up
consuming four or five times the normal
amount of CBD THC pills that I normally
take and those days when I go home all
right
end of the day kids asleep wanna relax
want to get a nice buzz going I'll take
four or five bong hits and I Mike's
Sobers judge yep give it a couple of
minutes take a DAB give it a couple
minutes we'll call for a couple minutes
Mike likes to cough and then I'll start
to get to where I want to be but on days
where I haven't been earning and it's
been office work all day maybe I didn't
even take a pill that day I get home for
that first bong grant puts me halfway to
the where I want to be it's so much
quicker I just think we really need CBD
I take picture every morning I don't
smoke it anymore but I feel like it's uh
what's the drug they give you when
you're it's like noir can to your heroin
it's like it's the same thing for my THC
CBD rescue pills for people who weigh
over consume yeah yeah I don't want that
I spend so much time and money trying to
consume all this THC yeah but don't you
believe like if you take a tincture in
the morning that's not like smoking it
yes smoking it is going to do something
different I don't know I should try I
just don't feel like I go the other way
well I'll give you a success story I
would love to hear it Kevin's been taken
off the transplant list fixed himself
with CBD Eights do you mind telling more
a little backup story about what he was
gonna have transplanted and what do you
have cured with don't go too far that
you're not comfortable I wouldn't ask
for too much details in 93 different
treatments to try to rid them of it
every treatment gave him worse symptoms
you never got rid of the hepatitis C put
them in
cirrhosis of the liver finally in 2011
they put him on a new experimental drug
what you see on TV now it's called
harvoni it rid him of hepatitis C but
there was so much damage done to his
liver that he had been listed for a
transplant for a liver but he was also
on so many other drugs because of all
the other symptoms that come along with
that that's how he became that opioid
zombie once we got him off all the
opioids and he started coming around
like a normal human being again started
taking the CBD tincture with me every
day smoking he doesn't die but he will
smoke flower his checkup in January
his liver functions are all coming back
to the point that the head doctor came
in and went wait a minute wait a minute
left the room came back with Kevin's
whole team and said look at Kevin look
at how good he is said I know what
you're doing keep doing it you look so
good your functions are so well how do
you feel about us removing you from the
transplant list that's pretty impressive
kindness it was like are you kidding I
was taking a DAB but that is amazing
congratulations to you and Kevin because
that's the greatest news and you can see
the pictures that you guys are having
agree and he doesn't look sick anymore
yeah he's still got issues he's he's got
diabetes so he gets [ __ ] he gets tired
in his feet he's got neuropathy and
because he's still got liver issues bad
way better than what you thought was
coming for you thought he was dying yeah
no you get to keep him he gets to keep
you yeah hope you guys have a lot of
more years together do you guys feel
like cannabis is messing with your
dreams do you dream when you smoke no no
I have so people talk about they smoke
indica to go to sleep and sativas during
the day I do the opposite kind of I like
to smoke a heavy sativa right before bed
look [ __ ] how can you sleep oh I just
lay down and giggle and giggle until I
fall asleep and I have the best dreams I
fly away I go to all the greatest places
we do all the big dab of that pre 98 and
it will knock me out oh yeah yeah if I
need like well like on Friday night like
tonight it's Friday I don't I can sleep
in a little bit tomorrow I don't have to
get up when the alarm goes off so I'll
just get and I'm tired cuz I work you
know what I mean I that's how I sleep
I'm tired my body I put in the hours
we carry a bunch when he's harvesting
now yes but so I'll smoke that a
super-heavy sativa right before I go to
bed and I'll have the best dreams I
dream I don't know I have all the dreams
that you think you can dream about like
flying dreams [ __ ] Ferrari dreams
weird sex dreams swimming in the sky
dreams living in a tree dreams I don't
that much I have the craziest dream
that's how I would be Mike that's what a
lot of people say I had fucked-up dreams
before I started consuming
yeah I'd lucid dream either way I had
the weirdest dreams when I was forced
like two years sober in Wyoming Oh
lucid dreams turn to like not cool fun
dreams but to like all kinds of weird
like getting busted for drug dreams so
hard you guys haven't eaten meat I can
see realistically I know 2001 I went on
Phish tour with my friend Rob and I was
a pain in the ass cuz I wasn't eating
meat so there was a lot of subway and a
lot of Taco Bell on that tour yeah shut
up - Rob for putting up with that so
it's been since at least 2001 since I've
consumed me and I had dreams the other
night that I was eating I was at a
restaurant where I grew up
Angelo's burgers in Bellflower
California they used to have the most
delicious [ __ ] steaks which is old
bro I was it might be I was I'm getting
hungry right now talking about it
I was eating a steak sandwich and
everybody at the table gave me that look
like if I were to just pull out crack
right now and smoke it
everyone gave me that same look like hey
you're wrong you're eating a steak
sandwich bro and my answer was the table
was like dude you're a strict vegetarian
doesn't look like it no did you do I did
wake up one night I took some medicine
and I woke up I took some mucinex and I
woke up with a [ __ ] peanut butter and
jelly sandwich in my bed that I do not
remember Church is almost perfect way to
end the story where I got lost stay -
don't listen to this and we'll talk
about it on episode 2 we'll get all
these people apart to wrap it up I want
to thank everybody for coming granny
together this is a great time thanks for
getting me super dabbed out you've got
some tangi dads I had some hardcore og
we took some green thumb rosin dabs
which you guys changed my opinion of
rosin I liked it was delicious and that
was delicious it tasted amazing but
normally even said that it lingered it's
kind of heavy
Reb thanks for inviting us to the church
we'll be back we'll come take some dabs
here this is a great place I rock thanks
for jumping in for a minute bro if you
have more weird dreams come tell us
about it tell us about on the show next
time we're just gonna strap you up with
a mic and let you go thanks thanks for
hanging out with this keep the girl
going cracker Mike thanks for driving up
with me thanks for having a great
podcast yeah we're gonna go find some
food
that's the mission alright ladies
gentlemen we're gonna wrap up the
podcast does anybody have any social
media they would like to shout out make
sure you follow davon granny on all the
social media especially Instagram watch
the party tricks live the Rev I'm on
Twitter Reverend for 20 talk about that
next time
of course I rock watts okay yeah he
rocks those watts he's a good grower
make sure you follow I rock and of
course follow cracker Mike and of course
the guys if you want to stalk me you
know how to do it you can find me at
Rasta Jeff 420 on Twitter you can find
the show at G fyh podcast on Twitter
make sure you check me out on Instagram
you guys we do a lot of Instagram live
videos lately it's been a lot of fun I
read or genetics on Instagram if you've
got some sin you aren't in all that
social media it's real easy contact me
through an email it's grow from your
heart at hotmail.com I would love to
hear from you ladies and gentlemen check
out the patreon at patreon.com slash
core from your heart also check out the
green faith Church in Colorado Springs
this place is super chill we'll be back
here alright thanks again everybody for
being on the show thank you until next
time take a phat dab and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]