Oh
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for another episode of the
grow from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation let's right up here a new
grower if you're a professional grower
if you're a new smoker or a dedicated
dabber if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who is just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host my friends call me Rasta Jeff I
want to thank you guys again for joining
me this episode of the podcast is
brought to you by my friends at the hell
a dank seed company if you need new
genetics for your garden I highly
recommend the hell a dank seed company
you can find them at dank seed dot store
ladies and gentlemen
roll up a fat joint pack up the bong or
start heating up that dab rig because
it's time for another episode of the
grill from your heart podcast welcome
back podcast world it's time for episode
316 a quick Thursday episode you know I
like to start the show off by letting
you know what I'm smoking on I've been
taking dabs of sour kosher live resin
full-spectrum extract from our friends
at Green Dot labs this stuff is
delicious it kind of smells like dirty
feet with diesel filled poured over it
and I really like it it sounds
disgusting
but it is so good I took a big old dab
of it and it just made my head go in
slow motion everything just went so it's
gonna be nice and calm should be a
pretty good podcast all right guys one
thing I want to mention before we get
into the show I know that the episode
numbers were out of order what happened
was I recorded the Monday episode I put
it up I was like that'll come out Monday
everything will be cool it had a number
it was number 314 then I decided hey
let's record a Sunday episode for moms
on Mother's Day I labeled that one 315
because that's what my brain does I went
in order I didn't think about it I put
that one out on Sunday 315 came out on
Sunday 314 came out on Monday sorry the
numbers got out of order a few people
have tweeted me I've gotten a couple of
emails I know it's wrong you don't have
to message me anymore
I'm not gonna fix it we're at episode
316 nothing went wrong we are okay but
hey thanks to everybody who messaged me
and tried to keep me updated and let me
know that I got out of order I
appreciate that
anyway moving forward here we are
episode 316 I want to talk a little bit
about what I got to do this weekend one
of my favorite comedians is Doug Benson
and of course Doug and I have kind of
become buddies over the past few years
since I've gone to so many of his shows
and interacted with him so much every
year Doug Benson comes to comedy works
in downtown Denver and does a live
taping of his podcast called Doug loves
movies Doug loves movies is a podcast
all about movies and movie trivia Doug
encourages the audience members to make
nametags it's not like a nametag that
would say hi my name is Rasta Jeff but
it's more like a movie poster idea the
idea is that you print a movie poster
and you replace a word in the movie
title with your name and then replace
one of the characters in the movies face
with your face and possibly add Doug
Benson and whoever you think one of the
guests on the shows maybe you swap their
faces with the guest face in your face
and Doug's face so it's a custom poster
like maybe you might have a poster that
says Rasta Jeff strikes back and you've
taken out you've put Rasta Jeff's face
right in the middle of it so it's Rasta
Jeff strikes back swinging a big light
saber looking like a Jedi that's pretty
cool um so that's the idea you bring
nametag posters and then doug has three
comedian guests that join him on stage
and they come out and they select a
nametag from the audience nametags and
they are playing for that person so if
the celebrity wins then the person whose
name tag they have selected wins the
prizes that come from a prize bag so
that's sort of the idea behind what the
the nametags the prizes and then there
are games that happen and Doug plays
random movie trivia games based on
whatever he feels like doing that night
and whatever he's got lined up for the
show so that's how Doug Benson show
happens that's what Doug Benson's show
is I know that I'm gonna get the
opportunity to smoke before and/or after
the show with Doug Benson so I rolled up
five 10-gram raw cones so I had a couple
of 10grams ready to smoke at all times I
had a couple in my pocket at all times
in case something came up and of course
we uh so i met my buddy i picked up my
friend Baker and Baker and I drove to
comedy works from downtown Denver maker
lives a little off of downtown we drove
to downtown Denver
in the parking garage then we met up
with my friend Brett Mary's motivation
on Instagram we may have gotten a little
bit stoned then we headed into Comedy
Works around 4:15 we decided to go
outside of Comedy Works and go smoke I
was carrying one of those raw cones in
the package it was in the little uh that
rock cones come in a package so that
they're sold the the rolling paper
without any cannabis has sold in this
cone-shaped package so that the paper
doesn't get destroyed I just rolled the
joint and put it back in there and then
I was walking out of the comedy club
just carrying that and a lighter so it
was kind of obvious what was about to go
happen and I looked behind me and it was
myself and Brett and my friend Baker and
another guy that I had seen before
somewhere but I wasn't sure who the hell
he was and then it dawned on me
I said hey you're Decker doom and he
goes yeah brother and he shook my hand
it was a friend who had been watching my
Instagram feed and we became Instagram
friends and he told me he was gonna be
at the show and I said hey if you see me
come introduce yourself he was smart
enough to see me and my crew go walking
out the back door of the club at 4:15
and thought I should probably follow
those boys and he was smart because we
went out there and smoked a 10 gram
joint and there weren't very many people
out there the people who were out there
were pretty damn cool so anyway we
finished smoking our joint and we go
back inside everybody gets comfortable I
worked out perfectly because right as we
walked in our food and drinks were
delivered to our table to our seats it
was it was perfect timing it couldn't
have been any better we sat there for
just a couple of minutes I had time to
pound down my snack and then the lights
went out and the comedy show started so
it was Doug loves movies so Doug comes
out and he tells jokes and uh sets up
the show you know for a few minutes he
talks about where he's gonna be for the
next few weeks and tells all of his Doug
plugs and just kind of hangs out with
the audience and then he brings out his
guests about five or ten minutes into
the show his guests this time were a
comedian named Jacob Seraph who is known
for traveling with Doug and doing a few
Doug loves movies podcast he's kind of a
regular there was another comedian by
the name of Dan Cheeseman who is a
semi-regular on the podcast and he is
not the Cheeseman from Cheeseman parks
if you guys listen to the podcast
there's plenty of jokes about that all
the parks in Denver are called Cheeseman
lots of businesses called Cheeseman
something he is not that Dan she
I mean also another comedian by the name
of John toll who I've seen before at
Comedy Works John toll is a funny dude
he's got a CD available that was
recorded at the downtown location of
Comedy Works uh he did a really good job
of sitting in with the two semi-regulars
it was his first time on the podcast
Doug likes to bring a hometown hero if
you will to be on the show he picks a
local comedian and lets them be on the
show that way we feel like we've got
sort of a connection you know what I
mean one of our players is on the stage
so Doug likes to do that I feel like
John toll held his own and fit in very
well with the other comedians so let's
see where should I go from here let's
give some shoutouts only give a shout
out to Doug Benson after every show I've
ever been to doug has taken time to come
outside and meet anybody who wants to
meet him if you want to take a picture
with Doug he'll be out there you can go
smoke a joint take a picture with Doug
Benson he doesn't mind he's friendly
he's cool as [ __ ] so shout out to Doug
for bringing the Doug loves movies
podcast to Denver all the time it's one
of my favorite podcasts and I love the
games so big shout out to Doug Benson
also a big shout out to Jacob cereth who
were gonna talk about here in a minute
another huge shot at two dale Cheeseman
he was really funny he did a little
Instagram live video for me with my
joint that I rolled also big huge shout
out to John
toll the comedian he's a new guy check
him out also I want to give you huge
shout out to everybody at Comedy Works
you guys Comedy Works treats me like
royalty they say that I'm a regular and
I don't feel like I go there often
enough to be a regular but if they're
gonna treat me like that I am going to
take it I feel like they treat everybody
super well Comedy Works is a super cool
club if you've never gone to a comedy
show and I've said this before go to a
comedy club even if you can't go to
comedy works even if you can't go to the
Comedy Store in LA go to the comedy club
where you where you are support local
comedy it's funnier than you think and
if you don't go to the comedy club it'll
disappear because nobody went to it and
then one day you'll say man I wish we
could get Joey Diaz to come around here
and I'll say dammit you used to have a
comedy club and you never went to it and
now you black Joey and now you want him
to come and you [ __ ] up and didn't go
to the comedy club before and it's gone
so go check out some comedy go support
live comedy go be a good comedy fan
don't heckle the comedians don't talk
[ __ ] just go enjoy the show buy some
drinks tape
waitress smoke out the comedian after
the show and have a good time and also
you don't always have to go see big-name
acts you can go see open mic errs you
never know you may get to see the next
Eddie Murphy at an open mic and you
could say man I saw that guy when he was
just some stumbling open mic her and you
can watch this new guy become the next
Eddie Murphy you may get to see that so
go support some comedy that's what I'm
saying it's good for you guys you could
tell how excited I get about it it just
makes you feel good go see some laughter
maybe eat a little bit too much edibles
maybe take too big of a dab and just go
see some comedy you go see a podcast
taping go have some fun and cut loose go
to your local comedy club and support
that [ __ ] I think it's good for you so
big shout out to Comedy Works they treat
me really well also huge shout out to my
friend Baker I'm not sure how often you
listen to this podcast bro but thank you
man
it's always fun hanging out with you and
I had a great time I owe you one
also big shout out to Bret you guys Bret
is leaving the country Bret is gonna go
on a I'm gonna call it a spiritual
journey he called it a sabbatical
himself but he's gonna go find himself
and he thinks him his self could be in
some other countries so Bret is selling
all of his personal belongings and he's
gonna fly to another country and he's
gonna travel around and then when he
thinks he's had enough of that he's
gonna fly back to the States and figure
life out so I knew there was one of my
last weekends to see my buddy Brett so I
decided to take him to the comedy show
with me we had a great time
shout out to my friend Brett I am gonna
miss the [ __ ] out of you bro I hope you
have a safe and amazing journey also
shout out to my new friend he's been
stalking me and trolling me and my
Instagram live feeds for quite a while
we finally got to meet we finally got to
smoke a joint and a dad together we got
to shake hands I shot it to my boy
Decker doom hey Decker it was really
cool meeting you bro I hope you're
listening to the podcast I hope you're
taking a big old fat dab also dude I've
got the the concentrate gift that you
gave me it's right over here I haven't
smoked it yet so I'm gonna have to smoke
that right after the podcast all right I
think I've covered all of that stuff I
said we were gonna talk about Jacob sear
off a little bit more when Doug Benson
brought Jacob sear off out on stage he
pointed at me and he's like hey you you
gotta quit doing the Instagram live
feeds what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna
wrap up the
Caston I'm going to play a clip from the
Doug loves movies podcast I'm not sure
if I'm supposed to do that not sure if
that episode this episode will get taken
down or something because I'm using part
of Doug's podcast Doug and I are friends
but I didn't ask for permission or
anything because I feel like if I do
this part it'll be worth it hey guys one
of my favorite podcasts is the Doug
loves movies podcast I highly suggest
that you listen to Doug loves movies if
nothing else listen to the recent
episode from Denver and hear them talk
[ __ ] to me a bunch of times but you'll
enjoy it it's a great show find an
episode with Mark Wahlberg those are
extra hilarious but anyway what I'm
gonna do is I'm gonna wrap up the show
I'm gonna do all my shout outs and my
advertising and then I'm going to play a
couple of seconds I'm not sure how long
it is I'm gonna play the clip from the
Doug Benson live taping in Denver of the
Doug loves movies podcast where Jacob
sear off [ __ ] attacked me from the
stage you guys I'm just kidding it was I
was all fun and games he was smiling the
whole time but when he walked out on
stage he immediately went to talk and
[ __ ] right to me it was fun we've met
before and he came up to me right after
he's like dude you know I was joking
right and before he could even walk out
of the comedy club I knew you would come
around the corner so I was doing an
Instagram live feed as soon as he came
out and I went like a news reporter I
was like this guy Jacob sure off right
here says I go live on Instagram too
much how do you feel about that I turned
the camera around and we did a little
interview with him on Instagram life it
was kind of funny but I'm going to play
a clip from the Doug loves movies
podcast right after I say all of this
stuff ladies gentlemen thanks for
listening to a quickie episode it's not
gonna be quick if I keep a rambling my
face off I know there was no cannabis
talk sometimes it's cannabis news
sometimes it's education sometimes it's
conversation this time it was Ross to
Jeff getting high and rambling with you
you guys thanks again for hanging out
make sure you find me on all the social
media follow me on Facebook simply
search for the girl from your heart
podcast on Instagram it's Irie
underscore genetics on Twitter it's at G
fyh podcast you can also find my
personal Twitter account
it's Ross to Jeff for 20 if you'd like
to say something and you're not into all
of the social media you can send me an
email it's grow from your heart at
hotmail.com also don't forget about the
youtube channel there are 270 videos on
the YouTube channel if you feel like
this podcast was worth a couple of bucks
you can contribute by going to
patreon.com slash grow from your
are all the information that you need
we'll be right there you guys help me
back Monday with another full-length
episode filled with cannabis news and
education it won't be just conversation
this time I know you prefer the grow
lessons and stuff like that so I will
get back to it I feel like these
Thursday episodes are a little bonus all
right you guys I'm gonna play the clip
from the Doug loves movies podcast it
was sitting right in the front directly
in front of Jacob serif he didn't waste
any time he walked out he sat down he
got introduced and then here is what
ensued you guys I'm gonna wrap up the
podcast I'm gonna say goodbye now I hope
you enjoy listening this episode may get
taken down because I'm using part of
somebody else's podcast and I don't know
if I'm allowed to do that so I hope you
enjoyed it I want to give you a huge
shout out to my friend Brett I'm gonna
miss you bro and until next time take a
phat dab and give your mom a hug for me
possibly North America's number one
prequel apologist
[Music]
hi Denver go Raiders I was just about to
say the Denver crowds love you cuz you
come in here and yeah they've just you
know you just you are what you are then
you immediately say something to upset
them I'm thrilled to be here it's great
I have to tell this guy though stop
doing so much live internet you know the
the Instagram live don't do that that's
annoying
I was doing this I read genetics live
right that's you yeah you're always
doing the live video stop doing that I
was at the notification and I have to
clear it the crowd favorite I know it's
with this conversation with in the alley
after the show you bring it up
I found this internet account is a
nightmare for me
great hosts great the ages two months
with the live instead I want to make
sure I told you be careful out there you
guys it's gonna rain but Jacob thanks
for being here