yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for another episode of the
grow from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower
if you're a professional grower if
you're a new smoker or a dedicated
dabber if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who is just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Roscoe
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me this episode of the podcast
is brought to you by my friends at the
hell a dank seed company if you need new
genetics for your gardening I highly
recommend the hella dank seed company
you can find them at dank seed dot store
ladies and gentlemen roll up a fat joint
pack up the bong or start heating up
that dab rig because it's time for
another episode of the grill from your
heart a podcast
[Music]
what's up cannabis community it's time
for episode 317 of the girl from your
heart podcast thanks again for joining
me you guys I just woke up from a
tremendous nap our friends from organic
has stopped by and we got a little bit
lit up I may have eaten too many edibles
I may have taken too many dads but I am
back on my feet I'm ready to do a
podcast I like to start the episode off
by letting you know what I am dabbing on
today I dabbed a little bit of
everything but what's gonna happen is
I'm gonna tell you about this then I'm
gonna press pause and take a DAB and
then we're gonna do a podcast I'm about
to take a dab of some stuff called
Clementine cookies from viola extracts I
picked this up at doctor's orders on
stem Beach doctor's orders was having a
sale on the green dot black label and I
stopped in for some of the green dot I
saw the viola Labs products on sale they
had a jar on the counter and it was
called Clementine cookies I took a smell
of it and before I could set the jar
down my mouth said I'll take a gram of
this please this stuff smells amazing
you guys I'm gonna give it a sniff right
now and try to describe it to you so I
can certainly smell the Girl Scout
cookies Girl Scout cookies has a
spiciness to it I think it's got a black
pepper kind of a spicy sort of a thing
that's a little bit of a sharp
astringent sort of a smell which is
honestly delicious and I love it that is
dominant in the aroma of this
concentrate but right under that there's
a
this candy sweet bottom from the
Clementine
it's like spicy delicious oranges and it
smells amazing the amount of Terps to
Crystal's was perfect in here I think it
was probably 70% crystals and 30% turps
I really like the texture of it the
flavor was super nice the high was
amazing it came on super fast and it
went right to my head right to my eyes
it made my eyes feel all droopy I made
my head feel all fuzzy I guess I would
describe it more of a stoned
than a high cuz I just wanted to chill
out I just wanted to stare into nothing
for a couple of minutes so this was kind
of an impulse buy and I am completely
satisfied with the Clementine cookies
live resin from viola extracts great
work you guys now since I've hyped it up
so much I think I'm going to press pause
and take a big fat dab and then we're
gonna come back with an email from a cop
all right podcast ruled I am back I am
heavily medicated I just took a fat dab
of the Clementine cookies live resin
from viola extracts it tastes better
than I remembered and the high went
straight to my brain one thing I did
notice I took the dab off of a rig with
a smaller mouthpiece I am learning that
I prefer a larger flared out mouthpiece
to little of a mouthpiece if you have to
make that kissy face with your mouth I
feel like it makes your lips all sticky
if you take a large dab so larger
mouthpieces for larger dabs that's my
opinion that's my advice I still want a
small rig but a flared out wider
mouthpiece for Less stickiness in my
moustache and on my teeth
alright you guys I'm obviously heavily
medicated before I took this dab break I
teased that we were gonna read an email
from a cop and you might say how do you
know it's from a cop well I was checking
my email a few days ago and I saw the
subject line greetings from a cop so I
skipped everything else I was working on
and I scrolled right down and I opened
up the email from my new cop friend and
it goes just like this it says hey Rasta
Jeff first off thank you for the amazing
podcast hey dude you're very welcome
thank you for the amazing email he keeps
going he says I've just recently started
listening to it and I'm going back over
old episodes about three to five hours
daily wow that's a lot of listening man
thank you thanks for the support
also if you've caught up on all the
episodes on iTunes and stitcher all of
the episodes are available on YouTube so
if you want old old content you can go
to the YouTube channel go to YouTube
type in grow from your heart podcast or
bring up the YouTube channel and you can
find all of the old episodes that way
you can listen to the really old stuff
also if you're all caught up on
everything on stitcher or iTunes I'll
keep going with the email it goes like
this I wanted to tell you a little bit
about myself and my current situation
first off I will tell you that I am a
police officer prior to becoming a cop I
used to regularly like everyday smoke
cannabis from about 16 to 22 years old
at age 22 I decided to stop a series of
positive events led to my becoming an
officer I told myself I would never be a
hypocrite I would never arrest or ticket
someone for something that I would do
like smoking weed rolling stop signs
driving too fast etc but I would be
happy to arrest people for beating their
wife breaking into houses shooting
others abusing children you see where
I'm heading I can honestly say I sleep
just fine knowing I don't break my
personal code I kind of feel if more
police officers had this approach to
their job that more people would respect
the police and the community would get
along with the police a little bit
better I don't feel that law enforcement
understands the long-term effects of
their harassment and some of the things
that they do to the community sometimes
a person will have an interaction with
law enforcement and they will receive a
ticket for something that they don't
agree with and then they've got to go to
court which means they've got to miss a
day of work or they've got to pay a fine
which means now they're even more behind
because not all of us are doing okay
financially so those people fall behind
financially they get a fine if you've
got the option of paying your car
payment or paying your rent or paying
that fine you're gonna pay the rent the
car payment because you don't see what
happens if you don't pay the fine now
you've got a bench warrant now you go to
jail while you're in jail you lose your
car while you're in jail you lose your
job while you lose your job you lose
your house and it begins a spiral of
[ __ ] and I don't know if law enforcement
realizes what they do to people
sometimes and when things could simply
be
excused or overlooked if nobody's
hurting anybody I don't see a reason
there's no crime if nobody's getting
hurt if nobody's causing a problem
there's no reason to [ __ ] up somebody's
life and so I respect an officer they
can use situational awareness and
judgment and not cause a problem for
somebody so man a lot of respect to you
for that thank you I appreciate you for
that not all cops are bad we got to keep
that in mind I want to keep reading the
email because I'm super rambley after
the dabs I just took the email goes on
to say about two years ago I had a
terrible injury at work fighting a man
that I was arresting after investigating
how he had molested a three year old boy
and I have had three major surgeries and
five giant needle injections man that's
a huge sentence there's a lot of stuff
to to absorb in that one so you had a
terrible injury at work fighting a man
that you arrested because he had
molested a three-year-old boy so that's
a lot of mental stuff to deal with first
of all you know that this man was doing
some terribleness and you had to arrest
him and then when that went down he
tried to physically fight you where you
got injured and it changed your life and
since then you've had three surgeries
probably all three of those are
traumatic and five giant needle
injections saying the phrase five giant
needle injections makes my toes curl
every time I say it so it sounds like
you've been through a lot man it sounds
like you're going through a lot and it
sounds like you were trying to be a good
cop so that's terrible that this is sort
of the pan you were dealt for being a
good cop I want to keep reading your
message it says obviously I was given
opiate pain pills like they were candy
and they led me into a deep dark place
I've heard this story a lot and I kind
of know how that goes it seems like a
lot of people get injured a lot of good
folks get injured they go to the doctor
they end up getting put on these pills
and it turns their life around it's not
the injury it's not the depression it's
not the change of life it's the pills
that these doctors are giving people it
seems to send them down a dark path he
continues to say really not fun and I'm
glad to be alive on this side of pain
pills
after nearly a year and a half of either
24/7 pain or opiate induced stupor
I got a CBD vape this is where the story
starts to change you guys I used that
for about a week and decided eff it give
me the real thing
so this guy was in pain he was in an
opiate induced stupor
this guy wasn't himself anymore he
probably wasn't enjoying life his family
probably wasn't enjoying him he wasn't
happy anymore he was just a zombie
because of these doctors just pumping
him up with pain pills so he got himself
a CBD vape and it sounds like it was
working for a little bit and then he
decided eff it give me the real thing
and that's where he goes on to say
cannabis has literally saved me from
pills cannabis has about the same pain
relieving qualities as pills but
cannabis does not leave me depressed
after I can say the biggest side-effect
I see is the munchies see the biggest
side effect which isn't even I don't
believe in side effect I think that is
an effect because you can't separate the
effects of something if you just said
what does it do to you he says it makes
me stoned it makes me forget things it
makes me kind of chill out it also makes
me hungry that's an effect not a side
effect in my opinion sorry random rant
but the worst effect he got from it was
the munchies and for somebody who has
been laid up for a little while and
who's been in pain and who has been on
narcotic pills that are making them a
zombie um
the munchies probably isn't a bad thing
you're probably a little emaciated you'd
probably use a couple of snacks honestly
but also he says that the cannabis does
not leave him depressed like the pain
pills did and also they're not doing a
liver damage they're not doing kidney
damage and they're not making you a
zombie they're leaving you functional
you've got the munchies that's not too
bad as long as you're not handling those
munchies with cartons of Ben and Jerry's
ice cream and Snickers bars as long as
you're treating that properly maybe you
got some some avocado slices or some
hard-boiled eggs maybe you got you some
hats on a log maybe you got some celery
and peanut butter with raisins on it
like a big kid
I don't know hopefully you're doing
something good to take care of those
munchies but that's if that's the worst
effect that's coming from it and you're
not getting depressed you're not getting
your liver torn up you're not getting
your stomach burnt up and you're not
acting like a zombie and you're
functional eat whatever you want to eat
maybe you get you a little gut you're
gonna be alright
he keeps on going and says I recently
started growing my own cannabis I can't
really do much physical activities due
to my injury but I am able to guard it
I really think that growing your own
cannabis is going to help you in so many
ways
it'll be very therapeutic because now
you've got something you can do that
you're physically able to do that you
can take pride in you can put some time
into that garden you can look at it and
you can sit back when you're done
working and you can go those plants look
good man cuz I did that I just put in a
few hours doing that and those plants
look really good and then when it's time
to cut them down dry I'm cure him and
smoke him you get to feel that pride of
I did this I didn't have to pay anybody
for this and then also there's this
thing of I know what's in here I didn't
spray this with any weird [ __ ] I didn't
do anything stupid to this I know it's
in this cannabis and it's such a good
feeling so let me continue with the
email he says I am able to garden and I
have an organic outdoor setup that is
awesome to hear man I hope you got to
listen to the episodes with Sean I hope
you listen to the episodes with Jesse if
you have questions about that send me an
email
he says I'm growing in smart pots so far
things are small but happy man that's
the best way to keep it for a personal
garden don't go uh don't get yourself in
over your head
he says ingesting growing listening and
learning about cannabis has saved my
life I'm gonna read that sentence again
you guys because this is tremendous he
says ingesting growing listening and
learning about cannabis has saved my
life
cannabis has saved another life you guys
learning about cannabis has saved this
person's life so shout out to cannabis
thank you to cannabis once again he says
there were days when I thought about
suicide or nearly killed myself by
taking more than the prescription and
Men mixing alcohol I haven't taken a
pill in months haven't had a drink and
mentally and emotionally I feel much
better
you guys this guy is not drinking or
taking pills and he is consuming
cannabis and his mental and physical
state have drastically improved cannabis
you guys I don't need to preach to the
choir right most of the people listening
are already going yeah Rasta Jeff we're
on your team you guys I love hearing
messages like this no matter how many
times I hear this it puts a smile on my
face it puts some pride in me it makes
me feel good about being a spokesperson
or an ambassador for this plant it
really puts pride in me again it reefs
parks the
that I've got like granny said the
passion has never gone away and it's
because things like this spark it every
single time I get a message so this part
is where it gets great he says Rasta
Jeff thank you for being a part of my
life and giving me this enriching
podcast hey man thank you for this great
email you were very welcome I'm glad you
didn't do anything ridiculous when you
were in those dark depressed days to be
quite honest excuse me for all the
throat problems you guys we're gonna
blame that on the viola extracts here to
be quite honest I had a traumatic brain
injury a couple maybe three years ago
and there were times I couldn't figure
out how to tie my shoes there were times
I'd be brushing my teeth and couldn't
figure out why I was standing in the
kitchen with her in the bathroom see I'm
still doing weird [ __ ] I was standing in
the bathroom with a mouthful of weird
[ __ ] there were times when the thought
of ending everything would pass through
my mind but I knew that it was just cuz
my brain was broken and it wasn't
working right so I'm proud of you and
I'm happy that you made it through that
thank you for sticking through it and
battling through that with us and being
on Team cannabis with us now you
wouldn't have been able to be a good
spokesperson for cannabis so thank you
for making it through that thank you for
enduring and thank you for being part of
Team cannabis thank you for having an
open mind and realizing that cannabis
could be part of what would help you
so you're very welcome is what I'm
trying to say and thank you for the
great email he goes on to say PPS I
would be happy to answer any questions
about law enforcement in a legal state
and my experience as a patrolman trainer
detective and a SWAT operator happy
growing from my heart
signed blue went green hey blue went
green thank you for the wonderful email
messages like this are part of why I do
this podcast knowing that I'm helping
people change their lives possibly
helping you save your life this makes
all the time the energy the effort the
frustration sometimes the struggle ah
it's all worth it because of messages
like this I really appreciate that so
you said that you would be happy to
answer any questions about law
enforcement I don't have a question
about law enforcement my question is now
that you have personally experienced the
healing qualities and properties of
cannabis are you going to or have you
been educating your fellow on for
have you been advocating in any way
saying hey guys we may be looking at
this all wrong have you done anything
like that um it's not your duty you've
done your duty trust me but it would be
cool if you could say some things like
that to some of your cop friends maybe
don't even approach them maybe just
bring it up you know when you're at
lunch with them or when you're on the
phone with bummer
I don't know I'm curious if you're open
about it with your law enforcement
friends I'm curious what you're going to
do in the future about that and are you
going to use your personal experience as
an opportunity to advocate for cannabis
just curious send me another email and
we'll talk about it on a future episode
hey again man blue went green really I
appreciate your service
I appreciate your attitude and I
definitely appreciate the great email I
hope things go well for you if you need
anything send me an email I'd be happy
to help you out
all right podcast world I received a
message on Instagram and somebody was
asking me what is the difference in the
way that medical and recreational
cannabis are grown here in Colorado they
said what's the difference if any and my
answer was pretty simple I said there's
no difference you guys a lot of people
think that medical marijuana is grown in
some fancy laboratory and it's done in
some magical mythical way but honestly
medical marijuana and recreational
marijuana in Colorado are grown in very
similar facilities I can speak from
experience I am the lead cultivator for
Three Rivers I run their medical
marijuana facility and I run their
recreational marijuana facility there
are two different buildings but they are
simply across the parking lot from each
other
okay it's building right here building
right here I run from one building to
the other all day taking care of two
different groves now they are the same
strains of plants but they are not the
same plants the plants in the medical
grow cannot enter the recreational grow
the plants at the recreational grow
cannot enter the medical grow they are
to be kept separate at all times it is
two different business licenses with two
different names two different entities
just owned by the same people so I
bounce back and forth and run both of
them now
now as for the facilities the buildings
are constructed and designed fairly
similarly we're using long tables from
Midwest as at Midwest hydro or Midwest
greenhouse supply some company like that
makes long rolling tables we've got
those tables in both facilities we've
got double-ended Gavita lights in both
facilities we've got giant HVAC in both
facilities we've got the auto water
system in both facilities both
facilities are fed the exact same mix we
don't buy this brand of nutrients for
this facility in this brand of nutrients
for this facility we buy a whole [ __ ]
ton and put it in the warehouse and then
divide it up amongst each grow as needed
so it's the same tables the same lights
it's the same nutrients it's the same
master grower it's the same grow Tech's
it's the same trimmers it is the same
trellis technique it is mostly the same
genetics so when a grow is started in
Colorado depending on how it started the
plants have to come from somewhere right
if the license if the recreational
license is spawned from an existing
medical marijuana license there is an
opportunity for a one-time plant
transfer so that means if I own a
medical marijuana facility and I would
like to convert my medical marijuana to
have a recreational marijuana side of my
store which means everybody can shop
they're not just Colorado medical
patients I would be allowed to do a
one-time transfer to my grow which means
I would be allowed to take a clone of
everything or 50 clones of everything in
the grow so I could go down my genetic
list I could get a rise I could get
blueberry headband I could get platinum
Tandy go get a clone of everything they
have to go in the computer properly and
they have to be manifested and
transferred through the computer system
and then legally transferred from one
grow to the other once they're at the
other girl they have to be received in a
computer system and unloaded and tagged
properly so you're allowed to do that
one time when a new facility opens so
it's the same genetics we're taking the
genetics from the medical marijuana
facility and manifesting them over to
the recreational facility it's the same
plants now we're
we'll just say platinum tangi will say
sour tan because we don't have platinum
tangi at the retro will say sour 10g
we've got sour tangi at the medical
marijuana grow hypothetically if we were
to open another recreational grow that
spawned off of our medical license we
could just cut clones of that sour tangi
put them in the computer make a manifest
for transfer transfer them receive that
transfer and now we've legally got that
sour tangi clone in the garden at our
new recreational facility now that's not
exactly what happened with Three Rivers
or anything but I mean that's
hypothetically how it works that's how
the clones are spread from one facility
to another there are other options to do
it um we can sell clones if three rivers
either the medical or the recreational
grow wanted to sell a clone we could set
up a business deal with another facility
we could sell them trays of clones they
could take 50 to 500 clones of whatever
they wanted of our genetics we could
pass it right along to them if that was
something we do we don't really sell
clones but that's where the genetics
come from you guys the Medical Marijuana
clones and the recreational marijuana
clones are the same plants they just
have different colored tags the medical
marijuana facilities and the
recreational marijuana facilities are
basically the same things they just have
different colored plant tags and they're
taxed differently and sold in different
stores we're using the same exact
nutrients I'm putting the same exact
amount of care the same pesticides are
allowed on both products the marijuana
enforcement division the Colorado
Department of Public Health and
Environment and the Colorado Department
of Agriculture have all agreed on a
certain set of pesticides we are and are
not allowed to use those are the same
for both facilities so I don't have to
make pesticide plans of attack for
different facilities I could just use my
same idea over here as I use over there
so I guess the short answer to that
question of what's the difference
between the way medical and recreational
marijuana are grown in Colorado of the
main difference is taxes that's the only
difference they are taxed differently
recreational marijuana is taxed much
higher than medical marijuana other than
the taxes it's the same plant it's the
same nutrients the same lights the same
tables the same pesticides it's all the
same stuff I don't do anything
differently in the medical grow than I
do in the recreational girl I don't go
over to one
would say ooh this is going to this
store let's do it differently I treat
all of them the same I love each plant
the same I make them all the best I can
I trellis them down I pop and crack the
sticks I D foliate them I'd treat them
all the same so the only difference
really is the taxes now with that being
said every store is going to have a
different level of quality every grow is
going to have a different standard every
trim company every trim crew is going to
have a different standard and a level of
quality of trimming so keep that in mind
if you go to one store and they've got
hairy buds that are untrimmed and super
dry check another store because they may
have perfectly dried and cured buds that
are beautifully trimmed don't judge all
of Colorado by one or two dispensaries
please shop around when you come here
but if you're coming from out of state
please don't feel like you're getting
slighted please don't feel like you're
getting skipped on the quality products
just because you're not buying a medical
marijuana product you're getting the
same exact quality as you would get if
you were a Colorado medical marijuana
patient the next thing I want to talk
about was inspired by my friend mama
bear dabs on Instagram a young lady
asked mama bear dabs how to get into the
cannabis industry and Lucy had great
answers she said first of all find out
if you can get a badge
get yourself a badge then come to
Colorado and apply for jobs just like
you would any other business
she also said to have a good resume I
thought it would be a good idea to
mention some of the things that you may
include on your resume to get yourself
into the cannabis industry or if you're
in the cannabis industry there are
things you can do to improve your resume
to hopefully improve your pay and your
status in the cannabis industry so let's
get right to it
here are some things you can think about
if you're making a resume trying to get
a job in the cannabis industry now the
first thing you should think about is
you're trying to get a job just like
you're trying to get other any other job
you need to be professional make a
professional-looking resume run spell
check a couple of times now if you're
not good at making a resume there are
plenty of websites that will
templates for you to go and kind of get
a good guideline on how to make a resume
follow that template follow that
guideline and make a standard resume put
in your information put in your skills
put in your education now this is where
we are going to dial it in and make it a
little bit cannabis industry specific
list any of your skills that you think
may help you with the job you're trying
to get if you're trying to be a
budtender
put any customer service skills that
you've had put in that you know how to
use the metric system put in that you're
familiar with weights if you're trying
to be a grower put in that you have
grown before put down the types of ways
you have grown have you grown hydroponic
if you grow in deep water culture have
you grown soilless have you grown soil
put in all of the stuff that you have
done so that we know who we're dealing
with if you're trying to be a trimmer
tell me how long you've been trimming
tell me your experience tell me what
equipment you have used if you're trying
to be a trimmer have you used the trim
Reaper have you used the tornado have
used the twister what have you used as a
trimmer you just a scissor guy do you
trim fast with your fingers also mark
down any trainings or certifications
you've got um I would always recommend
getting a key badge if you're going for
a badge and you can afford it get a key
badge there's no reason not to get the
key badge a support badge is great that
gets you in the door but that's all that
does I need a key badge on premises at
all times if I am in the commercial grow
and I want to go to the recreational
grow I've got to make sure there's a key
badge there keeping an eye on everybody
because I can't leave a bunch of support
badges in the room without a key badge
on sight it is simply illegal um if you
have worker protection safety training
document that if you haven't had worker
protection safety training I would learn
how to get worker protection safety
training in the state of Colorado so
that you can put that on your resume
also if you are a pesticide applicator
or you've had Department of Agriculture
pesticide training list that if you have
respirator training or respirators
certifications maybe you were a fireman
in the past maybe you worked with paints
or something if you know how to use
where clean
safely remove a respirator and you've
got a little card from the the doctor
that does respirator training you've
already got a reason to be hired because
that's one less thing I have to pay to
have you trained and certified on if
you've got HVAC training you are golden
if you've gone to any HVAC school put
that on your resume if you were an
electrician and not just if you're some
sort of journeyman if you've got paper
if you've got some sort of card that
says I have HVAC training or I have
electrical training put that down
because we want to know that sort of
stuff we've got seven flower rooms and
that means there are seven air
conditioners which means there are
probably ten air conditioners because
we've got veg rooms and a couple other
things now if you're a grow tech you're
worth a little bit of money to us you
can make some good money hourly but if
you're a grow tech and you're an HVAC
tech and my air conditioner goes down
and I don't have to call somebody from
another service I can say hey bro
the HVAC in room C just went down I'll
take over watering for you can you run
outside and see what's going on with the
HVAC and then I don't have to have the
outside service come who charges by the
visit and they charge a whole lot of
money just to come look if they show up
and get out of the truck it costs money
a lot of money and we would be able to
pay an employee a dollar or two extra
per hour to have you as part of the
staff and have you on-site so when that
HVAC does go wrong you're already there
I don't even have to call anybody you
just walk out there you fix it put that
on the resume so I know you've got that
ability you're already moving up toward
the top also write down each machine
that you know how to use if you can use
the wood chipper write down that you're
good with the wood chipper anything that
you can use the the trim Reaper anything
like that document that because we need
people that can run equipment the less I
have to teach you the better the more
hireable you are the more you can make
money right off the bat coming into a
facility I'll write down anything you've
got experience with like I am good with
the Gavita master controller I can
program your Gavita lights I know a
bunch of tricks and things inside that
controller that people may have
overlooked I've got a lot of experience
with it just putting that on the resume
that's one more thing I can do but other
people might not be able to do I am
familiar with the smart bees I know
to set up the Smart B units I know how
to install them I know how to program
them I'm very familiar with smart B
technology so that's another thing that
is on my resume I am very familiar with
the link for systems I have setup link
for systems in multiple facilities I
have done troubleshooting with link for
systems I have been on tech support with
link for before I've got a relationship
with link for I know how to use their
products those are really difficult
machines if you're new with them I don't
need to be trained on that I'm already
worth a little bit more money um
maybe you've been trained in bio track
if you know how to use bio track that's
that's three weeks of training we don't
have to give you bio track is a little
[ __ ] it takes a lot of time to learn
that if you already know how to do that
we're saving a lot of time metric
everything in the Colorado Marijuana
regulated business goes through a thing
called metric if you've been trained or
are familiar with not a metric system
that's cool too but metric is a computer
system if you've been trained or you're
familiar with that put that down put how
long you have been playing with metric
and put your abilities in metric what
you know and if you've done it a lot you
know what you need to put down to
impress us write that stuff down in your
resume and that makes you more valuable
if I don't have to train you in metric
you're already more hireable they're
already worth more money there's less
training to be done you're already more
valuable employee another thing I
recommend that you can put on your
resume is attend all of the metric
classes if you go to METAR see.com is
all I think it is it's metric comm they
are a multi-state service so if you have
regulated cannabis in your state there
is probably a metric program they will
offer classes a lot of the times you
have to have your marijuana Enforcement
Division badge to log into there I'm not
sure how each state is once you get your
badge you can login and you can start
taking metric classes you may be able to
take bud tending classes or grow tech
classes locally or online without having
a badge take those classes document them
write them down add them to your resume
the more you know the less I have to
train you the more valuable you are if
you can walk into the Grove and start
working today without shadowing me for
four or five
days without having to follow Brian
around and learn all of Ryan's tricks if
you can just come in and work you were
more valuable you were saving us a lot
of time so write down all of that stuff
on your resume make sure we know who and
what we're dealing with before we hire
you now another thing if you're applying
to be a trimmer this is really important
if you were applying to be a trimmer in
my facility I am going to ask you in the
very first interview how much can you
trim a day we dry trim if there is a guy
taking a giant plant and bucking the
buds off the sticks and handing you a
five-gallon bucket of nothing but buds
to be trimmed you don't have to do any
of the work of getting it off the stick
the big leaves are gone you just trim
your little ass off how much can you
trim today in 8 hours we're gonna go
from 8 to 5 at 8 o'clock we're gonna
start trimming your little scissors are
gonna get going and I want to see fire
come out of them at 10 o'clock I'm gonna
yell stop trimming let's go smoke some
dad's we're gonna go take a break we're
gonna come back at 10:15 I want you to
trim it from 10 15 to 12 at 12 we're
taking an hour lunch do whatever you
want for that hour I'll see you at 1
o'clock from 1 until 3 scissors are on
fire again from 3:15 to 5 scissors on
fire what's going on how much can you
trim a lot of people look me in the face
and tell me I could probably do 3 or 4
pounds I had one guy tell me I can
guarantee you 3 pounds every day dog I
hired him guess what a [ __ ]
pulled out like a half a pound five days
in a row guess where he works now not at
three rivers I don't know where he works
he lied to me he told me he could do
more than he could do I believed him I
hired him he [ __ ] failed he got fired
he was a good dude he was a good worker
if you would have said bro I could
probably crank out a half a pound a day
anybody came into the facility and
cranked out a half a pound a day guess
what he would have met his quota he
would have met his standards he would
not have been a bullshitter and he'd
still have a job so don't lie if you can
only trim a half a pound today tell me
currently I only can do a half a pound a
day we'll find you tips and tricks we'll
get you to a pound and a half a day you
just got to not lie to me if you go to
karate class and you say I'm a black
belt and I find out you're a purple ball
I'm gonna kick your ass because you lied
to me if you come into my grow and you
say I can trim half a pound a day I'm
gonna teach you how to be a [ __ ]
black belt and trim a pound and a half
if you come in and say I can trim two
pounds
I expect two pounds from you every day
that's a goal you set that was your goal
that you that was your expectation why'd
you lie to me you could have set 1/4
pound and then you could have said I
could probably do 1/4 pound and you
would've came in and trimmed half a
pound I would have thought you were a
[ __ ] rock star so don't lie to
anybody on your resume don't lie to get
the job because we're gonna find out if
you say I know how to do all this stuff
we're gonna take you in the grow and
we're gonna say do all this stuff and
you're gonna be mixing nutrients and I'm
gonna say what's the pH and you're gonna
go how do I check the pH we're gonna
know that you lied so don't lie don't
over promise always under-promise
over-deliver that's something I could
definitely say it would be a good idea
on your resume but don't set
expectations that you're not going to
meet because that is the best way to get
fired way quickly in a growth facility
all right so let's review really quickly
and then we're gonna start wrapping this
podcast up list all of your skills list
any equipment you've been trained on and
list all of your certifications I would
highly recommend to getting a key badge
if you're going to work in the grow I
would recommend either worker protection
safety training before you're even hired
or a pesticide applicator license
through the Department of Ag it's one
test it's affordable and you can do it
also if you're gonna do that
get respirators certified if you're
going to apply pesticides in Colorado
and a medical or recreational grow
you're required to wear a respirator
anybody wearing that respirator needs a
respirator certification it's really
easy it'd cost a few bucks you go to a
doctor you take the respirator that you
plan on using you wear that respirator
they make sure that you can put it's a
fit test as what it is they want to make
sure you can put it on right they want
to make sure you take it off safely
because when you take it off you got
your gloves on you've got this dirty
respirator with pesticides on it they
want to make sure you're gonna take it
off in a manner that you're not going to
spread the pesticides to your eyes or
skin um
so be respirators certified if you've
got any HVAC or electrical training
mention that if you can use any
specialized devices
kavita controller smart bee's link fours
mention that if you're good with any
computer programs bio tracker metric
mention that if you've gone to any
classes please mention that if you've
gone to clover
if you've gone to Oaksterdam if you've
been to any of the budtender trainings
mention all of that um honestly we don't
care about your pictures we don't want
to see any of your buds you're gonna
prove that part when you work in the
grow we've already got a master grower
that's gonna do that for you so just
write down what you can do write down
who you are we can grow already we want
to know what you're able to do we don't
want to see your pictures we don't want
to know about your Instagram just come
in with a solid resume be on time just
cuz it's the weed industry doesn't mean
you can be 15 minutes late um
don't come in super high I get it you're
applying for a job in the weed industry
don't come in so high that you can't
look me in the face they'll come in just
reeking you were applying for a job be
professional and also acts like you've
been here before uh act like this is not
your first time at agro if I feel like
the interview is going well I will offer
you a tour of the grow I'm kind of
checking you out at that time I'm taking
your temperature seeing if you can
handle being around that many plants
seeing if you're gonna freak out seeing
how big your eyes are gonna get seein if
you start reaching into your pockets
thinking about how to steal some [ __ ]
I'm kind of feeling you out when I take
you back to the grow to give you a tour
so keep yourself in check act like
you've been there before and don't let
things get to your head alright that's
my advice for a resume and also kind of
guess for an interview when you're
trying to get a job in the cannabis
industry hey I need to give a couple of
shout outs big shout out to my buddy max
power super huge starstruck shout-out to
my friend just an all ridge and a
special shout-out to jardin del rey
jardin del rey is a cool [ __ ] name
that's like a rockstar name or a
comedian name or something jardin del
rey it's like uh I don't know it's
[ __ ] cool I like that name stylish
name you got there ladies and gentlemen
I want to thank you for listening to a
rambley ass podcast I want to blame
these rambles on viola extracts I smoked
this Clementine cookies before the show
and in the middle of the show and this
[ __ ] just kept me talking I'm gonna
smoke some more of this here in just a
minute you guys make sure you stalk me
on all the social media find me on
Facebook simply search for the girl from
your heart of podcast find me on
Instagram I haven't been doing as many
Instagram my videos but I promise you
they are coming back I've been more
focused
getting the YouTube videos caught up but
anyway Instagram its Irie underscore
genetics come hang out on Instagram be a
part of my Instagram live videos maybe
I'll answer your questions there on the
live feed also stalk me on twitter it's
@gf wih podcast on twitter you can also
follow my personal page it's at Rasta
Jeff 420 if you want to see what I'm up
to if you want to communicate with me
and you're not into all of the social
media you can send me an email it's grow
from your heart at hotmail.com maybe
you've got a product you'd like me to
review maybe you'd like to sponsor the
show or maybe you just got something to
say that you don't want to share with
everybody grow from your heart at
hotmail.com is the way to do that you
guys I've been putting up more YouTube
videos I think I'm up to about 275 or
280 maybe more than that I'll keep going
I'm almost caught up you guys it just
takes a long time to get them going but
I promise you they are coming also don't
forget about the patreon campaign check
out patreon.com/scishow
gonna wrap up this podcast I should be
back Thursday with a quickie episode I
want to give a huge shout out to my
friend ty and Grand Junction and until
next time take the fat dad and give your
mom a hug for me
[Music]