yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for another episode of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right after a new
grower if you're a professional grower
if you're a new smoker or a dedicated
dabber if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who is just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Roscoe
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me this episode of the podcast
is brought to you by my friends at the
hell a dank seed company if you need new
genetics for your gardening I highly
recommend the hella dank seed company
you can find them at Bank seed dot store
ladies and gentlemen
roll up a fat joint pack up the bong or
start heating up guide a break because
it's time for another episode of the
glow from your heart a podcast
[Music]
what's up podcast world it's time for
episode 319 of the girl from our podcast
thanks again for joining me sitting
across the table is white Mike welcome
back to the show bro thanks man thanks
for having me oh man thanks for taking
time out of the busy schedule of two
kids congratulations
those new notes it's a lot dos vinhos
yeah you can tell where we're from
welcome well we're gonna show from
Pueblo Colorado speak real good Spanish
I was just an Instagram wives live
feeding somebody's tried to throw out
some German and I responded in German
and the whole room just went silent I
was like well I apologize for that I
thought that was funny welcome to the
show ladies gentlemen welcome mics on
the show we were gonna do a show about
what are we gonna talk about determining
ripeness and when to harvest your
cannabis plants before we get there
you know I'd like to start the episodes
by stop my talk by stalking about
let's talk about let's talk about what
I've been dabbing that was hard to say
I've been taking dabs of some viola Labs
Clementine cookies live resin I'm
opening it up to smell it right now
it is like spicy orange candy and I
really love the smell and flavor of this
I picked up three grams today when I
went I usually just get one gram of you
two ever it was like they have more of
that they do I'll just take three and I
will be on my way Mike is it time to
change that microphone cover is that
what your supplementally telling me
right now
it's
free spot but I've got Malamutes so I'm
used to free spots we're gonna blame
that on your Malamutes it's not Malamute
hair but it's not hippie hair either
some cool just pulling it off and
rolling with it
oh yeah we might want to look for a new
cover after the show welcome to the
furry spot podcast ladies it's gonna be
that kind of show we're gonna put this
show back on track we've got a couple of
spoons we should shout out shout out to
my friends at the hell of a exede
company shout out some water shut off
the water you're drinking water now you
guys Mike is drinking water this is like
a rare occasion I didn't pack properly
for this mission then some waters
happening you need some water anyway
Brite I don't feel bad for you and then
he went spilled half of it right down
your face Mike sure you can water you
guys that's a rare occasion ah the
holiday exceed company if you need new
seeds for your garden I highly recommend
the hell a dank seed company at dank
seed dot store support our friends at
the Helen tank seed company also support
more of my friends PL grow systems guys
I know you want to know what's going on
in your grow room at all times
sometimes you're away you're like I
wonder if that air conditioner clicked
on it's pretty hot outside I wonder if
that air conditioners working I wonder
you can't even focus you can't even
think about what you're doing like ah
conditioner working you want to drive
home and look but you can't drive home
you're just freaking out you know what
bust out your phone check out your peel
minder unit you can see what's going on
your girl room at all times how do you
get a peel girl how do you get a peel
minder unit you go to peel Croton
systems that's how check them out at
peel grow dot systems you guys peel grow
systems minder unit well let you know
what's going on in your grow room at all
times you can relax
you can enjoy what you're doing it's
awesome alright let's move forward
YouTube you guys all of the YouTube
videos are caught up I did it it took a
long time but they are finally there
that was a multi-year project I do
YouTube got evil right before right at
the scariest time yeah I was just about
caught up and then all of the YouTube
channels started disappearing
I don't put videos on myself consuming
on this channel on that so yeah I talked
heavily about it but they don't see it
so unless they're looking for it and
someone reports it we should be okay
we'll see how long it lasts either way
if it does disappear I'll find any place
to put it don't worry um YouTube is up
that's just to play some more people to
listen to the show I think we'll
probably get more more lessons more
views more interactions alright Mike you
got anything to say before we start
talking about um
determining ripeness on cannabis plants
you got me topics you want to bring
before we get on a ramble here not yeah
well the sewer things mike says we'll
see where this takes us alright so a lot
of people were talking on Instagram live
and on chat rooms right now about how to
decide when to harvest their cannabis
when is my cannabis ripe the seed packs
are gonna tell you a certain timeframe
they're gonna say 56 to 63 days they're
gonna say 63 to 70 days they're gonna
say 9 to 10 weeks the first time you run
that pack of seeds I would say go the
longest time frame that they give you as
an option at least plan for for sure yes
yeah if it says 10 wheat 9 to 10 weeks
go the 10 weeks because maybe in that
last week that's when you're gonna see
extra trichomes pack on you're gonna see
the extra weight come on you're gonna
see maybe some cool colors you might you
may you may see some [ __ ] you don't see
if you cut it down at week 9 so let it
go 10 weeks if it says 10 weeks if it
says 56 to 63 days let it go 63 I'll let
it go 65 if it looks ok and see what
happens
ah so that being said the way to
determine ripeness of your cannabis
plants is not by looking at the hairs
it is not by looking at it's not by
looking at I did air quotes when I said
I'm just I'm hearing different people
throughout my cannabis career
right like speaking at length about how
all of those are telltale signs of like
either perfect or good or completed or
operating a harvester and it's all
nonsense yeah what we are growing
cannabis for the viable part that we
want are the trichomes why would we look
at anything but the trichomes right we
want to harvest those when they're at
their brightest point so we should be
paying attention to the trichomes the
only way you can do that you can if
somebody tells you they can see the
trichomes with their naked eye either
steal their eyes or kick them in the
dick because they're a liar you cannot
see amber trichomes without some sort of
magnification you need at least 60 X
maybe a hundred X magnification to see
if a trichome is clear cloudy silver
milky amber busted ruptured if the heads
broken off of it you need magnification
you cannot see that with the naked eye
and if you can you're [ __ ] awesome
send me a message I want to hear about
it yep good get on Amazon start looking
the scopes folks yeah get yourself like
a jeweler's loupe
I have a scope from Dino light that
hooks up to my computer I plug it right
into the USB slot it took me just a few
minutes to mess with the drivers to make
it link up to my computer once it linked
up it was no problem ever I open up the
application I'm able to run the scope
over the plants and I can focus it in
and I can see those trichomes very large
on my computer screen and it makes it
very and I can take pictures so if I
can't tell exactly what I'm looking at I
can reach over and I think I press f11
and I take a photo right there boom yep
then I can go look later and I can see
if that plants ripe or not the the
computerized scope makes life a lot
easier but you can pick up some kind of
like a jeweler's loupe
it's a lot less expensive and just as
functional the 420 scope will work for
you just a basic jeweler's loupe
will work for you there's one that
Hydrofarm sells it spreads in half it's
got batteries in it then it splits in
half and the batteries are in one side
and the optics are actually on the other
side they make a 60 and a 100x I would
recommend 100x if you go for that that's
probably the best one on the market if
you're gonna get something like that but
I'm aware of there's probably something
better by now
but get some magnification magnification
will help you out in so many ways you'll
be able to tell if your trichomes are
clear if they're silver if they're
cloudy if they're milky if they're amber
if they're ruptured also you'll be able
to identify the pests and the funguses
and the problems on the undersides of
your leaves more accurately if you've
got a scope to look at those there's a
really useful tool throughout the growth
cycle for sure yeah once you've got all
of your tools dialed in and you've got
some money to spend on a couple extra
toys for the grow room get yourself a
scope it will really help a scope or a
loop or something that hooks up to your
computer all right so the hairs are not
gonna tell you how ready your plant is
Mike just tapped his headphones are you
too hot there no just got an itch all
right scratch it up buddy good boy good
boy
it's like starting to go dizzy
scratching behind his ear you guys
switchin tell you if your cannabis
plants are ripe are the trichomes we're
drawing for trichomes that's what we
want if you're growing to make quality
flowers if you're gonna make edibles if
you're gonna make extracts if you're
gonna make anything the trichomes are
what matter so pay attention to that
nothing else now the way that you can
tell the trichomes you're gonna see the
trichomes develop on your plant if you
have a scope and you can pay attention
through the entire process do that watch
those trichomes go from a little bitty
stalk watch them develop a head
watch the head of that trichome fill up
you'll watch it fill up it'll get juicy
and then it'll start to change colors
it'll go from clear then it'll slowly
turn to like a silver ish color then
it'll get cloudy
you'll be once you see it you'll know
right now you're going what does he mean
by cloudy you've got to imagine if you
got a fishbowl and then you put some
dish soap in there and stirred it up
it's cloudy that's what your cloudy
trichomes are gonna look like that's
cloudy now your next step after cloudy
is milky sometimes they turn kind of
bluish in my opinion they have a hint of
blue they have that if you stir it like
certain white paints and whatnot you'll
start to see a blue kind of undertone a
little bit yeah yeah and it's yeah a
nice patch of milky trichomes I always
see just a little hint of light blue in
there so the fishbowl I talked about a
minute ago imagine if I took your
fishbowl that had we dumped out the dish
because this is just gonna get gross if
we keep adding stuff I'm gross let's do
this differently imagine if you took a
fishbowl that's got water in it and you
poured just enough milk in there to make
it turn light white light white not it's
not gonna be [ __ ] boom like ice cream
but it's gonna be light white like you
poured some creamer in your coffee you
just lighten it up you can see it now
now that trichome is what I would call
milky that is a milky trichome you're
almost ready for harvest the next step
that's gonna happen is gonna look like
you had a spray bottle imagine if I took
like the little spray bottle that you're
spraying your plants with or whatever
you get little mister bottle what if I
poured some dr. pepper in there and I
walked right up to your trichomes
and just just give it a little spritz
and dr. pepper your trichomes are gonna
have a little amber spritz on them now
and that's exactly what I think it looks
like it's like you sprayed some soda
right onto your trichomes they're gonna
go from milky and then you're gonna see
just a couple of them get this amber
color this dr. pepper color right across
them and you're gonna see it happen
toward the top and kind of right in the
middle and then keep pay attention to
the whole planck's it's gonna move
around but when you see that first bit
of amber really start paying attention
because you've got a very short time now
they're gonna start that amber is gonna
start progressing throughout the plant
really quickly and when you look at the
scope and you can see you're gonna have
to look around the plant when 30% of
those trichomes start becoming amber
that's when you want to cut down 30%
yeah I say look in several places you're
gonna be like 30% how do I know and I
can see a hundred trichomes in there
just look around and use your best
judgment you guys about 25 to 35% is
where you want to aim for you're not
gonna notice a difference if you're a
few days off on your harvest honestly
you are not going to notice a huge
difference you've got a dry and cure
period once you cut down these plants
those trichomes are going to continue to
change all the way until the moment you
combust them you're gonna cut them down
you've got this dry period they're gonna
get beat up and harvest they're gonna
get cured they're gonna change there's
going to be so many different changes in
those trichomes so just a couple of
days in your harvest window will not
make a huge difference you're not gonna
notice it it's not gonna hurt your
feelings so pay attention to those try
comps get yourself a scope they're gonna
go clear then they're gonna turn silver
then they're gonna get cloudy that's
when it starts getting excited their
filter that's getting exciting they're
filling up with trichomes are with uh
cannabinoids now they've got different
things in their different psychoactive
ingredients inside of there that are
changing every day then they're gonna
get milky they're gonna turn a little
bit blue then they're gonna look like I
sprayed them with dr. pepper
when three out of ten went 30% of them
have that dr. pepper stain on them
that's when it's time to cut so you're
gonna say but it's my first grow with
this plant how do I plan that how do I
properly be able to flush and look out
for trichomes to be amber I thought of a
great way that we can all be safe you
keep in mind this isn't gonna be the
last time you're growing the strain
hopefully this is the first time you
grew it that's why you don't know when
the trichomes are gonna change colors
that's why you don't know how long it's
gonna take it's the first time you're
developing a relationship with this
plant the first time you got to learn it
the second third time you dial it in the
fourth and fifth time you [ __ ]
perfect this grow yeah so you're just
learning this one so keep thinking about
it this way if you're growing a
sixty-day plant if the package says grow
it for 55 to 60 days go that 60 days if
you're gonna go for 60 days
flush it day 50 and really start paying
attention to those trichomes if you want
to cut it down at a specific day just
make sure you flushed 7 to 10 days
pretty heavily I'd like to go 14 but 7
to 10 days should be plenty
if you want to let your plant go 70 days
if you've got something I bred you
probably want to let it go 70 days if I
bred it 70 days no problem start
flushing at day 60 and pay attention to
your trichomes you can cut down at day
70 if you don't feel like it's ready let
it go a little bit longer it doesn't
need nutrients to keep going it's just
gonna start getting tired but then you
can give it time to ripen up so I think
the way to judge when to harvest your
cannabis is by paying attention to the
trichomes if you don't have a way to
look at the trichomes you don't have a
way to accurately judge the ripe
this of your cannabis plants and you run
the risk of cutting them way too early
is what most people do if you feel like
they're done wait three to five more
days if you can wait seven more days
wait because they're only gonna get
better and don't cut too early because
you're anxious and eager
patience patience you cut clones or you
grew from seeds and those took time then
you've edged it out you spent a lot of
money on nutrients you've already spent
you're probably gonna put a hundred and
fifteen days into it why not put 120 -
what's another week right I know you
start getting itchy you start getting
that the crackhead lips and he starts
scratching your neck you're like yeah I
want to cut it down I'm thinking of a
friend of mine who was always in that
clip in lower nut he'd start at the
bottom of the plants are taking nugs and
I'm drying him out as fast as he could
to keep himself covered and by the time
we got the harvest it was just like the
top coal is left on the plant
yeah and then there's nothing to enjoy
because you fast ride everything and you
could have just had one huge harvest and
actually saw his dough you can see what
it looks like what your work actually
did instead of just destroying your work
slowly not getting any reward yeah so be
patient you guys that's that's one of
the main things that it's hard to learn
when you're growing cannabis sometimes
you just need to hide your scissors send
Mike home with the scissors but I can't
cut my plants up you're like oh you're
on suicide watch or something so I guess
that was a pretty quick way to do it but
I mean that's right to the point there's
no other way to explain that I'd get a
jeweler's loupe get some sort of
magnification and look at your trichomes
I know I keep saying it we're growing
for trichomes we you just got to get in
there with some magnification and spend
some time reading the plan yeah we don't
we're not worried about all the green
leafy part I mean that part tastes good
that's fun to smoke that's a cool
carrier but the trichomes are the goal
so make sure they're ripe something that
I should add if you are growing for
concentrates maybe cut a little bit
early start flushing early and harvest a
little bit early because once the if you
want nice and clear concentrates maybe
this is some industry secrets secrets I
shouldn't be sharing with the general
public but here you go guys I love you
and this is free if you want nice and
clear concentrates cut your plants down
before the trichomes start
getting dark if they start getting dark
what you are extracting is trichomes
your concentrates will come out a little
bit darker cut them down when they're
nice and clear and guess what nice and
clear concentrates it's easier a lot of
a lot of concentrate makers can make
super clear concentrates out of
everything now but it's easier it's less
to clean up it's less work if you're
pulling it down when you have got nice
and clear try comes out early and
process quickly yep they cut them down I
don't even want to tell you what week
sometimes like running big sevenish I've
seen it go there concentrates yeah a
little bit ridiculous but then you can
pull a whole one more harvest a year if
you cut everything down at the end of
week six but you could feel one more
harvest a year in your schedule that's
business unfortunately you guys do not
do that be patient let it go long enough
let it be done like Axl Rose said all we
need is just a little patience Mike just
gave me the funniest look all right you
guys hey Mike do you got any political
stuff you want to talk about for a
minute some there's always some good
news this week for medical cannabis
consumers or patients whichever you
prefer down in Florida a judge down
there ruled that they can finally
consume their cannabis products by
combustion and inhalation they made
smoking marijuana legal finally for
medical patients down there up until
recently they were sort of insisting
that people use non smokeable or
favorable forms so they were only able
to use teachers topicals
capsules and edibles and edibles well
that's okay edibles oils to choose
alright I mean it's it's quite a variety
of products and in florida's really just
getting off the ground but can they dab
concentrates now I'm actually I'm this
has this literally just happened the
small okay so no but they can at least
smoke a bowl now they can smoke a joint
which is why a lot of us choose cannabis
because it's that's how it's you
immediately effective you can get an
immediate effect and you can titrate
your dose perfectly perfectly like the
first time out the door no but by the
time you're like successfully treating a
pain disorder or something like that
like I can consume exact
to the point of no pain right and that
if I choose to consume further into the
points of enjoyment I can choose to do
that or stop I know about where my
medical needs are I know about how many
dabs it takes for me to meet my medical
requirements and then I know about when
I started going recreational I know
where that line is and then I know how
to sustain that medical and I also know
how to cross that line whenever I need
to so yeah we should be allowed to well
I'm glad that Florida is allowed to
consume properly now for a while that
was just a federal patient or two down
there that could smoke everybody else
had to eat but now it's everybody was
that our buddy it's our buddy herbs is
our buddy herb shoutout to Irv if y'all
don't know who rose and felt is hop on
YouTube and prepare to have your mind
[ __ ] blown away yeah this guy can
smoke whenever wherever let's just say
it would you think of the world record
holder for most joints consumed per
lifetime you don't think of a Jewish
stockbroker in Florida but you should
speaking of a lot of joints smoked happy
birthday to Tommy Chong I think he's 80
this weekend yes James oldest [ __ ] so
shout out to our friends down there in
Florida finally able to do it right
welcome to the club Florida how many of
those retired folk down there in Florida
are the cannabis consumers is that part
of who's consuming do you think oh for
sure for sure one of the the fun little
data points out of Colorado is our
medical program the average age is 42
not and that was when you and me were in
our 20s and early 30s in it and it was
still well into the 40s and that's
because boomers are a huge cannabis
consuming population they it's a
population with a lot of aches and pains
and if they can treat those in a way
that doesn't song come out and they can
enjoy those years substantially more
because they choose to use cannabis
instead of opioids for their pain or
trying to choose with just dealing with
their pain like they dive right on at
the top of those the edibles they love
at all I think it's a great social
lubricant and a great alternative to
alcohol I cannot I cannot manage alcohol
and so when I once I start drinking were
just gonna drink and it's not gonna be a
pretty ending like that's just how
my alcohol consumption goes I cannot do
to myself with dabs and cannabis what
I'm able to do to myself with alcohol so
I think just a couple of you know you
just smoke with people you just pass
around a pipe it creates that when you
pass around a pipe together you just
created friendship you know hey I hit
this you hit this we both consume the
same thing let's be friends now
I think it's just becoming more of an
acceptable social lubricant as well it's
not so taboo more people are willing to
admit that they consume cannabis which
is kind of nice a lot of people used to
only smoke behind closed doors it's fun
watching everybody come out of the
woodwork for sure it's uh it was lonely
for a while in the 90s like I remember
times where I was like you change
location and you'd spend months like
meeting new people and then figuring out
like who you should ask about cannabis
and how you should ask it I mean there
was a time before hey bro do you smoke
and then the reply of smoke was what bro
like that wasn't always a thing you used
to have to be like hey I noticed that
you have a Jeep Cherokee with a fish
sticker on it yeah yeah I walked in with
[ __ ] long ass hair and a Grateful
Dead shirt everything - want to go ski
maryjane together after class later like
it used to be [ __ ] complicated yeah
and now everybody's coming out of the
woodwork it's one of the things I really
liked about being a budtender is to all
walks of life coming in just having a
blast
um sharing a love of cannabis like not
one customer after another would match
up in any way shape or form it's not
like working in any other retail where
it's you you're at the hot clothing
store so it's all like 18 19 to 21 right
coming in here you saw hiking shoots so
it's all 35 and 45 grilled guys they
come in like when you're working in the
bud counter anyone of any age in any
demographic can walk in but we'd have
people from different countries just
regularly coming to check out what work
anybody 21 and up yeah 21 and up please
still but so that's just about every
walk of life is able to walk in there
you got
dudes that work in the industry
construction guys business guys doctors
lawyers firemen law enforcement
accountants car salesmen everybody was
coming in there yeah I mean you'll have
a $200,000 car next to a VW bus in the
parking lot and it makes for a good
photo for Facebook but other than that
it's just your regular workday you know
what I find is the guy that drives the
Volkswagen bus buys the more expensive
product than the guy that drives the via
the Beemer or whatever the other example
was the Mercedes the the the more you're
into the cannabis community and
lifestyle the more you care about
quality I think yes exactly you get a
lot of people that are like it all
smells the same to me and you just want
to smack them but like it all smells the
[ __ ] same what I get the same with
like seafood I know people that love
seafood and there's big intricacies
between like this particular product in
that particular project all [ __ ] it
smells like death to me I can't get
anywhere near it
and so like I get it some people just
don't have the palate to distinguish
cannabis varieties but man for those of
us our kin it's a wonderful world and
the more you get into the world the more
you care about quality the more you're
willing to dig into it a lot of people
like I don't care give me the strongest
yeah I went to a dispensary a new place
the other day that I'd never shopped in
before just because I went to weed maps
and they said they had a product I
wanted and so I already knew what I was
shopping for the minute I walked in and
I walk in and they're like hey welcome
to this place have you ever been here
and I was like nope no like let us give
you a tour and I said honestly I'm just
here for this the Green Dot star dog the
black little green dot black label start
on concentrating like oh well let me
show you around and I was like no I'm
here for the green dot star labeled star
dog black label and she's like we're
here the concentrates here's our
clothing and I was like no I want and
I'm like just get it yeah it took me so
many tries just to convince this lady I
know what I want and then when she
showed it to me she goes well this is
and she told me how much it was a little
pricey I don't know if I should say how
much stuff costs on the air but she said
a number and that's that's not you know
that's not cheap but I was like yeah I
want that one and I want one of these
also and she's like those are this much
yeah I want it and she acted like oh
okay and then is this a place on the
south side of town yeah I told you where
I went yeah typical I mean
my guess is that part of town they get a
clientele looking for a different price
point right yeah and so they were kind
of shocked when I asked for that
top-shelf stuff but they wouldn't just
walk me I was like I want high-end
concentrate that she wouldn't just show
me that and then they do this weird
thing most dispensaries you say yeah
I'll take that thing right and then
either that budtender walks it to the
cash register and rings you up for it
and takes your money until is you have a
great day and high-fives you right they
go okay and they push some buttons on an
iPad and she just kind of walked away
from me and I was like well know what
[ __ ] and she came back she was oh
they'll call your name when they're
ready for you sweetie walk around and
look around and I was like well okay so
I just walk around for a couple of
minutes aimlessly didn't really want to
see anything I've already purchased I've
already selected why do I want to go
Walker I'm done now yeah I don't take
money let me go home maybe somewhere
comfortable to play and so this point
they took a few minutes and then they
called my full name over the counter
over the PA which I don't know if that
was cool like isn't there should be some
discretion here like I just know I'd be
as well yeah like the people call me
something different here so I was like
oh I'm gonna walk over and be that name
and so then they they take your money
and they show you exactly what you
bought one star dog live resin and they
put it in a bag all smooth one well what
else I got a a headband from somebody
else that I've never tried it was pretty
good to another brand I'd never tried
they got the headband and they put it in
there and then they charged me my money
and guy like tried to give me some
speech about how don't transfer this to
anybody else and all this stuff and I
was like yes sir I took way too long but
my point was I just wanted to get in
there and get that high and concentrate
man they wanted to give me a [ __ ]
tour man to like break the tour I was
like no tour for me it was so
frustrating
just give me that concentrates its read
your customer better yeah right like
there's a person who wants the tour
there's a person who's who is excited to
wander around your store after they've
picked out what they want other way to
be charged for it they're a recreational
store but I still show them my medical
marijuana card because a lot of places
will give you a discount and they did
nice I went to a place today and they
had a long line and they're a medical
and recreational facility and they
actually offered to let me skip the
because I'm a medical patient like do
you only think oh you can go first if
you want cuz you're a med patient that's
like no no oh wait in line I'm not I'm
not today I don't
I'm not oh no no there's some med
patients for you there's a lot of ed
patients where you need to do it's
awesome they do that for right like yeah
no I'm not
yeah I got I got body pain I'm not like
right badly all bad off or anything
yeah I'm not on this entire like my
family that I'm not gonna get back right
now cuz I'm in line right yeah and I've
got three grams of deliciousness very
good price so I'm glad I waited waited
my turn and patiently got to check out
the bedroom it's uh there's a is the
cannabis industry kind of expands
contracts people try different sticks
and like the iPad or the Apple store
model frustrates the [ __ ] out it feels
weird like let me smell these three jars
and I'll buy someone I'm on a roll like
how it doesn't need to take all
afternoon I've got other [ __ ] to do I've
got three more stops to make before I go
home and when I get home there's new we
screaming kids like I don't have time
for your speech that's why there are so
many though yeah and that leads me to
something else that I should have been
saying on the podcast that I haven't
ever said before you guys if you're
going to a dispensary and the quality is
okay go to a different one next week and
see if the quality is awesome
because there are dispensaries with
better quality than where you're
shopping you don't have to go somewhere
just because it's the one on the way
home if you go to the dispensaries with
the quality products the one the
dispensary without quality products will
either disappear or they'll step up
their game and then we won't have this
problem of all this mediocre [ __ ]
weed on the market demand quality you
talk with your money demand quality and
quality don't feel bad about saying no
thank you and leaving without a purchase
either I people get to the and decide
they didn't want anything and as a bunch
at around to the [ __ ] yeah like I'm
sorry we don't have anything you're
interested in both of us had our time
wasted have a nice day yeah there's no
reason for you to be like what's the
cheapest thing in the store yeah I need
to spend eight bucks just cuz you spent
six minutes with me so me this pack of
papers I'll take the pack of papers yeah
like just no good god only differently
store they have paper
- feelings there are a lot of different
vibes there are a lot of different
processes the way that things are
handled is election product selection
yeah carries wild so wildly pricing will
be it'll see the same products on the
shelf for twenty that you'll see four
forty five on another place but then
they'll have the a rivaling product that
prices will be switched like viola is
twenty at one place and CSC is forty at
that place and then if I drive across
town the viola is forty in the CSC is
twenty and it's just [ __ ] how they
priced them for some reason there's
places in town that only carry one
concentrate line and then the
concentrate line they carry you can't
get in any other shop right there's a
lot of that and it takes kind of going
around to all the different shops
occasionally to kind of figure out who's
got what when I go to different stores
on different days of the week because
there's a store down south but on
Tuesday does turfy Tuesday and these
violas are on sale and then there's a
store up north that does a sale that I
like and then there's another store
right down the street from them and I
try to time up there too sales yeah just
try to pay attention go to those sale
days but you guys like Mike said you can
leave a dispensary without buying
anything this is your medicine that you
were buying for maybe you're shopping
for the day maybe you're shopping for
three days I usually shop for four or
five days at a time when I go in I want
to get my medicine for the next three to
five days doctor drive back and wait in
line and if I'm driving up to Colorado
Springs that's a 45-minute Drive each
direction plus I stop for food Mike's
been hostage in my car for that
45-minute Drive up there twenty or
thirty minutes into the dispensary and
then another hour getting food plus a
piece table drive 45 minute drive back
and then I want him to come hang out and
take dad's after Mike is a hostage for
that whole thing so Mike in conflict
nine hours yeah but it's [ __ ] awesome
nine hours if I can make that happen
less frequently that saves us time and
gas money
so yeah but my point is don't feel
obligated to any dispensary if you're if
they're not it's it's like anything if
you're going to the tire shop and the
tire shop has [ __ ] tires you go to a
different tire shop if you don't shop at
Kmart for the [ __ ] tuxedo I mean if
you want good quality go shop around
look at different dispensaries look at
weed maps I know
weed Maps as a weird
thing they don't pay me I use weed maps
I know what I'm shopping for I can go to
weed maps and look at the dispensary and
see what they've got and then you don't
have to go in there and look at all
hundred jars and feel overwhelmed is
that kind of suck sometimes
be leery of the review section as well
take it take your time to dig through
because a lot of the more reputable
sites like weed maps and a few of the
earliest Leafly like leaf buyer google
they they let the business ding down bad
reviews from time to time but they won't
let him take them all down especially
the really legit like spelled out bad
reviews where the customer is specific
with their complaints and not abusive in
their language those all end up staying
up and if you scroll down a little bit
you'll get past all the $2 off your
pre-roll for a five star review reviews
and get to the real meat of the store
and that's this stuff you're looking for
especially when it comes to like
selection pricing service right and then
their menus are their menus updated a
lot of places their menus haven't been
updated in two months and you go in and
you're like oh man I saw they have to
fire on the website you go in there like
yeah we've been still about four months
let me show you not fire complain about
that honestly a lot of dispensaries if
you go in there and you say hey I see
the golden goat can I get an 8 the
golden go out they're gonna go we don't
have gold and gold you pull up that
[ __ ] weed Maps page ago look it shows
right here that you got gold and go
they'll give you a deal
they'll do something for it because that
is their responsibility to keep that
[ __ ] updated I've driven to a dispensary
because they said they've had something
they didn't they felt really bad they
were like hey the girl that was supposed
to be updating it was actually there she
kind of got in trouble I felt bad but
they gave me a fat deal so it that's
something that every shop should be on
top of don't feel bad about shopping for
quality leaving without a purchase or
dinging them fruit inaccurate menus like
this is just standard [ __ ] before I've
talked about not tipping bud tenders
because I feel like they I don't know
sometimes it totally depends on the
interaction right yeah I always agreed
with that part of the concentrate today
I knew what I wanted
like I want three of these things and
they're basically the budtender had to
put three packs in a jar or in a baggie
and hand him to me and take my money
right and I did today point you're
tipping for them counting your change
back correctly right and she was smart
enough to give me my change in once
which is part of why she got a tip she
wasn't gonna get all five of it but
since she gave him back in one she got
three of them because she was smart
enough to break it down into some ones
which is that was the only determining
factors if she gives me one she's gonna
get a few of them if she does not she
don't get five right that wasn't worth
five it was worth three and they were
super friendly they're super nice but I
tipped I would have you I probably would
attempt to but the guy that was in front
of me was not pleasant and I felt bad
for the bud tenders I was like damn
there that guy kind of just [ __ ] your
day up so here's maybe this will fix it
you know that's part of why tip today
and I'm not against tipping a budtender
I just I'm all about it but before I
didn't do it as frequently and you have
to do something too I don't know I
almost always tip something but some
people definitely get the loose change
and other people will get a five you
just it completely depends on your
interaction if I walk in and go get me
two of those and you just sort of nod at
me and we're done like if I walk in and
you know and you're like oh like and
this is in your wheelhouse this came in
just so you know I'm you might begin and
I said yeah actually she had to go get
those out of the back today so she had
to go for a little walk
carry some stuff so I guess it was worth
me helping her out but yeah the guy
before me broke was not pleasant he was
in a bad bad mood today you know I've
been there both ways yeah on both sides
of that counter yep yeah I've been both
customers too there's been some bad days
out there that happened that's why we
have these delicious concentrates I want
to take a DAB to all this dab I'm
looking at the rig and I'm looking at
some ash New York City I'm gonna get
some of this Clementine cookies going
we'll take a dab and then we'll start a
hole to start wrapping up the show right
now Mike thanks for bringing your your
little wrap-up part to the show thanks
for having more stuff to talk about on
the podcast it's always great to have
your view your opinion your voice on the
podcast
and then he went blank as he's checking
his phone to see if he's got more
content that he can talk about um I went
to check Twitter real quick to see if
there was another story right in front
of me that I'm spacing out on the one I
can think of is right now especially if
you're in Colorado there's what they
call an on-site consumption bill sitting
on our governor's desk miracle of
miracles our state legislature kicked it
up I'm not sure the deadline for his
signature has passed I know there is one
you just grabbed a sheet of paper do you
have the answer I'm not I don't know I
don't have the deadline written down as
far as I know that it has passed this
step before it is on his desk it's just
sitting there waiting far as its
governor's it's for to sign it it's
tasting bill
it's Senate bill 1258 one two five eight
and what you can do is go to you guys
get a pen or type this into your web
browser right now it is www.koco.com
ents it's Colorado gov slash governor
slash share your comments with dashes
share - your comments go there it's
really easy
any pothead can do it I did it it's
super simple uh there are a few
questions the question to answer number
one yes okay I'm already answering the
[ __ ] for you making it easy the question
the answer to question number two bill
number one two five eight all right then
it's gonna ask you are you opposed or
for you are for it alright then it's
going to ask you to explain say please
allow this tasting bill this is
something we need here in Colorado
basically this if you're not familiar it
allows existing cannabis legal cannabis
businesses so licensed dispensaries to
allow on-site consumption of non
combustible cannabis product
so they can set up a little area where
they could perfectly legally set up a
dab bar or an edible sampling room where
you can go in and while you're you're
shopping you bring yourself a driver
just so you can enjoy yourself to the
fullest and go in if you you know been
looking at inaudible you having you know
honing up and tried yet but always just
kind of notice while you're in their
home what does the peanut butter Buddha
taste like [ __ ] banana what I need to
try that yeah and you'll have a chance
to just go in and get a smaller portion
of it get a sample of and try it take a
dab of an extract maybe you're not
familiar with or a company you're not
familiar with there's a couple of
different options that we'd be able to
do that we've not all allowed to do
right now um if this bill gets signed
it's gonna take a while to get
implemented it's gonna take a while to
figure out what best practices are and
and see exactly how it plays out but
this is a big step forward for Colorado
if we get Sun this would be really great
right now
brands do a thing called pop ups so say
Mike and I have let's see we've got a
dispensary right Mike and Jeff's [ __ ]
weed Robin Hood we'd hunt ya ganja
Emporium whatever Wheaton Jack we say
hey on Friday the girl from your heart
podcast is gonna do a pop up here and
the Grove my heart we're part podcast
right now if they were to do a pop up
there they can give away t-shirts they
can give away merchandise they can do
sales on marijuana products they can
give you a discount for coming and
dropping in through the dispensary if
you buy through the dispensary they can
give you a discount on that brand
through a certain time hey while we're
here you get a deal on our product you
know what I mean meet-and-greet shake
their hand get a keychain get a t-shirt
get your picture with them tag them on
social media interact a little bit what
I feel will happen now is these brands
will show up and you will be able to
actually get samples because they can't
do that now they legally cannot give you
a sample you will be they will show up
they will go into the tasting room and
today will be viola labs sampled a
pop-up day at Mike and Jeff's comes in
samples out a couple of grams of their
own product from the shop
into the tasting room and just there's
so many possibilities and not studly
dude and a pretty girl just dabbing out
people for the next two hours people in
line just check out the new viola this
is our new drop this is our new drop
there's there's a couple of things I
want to get up there bring up before we
get through with this story the first is
if this passes miracle of miracles and
this gets into practice please don't
[ __ ] it up for the rest of us
consumed with not a clear head but like
know what you're getting into don't go
don't overdo it make an ass yourself run
everybody have an exit plan what are you
going to do after this day at home are
you on your lunch break is this your
first step think it through and the
second point is the the anti park
community around the country such as it
is is pretty shitty at most what they're
trying to do but one of the things that
pretty good at is inundating a specific
person in government with a lot of
emails about a specific issue and this
is one they've hit a couple of times and
I'm not surprised it's sat on the
governor's desk as long as it has
considering the amount of anti pot
contact the governor tell him not to
allow this it'll lead to dead people on
the roads that are not about type posts
I've seen so uh get active get informed
contact your governor if you're in
Colorado right now to contact
Hickenlooper would be very very helpful
to the community I know a lot of people
who have been dying to set up some sort
of consumption area room lounge whatever
and fully be legal they don't want to do
it in the gray market or as a church or
a couple of the other things they've got
going on right now they want to be able
to do it as part of their legal cannabis
business and this is a big a big window
of opportunity to do just that and if we
can we should take it please please do
to the vein on Jeff's forehead just
raised like a quarter inch with that dad
I just took a gigantic yeah I might have
been too big for the podcast but I'm
gonna live it feels like I'm swimming
and there's no water here again you guys
I'm gonna try to read you this website
this URL after taking that dab it is
righto guv slash governor can you spell
that govt er n o R / share - your -
comments excuse the drool in the
cottonmouth at the same time man Wow I'm
flying Appa go there you guys it'll be
pretty self-explanatory if you've got a
half a brain you'll be able to fill out
the little questionnaire it's real easy
please do that you do have to put in you
have to sign it at the end don't be
afraid you guys get involved get active
don't be scared we're all adults here
that's how you get what you want is by
being involved with the politics with
the system if you don't tell me what you
want I'll give you what you think you
want and they're always gonna [ __ ] you
that way alright Mike you got anything
else you're searching through the phone
I see your thumbs going crazy your eyes
are darting funny story to a
acquaintance of ours that's all I'm
sorry podcast people I'm usually better
than that with my phone on the show if
you're not following this person already
follow Tom angle I'm not on Twitter
Facebook pretty much any social media
he's basically leading the country in
cannabis reporting right now Tom I was
that with an e or an a a a a an goe he's
got a lock I just [ __ ] my cup Mike is
not the best when it comes to grammar
and letters I'm super bad at spelling
and and super bad at name suggests Jeff
just combined my two [ __ ] yeah his
foes I just superhero fought him I'm the
boss now oh all right I usually don't
talk about memes my favorite new meme is
the lotion boss if you've seen the
lotion boss you know what I'm talking
about if you haven't seen it you'll see
it soon enough it's on Twitter it's at
Tom ang eol all one word
Tom angle alright Mike says to follow
that guy I will follow him also i'll
start paying attention um cannabis
reporting for forbes pretty awesome
social media yeah definitely worth
following if you want to stay informed
on cannabis news if you want to follow
me you can find me at at Nemo Punk 15 on
Twitter or pueblos for sensible cannabis
laws on face
well you said you had a funny story was
that something you were not gonna share
on the show one of our co-workers got a
tick on his back and it camp out with
his kids last night and he was like a
[ __ ] seriously have a tick on my back
what do I do and I just had to look at
my phone and laugh at it for a minute
because hey that's a question for Google
and B I [ __ ] you gonna check on
your back what you can do about it now
yuck high-five that dude forming sign of
danger
high-five nature sometimes it bites whoo
sometimes it sucks yep whoo you guys
sometimes it burrows the [ __ ] in oh I
got a disgusting story about a tick but
we're gonna save that for another
podcast this has been a good show yeah I
lived in Kansas for a little while
that's all I'm gonna say if you can
avoid it don't there ticks out there
bigger than this [ __ ] hash container
bro yeah Mike told you how to find it
make sure you stock me on all the social
media find me on Facebook simply search
for the girl from your art podcast find
me on twitter @ GF YH podcast you can
follow my personal account its at Rasta
Jeff 4:20 you can find me on Instagram
Irie underscore genetics I've been
having a lot of fun embarrassing myself
on Instagram live check me out on
Instagram live feeds you can ask me
questions about cannabis you can ask me
questions about dreadlocks you can ask
me all kinds of weird questions I'll
probably answer almost anything you say
it's a lot of fun hanging out take some
dads with me it's not as formal as the
show it's fun it's like a STONER pop
quiz after time it kind of is we talk
about movies you talk about music we
talk about life sometimes I hang out the
dad and granny
sometimes they hang out with other
people I bring my beautiful friend Lucy
on we talk about all kinds of good stuff
it's a good time so check me out on the
Instagram live feed Irie underscore
genetics if you want to reach out if
you've got a product you'd like me to
review if you like to sponsor the
podcast if you'd like to say something
and you're not into all the social media
if you've got a question if you've got a
concern if you'd like to tell me
anything cool you can send me an email
let's grow from your heart
at hotmail.com don't forget that the
show is available on iTunes the show is
available on stitcher and also every
episode is now available on youtube
simply go to youtube and search for the
girl from your our podcast also don't
forget about patreon if you feel like
this show is worth a couple of bucks and
you'd like to contribute go to
patreon.com/scishow
grow from your heart all the information
that you need will be right there
huge shout out to everybody who has
contributed to the patreon campaign I
show a big huge shout-out to my friend
Larry thank you brother I appreciate it
don't forget about our sponsors the hell
a dank seed company and also pol grow
systems I love you guys thanks for all
the support hey Mike you got anything
else to say while you're over there
scroll through your phone have green
that everybody have a good night
everybody
Mike thanks for coming to the show
thanks for taking time from the new kid
hold him the wife the family the dog the
house yeah it's good to get out but I
already miss it yep he's hitching to get
back you guys he's got his keys in his
hand you know I I just got several
messages all at once and I know what
that means I mean that means both kids
are screaming at the same time all right
ladies and gentlemen we're gonna get let
Mike get back to his civilian life
thanks again for hanging out with me
I'll be back it was just a joke my gosh
he's all paranoid now I lost him just a
starter moment I looked down and
seriously looks where are the keys he's
talking about [ __ ] did I drop them um
ladies and gentlemen be back Thursday
that's what I think I was gonna say I'll
be back Thursday with a quickie episode
you guys don't cut down your plants too
early let him finish up everybody likes
the finish sometimes nine weeks like it
says on the package ain't enough you
need to go ten that's right all right
ladies and gentlemen yeah I want to give
a huge shout out to my friends at DNA
genetics and until next time take a phat
dab and give your mom a hug for me