[Music]
yeah what's up ladies and gentlemen it's
time for episode number 32 of the IG gr
culture podcast it's your host roster
Jeff joining me today on the mic we got
our buddy Adam with us how you doing bro
I'm good man what's up with you hanging
out bro taking some dabs give a big
shout out to our buddy Mike uh Mike was
supposed to come join us on the show
today but Mike uh he hurt himself he
hurt his back so he's laid up he's
taking a night off big shout out to Mike
get feeling better man get well bro
we'll take some dabs for
you also uh on the last episode I said
that I was going to make videos of this
podcast uh making a video is a big pain
in the ass and it really detracts from
the quality of the show in my opinion I
was too distracted by toys and equipment
I wasn't able to uh make a good podcast
so I've decided to not make videos of
the show what I will do is keep making
cheesy ass YouTube videos with iMovie
and just put up videos that are mostly
still shots there'll be some video in
there but it'll mostly be stills of
stuff that is involved in the podcast
I'll take pictures of rigs pictures of
plants pictures of the guests people
pictures of myself it'll be stuff like
that because doing a video really wasn't
very fun I'm going to fade out this
music here big shout out to cat and c
and the Mystic Roots band thanks for
letting me play your music on the show
really appreciate it make sure you guys
follow the Mystic Roots band
um speaking of putting pictures of rigs
up man oh yeah I got a new rig today uh
big shout out to LSD gallery on
Instagram and also big shout out to
slugworth I think it's slugworth glass I
should have researched that but check
out slugworth glass whatever they're
called on Instagram I will tweet a link
to that so you can find them uh I
ordered the Master Shake rig from LSD
Gallery it's a little smaller than I
expected but boy do I
approve came with this super awesome
chainsaw Dabber here mhm I think this
little handle here they're encouraging
me to wear this as a pendant is what I
think's happening MH and this rig is
certainly designed to be worn as a
pendant uh this thing I think Adam said
what is that three Ines tall about three
in I would agree that's about 3 inches
tall bro um so I'm super satisfied if
you guys are looking for good glass that
uh will get shipped to you at a
reasonable price from good people that
do good business thick the glass is
thicker than it looks like it's going to
be yeah it's nice and heavy it's not
clear so you can't see like the
thickness of the glass but if you look
at the straw and and see even like the
handles and stuff it is thick and once
you handle it you yeah this Master Shake
rig is stylish uh super stylish well
worth every penny I spent it got shipped
here super quickly it went out the day
after I paid for it I paid for it on
Sunday I got a tracking number when I
woke up Monday morning so if you need
glass uh check them out they're called
at LSD Gallery uh they're pretty fresh
also owe a big shout out to task Rock
because when I ordered ordered my new
rig of course I had to get it's a little
10 mm rig it's my first 10 mil I like
the bigger stuff honestly but this
little one is cute and I love the way it
hits this will be my new uh just when
I'm dabbing by myself that'll be my new
personal rig shout out to task I got
myself a purple uh carb cap and a little
10 mm triniti nail to put on my rig and
it works perfectly love it satisfied
much respect at LSD gallery and at task
Rock and at slugworth glass I'll have to
research the slugworth one and highly
educated titanium Highly Educated
titanium make sure you check those guys
out well now that you're there let's
just do this this podcast is brought to
you by our good friends at Highly
Educated titanium if you're using
highquality concentrates like I know
most of you are you deserve a high
quality titanium nail made in America
don't trust a Chinese knockoff or an
American knockoff you don't want that
crap that's made out of cheap Metals
trust an industry leader trust our good
friends at Highly Educated titanium
Highly Educated titanium products are
made for dabbers buy dabbers right here
in the United States of America you can
shake the man's hand you can tell him
your ideas you can tell him thanks it's
somebody that we know someone that's
part of this industry so big love much
respect to Highly Educated titanium if
you want your own Highly Educated
titanium products you can check out our
friends at LSD Gallery they have a
limited selection available or for a big
big selection check out aqualab
technologies.com they've got a lot of
great Highly Educated stuff in stock if
you're in
Colorado uh these place this place does
not pay me but dude go check out
Illusions glass okay on Broadway uh we
need to take Adam hasn't been there I
feel bad we've got to Denver several
times together and I have not taken you
to Illusions we got to do that and I'm
probably in the market of purchasing a
rig so I may need a nail and there you
go I was going to ask you earlier where
I can pick one up Illusions glass in
Denver does carry Highly Educated
products they have all kinds of sick
glass it's not just a glass shop it's a
gallery that sounds like a written
commercial no no that sounds fun it's
[ __ ] awesome yeah dude I owe a dollar
because I just said the f word again you
guys get me on that oh oh starting on
episode 30 every time I say the FW I owe
a dollar and you guys are going to hold
me to that yep to the charity by the
time we get to episode 35 I'll start
doing $5 do every time all right yeah so
I'm gonna I'm gonna stop saying that for
it's sliit by me I yeah it doesn't there
are some listeners that it does not slip
by so thank you guys for listening and
making some money for the uh the person
that's sick that actually needs some
money it's a good way to do it it's a
great way to do it make sure you guys
follow task rock on uh Instagram and
Twitter it's task rock pretty simple
there task t a k rock with a k r o k
it's all one word task rock all right
sorry I'm fixing some sound levels here
not happy with something I got it I
figure out it's that knob right there
I'm picky dude good I'll turn up my
headphones you got solve everything just
turn up the headphones you can't hear
the mess all right this podcast is also
brought to you by our good friends at
naturegreen remedies.com visit
naturegreen remedies.com for gug green
genetics the Plata of labs Sin City rare
dankness mile high can Aventure iy
genetics and and many many more trusted
Brands Nature's green remedies is
running a special for our podcast
listeners type in coupon code September
14 for 15% off any order and you always
get free shipping at naturegreen
remedies.com you know that coupon code
does end at the end of September I'll
put out a new coupon code next month for
you guys I think we're running out of
weeks here yeah also this podcast is
brought to you by hyro indoor growing
supplies hyro indoor growing supplies
has two locations to serve Colorado
visit the Denver store at 62 71 Beach
Street Unit F or stop by the new peblo
location on 618 East 4th Street in peblo
Colorado check out hyro for competitive
pricing and a great selection of indoor
growing supplies don't forget hyro is
now stocking a full line of Botanicare
products at the pleo location so if
you're shopping for botanic ha get down
there now and tell them you're listening
to the hyro to the hro culture podcast
brought to you by hyro indoor growing
supplies that's a lot of grow in one
word grow grow grow grow from your heart
all right our last ad this show is
brought to you by our friends at tree
Thugger dcom tree Thugger do.com live
music lifestyle magazine check out tree
Thugger dcom for concert and Festival
news and reviews
www.re Thugger
docomo to the show bro I read your
Facebook about your adventures that
you're going to take off on you're going
to go on a travel you hopefully are
going to end up in South America bro I
wish you the best of luck I'll miss you
I love you every day and I hope to see
you when you get back keep doing what
you do with tree hugger cuz we count on
you for sure for sure he's got a big
adventure set up for his life I also
read that and it it sounds like an
adventure is the right word yeah yeah I
wish him well him and his him and his
beautiful young lady hope you guys have
a good time
together all right so uh bro you want to
take a quick dab and then we will read
some news for sure uh guys if you want
to follow uh the show on Instagram or on
Twitter it's igro culture if you want to
follow our guest he is overgrowth goov
sorry I stumbled on that one overgrowth
goov you can find him on Twitter and
Instagram you can find me I'm r420 on
Twitter or you can follow iry gentics on
Instagram and Twitter I post a lot of
stuff there I know that's a lot of
Social Media stuff but that gives you
some stuff to follow if you're listening
to the podcast if you're killing time
you can look at at overgrow theg see the
pictures he's posting you can look at at
I genetics and see the weed plants I
post you can look at igro culture and
see a bunch of canabo profile charts and
stuff like that lots of stuff to check
out also I encourage you heavily to
check out out the Forum on IR
genetics.com uh I've got a forum there
that is my website uh you won't be
censored unless you're a [ __ ] talker I
try to let everybody have freedom of
speech you can say what you want it's
not like Facebook I'm not going to go
and take down your stuff I'm not going
to make you use your real name uh
Facebook has been censoring people
lately Facebook has been taking down
accounts that are uh have fake names or
not even fake names just pseudo names so
if I disappear off of Facebook find me
on the for come join my Forum uh I'll
answer all of your grow questions there
uh I've got a nice community of friends
that are there we post up our pictures
we post stuff about our Gardens I've
been posting the notes from the podcast
if I type something out like a long note
I'll actually put it there on the Forum
so people can check it out so I
encourage you to interact with us I love
interaction of course there's Facebook
uh Agro culture on Facebook yeah it
sounds like I'm just plugging the show
again so we're going to take a quick dab
and then we will be back for the news
while we take dabs I'm just going to
turn up the music I got some Mystic
Roots band
playing um I think this is uh $100
bag I think so I think it's $100 bag
yeah we're going to take a dab real
quick while this plays enjoy
[Music]
guys we'll leave the mic's on so you can
hear Adam C yeah that's what I'm going
to do um speaking of which I got to say
a big shout out to bender and uh 420.com
uh they've
been doing it while I'm away and held it
down while I couldn't be on the internet
and stuff like that and big shout out to
you guys uh all the people back out east
uh we do not care Murphy's bro you know
who you are man thanks for listening
finding dude uh half of the guys from
the um from the 420 it just found out
that I've been on you know they just
thought I was spamming your your uh
podcast and it's like man pay
attention I was stoned when I wrote it
it should make a a little bit of sense
at
[Music]
least all right here we go the choke
fist I owe a big shout out to Bender as
well Bender if you're listening thanks
bro you made me three logos and all
three of them look sweet as [ __ ] I
appreciate it keep them coming bro keep
them coming we'll give you more shout
outs on the show it's the best I can do
for now yeah yeah but in the long run uh
we'll make it up to you we'll make it
worth it I appreciate it he he's a cool
dude and I didn't ask for anything he
just volunteered and made me some pretty
cool uh iy genetics logos dude how about
an igro culture logo that I can make a
sticker out of there we go I I'll you
know I'll put the the request in I'll
just tell him that he the show tell yeah
don't even tell him just that way if he
listens we'll find out we'll find out
that music was loud while we were
talking it's so uh we're taking some
dabs and some stuff blasted by my good
buddy at Garden of
Weeden uh follow Garden of Weeden Garden
of weed n h on Instagram sorry I'm
coughing after a
dab guys I hope you're taking dabs with
us while we're dabbing on the
show using those Highly Educated Nam na
mhm
yeah we couldn't hit that's some that's
some tasty stuff isn't that tasty I
think it's some Golden Goat we had to
hit the Hitman rig because hitting that
little mini slugworth would just make us
cough for an hour on the show big shout
out to those guys I mean you know which
guys the garden we oh that's what I just
I think that's what I was just saying I
well you said we were doing that but
yeah I big shout out to Garden of Weeden
big shout out I slipped you were in dab
world that's okay you had that dab
bubble around your head Adam's going to
be all right guys we'll just give him a
minute to catch up you there no I'm here
you good yep you good well I mean they
also they follow me on Instagram and
stuff like call your mom if think it'll
make the podcast better that could be
fun we're sitting here with can I say
yeah sure miss G we're sitting here with
your son and he's dabbed the [ __ ] out I
was wondering if you could just talk him
down a little bit well the the thing is
I'll sit here and I'll encourage people
like yeah go follow and troll the [ __ ]
out of her you know on Facebook but I
don't really care you know you want
people to troll your mom H it's whatever
that'd be funny it would be my mom
doesn't have any social media and I'm
glad about it I'm pretty glad about it
guys we're just rambling we're having a
personal conversation because we just
took dabs I'd rather talk have just some
rambles that are incoherent instead of
trying to read the news while I'm
choking over here the little
intermission so um this is going to go
up probably Monday I think uh yeah it
should go up Monday morning how' you
guys like that bonus little miniature
episode that I put out Thursday night
was that cool or what it I I've been
trying to catch up um it's going to go
tonight there's one as we're recording
I'll post another one when we finish I
know and then we'll have this one going
so we're I'm getting ahead of myself but
this is on Monday I'm living in the
future you're living in the future all
right I'm living I'm GNA live in the now
guys if you've got social media if
you've got Facebook if you've got
Twitter if you've got YouTube if you've
watched TV in the past couple of days
you have seen the anchor lady guys
excuse my Dollar on this one come on
don't charge me a dollar this for this
one this lady went on TV and she made
nice long speech and Her speech ended
with [ __ ] it I quit you guys know who
I'm talking about right I'm going to
read an AR I wonder if I can play the
video can I play the video and not get
in trouble uh it's on it's from the news
yeah I mean the news played the hell out
of it they didn't get permission well
maybe they did oh let's turn down the
music and let's try to play this video
because I'm going to play a quick video
then you guys this happened on the news
and then I'll read the
story now everything youve heard is why
I the actual owner oh it sounds like
[ __ ] I'm not even going to play it sorry
right well uh [ __ ] give me a second guys
I'm going to press pause we're going to
search for the actual good quality video
and I'll play it for you hold on I I owe
you that much give me a
second all right guys I'm back I did a
little bit of searching uh the video
comes in kind of late I should fill you
in a little bit this lady the news ran a
report about medical cannabis or
cannabis in Alaska and this lady was
reporting on it and then during her
report she states that she supports
cannabis and that she actually is the
owner of the alas cannabis club so this
is kind of where just to get you up to
speed so that's where she jumps in and
I'll play the video now and hopefully
they don't take it off of all of the
servers now everything you heard is why
I the actual owner of the Alaska
Cannabis Club will be dedicating all of
my energy toward fighting for freedom
and fairness which begins with
legalizing marijuana here in Alaska and
as for this job well not that I have a
choice but [ __ ] it I
Quit so you heard it right there
apologize and then uh the next lady on
the news they scroll they the camera
pops back up to the other lady on the
news and this lady the other co-host
looks like she pissed her pants when she
said that but so this lady goes on the
news and she uh she's a news reporter
and you heard her right there she just
said [ __ ] it I Quit live on the news so
I'm going to get into the article it'll
make a little more sense uh [ __ ] it I
Quit anchor explains her dramatic exit
and guys don't charge me a dollar for
all of these it's in the article I'm
just relaying the news uh the did I read
who it's by I don't know if I said who
it's by it's by Molly Riley from The
Huffington Post I think I'm going to get
me a a dirty nasty recycled jar to bring
over here and set on your table during
these podcast just for yeah just so you
feel dirty even dirty and you had to put
it like you have to stick it to the
bottom of the jar the F it jar the F jar
all right so it says a local news the
local news anchor who dramatically quit
her job on air following a segment on
marijuana explained her in a YouTube
video released Monday Charlo green a
reporter for anchorage's ktva announced
on air that she would be leaving her job
at the TV station to focus on marijuana
legalization in
Alaska uh so like I said they ran the
clip about cannabis and then she says
this everything you've heard is why I
the actual owner of the Alaska Cannabis
Club will be dedicating all of my energy
toward fighting for freedom and fairness
which begins with legalizing marijuana
here in Alaska she said and as for this
job well not that I have a choice but
[ __ ] it I Quit so that's where she
stirred up a lot of
controversy um she in my opinion the
attention should have been on um her
advocacy her support and her uh fight to
legalize and support cannabis instead
she chose one wrong word on the air on
TV and distracted it from all of what
she was trying to do she said the word
that cost me a dollar on the air on TV
so that Adam pointed it out that that TV
station is going to face a fine
absolutely the FCC is going to do
something even if it was early morning
and there was very small numbers yeah
there still yeah it could that looked
like a normal FCC goes from like 2500 to
like you know 250,000 she probably end
up paying the fine can they find her um
they they may able to but still that was
rude and her choice of words distracted
from her whole fight it made her kind of
look bad she could have quit on air and
probably sent a better message but it
wouldn't have been her
it wouldn't have been heard so broadly
it it would not have been heard by the
non since everybody has seen this on
every if the day it happened I opened up
my Facebook and it was all anybody had
posted all day so apparently she she got
herself popular the way she was trying
to do but I me she could have done a
little bit better of a job but then
there's also the you know I'm not saying
that the marijuana business is going to
fail but maybe she hits a snafu and it
kind of crumbles from underneath her
maybe she trusts the wrong part or
there's some kind of illegal there's all
kinds of things that could happen and
from here on out she's never getting a
reporting job again oh no you know
you're never getting on any kind of
capable access let alone you know making
a comedy show you know maybe that she
can come on our podcast whenever she'd
like well there you go there's the open
invitation yeah all right I'll keep
going with the article uh in the YouTube
clip green explained why she believes
the fight for marijuana legalization in
her home state is so
important there Comes A Time in each and
every one of our lives where we must
choose to continue to spectate or stand
up for what's right she said why are
Americans arrested every 30 seconds
alaskans every 4.3 hours why should an
aspiring someone lose their ability to
earn a higher education to become
someone they were not meant to be and
why should you lose the ability to get
public assistance in times of struggle
and need she continued advocating for
freedom and fairness should be
everybody's Duty I'm making it my life
work to uphold what America stands for
truly life liberty and the pursuit of
happiness ideals now need to be
defended I I kind of agree with her
there I I agree with her but as I've
been told numerous times throughout my
life it's not what you do it's how you
do it
and as hearing it over and over again is
you shouldn't have said f you shouldn't
have said [ __ ] you shouldn't have said
this you know I hear it constantly but
if that's the type of person of who you
are and you're able to stand up to that
scrutiny I'm I'm I'll back that you know
I'm not the type of person to bite my
tongue especially if you crossed me and
I felt like I haven't done anything
wrong um so if they were going to fire
her [ __ ] that company you know uh 100%
they weren't going to fire her until she
said that she owned that canas club and
she was legit anyway she's got a backup
job so she could have just said and I
since that's probably my last report so
it was nice seeing you guys have a good
night you know instead of [ __ ] it I Quit
yeah for sure it would blown if you had
the OPP yeah it wouldn't have blown up
and if you had the opportunity to go on
the news in front of camera would you
rather say and tonight I respectfully
design or would you rather be like you
suck you suck you suck [ __ ] it I quit
you just yeah so me yeah for sure you
know but you being my friend would kind
of stand back and say yeah don't be you
yeah yeah all right so the last line of
the article says alaskans are set to
vote on ballot measure 2 which would
legalize possession of small amounts of
marijuana for recreational use in
November Colorado and Washington have
implemented similar legislation in the
last year what the [ __ ] have they been
doing up there they made it against the
law to like drink in separate counties
that was ballot initiative one I'm
guessing and ballot initiative two is to
maybe legalized marijuana dude did you
hear the ratio a minute ago when it was
like every 30 seconds an American is
rested in in in in for pot in every 4.3
minutes in 4.3 hours in Alaska D what a
big [ __ ] ratio what are they doing up
there Arrested moose like hey get out
they're all after the moose knuckles
that's moose knuckles
well yeah well hopefully they legalize
possession of small amounts of marijuana
for recreational use in November that
would be freaking awesome uh they would
give us a lot less to watch on Alaskan
state troopers a yeah all right so guys
tweet me what you think about this lady
you know what I've seen so much about it
I know what you think about this lady if
you have to contribute to our
conversation let me know I'd be glad to
hear it uh add to it add to the
conversation keep the conversation going
uh did she screw herself by using the
language she did or did she actually
help herself out by using that language
that's what I want to know please
comment because see I'm on the border of
I'm down with saying [ __ ] it I quit but
then all my friends who have respectable
businesses and and respectable things
would be like no you really should and
it's usually afterwards you know it's
usually at this point in time where
we're talking now so probably shouldn't
have done that bro how many times have I
said that to you you you preemptive
strike a lot a lot more than my parents
did I'll tell you that much it took you
a lot less time to figure it out and I'm
good after that right I'm good yeah once
I say bro do you realize that you're
just about to put Nitro and glycerin in
the same container and Shake It Up do
you see that coming then you go oh yeah
I had Nitro and glycerin in the same
container
but once I warn you you're you're pretty
on it I have been guilty to fail you
know you got to fail to learn how many
if you try stuff and you do it perfectly
you're like I'm [ __ ] good at that I
owe a dollar for that one but if you do
something and you fail you're like boy
I'm humbled I really failed I got to
learn how to do this right yeah you
don't learn anything the first time you
get stuff right I agree so where' that
article go where is it here it is uh
Adam actually brought this article to my
attention it's written by Jeremy P Meyer
uh we found this on the denverpost.com
it says Colorado schools out Millions
due to marijuana excise tax
loophole well it's not they're not out
this this sounds like they had millions
in their pockets and somebody reached in
and took it out that's not the way this
went that's the way I read it yeah I
read this article it's a little
misleading but they have to do that with
headlines to get you to read it the
schools did get kind of punked a little
bit but it wasn't a loophole it was a
business move and it wasn't aimed it
nobody was like let's screw the schools
nobody did that it was just what
business people were doing because it's
how business was being done at the time
how the law was wrote yeah yeah the yeah
so it says a loophole built into
Colorado's marijuana system has allowed
thousands of pounds of pot to go untaxed
and has cost the state millions of
dollars that should have gone to school
construction Fund in 2012 Colorado
voters overwhelmingly approved amendment
64 which among other things promised
that the first $40 million in excise tax
revenue would be dedicated every year
for the state school construction fund
but this year only about $10 million is
expected to be raised thanks to a rule
that allows marijuana retailers to avoid
paying the tax in a one-time transfer of
wholesale
pot sure sorry I had to clear my my face
there surely Revenue will increase over
time as the industry continues to mature
and fewer license holders are able to
use the onetime tax-free transfer so
what they're able to do I haven't read
far enough into the article here but
what they're able to do shops that have
medical marijuana are able to move it
from their medical marijuana side to
their recreational marijuana side to
make it available for everybody instead
of just medical patients but there must
be a tax paid when that happens because
the taxes are different uh on the
medical side and the rec side and uh
Colorado tried to protect the medical
side a little bit by doing this but in
my opinion it has failed so uh I'll
continue into the article whether the
excise tax revenue will uh ever reach 40
million is anyone's guess my suspicion
is the amount will never be attained as
and was a pie in the sky figure meant to
attract voters if that sounds familiar
you may be remembering the 2008 campaign
for Amendment 50 that promised 182
million over 5 years to community
colleges from the expansion of gaming
however only 25.3 million has been
generated through the fiscal year 2012
to
2013 half the people are spending their
money on
pot the marijuana X Tax reeven revenues
would certainly grow if the loophole uh
that was created by Regulators to launch
the industry was closed there are still
275 license holders who could take
advantage of it according to One
Source the loophole was created to make
sure enough pot would be in the retail
Marketplace when doors opened on January
1st
2014 Regulators allowed medical
marijuana lenses converting to retail a
one-time tax-free
transfer that transfer was a big
difference between Colorado and
Washington the other state that
legalized retail
marijuana and why the sorry I had to
reread that s because it looked weird to
me something didn't sound right but okay
that transfer was a big difference
between Colorado was the big difference
is what it should say between Colorado
and Washington the other state that
legalized retail marijuana okay and why
the Centennial state was out the door
first Washington had to grow its retail
crop from seed Colorado officials say
9,711 lb of medical pot was transferred
tax-free to re retail stores
4,724 lb of medical marijuana was moved
to retail marijuana products and
manufacturers and
8,576 lbs of medical pot was transferred
to retail marijuana cultivation
facilities that last trench will be
subject to the tax once it is
transferred or sold to another marijuana
establishment yeah there will be taxes
made on this just not that original
transfer tax so it says it is estimated
the untaxed pot would have provided $3
million for the state school
construction fund or twice what the fund
received in the fiscal year Kathy
Gerhart a member of the public school
Capital Construction assistance board
that's a lot of wordss for a board a lot
that's a big title yeah uh provide the a
board that provides grants for schools
construction and renovation knew the
numbers were going to be low after
seeing February's receipts the first
month we were thinking we're going to be
rolling in cash she said then the second
month it was wait a minute we're only
getting fractions of what we thought
were we were going to get in this this
was not the voter intent she said I
don't think anyone who voted for
amendment 64 thought this would happen
she
said they thought the money would go to
school kids this is coming at the
expensive kids in really needy school
districts sorry there the text is broken
up oddly with ads here sorry uh the
building excellent schools today or best
fund is a competive grant program that
helps District districts with Capital
Construction it is able to support
projects in rural school districts that
don't have large property bases
necessary for Bond projects the best
fund over the years has received more
than $385 million in Revenue 90% from
the state land trust this year the best
fund is helping construction buildings
in the Edson 54 JT school district and
supporting projects in dozens of school
districts around the state for things
like roof Replacements and
boilers marijuana taxes are providing
less than 1% of the program's funds or
$3.1 million it would have made a big
difference she said whether there is a
tax credit on the other side there is
somebody to whom the tax credit should
have
gone okay proposition doua which was
approved by voters in 2013 mandates a
15% excise tax on imposed imposed on
unprocessed retail
marijuana but amendment 64 says no
excise taxes can be charged on pot
cultivated as medical marijuana
a transfer logically of medically grown
pot couldn't be taxed which is the basis
for the loophole The Simple Solution
then is to discontinu transfers the
state doesn't need them anyway the
retail pot industry is up and running
now and doesn't need the influx of
medical pot to prop up retail stores
plus transfers disadvantaged retail
Growers who have to pay the tax when
medical Growers don't for that onetime
swap it was never our intent to
manipulate the market said rep danan Pon
it's correct uh it's a correction that
needs to be made he said also a draft
Bill already had been written that would
stop the transfer after January 1st 2016
but the loophole should be closed sooner
to match the voter's intent and make
good on a promise that the revenue
should be going to
schools I I agree yeah the revenue
should go to the schools
but where's the other money going like
if
if why did it get exempt from the school
tools if
if I understand 40 million 40 million
sounds like a lot just that money they
said not make 40 million in like the
first 48
Hours um maybe in total sales maybe but
what they're saying is uh this tax that
they had this tax set up this tax was
supposed to go here and the money didn't
happen because these guys found a way to
not make the money we we had that you
read that article not that long ago
where it was 1.9 tax $1 1.9 million of
taxable money from this County alone
right well that was that's set up to go
to different places that this fund this
one is the one that didn't happen
because they said this money right here
specifically that's just [ __ ] why
they who who was the one was like yeah
cut the kids out you know like in the
council was like I got a good idea well
that's what I'm saying they didn't
that's it wasn't even aimed to do that
it's just kind of this rule was set up
to help them have enough herb for when
the shops opened but that was also they
said when this money is made it's going
to the schools but that just didn't get
made nobody was really like [ __ ] that
fund [ __ ] those kids that's
$2 uh nobody was really like that it's
just that's just how it worked out that
they found a way around that like if I
told you it would be nice if they were
like all right this we we got we were
expecting you know maybe $100 million
for the first year and they just said
you know what we'll have the best
schools anywhere you know like here just
take this next cheers us you know we'll
we'll divy it up but there why not you
know drop that common cor [ __ ] and get
on with your [ __ ] lives tell the rest
of the country that you we the high ones
yeah yeah
um we're not going to do
that I kind of agree that they should
change the rule by
2016 uh they're right if the shops are
doing it right they don't need to move
herb
around and if you're growing Medical
herbit needs to be there for the
patients mhm yeah so they didn't really
purposely screw the kids out that's just
how like if I told you if you uh drive
around the block every day on your work
you don't have to pay the $3 toll fee
but that $3 to toll fee goes to the SK
to the school kids you still drive her
on the Block you wouldn't give a [ __ ]
about that $3 and that's kind of what
they did they just drove her on the
Block they didn't really they didn't go
take the three bucks and stab somebody
for it they just skipped paying it they
figured out speaking of this whole
taking medical and taking it recre
um I went out to the shop the other day
I won't say which one but it was for
their
special there was nothing on the medical
side zero and they're like well you can
choose from the recreational there was
literally four
kinds and it was all sativa heavy 70%
you know who knows what they're talking
about I'm pretty sure I know what shop
you went to and they've recently opened
up another location north of here and I
have a a friend who stopped there just
the other day and they were hopping and
the place was full and had all kinds of
great [ __ ] so what they've done is
they've taken all their product from
their PUO West location no it's full
like well oh maybe they their their
marijuana yes but uh they they had a
whole shelf of shatter whole bunch of
new extracts and things like that and
all kinds of other stuff except for bud
and it was their special day and I was
in there like
11:00 you know it's yeah the shops need
to get together in my opinion for
sure I'm just saying that affected us
you know that affected us here locally
that affected me locally medical
patients you're on the that's so why
that really sucks is because as a
medical on the medical side the herb is
cheaper to just to start um it's
considered medicine it's it's not even
uh you know I I I'm not going to lie
about it I have it for not strangling my
wife and children don't say that on
there there you have it for stress
relief
but so on the medical side it's a little
bit cheaper to start with on the
recreational side they charge you more
then on the recreational side they add a
tax to it so let's just move the same
product from the recreational from the
medical side right over to the
recreational side mark it up 10 bucks an
e more screw the medical patients out of
it more than that 15 bucks an eigh more
half it's half the price more yeah right
so so yeah just mark it up way high
charge an extra tax for it and then
don't even care about the medical
patients anymore how can a shop do that
how can a business owner do that and
look his patients his customers in the
eye who whoa whoa they give you priority
over the wreck patience that means the W
patients can just sit out there and have
red card patients come in come in come
in and they do and they just sit there
so if you got that's the only thing you
get though right is that red card
priority then they should take you into
the red card side and take care of you
properly Pablo they won't let them open
up the they they already bought the the
location next to them had it all worked
out with the owner
and the city came in and says hold on no
no no no no no no no no no and they're
like what do you mean no we're doing
banging business and that's right there
you know perfect location and they're
like yeah but you're not spreading and
more of that we got enough there's 12 of
them right here so they put a stop to
that and I'm sure to the north huh
you'll have to let me know
but I don't know we'll go up there uh
you want to go to dinner tonight sure
let's go about a 45 minute drive from
here I'm dude one of the dankest D can
we please go I'm [ __ ] for real you
got to in the morning I [ __ ] that you'll
you'll be able to do it it's it's 11 o'
at Night Guru crack I'll go and I'll
even throw in 10 bucks on gas oh I think
we're going to go eat at this place in
Manito Springs up [ __ ] her and let's
go dud the mate factor in Colorado
Springs is amazing you I'm going to go
there and spend money man Springs the
Monte factor in Man 2 Springs go there
the most amazing veggie WAP get the
veggie WAP with the house dressing oh
get cheese and the cheese sandwich uh if
you want something cool get the veggie
wrap if you want something hot get that
cheese deluxe do you remember what was
in my coffee dude I don't drink the
coffee I know but he it was something
weird and fancy and I can't remember uh
I like the Jasmine maybe the dark roast
mate is amazing if you're going to drink
something from there okay I got a nice
coffee from there and it was good so
anyways plug all right let's just wrap
up the show and we're going to go to man
two Springs and eat at the mate Factor
it was good talking to you guys yeah no
I've got one more news article um where
did it go I have two on the screen one
of them is really long we've been going
35 minutes I feel my throat getting a
little itchy so we're going to do one
article and then really possibly drive
to manitu we'll see what our friend is
doing sh out yeah shout out to the
person that introduced me to the Monte
Factor love you for
that all right so here's another news
article this one was sent to me by our
good friend Mike who is laid out tonight
Mike hurt his back Mike's a big dude to
have a hurt back that's got to suck
shout out bro take
get better I wish you were here doing
dabs yeah dabs would help you out he
said he couldn't even get in his car Ian
it probably wouldn't if he hurt his back
because the the lung thing cuz he coughs
yeah Mike you like to cough bro you guys
that smoke cigarettes and take dabs you
choke so hard we got to quit that man we
got cigarettes are the dev M you know
where we can smoke all the weed we want
why are you smoking
cigarettes I know man I know I'm sorry I
know I'm not your dad I don't I do care
but I don't care that much all right so
prosecutors object to war on weed is the
title of this article I'm looking for
someone who wrote it who where's the
author was that mine or yours Chris
wigant was from Mike this one the mic
sent us I'm sorry that's cool you're I'm
dabbed out tooing keep the show on the
road keeping the show on the
road um all right prosecutors object to
war on weed by Chris weant I probably
said that wrong but you know that's how
I do stuff whoa technical glitch there
sound like I cut out for a second anyway
uh where was I Chris we get all right
the prosecution objects that's one way
to put it at any rate two news stories
from the Pacific Northwest today pose an
interesting question are prosecutors
beginning to get fed up with the war on
weed the two stories are completely
unrelated I should mention one is about
a current prosecutor at the local level
and one is about a formal former Federal
prosecutor making a noteworthy
endorsement neither has anything to do
with the other but both show some common
sense being applied in a in refreshing
ways it's too early to call it a trend
even a regional Regional One but it
certainly is a step in the right
direction at the very least so first the
local
story Seattle's elector geez Seattle's
elected prosecutor said Monday he's
dropping all tickets issued for the
public use of marijuana through the
first seven months of this year because
most of them were issued by a single
officer who disagrees with the legal pot
law in a briefing to City Council on
Monday City attorney Pete Holmes says he
is moving to dismiss a approximately 100
tickets issued by the Seattle Police
Department between January 1st and July
31st his office also said it would be
seeking a refund for 22 people who have
already paid their $27 ticket so one
state to the South a former Federal
prosecutor for Oregon has thrown her
support behind a ballot initiative to
legalize recreational marijuana for
adults in the state Chris Olen who
served as Oregon's Chief Federal
prosecutor during the Clinton
Administration made the news by joining
House member Earl bomhower and a former
Oregon Supreme Court Justice by publicly
publicly supporting the ballot measure
and here's the story I enforce our
marijuana laws but they don't work
Olsson said in a statement announcing
her endorsement filling our courts and
jails has failed to reduce marijuana use
and drug cartels are pocketing all the
profits she said citing fed Federal
statistics that show about one in 14
Oregon arrests is for marij want a
possession uh real quick here you know
we're not the government here in
Colorado is not bitching about the
cartel really any Much Anymore running
pot now they're starting to look at like
you guys you know what I'm saying like
the the guys who take care of patients
they're like hold on they're not
just we don't have control over
everything so we need that and and
that's what it's become it's not even a
crime anymore so now they're starting to
turn into well we're making tons of
money but how can we get just a little
more each year a little more each year
there's no worry of uh cartels anymore
the old guys around here a lot of the
oldtimers don't like to pay kind bud
prices you know what I mean you can get
if you know the right people you can get
an eth of dank weed around here for 25
bucks uh back in the day those guys used
to buy that Mexican brick weed for $25 a
half ounce and they love it uh they only
smoke a bowl a day two bowls a so some
kind bud would just kill them you know
two hits and they' just be [ __ ] but
lately those guys are calling up like
the guys I used to talk to years ago
they're like hey man I I can you get any
decent weed because they can't find any
of their old swag connects anymore all
that [ __ ] is gone that cartel Mexican
import weed is disappearing so it's not
around hook him up with that high CBD so
we got a first story here and this is my
interjection here I'm not into the
article right now uh the first story
here is about a prosecutor saying that
he's going to drop tickets written by a
cop because that cop's a dick and did
this out of his own you reported on this
on an earlier episode yeah yeah [ __ ]
that cop I'll take a dollar for that one
yeah uh and then we have another person
saying uh the laws don't work and they
state that they actually the drug
cartels are profiting so it it looks
like some people are starting to
understand some people are starting to
see the light these are positive reasons
why we want to legalize cannabis so I'll
get back into the article in the first
instance this was nothing short of a
prosecutor using using his prosecutorial
discretion to avoid wasting a lot of
time in the courts and more importantly
to reign in reign in one police officer
who was obviously on a vendetta against
the voters for passing a law he did not
personally approve of one single police
officer was was responsible for eight
out of all 10 tickets issued in the
Seattle for public in Seattle for public
consumption of marijuana during the
first half of this year the other 20%
were written by the entire rest of the
police Force to put this in another way
this officer wrote one ticket he
considered uh this officer on one ticket
wrote he considered the new legalization
law
silly while the other off while the
officer has been reassigned new duties
after this came to light there are a lot
of folks with cases still in the legal
system as a result of his actions what a
dick of a cop cops don't realize what
they're doing to you when they screw you
up for having some a little bit of weed
or whatever you're doing they don't and
some of them do and they love it that
[ __ ] sucks come on guys if you're a cop
some cops are listening to the podcast I
know you are I know you're a law
enforcement officer uh we want to
educate you about how not dangerous
cannabis is uh it's something that ask
us just I mean especially if it's here
just listen to the show just listen to
the show you guys will learn I inform
yourself listen to me I'm a smart dude
I'm an educated dude I'm reading news
I'm trying to educate people I'm trying
to keep people safe we're not bad people
did you not just hear Stoners with words
right there with yeah that was a that
was impressive smokes pot not a bad
person right yeah uh in Washington state
of course recreational marijuana use is
legal the voters approved the change in
state law and the prosecutors actions
quite obviously reflect the PE the will
of the people but it didn't have to
happen this way prosecutors in general
are pretty much tough on crime types of
people and if this particular prosecutor
has agreed with the cop's way of
thinking then all these cases would have
continued to clog the legal system all
the way to The Bitter End all $27 of it
this prosecutor however objected to that
scenario and applied some common sense
he's even going the extra mile and
trying to refund fines already paid that
is truly commendable that is a truly
commendable action once again reflecting
the will of the voters in legal reality
the second news item doesn't seem to
deal with actual legal cases it comes
from a prosecutor who no longer works
for the for the Federal Department of
Justice still this is a stunning
development Federal prosecutors after
all are not bound by any state law and
therefore can apply federal law whether
marijuana is still the most legal of all
drugs where marijuana is still the most
legal of all Dr illegal of all drugs
without even having to weigh in on state
politics Believe It or Not There are
some extremely zealous Federal
prosecutors all up and down the West
Coast who are fighting tooth and nail
against any state legalization efforts
in unprecedented and creative ways so
hearing even a former prosecutor bluntly
refute the entire purpose of the Federal
war on weed is a welcome development
indeed the language she used is a pretty
strong condemn nation of federal laws
she upheld while in office I enforced
our marijuana laws and they don't work
prosecutors are practical people who
deal with the real end aftermath of
arresting marijuana users so the
argument used is not a is a is not a
moral One locking up marijuana users is
wrong or one of racial equality black
and brown people are treated differently
by the court system or even a political
one The public's mood has shifted
instead it's a view from the front lines
of the drug war which relies on personal
experience in applying federal laws and
the relative effectiveness of carrying
out this job I enforced our marijuana
laws and they don't
work so this person instead of just
playing by the book basically saying had
weed go to jail had weed go to jail had
a lot of weed go to prison MH they're
actually looking at what they're doing
to people like I was saying they're
saying you had some weed you're a human
let's quit smoking weed here's a fine
get your [ __ ] together don't go to
prison forever don't go get butt raped
turn it they're taking some compassion
into this
finally they're just start to hear the
other side of the story and that's all
you nine times out of 10 you got to do
uh you know when you're going to court
and standing in front of the judge
everybody just kind of pushes you behind
your lawyer or public DET Pretender you
know sitting there and that's that they
say you have your day but a lot of times
they just ask you if you understand and
it's a yes or no question is all you
really get
so it's good that they're finally
starting to be like what did you have
you know yeah so all right so of all the
pro-legalization arguments this could
perhaps be the strongest one the laws
don't work they don't have the intended
effect the feds have been fighting the
war on weed for almost a century now
with precious little to show for it uh
yeah definitely right and in fact they
have severe unintended consequences drug
cartel drug cartels are pocketing all of
the profits therefore mindlessly
continuing on the same course is nothing
short of Madness I think that's what
they call Insanity Chris Olson is not
the first law enforcement officer to
have this Revelation and begin publicly
trying to change the situation an entire
organization already exists law
enforcement against prohibition or leap
for members of the law enforcement
Community passed in present to Advocate
the marijuana legal reform many members
are former cops who have firsthand who
saw firsthand how pointless the entire
war on weed truly was throughout their
careers now free to the prospect of
ending their career over a public
statement many are speaking out on the
subject their message is a simple one
prohibition didn't work and prohibition
of marijuana isn't working
either Chris Olen is to be commended for
raising her own prose prosecutorial
objection and for knowing her public
support behind a ballot measure in the
state where she used to uphold the law
the personal connection to the state
ballot measure might convince a few
voters even though even tough on crime
types uh that the sorry let me move this
page it's all scrolling on its own there
we go uh where were we uh all the rest
of the arguments aside the law needs
changing because it doesn't work it does
nothing short of waste time for the
entire judicial system for something
which shouldn't even be illegal in the
first place the Oregon ballot measure
race may be close the year Washington
and Colorado legalized recreational
marijuana Oregon had a similar but badly
written initiative on its ballot it
failed this time around the effort is a
lot more serious but reliable pulling on
the subject is notoriously hard to do so
the V the vote might be very close in
November guys if you're in Oregon when
this comes up go vote to legalize
cannabis so pro-legalization groups will
be very closely watching the vote this
year in Oregon and in Alaska and
Washington DC so assumably
assumably sorry my throat's burning out
I'm trying to go fast assumably they'll
also be closely watching the impact of
olsson's simple the laws don't work
message olsson's message is a powerful
one because it could reach voters not
generally open to other uh
pro-legalization arguments if you're a
Law and Order type of voter a formal
former Federal Prosecutor's opinion
should carry some weight in other words
perhaps more prosecutors both state and
federal both current and former can be
enlisted in this movement as I said it
is far too early to call this any sort
of trend but it certainly is a
development worth taking note of to end
on the legal theme we began on perhaps
the voters will sustain these
prosecutors
[Music]
objections man you can follow Chris on
Twitter this was written by quis Chris
Chris weant uh it's Chris weant weig g-
n t a very well-written article make
sure you follow him on Twitter thanks
for letting me read your stuff um
man people are catching on it looks like
it for sure um it's glad to see that
people are
just open for debate at least yeah well
and maybe like they said maybe now that
uh the state hasn't melted the older
people don't want to hear from you and
me that weed is harmless that cannabis
is helpful that medical marijuana will
help you people don't want to hear that
but if you're a former if you're a
former from the FED then they have to
listen to you because you're obviously
not full of [ __ ] huh well at least they
should trust you because you're the one
been feeding them the [ __ ] for the past
you know however many years so well now
what do we believe do we believe all the
[ __ ] that you told us for many many
years or do we believe your new [ __ ]
soon as we start believing the new
[ __ ] from the person that used to be
like ex-military then we're crazy right
along with him you know what I'm saying
they just label us as that they do you
know I don't know if you guys heard the
air quotations but they were there so H
whatever um man that's just crazy I hope
orgegon gets it going because they you
guys got so much talent I mean I've only
seen from social media and stuff like
that but I've seen people up that way
just you're right between two meccas you
know like there's you can't go wrong
you'll be the perfect
blind um and I you got many respectable
people up there already uh under medical
uh
coma um I think coma may have moved wow
but yeah it this is for wck weed also so
let's get the wck weed going on it
doesn't always have to be
medical all right let's wrap up this
show bro we've been going for a long
time it sounds like we're going to go
get some dank food over at the mate
Factor cheese
[Music]
sand all right um I wrote down some
shout outs and people we want to follow
make sure you follow I'll say it again
make sure you follow igro culture on
Twitter and Instagram follow overgrowth
goov on Twitter and Instagram follow iy
genetics on Twitter and Instagram uh big
shout out to the Mystic Roots band for
letting me play their music uh I think
that's all I got for a shout out
today um yeah all right we'll do this
part now that the show is over please go
to iTunes go to the iTunes Store search
for igro culture find the review section
give me a festar rating after that type
in a comment and let me know what you
think of the show and I will read your
comments on a future episode I'm not
joking if you guys leave comments I will
read them I like it I like the input um
like I said follow us on social media
Instagram Twitter and Facebook uh you
can email me if you'd like it's I GR
culture hotmail.com don't forget that
the show is available on iTunes Stitcher
and every single episode is archived
Forever on iy genetics
colorado.com big shout out to my ninja
Spence thanks again to everybody that
listened to the show take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me here comes
some Mystic Roots band
sweet
Andia bur in the
night sweet Amia yeah going to make feel
right sweet
Andia burn it in the
night
sweet going to make you feel right
I remember the
day J showed me the
way I REM
meditation it is the only
way so don't you abuse it yeah it's
resources is a
must just build a
split and pass it to us
yeah bur in the night