welcome back cannabis community it's
time for episode 320 of the girl from
your heart podcast this episode is
brought to you by our friends at the
hella dank seed company if you need new
seeds for your garden I highly recommend
the hella dank seed company and you can
find them at dank seed dot store also
make sure you check out our friends at
pol grow systems you can find them at PL
grow dot systems ladies and gentlemen
first off let me apologize for my
terrible sounding voice our friend Brett
also known as Mary's motivation I had a
going-away party and I went to that
going-away party and I smoked way too
much flour and way too much concentrate
and my voice sounds like crap I got a
little bit of a chest cold
I got a throat thing going on I got a
sinus thing happening and before we get
too far I just want to apologize and I
want to thank you for listening to this
episode while I sound like poop all
right I'd like to start the episode off
by letting you know what I'm smoking on
today I'm taking little baby dabs of
gorilla glue for ambrosia and also I've
got some of the New York City Beisel
ambrosia batter both from apothecary
it's been a nice mix fiscal and light
today just trying to stay lightly
medicated and not mess up my lungs and
throat again I'm on the path to recovery
and I want to keep moving forward so a
minute ago I mentioned that I went to my
friend Brett also known as Mary's
motivation I went to Brett's going away
party Brett is leaving the country
Brett's a little scared and nervous
about his trip but honestly I don't
think anybody deserves this more Brett
needs to make this adventure happen I
think it's going to be a great
experience for him so I'm super proud
and super excited for him his party was
awesome
at the party we were joined by of course
the always awesome Brett was there
dabbing granny and and Kevin showed up
also Lucy mama bear dabs is there always
good to see Lucy I got to bump into my
friend twisty seeds who I don't see very
often I got to have a conversation a
long conversation with Chandler dabbing
that was pretty cool Earle tycoon was
there
the dude from hits on hand was there LJ
fresh was there and several other new
and old friends were there hanging out
it was a great party there were a couple
of folks there who brought Koenig ours
which are basically blunts rolled with
cannabis leaves as the wrapper that
really [ __ ] up my lungs you guys my
lungs
not like that at all they were delicious
to smoke and we got really lit but that
is why I think I sound like crap today
so shout out to Bret for the great party
the party was a private party so not a
lot of people were invited the event was
at cultivated synergy I owe a huge shout
out to everybody at cultivated synergy
every time we do an event there every
time we do a large or small party there
it goes very well the place is very
inviting the staff is very accommodating
and I always have a great time so big
shout out to everybody who came to the
party extra huge shout out to Bret for
inviting me who was only able to invite
30 people I was honored to be amongst
those 30 it was a great party you guys
we smoked that place out for how few
people there were in there there's a
pretty big building and we smoked that
[ __ ] out pretty good you can hear to my
voice still alright well I've still got
some good voice left let's do a quick
podcast about flushing your plants
before harvest before we talk about
flushing I should do a quick recap in
the last episode I talked about
determining ripeness Mike and I went
fairly fast and we got kinda rambly so I
hope I made it clear that determining
ripeness is usually done by using some
sort of a loop so that you can see the
trichomes I mentioned using a 60 or 100x
loop one of our friends from Instagram
what's up dank Sinatra our friend dank
Sinatra i sheer photo and seeds sent me
a message and he says now I can't see
try comes with my naked eye but I can
tell ripeness of a trichome with a 16x
jeweler's loupe they said of course in
my mind I'm in my mid 20s so my eyes may
work a little better yes dude you are a
little bit younger than me you got those
fresh new eyes but he corrected me he
says he can see the trichomes with the
16x jeweler's loupe so you may not need
that bigger loop that 60 that 100 he
says the 60 is working or the 16 is
working for him so I stand corrected you
may not need that big loop 16 may get
you through also let's recap a little
bit about what I said about harvest
times I said that if you have a plant
that is said to go 60 days let it go the
full 60 days and start flushing at day
50 if you've got a plant that's supposed
to go 70 days let it go the full 7
days and start flushing around day 60
now you may say Rasta Jeff I want to
dial it in and cut these plants down at
the perfect ripeness yes you're going to
have to dial that in something I wanted
to stress is this is not your last grow
with this strain hopefully this is your
first run with this cultivar with this
cut so now you've got a new girlfriend
that you've got to learn a little bit
you've got to take her out a couple of
times you got to see if she wants to
come down at day 60 day 63 maybe day 67
maybe day 72 you've got to dial it in
exactly to the right day now you're
gonna see differences if you use
different nutrients you may get
different ripening dates if you have a
little bit of temperature difference you
may get a different ripening day so
you're gonna have to find the window and
dial that in hopefully this is not your
last girl with this cut hopefully this
is the first of many grows with a good
cut so if it's your first run with the
60-day cut start flushing around day 50
if this is your first time with a cut
that you think may go 70 days start
flushing it around day 60 now when you
get to day 60 or day 70 on whichever
plant you're running you don't have to
cut it down just because you've been
flushing for ten days start paying more
attention to the trichomes if they are
not amber don't cut it down keep
flushing for a few more days it's better
to over flush then under flush the only
thing you're doing is not giving it
nutrients it may have gotten a little
bigger it may have gotten a little
beefier but we're just trying to figure
out the plant for the first time so that
is how to determine when to begin flush
if you don't know the cultivar that
you're using maybe it's a brand new seed
maybe it's a new clone maybe you're just
new at growing and you don't know when
to cut it allowing the plant 60 to 70
days to grow and then giving yourself
extra time at the end is always your
best bet with a new cut alright so I
feel like I have established how to tell
if the plant is ripe and ready to cut
down and I feel like we have a good idea
of when to start flushing let's actually
talk about flushing our cannabis plants
I think flushing is super simple and
it's something people could easily
improve and they are really skipping
that step and I'm not sure why because
it's free it's a really easy step to
improve your cannabis and it is free
maybe people simply don't understand the
importance of flushing and why it's
important so let me tell you quickly why
flushing matters just imagine you've
been pouring salty nutrients into this
plant for nine weeks of flower plus
another three or four weeks of veg
you've just been filling it up with
nutrients
you've been pouring whatever nutrient
brand you're using even pouring nitrogen
you've been pouring phosphorus you've
been pouring potassium and you've been
pouring carbohydrates into these plants
for the past twelve weeks now all of
that stuff is built up inside of that
plant the plant is not using all of it
it's letting some of it go it's turning
some of it into a gas and transpiring
some of it out but some of it is still
in the plant
if those nutrients are left in the plant
when we harvest try and cure that plant
we're going to taste it the plants are
going to taste like crap if you feed too
much cal-mag too late in flower you're
going to taste it if you feed your
plants too much potassium silicon light
and flower you're going to taste it also
the plants are not going to burn
properly when you dry and cure these
buds they're not gonna smoke you're
gonna grind it up in a grinder you're
gonna roll a joint and it's just gonna
burn black and make a funky weird
charcoal that's because they're leftover
nutrients that you did not flush out we
can get that stuff out of there by
properly flushing the plants you were
mostly flushing the soil you want to
clean out the soil so there's nothing
left in your media but whether it's soil
soilless mix if you got peat whatever
you're working in you're gonna want to
flush that if it's rock wool if it's
cocoa you need to clean it out each
thing is going to take a different
amount of time to clean out but you want
to clean that out so the roots don't
have anything to eat then the plant will
start starving itself and it will start
showing as harvest fall colors and it
will taste proper when you dry it cure
it and smoke it so that's why flushing
is important you want to get all those
excess nutrients out of there all those
excess salts when you roll a joint and
smoke it you don't want it to turn into
a little briquette you want it to turn
into a nice white fluffy ash and just
flake away so that comes from a properly
flushed plant then that also comes from
a properly dried cure to trim to plant
but that comes and the
future today we're focusing on flushing
so that's why flushing is important you
guys you want your herb to taste good
you want it to burn well and you wanted
to leave a nice white clean soft - with
no weird chunks so let's actually talk
about flushing the plants flushing the
plants is really easy about 10 to 14
days before you plan on harvesting the
plants prepare the amount of water that
you would normally water the garden with
if you've got 1,000 watt light maybe
you've got a five-gallon bucket full of
water right so get that amount of water
ready when you would normally put
nutrients into the water don't do that
just don't put nutrients in there maybe
if you're gonna add anything put some
enzymes in there if you're using an
enzyme that will help break down all the
the decaying roots and all the matter
inside of the root zone and it will
speed up the process of the flush it
will help speed everything up but
enzymes are pretty much the only thing I
would put in there other than maybe a
little bit of shine maybe one to two
grams of shine from veg bloom but you
really don't need it
mostly all you would need is some
enzymes for the last couple of days if
you're gonna flush for 14 days maybe go
for like 4 to 7 days add 2 grams of
shine and add some enzymes but then cut
out the shine and just keep the enzymes
going until the end of the process so
the only thing you'd put in there are
enzymes and possibly some shine but you
would be probably just fine with nothing
at all so clean water add the enzymes if
you're gonna do so for four to seven
days add the shine if you'd like to do
so then adjust the pH to somewhere
between 63 and 65 you'll be just fine 63
and 65 that's a good window to adjust it
to then simply water the plants with
that minimal solution all you've got to
do is pour that right into the plants
just like you normally do any water soak
the plants and let it run through now
what you're doing pouring the enzymes in
there is going to help the natural
decaying process happen inside that root
zone there's dead things in there the
roots that are dying are dying in there
the enzymes are gonna eat that and
they're gonna speed up that process also
that shine is going to keep adding
density and trichomes and essential oils
to your plants if you choose to add the
shine you still need to flush for the
last week without the shine you guys so
make sure you cut that out
you can leave the enzymes in there if
you'd like to at the end but cut out
that shine for the last week now you're
probably at day 50 right if we're gonna
cut down at day 60 we're at day 50 we
just mixed up a bunch of water and we
just soaked that root zone so now you've
got pH D water with enzymes and possibly
some shine running through there those
plants are gonna start looking for
phosphorous and potassium and molybdenum
and all the other things that they want
there are 16 minerals that the plants
really want you guys start thinking
about that and learn all 16 of them that
will really help you think about what
you're feeding your plant maybe we'll
talk about that in the future but the
plants gonna start looking for that
stuff and all it's gonna find our
enzymes and shine it's gonna be like
well I've got essential oils I'm gonna
go beef up my trichomes and it's got
stuff to build trichomes but it doesn't
have the building blocks to grow more
plant material it doesn't have all the
nutrition that it needs to keep building
bigger buds and fatter stems and going
so it's gonna start showing you its fall
colors it's gonna start turning into B's
yellow golden colors you may get some
reds you may get some purples you'll get
some unique oranges I really like taking
pictures of my plants right right at the
flush phase because they really start
showing great colors the buds are nice
and fat the trichomes are all greasy and
shiny and then the leaves start getting
these cool golden tones to them but
that's when you know that the flush is
working there are no nutrients left in
that soil for the plant to eat and it is
getting hungry which is a good thing
because now you know that bud is gonna
burn smoothly it's not gonna have
nitrogen phosphorus potassium believed
in them iron calcium magnesium it's not
gonna have all this other funky [ __ ] in
it that we don't want to smoke it's just
gonna be nice and clean it'll burn nice
and smoothly and it will taste really
good so you're gonna start seeing these
fall colors come on that timing is going
to depend on your medium how much
nutrients you have been putting into the
plant it's gonna be very strained
specific and also temperatures are going
to have a huge effect on this if it's a
little cooler in the room your plants
are gonna turn a little more fall colors
if you have a lower nighttime
temperature you'll see a little more
purple from the buds you'll get a little
more fall activity from the plants like
what happened in nature so you're gonna
mix up the solution you're gonna pH it
you're gonna water in the plants it's
gonna run out of the bottom then
depending on your container size and the
vapor pressure deficit in the room you
were going to have to water again repeat
the process you guys makes up your
container put the enzymes in there put
the shine in there pH adjust it to six
point three to six point five and water
it right through the plants repeat this
process right up to a week before
harvest and then do the same thing but
simply take out the shine add the
enzymes adjust the pH and then feed it
right through the plants now the enzymes
are totally not necessary
the shine is totally not necessary you
can do all of this with plain water if
you're adding the enzymes and shine you
were going to have connoisseur quality
cannabis that's what I would do I would
do the shine up to the last week then
after that I would just do the enzymes
and then I'd probably do just two or
three days of playing water just to give
him time to finish up there if I was
going at 60 days I would end up going 63
in that last three days would just be
playing water and my grow is what would
happen there so just keep repeating the
process you want to rinse these plants
out do you want to rinse the soil out as
many times as you can between the
starter flush and harvest so if you can
get it to dry up and re water it every
other day that's great if it takes three
or four days that's fine you're still
going to get oh if you do it 12 days you
get three waterings in there if you go
every four days but if you're taking
that much time to water that means
you've got a large container or that
much time between waterings means you've
got a large container which means you're
using quite a bit of water to flush that
out which means you need to make sure to
get at least like 10 to 30% runoff water
so if you got like a 10 gallon pot
you're gonna want to get at least one to
2 gallons of runoff coming out of that
that's how you know you're flushing well
so get plenty of water coming out and
then flush the [ __ ] out of those plants
I do it as many times as you can but be
careful not to drown the plant don't try
to sneak in another flush time just to
get more water in there because that may
do more harm than good that may you may
kill the [ __ ] plant right there you
may just drown it you may suffocate it
that may be the end you may be cut down
early so don't ruin it right at the end
be careful to stay on your normal
watering schedule just make sure you
soak the [ __ ] out of it let it dry out
water it again do that as many times as
you can
in the last 10 to 14 days and if you
want to add the enzymes do that you want
to use shine do that those are the only
things I would really add at the end so
we have determined how to tell if the
plants are ripe we have determined a
good time to start flushing we know what
to put in the water to flush the plants
we know why we're flushing we know how
to flush you basically don't mix
anything up and you run that through the
plants this will clean out the soil that
is our main goal as that's happening
we're gonna see colors changing we're
gonna see trichomes ripening we're gonna
see plants finishing up now you're gonna
get a bunch of funky you may I'm not
promising it depends on your genetics
your environment it depends on a lot of
things you're going to get funky yellow
leaves you're gonna get dead foliage
pull that stuff off there's no problem
with just yanking that dead stuff off
make sure you throw it away get it out
of the grow room but just pull all that
dead stuff off and throw it away now
about a week maybe five or three days
before you harvest go in the grow room
and to start stripping off all the big
leaves this is going to save you a lot
of time when it does come time to
harvest there won't be all these big
giant leaves in your way just cut them
off while the plant is standing up while
they're still stiff while they're still
alive you can just snap them right off
pop-pop-pop-pop you can go really fast
you don't even need scissors for it once
you get the thumb technique to just pop
in a leaf off you can just go in there
and defoliate a whole section really
quickly so a few days before harvest go
in there and pull off all those big
leaves and that will save you a big
headache and a bunch of time when it
comes time to harvest the plants you
hang them upside down drive and cured
when it comes time to trim half the
leaves are already gone it will save you
a lot of [ __ ] and a lot of trouble
so what do you see them starting to get
funky take off the dead ones then just a
few days before harvest probably when
you'd cut out the shine maybe then go in
there and start pulling off the leaves
now another thing you might want to do
is you might want to reduce the
temperature just a few degrees do not
create a large swingin temps between
your day and night
do not go too cold at night do not try
to create something drastic if you can
bring it down two or three degrees
during the day and two or three degrees
during the night do that but don't go
crazy you guys don't shock the plants
right at the end don't give yourself
powdery mildew right at the end just try
to mimic nature and get a little bit
colder right at the end because what
happens right at the end of the season
it gets cold that's how things know oh
[ __ ] it's wintertime and those plants
will hurry up and finish so you'll see
more color you may get a little more
density and cool temps are good for
terpenes so lower the temperatures a
little bit right at the end now one
thing I'm sure people are going to send
me messages about and ask is do I use
any flushing agents no I do not use a
flushing agent I think all of the
flushing agents are kind of a sales
tactic they are not necessary and I
think they make your herb taste like
whatever they taste like it's the very
end why would I want to put in a new
ingredient I want to get everything out
so I do not use a flushing agent if I
were to use anything I would just use
the the solution I told you the enzymes
and the shine and then I would add
powdered coconut water would be the only
flushing solution that I would use and a
lot of people are saying what yeah
coconut water would be ideal but that
would get very expensive to buy it have
that much coconut water imagine trying
to get a five gallon bucket of coconut
water shipped to your house every three
days for 14 days that's gonna add up
it's gonna get real expensive but you
can buy powdered coconut water it is
readily available from a lot of gross
stores bill the soil can take good care
of you
they do not sponsor the show or anything
but I know that that's a reliable source
for powdered coconut water also
something I should mention um a lot of
people are growing no-till a lot of
people are growing in living soil or
super soil or some sort of live soil you
guys if that is what you're working with
you probably do not need to flush
because you have created the perfect
environment inside your plants rise of a
spirit or it's taking up what it needs
you're not feeding it bottled nutrients
it's not being force-fed [ __ ] so it
doesn't need to be flushed anything our
buddies some cool when he would mix up a
batch of super soil and put a plant in
there he would just beat it water for
the whole flowering phase and he would
say I've been
flushing the entire time so before
people start sending me emails yes there
are some situations where you may not
need to flush if you were going no-till
if you're going all organic flushing is
not a thing now if you're running that
you're already up to speed and you know
that we don't need to teach you about
flushing you were in the advanced
blackbelt class already I've got one
more thing I should mention before I
wrap up this so-called quicky episode
that's gone on for 20 minutes you guys
are very welcome thank you for listening
um a good thing to do is to measure the
EC or the ppm of your runoff water you
are pouring a bunch of water into your
plants right collect it collect the
water that comes out of the bottom of
your plant into some sort of a vessel
put your pH pen in there put your EC or
ppm pen in there and see what the EC is
now if you're in a soil or a soilless
mix you're only gonna get down so low if
you're in cocoa you can get those PPM's
down really really low see how low you
can get it maybe before you start
flushing that day the first day you
flush measure what comes out then
measure each time and see how low you
can get it and then just keep
experimenting see how low it goes every
day and see how low you can get the ppm
s I don't want to give any
recommendations on how low to try and
get it because it's going to vary based
on your medium and I don't want to [ __ ]
up your Gro you're going to have to
learn this based on your grow cocoa
you'll get it really low because cocoa
is inert cocoa is not gonna hold [ __ ]
same thing with rockwool you'll be able
to get the PPM's of your rock wall and
your cocoa down to amazingly low levels
soil soilless mixes those are still
gonna have some high ppm s because they
are soil and soilless mixes there's just
a lot of [ __ ] in there but play with
your runoff pay attention to that see
how low you can get it and it'll be a
lot of fun it'll be a fun experiment and
then you'll actually see what's going in
and what's coming out of your plants
maybe we should just talk about
measuring runoff anyway in a full
episode we'll talk about checking the EC
or the PPM's of a solution before you
pour it into your plants and then we'll
remesh
that same solution the EC or the P P PMS
when it comes out of the bottom of your
plants and we'll compare that to the pH
going in and the pH coming out and we'll
see what's happening in your rhizosphere
anyway that's a future episode I'm just
getting excited you guys measure the
electrical conductivity or the particles
million of what's coming out of your
plant and you will know if you need to
flush more or not and then when you cut
it down right down the ppm s and then
pay attention and then if you are
satisfied hit that number next time and
if you're not satisfied maybe flush a
little longer and try to go lower but
they'll be discouraged because it's not
all about the flush you still have dry
and cure to [ __ ] this up you could ruin
your whole crop after you cut it down so
ladies and gentlemen I want to thank you
for listening to my flushing episode so
so far we have done determining ripeness
determining when to flush we have talked
about flushing I think the next episode
in line is harvesting and then after
that we're going to do the dry and pure
episodes there will be some
interruptions to that schedule because
I've got an episode scheduled with some
friends and things always pop up but
those are on the chart to come up in
order ladies and gentlemen I appreciate
you for listening to my podcast thanks
for letting me ramble for so long if you
felt like this podcast was educational
and you learned something and he would
like to contribute to the podcast
financially I would truly appreciate the
support and you can do so by going to
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
and all of the information that you need
to sign up will be right there
it is really simple and I would
appreciate the support I'm not begging
for payments or contributions or
anything I will do this podcast forever
for free I'm really not trying to get
rich off of podcasting but there are a
few people who said they would like to
contribute to the podcast I like to make
sure there is an opportunity for that it
is patreon.com slash grow from your
heart what I will do with those funds is
I will pay for my website you guys I
host this podcast on my website it costs
a little bit of money to do that every
year
also I purchased a better MacBook so
that I can record more efficiently my
old computer was not efficient as the
polite way to say it but the
contributions will help to go pay for
the MacBook that I bought and also cover
the cost of the website also you may
have heard Mike mentioned that the
little microphone cover needed a
replacement I use the funding for things
like that so if you'd like to contribute
I would appreciate it I will quit
begging because that got uncomfortable
quite quickly ladies and gentleman I
would love it if you would stalk me on
all of the social media that is free all
you got to do is click around find me on
Facebook simply search for the girl from
our podcast you can find me on twitter
it's at g f YH podcast you can find my
personal
count if you're interested in trolling
me I am a Rasta Jeff 420 on Twitter also
you should check me out on Instagram my
an IRA underscore genetics on Instagram
I like to do live feeds where I go on
Instagram live and I hang out take a
couple of dads and then I take questions
from the Instagram live feed and I will
rant about your question and teach you
how to grow cannabis right there on the
spot I think it's fun because there's no
notes there's no preparation today
somebody asked me a fairly in-depth
question and I had to stare into the sky
and roll my eyes for about two minutes
and try to board out the reply I was
trying to give them because I wasn't
prepared and it's really a lot of fun
for me it's kind of like it's like a
game of stuff the grower or stuff the
breeder or something like that and I
really find it it's good for my brain it
keeps my brain going it keeps my Grove
knowledge on the tip of my tongue and it
keeps my brain active you guys know that
I had a brain injury a few years ago so
I like to do things to keep my brain
going the right direction anyway I'm
[ __ ] ranting today you guys who needs
a quick episode right find me on
Instagram I think you would enjoy my
Instagram my videos also why wouldn't
you want to check out some dope as
cannabis photography go check it out
also you guys one more thing YouTube
I've got all of the videos up on YouTube
you can find every episode of the
growing art podcast on YouTube now
hopefully we're able to get a larger
audience we can reach more people we can
teach more people how to grow better
cannabis we can dispel more myths we can
educate more people by having another
platform so make sure you support the
YouTube channel go click Subscribe go
like some videos to leave some silly
comments I would appreciate the support
because I think that's all I've got for
you today this was a super rambling
episode I wanna thank you guys for
hanging out with me I want to thank you
again for tolerating my raspy crappy
voice I feel like I talked it right out
by the end of episode I finally sound
pretty decent now that the show is over
so thanks for tolerating that at the
start of the show you guys I'll be back
Monday with a fresh new episode I want
to give a huge shout out to my friend
Texan toker
and until next time take a phat dad and
give your mom a hug for me
you