welcome back cannabis community it's
time for episode 323 of the girl from
your heart podcast your a source for
cannabis news education and conversation
I try to put a new grower if you're a
professional grower if you're a new
smoker or a dedicated dabber if you're a
cannabis activists or even someone who's
just curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you I'm your host my friends call me
Rasta Jeff wanna thank you guys again
for joining me this episode of the
podcast is brought to you by my friends
at the hella dank seed company if you
need new seeds for your garden look no
further than the hella dank seed company
you can find them at dank seed dot store
this episode of the podcast has also
brought to you by my friends at pol grow
systems a responsible gardener knows
what's happening in his grow room at all
times and you can monitor your
temperature and your humidity from
anywhere with the new minder unit from
our friends at pol grow systems you can
find them at pol grow dot systems ladies
and gentlemen this is a very special
Thursday episode of the podcast I've got
my friends Peter and lien from PNL grow
systems joining me on skype and we're
gonna talk about the PL grow systems
units and then we're gonna get a little
bit chatty there were a couple of
moments I had to edit because Skype was
getting choppy but for the most part I
think the show sounds pretty good so
ladies and gentlemen let's get right to
it live on skype here are my friends
Peter and Leigh from piano grow systems
well gentlemen welcome I have press
record I've got you guys on the show so
welcome to the show Peter and Lee from
PNL grow systems thanks for joining me
guys so can you tell us exactly where
you guys are from because when I first
met you I advertised that you were from
Australia and I've been corrected yeah
especially singers I'm originally from
South Africa being a link to an
Australian yeah fair enough it's a right
hemisphere wrong country but originally
from South Africa now living in in
England being here for 20 plus years for
my sins and I'm originally from the home
of Durban poisons beautiful
and I'm in London I've been there for a
good ten years now love the city I've
heard a lot of great things but I have
never been visit well now I've got
somewhere to stay
so I'll come see you guys all right so
of course you guys are that way
absolutely you have got space well
obviously Peter and Leigh are PNL from
P&amp;L growth systems would you guys like
to take a minute and tell me about how
you got into this idea of creating the
pl grow systems product products did I
lose you
something may have gone wrong okay so I
think where I was I was just gonna give
you guys an opportunity to tell me about
the company since you guys are obviously
Peter and Lee of P&amp;L bro systems would
you like to tell me a little bit about
how PNL came about and what inspired you
to create this company having the same
problem that if you wanted to take a
two-week holiday you'd come back to a
bunch of dead plants either in your
greenhouse or your grow space and really
we went and had a look in the market to
go and see you know what was out there
that would allow us to keep an eye on it
and remotely control it and there was
nothing within our price bracket that's
for sure you know there's some really
expensive kit out there that can do it
for you and whether you can even remote
into them is optional and usually would
require quite a bit of reconfiguring
your home or your rooters and firewalls
to let traffic in so the technologists
we just added like there's got to be a
cheaper way an easier way of doing this
and started building systems for
ourselves we started off with some early
prototypes that when we started posting
pictures of them people took interest
and it was after slowly building up and
showing what it could do and controlling
our own setup that interest grew and
grew and grew and we'd said they realize
you know we've solved the problem for
ourselves this
to make it really easy to get up and
running and able to access it from it
anywhere in the world and other people
are interested it and to be honest
that's really how you know the company
came about we solved the problem and
really there were others that one is the
same solution at an affordable price the
one thing about it was this the remote
access and making it easy to set up and
we've both got decades of IT support and
within the financial world okay and so
trying to make this thing as easy as
possible to reduce the number of support
calls I've made the fatal mistake of
offering my father IT support in the
past and so yeah I'm trying to make
things as simple as possible to to keep
the number of calls to a minimum is is
part of what we try to do you know if
it's not simple then we realize there's
going to be a problem for a lot of
people you know not everybody is a
techie that is absolutely the truth so
that's key to what we do I mean our
devices you literally you connect them
to your Wi-Fi network that's it you
don't have to configure anything else
everything happens super simply through
the website that's one of my favorite
parts about it is the simplicity and
also that I didn't have to add anything
to my computer system everything I need
is happening for me yeah the best part
then you can access it from anywhere
yes that's my favorite part that I can
see my grow at home while I am at work I
don't have to drive home and check on
anything it is completely simple that's
my favorite part is that I don't have to
come here to look at the plants I could
just check right on the phone I can look
at the cameras on one app I can look at
the minder on the other app and I know
everything is safe that's my favorite
part and the simplicity the other units
I've tried to use I've had problems and
this one I plugged it in and it works so
I think that is amazing
yeah and then we've tried to keep it
nice and modular as well so you know the
first unit that we've brought out is the
one with the sensors with ambient
temperature and humidity and another
temperature sensor that's waterproof
that you can drop into your your
reservoir for instance or you can put
into your grow medium I was using it out
in the greenhouse to check that the soil
temperature was up to the right
temperature before planting the Chili's
in the greenhouse prevent breach shock
for instance yeah and then because it's
modular and you know you tend to find
that most people's just want temperature
and humidity co2 is a nice to have but
only really if you're running in a
sealed environment and your average home
enthusiast and home grower is not
necessarily doing co2 enriched
environments so we can well we are we do
have a co2 sensor coming out there is
another modular piece that you just add
it it's not you don't have to change
anything and your setup you don't have
to buy a whole new piece of kit do this
well we just need to buy the sensor but
you don't have to upgrade anything
software wise or anything like that
which is great for people who just want
to add something later so if maybe they
can't afford the system right at the
beginning they can add on instead of
having to invest in the high priced unit
right away so that's a great great
addition there is accessible to
everybody as possible really
is there a vapor pressure deficit
reading available I mean we do that as a
calculation we so on the on the website
one of the outputs that you get which is
calculated on the fly is the VPD
readings excellent and that you can then
look at for free what we give to
everybody that comes with each unit when
you buy it you get free access to your
current readings and then 2 hours 4
hours 6 12 24 48 and 7 days worth of
historical data charted so you can look
at over time what's actually going on in
the environment and we take a reading
every 30 seconds so it's fairly granular
as to what's going on in the environment
you can see if somebody's open the door
and closed it again yes because you'll
see temperature spikes up and down you
can see when the fan came on page if you
pay enough attention you can see when a
big fan kicks on we've had a number of
clients who've actually said that being
able to see that has one of them
identified that the fan had sucked some
plastic up because they knew the fan was
supposed to be on and they couldn't see
the temperature drop so they went to see
what was wrong with the fan and others
have realized oh hang on I haven't
turned the heater on yes I can see when
he was supposed particular
can suddenly they don't see the
temperature actually coming up I
actually had an air there the other
interesting oh I had an everything I had
an air conditioner fail and I would not
have known without the minder unit I
checked to see what the temp was and it
was really high in there so I knew
something's wrong I need to get over
there and if I hadn't looked I wasn't
coming home from work for another four
or five hours and four or five hours at
that temperature I would have not had a
crop so it was worth the investment
already that's something that people
don't mean you know when we come to an
to sort of the whole environment control
node and monitoring of the environment
we listen to lots of podcasts and they
often talk about all the nutrients and
the lighting and all of that which is
all good and well but if the environment
is off it doesn't matter how good the
lighting is how good the nutrients are
if it's there forty five degrees
centigrade and ten percent humidity
everything's dead absolutely absolutely
growing cacti it's it's not surviving
there and the problem with your
run-of-the-mill hygrometer is that it
gives you the maximum temperature that
it was at and the minimum temperature
rosette with no indication as to how
long you were at the maximum and the
minimum temperature was it just a blip
were you there for 10 minutes or was it
four hours and so you know that's the
extra information that we provide and it
gives people their real insight into
what's actually going on I've noticed
that most of the swings happen right
when the lights go on or right when the
lights go off within the next hour is
when things really go different and
you're never there for that time you
don't know what's happening in that
grill room when those lights go off for
that hour it's really neat to find out
what happens with your lights your
temperature your humidity your vapor
pressure deficit in that our swing
that's the most interesting part in my
opinion so it's really neat to get
something like this and be able to chart
what's happening and then you can start
to do things like plan to actually have
fans
come on 15 minutes before the lights
come on just sort of reduce that as the
lights kick in and give everything an
opportunity to start up if I'm allowed
to come on and the same of the lights go
off you can actually stop things
expecting 10 minutes before if you're
running an already small
bass where if it carries on extracting
after the lights have gone off it cools
down too quickly so you might say well
before just before the lights turn off
turn the fans off and we'll stop
extracting than just a channels of
ambient cooling that happens and reduce
that drop off so you've already
mentioned several ways that these things
are going to improve our Gardens I've
already mentioned one great way I bet
getting into the states has been a huge
job for you guys well precisely I mean
that's where we see there being a really
big market and and that's you know it's
not kid ourselves you know if you look
at it as the as the gold rush equivalent
as it has been named that you know the
green rush absolutely during that time
everybody all the gold miners had to
have mining equipment whether they were
successful or not at the end of the day
that's the reality and you know this is
missing equipment that gives somebody
the edge in the green rush it allows you
to be able to have a much finer view and
control of the environment and with that
market there the fact is is that all the
homie growers and they're all missing
out they can go and spend three four
thousand which is really pricing them
out of the market for a you know an
equivalent ish system ours comes in at
just alright to do the exchange rate
conversion well our basic our entry unit
the mind oh it doesn't have a screen on
it which is ideal for like large but for
really small home users as well as all
the way through to large growth faces
that need to have lots of sensors
hanging and you don't want to screen on
all of them that these are just small
units got sensors hanging off them we
tell them 470 pounds
oh well that's affordable so that's what
about 120 dollars that's about 120 US
dollars so that's definitely affordable
yeah and if you can go ahead you know
and then you get all that data on the
website and we can we add analytics over
time I mean if we have enough customers
you say we'd like to see this we can
just add it to the website and everybody
gets it doesn't require applications or
software on people's phones etc to be
updated and that's what's beautiful
about it I have seen and the short time
I've been working with you guys I have
seen vast and
movements to the website it was a little
it was very new when I was introduced to
it and now it looks like a professional
website looks like one of the major
companies it looks like NASA now I think
it's really great yeah it's come a long
way since we first start thinking it has
heavy that started off
yeah the approach is the same as we've
done with the product range is it starts
off it has to do what it needs to do and
then worry about making it look pretty
afterwards
there you go home so you know that's the
first step is is making sure it is what
it is I think in this end does exactly
what it says on the tin and in this
industry too many people did that
backwards they tried to make it pretty
and then figure out how to make it work
yeah yeah Superman
pick a solution and then try and find a
problem for it yes that's the other well
you've told us about the the 70 pound
unit what's the other unit you've got
available for us we have is the mind a
plus and that has a screen on it and
that retails for 90 pounds so 50 dollars
I guess you're still very high that's
nice yeah and the nice thing about that
one is if you've got a sealed
environment for instance you can mount
it on the outside and then have the
leads running into into the environment
so you could have one on the outside but
you can see what's going on and then you
could hang a couple of the other minder
units without the screens within the
space if you wanted to monitor more or
areas now how were how many square feet
would you recommend I hang each unit how
far apart what I need them if I've got a
large room how many would I would you
recommend per square foot or so or I
guess you do a meter there I apologize
each sensor by its default I mean each
unit by default comes with two and a
half meter leads which is very Phoebe
yeah and we do them up to much longer
leads as well we do up to ten meters
which is about 30 okay so it really
comes down to how tight somebody wants
to be measuring it I guess each one
and I hang to me house that's three
meters wide but that's two of the
ambient ones and one it just each end of
the greenhouse a certain amount of
that's gonna refer depend on how much
airflow you've got moving around the the
room as well I mean I've got one in a
five meter by four meter area and that
gives me a relatively good a good
consistent reading so probably five
meters square would probably be good you
could possibly go a bit low but as I say
it depends on how much airflow you've
got going around the room as well that's
quite a large space to monitor that's uh
that's pretty impressive for one unit I
like that I expected less space yeah I
mean I would yeah so most home growers
are gonna be able would get away with
just one unit exactly I mean and I think
most the customer base does that is
excellent that's excellent I could
probably get away with one maybe two in
almost all of my larger grow rooms and
then what you can also do with them I
mean a little sort of a nice bit which
is probably more relevant to to the US
actually because you've got multiple
time zones which we don't have here is
you can actually set each device to be
in its own time zone so when you're
looking at the data you're actually
seeing it relevant to the local time oh
that's not telling to do a mental
calculations if you had grow facilities
if you were if you own you know multiple
facilities and you wanted to be actually
keep a nice centrally on what was going
on in each one of them locally in local
time we can Wheatley support there
straight away and then that's something
I haven't necessarily seen on others but
we hire a comedy comment emotion that's
a great feature sounds like when he has
a plane flying overhead indeed there's
plenty at h-hour
yeah and then the what these two perks
the mind and the mind of plus there are
entry level product and that's the ones
that we've gone to market with just
start but the real the crown jewel is is
the controller unit which allows you to
control
humidifiers dehumidifiers fans a CD
units heaters etc buy in response to
readings from the census so it comes
with four four sockets and we're close
to launching this in the UK and we've
have had a number of early adopters
you've taken this up and this is where
wheels for the US market and that's
where it gets really interesting is now
the ability to automate the controlling
of an environment so when the humidity
gets too low then it'll fire up my
humidifier and then when it gets to the
direct in turn that off and then if it
gets too high it'll put my dehumidifier
for me correct correct
excellent that's we can all use stuff
like that automation is key and mercial
grows yeah and again for the home girl
we're which is you know the target
market with the technology being able to
scale up in terms of what it can control
in size and magnitude yeah a a
dehumidifier a probably the states like
a $50 you know there's three new lyric
humidifiers that only turn on I mean
that's switch it on you tell it how fast
it needs to run and that's about the
only control you have over it you can't
tell it to cut off at different humidity
right if you want that you're spending
like $500 on a humidifier that will know
who to turn off at 75% humidity need for
example there's a huge price difference
in those systems but with ours this now
allow somebody to take their thirty or
fifty dollar humidifier and make it
perform like in terms of functionality
like a five hundred dollar humidifier
but I'll turn on and off only when it
needs to come on and all that's gonna be
helpful I do have a price point in mind
for that unit when it's ready
um in the UK we're looking at 400 pounds
for theft unit okay and that's worth it
that's it may sound like a high number
but for something that's going to turn
on and off my devices well worth the
price there that's more affordable than
a major controller from a lot of the
larger brands here
well that will that also be controlling
the lights and all of the HVAC yes you
can ever to control it'll operate it
operates as a standalone unit as well if
you just had it completely stand-alone
it is like an agricultural time at SRI
will do lights pumps it's when you then
link it to one or more of the minor
units that you get the additional
functionality of okay I understand
that's the humidity in that space and
that's connected to this plug is
connected to the humidifier that runs
over there I need to turn it on or turn
it off excellent this is gonna be a
great unit you guys I'm excited to get
one of these that's what we're looking
for we're looking for you know the
interest from the firm from the US
market there are from a purely from a
business perspective there are
opportunities to killya however there
are we looking to work with whoever we
can to make it happen these different
regulations in terms of electrical and
all sorts of fun funny games and I say
it's a great fun starting your own
business
oh I'm sure you get to amend it you get
to design a product and then master it
there and then before you send it to us
you have to redesign it because you have
to redo a few things I'm sure yeah and
there are 37 different plugs all around
the world so for me you're going for a
treaty global market you know when
that's 37 different plugs how far into
it were you before you realized 37 plugs
were the option at that point yes you
had to buy all 37 plugs to figure them
out that's great
well I appreciate the work you've put
into it you guys when do we when can we
expect the controller unit to be
available for the US market
if everything goes according to plan
over the next few months probably
looking towards Brad about early next
year okay but that's you know I would
much rather err on the side of caution
than know the optimistic
hey if any of the right investors who
happen to listen to this tell them since
you're plugging yourself Tom how they
can find you if they do want to reach
out at you well you can contact either
myself or Lee email addresses at pizza
at PL growth systems and it's Lee and
peel road systems also an Instagram it's
at heel growth systems and our website
is peel growth systems there you go guys
if there are any investors out there
looking to get into the business this is
a great opportunity and they could use
your support and I mean for the US
market in particular we've got some
particular interesting ideas to leverage
my and Lee's experience within the
finance world there are some interesting
things that can be done all of a sudden
with the US market it really it's
amazing I mean just speaking about that
looking at from over here there so it's
absolutely crazy to see what's going on
inspirational do you see any
legalization coming your way in your
guyses area I'm soon interesting mixed
bag because there's some economists is
saying within five years because of how
much the rest of the world is changing
and you know I don't know if it was
white Mike or guru and the do growth and
on the DG's he sure who said what first
accursed sales it's now exceeding
equivalent or exceeding cosmetic sales I
mean that's a big in this
yes that was that was minor when you
happen to the 50
I thought so when you up into the fifty
billion dollar market yeah the rest of
world starts to think maybe it's not so
evil maybe no it won't make you crazy
and actually no thought okay so I think
yeah I think it's interesting to see
with her talk that's honest we said the
same thing at the same time my friend
money does talk money's got the loudest
voice in the room every time when they
lose the tax on cigarettes I can't go
[ __ ] need to hear that somewhere else
yep and maybe that'll be your guys's way
in because I'm sure that when they
legalize cannabis and your area you will
be in every grow room because you're
already ahead of the game you know giant
veg bros who are using the system in
their outdoor in their allotments over
here there there's a whole interesting
market here too you know and you know
for anybody who is in the UK who is
interested in pecan technologies a
hydroponic shop up north they're
probably quite happy to speak about
their experience with us they were using
it in their lab at the moment where
we're working with and he said NPK
technologies yeah I'm gonna check them
out myself just because I'm very
interested in what you guys are doing
have a great podcast and and YouTube
channel they've had mammoth Keo and I
forget the guys name from mammoth key
remember my curves I should say or
they've had him on a number okay
and also go from great white there you
go guys another great podcast it's a
really good really good interesting
contrast to listen to me
we will check that out what I find when
we've spoken to investors here as soon
as you talk about the US market and the
analogy with the gold mine room and you
know
rush in the green rush and the goldmine
equipment suppliers and that's what
we're doing and we're in there you know
in scenaries support business we don't
touch the product at all you know we
don't process it we don't touch it it's
got nothing to do with that and what I'm
looking with you know to build into the
system going forward is ability for your
home be able to select distrained from a
database see what the previous flowering
time is and what the average uses
flowering time was they can select it
till the system that's what I'm growing
I'm starting it on this date I want you
to veg it for four weeks and then cut
over to flower to whichever the reader
or the flowering and average user flower
time for instance so you can really make
it easy for them in the system will do
that it will just do the lighting
schedule for you for instance and they
can set up their punch a jewel so where
the pumps are linked to the lighting
[ __ ] you'll so if you change the
lighting [ __ ] you'll someth
automatically address this you've said
never come on when the lights are off
Iran has changed 15 different pump
timers because you've changed you like
it right automatically updates itself
and follows it and that's gonna save a
grower time for a guy like myself who
has 25 fans to go change they've all
just adjusted themselves for me yeah
exactly that's gonna save me time yeah
you're talking about
VPD well yeah that's the other bit that
comes into play is as the lights go over
all the temperature comes down humidity
goes up VPD you know plummets for
instance and again if your humidifier
even a $500 humidifier
I guess 500 humidifier it doesn't know
that when the lights go off it needs to
drop to 50% humidity just as an example
from 75 to 50 when the lights are on you
need to keep it up here because of the
increase in temperature and the like to
get one of a feeling to drop it because
of the decrease in temperature again
that's something man Wow yeah this is
software that we're working on that's
what it sells for the controller
the idea is be able to tell that I won
for the first five weeks that eligio
eight and for the next ten weeks VP of
sixteen and the system just takes care
of it for you in terms of monitoring
temperature and humidity that's pretty
impressive that's gonna save me a lot of
time a lot of energy a lot of questions
I can go in before the flowering cycle I
can set up what I need and then I can
just know that it's all gonna happen for
me I don't have to ask one of the grow
Tech's to make sure to turn something
down or turn something off that's gonna
prevent a lot of error because humans
make mistakes hopefully we've taken that
out of the computers and they're not
going to make those mistakes so this is
one of the other things that we've
implemented as well is that you can set
an alert so that way if your temperature
does go above a particular level you may
be see goes from above a ticket
particular level you'll get an email
that tells you that it's high so you've
got chance to go and intervene and
you'll get one of them at the moment
every 15 minutes so that where you get
reminded that there's a problem you've
got a chance to go fix it before any
damage gets done my way can get in the
car and drive right over there and
unplug those lights before they roast my
plants exactly I love it or you can tell
I mean better still really what you can
do is you can just you should just go to
the website and tell the controller to
turn the lights off you didn't have to
get in the car
letting someone stay where that's a
standard feature you get with the minder
as well each of the minders other than
just recording your data you can also
set your maximum and minimum temperature
and humidity and you'll get emails if it
breaches either of them that is
excellent so I don't even have to drive
I can just say turn that off until I can
finish recording and then I'll go over
there and fix that absolutely I
appreciate that you know for the you
know from a shops perspective what's
kind of nice is somebody can walk in and
they've got a problem with the growth at
home they can walk into the shop and
they can actually show the guy behind
the counter the data that they're always
asking for you know what's your
temperature and humidity being for the
last week and now they can show them so
instead of just you know standing there
looking at the guy gone missing like I
don't know
hot and not very humid you know not not
very accurate they can actually show
them that they can get a far better
analysis of what may be wrong it's been
from the consumers point of view spend
less money on trying to solve the
problem because we get it right the
first time and maybe reputationally
wires from the shops perspective is that
they're giving the right advice first
part yes so the product the products are
available online if people want to go
look for them
they can find you at Pio grow systems is
that correct peel grow dot systems all
right so that's where the the minder the
minder plus and coming soon the
controller unit will be available right
all right no the pressure is on you guys
cuz I just told everybody but that
controller unit is coming so you guys
got to get in the the workshop there and
stir soldering but we have a number of
early adopters you've been running it
and are running it at the moment
and to help us make sure that we're
going down the right line with it from
everything I have seen you guys are
going down the right line the
improvements on the website have been
amazing the upgrade to the the second
system that you sent me was obvious the
minute it came out of the box the second
one was much more sturdy so I can see
that you guys are improving every time
we do business together so it's
noticeable already thank you
yes sir gentlemen it feels like we have
oh it sounds like you've got something
go ahead let's hear it oh thanks for
joining me thanks for taking some time
out of your day to be on the show with
me ah it feels like we've covered all of
the business part of the podcast and of
the interview I don't like to call it an
interview it's more like hanging out
with my friends is there anything that
you guys would like to say while you
were on the podcast anything you'd like
to put out there while you've got a
microphone on you
I mean I would just like to you know say
that big thanks to everybody who has
actually helped us so far it's not just
a a case of hard work and what and
dedication to it but it's also loyal
clients and fans who've helped support
us that sounds a bit cheesy the fans but
yeah they have gone way beyond what we
would expect in terms of helping to
provide us and that is really
appreciated so yeah I just like yeah
that's pretty much that's respectable
I may be medicated support of people
like yourself jeff has helped us get a
long way and it's it's really
encouraging it's encouraging us to do
what we do and we're loving it well I
appreciate the opportunity to work with
your products and make friends with you
guys and it's an honor to be involved in
something from the very beginning I was
part of it I feel like I got one of the
very first units I feel like I got to
see come a long way so thank you for
letting me be a part of it thanks for
trusting me with your products and
thanks for letting me advertise for you
I do appreciate that you really
appreciate it and speaking of products
we need to ship you the two new the
newest design once we'll send a couple
over and we'll throw in an extra mind a
unit that you can give away a surprise
to someone oh that sounds amazing
I'm sure my listeners ession my
listeners are already drooling for that
they're already waiting to figure out
how we're gonna do that so we'll set up
a giveaway I appreciate that more than
you even know that is gonna make
everybody really excited the other great
podcast as well it would be good to hear
more about you know where all the best
ways of maintaining an environment what
are the tricks okay because it changes
you know you know there's small
environments where people are growing in
spaces that are 3 feet by 2 feet and
that's keeping that regulated compared
to something that's you know 30,000
square feet there's a very different
game I mean even up to you know 10 by 10
for just an idea you know that whole how
it changes and what are the tricks for
being you know try and maintain it
that's one of the ideal temperatures and
humidity is because this is where vpe
gets interesting is it can kind of throw
conventional thinking out the window
absolutely one blade you said that
because the next podcast I have written
is all about VPD so we'll go from VPD
and then we'll start talking about more
environmental controls from there so
perfect timing great suggestion I'm glad
you said that in our simulations once we
got the VPD dialed in and we main
managed to maintain it so on our charts
you've got though the maximum ideal VPD
and the minimum VPD we've managed to
keep it pretty consistent between the
lines and within three days you can see
the difference the plants are just
they're more turgid they're preying up
more it's such a significant difference
when you can keep it in that zone the
ranges for the sake of clarity yeah the
minimum and maximum is suggested ve D is
precisely that it suggested we highly
recommend that you look into it yourself
before committing yes it is a minefield
a little bit of a leaf size and shape
difference may affect your desired vpb
is something I've noticed yeah
all right gentlemen find out what what
the target numbers are for you're using
growing and then that's what you go from
out is purely an indicative minimum and
maximum yes something like like a
hydroponic lettuce versus aa something
that's not hydroponic I'm I don't want
to say cannabis but versus cannabis you
may have vastly different desired VPD so
pay attention to your plants and make
sure you dial it in for your plants
everything is a suggestion there are no
hard fast rules when it comes to growing
cannabis well gentlemen I'm going to
yeah we could chat for hours that's
where I was gonna say I'm gonna wrap up
the the podcast portion of this I want
to thank you guys for joining me for a
really long hangout thanks for all the
great information on the product
I'm gonna press stop on the recording
and then we can just hang out and chat
for a few minutes if you gentlemen would
like alright so I'll press stop so that
way you don't incriminate yourselves
anymore all right five cast so what I
want to thank you again for listening to
another episode of the girl from your
heart podcast I would appreciate it if
you stalk me on all of the social media
you can find me on Facebook simply
search for the girl from your heart
podcast you can find me on Twitter it's
at G fyh podcast and on Instagram I use
my other company its Irie underscore
genetics if you've got something you'd
like to say and you're not into the
social media you can send me an email
it's a girl from your heart at
hotmail.com I would love to hear from
you also if you'd like to sponsor the
podcast if you've got a product you'd
like me to review all you've got to do
is reach out to me and grow from your
heart at hotmail.com and I will get back
to you ladies and gentlemen don't forget
about patreon you can support the
patreon campaign at patreon.com slash
grow from your heart I would appreciate
all of your help ladies and gentlemen I
want to thank you guys again for
listening I want to thank my friends
Peter and Lee for joining me for an
excellent Skype call I had a lot of fun
with you guys
I'll be back Monday with a fresh new
episode and until next time take a phat
dab and give your mom a hug for me