yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for another episode of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right if you're a
noob rower if you're a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
dedicated dabber if you're a cannabis
activists or even someone who is just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you I'm your host my friends call me
Rasta Jeff I want to thank you guys
again for joining me this episode of the
podcast is brought to you by my friends
at the hell a dank seed company if you
need new genetics for your garden I
highly recommend the hella dank seed
company you can find them at dank seed
dot store ladies and gentlemen roll up a
fat joint pack up the bomb or start
heating up that debris because it's time
for another episode of the grill from
your heart podcast
[Music]
welcome back podcast world it's time for
episode 324 of the girl from your heart
podcast this episode was recorded at
giddy ups office also known as the emo
tech headquarters this was a really fun
episode to record in this episode i'm
joined by dad and granny
i've got max from tnt concentrates and
of course we've got giddy up from emo
tech and of course giddy up concentrates
and a whole bunch of other things that
he'll talk about on here also in the
room were a few people that did not get
on the mic but they were hanging out
shoutout to all of them they may get
mentioned if you don't catch you they
are it's because they didn't really want
to be miked up some of them do speak up
throughout the show maybe you'll catch
who they are but I think they'll be just
fine if they remain anonymous you guys
with all the people in the room this
podcast gets a little chatty so I'm
gonna keep the intro short make sure you
support my friends at the hella dank
seed company you can find them at dank
seed dot store ladies and gentlemen
let's time travel back to Denver with
dab and granny max from TNT and giddyup
all right podcast world we are here you
guys can continue to talk go for it the
bass no chatter is great I like the vibe
and we're here at emo Tech in Denver
with a table full of amazing
concentrates and a group of amazing
folks I'm going to start off to my left
a repeat offender joining me on the
podcast the always beautiful Daniel
lettuce I would love to stay here on
that bullshitting thanks for joining us
thanks for putting this together oh yes
it was my fault look at her that's all
my boy toys here tonight grannies Harrow
muppet emo tech also on mics and say
he's all well he's talking about their
giddyup is in the house ladies and
gentleman welcome to shop guys good to
be back in Denver good to be back home
literally her back in Denver you been in
Denver for like an hour now I think I
travel a lot these days you can never
really tell where I'm gonna be showed up
with no shoes and a tank top and walked
in with a half a sunburn was like what's
up [ __ ] I brought Terps come I
come from the Midwest no man's land my
kind of friend right there hey dude
thanks for letting us do this in your
amazing facility this place is [ __ ]
cool well I appreciate my my pleasure
and my pleasure is why we keep it nice
and we like to have the community and
the culture come in and being all cold
and scientific is just too much like
hospital work man we'd like to have some
character around here I like the
decorations on the wall who painted over
there
oh man that's uh that's our boy right
there that's Brooks I knew that was who
it was I didn't want to embarrass myself
and be wrong shot to Aaron Brooks with
the great decorations on the wall we got
a a monster II and Aaron Brooks looking
monster grabbing a bumblebee squeezing
some honey out oh this one over here so
this was all done by a royal stain who
is graphic designer for grassroots okay
recognize that all right now that you
say that he did a bender the bender
right here of the the daily was at the
Daily Planet
yeah the Daily Planet from Futurama up
there was done by scenario scenario was
a tech nines production manager for like
nine years did a lot of art with him and
like was the guy that ran the lights at
all the tech 9 concerts like super cool
artists but more of an electronic artist
that is also a tagger
so we character in these walls yeah yeah
and he did my glow-in-the-dark logo
right up here in our galaxy there you go
my mom added the disco balls the disco
ball Center come on for the disco balls
those make it all happen
great facility if you guys ever get the
chance to drop into emo Tech in Denver
you'll know how to find it if you need
to be here over there another on the
other mic hitting a blunt right now
staring off into space did you just find
that bro did you just find if the space
is there you use your microphone voice
max is on the show kind of welcome to
the show back in come my stripper name
[Music]
night thank you joining us on the show
bro patreon throw some dollars in this
thong let's go where's I'm classy I'm
classy I got that which account where I
showed it sounds like twitch is a place
to show dick though let's see and that's
why it's all about how you brand showing
your genitals to random people on the
Internet
that's all it is just like weed I want
to give a shot it's my friend giddy one
night a long time ago I was on
ChatterBait no it wasn't ChatterBait it
was chatroulette a debates a whole
different story
yeah chatroulette and giddy pops up on
chatroulette
yeah dude like back in the day so I was
growing and extracting out of the house
so I had like no [ __ ] friends
right cuz I was like a double liability
for like breaking the law had aggro go
and I had an extraction lab in my house
an Oklahoma no here here in Colorado
Springs man and I was so lonely I needed
human contact couldn't have friends come
over and hang out so I hop on the
internet you know like I do tinychat
tiny Chapel and like it was so fun to
like get out there with no you laughing
and hey anytime you could you know you
got you know you got a friend with
character if you ever see him on
chatroulette and you don't see him dick
first I've never seen Gettys dick that's
right I was fully clothed I was smoking
weed with people on like dicks in our
pants Dinks in our pair this is before
the days of the Instagram live before
the Facebook just be on one thing and
you had to find other weirdos to hang
out with and you just randomly find
people in a row next to [ __ ] this weird
guy he's got his dick out park said it
best
okay we're gonna talk to somebody and
that's a dick all right we'll just click
alright that's a dick it's another day
some Asian dude alright another dick and
we smoked and then we got we got stoned
and rambled on and probably looked at
dicks after that actually I once thought
once I hit somebody that was my deal on
I'll channel it on top of that uh I I
speak a little Italian and I speak a
little Spanish so like that you can
locate by like region two and I would go
on places and I would like try to have
conversations with people in there and
like flex on my [ __ ] right he's got you
just giggle oh you want sweetheart
granny's blushing I've never seen granny
trilingual amore you want me to sing to
you in Italian yeah I do
we've got time for that we'll hit it and
relax about the show
nicely make sure listen to hope don't
forget don't let us forget that we are
out some music hey I'm not responsible
for anything your wife does after I sing
in Italian silently in the corner there
is Kevin also known as grumpy grandpa
he's hanging out in the corner
moderating us all in line not
responsible and did the arm wave so
we've got a couple of things we could
touch on here a few days ago giddy
teased about you can't believe what's
happening in Denver I think it's my
responsibility to pry that information
out of you my friend what the hell is
happening in Denver no I think I think
the secrets kind of out of the bag now
the reason and the reason why I didn't
want to touch on it and talk about it
too much in my post because I was
waiting on more information to come in
hit me a little diamond deposit in that
blunt what a why you know name names one
of the larger facilities in the state in
Denver had contacted me and they'd went
over their SOPs with diamond production
with fire department as the fire
department those guys are great first of
all big shout out to Denver Fire
Department those guys have always been
like really cool to work with
considering what we did and like they
worked with us when it was sketchy as
[ __ ] then because of them now companies
like mine and other companies can
flourish in multiple states so yeah
much love to Denver fire department over
here what doesn't a lot of people like
did they get involved because of some
things they got they got involved
because somebody had a jar pop in an
ignition on a high saturation in a lab
now wait break that down to normal
people talk yeah most of the people
listening are sorry I'm talking to the
room I'm holding my you stand that but
so from what I understand there was a
the way a lot of people make jar jars of
diamonds is jar tech you put a high
saturation of butane in the jar set a
temperature put it in and diamonds drop
out and you'll have the separate but it
takes a lot of and have a lot more
butane than you ever want to put in an
electronic oven so it was kind of those
things that we knew was gonna be
short-lived we knew what we knew that
wasn't when they got that tech that tech
it exactly that that technique the way
that most people entry-level start doing
it they're definitely not gonna be
allowing that they're not gonna be
allowing poor offs that reach a certain
limit on the if here so basically it's a
denver comes in show me your SOP explain
we're gonna go over how you do your
diamonds so when you pop your lid off of
your extraction device to pour in to be
a pressure vessel jar anything that you
have anything about pressure vessels
they are not liking pressure they will
not have pressure vessels in ovens they
won't have pressure vessels that that
stand for a long time so they're not
liking the what they're seeing right now
from the pressure vessel market they are
definitely absolutely not liking jar
tech that doesn't mean there's not a way
to skin the cat yes you know I'm telling
the man who like one of the best diamond
producers that I even know of is sitting
across from me right now so in a dad is
five gram diamond later as you know
there's no way but what it's gonna do is
go clean out the riffraff in the legal
market just gonna shake things up and
it's gonna prove for mainly like what I
look is the people that I messed with is
the guys in the lab it's another hurdle
if you can't adapt and go then we'll all
this dried the prices of the
concentrates up it depends on what the
stock is of the market for some places
that people shop if you shop at one or
two places it could happen it well I
mean if they come into your place and
you buy if you're the type of customer
that buys the white label to the Spencer
in that dispensary that
vertically-integrated dispensary wasn't
ready for it they may increase the price
of what they got because
they're gonna have to rego a lot of
these people have a large stock of
diamonds and it's not a problem that's
going to it's gonna take them off their
feet long enough to affect that large
supply of stock so do you foresee this
happening statewide I know you gotta say
nation everywhere but we're gonna talk
what did but what what Denver do they
all do can we compare this to how people
used to open blast they're shatter and
have all these explosion there's
definitely some comparisons while I do
believe that the same dangers exist in
both one is significantly less case in
point
no I mean nobody talks about you know
jars popping and I don't mean we put
thousands but thousands of jars out and
you know into into the process and if
you do it the right way it doesn't
happen
well TNT and I had this discussion and
he said the well the state can come in
but that doesn't fix stupid well you
know it's funny because right here right
here in this building that were setting
in Marc Rudolph of the Denver Fire
Department very classy fellow smart guy
and knows exactly what we all do he's
actually trained and certified on
multiple hydrocarbons I've trained him
on my equipment in he's a good guy he
came in here one day after there was an
accident with an emo tech machine in a
lab and they brought me the video you
know what happened here why was it fell
you know we went and did an incident
report on it and feel that like from
what we could see was all of the things
that led to the accident which in that
case was a Lou gross negligence of the
owner the extractor quit and they sent a
female blood tender that had never been
in the extraction lab out to finish
someone's run so something she did not
know what she was no she was come no she
wasn't certified to run the Machine she
didn't work in the lab she had no idea
she was trying to be safe and made some
mistakes that that caused the vessels
lid to come off and actually all the
butane lakes she didn't shut off the
valve she didn't next
any of the stuff that you're trained to
do like in the case of a catastrophic
failure for any machine and that's one
of the parts of the peer review when we
talk about you buying peer reviewed
machines we talked about asme
certifications what has happened here is
a group of engineers have taken whoa
it's Stormin we just lost power for a
second
Podcast kept good Podcast don't care but
did y'all see the glowing horse head
when the lights went out that time
nobody has gone over that particular
machine or design of machine to see if
there is a functionality a function of
our function of the machine that
wouldn't that would cause a catastrophic
failure part of that peer review being
done is you have to have your
instruction manual you have to have a
clear set way of training and in and you
have to have a certification program for
the people that actually run it and put
it up on the wall so with none of that
ever being a placement of you know that
was the first steps into a multi-step
problem the customer and Marc Rudolph
said giddy you make these things idiot
proof and they just keep making better
idiots supposed to be a joke I was just
saying I've been talking for 90 seconds
[Music]
13 they're just gonna devices in your
facility going to I mean there's a
million ways to skin the cat so they're
just gonna have to go around using
pressure vessels and I think I think the
thing is I don't think it doesn't just
you can't they but they won't just say
yes pressure vessels what'll it take
we'll be a company like mine getting the
peer review in process to get to get a
vessel to get a pressure as they'll
accept pressure vessels are like the
low-hanging fruit though anybody
precipitation of THC
I mean there's there's a million other
ways to do it but I mean that's
definitely the most
proof and quick fast repent and and you
can hire someone and train them how to
do it in a day and it doesn't take a
real real grasp of science to do it that
way that's kind of monkey-see monkey-do
and yeah and that but you know that that
also in itself has inconsistency in the
product you can't get what you can't get
what he makes right there J you guys
can't see what we have on the table
there are some diamonds here you can't
get what he has as consistent as he has
like bar Jalan in an oven with some
three month employees you know cuz you
fired everybody like that that takes
work so we're not gonna see too drastic
of a change in the market no it's just
gonna be enough to shake up what I see
is a bunch of complacent people in the
market happy with mediocrity that think
they got it [ __ ] going on as long as
it makes a better product for the
patients that's all that matters we're
just as long as it makes a better
product and it is the industry I mean
that's what everything is meant to
happen you know totally how we need to
say facilities there's nothing that
anybody can argue about this being right
or wrong you can't come set set across
from me and look me in the eye and tell
me that your [ __ ] jar Tech's safe I
know it's not I people have kept it real
secretive I'm not into the concentrate
making so I've kind of I've ignored the
tech but you guys spilled more of the
tech on this episode than I've been able
to get out of people that have been
working on this for a long time so I'm
kind of new to jar tech yeah that sounds
dangerous as [ __ ] I'm surprised this is
the first time the first diamonds I made
were jar tech the early days we were
doing pressure relief valves on jars
like when we first started that's yeah
it's kind of the tech weird is he
finding 15-pound pressure released
pressure valves on jars we went down
like a six pounds I just I just worked
my it mess trial and error without
when we were still using yes very
beginning tail end of but now we use
argon or nitrogen to back purge to back
pressure eyes which is it's way easier
because you start off with a clean
solution rather than starting your
recrystallization in a dirty solution to
begin with people are trying to take
notes there are people that are
listening to the show that are just
scribbling down their backspace and what
you just said trying to figure that out
yeah if you want to share any of that
information
you could keep going if you'd like how
to do any of those steps a little more
in-depth or if you'd like to keep your
tech to yourself feel free to teach us
all about the tech man follow him he'll
give you what you need for I'm sure if
you really want to make it change then I
would just say purchase your hash from
somebody that knows what they're doing
and on top of that man [ __ ] like your
money is all your power people and
that's the industry that's how you vote
support research the people that you're
buying from look into this you know and
like it makes you're making people a lot
of money you're giving your money to a
place you should feel good about it you
know what I mean are all diamonds
created equal no no material to like so
you can make crystals out of shitty ash
okay so on that talk about dropping
diamonds out of crew but I yeah people
do it people drop diamonds out of crude
and it's actually if somebody puts you
on to it it's the simplest process in
the world is no different than anything
else we do are people doing that oh yeah
yeah yeah and here's the thing here's
the thing as long as you take care
you're right your [ __ ] is thorough that
is the same THCA that you're getting out
of whatever as you were getting out of
the most fire prime cure buds and that's
where the connoisseur attitude has to
take a backseat
to the designer you know cannabinoid
makeups that we're doing nowadays this
is gone beyond we were taking everything
that you love and separated it and now
we can do designer mixes on it I'm still
a holistic smoking guy like my raw
products like water hash I don't like
rosin
I like BHO but I don't like it over
processed why is it you don't like rosin
I really want to know I don't like don't
get me wrong I was I just know I even
heard you say the other day like you're
considering making rosin my drop drop to
the floor do you know how many people
had to go oh my god did I hear what he
said love hash if I don't get the fire
rosin no you were like Nick of T's rosin
that they dropped out at fields out
there man it was so far and I come
across fire rosin I don't like rosin
enough to take a chance to dab it to not
like I do not like the taste of bad rose
and I do not like the burn neither do i
I don't like the stuff that makes my
nails live bad weed I do not like that
really good Ross and I've been smoking
some really good rosin somebody's also
got to check those vegan [ __ ] man rosin
boys out here running around acting like
[ __ ] don't stink I swish swish I'll see
you in the streets I'm glad you said
that on a low voice on that mic that is
perfect we're just gonna I'm not having
an edit fat yeah a lot of the rosin I
smoked tastes like a burnt popsicles
yeah or something and that's it bro I
love everything done if that shit'll
burnt and I'll smoke it it's kind of
like sometimes rosin is like like how
people used to look at BHO like it used
to be just the trim and stuff like that
they would go to it like that's how some
people look at Roz and a lot of people
with all the melts and stuff like that
that isn't full melt gets
dumpin Roz and I mean there are there
are some people that are doing you know
like squishing the 90 in the 120s which
makes amazing tasting rosin but a lot of
its taking out the joke I guess sorry we
just discovered a tech thing it's being
solved for me
I appreciate my friends are helping me
out it's plugged in right down there but
I don't know if I plug it in to have
some monstrosity because it's funny and
because it gets panties in a wad panties
in the water and honestly in this day
and age I really don't even like to
think that I do that on this game if you
notice I don't make many rosin jokes
many more that linger I'll pop one out
every now when like creativity strikes
but uh I mean that's another real topic
is how hateful everybody is on the
Internet of people I love I love a good
rosin talk I love what it does yeah I
love what it does it gets people moving
I just see something and I'm like it's
like I could call I could say something
politically incorrect or I could just
[ __ ] call it rosin ish you know and
just tie rosin to it and what were you
just handed besides heaven how else
would you describe that jar fire I got a
baller as jar here some white almost I
mean yeah white like champagne colored
all right podcast world unfortunately at
this point in the recording that
technical issue I was talking about
caught up to us I was forced to press
pause on the recording I had to restart
the computer while the computer
restarted we smoked down we got lit up
in that building we smoke some dabs of
THC a crystals we smoked some rosin we
smoked a couple of blunts we made that
place cloudy and then we all sat back
down in our seats and we got back down
on a podcast and here is what I captured
so before a technology went haywire on
us we had a little low we had some
lightning we had some wind we had some
stuff we have Denver as well we've got
it kind of disrupted my recording
equipment but we are back on track we
took a nice fat smoke break during that
break I was given a dab of so
Rasen from my friend max here at tnt off
of this gorgeous little rig what what
strain did you give me to dab bro
that was some the chem the cam yeah
you're right bro not all rosin is [ __ ]
I'll give you that that was pretty good
bro thank you no problem
it gave me a different kind of stoned
BHO dabs crystals any type of eh oh I
feel like it's missing this eye high
that I agree yeah it's that's not in
there whatever does this to my this when
you smoke well I always did smoke blunts
also but I noticed it from that that
rosin dab it went right to my eyes right
to the front of my face and you don't
get that from BHO so that's kind of cool
that I've missed that I don't I don't
think it's not that you don't get it
from BHO I think it's people get into
the habit of smoking one type of product
you know if you smoke BHO and you go
smoke cause it's gonna affect you
differently because it's gonna it's
gonna work differently you haven't had
it for a while and it's great and when
you bounce back and forth it's almost
like strain like I think cuz I hit good
rosin bro and you're right it it gets me
completely different high than my BHO
gets me but if I if I only smoke flower
for a while and then I go smoke BHO the
BHO hits me right again to where I'm I'm
just stubbornly stupid rosin messes me
up yeah it puts me to sleep like bah oh
yes chill it just threw me back I'm just
like whoa well you also been smoking
these fine CBD products oh yes this CBD
became let's talk about this Oklahoma
CBD products from Max all guys Gideon is
resting rosin it's the rosin I smoked
he's got he's got several seconds he's
dabbing now there's a big contemplation
on how long he should wait he's making
the candy cuz it looks real nice it's
clear it's super clouds nice carbon cap
is on it's like you guys were here with
us taking a DAB he's got a sexy mohawk
it's hanging it's sexy
you've been practicing let's go back in
four seconds he's gonna finish the dad
because he is a grown man he's smacking
his lips we're gonna ask him what he
thinks about the rosin here as soon as
he's done with this micro cough he's not
gonna cop to smell it it doesn't have
that uh that Burt popsicle smell that
I'm used to with rosin it didn't have
that taste at all it's actually smooth
it was pleasant I tasted like Cammy it
tastes to feel it in the front of my
forehead nice quick but now again do you
think that's because of the starting
material is the starting material was
good and the process that they had for
making rosin was done right yeah a lot
of it is the starting material you can't
you can't turn you can't always like you
always got to remember the starting
which other material can't polish say
you're right
that's why they have flower categories
and all these awards the process he
exhaled he would back any exhales he
just relaxed back part of the couch just
become one his legs a cry looking like a
yogi over there I've got a question for
him and I'm trying to give them in a
moment so that he can get his brains
back in his head after that Deb hey we
just took some dabs of this calm
extracts this concentrate smarter was
this done in the first FDA certified
that's right cab Ken tech can techlabs
is the first the first lab boom to get
FDA approval on all of our [ __ ] but what
makes it even better what state it's a
made in Oklahoma it's actually one of
the reddest states around we've got
medical marijuana on the ballot June 26
if anybody's listening Oklahoma make
sure you go vet vote YES on 780 yet 788
well you know we uh we passed him fat
Oklahoma and now
you know we're doing high CBD hemp and a
lot of other stuff too we're doing CBG
we're the only lab I know right now that
will make a product specific blend for
somebody in that CBG to it which
cannabinoids can you put into that
specific blend no we want to drill you
right after you take a DAB I apologize
for that I'm good time any better I hit
that rosin like like my girlfriend was
watching you know I'm saying that [ __ ]
was fire
I got brave grannies here yeah
max is huge FC everybody's watching me
smoke crosses we all smoked brass and
now we're on the couch my face is high
you know it's it's really it's coming
along so quick and which cannabinoids
which cannabinoids well there's no THC
so no Delta 9 as far as I know no Delta
8 either and that was gotta be the one
that people would be curious about
because it's new you know what I mean
it's not THC Delta 9 which in a lot of
the states that particular verbage is in
the law so if you have a compound that
is not that you can kind of argue that
you know while it is THC but it's not
tasty Delta 9 which is which we know so
they okay so I have a question then is
there any chance that smoking this would
cause someone to have a hot UA say you
work for the federal government yo say
you work for the federal government and
you smoke this you smokes for a
wonderful product no you will not you
well not you have to watch that about
CBDs and that is honestly she'd ask
questions that you could ask so we use
provar ting out of massachusetts to test
all of our to test all of us we have all
of our COAS
our SOPs the way that we produce our
hand we have no THC and we keep all of
our test stores to back it up on top of
that as we were open this company we did
matches with our people that smoked and
we didn't have people pissing hot we did
have people that smoked other people's
product that didn't smoke any THC that
did piss hot yes there's a lot of places
in Oklahoma right now because the CBD
market hit they're crazy and they popped
up like vape shops on the vape shop
[ __ ] oh there's a lot of people who
are selling stuff that pisses hot
there's a lot of people that are using
fraudulent tests or like you know
getting one test done on something and
reusing its deal but um what's being set
forth right now in Oklahoma as a means
to enforce all that you know just like
it happened to Colorado they're doing it
like that on the CBD side prepping for
what we pulled at 56% in favor of bill
788 passing medical marijuana in
Oklahoma who would that yeah I was gonna
say who would put THC in a CBD product
it's not that they're putting THC in a
CBD product on axe they're effectively
removing any THC from the product if
there's a if if they're if they're not
processing everything right you know
there can be trace amounts of THC in it
that's gonna cause people jobs child
support cases that's gonna wreck
people's lives it definitely it
definitely will and it definitely has
and there's a lot of products out there
and you know my brother my brother
didn't make any friends when he started
testing people's product you know and
going well and look at you guys this
came back you know testing hot for THC
like it's not what we're doing here you
know like like you're gonna get people
in trouble
so it's calm extracts K ALM extracts you
said that's available in all 50 states
you can you can check out can techlabs
at CA in Te KL ABS and get a store
locator for like our pure can a suitable
line the calm line this is where the
giddy up CBD line of smokeable CBD
products is going to be coming from with
my my particular strand of terms
it's gonna be real nice it's gonna have
everything is going to have online batch
number tested so you could check the
test scores too but you know that's what
we need are these cannabis Dr Terps that
are going back in food great herbs
cannabis derived terpenes no THC all
depends it depends on which ones it
really depends on which one summer
actually
hemp derived terpenes some are other
natural plant derived terpenes depending
upon which which terpene profile I don't
think I'm really disappointed about on
this packaging is your face is not on it
and that's because it's coming unless
this is you laid out on the M no do you
model for that no that didn't that that
right there is um that right there is a
house product with terpenes that the lab
has been working on now now that I'm
actually on as as part owner and part
shareholder we're going to establish a
licensing agreement between me and and
the company that brings the giddy-up CBD
line that I've been wanting to debut
there and that'll be distributed to our
distributors across the country and
it'll be available pretty much
everywhere we have you know we're the
same people that produce a quantum CBD
water our waters are in erawan in
California they're in a lot of stores in
Oklahoma and really they're it's a wide
range we've got distributors all over
the country that send out our water and
to be perfectly honest we've given away
you know hundreds and hundreds of
thousands of bottles to you know get out
and do the more excellent thanks for
getting CBD out there more people need
access to CBD more people need access to
actual CBD there's too much snake oil
and [ __ ] out there you don't see
somebody yeah no no you don't want
Chinese
I don't want fish oil you don't want
dragon's blood you want actual CBD yeah
and and that's that's a big part of you
want every you know every kind of
annoyed you can get so us being guys
that offer an extract to that has CBG
which not a lot of people do what's the
benefit of CBG there's a lot of benefits
to CVG and without getting too technical
into it CBG really kind of affects your
focus in your head and like it's it's
really it's really while CBD is is
healthy body
CBG apparently appears to be really
healthy mine is that the one they're
saying will help us with Alzheimer's
it's one of the cv g'v is one of the
ones into that and CBG is also the
precursor to everything almost
everything that exists in the camera i
like to equate it as stem cells for weed
the precursor oh you like that don't you
trademark trademark don't you
[ __ ] go putting stem cells [ __ ]
on oh I want to hear none of you
[ __ ] talk about stem cells
that's my [ __ ] hashtag wheat stem cells
hashtag wheat stem cells stem cells in
your weed hash that get e sales get
concentrated get e cells but that's the
way I like I like to explain it I don't
like honest managers I would I can't
wait man we're so close to we're so
close to just really having such solid
data on isolated cannabinoids bro and
that's the cool thing about this plant
is when you start mixing these and
ratios I love I love a 10% CBD to CBG
ratio I've always said I don't know
about always for a long time I've been
saying that we'll be able to go into I
don't know what type of facility it'll
be maybe it's similar to a pharmacy in
my mind and you hand them your little
card and your cards got your print print
out on it I want this much CBD this much
CBG this much THC this much limonene
this much pine oil and each of us would
just go in and stick out our Slurpee cup
and concentrate would fill up your
Slurpee cup with your exact order
there's four grams of the Jeff Hanks
I'll tell you we're not we're not far
from that of course we all would but
we're total at the isolation of
cannabinoids is all we're getting close
being able to make a special mixture
before you go to bed you know what I
mean yeah a little bit THC let's talk
about medicinally we can isolate true
formulas to fight specific
yeah absolutely because if we can make
formulas to to help ladies that are
going through breast cancer or prostate
cancer I mean that's you know people
with seizures how people with
Alzheimer's people with brain injuries
people but we will be able to isolate
formulas specific design design if we're
already doing that almost right now it
does an amazing job of doing it itself
and its form but I mean oh we could
definitely assist it
well all we're doing is just moving
stuff around you know what I mean and
the cool thing is is and the reason why
we say anything and why you'll hear you
know where you hear people going it's
the cure for everything the reason why
there's some truth to that is because of
the versatility of the effects of the
difference of the different compounds in
the plant there's an anti-virus there's
anti-inflammatory anti-inflammatory the
door anti fungal tech turret you know
there's so many different things that
the plant can do that when you start
isolating the compounds in the plant and
tracking back their ratios to see what
interacts with different people and
maybe it's something by blood time maybe
it's something by genetics that is
identified 50 years from now of working
with the plant nicely but that we will
derive the cures for most advanced
sicknesses from this plant in plants
like it it's that technology it's that
time it takes to do it and that's why
and it is you said and plants like it
because we know different spices have
the same holistic effect yes that's
right you found that out what the apple
cider vinegar did you know that cough so
much it got it out of me so I don't I
don't know the exact science behind the
Sun I'm gonna sound completely ignorant
but we can do DNA tests on ourselves now
and we can find markers in our DNA that
are going to predict hey you may get
Alzheimer's hey you may be prone to
cancer because of these genetic markers
in your DNA I listen to a lot of Joe
Rogan I don't absorb it all I'm driving
that's the short version of what I
understand
one day we'll be able to match up those
genetic markers with our cannabinoid
needs nope
you'll print out you'll take a little
blood you'll get your DNA and they'll
say hey your DNA is shaped like this
you're gonna get Alzheimer's you're
gonna get prostate cancer which
cannabinoids do you need which Terps do
you need
here you go start consuming if you eat
eat this if you dab dab this we'll be
able to dial it in based on a printout
and we'll be able to use it all so
that's the future bro and as you know
it's great [ __ ] high right now that
this makes it makes all the sense do 50
but think about dudes I mean look at
what we mean and let's let's step back
and let's get a little deeper for just a
quick look at what we've done in the
last 50 years
I'm of a special part of the generation
on the last of an analog generation I
was born into an analog world and I
became a young adult and a digital age
when it showed up and you know I
remember my uncles only having physical
toys to play with yes I started life
with physical toys and up until I was a
teenager and then when I was a teenager
at home video games and check him out
computers came out like the world
changed oh you got a pager my parents
brought home in a manner radar range
that's it was huge but we imagine
imagine oh I remember the color TV we
brought home I mean I'm dating myself
actually I remember our color TV too
while the time may seem a little off in
my situation you have to also remember
we was porous buff we was poor poor
growing up so I remember my
black-and-white TV even when I was like
five we got a color TV and it like blew
my mind
got color on that thing oh my god
but uh I mean look that's a special time
in like human history to exist and to be
born like a time where you go from
Industrial Age and steam and you know
fossil fuels to literally podcast
Instagram live Digital nuclear [ __ ]
worldwide communication everybody is now
you know what I mean there's no lag
between exchange of information but
that's not always for the best nobody
said that no no no but I'll tell you
what but it is different it is very
different because that it changes our
whole culture and it changes us as human
beings if you look if you look at 50
years in the future hundred years in the
future we're gonna have so much
information that comes to the human body
that comes to the world that exists
around us the ways to quantify that data
the things to do with it stem cells stem
cells like cannabis becoming leave them
begin being isolated as it fits in I
should tag the people in this room with
some sort of tag and say hey when they
die we got to check out their lungs and
see what all these different
concentrates work I'll tell you what
I'll tell you what I'll say it publicly
I'll saying that forever that we're like
the crash test dummies for smoking all
yes oh yeah we're we're dabbing Terps
who knows if we should even be dabbing
Terps at the concentrates were dabbing
Terps
and we're dabbing titanium nails right
as she sees fit but I'll donate my
[ __ ] [ __ ] to science to like study me
as a lifetime [ __ ] smoker I mean me
too there's a daily [ __ ] lifetime
smoker sell our the NFL science program
for concussions good I'll put my money
where my mouth is you can have it all I
don't need it once I'm dead you can can
we get there
a lot of time for him me and you be 85
years old and they'll be like yo homie
get your new body download you into a
robot we got some stem cells we're gonna
shoot them into your neck I'd be like
maybe like 9 foot tall bro a rocket [ __ ]
if you can feel that good would we even
want to consume cannabis anymore would
be like now I can fly I guess you're
right even if I could fly already I'd
still want to fly with some dads you're
serious pod care of it now this is ow we
got 15 solid minutes of talking about
concentrates and now we're talking about
life people will listen
they love hanging out there's a hashtag
hashtag they like it when we ramble
because they a lot of people we take it
for granted that we're sitting at a
table with Darby home rigged with a
hitman rigged with several jars of
high-quality concentrate baller jars you
guys not just little screens like brainy
grams 7 grams 4 grams 6 grams there's
and then a couple ounces of flour
sitting on the table there's a lot of
[ __ ] going on here we are spoiled there
are people listening in your hometown in
Oklahoma they can't have this on the
table there are people can't do this
folks with people Texas would go to
[ __ ] jail for happy tables that's the
time to be alive too is the time when
going from when this came out to be
illegal and being you know something
that criminals did and stuff like that
to everyday mom and pop smoke in
everyone smokes I mean it's I mean
they're still [ __ ] in jail on
that [ __ ] you know and like it's so
crazy we're out here going to cannabis
cups and there's still more [ __ ] in
jail yeah yeah these guys just showed up
and threw concentrate on the table like
shaven head bra free chin and nothing to
worry about it is mind-blowing that in
Texas a little bit of weed is a
misdemeanor but a gram of Constance and
Florida felon it's that way in Florida
if this were Texas and one cop come in
here all there's enough concentration
not just concentrate bro most of its I
tell you what around us yeah - Oh bees
I'll tell you what there's only one
licensed facility in the state of
Oklahoma that equipment like this can
even set in for that purpose and that's
ours that you the people listening have
to meet some sketchy dude in a parking
lot at Walmart and so yeah that's that's
what we're here for
yes that's why we're still activists and
we're not just out here like trying to
get rich like it's why we still do the
so we still put in the work because
there's a lot of people in America
before I forget cuz I am high when Jeff
said about meeting the shady person in
the parking lot guys don't be buying
your weed off Instagram do [ __ ] I don't
want to hear hey I gave the person my
money and got nothing come on come on
somebody that looks like Jerry Chrissy
key tries to sell you read on the
internet don't do it okay okay he's got
curly gray hair like a goatee he always
got pictures with people's weed and [ __ ]
collared shirt somebody had a fake Rasta
Jeff account trying to sell it selling
but luckily enough people knew who I was
where like bro shut this down because
I've got a reputation where I always say
I'm not gonna sell you wheat online
trying to pour Jeff sure he's a good
dude chap - Jerry shut up Jerry
this rad reefer gets a lot of them yeah
she posts a lot of pictures so it's easy
yeah yeah she is a fantastic grower yeah
I mean I think it's kind of sorry that
we even have to say don't do this it
runs deep runs deeper than than just
people faking people out on the Internet
bro I know I know people out there that
sent up entire companies to knock off
somebody's product and sell it to a
particular state you hear about it you
know like that that's why brass in my
opinion that's why brass knuckles is
getting sued
you know what I'm saying has a bunch of
knockoffs there's a bunch of [ __ ]
knockoffs man that that we're out there
going and people tested them and they
hit hot and because I I had people try
to call and sell me from China brass
knuckles pins I have the emails on my
computer a factory in China I can't wait
to find some trying to sell me their
genetic rate up pins and put my oil in
it for whatever like there's no doubt in
my mind that the guys at brass knuckles
are they take it seriously they love
this [ __ ] they're like us you know what
I mean like they they live this life
this loose what I call the prop 215 live
for [ __ ] and forwarding the plant and
the culture at the same time as trying
to go legit you know trying to cross
over and they test [ __ ] they test their
oil they use its you don't not test your
oil at this level no somebody's gonna
buy it and test it and find Michael you
know that's yeah they're gonna find some
no that's gonna happen
I tested every product that we sold here
in Colorado that I may have tested every
product that we sold in Nevada test
every product that's been sold Oklahoma
City it's a new facility
I do not operate in California for
anybody other than myself and my
immediate you know surrounding when I go
to do runs out there it was like we're
hanging your stuff in California you
know
because 80% of the weed would not pass
testing it does not pass testing they
test it whose people still sell weed
that has been sprayed with [ __ ] or it's
not gonna waste my time and please sell
it to the clubs and people buy it and
then those people tested on their own
just because they want to know and
they're still finding out that people
are still spraying eagle 20 have it but
do you think so here's here's this crazy
little bubble that's gonna pop you wanna
hear how some shits gonna go see now
let's see why co2 is gonna try and make
a comeback right I believe that over the
next 18 months don't do that to us it's
not gonna I can't help that are capable
people taste things people do taste
oh I'm not a co2 fan I'm not a co2 would
you smoke co2 be for Roslin no cross
okay I don't I think all of us here are
saying yes hey hey if you give me a co2
pin and I hit it and you don't tell me
the co2 and I hit it yep I get a shitty
attitude real quick about fist-fought
Addison the first time I ever met him
feel the same way about Mexican CBD bad
Mexican CBD uh-huh everybody loves the
Mexican see y'all guys have ran with our
[ __ ] jokes lifestyle I literally had
somebody [ __ ] come to me it was like
hey it's like what cool like that's the
joke that's the joke they're like I
heard you do Mexican cbt
I'm gonna edit any of that that's gonna
be this on my live before Duke is like
we ready you're already we always we
always laugh in joke because everybody
imagines this [ __ ] crazy lifestyle it
is a crazy lifestyle you more so than
probably any of us sitting here I just
agreed dude look at your hair yep
your hair says I like to party to get
down throw the hearts down I put the I
wore this today with flip-flops from
California oh no from Oklahoma I thought
you're coming from yes agent for a
lighter to light your joint that's how I
like to party like that time that's how
I'm wild and dangerous
I like airsoft and I like smoking weed
in [ __ ] public places sue me [ __ ]
sue me that's those are acceptable I'm
down you know hurting anybody I don't
want any problems I'm down I don't dress
yeah soft with you take one I think I
moved to Hollywood never buys like
Kitty's gonna get strung out on heroin
I'm like bro I don't even take allergy
pills did they really say that no they
did but like everybody everybody's like
seeing me out party and stuff and they I
think that are I think no he's my man
have fun let's smoke a lot of weed let
the guy have come on no no I am a
businessman
I'm professional but that was the that
was the message I got random ly got some
message from some follow that was like I
heard you're some [ __ ] junkie don't
know that I'm like [ __ ] maybe and that
was the Mexican see he's like I know
what Mexican CBD he's like bro we made a
joke because people were snorting CBD we
were like oh [ __ ] you know somebody
out here is like got some straight
[ __ ] cocaine CBD mix personal [ __ ]
that there's no and we were like yeah
[ __ ] Mexican CBD strong [ __ ] and it
be in it like became this like standing
joke there like whenever you're at one
of these [ __ ] weed parties there's
somebody there that's like gonna
justifiably you always get that one guy
tries to justifiably talk about some
other drug I just do it because of this
bro just once in a while now it's it's
it's it's it's it's you guys all know
what the Mexican it's mushrooms known on
the joke hey yeah it's in Denver
Colorado is working there working as
much mushrooms for my dad used mushrooms
there so like if we're because I mean
I've said what drugs that don't do I'll
say what drugs a dude is nothing wrong
with mushrooms in moderation in
moderation and in safe environment I
think they're extremely I think they
show a lot of promise in a depression
and social anxiety issue stuff like that
read at least one Terence Mckenna book
before you venture into the world of
mushrooms but I uh I've had nothing but
Pleasant you know psycho [ __ ] out
there experiences I like to recharge the
spiritual battery just as much as the
next refresh wash it out wash it out
what's a what's a spiritual dose
forgetty a lot probably more than I
should talk about in the show know when
I do find the need for those like and I
can tell like you I'm not a religious
man like I like to consider myself a
relatively spiritual man
like in the sense that I try to flow
with the universe I try to go and I try
to be aware of my surroundings you know
when I feel like I need to get back to
the part of my brain that I shut away
day after day when I go to work I lock
in the back of my mind that you know the
the the thing of the the creative
thoughts that flow and sit like that I
smoke weed to [ __ ] deal with stress
and I enjoy taste and like and you know
like I feel better smoking weed but
that's the numb the pain like I I do i
do hallucinogens to to look the pain in
the eye and see what's going on I don't
know about y'all but every time I get
done I kind of know what I need to do
with yeah I'd be real with myself when I
do it and I'm very introspective when I
do hallucinogens I don't like to do them
at parties or the three exactly yeah
yeah but by yourself by the campfire
just get out so you're three gram 5
grams 7 gram kind of guys though 7 girl
you do it that's the students over here
shaking his head that just getting
started or not blowing out of the water
he said I'm too old for that [ __ ] that's
everybody who ever wants to remain
anonymous on the podcast ok he's too old
we got another I'm too old for that [ __ ]
we got a couple of them - we got it we
got one guy he doesn't like them I love
them sounds like Kevin enjoyed himself
the last time I think I saw some
Instagram videos yes we were nothing
well we're not gonna incriminate anybody
oh yeah that has to come out man the
oars were wonderful that day I totally
think that you know with my experience
in the past with it and like it should
absolutely be thought of as a type of
therapy for for a lot of people's
possibly don't produce dopamine which
are like a lot of TBI people because of
because of our long-running more we have
a lot of TBI survivors that also have
PTSD and that really works we're kind of
both of those yeah I see in the
headlines a lot that you know that that
is like something that they're trying to
at least get some attention on and I
think because of Colorado we have a huge
military population yes we do that's
right we have a lot of veterans here
that have been through those wars yeah
so I think maybe that has something to
do with why they are looking into it
here well I mean it makes sense I think
that the large population really has a
lot of the VA here and now I think
honestly with the the the pressure that
they've had on them from our soldiers
coming home that are you know the VA
typically their mo is kind of like
medicate the problems yeah heavily
heavily I think their pressure for
marijuana has got the same people
showing up saying there's other
alternatives not just marijuana but you
know LSD mushrooms therapeutic doses
micro dosing mushrooms I know a lot of
people that that are that micro dose
that say this is like changes anything
about my I follow people on Instagram
that do a journal every day I take this
much and this is how it's improving
I see it working for people I think
everything that's growing out of the
earth was put here for a reason some a
little [ __ ] kill you some of it at
the right dose will cure you the same
same thing the wrong dose will just ruin
you I never encourage anybody to
recklessly do anything
like never do anything that jeopardize
anything you know you know like I've
always chose to do a row I do it in a
safe environment when I do any kind of
hallucinogens you know like I never
would drive or have that like you'd be
lucky to get me out of my bed well if I
had seven grams that once I would not be
driving that's the way to do it that's
the way you get seven I do I do there's
a difference in a spiritual dose in a
micro dose that's absolutely and I if
I'm going in I'm going for that
spiritual experience I need to look in
there and have the problem identify and
then dance around on my head and then
find a solution to that problem there
are other things that will take me to
that room much more quickly and reveal
problems for me but we'll talk about
those on other episodes oh boy I've got
a little giggles throughout the room for
the folks that have participated in our
brain one day show you what's wrong
you know the the thing you know what
turned me off about DMT the taste no on
it
I've never done all I've never done it
I've never done a smoke everybody just
looked at me like I was a hell snow pipe
is the way to go but the Terps on top
that that would just pulling I'll tell
you what I watched somebody blow your
mind but won't be named who won a
cannabis cup actually a special
shout-out to the crew of Team Elite
genetics my boys can bill rimy the one
another cup up in NorCal this last trip
gradual ation thank you like round them
up six for me now like these heavy yeah
and I think that's I think I said the
last three I didn't even know they
hinted the product until we had one so I
was like oh sweet I got a phone call
when I was airsofting that we won down
in SoCal on the product that we ran for
he's got great product but uh
I swear I was somebody at will not do
tiempo somebody will somebody at the cup
like I watched somebody hit a big Ojeda
DMT and then go up accept their award on
stage it's kind of blew my mind no but
yeah slobbering all over him no no he
wasn't he nobody in the world would have
known he was a total like he didn't I
just totally witnessed it happened like
how much did this I want to say but DMT
is a three puff drug hit number one the
paper starts crinkling hit number two
the paper tears hit number three you're
[ __ ] in there fifteen minutes later
everything is just like whoa what the
floating in gelatin or something anymore
I'm normal again but that first one I
could see maybe maybe functioning off
one light puff that but - you start
getting somewhere in three years all
these great analogies now listen listen
these are great analogies but somebody
once told me I think it was a Joe Rogan
podcast that I heard and he said doing
DMT is like having your computer desktop
and it's like doing DMT takes all the
files on your desktop and shrinks them
down into one file that was labeled wild
[ __ ] yeah
yeah and I has a real good analogy I
have way too many [ __ ]
responsibilities to not give a [ __ ]
about them I'm scared to death that I'm
going to do DMT and go it doesn't do
that to you it doesn't dive you already
know pimpin you already know I've never
talked about this on the five and that's
the problem it won't run my life but
it'll change it drastically it will take
I change your thought process not as
drastically as you're gonna think it's
and it's very I haven't done a
psychedelic drug since my traumatic
brain injury had a severe traumatic
brain injury and for a little while I
heard a humming noise that would not go
away and it was terrible and that noise
is gone and I'm afraid that if I do any
drugs it's gonna come back and if it
comes back I don't know how I'm gonna
handle it especially if I'm tripping or
something so I'm afraid but before then
it would not be rare to find me doing a
blast of DMT what I felt like it would
do I describe him as the mooninites from
Aqua Teen Hunger Force those little
square guys yeah those little guys you
take a blast of DMT arrest your
microphone you fall back into the chair
and those little guys danced around in
front of me and all they said was hey
it's okay and they just kept like
rubbing me on my knee and on my shoulder
and then go it's okay bro and you start
thinking about all that well what could
they mean and that triggers you to go
well what could they mean and then you
remember well that happened when I was a
kid [ __ ] and then I go home okay I guess
it's okay remember all this dumb [ __ ]
that you've suppressed or that you're
dealing with or whatever dumb [ __ ]
trivial [ __ ] that shouldn't even be
bugging you it pops up in your head
vividly it's got spotlights on it but
you can rotate it in every direction you
can look at it from the bottom you can
look at it from the side and you've
stepped back and you can pivot it all
around and then those little those
little guys they go hey bro did you ever
think of this maybe you're just clinging
to some stupid [ __ ] it's okay and then
you come out of it and you go oh it's
okay it's okay it's like cleaning your
stupid [ __ ] filter is kind of what it
does it's a good way to get pat like if
you're stuck on something if something
happened and you got a thing in your
brain like why this why or a [ __ ] how
or or whatever look some DMT and put
that in your mind and you'll you'll know
why or how I gotta go to work realizing
what I'm looking at yeah but DMT is like
a 15 30 minute thirty minutes at the
most and you're like oh I was so [ __ ]
up thirty minutes ago I can't
when I retire I'm gonna become that old
hippie yes I am living proof of that
retire you can do it ever you down I
love it i watch granny on microphone
voice brother microphone voice hello
jelly watching her sometimes I'm like
she's living life I love it people talk
[ __ ] to her about this like Church
raised she's [ __ ] got her thing I
have a great husband supports me yeah
you're watching her on Instagram
[ __ ]
get off the couch and do something
granny yep we do that's our
wake-and-bake I wake up
Gaby's usually made me coffee like Gaby
don't have to wake up early we'll lay in
bed in the morning to watch if I don't
if I don't go live with her it's because
I'm laying in bed with Gaby yeah we're
just watching well this morning they
were like where's giddy and I said oh I
had to go giddy up could come and I
wouldn't even have him come live with me
so don't even ask didn't say that you
didn't say that
I go on live the other day and they were
like all the followers they're going
granny you missed it what did I miss
giddy was live from the shower you
missed it granny
giddy up was live in the shower I got a
warrant I've got a waterproof phone down
a firm grip and I yeah I'll let you get
it on the shower Dave just follow my
private snapchat do you get a bunch of
lovely female followers as I said alive
with granny ice I checked as I've told
her this before like I saw my analytics
one day I have like 65% female followers
no way
it's [ __ ] call shenanigans my feeds a
sausage fest bro Oh God look at my
followers it's crazy it's crazy granny I
mean when you see me go live and my
followers it's its majority every dude
is a facial scrubber what
man I got black girl magic bro my
girlfriend oh yeah is that cocoa butter
or my girl the mic for somebody else
before I got black girl magic magical
it's doing wonders did you glow and burn
my girl my girl Gabby makes mohawk beard
the glowing skin she makes her own
essential oil mix she hits me up with
like rose oil
yeah rose oil I can't be a thieves or I
can't be given like [ __ ] I like but I'll
tell you this I'll tell you this I am I
am it I am at heart scientists if I may
not be won a beauty secondary or
education but thieves oil man but you
know about thieves or these I usually
don't [ __ ] with them seams do you
research I'd like to take the second to
plug in my private premium snapchat if
you guys will make sure you check him
out it's [ __ ] worth it do you accept
that mo if you're in the band bobs and
beards and Terps he's the way to go I
[Music]
was making Instagram that I follow was
making a joke about follow my premium
snapchat and I sent them my scent and I
went when I sent him like like a face
emoji that was like you know skeptical
emoji face and your high brow she was
like don't judge I was like I'm not
judging beside which credit card to use
that's such a funny thing that that the
sex worker business is actually flourish
like that's the one that's the most
premium I've never I've personally never
paid for a premium snapchat or anything
like that for premium snapchat bro who
does people pay for that yes they do
people pay for it like there's there was
a whole documentary deal that about
where they talk about they use Bitcoin
and [ __ ] bro like shakes me making mad
money bro
yes they do but then twist
chances are bro if your phone is ringing
its twist
oh just got a turned it back on but you
know what out of the canopy you know
snaps I'm pretty I'm joking about it
when I say you're joking I know my back
page put your clothes back it's never
been the way I've thought to mark it if
you've got a good cannabis product the
Terps will sell themselves you don't
need to put staties on it it's yeah
Terps myself professionally spell [ __ ]
right spell [ __ ] correctly right in a
complete sentence also like I don't know
about all that bro from Oklahoma I'm not
necessarily she wants to be on the show
let her her to spell things correctly
for you I love my staff he's got a great
building here I know we we [ __ ] a
lot this is a pretty dope facility you
got some comfy couches there's hay
hanging out surrounds himself with smart
women that's what I've noticed from the
show I surround myself a very smart
determined strong women there you go
guys if we're gonna take one lesson from
this podcast surround yourself with
beautiful smart women if they're if it's
women in your life if it's your mom if
you're davon granny if it's your
cannabis plants if it's your daughter
smart beautiful women in your life
surround yourself and learn from them
treat them right dude you could do you
guys it's getting kind of late we should
wrap up the show a few of us have a
quite a drive to get back to our our
domiciles for the evening
thank everybody for hanging
let's do a whole bunch of social media
shout out so that everybody knows how to
find everybody of course stabbing granny
you know how to find me just watch your
Instagram me and Gideon hey max how can
people find you TNT underscore
extractions one on the Instagram he goes
live occasionally check out his dope ass
bird that bird his coolest [ __ ]
obviously giddy how can we find you I am
official giddy up on Instagram that's
usually my platform foreplay
when you gonna get verified bro I know I
was asking a couple my Vera five frenzy
today like you know I was part of that
uh I was part of that group that got
hacked and extorted that's another
episode bro we're gonna have to hear
about that on Instagram you know about
that you remember that yeah I was
deleted as well
you are too were you a story no you
weren't
they asked me for money but we didn't
pay I said you paid I paid and then did
you get it back and then get it taken
away again yeah yeah that's what
happened yeah yeah yeah disappear nobody
ever hit me up for money though no I
can't got trace back because I got hit
by this they told everyone that was in
the know like I didn't know either but
everyone that was like oh of you got
your account got you gotta hit up
Lincoln Blake to get it man like I won't
call the trolls [ __ ] him I got feelers
right so I got feelers
there was a big group message with a lot
of cannabis business owners in it in
this group and eight of the
[ __ ] in the group or real
players and this had affected their [ __ ]
to where they saw when their [ __ ] went
down for a month and got taken away like
they ran the numbers on it they were
looking to pay they were looking for any
chance from losing their install no oh
yeah yeah yeah they like my doodling
literally sir he said I can't stress to
you enough he's like I can see a literal
dollar amount of when they take my stuff
down and I can't run my specials too
much so
Media on my Instagram and they hired
lawyers they hired lawyers they went
through all this stuff and it turned out
to be a facebook employee so yeah like
that person was fired and like all it
was owned by Facebook so hi like we all
paid we had all found out we had paid
the same person and you know I'm not
sure what happened of that I know a lot
of people got their [ __ ] back I did not
get my [ __ ] back and I lost my 27 one
thousand four and I never after that I
did I didn't structure my Instagram the
same way I didn't do it the same way it
became way more informal to me because I
was kind of just starting over and it
didn't at the same time because back in
the day I'd show tech ID you know I gave
a lot of [ __ ] through my Instagram and
now now I'm just hanging out on mine I
post more pictures of myself in my life
and I feel like it's more fun it's more
interactive and I get have more
interaction with my followers instead
they're just here's a picture of a plant
yeah I could see how Instagram know
thanked a large business it would affect
my business I've got a very small
business and it would affect my business
hugely hugely is that a word I if I
can't advertise through Instagram what
do people do first thing you do and you
wake up a lot of people if you got that
if you don't have somebody next to you
wake up and you scroll through that
Instagram what's going on in the world
who's doing what and they see I read
genetics emo Tech they see our post now
we're on their mind if they don't have
that you and we somebody else is on
their mind in that spot well not just
that but you know YouTube we're very
many people lost their users Jam YouTube
channels down the drain they all got I
got mine back I did coral reef or a
reefer okay by YouTube following so
small it never got
the first place like 250 YouTube
followers but big thank you to each and
every single one of them I love all of
you individual I don't know who my
YouTube followers are whose Mac said my
voice is so serious
thanks max I'll follow your premium
snapchat if you listen to my podcast I
do this New York live I'll bring the
backs of conceived the first thing when
I wake up in the morning this is getting
weird in here it's getting strange
alright we should start wrapping up a
podcast I said that a few minutes ago I
want to thank all these people for
gathering X is bringing the tremendous
turps the rosin that changed my mind
the FDA lab approved CBD the Terps the
flowers this is a great place to hang
out UPS can techlabs say it again
advertise Bravo detect labs CA n-tek L
abs with a store locator and find some
product you can get the products that we
were enjoying this evening you could
partake just like Colorado kids you
could be big boys you could write the
big ramp just like Tony Hawk John talk
to your plug about carrying TNT
extractions you should definitely hit up
your plug and tell them that they should
carry some TNT I don't know guys if
you're making extractions you need a
Nemo tech machine get yourself a Nemo
tech machine learn how to use it don't
blow the [ __ ] up make extractions with a
Nemo tech do like a bath right uh giddy
he had to run he walked away he was
right here on the couch he's running
around the room thanks for letting us
have a show here at your cool place man
it's my pleasure this was awesome we'll
do this again we've got more stuff to
talk about I'm sure we will be back
granny thanks for uh thanks daily and I
think it's master guys's bedtime I
appreciate you for being out this late
Kevin yes it sure is I saw was ten
o'clock we decided to wrap it up bro you
were quiet but thanks for hanging out
you brought great concentrates that's
our friend from out of state who would
rather remain anonymous you guys I'm
gonna wrap up this portion of the
podcast
be back to put a tail on this [ __ ] I'm
super lit thanks for hanging out with me
I'll be right back Regent ethics that's
right girl from Jax is doing a live
Instagram I think I'm gonna do the same
thing alright podcaster I wanna thank
you guys for listening to a long episode
of the growth for our podcast I want to
send another huge thank-you shoutout to
dab and Granny Max from TNT extractions
and giddyup and of course to all my new
friends I made sitting in the room who
did not have microphones who chose to be
silent thanks for hanging out I had a
great time were you able to listen to
the entire podcast I know we got a
little rambley at the end I felt it
getting loose but I thought it was kind
of cool it was getting comfortable
everybody was just being themselves and
I felt there was no reason to cut that
off so I left it in for you guys and I
hope you enjoyed the rambly part of the
conversation let me know if you were
able to listen I would like to hear your
feedback on this episode send me an e
mail it to grow from your heart at
hotmail.com let me know what you think
ladies and gentlemen make sure you find
me on all of the social media on
facebook it's the girl from your heart
podcast on Twitter it's at G fyh podcast
on Instagram I use my seed company it's
Irie underscore genetics make sure you
check out I read underscore genetics on
Instagram check out my sweet cannabis
photography ladies and gentlemen if you
feel like this podcast was worth a
couple of bucks you can contribute to
the show by going to patreon.com slash
girl from your heart patreon.com slash
bra from your heart we'll give you all
the information you need to sign up to
contribute to the show financially I
would appreciate the continued support
big shout out to everybody who has
helped me out on patreon in the past and
in the future podcast world I'll be back
Thursday with a quick episode and I'll
be back Monday with brand new
full-length content I want to give a
huge shout out to my new friend living
free 85 and until next time take a phat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you