[Music]
welcome back podcast world it's time for
episode 325 of the girl from a heart
podcast your source for cannabis news
education and conversation this episode
of the podcast is brought to you by my
friends at the hello tank seed company
if you need new regular or feminized
seeds for your garden I highly recommend
the hell a dank seed company you can
find them at dank seed dot store ladies
and gentlemen this episode is a
compilation of my Instagram live feeds I
like to go on Instagram live hangout
with my friends take a few dabs and talk
about cannabis if you want to check out
my Instagram live feed all you have to
do is follow me on instagram it's IRA
underscore genetics I RIE underscore g
en ET ICS IRA underscore genetics on
instagram follow me turn on your
notifications but when i go live it'll
pop up at the top of your screen you
click the notification will take you
right to the video you'll get to watch
me hang out take live questions take
some dads
if you ask a question I most likely will
answer it in the live feed so check it
out on Instagram join me be a part of
the live feed maybe I'll put your clip
in the next Instagram live episode
ladies and gentlemen before this intro
gets too long let's get right into it
here's episode 325 of the girl from the
heart podcast
[Music]
alright so if you're trying to get all
that reclaim out of your rig so that you
can use it it's a good idea to make
edibles out of it if you want to dry it
out and smoke it you could do that but
edibles is probably the way to go if
you're gonna recycle your reclaim the
easiest way to get it out out of the rig
without destroying it is to run the tap
water get the tap water super hot and
then just fill the rig with hot water
and pour it out into a container if the
rig and the water are really hot it'll
come out really easily if it's cold
that shit's just gonna stick and make a
mess if you put a solvent in there to
loosen it up you're gonna ruin the
reclaim so the best way to get it out is
probably just hot water and pour it into
something and collect it
maybe pour it onto some parchment might
be your best bet not sure how to collect
it that way I honestly don't [ __ ] with
reclaim I'm a little bit stuck up I
throw the reclaim away another good way
to catch your reclaim you guys and make
it more usable and to keep it from the
water is a drop down simply put a drop
down on your rig a drop down is a piece
that goes from the joint of your rig it
drops down at an angle and then it goes
back up and you put your nail on the up
part and your reclaim will gather in the
bottom of the drop down instead of
making it into the water of your rig
it's more accessible and it's easier to
smoke from there than it is from the
water so that's what I would do with the
reclaim if you were trying to use it
Jessie says chem for chem D or chem 91
my answer is yes please but honestly I
like the chem 4 cuz it's chunky I like
that when you oh it smells like I think
it smells like when you open a can of
tennis balls a fresh can and tennis
balls has a really certain smell it's
like got a uh I don't know a certain it
smells like him chem 4 but it's got like
a tires kind of a thing going on I
really like that Kim D I don't know that
I've got enough experience with real Kim
D to be honest chem 91 I love that nasty
skunk funk terrible smell I love that so
if I want to grow it probably chem 4 if
I want to smoke it can 91 if I need more
information Kim D [ __ ] marry kill uh
[ __ ] Kim for Mary Kim 91 and kill Kim D
yes we just played around a [ __ ] marry
kill with cannabis strains you guys so
the question was what was your view on
11 on and 13 off to mimic the tropics
they're asking about light cycles 11
hours on 13 hours off for the plants to
mimic the tropics that's not a bad idea
it saves you an hour of electricity
which over a 65 day flowering cycle is
65 hours of light for each bulb that you
don't have to run that closure equipment
a little bit and also when you're doing
a phenol hunt I think a longer dark
period gives your plants more time to
show a phenol Fino typical expression
you'll see more variance you'll see the
plants actually do what they're supposed
to do it may affect your yield it may
affect positively or negatively
depending on your strain I think it was
DJ short that was saying 11 on 13 off
yes that's probably where you heard that
DJ short on a high times forum on one of
the panels on free weed free weed I'm
probably on that podcast it's probably
where you heard that and it's not a bad
idea it'll save you like I said it'll
save you one hour every day and over a
63-65 day flowering cycle that's 65
hours worth of electricity and if you're
running four lights at 65 times four is
a 240 is 270 [ __ ] right 260 hours of
lighting that you're saving that's quick
math don't [ __ ] hold me to it
ah but yeah it's not a bad idea it'll
show more phenotypic expression I think
it's not a bad idea it'll bring out more
flavors more Terps - the question is
question for you Rasta man when you do
an open pollination with a single male
do you put it in the room at the same
time as your girls when you start
flowering no that's very strained
dependent something like grateful dog
wants to be pollinated around day 25 of
its life of flowering lemon skunk wants
pollen closer to day 32 so I've got to
put the mail in the room to get him
pollinating to get him flowering to get
him pollinating to where when the
grateful dog plant wants pollen and the
lemon skunk plant wants pollen that male
has got pollen ready for them also I've
got to time it to where the lemon skunk
plant and that grateful dog plant are
ready for pollen on the same day so that
means I
got to put the mail in the room a few
days ahead of time just a couple days it
depends on what plants I'm working with
I know which plants I need to do this
with cuz I've done it a few times now ah
gotta put the mail in the room first get
him going I kind of put him in a
separate space he's far from all the
other ones he's isolated so he's in
there flowering then I will put the
lemon skunk in there because it's got to
get ahead of everybody then I will put
I'll wait like what is it six or seven
days let the lemons gunk get ahead then
we'll throw that grateful dog in there
so now they've at they're actually
perfectly timed now it sounds like one
winning way late and one way in early
but when pollen comes this one's gonna
have fat pistols the buds are gonna
start forming it's a shorter squatter
indica plant so it's not gonna get as
tall it's not gonna get it doesn't take
as much time to finish so it needs to be
pollinated earlier that lemon skunk
plant needs a little more time to
stretch out and give me all those little
bud sites to create seed sites so uh
yeah I got it I got to stagger them the
boy goes in first then the lemon skunk
then the grateful dog depends on what
else I'm working with the question is
I've got seeds available on dang seed
store and somebody wants to know if the
blueberry cookies packs are all the same
or is the s-1 pack different than the
one not labeled s1 I'm not sure how
they've got them labeled on the website
I need to take a look and see what
they've gotten going on up there but
this is a good opportunity to talk about
s ones and our ones now
this is a label for feminized seeds
normally you see things like f1 or f2 or
BX or IBL now you're starting to see on
feminized seed packages you're seeing R
1 and s 1 R 1 means a reversal an R 1
means I reversed it plant and I used its
pollen on a different plant it's a
reversal an s-1 is if I were to reverse
a plant and put that pollen on the same
cultivar so that is selfing it's only
selfing if you're putting the pollen on
itself if you're putting the pollen on
something else it's a reversal so s1 is
a self 1 it's only gonna have that
plants genes in it no other no other
genetics no other adulterations it's
just gonna be that it is going to be
just blueberry cookies I took the
blueberry cookies girl and I put
reversed blueberry cookies pollen on
there and it is selfed that is seeds of
itself s1 now reversal if I take that
blueberry cookies pollen just as I did
and I throw it on the Platinum tangi I
have now made a reversal that's not a
self because I've opened up the line I
put something else in there so that's
the difference between an r1 and an s1 a
reversal and a self plant so the
conversation was we were talking about
reversing plants and using reversed
males or reversed females for breeding
and what the future of that holds and
then I was making sure to support the
idea of making feminized seeds there is
a reason for femme seeds a lot of people
hate on FEM seeds a lot of people bash
FEM seeds it's not a lot of people's cup
of tea a lot of people feel about FEM
seed the way I feel about Otto flower
seeds so I completely understand it but
there is a reason and a good purpose for
feminized seed and here is the reason
why I recently reversed a clone of
blueberry skunk I grow for a large
facility
some of those flowers for that facility
were smoked by a very well-known breeder
who has been in this game for longer
than I could ever imagine
he started this [ __ ] he didn't start it
he was one of the first few and he's
still killing it he's ahead of the game
now I don't know if I'm supposed to
disclose who I did this project for or
not because I was actually commissioned
to make these seeds anyhow this breeder
who used to be well known on hash church
and I GC and overgrowth the government
com this guy was a pioneer yes he was a
pioneer he's one of those guys so this
guy smoked some of the flowers that came
from my facility and he said holy [ __ ]
that's got such an amazing flavor what
is that and we told him what it was and
he said can I have some seeds of it and
we said there are no seeds of that it's
kind of a clone only and he said make me
some seeds and that became my job I
reversed it to make seeds for him
because he thinks it's got some amazing
very unique turps and he wants to use it
in his breeding projects now he is in
another country so there's no way to get
him a plant safely legally discreetly I
can't get a clone of the blueberry
cookies to him we can very easily get
him some seeds he can get the seeds to
his own country it's legal for him to
travel there with seeds it is illegal
for him to travel there with a clone so
he can take the seeds so I made the
seeds he wants to work with that so all
I did was reverse the blueberry cookies
I used that pollen I put it back on a
blueberry cookies female and I made s1
seeds now that's gonna show very close
representations of that blueberry
cookies it's gonna be just like it
you're gonna see a little bit variance
closer to mom closer to dad but most of
them are going to be the blueberry
cookies that I started with now he's got
that blueberry cookies and I didn't
adulterate it by adding another male or
another female to the mix and that's
what would happen if I would have taken
a rise or whatever other male I've got
and put pollen on there I would have
adulterated it and watered down that
original genetic but now he's got the
original blueberry cookie seeds
it's an s1 version a selfed version of
the blueberry cookies it's unadulterated
so that is the advantage of working with
feminized seeds the main advantage in my
opinion also men sometimes you just want
to breed some [ __ ] and you don't have a
male of it and the best way to do it is
to reverse it I know that what comes
from that blueberry cookies reversal is
going to be amazing because I've seen
what the female blueberry cookies plant
does and I know it's phenomenal so I
already know that what I use it for you
can already see 5050 what's gonna happen
is you're working with two females so
that's the advantage of making feminized
see you hated on FEM seeds for years but
they definitely speed up your selection
process by years and for people in
Colorado now we're getting limited on
plant counts lower and lower
every time every year they drop our
plant count we used to be able to grow
tons of [ __ ] plants and now I've got
empty grow rooms because we can't grow
as many plants as we used to be allowed
to grow just unplug [ __ ] Gav grow
equipment away we're down to very low
numbers of plants if they keep going
lower it's not even gonna be worth
having a light so people that are
limited to 6 plants they want all 6 of
the seeds that they pop to be female
they don't have time to [ __ ] with a male
they can't run 6 because they think
they're gonna flower 6 they've got a
space they've got six pots they grow
that boy [ __ ] now I gotta wait till the
whole next cycle to run 6 I'm wasting
space it's so and if they can't run
extra they can't run 10 and then call
the boys because now they're already
over their limit so 6 is the limit they
got to run all 6 so that's why FEM seeds
are good for those folk unrelated a bit
I have a lot of pure sativa Sun
preserving and seating for future
generations some of these males are
autoflowering I get rid of those dudes
first yes any do that Otto flowers you
get the [ __ ] rid of them stress him get
him root bound over feed him if he
starts to auto flower get rid of him see
that's why it takes me so long to find a
new male you guys because I abused the
[ __ ] out of him before I take it to a
breeding room ah also here's a rant that
I like to give say you've got a pack of
10 seeds and if you're gonna breed I
hope you're using more than 10 seeds but
10 is a good number to talk about say
you've got 10 seeds and you're gonna
breed out of that pack say you're like
just a hobby breeder you're like oh man
I really want to start breeding I'm
gonna buy a pack of Rasta Jeff's cream
my podcast today is gonna be about the
cream I want to breed I wanna get a pack
of the cream and I want to breed
do you get a 10-pack you're gonna get
hopefully science dictates you're gonna
get five males five females or somewhere
in that you're gonna get four and six or
five and five somewhere around there
right so hopefully you've got I'm gonna
say for the sake of my ramble here that
we got five males and five females if
you're looking for a male to breed you
put those five females aside they don't
count right now they're in another room
we're talking about the boys that first
male that flowers the first one that
starts to drop in his balls real big cut
him down throw them away you don't want
to breed with that one at all at all at
all get rid of him that's the male
that's gonna dominate your cross that is
the one that is going to be just a
reproduction of that plant to everything
you breed if you breed it to star dog if
you breed it to day breaker if you breed
it to platinum tangi it's all gonna come
out like a male plant it's just gonna
ruin your crosses it's gonna make him
it's gonna be a boy it's just gonna be
it's just gonna be that male all over it
all over everything
so the second one you're getting a
little closer to what you want but if
you've got if you've got five boys I
usually find myself using the third or
fourth the third or fourth out of five
are usually what I use the first two
that go to dominant that third one he's
usually the one that's got the right
structure in the right shape the fourth
one is usually right behind there and
the fifth one is usually too tall that
boy that is way [ __ ] tall I get rid
of him
he's gonna be real dominant also if he
likes to stretch so say your girls are
two feet tall you'll have a boy that's
three feet tall I just get rid of him
I've noticed that he just makes tall
tall plants he just wants he makes
plants since one it they want to get up
above everybody so that when the pollen
comes down it rains down but his girls
also do that also it feels like huh so
you got a ten pack you pull out five
girls you got five left those first two
boys get rid of them three and four
those are your breeding prospects most
likely number five he's gonna be tall
and goofy he's probably not the one you
want to use all right that's just from
years of breeding and experimenting and
going through boy plants that's what I
have learned from looking all right
genetic drift bro I don't believe in
genetic drift I don't think I've never
seen it I've never experienced it
I've seen people [ __ ] up plants and try
to take unhealthy clones that are shitty
just because they're unhealthy but then
I have
been given those types of clones I'm not
saying and I'm looking at these clones
and these clones are great I've been
given terrible clones and I've revived
them and then cloned off of that a
hundred times and they've been stellar
dude the flow that I work with let's
talk about flow my flow has been through
hell and back I've had flow since 2007
yeah and that [ __ ] puts out still she
has been through Moot house moves she's
been through me one time I got the flu
and I was so sick that I looked up at my
garden and I was like that needs water
and I threw up and way back to bed
that's how much I cared about my plans
because I was so [ __ ] sick and that
flow she almost went but she's back
cloned off of her she's alive and that
flow was amazing if any of my plants
were gonna show me some genetic drift a
flow would have told me about it she
would have been like look genetic drift
not happening dude I would have
experienced it by now because when I was
a new grower I was a horrible [ __ ]
cloner my grow game was on point from
the beginning but my clone game was weak
I couldn't clone for a long time
shout-out to my friend who got me into
easy cloning it taught me how to clone
then shove it to my new friend who
really stepped up my [ __ ] cloning
game so I don't really think that I
believe too much in genetic drift that's
not something that I support you get
some new gear the sound is great no this
is actually
thanks for the compliment on the sound
here this is the podcast equipment this
is what I record the podcast on I'm just
running into a Mackay mixer I got the
Mackay 1402 that I've had for a hundred
years then I run that into a dbx
compressor because I like the
compression and the gate like watch this
is what it really sounds like in this
room you hear all that [ __ ] noise can
you hear the hum that's my nose but
watch oh yeah
a little compression and sound gating
it's [ __ ] clean right yeah none of
that crap so it's just the podcast gear
got a compressor here a dbx compressor
to channel dbx compressor that runs into
a tascam u.s. 1200 which is what takes
me digital I've got a little preamp on
the mixer that gives me a little turbo
gives me plus 48 to make my mic a little
hotter I've got the game up quite high
quite high I make it I like the game
pretty high my mic it makes it so you
can hear everything I like it crispy I
got the bass turned up a little bit on
my voice just because it gives it a
little more boom and it makes me less
nasally because you can hear got some
[ __ ] in the nose it takes that out a
little bit I turn the compression up
quite high I got the gate quite high and
then I run through GarageBand and I
don't think you guys hear you do hear
the GarageBand effects also I just run a
noise gate on GarageBand and then
there's a bass booster I run two
different tracks at the same time on
Garageband they have two different
effects on them they layer and it just
makes me sound it makes it thicker and
bolder honestly has all it really does I
don't run any exciters or des or
anything and try to keep it mostly
simple but thanks for the sound
compliment thanks for letting me rant
about my sound gear I hope that made
sense to somebody so John Henry 1060
says how often do you change your cloner
water honestly I do not change the
cloner water those cones are only in the
cloner for 10 12 maybe 14 days at the
most I don't feel the need to change the
water what I do is I add a whole bunch
of clear res I've got a 180 site cloner
that I like to use it's the botanic air
180 I just prefer that one lately it
seems to be the most reliable the pump
is better the sprayers are better it
doesn't clog up as much so I will put
the water in the cloner to the desired
level I fill it just below the PVC halo
the water is touching the bottom of that
and then I add clone acts the purple
collect liquid solution I add that until
the EC is at one point one or one point
to you at one point o to one point to
just I'll hold your EC pin in there pour
in go ahead and pour in like 250 mils
spin your EC pin around in that water
and see what the EC is and then keep
adding until you get it to about one
point zero to one point two so now you
got water with solution in there then
cut your clones dip them in the clone ax
put them in the plugs
drop it in the cloner let it run for a
little while then that purple shits
gonna fall off of your plot your clones
the purple clone x gel is gonna fall
into the water let it run for a couple
hours go do some other [ __ ] and come
back unplug it pop it open and check the
pH at that point pH it to somewhere 6.0
is ideal 6.2 will work but somewhere
between 5 9 and 6 to pH that [ __ ] to 5 9
and 6 2 and you will be ideal then add
about 200 to 250 mils of clear rez just
pour it right in there
clear rez and then do that every 5 days
if you add the clear rez every every 5
days you will not have to change your
water the clear rez will take care of
any problems all right so put some clear
as in there and you don't have to change
the cloner water then when it's done
pour 2 cups of bleach in there and let
it keep running for quite a while and
then dump it all out and clean it out no
be fresh and throw the clone plugs away
buy new clone plugs unless you're using
permaculture using pur McClellan's clean
those out appropriately they tell you
how to do them any bottom so if you're
using those use those again shout out to
my friends at perma clone clone callers
if you're using the cheap ones throw
them away buy new ones and I suggest you
check out perma clone if you could get
beans from any time and place what would
it be
that's such a crazy question I'd like to
fly around to like three or five places
in the 70s and get beans before [ __ ] was
adulterated I'd like to go to Thailand
Vietnam Afghanistan and some sort of
South American stuff but I don't know
where or or I'd like to have some of
those seeds of the chem dog hat those 13
beans that chem dog had I'd like to have
10 of those
all right podcast rolled I want to thank
you guys again for listening to an
Instagram clip version of the girl from
your heart podcast thanks for hanging
out with me I know the past couple of
episodes have not been very grow related
but I promise you the next few episodes
will be very grow intensive it's just
kind of the way things timed out for me
I had the opportunity to get granny and
giddy on the show then I had this
episode kind of put together already so
it's how they came out I'll get back to
the girl lessons we will get back going
I know a lot of people are looking
forward to the drank your episode so I
will get that out for you very soon I'll
be back on the girl episodes Monday you
guys so thanks for listening to a couple
of episodes in a row that were filled
with chatter the show is cannabis news
education and conversation we've gotten
a couple of conversations out of the way
I will get back on the education ladies
and gentlemen make sure you follow me on
all the social media I would appreciate
it if you find me on Facebook simply
search for the girlfriend heart podcast
you can find me on Twitter it's at G fyh
podcast and of course find me on
Instagram
it's Irie underscore genetics that's
where you can watch all of my Instagram
live feeds if you're not into social
media and you've got something to say or
you'd like to sponsor the show or you'd
like to send me a product to review you
can reach me through email it's grow
from your heart at hotmail.com and I
would love to hear from you
also don't forget about the patreon
campaign if you feel like this podcast
was educational and/or informative and
you feel like you would like to
contribute to the show financially all
you have to do is go to
patreon.com/crashcourse aport and to
everybody who is contributed to the
patreon big thank you I truly appreciate
all of the support thanks again for
listening to an Instagram live clip of
the podcast I wanna give you huge shout
out to my friend smiley selfie and until
next time take a phat dad and give your
mom a hug for me