you
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for another episode of the
grow from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation let's write up here a new
grower if you're a professional grower
if you're a new smoker or a dedicated
dabber if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who is just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me this episode of the podcast
is brought to you by my friends at the
Hell a dank seed company if you need new
genetics for your garden I highly
recommend the hella dank seed company
you can find them at dank seed dot store
ladies and gentlemen
roll up a fat joint pack up the bong or
start heating up that dab rig because
it's time for another episode of the
grill from your heart podcast welcome
back podcast world it's time for episode
327 of the girl from your heart podcast
thanks again for joining me you know I
like to start the episode off by letting
you know what I'm smoking on today I'm
taking dabs of this New York City diesel
ambrosia batter from apothecary farms
I'm giving it a nice smell right now
this stuff smells like like diesel fuel
with a little bit of lemons make int of
oranges and then there's kind of a sweet
tart sort of smell on top of it that I
really enjoy I one thing about the New
York City diesel and Broza batter here
that I'm smoking on my eyes really don't
get red when I smoke I can smoke and I
don't get red eyed but when I take one
dab of this New York City diesel my eyes
go fully bloodshot red I'm not sure what
does it but I get super red I get super
head hide from it and I really enjoy it
and if that weren't enough I've been
adding this sour amnesia high
cannabinoid full-spectrum extract into
the mix and it just adds a really a nice
it's like turbo charging my dad it is
really nice I like the lung expansion
and the flavor from the New York City
diesel then you put the high cannabinoid
full spectrum extract on top and it
really makes it like a turbocharged dad
so I am in the mood for a podcast you
guys I feel super rambley I feel like I
got a lot of energy let's get into a
podcast this episode is going to be all
about trimming your cannabis plants
that's right we've learned how to tell
when the plants are ripe we've learned
how to cut them down we've learned how
to harvest them we learned how to hang
them until they're ready to snap
we know pretty well how to dry and cure
now let's talk about trimming our plants
now there are two different ways you can
trim there's wet trim and there is dry
trim I definitely prefer dry trim I'm
gonna say why is dry trim better
I think dry trim is better because it's
less sticky and it's much easier to work
with it's also less work the leaves are
dry those leaves are gonna fall off all
you have to do is just brush them with
your thumb maybe touch them with the
scissors and those brittle leaves will
come right off of there the buds have
dried and tightened up and then it's a
little more obvious for a new trimmer
what to take off you just want to take
off that fluffy outside [ __ ] so it's a
little less work it's less sticky and
there's also less chance to ruin your
buds by improperly storing them a lot of
people once the buds are trimmed if they
wet trim they like to just shove them
into a container or a package and then
those wet buds go into a container and
that's when they get ruined so we're not
even gonna let that happen we're gonna
let the buds dry then we're gonna trim
them then we'll put them in a container
now a lot of people have listened to the
dry and curing episode you may be
trimming these buds before they go into
the jar for cure you may be trimming
these buds after they've been in the
cure jar for a little while it's all the
same process the leaves should be
similar in dryness they should just be
popping right off of there you might not
even need scissors for this
sometimes when I'm dry trimming the only
thing I use my scissors for as for
cutting the plant into smaller pieces
and cutting the sticks out and cutting
the bigger buds down to smaller buds now
let's talk about a few preparations we
can make and a few items we can have to
create a comfortable and successful trim
environment for ourselves
trimming sucks it's going to take a long
time you're sitting in a chair with your
elbows up high staring straight into
something for a long time your neck your
elbows your eyes your back that stuff
all gets sore and tired so let's try to
make it as comfortable as possible I
like to have a nice clean space I've got
this table where I like to do my work I
clean the whole table off there's
nothing on the table except my dr.
pepper and some trim supplies maybe my
phone for some entertainment but it's
just there for music I'm not gonna be
touching it don't have your phone out if
you're trimming you guys it's so [ __ ]
distracting and it'll slow you down
it'll take twice as long put on a
podcast hit play
start [ __ ] trim it anyway I like to
have the table nice and clean I don't
need [ __ ] in my way I need maybe my
scissors for cutting
my buds into smaller pieces and then
just a few basic essentials and we'll
talk about those a nice clean space I
also like a nice comfortable chair
you're gonna be sitting there for a
while get a cozy chair so a nice clean
workspace in a cozy chair are super
important for me for trimming but then
you need some sort of entertainment
hopefully you got somebody there to talk
to
usually I got Mike or somebody around to
[ __ ] with some sort of conversation
makes trimming go much more smoothly but
if you don't have that option put on a
podcast you guys I like to put on a
podcast of course I recommend old
episodes if the girl from your heart
podcast put on some Joe Rogan something
like that maybe a YouTube video
something to entertain yourself to
listen to but nothing to look at back in
the day we used to trim all around the
TV and we would watch youtube videos and
trim I found that that is super
distracting don't watch videos people
will put their [ __ ] scissors down and
you'll catch them just watching TV if
you're paying people to trim don't have
a TV in the room podcasts maybe some
stand-up comedy it's hard to get
everybody on the same page when it comes
to music but maybe you play some good
music just some sort of stuff to make it
comfortable and help the time pass
without your brain going crazy is what
I'm getting at you guys so you got a
clean space you got a chair to sit in
you got a good YouTube video on you got
a podcast going so now your cozy your
mind has entertained now you need some
gloves put some rubber gloves on you
want to wear gloves and you're trimming
you're going to get extremely sticky you
don't want to have to itch your face and
have to go wash your hands just to
scratch your face you're gonna be your
hands are gonna be covered in trichomes
and resin you guys wear gloves also you
need some good scissors I like the
little tiny Fiskars diamond tip scissors
that you get you can they're expensive
at the gross store they're cheaper at
Hobby Lobby they saw them in the craft
section right the craft section of Hobby
Lobby that's all of Hobby Lobby there's
some in the fabric section over by the
fabric there Fiskars diamond tip
titanium scissors I really like those
they work really well for trimming
they're super light get something with a
spring in it that opens on its own
because you don't wanna have to be
opening and closing scissors you don't
want the kind of scissors to have loops
that go around your fingers cuz you're
gonna be cutting for so long those
little loops around your fingers are
gonna dig into you you just want
lightweight super fast trimming shears
they're easy to find and they're
affordable maybe get yourselves two pair
so that you can set one in the rubbing
alcohol to clean off
you can dirty up another pair swap them
out real quick and I'll have to spend a
lot of time cleaning your scissors so
you need some good gloves some good
scissors then you need some containers
you need a container for untrimmed buds
I recommend a five-gallon bucket for the
untrimmed buds maybe you don't have that
much herb maybe something smaller will
work then you need another container for
trimmed buds then you need another
container for savable trim and then we
need another container for waste so you
need trimmed buds untrimmed buds usable
trim and waste a couple other things I'm
gonna recommend and you're gonna say why
the hell would he recommend this for a
grow I would recommend either some
coconut oil or some baby oil for your
trim session you're gonna say why do we
need that here is why when your fingers
and hands and arms get all sticky
you can use the coconut oil or the baby
oil to remove the trichomes that's right
if your hands are all covered in resin
my thing is that my arms get covered in
rezident cuz i'm the one cutting down
the plants I'm reaching in there and
playing with them and turning them
around my arm hair and [ __ ] gets all
coated in trichomes and plant resin so I
use a coconut oil or baby oil to just
rub up on my arms and rub that [ __ ]
right off and all the resin comes right
off and then you're not all sticky
alright so that's a basic breakdown of
things that you're going to need for
your trim session you need a nice clean
space in which to work you need a nice
cozy chair in which to sit you need a
good podcast to listen to probably the
girl from your art podcast then you need
some gloves you need scissors then you
need your containers then you've got
your cleanup supplies now let's talk
about doing the manual work hopefully a
few days before harvest you went in and
did a pre harvest defoliation now what I
mean by that is while the plants are
still alive while you're flushing
anywhere between I don't know seven days
before harvest up to the day of harvest
you can go in there and just start
pulling off all of the big leaves the
plants are done growing they're just
flushing out they're just finishing up
the trichomes are ripening up you don't
need all that excess leaf in there so
just go ahead and tear all that leaf out
of the room having a pre harvest
defoliation session will save you a lot
of time when it comes time to trim
because all of that long straggly leaf
is already gone it's not even there to
deal with it's already been removed and
it will also help your drying and curing
time so go in and pull off all the big
leaves before you harvest then it's
harvest time I've done a highly detailed
harvest episode if you haven't listened
to that go listen to that then come
catch up
at the end of the harvest episode we're
left with our plants hanging upside down
in a controlled environment now we want
those plants to get to where the sticks
snap once the sticks get snappy you can
start trimming you can also start
trimming them after they've been in
their cure containers for a little while
I like dry trim I'm just waiting for the
buds to be dry enough to where the
leaves kind of just flake right off
there's still gonna be moisture inside
those buds there's moisture in the
middle but the outside is dry enough to
where you can just kind of knock the
buds off the leaves off the buds with
your thumb I'm making a little motion
with my hands that sort of looks like
I'm playing a video game like I've got a
game controller in my hand but my hands
are really close together in my mind I'm
just holding that little bud with my
four fingers or maybe with my left hand
and I'm just knocking the leaves off
with my right hand just like I'm just it
looks like I'm playing a video game I'm
just holding the bud and just rubbing
the leaves right off if you hold it with
the bud facing up if you rub down those
leaves will just rub right off you'll
see what I'm talking about when you
figure out the technique you go man that
is so easy so my point is that I want it
to where the buds are dry I want to be
able to just knock those leaves right
off so here is how I actually do my
trimming whenever I'm working with the
plants I like to wear gloves so step one
of trimming is put on some rubber gloves
I like the six millimeter nitrile gloves
I don't care if they're black I don't
care if they're blue I just care that
they fit and that they're comfortable so
glove up I don't want to get all sticky
and also I don't want to get my skin all
over the buds so step one is glove up
step two of trimming is to knock all of
the buds off of the sticks into a
five-gallon bucket this makes it so much
easier just go and get everybody off the
sticks into a bucket and then discard
all the sticks now you've compressed
your work into a much smaller space it
looks way less overwhelming and you can
see what you've got ahead of you you've
got a five gallon bucket filled with
buds that you need to trim it doesn't
look like this big sprawl of branches
and leaves and [ __ ] everywhere just a
bucket it's way less intimidating and
you can get through it so knock all the
buds into a bucket maybe you can use
just a small bowl maybe you can use
something smaller I'm not sure how much
you grew maybe you need five buckets I
hope you need ten or twenty five gallon
buckets but find the container that's
the right size for what you need a five
gallon bucket from Home Depot or Lowe's
is really affordable and they're
disposable so I like to use the buckets
so I knock everybody
into a bucket now I've got a five-gallon
bucket full of buds my next step is just
to reach in grab the butt off the top
and start trimming now I'll actually
start talking about trimming a little
bit and the actual trimming of the bud
process the idea is to knock or cut off
all of the excessive leaves and stems
and give yourself a nice pretty
presentable but you guys know what a
good trimmed bud looks like when they
start off they're covered in leaves it's
our job to knock those leaves off we
don't want to smoke leaves leaves
contain chlorophyll leaves don't taste
good leaves don't get you high what we
want is a nice frosty green nugget so
once you guys get started trim and
you'll see what's leaf material and what
is a usable but once you start digging
in there and just start knocking off
some of the leaf you'll find that bud in
the middle and it will start to become
very obvious what you do and do not trim
if your buds are kind of airy and fluffy
don't trim too deeply just knock off the
leaves I like to grab the bud by the
base by that little stick at the bottom
of the bud and just use my thumb to push
the leaves off I just kind of spin the
bud in a circle with my left hand I will
turn it I'm looking that's
counterclockwise no that is clockwise
I'll turn the bud clockwise and as it
comes toward me I'll use my right thumb
I'm using my left hand to spin the bud
toward me and is that one side come
towards me comes toward me my thumb just
knocks the leaves off right there I'm
just wiping them off like I'm just just
scraping the leaves off they're so dry
that they knock off on their own and
don't press so hard that you're [ __ ]
up the shape of the bud and knocking off
trichomes you can do this really gently
you'll find the technique after you do
it a few times it'll be really
comfortable and you'll get really fast
at it a lot of people like to do this
with scissors they'll hold it in the
left hand and they'll take their
scissors and just turn it and trim it
the leaves are sticking off horizontally
just keep your scissors horizontal you
can get adjust your angle as you need
and just spin that bud and keep cutting
just like you're giving it a haircut you
just want to take off those leaves and
leave that bud there so just knock off
the leaves don't carve too deeply into
the buds and don't squish the buds while
you're trimming them don't squeeze them
super hard and try not to handle them
too much a little tiny bud doesn't need
a lot of handling you don't want to get
all those trichomes on your gloves you
want to leave the trichomes on the bud
so you can use scissors if you want I
like my thumbs for most trimming you
guys the little edge of my thumb and my
thumbnail is a perfect little trimmer
form
I've mastered that technique I knock off
the little leaves and cut the big buds
into smaller sizes if you guys can see a
stick in there and it's like one bud and
then a little stick in another bud take
that [ __ ] out nobody wants to buy a
stick connoisseur quality bud is taken
down to the small part if you want to
leave your buds in big buds that's fine
it's up to you I like them smaller a lot
of people don't want to buy a big stick
you'll see people I don't know you'll
have some customers that want big buds I
used to have people that just wanted big
buds and then some people know better
they're like man I don't want to buy
that quarter that one one bud that
weighs a quarter because I know right up
the middle of it as a gram of stick and
I'm getting ripped off so some people
want it some people don't
that's up to you so once you've got it
trimmed up to the size you want it and
the the amount of trim you want I cut
off all the little leaves at the bottom
also there's like a lot of people leave
a little cabbagey looking leaves at the
bottom I cut that [ __ ] off
I call it cabbage and I also take out
the handlebar sticks on the bottom
you're gonna have the branch that the
bud was actually stuck to the branch to
and then there's two little sticks that
come out that those first leaves were
attached to and they're all dry and
should you look and cut those off of
there if you've got a pound of weed and
you've got all those little tiny stakes
in there
those little sticks make your pound look
like [ __ ] just take it out and your
pound is gonna look so much better it's
gonna be so much more desirable it's
gonna get you more money all right so
that's the bottom line here trim it and
it's worth more money so take off all
the leaves take off that little stick at
the bottom knock off all the crow's feet
if you've got a little tiny pointy leaf
sticking out of somewhere cut that out
or knock it off with your thumb those
little triangle leaves make you look
lazy if you did a whole good job on most
of the bud and you just left one or two
little triangles at the tip you look
lazy take that stuff out of there so
while I'm doing this all the trimming
work I trim over a tray or a container
to catch what I trim off all that little
stuff that gets clipped off is going to
be used to make concentrates or edibles
in the future so gather all that stuff
up take care of it don't just don't trim
into the floor and then sweep it up
don't trim onto the table and then scoop
it up trim onto a tray trim into a
container so that it is kept clean so
it's treated with respect because it may
go into edibles and things that you're
gonna eat need to be treated with
respect things you're gonna smoke need
to be treated with respect this is our
medicine so gather this stuff up and
vacuum seal it I like
to keep the trim in a vacuum-sealed bag
in the dark until I'm able to use it get
that to your extractor as soon as you
can now the sticks those are thrown away
I throw all the sticks away and a
commercial grow they're thrown away in a
home grow those should go to the compost
pile or they can be burned or something
but the sticks are trash don't try to
extract sticks you guys that's a waste
of time it's a waste of energy you're
not gonna get anything out of it and
also if you're adding the sticks to the
trim you're just making the hash worse
you're not making it better what goes in
comes out and if you just put [ __ ] in to
make more you're gonna get more but it's
gonna be [ __ ] so gather up all your trim
vacuum seal the trim keep the trim in a
dark place and get that to somebody that
can turn that into concentrates for you
also
if you've got like yellow or brown or
funky leaves that are falling off as
you're trimming separate those pull
those out of the trim don't send that to
the extractor that's gonna make your
hash and dark that's gonna make your
hash taste like [ __ ] it's gonna make it
less potent and it's gonna make it less
desirable so do a little work clean it
up get it out of there and you will have
a better product so use your thumbs or
some scissors to gently remove the
excess leaves and the little stems from
the buds get rid of the handlebars get
rid of the crow's feet
now once the buds are trimmed to your
satisfaction you can place them into a
container for finished products now when
I say to your satisfaction how you want
to trim your buds is up to you if you
want to leave it a little fluffy go for
it you want to trim it nice and tight go
for it that is up to you if your product
is for you personally then you can leave
it as leafy as you want you can knock
those leaves off right before you smoke
it you can clean it up yourself if you
plan on getting top dollar for your
product you'll need to have a tight
clean trim job one thing I should
mention that will help us speed up the
process of trimming is the rule of thumb
if the bud you were trimming is not
bigger than the tip of your thumb it's
probably better to let that bud go to
your hash pile and trim something more
substantial put those little popcorn
buds in the hash pile put it in your
trim pile and you can make better hash
that will improve the quality of your
concentrates so if it's a little tiny
bud don't waste time trimming it just
throw it in the hash pile and don't
waste your time trimming little tiny
buds if you feel like that little tiny
bud is worth less money then
time it is taking you to trim it set it
aside and put it in the hash pile you
don't have to trim that if herb costs
ten dollars a gram and it takes you like
a minute to trim that little nug it's
not cost-effective so toss that little
nugge into the trim bin we'll add that
to the concentrates grab something that
we can trim and get on the shelf and
make it purchasable for the consumer so
if it's real tiny if it's ugly
don't bother trimming it you can put
that in your hash pile you can add that
to the to be extracted pile and that
will just improve your concentrates it
will also speed you up of course if you
need every little half gram every piece
of gravel out of that crop to make your
goal to make your wait go ahead and trim
that up add that that'll be weight in
the bottom of the bag but if it's not
necessary if it's just for you put that
in the concentrate pile and speed
yourself up and the commercial grow the
growers are expected to kick out a pound
minimum per person per shift some people
turn in two pounds every day and if they
spend time trimming that little gravel
[ __ ] they would never get there we have
a way of separating all those little
tiny buds all that little stuff gets
filtered out it gets pushed to the side
and then all of that those little buds
and the trim and they're combined and it
gets turned in to concentrates so do a
nice tight trim if you want to sell it
but don't go overboard don't trim it too
tight and also don't try trimming all
those little buds or you're gonna put
yourself in debt you've got to pay your
trimmers you're spending your time make
it cost-effective
now something I want to mention trimming
will be very strain dependent some buds
are tight some buds are real fluffy some
buds are a little compacted little rocks
you can just kind of rub your fingers
over those and those are gonna trim some
buds are airy and have a lot of texture
to them those are gonna be a little
harder to trim because you don't want to
knock off all those calyxes you're going
to have to adjust also if you're working
for somebody else you're going to have
to adjust to how they want it trimmed
when you go to a grow and you're working
for someone else they get to dictate how
tight your trim is don't over trim don't
under trim you trim to their expectation
if you're not sure what they want
have them trim up a bud and show you
have them trim up two or three buds and
set those at your workstation so you
have something to refer to as the day
goes on so that you don't forget and
also if they come by and say hey why you
doing it like that you got a couple
little buds to show them you can say
these are what you showed me this is
what I did show me the difference show
me where I'm going wrong then they can
say [ __ ] you're doing it just like I
showed you I'm sorry so we got a nice
tight trim we're setting the trim in one
pile we're setting our little tiny buds
in another pile we're mixing that up so
we can make good concentrates out of it
we're getting rid of all the sticks you
guys I think we have covered most of
trimming one great thing about trimming
is scissor and glove hash all that
sticky [ __ ] that builds up on your
gloves and scissors is smokeable you can
smoke that right away Mike loved scissor
hatch Oh what I like to do if I've got
if I've been trimming so see even trim
and you've got this weird layer of like
sticky gooey looking [ __ ] all over your
gloves that's resin that's trichomes
that is potency rub your hands together
and you'll start figuring out how to rub
your hands in a circle to make that
stuff stick together a little bit of
heat goes a long way so if your hands
get warm it'll start taking that resin
right off of your hands I don't want to
smoke it off your skin back in the day
we used to call it finger hash but
please wear gloves now and we're gonna
call it glove hatch you can scrape it
off your scissors you can smoke it off
your gloves then put it in a bowl you
can put it on top of some pot or just
put it in an empty bowl and just put a
flame to it and melt it just slowly melt
that [ __ ] until it starts smoking and
you can smoke that sizzurp hash that
glove hash you can smoke it right away
but please don't pass that [ __ ] to me if
you did that off your skin and weren't
wearing gloves I don't want to smoke
your skin so that's one good thing about
trimming is you get scissor hash right
away I think that anything that sticks
to your gloves
that's yours you get to smoke that if
you come trim for me and that [ __ ]
sticks to your gloves I have no problem
with you rolling that right off your
glove put that in a pipe and smoke it
right in front of me you earned that
that is your scissor hatch that means
you're trimming your ass off if it's on
your scissors scrape your scissors off
smoke that [ __ ] what a lot of people
will do all the trimmers in the room
will just gather all their scissor hash
into one pile and put it into a big ball
and then at the end of the day you guys
all smoke that together it's like a
little celebration but it's smokeable
that's my point
you can make edibles out of it if you
want to but I would recommend smoking it
Mike loves smoking it's not my favorite
to smoke it's a little law it's heavy on
the lungs and it tastes kind of wet but
it is potent and it will give you a big
fat hit another great thing about dry
trimming that I didn't mention is that
when you were done trimming you can now
weigh your product you've been cutting
off the extra crap and throwing that in
one piled and even throw in those spin
buds into one pile all you got to do is
set that container on the scale and
weigh it now one thing I would recommend
it's a good idea whatever container
you're going to throw your buds into
your finished buds if it's gonna be a
bucket if it's gonna be a Tupperware
container wave that and write the weight
of that on your container so that when
you're done trimming into that container
you know how much that weighs
so just subtract the weight of your
container and now you know how much
product is on the scale so it's always
rewarding knowing how much product
you've got right at the end of the trim
process when you wet trim you don't know
cuz you've got a way for it to dry still
so when people say how much did you trim
today and they said I trimmed a black
pound how do you know bro it was wet
it's got a dry we'll find out in a few
days so if you're paying people to trim
by the pound dry trim is the way to go
because now you've got dry pounds to
weigh you don't have a wet pound to
guess on the weight so here's one more
thing I should definitely mention to all
of my friends who have never trimmed
before everybody who is new with
cannabis here's something that I have to
tell you when you were trimming or
working with plants in general do not
touch your eyes with sticky trim fingers
don't rub your eye with the back of your
hand go wash your hands before you touch
your eyes if you rub your eyes with
trichomes or plant resin on your finger
it is going to burn for the next hour
and it is sticky every time you blink
most of the time you think you can blink
and it'll fix your sticky eye or
whatever is in your eye not when you
have resin in your eye every time you
blink it gets [ __ ] stickier and it
feels like your eyelid is sticking to
your eyeball and it just burns so wear
gloves and if you need to itch your eye
take your [ __ ] glove off your hand
VIN it your eye I would almost consider
washing my hands before the itch take
the glove off go wash the hand then
scratch the eye but I understand
sometimes you just got to stick your
finger in your eye cuz shit's going
weird take that glove off you guys don't
put plant resin or trichomes in your eye
it will [ __ ] suck that's the
technical term for it it [ __ ] sucks
there's no other way to describe it it
[ __ ] sucks you guys alright
so I feel like I've given you a pretty
good lesson on trimming I know I didn't
teach you exactly how to trim be active
holding the bud and putting the scissors
to it is something you're going to have
to experience you will develop your
technique in your style I feel like I've
given you a pretty good outline you know
what to do with the product you know how
to get it there you just need some
practice doing it get some buds
put some scissors to him that's the only
way you're gonna get good at it it's the
only way you're gonna get faster at it
when we hire new trimmers at the grow we
don't always hire the people that claim
to be the fastest trimmers we hire the
people that interview well and seem like
they're gonna fit in with the crew if
they say they can only trim a half a
pound of weed when they start that is
fine if that is real if they say they
can trim a half a pound and they only do
a quarter pound then I've got issues but
they say I can trim a half a pound in a
day I'm fine with that we will train
them we will teach them our system we'll
teach them some tricks they'll get in
they'll get a rhythm they'll get a
routine and eventually they'll be
trimming a pound and a half a day so
it's all about just finding the rhythm
it's all about finding the groove and it
takes you a little bit of time and
experience to get in there and do it
also these are buds these are precious
to people I've been in this industry for
a long time I can grab a flowering plant
that's a few days in and just cut that
[ __ ] down and feel no remorse or
anything if that's what needed to happen
in a commercial grow
I killed a plant a lot of people treat
little buds like they're the most
precious thing they've ever seen which I
respect you don't get to grow a bunch of
plants I have produced over a ton of
cannabis in my life I am responsible for
a ton of cannabis but having been
produced a lot of people don't have that
under their belt so every bud is
precious to them they don't want to [ __ ]
up one single but I get that so when
they're new at it they go really slow
especially a higher trimmer that is not
their product that is your bud that
they're playing with respect them for
taking their time and going slow with it
but also encourage them to go faster you
have to learn and go faster but people
like to go slow in the beginning because
they're playing with gold they don't
they're playing with a little pieces of
gold they got little babies in their
hand and they're new so they're kind of
intimidated so keep that in mind you'll
get faster as time goes on is what I'm
trying to say you guys you just need
some practice you'll become a good
trimmer if you want to become a good
trimmer and if you want to get your foot
in the door in the commercial marijuana
industry being a trimmer is probably the
number one way to get in the door
trimmers and bud tenders are how you get
started so trimming can be really
time-consuming and tedious but it is the
last step before you claim victory in
your garden if your garden is for sale
you're one step away from money if your
garden is for medicinal uses you're one
step away from feeling better
so trimming sucks but you're almost
there it's it's the hardest most
time-consuming tedious part in my
opinion it is my least favorite part but
it is one step away from sweet success
all right podcast rolled I hope this
trimming lesson made sense again the
only way to get good at trimming is to
get sticky and get some practice get in
there get your gloves dirty get your
scissors all sticky and start trimming
up some weed if you want to learn and
you've got friends that are harvesting
volunteer to trim for free everybody
could use a free trimmer and we know
we're gonna have to teach you that's
fine but we hope that in a few harvests
you're gonna show up and you're gonna
trim your ass off like a savage so there
are people that will help you learn by
letting you trim for free if you get
those opportunities please do take them
ladies and gentlemen I'm sure I left
something out I'm sure I miss something
if I sparked any questions with this
episode I invite you to email me all of
your questions my email address is grow
from your heart at hotmail.com I would
love to hear what i skiped I'd love to
hear what I left out or if you've got
some other random questions I will
answer those also once again it's grow
from your heart at hotmail.com ladies
and gentlemen thanks for listening to
the trimming episode here is the part
where I pitch my patreon campaign I
would truly appreciate your support on
patreon if you feel like this podcast
was worth a couple of bucks and you were
able to contribute financially you can
do so by going to patreon.com slash grow
from your heart that's p80 r0n
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
if you'd like to contribute to the
podcast all the information that you
need will be right there
if you contribute to the podcast I will
use those contributions to pay for the
website that keeps the podcast free for
everybody and I will also use those
contributions to pay for the upgraded
MacBook I bought so that I can keep the
podcast coming and keep the videos
coming to everybody for free you guys I
will never charge you for this podcast
as long as I am able to put this podcast
out for free it will be free for you as
well I may in the future release some
paid content which will be bonus content
but this version of the podcast in this
format always will be free iTunes
stitcher and the YouTube channel as it
is will always be free I do this because
I love cannabis and I love you and I
want you to be able to medicate and
recreative esthe ways possible with the
highest quality
cleanest safest products available and I
think the only way you can do that is by
growing it yourself so I've got to teach
you how to do that so that you don't
have to rely on anybody else so my point
is that the podcast will be free but I
know there are people out there who
would like to contribute because they
emailed me and they said hey Jeff how
can we help you out
so patreon is the best way to do that
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
also I would appreciate it if you stalk
me on the social media you can find me
on Facebook simply search for the girl
from your heart podcast on Twitter it's
at g f YH podcast and on instagram i use
my other company name it's I read
genetics i RIE underscore genetics on
Instagram make sure you follow me there
you guys don't forget that the podcast
is available on iTunes stitcher and
every single episode is archived on the
youtube channel simply search for the
girl from your heart podcast you guys
don't forget to check out our friends at
the hell a dank seed company you can
find them at dank seed dot store thanks
again for listening to this episode
everybody I'll be back Monday with a
brand new episode I want to give you a
huge shout out to my friend grim bolt
the druid and until next time take a
phat dab and give your mom a hug for me