yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for another episode of the
grow from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation let's write of here a new
grower if you're a professional grower
if you're a new smoker or a dedicated
dabber if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who is just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me this episode of the podcast
is brought to you by my friends at the
hell a dank seed company if you need new
genetics for your gardening I highly
recommend the hella dank seed company
you can find them at Bank seed dot store
ladies and gentlemen
roll up a fat joint pack up the bong or
start heating up that dab rig because
it's time for another episode of the
grill from your heart a podcast welcome
back podcast world it's time for episode
328 if the girl from your heart podcast
thanks again for joining me you know I
like to start the show off by letting
you know what I'm dabbing today I'm
smoking star dog ambrosia batter from
our friends at apothecary farms if you
know me you know I love the star dog I
love the aroma I love the flavor I love
the high I love the way it grows and of
course I love taking pictures of star
dog she's a very photogenic strain so
today I'm taking dabs of star dog and
Broz your batter from our friends at
apothecary now if you've been following
the show lately you've probably caught
the episodes about determining ripeness
of your cannabis plants then we did an
episode about flushing your plants then
we did an episode about harvesting then
we did an episode about drying and
curing your cannabis plants then we did
an episode about trimming now it is time
to clean up the grow room and get
restarted for the next cycle let's talk
a little bit about after harvest
cleaning it sounds pretty basic but
there are a few things you may overlook
now if you had bugs or powdery mildew
you may want to step up your cleaning
product you may want to step up your
cleaning regimen but if you didn't have
any bugs or any issues I think a light
bleach and water solution should work or
maybe you might want to get yourself
some flies in and use 15 to 20 mils a
thousand per gallon of water use that to
clean up
whole grow either way whatever product
do you use let's clean everything let's
clean the walls wipe down every inch of
every wall start at one section at the
top and just work your way down and to
the right and then just keep going until
you've covered every inch of that grow
room also if you can reach scrub the
ceiling if you can't reach find me I can
probably reach if not get a ladder scrub
the ceiling
let's clean it with either bleach and
hot water or FISA and hot water and just
get anything off of there that may be
hiding that we don't want in that grow
room maybe you've got a spider light up
there chilling out maybe you've got a
little bit of powdery mildew Spore that
you don't know about maybe there's a
piece of pollen up there that you don't
know about let's clean everything just
to be sure so clean the walls clean the
ceiling clean your light reflectors
clean the whites the top of the lights
they're probably dusty up on top the
reflectors they're dusty on the inside
clean those things take this opportunity
while the rooms empty and clean
everything you guys so take the white
reflectors down if you think they need
some cleaning clean them hang them back
up clean your fans take the fans off of
the wall take the little grate off the
front unscrew the little thing that
holds the blades on take the blades off
clean the blades I know they're dirty
fans get disgusting the grate on the
back is filled with muck and hair and
just weird random gunk that I can't even
tell you what it is
clean that [ __ ] out of there you're
probably gonna be disgusted that you've
been blowing that [ __ ] around in your
grow clean your fans while you're
cleaning the fans look at anything that
moves air or blows air look at the air
return on your dehumidifier that thing's
pulling in a bunch of water and a bunch
of air and then it's blowing air back
out does that filter need to be changed
does that dehumidifier need to be
cleaned off is the water line it's
draining water out of your dehumidifier
is it gunky does it need to be cleaned
is the reservoir that you're dreaming
your dehumidifier water into starting to
develop slime and algae if so you need
to clean that stay on top of those sort
of things so clean the walls clean the
whites clean the fans clean your
dehumidifier dust everything the top of
everything is dusty the top of
everything is funky you've been spraying
pesticides in there
imagine you sprayed some stain
he pesticide like as a max in there then
it got dusty it's just sticking to the
eyes of Max it's funky it's gross clean
everything wipe it and dust the tops of
everything clean your hydro tables if
you've got tables in the room clean them
if you've got trays and you can take
them outside take them outside spray
them down with the hose if you've got a
power washer hit him look the power
washer if those tables are real dirty
scrub them down with some Phi's and
scrub them down with some bleach make
sure you rinse them out real good and
just get them real clean you guys are
the Phi's n is gonna foam up be prepared
for that you're gonna make foam with
flies an and make sure you clean
everything out when you're done using
cleaning products clean out your tables
and reservoirs really well if you use a
cleaning product but rinse the [ __ ] out
of those hydro tables rinse the [ __ ] out
of all your tubing and all of your lines
clean that stuff so that it's not
clogged and so there's no algae in there
here's something people don't pay enough
attention to clean the floor yes I know
we just walk on the floor all day right
sweep it mop it clean it up if you've
got some sort of poly film or panda film
on the floor some sort of subfloor
doesn't need to be replaced are there
holes in it has your poly or your Panda
film started stretching and getting
holes from the staples you need to duct
tape some spots check that kind of stuff
out clean your floors everything lands
on the floor the floor is gross clean it
up also here's something I should
mention if you've got light reflectors
with glass on them so that they're
air-cooled clean that glass take that
glass out wipe that [ __ ] down with some
Windex let it dry and put it back clean
the reflector glass also clean all of
your air conditioner filters check them
make sure they are clean if you've got
ducting anywhere check your ducting make
sure the ducting isn't bent in any weird
places make sure there are no clogs make
sure all of your duct is secured make
sure it's duct taped or clamped
somewhere so that the air you're trying
to move away from the grow doesn't
accidentally end up being blown right
where you don't need it if you've got a
leak that air is just gonna come flying
out of there you may just be moving the
heat from the light right back into the
grill room then your air conditioner has
to work harder and you can't figure out
why the room isn't cooling down and it
gets frustrating so check all of your
ducting check your carbon filter is that
carbon filter still filtering can you
smell the herb out
when you grow did anybody mention that
your harvest stunk really badly how long
have you had that carbon filter did you
write it down you should know when that
carbon filter needs to be replaced a lot
of the brands say they will last two
years I never believe in that I've never
had a carbon filter last two years
also that carbon filter cover maybe
you're gonna leave that filter there for
two years and it's got that little dust
cover on it take that ugly thing off
throw it in the washer with some oxy
clean and clean that thing nobody wants
to see your pictures of your black and
gray carbon filter dust cover that is
gross
also you guys get in there and clean out
the reservoir if you've got a reservoir
that you mix your nutrients in or that
you use as part of your hydro system
that you're pumping your nutrients from
right to your plants clean that
reservoir why wouldn't you want a clean
fresh start you don't want biofilm and
funk in there because that's going
directly to your plants also clean all
of the tubing I've already said that
once but clean it all because all that
gunk will end up into your plants
another thing we should remember to
clean is the emitters if you've got a
hydro system with some sprayers or
emitters or sprinklers at the end of a
line make sure you pop those emitters
off and clean them they like to get
filled with some gunky funk now is the
perfect opportunity to take all those
off and clean them up real well another
really important thing we can do while
we've got the room taken down we can
decide if we need to replace any bulbs
how long have your bulbs been in the
grow depending on what type of lighting
you're using it may be time to swap out
some bulbs when bulbs get old they still
draw the same amount of electricity but
they do not put out the same amount of
light so you're paying for that
electricity and it is not making it to
your plants so check your bulbs and see
if they need to be replaced a good way
to find out if they need to be replaced
is to get a lumen meter a lumen meter
will measure how much light is coming
from your bulb if your bulb is putting
out less than 75 or 80 percent of its
maximum output it is time to replace it
now how do you know what the maximum
output of that bulb is the way to find
that out is to buy a brand new bulb put
the bulb in your reflector and turn it
on then you've got to wait a few minutes
and let that bulb get to its maximum
brightness it takes a little while for
the bulbs to heat up and get to the
right spectrum and get all the way
bright once it's bright and all the way
heated up go about 12 to 18 inches from
that bulb and measure what the lumens
are right there and write it down write
down the date and the amount of lumens
then check it now when you're cleaning
the room go the same distance away with
that lumen meter and see how many lumens
are popping up if you're not satisfied
with the amount of power you're getting
out of that bulb it is time to replace
it if you feel like you're paying for
electricity that it's not making it to
your plants it is time to replace your
bowl the lumen meters may be expensive
but a lot of times the grow shop will
let you borrow one because they know
that if your bulbs are bad you're
probably just gonna come buy more bulbs
when you return the lumen meter so ask
him at the gross store they may have one
available that you can borrow all right
guys
most of the cleaning stuff should be
fairly obvious clean the [ __ ] out of
everything scrub everything if you're
gonna put plants in anything that had a
cleaner in it make sure you get that
cleaner out replace the bulbs replace
the filters some other things we may not
remember to think about our check and
reset your timers and all of your
programs if you've got your lights on a
certain schedule fix that schedule if
you've got your co2 or your auto
watering on a schedule make sure you
correct that schedule before you put new
plants in here did daylight savings time
happen check that is the timer on the
right time is your timer on the right
day a lot of the controllers have a day
that you can set is it Monday Tuesday or
Wednesday is that the proper day do you
have AM and PM set properly make sure
you check out all of your controllers
before you put plants in there and you
accidentally flower them way too early
also check out all of your co2 controls
another thing I like to do at this point
in time is calibrate all of my pens and
meters I like to calibrate my pH pen I
like to make sure that my EC meter is
working properly these are all things
that you should check on between
harvests I like to calibrate my meters
about once every two weeks to tell you
the truth probably every 10 days I just
like to check on them and make sure that
those things are accurate another thing
you should have a fire extinguisher near
your grow check on that look at
little gauge on there make sure it's in
the green if your fire extinguisher
gauge is not in the green either buy a
new one or take it to the fire
department and have it refilled
correctly I really hope you don't have
to use that fire extinguisher but if you
need it I really want it to work for you
also check the batteries in your smoke
alarm yes I said smoke alarm your grow
should have a smoke alarm you don't want
to burn down the house because something
went wrong in the grow room and you did
not have a smoke detector and a fire
extinguisher so be a responsible grower
make sure that the safety precautions
are in place now since we're checking on
the fire extinguisher and the smoke
alarm it is a good time to check on your
respirator are you using a respirator to
apply pesticides
I really hope you're using something to
keep yourself safe if you're using a
respirator now is the time to check
those cartridges how long have they been
on there is it time to replace them is
that respirator clean maybe it's time to
watch a Google video and learn how to
properly clean and take care of your
respirator that thing is going to save
your life over time take care of that
also it's a good time to replace your
gloves do you need more nitrile gloves
do you need more time x suits now is a
really good time to make a list and go
to the gross store and stock up on those
types of items alright so we've got the
grill room nice and clean we have
checked all of our safety precautions
we've refilled all of the necessary
supplies now it's a good time to do a
quick inventory of your pesticides and
nutrients and any accessories you think
you may need if you're gonna need
pesticides or nutrients start ordering
that stuff now so that when you move
your plants back into the room you have
got all of the nutrients and all the
supplies you need so that you don't miss
a day of the grow cycle so we've got
everything cleaned up we've checked out
all of our safety equipment we've
restocked of our personal protective
equipment we have reordered all of our
nutrients now if we didn't have any
problems with pests or powdery mildew it
is time to start running that room and
get it prepared for the next cycle now
if you did have pests or problems there
are a couple of more steps that we need
to take we need to clean this room
thoroughly we need to spray it with some
products we might want to go a little
harder with the bleach water we might
want to go a little hard
with some Phi's an you might want to get
a product called procure if you had
powdery mildew you're gonna want to
spray something to get rid of the spores
in that room if you had bugs I would
recommend spraying some sort of
pesticide through the entire room just
mix up your pesticide sprayer your pump
sprayer if you don't have one go get one
from Lowe's get a good one
get a deck sprayer that can handle
bleach because you're gonna be putting
some chemicals in here they're not that
expensive you just need one that holds
about a gallon maybe two gallons of
water fill it up with water put your
cleaning product in there whether it's
Faiz an whether it's procure whether
it's a bunch of bleach maybe you want to
use granulated sulfur if you had a PM
issue mix that up spray the [ __ ] out of
the entire room this is your best
opportunity to spray everything and
eliminate your problem there are no
plants in there so you can use products
that you wouldn't spray when you've got
plants in there so get in there and
clean the [ __ ] out of the room I would
start with the normal cleaning I
recommend it take everything down and
clean it then put it back up then setup
the room and before you put the plants
in there go in there with this extra
hard commando cleaning spray and go
really hard you guys you got to get all
of the bugs out of there or you're just
gonna bring plants in there and they're
gonna get bugs or they're gonna get PM
and you're gonna have another struggling
harvest and nobody likes to struggle
through a harvest so now we've taken
everything apart we've cleaned the [ __ ]
out of the room we've replaced the bulbs
we've replaced all of our filters we
have calibrated all of our equipment
we've got new protective equipment we
have tested our safety equipment we've
put the room back together we've gone in
there and done another final spray maybe
we hit it with thighs in maybe we
sprayed procure on everything to try to
get rid of our problems
maybe we just sprayed bleach water real
hot bleach water in there maybe we went
in there with some h2o too that would
work really well also but if you use any
type of product like that you guys make
sure you wear personal protective
equipment some goggles and a respirator
you don't want to spray bleach you don't
want to spray h2o2 you don't want to
spray flies in without some sort of
protective equipment that shit'll be
terrible for your eyes terrible for your
skin please take care of yourself and if
you're using a sprayer to spray anything
please use some sort of
respiratory protection please now once
the room is put back together
here is something I suggest I would turn
on the lights I would turn on your
blowers I would turn on the fans I would
turn on the air-conditioner and I would
let everything run for a few minutes and
I would stand in the room and pay
attention is there anything wrong is
there anything you could dial in is
there anything you could adjust do it
while you're in there then go outside
and walk around your grow space if your
grow is at your house just go walk
around the house just go pick up trash
around the house or whatever and see if
you can identify any light leaks do you
see light coming out of your grow room
if you see light coming out there is
light going in we do not want and cannot
have light leaks in our grow room so
walk around the house walk around the
perimeter identify any possible light
leaks also listen do you hear the
blowers do you hear the fans do you hear
your air conditioner is anything outside
making it obvious that you're running
aggro in that house this is a good time
to discover that we've got light leaks
or that we've got noisy equipment so
that we don't get ourselves in trouble
you do not want to attract law
enforcement it may be legal where you
grow it is legal where I grow I am still
stealth because you know who's worse
than law enforcement [ __ ] thieves you
don't want people to know you've got to
grow in your house because somebody may
come and take your crop from you that is
a real thing keep that in mind you have
to be careful even in a legal state keep
your grow stealth so walk around outside
look listen smell pay attention see if
anything is going wrong outside once
you're sure that everything is fine
outside that's when you can go back in
the grow room turn off the lights in the
grow room and stand in there for about
ten minutes let your eyes adjust now is
the time to find out if any light is
leaking into the grow now is the time to
find out if the sunshine from outside is
coming through your ducts for your
vented hoods
right into your light reflectors into
your grow room and shining light on your
plants during a dark period now is the
time to find that out now the catch to
these last two things
you're only gonna be able to tell if you
have a light leak outside if you go walk
around the house and it's dark outside
the only way you can tell if you have a
light leak inside is if it's light
outside and you go in the grow room and
you turn off the lights on the inside of
the grow room so you're gonna have to
find the time of day to do that you're
gonna have to do some investigating and
some inspecting but these are very
important details to not overlook make
sure your grow room is light proof make
sure there's not a lot of noise coming
out of there and also find out if you've
got too much aroma and correct it if you
do you don't want to attract attention
that you don't need once you've been
growing for a while or if you're
somebody who is looking for grows so say
myself I've been growing for a long time
when I used to go walk my dog in my
neighborhood I would always discover a
new grow I would go a different route
I'd go two blocks that way three blocks
that way I block that way and then I'd
come back and then the next day I'd just
do a different pattern I would always
find a new grow about once a week
because I know what I'm looking for
listening for and smelling for I know
the details I know the clues if I hear
you're weird blower at 3:00 in the
morning going from your basement window
chances are you got to grow in there if
you've got an air conditioner in your
basement window in the middle of winter
chances are there's a grow in there if
you've got one window by the basement it
has no snow and the rest of the backyard
is snowy there's a grow in there if
there's one spot on your roof above one
bedroom that there's no snow on it
there's a girl in there there are really
easy signs that give it away so pay
attention you guys because if I can see
it
law enforcement can see it and so can
the thieves so be careful with your grow
try to stay stealth even in legal states
there's no reason to brag there's no
reason to set bait
all right podcast world I feel like that
is a pretty good clean and reset episode
hopefully I mentioned some details that
you would have overlooked hopefully I
rescued you through a couple of pitfalls
now you don't have to make those
mistakes hopefully everything was well
in your grow and you don't have any
problems hopefully you don't have
anything funky to deal with also now
that the grow is nice and clean let's
[ __ ] keep it clean let's get in there
with a mop and a broom every day if we
need to and mop and sweep that [ __ ]
let's get in there with a shop vac and
suck
you know that [ __ ] in the corner you've
been looking at get the [ __ ] shot
back and back that out it's not gonna
shot back itself and that's a great
place for a spider mite to hang out
that's a great place for some aphids to
hang out and breed that's a great place
for some powdery mildew to start that is
just a vector for problems so now that
you've got it nice and clean don't be
lazy get in there and clean it as often
as you can
they say that cleanliness is godliness
and I think that most applies in
kitchens and grow rooms you guys so
clean up that grow room
give yourself a nice clean environment
give your plants a nice healthy start I
think your plants will be more
comfortable and I think you will also
notice working in a cleaner more
organized environment will make you
happier
it'll make you faster and more
productive and [ __ ] now that you're done
cleaning up the grow room why don't you
clean up all your supplies go organize
your nutrients go organize the
pesticides the measuring devices your
cleaning supplies go write down a list
of anything that you can need anything
that you're low on go get yourself
organized also get a notebook and start
making detailed notes start documenting
when you changed your bulb start
documenting when you change your carbon
filter start documenting the last time
you change your air conditioner filters
it calibrated your meters start writing
that stuff down so that when something
comes up you can look in there and go oh
that's why my pH meter isn't working I
have it calibrated the [ __ ] thing in
two months you may find some things you
were slipping on if you start taking
more notes
all right podcast rolled I feel like
that pretty much wraps up my clean and
reset the grow room episode I want to
thank you guys for listening thanks for
hanging out with me for another episode
this is the part of the podcast where I
remind you about patreon if you feel
like this podcast was worth a couple of
bucks you can contribute by going to
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
and all the information that you need
will be right there
you guys don't forget to check out my
friends at the Hell a dank seed company
you can find them at dank seed dot store
also I would appreciate it if you stalk
me on all the social media you can find
me on Facebook simply search for the
girlfriend Hart podcast you can find me
on Twitter it's at G fyh podcast and on
Instagram I use my other company name I
use I Ari underscore genetics make sure
you check me out on Instagram if you'd
like to reach out to me if you've got
something you'd like to say nor not into
the social media
if you've got a product you'd like me to
review or you'd like to sponsor the
podcast or maybe you've just got a
question you'd like me to read on the
show you can send me an email my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I would love to hear from
you
ladies and gentlemen don't forget that
the show is available on iTunes stitcher
and every single episode is archived on
youtube go to youtube and search for the
girl from your heart podcast and you can
listen to every single episode of the
podcast right there on the youtube
channel big thanks to everybody who has
subscribed and left comments on the
YouTube channel I appreciate your love
and support I want to thank everybody
once again for listening to a rambly
podcast I will be back in a few days
with a fresh new episode I want to give
you a huge shout out to my friend mama
bear dabs and until next time take a
phat dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you