[Music]
secet is the come come the
secret here we
are Bor to be
Kings welcome to the cup I'm so glad
that you made
rester
me
[Music]
choer like mster leaning lowair thinking
IIT
next judges EXT
exord tis got well aware Highly Educated
top a you damn right we but I still hit
scared
[Music]
call1
got's yeah what's up ladies and
gentlemen welcome to episode number 33
of the igro culture podcast they call me
rosta Jeff and I will be your captain
for this Mission I give a huge shout out
to hydro you're listening to The Secret
Cup Anthem by Hydro The Secret Cup was
in Denver this weekend and our boy
Spence from the garden of weden took
home first place in the secret cup
mountain region coming up in just a
couple of minutes I'll have an interview
with Spence but first this podcast was
brought to you by Highly Educated
titanium if you're dabbing high quality
concentrates you deserve a high quality
titanium nail don't trust a chinese nail
or an American knockoff made of cheap
medals trust the industry leader trust
Highly Educated titanium for more info
on Highly Educated titanium products
visit www. Highly Educated ti.com
this podcast is also brought to you by
Nature's green remedies.com visit
Nature's green remedies.com for gag
green genetics the plat Labs Sin City
rare dankness mile high can Aventure iy
genetics and many more trusted
Brands Nature's green remedies is
running a special for the podcast
listeners type in coupon code Harvest 14
for 15% off any order and you always get
free shipping at naturegreen
remedies.com once again that coupon code
is Harvest
14 this podcast is also brought to you
by hyro indoor growing supplies hyro
indoor growing supplies has two
locations to serve Colorado visit the
Denver store at 6271 Beach Street Unit F
or stop by the new pbla location on 618
East 4th Street in peblo Colorado check
out H gr for competitive pricing and a
great selection of indoor grow
supplies I want to send big love to our
friends at tree Thugger dcom this
episode is brought to you in part by
tree Thugger dcom live music lifestyle
magazine check out tree Thugger dcom for
concert and Festival news and reviews
look out at the cookout with tree
thug.com much love and respect to all of
the sponsors for making the show
possible I had Spence over and we did a
great interview so I'm not going to
waste much more time with an intro let's
get right to the interview part here we
[Music]
go all right ladies and gentlemen we are
back and we're hanging out with the
winner of The Secret Cup Mountain
Regional we got our buddy from the
garden of Weeden it Spencer how you
doing today buddy good brother how are
you I'm doing good bro I was just told
that there's a garden of Weeden song
written by our boy sloppy and it is
freaking sweet yeah it's pretty tight
shout out to sloppy thank you big shout
out to our boy sloppy what's up brother
thanks for listening to the podcast I'm
going to play your song at the end of
the show thanks for uh permission in the
future Spencer said I could play I gave
him permission and it says Garden of
Weeden in it so it's all
Spence so thanks for joining me on the
show bro no doubt for sure always a
pleasure to be here oh man it's always
fun taking dabs with you we hang out a
lot and I like it um so Spence is the
winner of the mountain region Secret Cup
uh some people might not be familiar
with the secret cup so let's take a
little bit to tell them what that is um
The Secret Cup is a well it's actually a
tour which they go to different places
they go to two places in Cali if I'm
correct um I don't know if it's ever
been put that way as a tour because that
would be a hell of a marketing way to
put some shirts out I mean that's how I
think of it it's a tour and then there's
a championship in the middle at the end
of the tour that's a good way to put it
I hope they're listening and they get a
marketing idea from that um but yeah
California Seattle here maybe Michigan
I'm not sure Arizona Rhode Island and
then all the it's basically a
competition of anywhere from 30 to 40
hash makers all enter a certain amount
of product um and then each one of the
people that enter are considered judges
because we all receive a judge pack go
through them and kind of give everything
a score from smell you know strength
smoothness harshness color flavor you
know down the line so each contestant
actually get uh3 of every sample right
yeah so you get to taste what everybody
else is D or what everybody else entered
and you're the judge right yeah and
we're the judges so that's kind of a
good thing about it is you know it's not
being judged by just you know random
people or like you know just it's not a
well it's technically is a blind judge
because nobody gets to see what you know
yeah what everybody's entries are so
it's all just numbered in whatever
numbers or what you vote for so when you
got your judges kit how how long did it
take you to find your your entry like 2
minutes 2 minutes yeah your you just had
a lot of taste yeah yeah no well I just
you could go through the entries and
kind of just smell and I make the hash
so you kind of get attached I guess you
could say to like you know which is
yours and what what is not I had there
was a couple that I was like e maybe and
then as soon as you find it it's perfect
it's like yeah that's it I could tell my
flowers sorry guys I'm all choked up I
actually I went to the secret cup for
two days and took an amazing amount of
dabs and then today I went hung out with
some friends in Denver and my lungs and
throat are burnt out from dab and you
guys got to hydrate if you're dabbing
that's something that I'm learning more
hydration Spence reaches through the
water as I say that we're all redyed and
throat
dried so uh yeah everybody got to I had
the honor of tasting a couple of my
friends were judges and entrance
contenders I don't know what the hell
they were called they were judges and
they entered and I got to taste parts of
their sample packs some were amazing
some uh I don't think I would take a
second da of a lot of those yeah I mean
there's
definitely there's was
38 competitors in this one so 383s you
got to go through and you know it's kind
of tough depending on which kind of what
kind of like I'm a weed snob so I'm
definitely going to be an oil snob you
know what I'm saying so it's just and a
lot of it's personal preference whether
or not you like it this way or you like
it that way so it's kind of that's why
it's good that we're the judges cuz it's
at least honest opinion
I wanted to wait a little bit to get
into live resin but I was worried with
you entering live resin people were
going to say it's not stable because the
popular [ __ ] the rage is shattered is
shatter and the live resin is not
shatter at all it's kind of it looks
like oil yeah it's like oil um and then
depending where it's at you know it's I
think somebody said 66 degrees is when
it actually gets it'll shatter if your
if your house is 66 degrees like your
house cold you'll have shatter live
resin
but it's almost that in here tonight
it's getting nice and cool in Colorado
temperatures are changing like this oil
is cool right now it's chilling um hey
thanks dude the other day you gave me a
little sample of Earl and I didn't even
realize that I've been dabbing off of
the entry I've been dabbing the winter
here for several days thank you that sh
is tasty thank you uh so in a second
we'll talk about what's in that uh the
event uh we kind of talked about what it
is uh the people that enter are the
judges we all everybody gets to taste
the entries uh so that's what it's all
about and Spence was actually chosen as
the overall Champion uh there's a couple
other things I want to talk about there
was two location changes uh yeah if not
if you could probably count three yeah
cuz the venues in Denver got switched
twice I want to give a huge shout out to
Big D right now Big D was smart enough
he uh hired a professional event company
he h hired the right Event Services
Group right event group or something you
know what I mean the right group uh was
in charge they booked and secured a
location as they got there and started
to set up they were told that they were
not allowed to do the event there uh Big
D is smart enough to where he just made
another phone call and said hey
everybody go to location number two he
had a second spot lined up
unfortunately uh that got shut down
also so um I think AJ hashman made a
couple of phone calls and a couple of
emails were sent and The Lazy Lion sorry
about the cough again guys I'm really
sorry that sucks to do a podcast with
that I bet it sucks to hear uh The Lazy
Lion and the spyy Vape Lounge
volunteered to let the secret Cup come
have their party there they already had
[ __ ] booked for that night they canceled
it and they came and or they let us come
and have a huge party there so big shout
out to Big D uh AJ hashman and everybody
involved with the Speak Easy and The
Lazy Lion that was super cool uh a lot
of the vendors packed right on up and
came with them most of the booths were
full um most of the artists came
Saturday was a little a little kind of
bare but Sunday was pretty crowded in
there yeah Sunday it it got crowded just
depending on what time of the day it was
yeah uh the Speak Easy was pretty neat
uh I was able to get into the Speak Easy
The Lazy Lion was actually the VIP
lounge so uh I didn't have my VIP badge
so I couldn't go in there yeah the lazy
Lon is it's they by far have the
headiest glass collection I've seen ever
nice um have you ever seen that
uh what is it the Joe Peters queen bee
it's like a huge like I think I saw the
picture that Maddie posted of it shout
out to Maddie what's up Maddie um that
piece is like
80k I don't even want to touch it I
don't even want to say that on the C
it's are you able to hit it they let you
I was going to say that's crazy half the
rigs are just for a display I did see a
bong with a goldfish swimming in it uh
it's labeled not to smoke out of it's
like please don't smoke out of this but
they got a bong with a big base and it's
a beta fish actually I said goldfish
it's a beta that's pretty novel yeah
yeah I'm surprised known thought of that
before all right so uh shout out to the
places and people that made that happen
uh let's talk about your entry now um
your entry was live resin uh do you want
to tell the people what strain it was or
are you kind of oh it's already out it's
um it was czo G from uh Sin City
Seeds um and it was mixed with Scott OG
from rare dankness um classy mix yeah
yeah the czo G was a Kosher Kush
dominant um
um pheno I guess You' call it um
so if you guys need to know about pheno
types go back a few episodes yeah for
sure we talked about that yeah but um it
was a
real the uh scoto G was just an awesome
OG nice it was definitely lanky a very
very not super tall but it was you know
taller than I would usually like plants
to be but um super fuy Ian heavy indicia
just you know awesome resin production
um and a pretty decent yielder too um
that was the one I mixed with the sins
which is a kosher dominant which the sin
OG is blue power and Kosher Kush so it
was a kosher kosher Kos dominant um feno
and it just had a way better kosher like
burnt
rubber isy smell which comes out in hash
as an OG
smell real it's got a fuy funk
this hash definitely has a f Funk to it
it's delicious um I smoke a lot of
sativas because like you said I'm a
sativa breeder I smoke a lot of the
sativa or a lot of sativa in this Inda
kind of dominance in here it really sits
me down it makes my eyes droopy I really
appreciate it it's really not a really
nice cross what's got the C citrusy
spice to it what's adding that there's
like sort of a a spice to the end it's
almost got a lemony Citrus um it comes
from the Scots okay um you get a little
bit of lemon um OG like that OG pness
and sometimes the pine can transfer over
to like a citrus
lemon um so it's a very it was a good
strain you know it was a feno hunt out
of you know I ran a pack and I kept you
know three or four of them and you know
there was three or four of them in the
in the room and I got to pick which ones
I wanted to make yeah the entry with so
it was really it's really cool being
able to actually go in and you know pick
what flavors a lot of a lot of the
people who won you know were like thanks
to this person for let me get the
product you know and it was cool for us
cuz I don't have to ask anybody for
product it all comes from us all inous
is great too and it's good to know I've
seen your guys's Garden it's good to
know that it's a clean Safe Garden where
my medicine comes from I get a lot of my
lot of oil comes straight from you guys
I'm kind of picky about where I'll get
it yeah and you guys are the first
people I go to when I need
medicine uh how do you uh when you're
looking in the room what makes you
say that strain and that's scen right or
that plant and that plant right there
are going to make award-winning oil
um
honestly it's more of just you kind of
literally go plant to plant and just you
know you can't you can't do it in the
day it kind of takes you know a week or
two you know as they're finishing to be
able to tell which flavors are going to
come
through
um I was I don't even think I was going
to do well I made another batch the
green ribbon batch
um but the green ribbon just didn't
carry it the same like when you feel
some plants you know how they're like
some plants are like super sticky where
you touch them and then your fingers are
stuck together and there's some you
touch and you get like the stringiness
resin and then there's some you touch
where it's like just wet where you don't
even it's like slick uhhuh so you just
kind of go and look for different you
know okay for me it's a lot about
flavors so I like to you know your hash
is always flavorful I had a bunch of
your shatter with me at the secret cup
and everybody I would dab out would go
ooh that's tasty and yeah it was a lot
of Golden Goat that you made and some
cookies that you made I've got some
cookies you did a while back I've got it
on secret stash secret stash hey shout
out to Vigor lover shout out to Vigor
lover for the gift edit it right there
he's the homie uh somehow he got to me
some solventless hash that tastes pretty
damn good right on bro good work I'm
going have to edit some of that [ __ ] I
don't know what I can leave in he smokes
mids though so it's cool hash team
mids poor guy cannot get away from that
[ __ ] so uh we talk a lot about live
resin on this show I am not a hash maker
everybody tells me that I've always got
great hash they complement it I got to
say I don't make hash I know a lot about
making hash because uh little Kev bro is
my buddy you're my buddy I know how to
read uh the internet tells you all about
making dabs if you want to know I like
to be educated but I don't make hash uh
I've been trying my best to describe
live resin to people a lot of people
have asked about it after you exhale
that [ __ ] monstrous dab I owe a
dollar for that one I owe a dollar every
time I say the f- word on the show but
after you yeah uh will you teach me and
our listeners a little lesson about what
live resin is and kind of how it's
done um okay so everybody's heard of
fresh Frozen bubble hash so basically
where you harvest your plant you
essentially freeze it or flash freeze it
um and then for ice hat you'd you know
wash it in your bags or whatever so now
now instead of you know as far as
opening blasting I know people who do it
live resin but I think it's once the
Clos closed loop game came out and we
figured out you could do that same
process in a Clos loop at a bigger scale
it it completely changes P for the
better in my opinion I think so um
obviously yeah so basically it's fresh
frozen Clos Loop BHO um all right if
done proper I'm going to I'm going to go
a little slow on that one he's taking
plants that are ready for Harvest chop
them down freeze them in the Deep Freeze
and then put them in a closed loop
butane extraction system which uh we'll
talk more about that I think Kevin and I
have talked about that but there's open
blasting and closed loop Spence uses a
Clos loot method and blast the fresh
frozen like that M does it need to be
vacuum purged after that um yeah well
once it comes through your system you
it's really you know
it takes a lot of the butane out before
you even get to touch the product using
that closed loop using the closed loop
so it pumps it out because it takes all
the liquid back out ah you know so then
you're left which is your product um as
far as you know flavors I really think
it keeps a better tur profile it
honestly if you all right so this is
going to be kind of hard to understand
but it tastes like it smells when it's
growing if you can understand what you
know like when you touch a plant and you
smell your fingers that crazy smell you
get that it doesn't ever smell like that
once it's dried and cured but once you
when you're stripping or making hash
from a fresh product you get that fresh
flavor it's like if your bud was a fruit
and you took a bite out of that fruit
that's what this hash tastes like and I
love it it's got uh the turpenoid and
that's yeah the turp profile in there
and that's just everyone's new word now
is TPS turs TPS so I just feel like an
[ __ ] every time I say turps but the
turps in that it's tppy slurpie just
like a big it's like a bite of candy
every time you hit a dab of it it's
amazing it literally is like it could be
dessert like one somebody needs to make
some Jilly Bean live resin oh don't
worry there's dude there's crazy like
all right so blueberry Sour Diesel that
sounds ridiculous doesn't it yeah it
sounds delicious yeah uh yeah uh some
Tangi or yeah there's a lot of sh I made
cookies live it we got we got across
some Tangi and some Grateful Dog
see the Tangerine dog the look on your
face Tangerine dog I've been writing
down strain names guys if you have neat
strain names you can feel free to tweet
those to me at igro culture I might use
one of them if I use your screen name I
might send you a pack of it when I make
it if I remember and if I can find your
Tweet yeah yeah
um but yeah so live res is basically you
know fresh fresh frozen V just I think
it's a more flavor vacuum purging it I
think that's what I was asking oh yeah
vacuum purging after you know everything
I do goes into an oven after you know
you extract it from your system because
your system takes um pretty much a good
majority of it out so but you still got
to go through your vacuum process to you
know keep cleaning and removing certain
gases and stuff like that uh do you know
do you do you do anything special to
your plants or flowers U if you know
you're going to make oil out of them for
live resin um no um I have done like
what was it 48 Hours of dark before um
but no I I really think with as far as
live it's all about the product you put
in you know the better you know the
flowers that are going in the better the
oil is going to come out so no trim run
in this room right yeah I'll pass no
trim run I I honestly like from my trim
like my personal stuff I still open
blast it and I'll make it it's you know
I think it comes out better than the
closed loop but it's good for patience
people need it but we're snobs over here
and uh I'll I'll stick with this Nug Run
yeah the nug I can almost tell a
difference uh I can almost tell even
smoke and shatter I can tell a
difference in nug and Earl uh Nug Run
and trim run yeah definitely tell
difference and you can taste once you
start smoking live you can taste the
difference between if it's in a closed
loop and if it's not in a closed loop I
feel super spoiled now that I smoke so
much live it's like I just it's a good
it's a good I find myself hiding my live
like just my live resin's over here and
the rest of my shatter is over here we
can smoke this shatter all day the live
resin I'll bark at you like a dog if you
get near it yeah all right so uh a
little bit more about the secret cup
stuff dude you're a freaking Champion
now bro you are a secret cup winter has
it sunk in yet um no well what's funny
is about this is I went to what was it
Secret Cup last year when they had it in
Denver um I went with a couple buddies
of mine and that was like right when I
was really first getting into really
making like oil like more than just you
know every now and then um
um and I remember telling everybody I
was like dude we're going to enter this
cup next year and we're going to win it
and then you know a year later we
[ __ ] oh snap my bad you could say
whatever you want I'm just trying not to
say [ __ ] so much that's another dollar
actually every time I say it I owe a
dollar to a charity so it's kind of not
that bad
um and I said we were going to win it
and we came out and you know brought I
think we came real proper and then a lot
of the differences between I think
us which I don't speak for everybody you
know what I'm saying because I don't you
know I don't know everybody that
competed but like we didn't have to
Source our product we were able to
actually go pick it and that I think
that made a difference as far as hug
difference flavor being able to pick
certain flavors and knowing what you
want and hash you know it was just easy
I would I would have hated to have to go
Source you know what I'm saying just
find something that's good enough to
make I actually have a guy that comes
straight to me for his secret cut
material and yeah he's always like bro I
need it I need this crop at this time
and he me a head up you understand how
it is it's just all about quality for
sure for sure um and then I grow weed
first before I make hash so you know
it's it's a lot different when you spend
10 weeks with a plant and then make hash
instead of buying it off the shelf and
making hash with it there just it's a
lot more full circle yeah um which is
important to us like as we say it's
grown by us processed by us and smok by
us from seed to live resin to a cup yeah
nice that's that's super awesome so it's
it's cool it's been a fun experience
hasn't really I don't know if it sank in
because I wasn't you know honestly I
went in with a thinking I was going to
have a top three finish that's just how
I'm just competitive I hate losing um so
it was cool being able to go in I almost
thought I lost once they did all the
awards and then third second I was like
oh no we didn't win that's something I
wanted to ask you uh they did they did
uh like highest CBD they did best TPS
they did crowd's choice or something
like that uh what was it connoisseur's
choice connoisseur's choice and then
they do third second and then Big D said
so first place and he said something to
the equivalent of you guys already know
who it is and I was like oh then it's
probably somebody that's already gotten
an award is what I assumed but then he
said garden and as soon as he said
Garden I think I peed a little bit on
myself I was like
who um he went through and did second
place and it was the the bubble which
the bubble was fire I'll give it that
you know what I'm saying um I didn't
even know it was bubble that won the
second place solventless bubble um but I
looked at Maddie and I was like we might
not
win and then like he did the
announcement whatever and it was tight
and I wish I would I wasn't thinking I
was going to win so like my speech was
super like
short and to the point I guess you could
say it was well it was perfect uh you
said something about where you're from
this ilal so it's great to be here with
all these people making hash and
celebrating and winning and that's
pretty pretty
awesome so you didn't know you were
going to win no I didn't didn't know I
was going to win um I think I thought I
was going to win but you know it just
came through you know I think we really
just put in everything we had into the
competition so it paid off for us were
there any other samples that stood out
um yeah there was a couple there was um
K bills the you know shout out to K bill
for you know coming up with the live
resent Tech um is that who made that
yeah K Bill who won third is actually
the dude who came up with live resin
nice dude you beat that guy his own when
he was talking in his speech he was like
there's some there's some guys out here
doing you know my same technique that
are killing it um and I'm going say he
was regarding me um but yeah his is his
was on point uh he did it was sour d
deep chunk and Gorilla Glue and I think
it was just it was really good but it
was just too complex it wasn't like
straight to the not straight to the
point but just the glue and the sour are
almost the same thing and then the Deep
chunk is I think a sour diesel deep
chunk or something like that it's just a
purpley strain um I think if he would
have done the sour d and the glue it
would have been a whole it would have
came out a whole lot better in my
opinion I think the flavors would have
pulled through just that SI s with a
uh what was it and Gorilla Glue is
Gorilla Glue is basically a old school
sour or something like that that Gorilla
Glue was a ridiculous plant bro yeah
that is some crazy [ __ ] I've got one
growing right now and you got to tie it
down and it will break the tie downs
it's like no I literally had one that
had I think it started with three tops
and I literally just as it would grow
would just super crop each top down and
then now it has like 18 tops I literally
have a 10 gallon Gorilla Glue that has
20 stakes in it I'm going to have to uh
take a plant out of the room or
something because these two gorilla
glues are taking more space than I
completely predicted yeah uh I read who
made it the other day on The Forum yeah
yeah yeah and I read the cross too and
I'm not surprised that it's so killer
now that I read it it's uh what is it
Kim sis sour dub and chocolate Tha yeah
yeah that's what made me think of that
you were talking about the chocolate I'm
taking a dab so you got to talk for a
second oh it's cool um no but yeah I'll
give another shout out um thanks to Big
D um um Jeremy Nory from rig Rags um
coming out from Cali coming to support
the Colorado movement
um everybody who made the drive from
Denver to the Springs to go dab like
that is so true um not a lot of people
you know can say hey let's go drive an
hour down the street or down this
beautiful damn State we live in and go
dab with every all of our friends even
even the people we don't know that we're
all you know nobody's the best thing
about our type of events is there's
no rowdiness there's no drunk people
around getting mad and trying to fight
you know it's just people high and
kicking it which is right down my alley
there's too much expensive glass around
to get Rowdy exactly like people don't
want to pay for I'm not trying to pay
for a $10,000 Mother Ship RI I'll tell
you that so you won or actually the
award started in the uh the PA system
was kind of shitty and nobody could hear
so everybody just moved right up to the
front you had a rig a Toro rig sitting a
table a rig a torch and a little piece
of shatter just sitting on the table you
left that [ __ ] I left it we all walked
away left it sitting on the table I
found it there an hour later just
sitting there chilling out nobody
touched it all the shatter was still
there perfectly intact it's good to know
you know it's good to know you know you
don't have to worry about things like
that good Community for sure uh dude you
got a big old box of prizes I saw a
torch with uh shaped like a cup like a
Cannabis Cup looking thing yeah it's a
it's a vector torch that has like like a
cup trophy on it that has a a gold
dragon wrapped around it and it says
like first place and it says Secret Cup
on the back and then inside that cup
it's filled with like I don't know it
looks like live so we'll call it live
it's filled up with just you know looks
like a bunch of oil which was pretty
sick um I got the torch I got a a rig
from Monsters glass company if if
correct me if I'm wrong I'm sorry um
it's a sick rig it has like a little
puppet flip disc in the bottom which it
came with like a maging pendant which
the pendant is huge it's a dope pendant
um matching
Dabber what else did we get um there was
a box of stuff I'm glad you had Big Mike
with you big Mike was toing that box
around like a toy box yeah that's what
was in there the the rig was there a new
enil in there oh I got that from it
wasn't in the box but that was a part of
the prize and do the enail rocks nice so
whoever made made those shout out to to
you for that cuz it my other eail is
going to be in the corner getting Dusty
now so got a pretty sweet uh Grassroots
hat yeah uh and that prize box was huge
no no it was it was you know so so much
worth you know giving up you know 20
grams Al live which is you know I could
keep that and smoke that for a while but
you know it it comes back worth it and
and you know you get to spend two days
with you know an awesome Community with
Maddie around bro that's like 20 days
worth of dabs you know what I'm saying
my lady smokes so much oil it's crazy
but you know she has a I don't know it's
like she dabs but she doesn't get she
gets high but then she'll like take
another dab and get UNH high and then
she wants to take another dab cuz she's
thinks she's UNH high and then now she's
high again and it's just it's cool I
mean I don't she can smoke all the oil
she wants shout out mie for sure keep
dabbing keep dabbing that prize box was
sweet uh so now you get to go to Vegas
yeah uh is that the semifinals or the
finals Vegas is the finals Vegas so it's
the top three from every place on the
tour in Denver or in Vegas myad in Vegas
I might have to I usually don't go to
Vegas I think I think well I
was That's How popular you are we'll do
it I'll record now you got to be back
all right all right so we were talking
about
I'm going to have to think about going
to Vegas yeah we were looking in houses
and they do they in Vegas like every
house is nice it's not just like it's
not poo where there's only one street
that has nice houses on it um we uh so
we're looking into like getting a house
for like a week cuz I guess I don't know
how long everybody's going to be there
but if we're going to get it we'll get
it for a week that sleeps like 10 people
they all have every house has a pool and
backyards so just go to I'm not going to
I might party like one or two nights but
otherwise I'm just going to kick it cuz
it's Vegas you'll lose I'll lose too
much money in Vegas yeah Vegas is
expensive and it's expens that's why
it's you can get a house like a
six-bedroom house for a week for like
900 bucks for the week hell yeah so
that's like 75 bucks a person yeah I'm
Gucci with that yeah we can we can
afford that for sure do I U but yeah so
Vegas is it's in December not 100% on
the dates but somewhere in December what
are the weed laws like in Vegas um I
couldn't tell you that's some stuff
we're going to have to research we we
look like we need to get pulled over if
we're in Vegas yeah you know what I'm
saying I'm not trying to do that yeah I
heard of Vegas jail I might just fly
there yeah I'm flying there if I go I'm
not driving to Vegas why not because you
got to drive through Utah or some [ __ ]
no Arizona yeah still New Mexico Arizona
still see just get on a plane like an
hour later you're in Vegas all right
whatever oh um I guess we're fine I
guess Maddie we're fine um get your
tickets now it'll be cheap yeah but I
got dogs what I'm going to do about my
dogs for a week you'll be gone for less
time if you fly you don't got to waste
all that 14 hours worth of driving what
are you going to be you got all kinds of
homies that'll take care your dogs no
all my homies want to go everybody no
I'm
going we need somebody to take care of
saraka Nana oh yeah so it's in December
it's top three from
every you know spot on the tour that's a
such a good tour the secret c tour um
but yeah so it's a competition and the
winner of that one is The champ is the
gets the gold WWF looking belt WCW
whatever they are either one I don't
care but I want that the pro wrestling
looking belt how many winners have there
been before you I know there was uh
Mortimer won last year Mortimer says she
won finals Ryan Skipton was one year was
there another year I don't know I think
it's only been like it ain't been that
long okay well shout out to the previous
winners I saw Mortimer says that the uh
the event gorgeous as always for sure
yeah so what else have you won bro um
you've been talking about this uh thing
you do on Thursdays oh so Thursdays in
Denver at the 710 hatpin social
Lounge off of kfax Thursday night they
do a top shelf Thursdays it's a right
now we're in the process of a
16 person extract tournament basic Bally
so it's
bracketed um so I won my quarterfinals
on Thursday before the secret cup so I'm
now into the I'm one of four did you
enter the same material um no I did a
the Cindy Lew killing it with different
[ __ ] even yeah um Cindy Lew times
Freedom baby uh just awesome floral just
goodness um and then I did that green
ribbon live sugar butter or whatever
people want to call it I call it Sugar
because it's not like a butter butter is
like wet and pasty and it does look it
almost looks like uh bubble has almost
yeah so so tasty yeah know it's
awesome um yeah so we do that and then
I'm into the semis so
there's two more rounds into the finals
or in of to make the other side of the
bracket so it's I think it's me and K
Bill K Bill's in a [ __ ] and me and and
then there's like four other people that
are fighting for the last two spots um
and it's pretty cool so I've won two of
those and then won The Secret Cup you
won the super Bud Bowl I won I think
like second in the super Bud Bowl okay
um have you participated any in any of
those closet Growers Cup events no I
always missed the well it sucks cuz a
lot of my stuff I grow so if it's not
timed perfectly to where I can take
stuff out of my garden I usually don't
enter which is cool yeah which is now
I've got 10 weeks to get all the flavors
I want to do for the cup ready to go
that's just enough time yeah I've got
just enough and it's perfect because I
have just the right amount of plants
that are just big enough they're
outgrowing their threes now so they're
ready to go
into probably like tens or so and just
finish from now to then and I'll be able
to pick what I want when I want it which
flavors we want to do stoked to see what
you enter yeah I get the privilege
Spence calls me up and he's like bro I
just ran like seven batches alive I need
your expertise I don't know what to
enter and I go over there and they heat
up the email and Maddie passes me dabs
and they won't tell me what they are but
they just watch my reaction and then I
go that one
bro
um no it was definitely a good
experience being able to you know win
something and it's good for you know I'm
not from Colorado I moved here so like
it's cool cuz like I called my parents
like yo I just won this hash competition
mom and my mom's like what like what
does that mean blah blah blah um so it's
it's good to know that my like I'm
actually you
know progressing you know and getting
further into the scene I guess the weed
scene um so it's cool being able to know
that out of what 38
people from Colorado or came to Colorado
to inter hash I had the best hash and
that's not just 38 random people that
shit's invite only you have to get like
the secret it's like Kum of hash it's a
Kum hash you got to invite um you can't
just show up it was a private party for
sure private party so what's uh what's
next for the uh The Garden of Weeden um
other than Vegas other than crushing Las
Vegas and taking home the belt and
bringing it to peblo Colorado
for sure to get it all dusty and yeah go
swim with it on in the get it
stolen I'm going have to get like a fake
one a a dummy belt to wear around yeah
um I've been talking to some people um a
lot of people that I met you know
traveling you know different networking
stuff this year
um I don't know I kind of want to we
might be traveling to a couple different
places to let people experience live and
kind of you know get people to show that
hey there's
another form of hash on on the map that
is got to take this to the other legal
states show them what's up and so
there's a couple people that I talk to
you know through social media and you
just networking that you know hopefully
if it works out it I it would be awesome
but um who knows you know we're kind of
just doing our thing we don't really you
know especially here in Colorado it's
such a legal scene you have to you know
you've got to have money to you know get
a license and go that route and have a
building blah blah blah I'm just the guy
that lives on the you know and just
grows really good weed and makes good
hash you know what I'm saying so that's
you know one day there'll be you know a
business or something like that in our
future but right now we're just you know
we just like to grow pot and live in
Colorado it's better than living
anywhere else I agree to that for sure I
agree to that but that's a great way to
wrap up this little interview with the
champion well I'm calling you the
champion already [ __ ] you're the champ
of my mind bro you're going to win that
[ __ ] I got faith in you uh dude thanks
for coming to the show you got anybody
you want to give any shout outs to or
anything like that um let's see shout
out to my lady Maddie um
floppy Nan sck Harvey
Bane uh you better get big mik Earl Inda
Big Mike who's not here and he hates his
life right now um f broke his iPhone I
want to say on the phone we kind of
talked about that bro yeah broke his
brand new phone he just got a week ago
um that's really about it shout out to
everybody that supports irog gentics
Garden of Weeden you know anybody that's
doing something you know positive shout
out to y'all yeah big shout out to
everybody that's growing their own um
what else we are we're going to do
garden of weeding is going to be
sponsoring an epilepsy fundraiser in
Denver end of November I think um is
when it is um so I'll try to get some
more information about that which it'll
be you know it'll be our first time
actually going to an event like this and
kind of you know being out in the
more not necessarily hippie crowd but
you know just kind of being more in the
medical side of yeah get out of the dab
Kid scene get off the couch and stop
dabbing and kind of go you know hang out
with these kids that you know this this
stuff saves their lives like there's a
kid um you've heard of was it team
Landon yeah yeah um I actually got to
meet uh a buddy of mine who makes all
the oil for him all the CBD stuff um his
oil tested what was it like 40 40% CBD
you know what I'm saying nice um and
it's cool cuz he knows that the little
kid will be like hey or Landon will be
like hey Mommy I need my cannabis it
makes me feel better you know which you
know that's cool so we're going to go
out there support you know the other
side of being free in the Cannabis
industry you know just being able to go
actually help people which is you know
cool for us giving back to people who
need it got to pay it forward for sure
the medical is what started this for us
we can't forget them no not at all we
the if it wasn't for the people who need
it for medical reasons the people who
don't need it for medical reasons
wouldn't be smoking it legally at least
that's the truth for sure all right bro
you got anything else uh no man thanks
for having me on thanks lot thanks a lot
for coming we'll have you back guys if
you have any questions he actually make
sure you go follow Garden of weed and
it's Garden of weedn on Instagram you
got a Facebook Are You full on Facebook
yet no but it's coming yeah so uh follow
him on Facebook he gets up to 5,000
followers try to get in there before he
before he fills up so what you got uh
there's a uh check out sloppy 919 on
YouTube and check out the Gard of Weeden
song I'm at the end of this episode I'll
I'll post it I'll post a link to it on
my
on page as well so people can click on
it nice right on guys thanks for
listening I'll be back in just a second
to wrap everything
up all right guys I want to thank Spence
once again for coming back and I want to
thank you for listening to the show I
want to give a bunch of shout outs
before we wrap up I want to give a shout
out to John from Medicine Man also shout
out to AJ hashman huge shout out to Big
D none of this event would have been
possible without Big D want to give a
big shout out to hydro thanks for
performing The Secret Cup anthem song
for me right before the awards that was
dope as [ __ ] also big shout out to our
new friend Jessica much love to curbside
concentrates zet free toas and Justin
from a64 magazine also big shout out to
my friend Robert and his wife anito
what's up guys it was great to see at
the show uh much love to Jay Dizzle jdub
and the weed pimp crew Colorado bearded
dabbers shout out to call me Big Mike
Maddie of course shout out to Spence and
the whole garden of Weeden crew fish
Phil Stephanie also a shout out to
Claude and Melissa from sweet Stone
candy
big shout out to Grassroots shout out to
Nexus creations and of course the Lazy
Lion and the Speak Easy Vape Lounge also
need to send some love too the real OG
kushman need to send love to task Julie
dread White Mike the grimy Gatsby DJ
Nick natural Mystic cannabis caregivers
and Cockroach
719 I want to send a huge shout out to
sloppy 919 I'm going to play The Garden
of Weeden song from sloppy make sure you
go check that out on YouTube search for
sloppy 9919
all right so now we'll wrap up the show
now that the show is over please go to
iTunes go to the iTunes Store search for
IG gr culture find the review section
give us a fstar rating after that type
in a comment and let me know what you
think of the show and I'll read your
comments on a future episode s your
listeners you guys can do the same and I
will read your comments make sure you
follow us on Instagram Twitter and
Facebook Instagram and Twitter is igro
culture Facebook is simply IG gr culture
you can email me ulture hotmail.com
make sure you follow iy genetics on
Instagram don't forget that the show is
available on iTunes Stitcher and every
single episode is available on iy
genetics.com I have started slowly
uploading each episode to YouTube so
you'll be able to find cheesy videos
there if it's easier for you to watch
the show on
YouTube thank you guys for listening to
the show Once Again big thanks to Big D
thanks everybody that hung out at the
secret Cup this weekend and made it a
good time big Shout out to my ninja
Spence thanks again for listening take a
fat dab give your mom a hug for
me you like you know no other turn on
each other and kill your brother trust
no bullet I'm call it how I see it tell
you got fire I'm call it how I bre it
always got work you can call
[Music]
me I just call it how I see it in the we
we in the we get weed the weed get weed
I just call it how I see it I just call
it I see it uhuh only fire I it
[Music]
the
enemies blow
[Music]
in
you the my I know you smoke but you
smoke