you did a welcome back cannabis
community it's time for another episode
of the grow from your heart podcast your
source for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right up here a new
grower if you're a professional grower
if you're a new smoker or a dedicated
dapper if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who is just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host my friends call me Roscoe Jeff I
want to thank you guys again for joining
me this episode of the podcast is
brought to you by my friends at the hell
a dank seed company if you need new
genetics for your gardening I highly
recommend the hella dank seed company
you can find them at dank seed dot store
ladies and gentlemen roll up a fat joint
pack up the bong or start heating up
that dab rig because it's time for
another episode of the grill from your
heart podcast welcome back internet
world it's time for episode 330 of the
girl from the heart podcast thanks again
for joining me sitting across the table
from me welcome back to throes white
Mike thanks for hanging out dude you
know thanks for having me thanks for
making some time away from the family
away from the work and away from this
super hot day to come hang out it's nice
to get out every once in a while man it
is it's roasting hot out there
yes sorry people the weather here is
[ __ ] insane right now it's got
everybody acting goofy like slow and
lethargic it's only been hotter than
this one day ever here wow it's
yesterday we were three degrees short of
the ever record for this area and today
we hit the the record for ever here I'm
not sure how close we got today it was
all so stupid
yeah it's ridiculously hot here we'll
Commission about the weather let's do a
podcast Mike is here I am here we're
gonna do a good show for you before we
get too far this podcast is brought to
you by our friends at the hell a dank
seed company that's right if you need
new regular or feminized seeds for your
garden I highly recommend the hella dank
seed company you can find them at dank
seed dot store the holidaying seed
company is doing a fourth of July sale
that's right from July 3rd through the
July 5th if you use coupon code int you
will get 20% off your whole order also
rumor has it there will be a fresh drop
of new I read genetics so make sure you
check out dank seed dot store all right
we got the advertising out of the way
the next step is to talk about
what we are smoking on like how you
feeling over there bake a baked like a
cake we were smoking this on the last
episode you guys were in love with it
I'm in love with it it is the sinful
banana sauce from contraband
concentrates that is the in-house
concentrate company at a cut above
dispensary in Colorado Springs the
sinful banana sauce comes in at eighty
seven point eight percent THC a is a
cross of sin mint cookies and honey
bananas and this stuff is delicious I
approve it tastes really good but the
other one hit me substantially harder
I'm reaching for that one now to talk
about that that is the Durban cush sauce
from the same company the same place
this one tested at ninety point three
percent THC eight but it's also got two
point one percent THC added to the label
there the other one didn't have that
listed so that might be what's uh what's
giving you that extra punch I don't know
the other one doesn't have any of that
stuff listed it's blank there so maybe
that's what's giving you Dexter I don't
know that should be listed on the other
container honestly that doesn't make any
sense to me but yeah the Durban cush
this one's got that and it's super
Durbin II smell to it what a Papa
doesn't have dyed pine into it but it's
very Durbin II it seems like the cush
took out that pine end it's got sort of
a sweet into it like a candy sort of a
thing and that look at the crystals in
that one bro yeah big old chunky
crystals in there my dad was really
pretty yeah Mike's dad was bit more than
the brain yeah it kind of ran him over
he had to go catch his breath go have a
cigarette I've been fiddling with this
pen like it's a holding me drown into
the world only thing keeping you here in
reality alright well welcome back to
earth Mike let's do a podcast about
legalization legalize it let's start
here close to home first big shout out
to Oklahoma way to go way to go you guys
are legal now just I think it was Mike
said two years ago you guys were trying
to sue us for having cannabis and now
you in 2014 the Oklahoma was part of a
lawsuit suing Colorado for our audacity
to legalize marijuana in the this week
last week Oklahoma legalized medical a
more liberal legalization
than any state since California there's
not a list of qualifying conditions a
doctor you know sign up recommendation
for any condition you see spit here she
sees bit too that's pretty cool
so if they just say yeah you can have it
yep yes or no
there you go yeah and on top of that
they can have three ounces in public wow
yeah wow that's pretty cool we can only
have as a recreational patient you carry
two is a direct patient carry one is a
medical patient you can carry two so
that's a little different there you guys
I just realize in the headphones you may
be able to hear my air conditioning it's
a little clicky floppy tingly sound in
the background I'm trying to filter that
out with some pressure here oh it's uh
it's a hundred and four degrees you guys
you have to just let me have a little
air conditioning in the background today
and we'll try not to complain to the
station it's after nine o'clock at night
and it's over 90 degrees outside here
we're used to [ __ ] yeah I got it up on
high still I just reach down to to turn
up the compressor on the audio equipment
I was like no that's pretty much where
it goes it's not gonna if it goes any
higher we're gonna start cut now that's
why you hear our voices get short
sometimes at the end of the words don't
finish typing a presser up but we're
just gonna have to deal with that sound
of that air in here a little bit cuz it
is hi you guys
so um Oklahoma welcome to the medical
marijuana Club you don't have to have
any qualifying conditions to go get your
medical cannabis as long as a doctor
there feels like you can do it you can
do it so you guys are listening to this
show my friends my friend my friends you
have got a head start
you've got an education you've got
basically kind of a a course it has good
listening for a while you've got a big
jump on most of the other people in your
state yeah go go be a part of this new
revolution go be a grower go be a
trimmer go be agro tech go be an
extraction coordinator there are so many
different positions to fill in that
industry and if you don't want to be
involved with the packaging labeling
marketing sales yes also security I was
gonna say they're gonna be ancillary
businesses that pop up you're gonna it's
Moshe is you've got another business
like if you're a contractor or tradesman
HVAC start thinking that way HVAC techs
electricians yep you're gonna need
somebody they're gonna need somebody
that can drive a forklift in their new
facilities but what I'm saying is go get
in there and get a head start
and also if you're not gonna be involved
in the weed industry maybe open a head
shop so many head shops are gonna pop up
open up a gross store open up all the
laws and go along with it lodging
because now more people are gonna be
coming there what's medical marijuana
it's not recreational so it's not gonna
have as much impact as it did here
because people come here to buy it
let's but container places places that
make containers for the product when we
go to the conventions here a good
portion of all of the booths are simply
medical approved containers that we can
retail our products and so maybe have a
container company they're gonna need
representatives for their companies that
will drive around up and down the state
or you're a square so all over the state
and call Russia's 1 highway you go up
and down all day long and you go sell
products up and down that highway but
you're gonna want to drive around your
state and represent your brand maybe
that's your niche but find your way in
there if not in the industry itself in
an ancillary business if you're not
comfortable or allowed to get in that
industry maybe you just want to be on
the fringe get an ancillary business
that's a part of it there are a lot of
things it will be involved with cannabis
becoming legal Mike you got some more
notes over there about Oklahoma not
especially okay I I wanted to get a
little more in-depth but I did now I'm
saving some of the commentary for after
we do Canada for after we do Canada well
then yeah that's a good segue I guess
it's a lot that a plot that I want to
say that applies to both locales but
Canada legalized yeah okay I'm just
going legit yes they talked about it a
long time ago and now they are doing it
Canada has legalized cannabis it was a
campaign promise that they carried
through on and on October 17 marijuana
will be legal across the country it's
split up in two Providence's just let
her provinces look just like the US is
split up into States and just like the
US every province is gonna have their
own laws it looks like completely I've
got some outline of some of the basic
rules but it looks like it's gonna vary
pretty heavily from one part of Canada
to the next state-run stores in one part
couple hundred stores that are privately
owned and another
no stores in another Wow some areas
allow commercial growth some areas don't
some areas allow home growth some areas
don't some legalize for everybody when
they turn 18 Alberta in Quebec it'll be
legal once you turn 18 all other
provinces it won't be legal authority I
know the anti pot groups are just
shocked that they didn't go with 21 like
we did right right an 18 and 19 is weird
to have two different ages because what
if you are 19 and you have your weed and
you drive across state lines like oh
[ __ ] I gotta throw my weed out the
window now yeah yeah I just can't take
it with you there I guess that's we have
similar problems here but that's so
weird like just an age difference yep
four plants per household it looks like
but it depends again on your area
Quebec in Manitoba specifically have
already banned home grows completely
like all forms of home grown oh wow
Canada's got an interest in cannabis
history they basically went through what
Puebla is going through now or ours part
of Colorado's going through now with all
the illegal home gross they did that in
the early thousand yeah yeah we learned
a lot of what we know from Canada a lot
of people remember the ice out in Canada
power went out for a long time in Canada
and people were managing grows and that
was a huge thing that we were paying
attention to on the Internet at that
time and then after that a lot of things
went wrong and a lot of the Canadian
growers got in trouble that's where the
romulan comes from you guys is Canada
romulan is a Canadian strain when I was
in college all the best came down from
Canada but their history with it's a
little different than ours their
politics was way different than ours so
they went about this a very different
way than the u.s. yeah they did yeah
they definitely did the age difference
that just automatically before it even
starts just no home grows in some places
that's pretty intense oh they they
wanted this the the government wanted to
do this early summer was when they
wanted to roll this out and they delayed
it till October to give all the
different little of local governments a
chance to weigh in and hash all this out
and figure out how they wanted to play
it local control is kind of a big piece
this from what I see isn't that kind of
the opposite of how we do it here in the
states in the states we can I say hey
we've got this idea we're gonna make
these new rules go and then you go and
then along the way they go oh we didn't
see that rule we're gonna have to dial
that and they just go make a new yeah so
they seem to have gotten it right even
though we don't agree with everything
roll out slower they did it seems to
have worked better they have some things
I really wish we had that would make
this rollout easier so what a national
health care oh yeah I'm that simplifies
this [ __ ] a lot they're known for being
more just chill more polite and that
helps their politics like their politics
follow suit a little bit at least in the
national media I've never been to Canada
for more than like 15 minutes so since
the medical industry isn't going to lose
business because it's not a business in
Canada as much as it is here they're not
lobbying against marijuana as much as
what you kind of said I haven't followed
this that closely but pretty much all
the marijuana and entities in Canada
that I follow have been at least
generally in support of this change some
of the longtime activists are getting
really pissed right now because like new
politicians like look what we did and
they're like go [ __ ] yourself we've been
fighting for this for 30 years and now
you're doing it in a way that kind of
excludes us and so that some of those
factions are starting to get a really
pissed but a lot of those people at the
same time have been really really really
pushing the envelope for a long time
that's how we got here and I can't fault
them for continuing to do what got us
here like without them we wouldn't be a
collar right and be here Canada wouldn't
be legal
Oklahoma wouldn't have just gone medical
but for the most part like just having a
more calm political system they were
able to have discussions in an adult
manner that we're not able to have here
yeah things are we get he automatically
here the extremes yes like when you
bring up marijuana legalization you're
automatically talking about teenagers
getting stoned and killing people on the
highway
Ravin white edges or it causing
schizophrenia or like you just
immediately the conversation is extreme
everybody is Maury no doubt instantly
you know there was a lot less of that
pretty much the only big anti marijuana
group up there Sam Canada and there of
[ __ ] horrible export of ours so
they're mostly all about it and Canada
has been pretty pretty relaxed on
marijuana waz from what I understand in
the past anyway yeah for a very long
time we're getting be stirs delivered in
high school years ago just coming down
from Canada just flooding it in good old
Canadian we did see it FedEx my dorm
nine but like that's the guy I purchased
from FedEx from Canada it was wonderful
mad friends up in Oregon and Washington
that were showing up in Colorado with
that way back in the day they've been
fighting the good fight for a long time
and it's they're the only the second
nation to go nationally after a year
away they're going with a totally
different system so again like I'm kind
of cheese because we're gonna get a
whole new data set now nice yeah it's
kind of fun one of the upsides to the
anti-pot crowd is Canada's gonna have
more data collection from the onset
nobody here considered to do it like
after a holiday like st. Patrick's Day
liked by the Wednesday after st.
Patrick's Day the newspaper has the DUI
results from across the state like here
it here it is broken down by county that
were six people in Denver there were two
people in Douglas like you can see it
easy because it took mothers against
drunk driving fighting for twenty years
to get that system built when we
legalized we like two years later
they're like yeah we don't have a system
like that for weed we don't have any
idea what's going on dealing with this
so just recently there's they've started
to try to collect that data and it's
given the anti pop people a chance to be
like lock this there were no cases last
year in this case this year there's 900
cases and it's like the last year they
didn't look yeah we didn't we didn't
know there was a test on that we never
took notes but they're not gonna have
that advantage in Canada and the data
collection is gonna be not complete but
more so they're from the outset which
one for people like me it's the upside
to legalization like the more research
that happens on it the better and idea
it becomes yes and then we can see data
and numbers and then we have tangible
evidence to pass on to the next people
that are trying to do it the most people
don't really realize how permissive and
infectious our prohibition laws have
become over the decades how much of
American society they've infected and
eroded and [ __ ] up and [ __ ] with it
what's what that's continued to do what
the ripples from that have done and
undoing it in even a little way is good
like earlier we did a Instagram live
video and someone asked me what the
worst part of Colorado's legalization is
and I couldn't think of an answer like
there are parts that are more annoying
than others but there's not one single
part of our incomplete [ __ ] up over
restrictive legalization law I don't
prefer to it's prohibition counterpart
alright like do you I had to make a
transition I came from the black market
much more so than I did but yeah yeah so
there was a lifestyle change came with
legalization when this plant was illegal
so it bets back in the day I feel like
that's long enough I don't feel
uncomfortable saying this you guys where
we live several years ago don't be too
specific we'd would cost $4,000 a pound
now where we live we'd cost fifteen
hundred twelve hundred dollars a pound
for the same quality yeah yeah why yeah
just gonna yeah right and there's
nobody's gonna buy it anyway inside the
market it's even worse you places like
Oregon right now they so over produced
and they so restricted the distribution
market that the prices falling out the
floor like imagine now but legalization
did the same thing to the black market
and that's one of the points is it's an
economic weapon against the black market
if I were to continue trying to grow as
a lifestyle my product is worth a
quarter of what it used to be it means I
get to live a quarter of
the way I used to means I get to eat a
quarter of the Thai food I used to eat
that means I get to buy a quarter of the
door you have to do 150% more or you
have to jump into the legal industry
because you've got experience and you've
got know-how and you know what to do
with it you know how to get in there and
lead it and you know a bunch of people
you know that was the way to do it to be
confident and go there and crush it that
way though most of the people that tried
to just do 150% more illegal [ __ ] couple
of quick they're gone yeah yeah yeah I
used to have a house decked out with
lights now I got a t5 and a flowering
light it's so much easier yep life is
simpler yep it's less stressful being
legal well Mike I feel like I bartered
your your Canada report you got any more
notes on Canada that you want to get
covered before I start specifically but
okay so the next piece of this like it's
awesome that Canada is going legal now
and it's awesome the Oklahoma one
medical but now like a lot of the Nitty
Gritty work begins if you're not already
active in local government get active if
you're not already following local state
province country news start following it
now otherwise you'll wake up in the
legalisation law will be written to
exclude everybody except people they can
come in with several million dollars in
open a corporation Colorado pushed out
all the small growers because they were
worried about small-time black market
grows
becoming legal and just kind of what
walking a fine line between legal and
illegal so they made you upfront invest
as much as they could get away with
making you invest to put that guillotine
or around you and now that all the
quality is going down because it's just
ran by money a little more passion the
the quality took a huge hit here in
Colorado in generally you can still find
what I consider the best herb on the
planet if you take your time to go to
the right places and shop around and and
get what you're really looking for but
there's a lot of crap
a lot of crap available and it sells
unfortunately
it's unfortunately most people that are
in this just for money when they look at
their bottom line the the first
they cut his talent his talent cost a
lot of money yes they do and they can
get their cousin to do the checklist
that the talent made and they think it's
the same thing and it's not they find
they find out after a couple of crops
that quickly becomes apparent so we were
talking about getting into getting in
now getting involved now how can they do
that what is it easy what's what's the
first step it starts we get involved
like you have a local newspaper there
the the news agency that's going to be
covering zoning rules in your area home
grow rules in your area zoning for
stores if all that hasn't been finalized
yet they're the government agencies
making all those decisions and for the
most part you can just look up the
meeting time and show up and if you do
that a couple of times and just kind of
sit back and observe you can figure out
what the little easy process is to go
speak in front of that body and say
whatever you want they've almost
universally got some sort of public
forum spot during their regular meetings
where you can get up there and rail
about whatever it is you're passionate
about and that's the easiest way to
really start getting their attention you
can also email all these people call all
these people local elected officials get
paid to make random people in the public
happy that's how they keep their job is
making enough people and in the
community they serve wander around and
go hey do you know about Bobby down at
the Statehouse he's so helpful that way
they keep their job and so when people
call them during the day nine times out
of ten they answer and it's just like
hello I'm your local elected official
who are you what can I do for you what
can I do you for and even if they
disagree with you nine times out of ten
they're fairly polite and helpful and
they're like well I disagree with that
but if you talk to my co count you know
Co commission or so-and-so you know I
think he's more receptive to this and
he'll be more willing to help you get
whatever you want done submitted in
front of our committee
council they could pass you along to the
right person at least hopefully but it
starts with just reading the news and
following these stories and going to the
meetings and sitting back and observing
and honestly not enough people do it
the people that go are the handful of
people like me that are passionate about
it for some weird sort of broken
childhood reasons and the people who
were my exact opposite and against it
and those are the people that tend to
dominate the meetings and I finally
snapped in one meeting it was like no I
can't let people who can't formulate an
entire sentence yeah I know who to speak
for my community like he doesn't
represent me at all he's representing my
community badly I can do a better job
guaranteed even as nervous as I am and I
started getting up and speaking in it
was terrifying the first time I was on
the front page of the local paper
it gets annoying as much hate I get from
the anti-pot crowd down here but is
worth it like without what I did we
wouldn't have what we haven't well
that's very true
it just took me doing like it just took
one of me to get most of what we have in
public I went to several of those City
Council meetings in the first couple I
was just hanging out and attending and
it was nerve-racking I was just just
there I wasn't even speaking I wasn't
doing anything but after the second or
third one you get the flow you see how
it goes you hear people speak and then
you realize that everyone that goes up
and speaks it's just a working-class
person who just wants some [ __ ] in the
community to be different and that's
they may be judging you because what
you're asking for is cannabis related
but at the same time they've got to hear
you and you are their community so
they'll listen so just go a few times
get it figured out find out where you
fit in and then speak one day and when
you speak other people that are
passionate will see you speak and guys
like myself will walk up to you and go
hey bro can you like teach me like
because I don't want to go be involved
so much because I look like this and I
do this but it'd be cool to have some
knowledge and then you'll start finding
like-minded folks and you'll start
falling in with the right right folks
and then you'll get it figured out when
I first got started going we just watch
by the fourth or fifth meeting like
elected official
we're coming up to me after the meeting
and gone why are you here like not to be
rude or like to encourage you not to be
here it's just like you're not one of
the crazies you're not paid they're not
media and you haven't gone got like
freaked out about whatever local rule or
called us fascists or anything yet so
like why are you here and I just calmly
like I'm I've got an issue
that's important to me that's coming up
from in front of council and I wanted to
get a feel for the meetings and they're
like cool like they don't that they're
interested that you're interested is all
yeah even if they disagree with you
they're glad you could put a coherent
argument together because if you go to a
few of these and watch there'll be three
or four crazy people that have the
public speaking rules on lockdown and go
every week to rail and like call your
local elected officials fascist and
[ __ ] about how they're taking away you
to say it's because it's an always
there's always one elderly person
bitching about the same bumpkin thing
for the past eight years in there yep my
mic off so you got to talk for a minute
I'm gonna do a DAB I've had the same
really nice lady come and asked me to
stand up in solidarity when she asked me
to in you know who in the crowd wants to
impeach the council with me she's
everybody stand up when I say that and
she'll go to everybody in the meeting
and spent like an hour talking to people
and then nobody will stand up she's done
a hundred times just go and watch and
when you start making a coherent
argument you can see their faces light
up like people dying of thirst being
offered water thank you because it's a
lot of nonsense and when it's not total
nonsense it's ridiculously specific
legal jargon that gets read aloud by
somebody with a voice that's designed to
put people to sleep usually and so they
just latch on to whatever you're saying
and I was able to turn seven people who
are definitely against me into five
people that were with me in like two
months of just going down and in using a
three minute window to point out
economic benefits of legalization and I
wasn't using anything that I didn't
Google if you're not good at asking
Google the right questions hit me up
online and I will help you like that's
really all it takes how can they how can
they hit you up you can find me a Pueblo
for sensible cannabis laws on Facebook
or at Nemo Punk 15 on Twitter
nice bad buddy it tastes so good
was that the Durbin of the bananas that
was neither green dot Labs screaming
scout full-spectrum extract there's got
to be something screaming and Girl Scout
cookies and it tastes so good
yep or a weird for you know with a loud
scout I wish they'd start putting
further genetic information on label me
too let's just [ __ ] you and your boys
name feel free to write that too I
respect that more than just putting
shenanigans on the side of the package
it's just straight sauce so you're just
gonna get it's like just a liquid dab is
all that raw there's a little Turpin
there little diamond in there that needs
to be heated but yeah so yeah we came to
a pause in the show um how is how is
Canada changing how is this going to
affect us in Colorado
Canada's but when Uruguay legalized Oh
keep that for you can ah when you're
boiling guys the West went so whoo yeah
like cute little old man president yay
like all nine of your people have legal
weed now good for you like that's
literally how the West reacted and there
were a couple anti-pop people that were
like this will not stand you were in
convention of 90 but for the most part
no one gave a [ __ ] but Canada's major
there a major US trading partner we
share a huge border there in all the
summits they participate in all the
community
of committees they're one of our major
partners in everything this impacts a
lot and stuff that it doesn't directly
impact they're gonna provide us all the
data that we need for legalization
everywhere else Colorado is doing that
but it's harder to find I have a feeling
that Canada is gonna be really upfront
and loud and proud about this because
they've got universal health care they
can track some [ __ ] we can all right a
little better and a lot of like that's
what I'm really looking forward to about
cannabis legalization like I've got
legalization here I don't need to travel
to enjoy it right y'all want to give me
a killer job in Canada I'm willing to
get we need to get some passports
because a hockey puck I don't know what
they call it there we've both I know
that I've been requested my presence has
been requested in Canada to help get
some things going so I need to try to
Tim Hortons for our Canada with
listeners but I don't know anything else
about Canada other than I love all the
people I've met from what was i taunt
adventure in what I think yeah right
they said come get some poutine in
French women and I was like well that
sounds like a win-win situation for me
there's a lot about Canada you'd enjoy
everything but the weather I think I was
gonna say it's [ __ ] 100 degrees let's
go let's go here I'm talking funny I
actually have a random chatter I lived
in Lawrence Kansas and I knew a couple
of kids from from Canada coolest [ __ ]
kids I hung out with so one dude was a
drummer is a huge Neil Peart fan a
he said boss diesel a lot I thought it
was pretty funny I'm sticking to it
alright so since Mike is gonna choke for
a couple of minutes I've got an email
that I think I should read and now is
probably the best time I'll leave Mike's
microphone on just so that you can hear
him over there I'll put him about
halfway if he decides to talk I'll turn
him up this email comes from our
Canadian friend and it's perfectly timed
I don't know if he wants his name said
we'll get to that part it says here US
Canadian friend actually says his name
in the email he says hey what up Rasta
Jeff squishy Macross in here I'll just
get right to it I cannot express enough
how thankful I am for your show after
listening I realized I had to stop and
reassess everything I was doing not just
in my garden but in my life
was growing illegally putting my family
at risk and doing nothing with the
cannabis knowledge I had so this dude
realized one day probably because I said
you're gonna get [ __ ] raided I've
said that on the show and he thought oh
that man they'll shoot my dog it'll take
my kids that's your [ __ ] dog that's
the truth as soon as that front door
comes off life sinks in quickly trust me
he says since listening to you and your
amazing guests that's you Mike I've
stepped up my game I've become
determined to be a positive light for
cannabis sharing information with anyone
that will listen you have given me the
tools to break down barriers and
communicate with the people about
cannabis who are otherwise uninformed
people are overwhelmed with the amount
of cannabis information I am able to
clearly articulate to them and I've
never had a negative response
I have sought out a company aimed to
assist people in getting people safe
access to cannabis in Canada they're
helping me through the process of
obtaining a personal production license
I am now able to confidently and clearly
express how and why I use cannabis to
doctors which is something I would not
have been able to do before he says from
your episodes I was able to build a
cannabis tailored resume and obtain a
position at a licensed producer so we
got another person this is the second
person that I've got an email from
recently that we got we helped them get
a job in the cannabis industry he goes
on to say I've also gotten involved in
my local cannabis community attending
public oh sorry the computer just said
their updates available will do that way
later or not right now don't do it we're
gonna have to tell it later is Apple
will just keep begging remind me
tomorrow there we go we'll keep moving
with the email he says I've also gotten
involved with my local cannabis
community attending public cannabis
information sessions and I participated
in several government engagement surveys
to ensure my voices heard excellent this
guy's on the right path good job squishy
he goes on to say recreational cannabis
will be legal here in Canada in 8 to 12
weeks and I am proud to have been a part
of the process here's the part where it
gets cool dude he says I believe that
you have also contributed indirectly
because without the guidance of you and
white Mike I wouldn't huh I would not
have gotten involved so we had a little
bit a little bit of the tickle there if
you meant like Canada doing their thing
that's awesome yeah yeah well that's why
I've been trying to get you over here
also do this counter Depa sewed with you
I want to share this with you dude he's
got two kids and a great wife I would be
there all the time if I were you I he
keeps going he says so you're completely
right when you say together we can
legalize cannabis worldwide do it that
means a lot to me
ah that's that's huge I know we're kind
of joking about it but bet is huge thank
you for uh first of all thank you for
taking action thank you for doing it you
had to do it I inspired you i sat here
and taught us a lot of Awesome in that
email yeah I sat her and talked behind a
microphone and said what to do you
actually had to get off the couch you
had to go get a shaky voice and speak in
front of people and thanks for giving me
a little bit of credit and I man thanks
for getting inspired so we're gonna keep
going there's a lot more he says I'm
sure when he started the agriculture
podcast that's how long the students
been listening agriculture thank you bro
for you guys you guys don't know I had
to change the name there's another
company I grow and they got they got
angry about that [ __ ] they did not like
the weed leaf logo no they came at me I
know there's a weird sense of pride when
you get a cease-and-desist I was
stealing from someone noticed cool
someone's looking anyway we're gonna
keep going he said when he started
agriculture you had no idea just how far
it would go and the way it would affect
other people's lives I have so much
respect for you and your selfless
approach to helping improve people's
lives I hope this email makes your day
the way you made so many of mine dude it
totally may it's made my week because I
read this several days ago and I knew
this show was coming up so I've just
been checking it out and smiling about
it all the time I think I sent a little
screenshot a part of it to my coop so I
gave him a little teaser oh man thank
you you made my day I'm glad I'm able to
make your day I'm doing I'm glad you're
out there doing it for Canada - thank
you I don't know what you guys say in
Canada you got like Rastafarians we say
big up so big up bro the email keeps
going he says I'm not a Rastafarian but
I praise Jah for this gift that Rasta
Jeff and the girl from your heart
podcast may his light continue to shine
on you and your gardens PS I've taken a
fat dab and given my mom a hug for you
this guy's killing it doing all of it
he's got it all correct bro Thank You
Man I appreciate the support thanks for
uh being part of the Irie army squishing
Macross on and
you definitely tee my region etics girl
from your heart crew whatever you want
to call it now we need some sort of cool
name
you got the Irie army what are we gonna
go with podcast listener just the Hydra
army is that what we are that's
definitely part of that IRA army so we
appreciate that we're gonna make that
stick we're gonna skip that it's the IRA
army squishy thank you for the great
email dude I appreciate it I know I've
said it over and over I'm [ __ ] high a
[ __ ] I want to make sure I say it
seriously
I get jokey when I get stoned I don't
take [ __ ] super seriously I want to make
sure you realize how much I appreciate
that thank you for the great email
Congrats bro Congrats on the success up
there to get notifications to let us
know how it's going
i I'm gonna follow Canada pretty closely
they've I've seen some concerning press
already where I'm like oh really that
had to happen already and I've seen some
stuff from like [ __ ] yeah Canada and
I've almost never said that in my life
so it's definitely a cool time for
Canada Oklahoma as well no Mike I've got
why I may have two more questions for he
depends on how long we go on this one
question how long until we're federally
legal here in the States now I used to
think about it would take us about
another decade about another decade um
if you follow politics at all you know
that everything that's true um one is
true anymore
it's true we live in a banana ranek time
where we're led by an orange crazy
person yes yes so ten years you think
I'd be down well I would be cool if I
would be satisfied with seeing so many
there's so many things that are in play
on this particular question are up in
the air right now
that wasn't true under any of the
previous presidents easier I was getting
any other time in our lives I was gonna
add the the deciding factor is probably
the next two presidential elections is
what I would decide the midterms are
gonna be insanely important and then the
next presidential is gonna be huge
it'll be huge and the presidential after
that will also be huge yeah by the time
the next presidential happens like
another
Supreme Court C will be there open or
damn near close we just had one open up
this week Senate population changes
rapidly right now we just saw like a
legit [ __ ] socialist when the person
who was going to take over for like the
ranking Democrat they were the next in
line for the throne got D [ __ ] thrown
in a primary - like a 28-year old
unknown chick with like a super
immigrant a name like she had a long
[ __ ] hill to climb in just home run
home run home run home run won the
[ __ ] election nice and right now that
in a couple of other things along with
President Trump and all of those
everything's like I don't want to get
into too much and make this show super
political but a lot of [ __ ] that would
affect federal legalization happening or
not happening is all up in the air right
now the hardcore members of the Senate
that are against it might not have jobs
in six months or a year 18 months the
people that are for it also might not
have jobs right everyone can swim
president Trump could [ __ ] legalize
it through some sort of bizarre decree
or he could start really pushing the
Senate to do it the proper way or he
could get impeached like just keep going
a lot of fun you can do different ways
or you could [ __ ] this OD on diet
pills one day it's the world is a very
strange place right now and in
predicting something like federal
legalization that's gonna take so many
different acts of line like that's tough
then let I'd I wouldn't expect it
anytime soon definitely don't invest
money tomorrow based on it happening
soon one more thing I kind of want to
touch on that I honestly have no
education on but I know that this is a
thing somewhere along the line when
Canada legalizes can't has legalized
cannabis and when the state's finally
legalize federally what sort of
international rules or treaties are we
breaking because I've heard there
Russia mentioned there's a major UN
Convention that says you can't legalize
basically narcotics drugs of abuse and
enjoyment if it's not beer you can't
legalize yeah yeah it's a policy that
the u.s. really really pushed like it's
basically ours that we forced on the
rest of the world the rest of the world
was happy to jump on our [ __ ] so
it's not all our fault
but it's all our fault so if we look
donate and now we're falling on it our
slaves
there's a number of countries that have
called us on it and the in the UN and
call this out on our [ __ ] like hey you
push this on everybody and now Colorado
and Washington [ __ ] do what I mean
they say it in German so no one in the
u.s. knows it happened but it did happen
and it's happened repeatedly it just
hasn't had much of an impact yet the
anti-pop people bring it up every now
and then it will be in violation of UN
Convention it's like whoa [ __ ] Russia
invaded a country and we just kind of
chill it's kind of hang out we no one's
gonna like [ __ ] cut us off trade
because we legalized weed I thought I
saw headlines while I was skimming
through doing a quick a little check
that Russia was already offended that
we're doing it well that janet is doing
it that's one of the things that we're
really gonna see with Canada now like no
one really cared when Uruguay did it and
their global impact
I mean it's substantial for Uruguay but
it's not substantial for some of the
other major countries especially when
compared to Canada like they're not
comparable trading partners as far as
I'm aware in any way and so when Canada
does this a lot a lot of people who were
able to completely ignore Uruguay doing
it cannot at all ignore Canada all right
that makes more sense it makes much more
sense mm-hmm all right you got any more
for Canada to make sure we know Canada
there you go way to go Canada will quit
making make it funnier smoke enjoy and
watch Tamaki II guess we're not gonna
make quit making funny because Mike had
one more burn to throw at you
I love you guys it's I know it's not
perfect I know there are a lot of issues
with it I know some of the penalties for
going around or outside of the limits
are just as harsh or harsher than they
are now but trust me give it a few
minutes participate make sure that the
laws the zoning the distribution stuff
the conversation around it is rational
and you'll be a lot happier with
legalization and you ever work with
prohibition trust me all right gentlemen
I'm gonna give a few shoutouts right
quick I'm just gonna jump right in with
shoutouts I wanna give a shout out to
Tanner am a shout out to Melanie
Alexander and a shout out to Todd Keller
that's what I got for me for shoutouts
for today we're gonna keep going with
the podcast after that I just wanted to
make sure to do that cuz I kind of been
skipping on that I've been slacking on
that but I still think about you guys
wanna make sure to get some shout outs
in there let's move forward with the
podcast hey Mike thanks for hanging out
here I see you grabbing the phone yes
you've been here for quite a while we're
gonna have to start wrapping up the show
and get you back to the kids and the
wife and animals mostly chaos that's to
back out there in the heat so the [ __ ]
ready for tomorrow
go crushing the heat again no dad you
guys we need some air conditioning if
you could just turn up the air
conditioner in Colorado that be cold
there's a little bit if you're in
southern Colorado like we need to all
get together on a Facebook page your
[ __ ] Twitter account or some and then
I'll go outside Mike sprayer hose in the
air for 20 minutes together I don't know
if that's even gonna work who do we
complain to about this heat can I see
your manager it's hot like 105 people
check on your big friends people it's
hot out there ladies and gentlemen don't
forget about the hella dank seed company
fourth of July sale got it's fourth of
July already dude it was just 4:20 last
week what's happening it's flying fourth
of July sale is coming up that's right
from July 3rd through July 5th that's a
short window if you use coupon code re
20 you can get 20% off your entire
purchase plus there will be a new drop
of I read genetics coming soon I'm
working on the custom packaging if the
custom packaging happens on time it will
come that if not it'll be in that old
standard packaging we're working on it
we're trying to get it there we're
trying we're trying don't forget about
the holiday exceed company guys you can
find them at dank seed dot store they've
got regular see they got feminized
they've got hydrogen etics they've got
bog they've got a great bunch of brands
there go check them out also don't
forget about the patreon campaign if you
feel like this podcast was educational
informative and/or entertaining you can
go to patreon.com/scishow or from your
heart you can learn how to contribute to
the podcast make sure you stock us on
all of the social media you can find us
on Facebook it's the girl from the heart
podcast on Instagram you can find me
it's IRA underscore genetics on Twitter
the show is at G f YH podcast
I am Ross - Jeff 420 mike is at Nemo
punk 15 on most of the social media also
make sure you check out Mike's Facebook
page at is pueblo for sensible cannabis
laws go stalk him on there go send him a
message let him know you're following
him let him know that you support a
legalization if you've got questions
about getting active about legalization
if you need guidance if you just want to
say what's up go talk to my Duty's
hanging out with the kids all the time
you could use some interaction I can
chat on the phone yeah you can set the
kids in the life body before you double
up y'all wrap it up so you don't double
up that's worth it they're gonna make a
lot of money so that's alright now we're
already working on another shirt make
sure that's my friend non-toxic yogi I
want to thank everybody for all the love
and support ah ladies and gentlemen if
you've got something you'd like to say
in your not into all that social media
stuff or if you've liked if you'd like
to sponsor the podcast or if you've got
a product you'd like me to review um
whatever if you'd like to just reach out
send me an email the email address is
grow from your heart at hotmail.com
I love hearing from you I've got a lot
of emails that need to get caught up
I've been packing the show with grow
lessons we will get back to emails
pretty soon I know they're there you
guys seem to have been loving the grow
lessons the podcast is ranked 635 out of
40,000 shows I must be doing something
right so yeah we're gonna we're gonna
keep going the way we're going we'll get
back to emails pretty soon well blend
some of those in you guys you can listen
to the podcast on iTunes you can listen
to the show on stitcher hey I'm working
with stitcher they told me one way to
try to fix a show that [ __ ] didn't work
dude I'm sending them emails we're gonna
figure it out I apologize that the
stitcher application doesn't work
hopefully hopefully you figured out that
you can listen to it on the stitcher
website you don't have to use the app
maybe you can go to YouTube I put every
single episode on stitcher listener
who's converted to YouTube I see a lot
or listens on YouTube if you guys
continue to listen on YouTube I will
improve the videos I know that sounds
like I'm bargaining with you but I've
got more time now and if I see that
that's a thing I will do it better
when I see that it gets response I will
improve it but it just takes a lot of
time to make videos I'll start putting I
don't want to make these high quality
videos and have YouTube jack my channel
but they gave custom grow back his
channel they give they're giving people
back their channels so I think I'm safe
bolted pretty good and I don't know if
it was enough like that's one of the
other benefits of being a home country
being legal yeah that's not an issue
anymore
no the heat you're gonna take for
getting up and standing up and saying
the rules around this should be rational
like if that's your message the heat
you're gonna take for that it's gonna be
pretty minimal where is if you stand up
and do that in a prohibition area the
heat you're gonna take for that can be
pretty intense for sure for sure alright
y'all make the YouTube videos better
I'll start putting more images in there
maybe I don't like recording my face and
doing the show like that I just really
don't like doing it I've done a couple
maybe I'll do more of those it just
depends if if I get enough YouTube
interaction maybe you will start doing
that
don't forget about patreon alright
ladies and gentlemen thanks for
listening to the podcast Mike thanks for
coming and hanging out kids hey Mike's
wife if you ever happen to listen to the
podcast thanks for letting me borrow
your husband for a podcast I bring him
over here he gets higher [ __ ] and
rambles for a little bit or kids
he said Pink's wives sorry kids yep
alright umm you guys do what you can do
to get cannibus illegalized in your area
get active get loud get your voice heard
don't be afraid
anyone can go to a public meeting and
listener talk anyone can write a letter
to their local paper and have it
published it's free content for the
paper they [ __ ] publish everything
don't show up to the city council
meetings blazed out go professional put
on a collared shirt look nice
represent us clean shirt comb your hair
if that's a thing thanks Mike Lee and
do-rag thanks Mike comb your hair
hey for
99% of the population those words are to
[ __ ] you I try to remember that it's not
just let's talk it on here so I don't
advocating [ __ ] but I mean anyone can do
this if you're not the type of person
who's comfortable public speaking and
you're more comfortable writing an email
like there's the newspaper can't like
look you up and be like [ __ ] Donnie
Brasco don't live there if you if you
make up a decent pen Nnamdi plumber a
pen name and send a letter to your local
paper advocating legalization under a
pseudonym look that's not a crime and
they'll be more than happy to publish it
if you use appropriate language and make
rational arguments and anyone can do
that yep in everybody
yeah email email local officials just
follow this stuff and be informed and
when it comes up in conversation
enlighten the conversation also if
you're one of the people like me who
knows way too much about weed one of the
things I found helpful with non weed
people is ask them how much they want to
know yeah sometimes we have a tendency
to kind of dump truck unload our
information onto people and they're like
I just wanted some weed that'll my girl
like she said go buy his weed so I'm at
the weed store and buy Clementine for
girls like now I know you know a
master's degree worth about weed and
she's pissed because I've been to the
store for an hour and a half yeah yeah
just ask all right you guys get
yourselves active out there and I always
say this every time if you're going to
be involved in writing making creating
the rules of legislation around cannabis
in your area please include some more to
consume there's nowhere to smoke legally
here give us dude how about a smoking
park an outdoor smoke park Oh Mike just
not a dis have your dog fart for
starters yeah exactly that's what I saw
just put your dudes kicking around a
hacky sack like if you're cat people
don't go to this part like that's your
not discriminating against cats right
like we could non-smokers yeah [ __ ] them
we could have a part yeah yeah then make
us put up [ __ ] [ __ ] you can't see
through a vehicle with that as long as
we can be outside got a picnic table a
couple of children make you like smoking
lounges in the airport ten years ago
that was not pleasant but do you include
some sort of smoking consumption area
joke-a-lot and outside smoke bark maybe
an inside like somewhere where you can
go kick it have an outdoor patio I loved
it when we could go to different places
and smoke there was the canna the candy
Canyon was set up real classy
it was painted kind of I mean for a
smoke lounge for what we had it was
painted in absolute modifier it was
decorated by a yoga chick like it was
very yoga chick like in there so it felt
kind of nice and I mean it was clean I
had hardwood floors it had some IKEA
couches there were paintings on the wall
the real others there were no TVs there
was no loud music and it was chill then
right across town was the the dab lounge
they got pool tables
they've got [ __ ] a stage with
comedians live it's more of like oh my
god bars in a place yeah and then right
across town is the a 64 over they
actually turned an old bar into a smoke
Club so where there's a bar and people
are just sitting at the bar smoke and
watching the game it was mostly just
dudes our age smoking a joint watching
the game and like can I get another
pre-roll and the girl up there just
passes in pre rolls and she's the
charges just like they're getting
another drink
they just sit there and smoke pre-rolls
and dad's and watch the game people
freak out about that concept but it's
like we already have an infrastructure
built for people to gather at a location
become intoxicated and have someone else
deliver them home like we [ __ ]
invented that shift for bars and
football games and literally every other
event adults gather in groups of more
than three like there's no reason we
can't do this with the weed other than
people we people are uptight about it
people are scared you should hear the
conversations around that around this
topic in Denver it's absolutely not yeah
it's going crazy right now we're we
definitely need somewhere for it we got
really close to having answer and we
just our latest attempt just failed yeah
again again all right guys we're about
to wrap up the show and we got super RAM
believe that's what a bunch of good
sativa dad there's some driven poison
and that stuff they do like it when we
ramble they absolutely do you guys
thanks for supporting the show thanks
for listening thanks for all the
interactions my emails my Twitter my
facebook my Instagram my patreon
everything has been blowing up lately
the holiday exceed company has been
going crazy lately
I truly appreciate all
support I've been changing my life to be
more available for what I want to do in
this podcast is part of what I want to
do this is heavily what I want to do so
thank you for supporting my endeavors
without the support from all my friends
and family my listeners my network I
would not be able to live the way I live
so I appreciate you guys and I love you
for it I'm gonna wrap up the podcast
before I start crying I'm just kidding
thank you everybody you guys are just
awesome listeners we love all of you
yeah yeah each and every one of you know
who there's not one guy over there that
one guy no you're cool bro you can be
part of the group again we'll bring you
back ladies gentleman thanks again for
listening to the podcast you know I'll
be back in just a couple of days with
another episode I know this episode had
no girl lessons in it but you got a
whole bunch we'll get back onto that
we'll also get to some emails got a lot
of great stuff coming up
ladies and gentlemen I'm gonna wrap up
the podcast I wanna give you a huge
shout out to my friend Kelvin Medina and
Oklahoma
what up Calvin and until next time take
a phat dab and give your mom a hug for
me