Oh
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for another episode of the
grow from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation let's write up here a new
grower if you're a professional grower
if you're a new smoker or a dedicated
dabber if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who is just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host my friends call me Rasta Jeff I
want to thank you guys again for joining
me this episode of the podcast is
brought to you by my friends at the hell
a dank seed company if you need new
genetics for your garden I highly
recommend the hella dank seed company
you can find them at Bank seed dot store
ladies and gentlemen roll up a fat joint
pack up the bong or start heating up
that dab rig because it's time for
another episode of the grill from your
heart podcast yo what's up internet
world it's time for episode 331 of the
grill from your heart podcast thanks
again for joining me this episode of the
podcast is brought to you by my friends
at the hell a dank seed company if you
need new regular or feminized seeds for
your garden I highly recommend the hella
dank seed company and you can find them
at dank seed dot store you guys know I
like to start these episodes off by
letting you know what I'm smoking on
today I've been taking dabs of this soul
cleanser full-spectrum extract from our
friends at Green Dot labs at his cush
cleaner and chem for together and they
describe it as a lemon-lime sport drink
when Dex and chem dog gas flavors you
know the lemon-lime sport drink was very
very dominant in the flavor then when
you exhale there's a hint of that Windex
and I know that sounds crazy but it
tasted and had a little aroma of Windex
and then the after flavor is definitely
that chem dog gas with a little bit of
the lemon-lime sport drink just chilling
there so very well described that's the
sole cleanser from our friends at Green
Dot labs also after that I took a big
dab of some cherry diesel live resin and
that seemed to put me in a really
rambley talkative mood that cherry
diesel was super smooth it had a candy
flavor to it and really made my head
spin so the combo has got me nice and
talkative this should be a great podcast
all right before we move forward into
the main topic of the podcast I would
like to read a couple of emails this
first email comes from
who calls himself Marco s cuando las and
the email goes like this hi raasta Jeff
thank you for your great show it pains
me to hear you recommend Hobby Lobby as
a place to buy supplies Hobby Lobby is a
politically active right-wing
organization lobbying for the
continuation of the war on drugs you're
giving your money to a corporation who
would like to see you your friends and
your family rotting in jail for the rest
of your lives
now what this email is referring to is
in the trimming episode I mentioned
picking up your scissors at Hobby Lobby
um this guy is correct we should not be
shopping at Hobby Lobby thanks for
waking me up to that the reason I said
Hobby Lobby is because not everybody has
access to a gross store not everybody
can just drive right up to grow
generation or one loved garden supply or
a grow warehouse or way to grow not
everybody could just zip right over
there and shop around and get the best
deal on scissors I blurted out Hobby
Lobby because that was my back-up plan
when I didn't have a gross store around
here those places have a Hobby Lobby
also some people aren't comfortable
going to the gross store they can't be
seen at the hydroponic store they can't
be seen parked out front there they
can't be seen in there they just have to
be a little more careful they can go to
Hobby Lobby they might be going to Hobby
Lobby already they can just cruise over
and pick up a pair of those scissors but
you are correct we should not be
shopping at Hobby Lobby if they are
continuing to participate and support
the war on drugs we don't want anything
to do with that so let's stop giving
them our money here's what I like about
this email our friend Marco s windowless
offers suggestions and other
opportunities he presents a problem
offers a suggestion on how to solve that
problem he says instead I suggest
sending your listeners to either their
local grow shop or a shop that supports
our community like build a soil then he
adds I just got titanium bladed scissors
for eight dollars and 40 cents on sale
at bil the soil so you guys that is a
great option let's try to skip Hobby
Lobby if we can I should not have said
that I should not have recommended that
let's skip the Hobby Lobby let's try to
go somewhere that supports our community
better first off let's try to shop at a
local grocer that supports our community
if you cannot do that then maybe find a
craft store that is locally owned
maybe you got a craft store owned by a
little old lady and her daughter runs it
maybe give them your money but try to
put your money back into your community
and not somewhere
is going to support the war on drugs if
all else fails that's when you go to
Amazon our friend sent us another email
saying that it's probably cheaper to
shop at the gross store which yes that
is probably true but not everybody has a
gross store and not everybody can go to
the gross store so some folks are gonna
need a back-up plan
some folks are gonna need a way to get
their supplies discretely if you can't
go to your local grocery store that
supports your community locally that's
when you turn to Amazon but if the
products are available locally and
they're competitively priced and you
don't put yourself in any jeopardy by
going to a gross store please shop at
your local grocer or that supports our
community if you've got a chain store or
you've got a mom-and-pop store try to
support that mom-and-pop store let's try
to spend our money wisely let's try to
support people instead of businesses so
why only huge shout-outs my friend Marco
s windowless dude thank you for
listening to the show thank you for
waking me up thank you for reminding us
that Hobby Lobby is not on our team and
thanks for the great email dude I do
appreciate it Rai Rai Rocco all right
you guys I've got one more email and
then we're gonna get to the main part of
the podcast this email goes like this it
says Rasta Jeff thank you for your
podcast I am new to the industry I've
worked for the Department of Defense for
14 years now I was against all things
cannabis until recently I really just
want to say thank you I listen to your
podcast and the DGC podcast and you all
have turned me on to cannabis as
medicine and I wholeheartedly believe in
it Wow here's the part where I wish I
had some sort of audience applause sound
effects to insert because that is great
this person worked for the Department of
Defense for 14 years and they were
against all things cannabis but with the
help of the dude grows crew and myself
we were able to convince this person
that cannabis is medicine and now they
wholeheartedly believe in cannabis as
medicine so we have flipped this person
they agree with us now let's continue
with the email it says I am currently
looking to get away from the enemy and
they save the government Babylon and
into the medical cannabis industry now
that it's legal in Oklahoma I hope to
make a life of helping people heal and
feel better about life and themselves I
use and have used for about a year now
as my health is not what it once was I
have seen my dad pass away
from cancer due to Agent Orange and I
wish he had access to cannabis my mother
is currently battling breast cancer and
has used cannabis to keep her weight up
as well as myself battling melanoma and
currently using for anxiety and stress
relief thank you for giving me good
material to listen and learn from as
well as just making my morning commute
better I fully believe in cannabis and
now that I have been born again to the
great things it can do I will never turn
my back on it I will advocate for it and
just want to say thank you from the
bottom of my heart thank you you guys
these messages like this are
overwhelming to me this is why I do the
show I'm not sure if I want to dance
around I'm not sure if I want to cry a
little bit ah I've got a huge smile and
I feel a little bit numb these messages
make all of this effort worth it these
messages make every frustrating minute
behind this microphone these messages
make every second of writing this
podcast these messages make the couple
hours that I miss doing other things
with my friends sometimes I got to skip
out on [ __ ] because I have to record hey
bro you want to go down and do this nah
man I'm gonna record a podcast and all
my friends go have fun I'm here
recording these messages make everything
I've missed worth it these messages make
every night I've stayed up late to edit
a show worth it
messages like this are why I have a
podcast messages like this are what we
are here for this is why we have a
cannabis community we found a friend who
was part of the Department of Defense
and was against cannabis okay now they
are dedicating their lives to helping
other people learn how to use cannabis
to better their lives to improve their
well-being to enjoy their life better
this person has done a 180 they were on
the other team now they are fully
supporting our team so that's what our
podcasts are doing you guys that's what
our advocating is doing this is what
standing up and speaking up for
ourselves and speaking out for ourselves
has done we are able to help more people
we are convincing more people that this
is a medicine so this person wrote this
email to say thank you and I appreciate
the thanks but thank you because this is
the best compliment that I could have
received this is the best email I could
have gotten
all week this made my day this made my
week so thank you
I truly appreciate this now I also want
to say I'm sorry that you lost your dad
to cancer from Agent Orange that is
terrible but I am proud of you for being
able to help your mom with her breast
cancer I hope that helps her keep her
weight up and also I hope you say that
you're using cannabis to fight your
melanoma and using it for anxiety and
stress relief perfect uses I hope that
continues to work for you people often
forget that our mental health is just as
important as our physical health and
sometimes that little mind escape the
cannabis brings you can be a healthy
thing you forget that you're sick you
forget that you're in pain and you're
able to relax and enjoy your life for a
little bit and that's what it's all
about enjoying life improving the
quality of life so this is a great email
thank you I'm proud of you thanks for
joining our team and thank you for
thanking me I think this feeling is
mutual we agree so thanks a lot you have
made my day if you guys have any more
questions or if there's anything that I
or my audience can do to help your mom
or yourself out please let me know just
reach out to me we would love to be
there for you
also take a phat dab and hug your mom
for me hey thank you for the great email
I do appreciate that I get a lot of
praise and a lot of thanks for the
podcast but messages like this always
touch me you guys so don't ever stop
please and if anybody else out there
would like to send me an email letting
me know about their change of heart or
maybe how you've convinced another
family member that cannabis would be
useful or maybe how you've turned
somebody else from the dark side to the
green side I would love to hear your
story I would love to hear your input if
you'd like to share your story with me
my email address is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com I look forward to it all
right you guys I've been going for just
over ten minutes now I haven't taken a
drink I haven't taken a DAB I'm going to
press pause for a quick second probably
play some music for you I'm gonna take a
couple of dabs all that music plays and
when we come back we're going to talk
about the difference between R 1 and s 1
labeling on seed packages
[Music]
all right podcast rolled I am back
remember those dabs I was telling you
about they worked they are working I'm
feeling great I'm well hydrated I'm well
medicated and I am back to talk about
podcasting before we get into the main
topic I've got one more thing I'd like
to remind you about and that one thing
is patreon if you feel like this podcast
was educational entertaining or
informative and you'd like to contribute
financially to the show you can do so by
going to www.petland.com
slash grow from your heart all of the
information that you need will be right
there
you guys I offer several different gifts
or rewards for my patreon contributors
that's the quickest way to get your
email read on a show or the quickest way
to get a shout-out from me
but I also offer things like a 30-minute
one-on-one consultation through FaceTime
or Skype we can look at your grow room
you can bring your plant right up to the
camera you can show me what's going on
with your plants and we can diagnose a
problem if you've got a problem or we
can walk through your grow room if
you've got your phone and we could just
look at your grow and figure out what's
going on we can figure out how to
improve your grow or if you've got any
weird growing questions that you don't
feel like you can we can answer through
emails or whatever you can get personal
consultations the way to do that is
through the patreon campaign and the way
to find the patreon page is
www.patiyer.com I seed and feminized
seed labeling if you guys pay attention
to the show or if you pay attention to I
read genetics you know that I am making
golden
feminized seeds and more lemon Jeffrey
feminized seeds the golden goat will be
straight golden goat I took a golden
goat female and turned it into a male
I used that male golden Gopalan and put
that to a golden goat female which will
make seeds it will only have female
chromosomes because there was no male
involved i reversed a female it will
only have female chromosomes and it will
only have gold and goat genetics so
those seeds will be gold and go s once
now in the same project I am making
lemon Jeffrey lemon Jeffrey is a lemon
skunk female pollinated by that reversed
golden goat male so that's golden goat
pollen with no male chromosomes applied
to a lemon skunk female that will
produce feminized lemon Jeffrey are one
seeds now before I get into the R 1 and
s 1 let's quickly talk about regular non
feminized seed breeding labels if I were
to breed something non feminized will
use a rise as an example a rise is a
golden goat female to a Daybreaker male
you would put in parentheses golden goat
x Daybreaker in parentheses that's
golden goat to Daybreaker that would
make a rise f1f1 indicates first filial
generation which means it's the first
time that strain has been crossed if I
take that strain and find a male and a
female and breathe them together what
comes out of that will be the f2 and so
forth so that's where the F comes in and
regular seed breeding when you're
breeding with feminized seeds that's
when the F is replaced with R's or
assets now let's talk about the R's and
s's let's start with s first if you see
a seed package and it is labeled golden
goat s 1 that indicates that those seeds
came from a reversed golden goat female
that was turned into a male that pollen
was used on another golden goat plant
and it is itself the letter S indicates
that it is itself and no other genetics
were introduced into that cross now good
reason for doing that is to preserve
genetics let's say that I get tired of
growing golden goat or something goes
wrong and I can't have gold and go
anymore or
let's say maybe there's a fire or a
flood and my golden goat plant gets
destroyed I have got s1 seeds of golden
goat to keep it in preservation the
seeds that I release for golden goat are
s1 seeds because it is a female planet I
do not have a male there is no known
male of golden goat floating around so
the only way you could make more seeds
of golden goat would be to reverse it
and make self seeds out of it make s
ones and that is good for
self-preservation it's also good to get
those genetics out to people in other
places that don't have access to the
clones you can get the seeds out to
people that way everybody's got the
opportunity to grow something similar
very similar to golden goat so s stands
for self and that is selfing a plant
that is for self preservation and
preserving genes it doesn't adulterate
those genes with anything else if you
were to cross the Golden go to something
else you've created a new cross say the
Daybreaker
then you could find a male that looks
like that golden goat and do that to the
original gold and go female and now
you've created a back cross which is
different that's non feminized and
you're gonna have a lot of variation
you're gonna have to work that but the
feminized route the self route there is
no adulteration no introduction of new
genes so it's really easy to get exactly
the golden goat you're looking for so
that is selfing selfing is taking a
plant and making seeds of itself without
adulterating its genetic makeup now that
we understand selfing let's talk about
our R stands for reversal and r1 is a
first generation of a reversal if I were
to take that feminized golden goat
pollen that we were talking about
earlier and put that on a different
plant that is not golden goat now we
have created what's called a reversal
and that will be feminized and it will
be a new cross lemon Jeffrey is an r1
that is feminized golden goat pollen on
a lemon skunk female and that makes a
brand new cross so that's a reversal one
it's an r1 as what you would label that
that would be your lemon Jeffrey r1
let's talk more about an r1 what is the
purpose of an r1 the purpose of an r1 is
to create new and unique
crosses I know a lot of people are
haters on FEM seeds but they are very
useful for people with limited plant
counts and for people that can't risk
wasting time and space on having a male
plant so there is an application forum I
do not hate them I support them I make
them myself
so the short version of this story would
be if you reversed a plant and put the
pollen on itself that is a self if you
reverse a plant and put that pollen on
any other cultivar you have just created
a new reversal both of those the r1 and
the s-1 are both feminized now let's
talk about phenotype expectations from
the two of those obviously if you're
doing an s-1 you hope to find really
close representations of your original
female plant you're going to see some
traits of the parents of that plant but
it's going to be very close
representations of the original plant
you start with some will lean towards
the mom some will lean toward the dad
but most of those phenotypes that come
from those femme seeds are going to look
a lot like the original plant you
started with now let's talk about the
phenotypes from reversals reversals show
phenotypes a lot like regular breeding
you're going to see a perfect 50/50
blend of the two parents you start with
you'll see some that look a lot like the
female you started with you'll see that
some that look a lot like the dad you
started with you may get little
indicators of the grandparents reversals
are going to show you different
phenotypes a lot like normal breeding
but I think a little bit of variation is
to be desired when you're working with
seeds that's why I like to grow from
seed if I wanted everything to look
exactly the same I would grow from
clones so expect to see a little bit of
phenotypical variation if you're running
reversals if you're running selves out
of a six pack you will definitely find
the one that looks just like the one on
the package or just like the one you saw
on the website or just like the one that
you smoked somewhere that got you super
excited about it now you've got that
cross now you've got that specific
phenotype and you can grow it for
yourself all the time make sure you take
a clone oh please make sure you take a
clone all right you guys I feel like I
broke down the difference between
reversals and self seeds both are
feminized the main difference again is
if I took that pollen from one plant and
applied it to itself or apply
Paul in two different plants self is s1
anything else becomes a reversal that's
an r1 keep that in mind always keep in
mind when you're labeling genetic
crosses that you list the female first
ladies first all the time so when you're
listing genetics it should go female X
male that's how you list your crosses
then you put the name right up above
that so ladies first all the time when
you're listing genetics I see a lot of
people cross that one up on the internet
and why does it matter because it's a
different cross golden goat to day
breaker and day breaker to golden goat
are two different crosses so that does
matter you should list it correctly all
right you guys I want to give a couple
of really quick shout out someone to
give a huge shout it's my friend Tyler a
shout out to Miles Porter and a huge
shout out to Maddie
E all right you guys before I start
wrapping up this show I've got one more
thing I'd like to talk about I get a lot
of messages from people asking how do I
get into this industry how do I get a
big gross started how do I move to
Colorado how do I get a facility how do
I get licensed how do I get plants how
do I set it up can you teach me to grow
can you help me do this the first step
to that you guys is to learn to grow
some cannabis don't buy a big facility
don't get a big-ass license get a light
get some seeds learn how to germinate a
10 pack of seeds learn how to run a crop
from seed to harvest learn how to
identify males learn how to grow the
product before you even think about a
big facility master a small facility I
see so many people that don't know how
to grow I think they're just gonna jump
into it and master this you guys I've
been at this for a long time and I still
experience crop problems I still get
spider mites occasionally I still see
powdery mildew the thing is I've
experienced it in small enough grows
tour I know how to deal with it and I've
learned how to adjust that to larger
grows when you walk into your
multi-million dollar facility with 250
lights and you see spider mites in there
you're going to [ __ ] your pants because
you've never dealt with it
if you've dealt with it on a small scale
if you've had one pound of cannabis at
risk if that was gonna be your loss from
those spider mites that's okay that's
your one pound of extra money that you
were gonna make you may not get to have
as much fun this summer that's cool
when you walk into that facility and you
see 500 pounds at risk from spider mites
you're gonna get anxious you're gonna
sweat in places you didn't know you had
sweat glands it's gonna make you sick to
your [ __ ] stomach you're not gonna be
ready for it
you're gonna panic you're gonna do more
[ __ ] wrong to cause more problems before
you think about building a warehouse
before you think about a 10 lighter
before you think about six or four
lights hang up a light learn how to grow
build a relationship with the plant
understand the cycles of the plant
understand what that plant needs
understand your goal with the plant
understand why you're doing it before
you go build yourself a giant facility
and invest all of your money and risk
losing everything figure out if you can
do this and also don't become one of
those owners that's just money hungry if
you stop and you build yourself a small
grow and you grow a few plants you'll
build a relationship with the plant not
just a financial relationship you'll
actually have a connection it feels
really good to grow cannabis you fall in
love with your garden you fall in love
with your plants and they make you feel
good before you even smoke them you get
to feel rewarded because you watch them
grow so you won't be one of these money
hungry owners you'll actually understand
what's going on you'll understand that
when I tell you this is going to be 14
weeks until I harvest this I've got veg
I've got flour then we cut it down a lot
of owners will say 14 weeks huh I'll be
back in 12 weeks we'll cut it down and
you say dude I said 14 and they go yeah
11 weeks sounds great
and you're like wait a minute I thought
I I thought you said 12 last time in the
accountant goes yeah 10 weeks will be
perfect like that's how that [ __ ] works
so don't be that guy
build a relationship with the plant
understand the cycles understand why the
growers are being so meticulous with
what they're doing understand why the
growers need your patience I really
think that starting small with one two
maybe three lights at the most is the
way to go I would recommend you start
off with a thousand watt light for
flowering and a thousand watt light for
vegging and be able to run a perpetual
cycle never have an interruption every
time you cut down a crop move more veg
plants in every time you cut down a crop
move more veg plants in you should
always have a cycle going before you can
mask
that don't even think about running a
large facility so you guys my point here
it starts small and then go big because
I see a lot of people try to start these
big facilities they run into problems
they were never prepared for they've got
zero experience and it turns into
absolute catastrophic failure and it's
expensive and it's embarrassing so you
guys start off small learn small fail
small learn how to correct your failures
on a smaller level and then once you get
good at that [ __ ] then expand and then
you're gonna [ __ ] up that too and learn
how to rescue a bigger crop and if your
main goal is to grow for a commercial
production facility or run your own
commercial production facility start
learning commercial horticulture
practices now don't become a home grower
don't become a basement grower don't
become a garage grow or become a
commercial cultivator yes you may be
doing it at home but you can still have
the mindset start thinking what products
am I allowed and not allowed to use what
is sustainable what is non sustainable
start thinking about man-hours start
thinking about electricity run your
personal grow as if it were a business
if your plan is do have a business with
your grow all right you guys I feel like
I ranted on that way longer than I had
intended so thanks for listening to that
let's start wrapping up this podcast
make sure you support my friends at the
hella Bank seed company if you need new
regular or feminized seeds for your
garden I highly recommend the holiday
exceed company you can find them at dank
seed dot store make sure you check out
their fresh drop of eye region etic
seeds they've just got a fresh drop of
space force that is space [ __ ] to arise
it's got a bunch of funky rotten mango
fermented fruits melon phenotypes
it's a sativa dominant hybrid it grows
like a beast I think you guys will enjoy
that one it's also got some really cool
custom packaging so make sure you check
out that design you can find that at
dank seed dot store ladies and gentlemen
I would appreciate it if you find me on
all of the social media you can find me
on Facebook simply search for the girl
from your heart podcast on Twitter it's
at G fyh podcast you can find me on
Instagram it's IRA underscore genetics
come hang out with me on Instagram I
like to do Instagram live videos I take
dad's answer grow questions that hang
out with my friends you never know what
could happen I'm
Instagram why feat it has been a lot of
fun lately if you've got something you'd
like to say if you'd like to sponsor the
podcast if you've got a product you'd
like me to review if you'd like to reach
out and you're not into the social media
you can email me my email address is
grow from your heart at hotmail.com
don't forget you can find the podcast on
itunes on stitcher and every episode is
archived on youtube simply search for
the girl from our podcast on youtube you
can find all of the old episodes don't
forget about the patreon campaign once
again that's patreon.com/lenguin dolis
for that great email ladies and
gentlemen I'll be back Monday with an
episode all about 7-10 so get your dab
rag ready when you listen to that one we
will be talking about 7 10 hopefully you
could take some dabs with me on that
episode ladies and gentlemen thanks for
hanging out thanks for listening to me
ramble for almost 30 minutes I'll be
back in a couple of days to do it again
I want to give a huge shout out to my
friend Mel and her crew in Vegas and
until next time take a phat dab and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]