yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for another episode of the
Grove from your heart podcast your
source for cannabis news education and
conversation I try to hear a new grower
if you're a professional grower if
you're a new smoker or a dedicated
dabber if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who is just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host my friends call me Rasta Jeff I
want to thank you guys again for joining
me this episode of the podcast is
brought to you by my friends at the hell
a dank seed company if you need new
genetics for your gardening I highly
recommend the hella dank seed company
you can find them at dank seed dot store
ladies and gentlemen roll up a fat joint
pack up the bong or start heating up
that dab rig because it's time for
another episode of the grill from your
heart podcast welcome to the show a
podcast world it's time for episode 332
of the girl from your heart podcast this
is the 710 episode happy 710 I hope
everybody's taking fat dads hope
everybody's smoking on some good oil I
hope you got some quality product hope
you got some diamonds hope you got some
turps hope you were getting Irie with us
on this 710 holiday you guys know I like
to start the podcast off by letting you
know what I'm smoking I just took a
gigantic dab of some contraband extracts
Durbin Kush sauce I had one giant
crystal left over I was saving it just
for this occasion it's got me super high
I'm a little bit shaky I'm completely
sweaty my eyes are jumping around this
is going to be a great podcast I will do
my best not to cough but this is the
7/10 episode so I make no promises
ladies and gentlemen this podcast is
brought to you by my friends at the hell
a dank seed company if you need new
regular or feminized seeds I highly
recommend the hell a dank seed company
and you can find them at dank seed dot
store alright you guys this is the 710
episode we all know 710 is all about
Gavin but why is 710 all about Davin
let's get right into this episode and
talk about 710 why does 710 represent
dabbing well if you turn the number 710
upside down it says oil and what better
time to smoke some oil than 710 now you
might say who came up with that
I know who came up with that it was our
friend task rock from highly educated
big shout out to task for being a part
of the oil movement since the beginning
task and a few other folks were on a
conference call they were talking about
the new movement what the future was and
tasks coined the phrase 7:10 on that
call so bigshot it's a task and his crew
for coining the phrase 7:10 and starting
this oil movement alright so now we know
where 7:10 came from and what 7:10 means
let's talk a little bit about dabs and
dabbing and actually participating in
some 710 activities and I didn't write
this part down because I didn't think
about it but it just dawned on me some
people may not be real familiar with
dabbing some people mean maybe like
what's he talking about dad's and
dabbing so let's start from the very
beginning a dab is when you take a small
portion of a cannabis concentrate
usually some oil or some shatter or we
moved on to different types of
concentrates we're gonna talk about
those later in the episode but you take
a small very small portion of a
concentrate just to dab just a little
tiny piece like a crumb like a big piece
of kosher salt like a small seed just a
tiny piece just a dab and you put that
little dab on a dabber and then you heat
another piece either a banger or a nail
or a bucket we'll talk about that in the
future also you heat up your piece of in
you push that dab onto the hot piece
which is attached to your rig and then
you smoke through the rig and you inhale
that cannabis concentrate you just need
a little tiny bit so that's what a dab
is you smoke it just like you would
smoke anything else except you eat the
piece and then push the concentrate into
it instead of putting the concentrate
into it and then applying the heat you
just do it backwards so what I'm talking
about dabbing or taking a dab that's all
I'm talking about just getting a small
piece of cannabis concentrate and
putting it into a nail and smoking it
through a rig inhale exhale that's
dabbing it's nothing crazy you're not
doing anything fancy you're just smoking
inhale exhale that's all it is so that's
taken a dab now the next obvious
question is what happens to me when I
take that dab taking a dab depending on
the size of the dab and the heat of the
nail sometimes the nail is too hot you
coffer a little bit from that sometimes
it'll cause you to cough sometimes
people just cough from smoking a dab
expect to cough on your first dab don't
be afraid to coffee
to turn red you may make a little snot
you're just gonna cough harder than
you've ever coughed before that's okay
we're gonna laugh at you the first time
we've all done it any experienced
stabber knows that you're gonna cough
that's gonna be okay expect that on your
first stab now here's the part that you
got to be prepared for depending on your
tolerance how often you smoke how
familiar you are with being high how
much you've eaten today your blood sugar
your surroundings how big your dab is
how long you hold it how hard you hit it
you may get pretty high off of a DAB if
you take them a medium sized ad for your
first dab you're gonna go skyrocketing
high these concentrates are in the low
70s to high 80s percent I've seen them
some of the concentrates I buy are in
the high 90s of THC a concentrations
when you're smoking flowers those are in
the high 20s so these are four and five
times stronger so that one hit that you
take off of a joint that doesn't get you
high this is like taking five hits off
of a joint at one time it's almost kind
of like smoking a whole joint at one
time is what it feels like sometimes now
you might say cool I want to smoke a
whole joint in one hit you might but
it's gonna come on so quickly that you
get so high so fast that sometimes it's
uncomfortable sometimes it makes people
paranoid sometimes people freak out a
little bit you haven't been this high
that quickly until you smoked a DAB it
takes a lot to get you there a big fat
bong hit won't do it a little medium dab
that'll put you in a new place so the
first time you take a dab be prepared to
get super high now the benefit to
dabbing is if you're smoking for
medicinal purposes it affects you
immediately by the time you're blowing
that dab out some of your medical
ailments will be eased you won't feel
them your pain will be gone your
suffering will be limited you will feel
better
almost immediately that's why
concentrates are important that's why
it's so popular so the first time you
take a dab be prepared be sitting down
be with friend and if you've never
smoked flour if you've never smoked
cannabis or marijuana whatever you want
to call it I highly recommend starting
off by smoking some weed start off like
most of us did it's kind of intense just
to go straight to dabbing I would assume
I smoked weed for a long time before I
smoked to dab so that that is a good
segue let's talk about the first
I smoked dabs I smoked plenty of crappy
Mel hash and weird hash and all kinds of
[ __ ] hash up until this point and
then one day a friend of mine we did a
little uh I got some some flowers from
him and he gave me this little parchment
paper folded in half and he was hey bro
when you get home put that on top of a
bowl and just give that a little hit and
I was like oh man I've heard of this
this is that BHO butter stuff people
were talking about so I get home and I
take a shower and I get ready to go out
for the night and I'm like I'm gonna go
out to the weekend I'm gonna go do some
[ __ ] and I've got plans with some
friends and I'm like oh I wanna get
stoned before I go out for the night
and I remember he gave me that little
parchment with that stuff in it I've got
a brand new pipe over there on the
drawer so I get it get that pipe out of
the drawer and I put a little bit of bud
in there just enough to make sure that
[ __ ] doesn't fall through the hole and I
put that little bit of wax in there was
just it was more like shattered but it
was kind of it was like melted shatter
since I'd had it for so long it kind of
got funky so I just put that it was
shatter I put it on top of the bowl and
then I just melted it in with my lighter
and I took one fat hit of it and I blew
it out and by the time I was done
blowing that smoke out I was wandering
to the bed with my eyes crossed and half
closed and I just laid facedown in the
bed
I wasn't like in a comfortable position
I just got to where I was in the bed
face down and I closed my eyes and I
went to sleep for about an hour and
twenty minutes and I woke up and I was
like oh my god I was still high I had to
get my [ __ ] together
and then go out and I went places people
were like dude how high are you and I
was a cry smoke this [ __ ] it [ __ ] me
up so that wasn't even a dab that was
just smoking a little bit of concentrate
off of a bowl my first real dab was from
a guy known as Big D mr. Daniel Desai
from top-shelf extracts he had a booth
at the first cannabis cup in Denver
before it was recreational we had a
medical cannabis Cup at the Expo event
center and Big D had a booth with
Broadway Wellness and he had a decent
line and he was offering dabs and I got
in line in the my date got in line in
front of me I let her take a dad and
when she took her first dad I had to
catch her she almost fell over she got
wobbly and shaky I had to put my arms
around her and hold her up I was like
you alright she goes that [ __ ] hits
and I was like I can't [ __ ] wait and
I get up next in line in this big dude
with the shaved head he goes are you a
heavy smoker or you knew and I go Bryce
smoke he goes ok and he gave me a decent
sized dab off of a swingarm skillet on a
dub tube we'll talk more about that in
the future that dab [ __ ] me up so bad
I don't think I smoked for the rest of
the day I was so high and I coughed for
10 minutes but it was a great thing I
went back later that day and bought that
dub tube and one of those skillets so
that I could smoke those dad's all the
time after that so then I came home from
that cannabis cup and I called up all
the friends the next day I had Kevin
over I had pops over pops I miss you
brother pops past a few months ago and I
miss you pops
but I had Kevin over I had pops over
Mike was over pretty sure Tony was over
and I don't remember who else was there
but we all gathered at my house and I
showed everybody this new device this
new apparatus and like that's [ __ ]
crazy and it was a swing arm skillet so
it looked like you took a bowl that went
on your bong like just a bowl that would
fit into the bong but then you took a
longer stem and bent it so that it was
upside down so that it looks like you'd
pack an upside-down bowl is what it
looked like but then they affixed a
piece of aluminum wire around it that
had a titanium disc at the end of it
like a coin a coin of titanium and it
would swing to where that titanium coin
would lined up line up underneath the
bottom of that the bell of the bowl
basically you would heat up that
titanium pad that coin swinging
underneath there then drop your dab on
that titanium pad and that that nail
that skillet would actually fit on to
your bong or your rig with a joint like
your normal bong Bowl would so then that
would be attached to your pipe or your
bong or your bubble or whatever so they
need to put the dab on you'd heat up the
titanium swing the piece under then it
would be underneath the wide mouth of
that bowl then you would put the dab on
there and need smoke and since it was
like that bell shape it would suck the
dab smoke right up into there through
your pipe and then into your lungs so I
called the crew over we all gathered in
the basement we all sat around and we
all looked at it like wow that's crazy
and I heated it up and back then you
guys we were heating the [ __ ] out of it
we thought we had to eat these things so
they were
and glowing that's not necessary we're
gonna talk about dab heat in a minute
also I would heat it up and then we all
took one or two dabs we all caught for
like five or ten minutes I think we hung
out for like thirty minutes total after
that and then we all said our goodbyes
everybody's like well bruh I'm gonna go
home I got to go do the rest of my day
I didn't hear [ __ ] from anybody in that
group until about six hours later we all
started texting each other like hey bruh
I just woke up from a killer nap what
the [ __ ] are you doing like I just woke
up that [ __ ] was amazing I just woke up
starving to death man I thought it was
hilarious everybody that was here had to
go home and take a little nap I didn't
hear from him for at least four to six
hours each person so that was our first
dab experience that was how I acquired
my first dab so I took my first dad dabs
were available in the dispensaries by
this point I was able to get them from
my friend who had introduced it to me
also I worked in a local dispensary so
people were coming in and offering us
product all the time I was picking up
concentrates from them plus I was
driving to Denver and finding
concentrates all over the place at
dispensaries plus everybody around here
was learning how to make their own
concentrates so that's a good way to
segue into the evolution of the actual
dabs today I would be embarrassed to
show you the dabs that we thought were
the best hottest fire [ __ ]
four or five years ago then I guess the
word would be mortified I would be
mortified to share with you dabs that we
thought were good dabs six or seven
years ago concentrates have come a long
way of course there was always decent
like water hash and bubble hash but I'm
talking about BHO waxes shatters things
like that so when it first started
people were making crap
we called it poop soup it was black it
smelled like hell it wasn't properly
purged it's still you could tell it
still had residual butane in it you
could tell something was wrong so when
you're making BHO you should use I
prefer a glass tube some people will use
stainless steel I've seen people use
aircraft aluminum tubes but you need
metal or glass and I've seen people use
PVC tubes now you're running a solvent
through this tube
I would imagine something from the PVC
will end
up in your concentrate I've seen people
use the shittiest weed I can only
imagine what some of these people were
spraying on their weed before they were
turning it into BHO what I'm saying is
back in the day you guys the stuff that
we used to get was black and terrible
and funky and over time it got a little
more clear and a little more clear and
people were learning how to make clear
clear shatter shatter that was so let me
explain shatter because this was kind of
how it first started with shatter and
wax and butter so first it was first it
was this black solid not solid but like
black layer of stuff that looks like
kind of like like black Jolly Ranchers
like if you had a dark Jolly Rancher a
really dark purple Jolly Rancher on some
parchment paper that's what it looked
like then it started getting more
transparent and turning into an amber
honey color it looks like you had
hardened honey or yellow Jolly Ranchers
on the parchment paper that's kind of
what shatter looked like it would be
thin sheets and it would be like amber
colored glass and now would start that's
started getting better that tasted
better it had a better hi to it it
didn't make your lungs hurt so bad and
then we started learning to smoke it at
a little cooler tip and we're gonna talk
about that in a minute - that also
affected the long burn on the chest burn
and I apologize for in the throat a lot
I've been taking a lot of dads but it
got more clear and it got more shatter
II then we started learning how to make
waxes and batters out of that so wax was
you would take a shatter that was almost
done and then you would just whip it
you'd put a dremel tool to it or just
whipping it with the whisk real hard to
put air in it and it would fluff it up
and make it into wax we learned how to
purge things we learned that running the
butane through it
put butane in it you had to get all of
that butane out we started putting our
product in the vacuum oven to get that
butane out we learned a lot of things so
it went from black goop to shatter which
was basically amber colored glass or
Jolly Ranchers and then we learned how
to make waxes out of that then we had
butters or batters which were kind of
waxes that wouldn't solidify certain
strains have certain Terps in it and
certain things that just they all react
differently so sometimes you'll try to
make you'll try to make a shatter and
you'll end up with what's called snap
and peel which is kind of more like a
Laffy Taffy consistent
see which is acceptable it's justwhat
that strain is gonna do so we learned
how to purge it we learned how to get
all of the butane out because there were
times when you would throw a DAB on a
hot nail and it would sizzle up at you
we would assume that that was leftover
solvents I have no evidence of that but
that's what we thought was happening
then we started purging with the vacuum
oven and things got a lot better and a
second ago I said Laffy Taffy but I
totally meant a fruit roll-up so excuse
me for the head it would snap like a
fruit roll-up you know a fruit roll-up
he could just peel off a little piece it
would snap and have that text that
texture I was more like a fruit roll-up
so forget I sent Laffy Taffy that just
dawned in my head so let me explain
waxes a little bit waxes and we're kind
of basically like smoking it was like
wax you could handle it a little better
you could pick it up
it wasn't shattering so shattered would
snap sometimes he tried to get some on
the dabber and it would snap and it
would break and go flying across the
room if he put too much pressure on it
wax was kind of easier to handle because
you could pick it up and you could drop
it right into the nail so that was a
difference and a lot of people used to
say that wax wasn't purged and I'm not
sure why people would say that because
the wax was just as purged if not more
purged because it's been through the
same process as the shatter then it was
whipped to make it into the wax
consistency and when it was whipped it
released even more residual hydrocarbons
so the waxes are purged I'm not sure why
people always said that that's what a
wax is it kind of looks like a small
piece of a fluffy crayon not as maybe
not as dense of a wax as a crayon but
similar it's a just little pieces of
broken crayon maybe and you just need a
little bit of that stuff that would get
you super high back in the day I like
taking big old chunks and pressing a
giant chunk of wax onto the nail and try
to smoke as hard as I can and see when I
had to stop that was always fun so we
started with that black goo we got that
nice and clear we learned how to get all
the residual solvents out of it we
started learning how to preserve turfs
we started learning how to make nice and
clear high-quality shatter shatter was
the feint for a long time
shattered in wax and sometimes butter if
you could find some good butter that'd
be alright a lot of people were opposed
to it they didn't like the consistency
so shatter and waxes were the hot thing
for a long time then some of our friends
here in Colorado got the bright idea to
cut down some plants
and freeze them and run them fresh
frozen through an obidos machine which
is a closed loop system concentrate
making machine if you want if you're
interested in a high quality closed loop
machine look for an obidos from emo tech
shout out to my friends at emo tech hit
up hit up giddy up
it'll take good care of you but kind
bill and a few other folks kind bill and
giddy decided to put fresh frozen plants
through an obidos machine so when you're
making ice wax or water hash it's a good
idea to freeze the buds the frozen buds
work better when you're making water
hash they thought instead of drying the
plants let's cut them down and freeze
them and put them through the BHO
machine the obidos the butane extraction
device so they went that method and what
came out they named it live resin
because that fresh freezing process they
cut down the plants took off the large
leaves and then froze them then ran them
through the machine that fresh freezing
process preserved all of the fresh plant
terpenes that essence of the freshly
harvested plant it brought that out in
the concentrate and it made this bright
gold mushy fluffy texture eeee delicious
I don't know it was for a long time
everybody was crazy about live resin it
was all people would talk about for the
longest time so live resin was made from
fresh frozen plants through an obidos
machine ah giddyup and kind bill were
some of the first folks making live
resin because it was done in kiddies
machine then our friends in the garden
of Weeden of course ran a bunch of live
resin and want some cannabis cups with
that so the live resin became the thing
everybody wanted that live resin live
resin was the way to go that really
revolutionized the machines it
revolutionized extracting and it put
some science into it and I think that
inspired people because out of the live
resin people learned how to separate the
terpenes and the cannabinoids for a
little while now we've been able to buy
jars of strained specific terpenoids
terpenes so I've got a little vial in my
hand this is a one DRAM vial it
contained one gram
excuse me for clearing the throat again
I apologize I usually edit those out but
we're gonna keep going it contained one
gram of lemon Jeffrey Hyder peeing in a
full spectrum extract it was about 99%
terpenes and less than 1% cannabinoids
in this little jar a long time ago when
we were making shatter and live resin I
would see these little shimmery pockets
you'd have a sheet so if you ran a
quarter pound of flowers you would end
up with about an ounce of concentrates
and that's a parchment paper about the
size of a notebook piece of paper with a
puddle right in the middle of it that
would be your ounce of concentrate
somewhere in that puddle I would see a
little extra shimmery spot it looked
like you just dropped just a little bit
of water in there and I would I would
pay attention
I would dab off the edge of the the edge
of the concentrate this edge over here
of the whole slab we called those a big
slab and you've got an ounce that's a
slough I guess an ounce or more would
work as a slab maybe seven grams or more
that's a slab of concentrates if you saw
it on the parchment paper saw it laying
out I'd say oh that's a slab so I would
go from this edge of the slab and then
in this edge of the slab and I would
compare the flavors based on the texture
some would be one edge of the slab may
be harder than the other maybe because
you've got this big 28 gram piece of
concentrate that was made it was liquid
and it solidified again so now it's
non-homogeneous I feel that some parts
of that are gonna contain different
things I think those little wetter
puddles in the middle that I was
spotting were the Terps we were already
kind of separating the terpenes from the
cannabinoids because I would reach into
the middle where those little water
pockets weren't dabbed at and it would
taste so good I'm sure that's where the
tert pockets were hidden so now we went
from the goop to the waxes and shatters
to live resin now we learned how to pull
out terpenes I was buying Terps and
taking chunks of live resin and chunks
of shatter and dumping
dunking it right into the terpenes and
then taking a fat dab of that that would
be tremendous that used to make I feel
like the terpenes wouldn't enhance the
high by a good percentage the terpenes
are not cheap when you're buying
cannabis derived terpenes so it
definitely was an experience at that
time they were way more expensive than
than they are now there are about a
third of the price now from when they
first came out
but that's because a lot more people
have learned the tech and they're more
available and that's what happens with
legalization so along with the Terps
came the high cannabinoid full spectrum
extract oh if you listen to the podcast
often you've heard us have a few vague
conversations about making full-spectrum
extracts it happens when there is a
solution under pressure there is butane
let's just kind of skip the process but
anyway there's a jar and the part that
floats to the top is mainly the Terps
the crystals that form in the bottom are
the high cannabinoid full-spectrum
extract if you leave those crystals in
the bottom for a long time undisturbed
with no vibration you don't open it up
you don't cause it any drama
it's gonna form a large diamond if
you're doing it correctly so now we're
getting small chunks that we call HC FSC
also known as little crystals and we're
getting HT FSE so you can get the hi
Tareen full-spectrum extract in the top
liquid part that's all Terps so you can
buy one strand of HC FSC crystals and
then you can buy a couple of different
varieties of HT FSC and you can pour up
and make different varieties and
different flavors just like when you
used to mix the Jelly Bellies back in
the day so you can buy one gram of one
two grams of the other and you can have
different flavors you can mix and match
you can pour them together or you can
just smoke the crystals by themselves
it's always fun I like to take the
crystals and mix them in with some
batter and some turps
that's always a good hi the batter gives
you a good long punch the Terps give it
a good flavor and a good head rush and
then that HC FS e crystal makes you go
super high so so you've got your HC FS e
small crystals then you've got your h TF
SC which is the liquid to the high
terpene full-spectrum extract you buy a
jar of like a gram of we'll say just a
gram of Gorilla Glue eye cannabinoid
full-spectrum extract crystals and you
get another gram of Jack flash I can
have annoyed full-spectrum extract
crystals then you go get yourself a
couple of jars of Terps maybe some lemon
Jeffrey and then a cheese and then you
can pour a few drops of this one over
here and then you can take a dab of the
gorilla glue hi cannabinoid full
spectrum extract crystals with some
lemon Jeffrey Terps on top of it you can
experience that high
then you can get your cheese I don't
even remember the strains I said you
guys but you can mix and match that way
you've got a little mix and match and
it's really fun and then you definitely
do notice different highs from different
combinations so we got to making our own
full spectrum extracts then came the
diamonds we learned that if you leave
those crystals under pressure in
solution long enough they create
gigantic diamonds and a lot of people
like dabbing just big old diamonds
I think the diamonds get me ridiculously
high
I think the diamonds need a little bit
of turps added to them you got to add a
couple of drops of Terps to the diamonds
or it's a little too intense I think
that the THC a crystals the diamonds
make you go SuperDuper high you
skyrocket high like a firework I think
the terpenes that you add to that are
the color your firework makes that may
be a weird way to describe it but the
Terps are what decide if you're gonna
get paranoid if you're gonna get the
munchies if you're gonna get laid-back
if you're gonna get talkative the Terps
decide what's going to happen and the
THC
besides how high you're gonna go with
that is what I feel when there's no
Terps to it you just go real high and
you kind of get a headache and then you
sober up real quickly is what I feel
like so it needs some turps to control
the drive or the rocket just goes flying
off the rails and then it crashes and
it's done so that's the crystals the
diamonds by themselves when you take the
high cannabinoid full spectrum extract
diamonds that are kind of chunky and you
pour the Terps over them and you see
those diamonds floating in the liquid
turps and Sutan sure if you guys pay
attention to social media you see people
with little jars and they've got this
golden liquid stuff in there and they've
got these little chunks just floating
around and they're these little crystals
that is what's being called sauce those
are diamonds those are HT FSC crystals
floating around in Terp sauce you guys
it's cannabinoids and turbo way to smoke
right now I like a pretty good sized
crystal was just a little bit of the
Terp sauce on it I like the high from
the crystal like I was saying earlier
and then I like the Terp sauce just to
guide that high give it a direction and
also add some turbo flavor to it so that
seems to be the trend right now is the
sauce the crystals the turn
and the Diamonds seems to be the way to
go also we've got to talk about our
solvent list friends I am not much on
the solvent list smoke if you pass me a
solvent list AB hell yes I will take it
do I buy solvent list concentrates very
very rarely it's got to be very
impressive to get me to buy a solvent
let's concentrate
I would rather buy some sauce because
they're about the same price sometimes
this solvent list mmm excuse me with the
throat once again at 7/10 not gonna edit
it keep going
take a dab with me every time every time
I clear my throat in this episode you
take a DAB that'll be fun
here we go but solving this is sometimes
more expensive than sauce as what I
think I was saying let's talk more about
savile a solvent less includes stuff
like eye swags if you see the kids that
show up to the dispensary with a cooler
and they leave with a little cooler
they're probably buying ice wax they
keep it cool until the moment made a bit
those plants are harvested in a cool
environment they're stored in a cool
environment possibly frozen I'm not sure
they are processed in a cold environment
they are made with ice water then
they're graded up in a cold environment
the entire process they are kept in a
very cool environment until the minute
they are dad a lot of people are opposed
to smoking solvents our friend jinx
proof won't smoke butane hash or solvent
made hash because he's epileptic and
he's afraid to smoke something made with
butane which is respectable so a lot of
people go for the solvent list they like
the ice wax or the water hatch also
there is rosin rosin has made a couple
of different ways rosin can be made and
I'm just gonna give you the idn't I
don't make rosin and if you listen to me
a lot you know I don't enjoy smoking
rosin but I'm not biased I'm gonna try
to give you guys a fair report on rosin
you make rosin basically by putting a
nugget into a little mesh pouch a very
specific micron mesh pouch I'm not sure
of the specific micron because like I
said this is not my wheelhouse but this
is my understanding you put a nugget or
some nuggets in a mesh pouch a very
specific micron mesh pouch you then I
think wrap that you fold that in
parchment paper then you squish the [ __ ]
out of that with the press I've also
seen people use a hair straightener to
do it they use a hot hair straightener
and a clamp to tighten it down real
tight you want heat and pressure so then
you're gonna squish that bud with heat
and pressure and wear that parchment
paper where it's folded in half where
it's not folded the other side the open
side you're gonna get some juice
dripping out of there
that is your rosin that golden resin
juice that comes out of there that's
rosin when you unfold that parchment
paper you're gonna have right around
your little square of a micron mesh bag
you're gonna have all this goo that came
out scrape that up
that is your rosin that you want to dab
that is solvent list and you can smoke
that immediately and it's kind of safe
to make if you can enjoy the flavor and
you can get it the way you want it the
temperature the pressure just with a few
simple tools you can make
dable rosin at home from flowers know
what a lot of people do it will take
some hash some water hash some bubble
hash maybe it was some ice wax at one
point and they will press that into
rosin and that makes really good rosin
the rosin that comes out of that once
it's already been cleaned and you're not
pressing all that plant matter and
you're pressing water hash into rosin
that makes delicious rosin that's the
best rosin I think you can make any
press hash into rosin so chatot or
solvent list friends I hope I did you
guys justice honestly I don't smoke a
lot of solvent list if you want to come
on the show and talk about solvent list
and teach us about it you were more than
welcome send me an email let's grow from
your heart at hotmail.com
or if you're one of my friends text me
or hit me up on the Instagram and we can
talk about that another type of
concentrate I should mention but I am
honestly not a big fan of his propane
honey oil most of the concentrates I
talked about before we're made with
butane and other techniques there is
you'll see Pho on the shelves when you
shop at the dispensary that is propane
honey oil yes we are making concentrates
with different gases different gases or
different temperatures they will bring
out different cannabinoids I've noticed
that the phot really brings out good
flavors but it makes my lungs feel
really heavy when I smoke it it makes
everything come out kind of waxy it's
kind of got that ah Cheesecake batter
sort of a texture to it and it doesn't
taste too bad but it really makes my
lungs heavy and it doesn't have the
proper high I don't enjoy the high to
Pho so that's another thing that I
should mention is available so you guys
we went from smoking doodoo
just seven or eight years ago we were
smoking crap justjust the monkeyest
crappiest stuff there would be different
colors it'd be brown it would be black
it would sizzle on the nail it would
give you a headache sometimes it would
make your throat burn and now the
concentrate that I've got in my hand is
super super clear I can see my finger
through the bottom of the jar and there
are just little little diamonds sitting
in here it's not the same color but I
want to compare this to the beauty of a
little hot cocoa with little
marshmallows on the top you know those
little little tiny marshmallows that's
what these little diamonds look like in
here and then they're just cascaded
throughout this little little Terp sauce
and it smells wonderful
it smells like orange candies and jet
fuel it's so delicious this is the Reba
jam from Green Dot labs so guys we went
from smoke and crap to smoking the best
stuff on the planet
in just a few years and that's because
of legalization so that is the evolution
of the dabs now let's talk about some of
the dab equipment let's talk about nails
at first I talked about the skillet
that's that upside down bong bull with
the piece that swings underneath it and
then you heat that piece you swing it
under there and you set your dab on
there hope it doesn't run off of there
onto your leg while it's still hot
because that's happened and it's [ __ ]
hot and it sucks so we started off with
the skillet then we learned to use a
nail now a nail you had to have a male
rig most so if you've got a bong it's
probably a female your bong Bowl fits
into the stem right now imagine if that
stem were the male part and the bowl fit
on the outside that would be called a
direct inject Bowl is what that is if
you had a direct inject Bowl that's a
male you just set the dab nail right in
there they made a dab nail it kind of
looks like a big nail it would be excuse
me it's a titanium hopefully titanium
you want a quality titanium nail you
don't want to smoke some Chinese stuff
because you're gonna heat it up it's
gonna off gas I'm not gonna rant about
that but a titanium eel I recommend
highly educated titanium so you get a
titanium nail it is kind of a it looks
like a nail it's got a head on it and
then it's got a long body right but it
would have another piece on it that
would screw up and down and make it
adjustable so you can adjust the height
that piece would sit and so you drop it
right into the male part of the rig and
you'd adjust that
to where it would fit into the rig and
stick out enough to where then you would
slide a dome over it so you would heat
the nail then you would slide a dome
just like he would put your bowl onto
the bomb he would slide a dome over that
nail and it would fit over there and the
purpose of that is then you would take
your dab and touch that hot nail with it
and the smoke would kind of stay it
would be trapped in that dome and then
he would smoke through the bong or the
bubble or whatever you're using and he
would hit it that way so we went from
the skillet to the nail and dome method
the nail was a little archaic but it
worked very well I would see a lot of
people try to carve the nail and burn
the [ __ ] out of themselves it took a
little while for people to catch on to
the nail tech it took a long time to
teach people not to heat the [ __ ] out of
their nail I still take a pretty hot dab
back in the day everybody was going even
hotter than me we had to teach people to
mellow down on that some people still
don't want to hear it including myself I
guess so you had the nail with the dome
on it you're probably familiar with that
then task rock started making different
types of nails and he made the flux nail
the flux was my favorite I check out the
flux nail by highly-educated when I used
a domed nail the flux was my go-to but
then TAS came out with the domeless nail
so the domeless nail kind of looks like
a rook from a chess set you guys it
looked like the rook on a chess set I
got to write something down here excited
in write down carb cap the carb cap
changed a lot of stuff when I came to
dabbing I didn't write that down so the
the domeless nail kind of looked like
you took a rook and set it right on your
pipe right on your rig it was shaped
like it tapered it was wider at the
bottom and it tapered up and then it had
this wide head on it with like a dish
with a piece up at that in the center of
the dish it looked like it kind of had
an axle that was hollow so it had a dish
you could drop your dab in but the
sinner
had a a wall around it so that your dad
wouldn't fall right down the hole but
you could smoke and the smoke would go
up and then down that hole through the
rig and you could hit it I think I
described that accurately imagine you
took a rope from a chess set drill the
hole right through the top of it and set
that [ __ ] right on top of your
nail that's kind of what it looked like
but if you dropped your nail right on
there it would fall through the hole in
the middle right so they just put a
little ring around that so we didn't
fall through now you got yourself a dish
with a hole you'd smoke on there now
that was cool but you had to heat that
thing real hot to hit it and he would
put your dab on there and part of the
smoke would get away and they need
chokha locks it was so hot so task
invented a thing called a carb cap a
carb cap was another piece of titanium
that fit perfectly on top of your
domeless nail now that carb cap would
trap the heat inside of your nail and it
would minimize the amount of outside air
that was allowed to pass the surface of
that nail which would stoke the heat of
the nail and make your dab burn better
at a lower temperature so now you were
getting a better flavor dad because he
weren't burning off the Terps it wasn't
burning your lungs it wasn't burning
your throat and he didn't have to use so
much heat to get all of your smoke he
would drop a big old dab on there and
he'd cap it and that heat would remain
inside the nail as it was covered and
then you could just keep pulling on it
until you get all of it otherwise he had
to heat it real hot and just try to get
as much smoke as you could to try to
take a big dab and part of the carb cap
evolved from people were taking a
domeless nail and placing their thumb or
two fingers over the hole of the dome to
kind of minimize and restrict the amount
of airflow to get a lower temperature
dab it's kind of what inspired the carb
cap so we went from the domed nail to
the domeless nail to the dome domeless
nail with a carb cap then somewhere
along that point task rock invented the
email the email was a domeless nail with
a coil coming off of it it had a wire
that went to a box that would regulate
the temperature of that coil that would
heat that nail so you didn't have to use
a torch to heat your dad nail anymore
it was electric and it was always
running you'd plug that son of a [ __ ]
in you dial it to a temperature you'd
wait a couple of minutes for it to heat
up once it's hot it's gonna be hot until
you turn it off so you could take a DAB
I can pass it to Kevin Kevin would take
a DAB we'd pass it over to Dee Dee would
take
damn it pass it back to me and I take
another dab and he'd realize oh my
goodness this thing is gonna be a
problem and everybody got so stoned when
the email started first coming around so
shot it to our friend task rock for
making the first email he gets credit
for that you guys he gets the first
email there'd been a lot of companies
that I made a lot of emails after that
but task did it first so shout out to
task rock and the email um somewhere
along the line so the email got popular
then we started seeing things called the
banger and the club banger the quaff
banger qwave banger you can see quadric
wave I'm not sure how you say it I've
been corrected both ways so go with
whichever one you're comfortable with
but this dude wave made a thing called a
banger it was probably the most commonly
seen dabbing nail after the original
titanium nail it's the one you see the
most the one most copied the most
knocked off it fits on your rig and it
comes up and then it has an angle to
where it gets horizontal - they've got a
45 or a 90 degree angle probably on it
or that the dish part sits horizontally
then it's just basically got a glass
symbol on it and you heat it and you
drop your dab in there and then you
smoke it and you put a carb cap over it
and then let me write down bubble caps -
because we didn't talk about bubble caps
because when we get to these other
things we're gonna need a bubble cap so
basically the Banger looks like a piece
of glass at an angle that attaches to
your rig or your pipe with a thimble on
it and then you would heat that and when
it got to the right temperature you drop
your dab inside of there put a carb cap
on it and at this point in time a carb
cap was just a flat piece with a hole in
it so that you could restrict the air
then we started getting directional carb
caps it would have a little piece of
glass it would just point the air in a
certain direction and you would turn it
to move the oil around in your nail a
little better because people were taking
big dabs so that was the kind of the
start of the club bangers what they
called it the glass version of a nail
from the banger we started seeing
variations of that we saw the gavel from
highly-educated we saw the trough from
who made the trough we can't think of
who made the trough right now Joe Peters
then we saw the Joel Halen honey hole
which was very similar to the trough
we saw the Grail from Toro then we saw
the core reactor which was kind of these
are all just variations on the on the
original banger and they're just
slightly different but the core reactor
was bigger and it had a piece like a
hump of glass in the middle of it that
would hold a little bit of heat longer
so you could take larger dabs at lower
temperatures it was just like a banger
just like the quaff banger but it had a
larger chunk of glass in the very middle
of it that would hold the heat so that
was the core reactor then we started
seeing the thermal banger which I'm
gonna try to describe to you now I've
got one in front of me it's what I've
been hitting it is just like the normal
banger so you've got the joint that fits
onto my rig it just sets right on the
rig like a bong Bowl wood and it's got a
90 degree angle then it's got it looks
like a glass thimble honestly just a
piece of just a glass looks like a
little glass jar or a glass thimble or a
glass Pepsi lid from a Pepsi bottle it's
about that size and it is attached to
this glass a 90 degree angle then inside
of that is another glass dish that looks
like a smaller thimble so it's like a
thimble inside of a thimble and the idea
is that you heat the outer thimble and
the heat never touches that inside
thimble so it doesn't get dirty and
funky and you don't burn your dab is bad
so you heat the outside part
you drop your dab in there then you put
a bubble cap over it a bubble cap is
shaped it's a bubble with a piece of
tubing so imagine you took a straw and
heated it and you blew on it and it
expanded in the middle and you put a
bubble in it that's what a bubble cap
would look like then you cut it off
short on both ends so part of that the
bubble seals the cat the Banger so now
it's sealed off you drop the bubble cap
on there it's sealed
one end of it points down inside of the
Banger and one end of it points up and
you turn it and when you turn it that
moves your oil around inside there and
it gets nice and deep inside of the
banger so it moves that oil around
inside the bottom of the banger so your
oil moves and doesn't stay in one place
and it burns the whole dab and you get a
nice low temp dab that tastes really
nice so that is and you also use that
carb cap on the the core reactor banger
so that is going to the evolution of we
went from the titanium the skillet to
the nail to the flux to the domeless to
the email
then we started using bangers and yes
they do make so bangers are glass or
quartz off your pan like 20 or 30 bucks
they're glass if you're paying 180 150
they're probably quartz I hope you can
get a quartz email you can get a banger
with an email attachment yes that is a
thing I really appreciate that I enjoy
the way that works the way that tastes
and the way that dabs so we've talked
about the core reactor we talked about
the thermal banger we talked about the
gavel the trough the Grail those are
just different versions you guys from
different makers let's talk about the
bucket the bucket is what mothership
uses the bucket fits it looks like a
bong Bowl it looks just like you're
gonna pack a bong bowl but it's got this
little hinge on it and that hinge has a
piece that swings out and it's got a
little titanium dish on there you swing
it out you heat that titanium dish you
swing it back in and when it cools to
the proper temp then you drop your dab
on there and then you use what's called
the ofz is what the carb cap is that
fits on the mother ship bucket there's
also this new thing called the knot I'm
not sure what it's actually called it
looks like a pretzel knot it is
ridiculous it looks like the Hat you
draw you heat it then you drop in this
other thing and then you put your dab it
you heat another thing and drop that
inside of it and it looks like the hash
falls to the bottom and keeps recycling
up to the top I am not familiar with it
granny does not like it there's another
thing from Toro it kind of looks like a
bird feeder I'm pretty sure that's from
Toro I even ever tried that it doesn't
look just doesn't look like it makes
sense to me it looks like I would rather
dab off of a banger you guys will see
that one online the one you drop the dab
in the top and then it falls to the
bottom somehow and it looks it's shaped
like a [ __ ] Cole what Coleman lantern
it looks like a bird feeder or something
I'm not a fan of that thing I haven't
used it but still it just looks like
it's more cumbersome than it's worth
it looks like a pain in the ass and it
doesn't make sense to me also there are
insert dabs insert dabs kind of you have
a bigger banger and then you heat the
bigger banger and then you put your dab
inside up a smaller like a just a glass
dish and you actually set that inside of
the banger and then you put a carb cap
on there and then you give it a second
for the heat to work its way to your dad
and then you toke on it and that way you
can just pull out that little dish when
you're done the insert and you can clean
that dish off and you have a clean nice
turkey dab every time it always tastes
delicious and it always tastes fresh
because a lot of people don't want to
smoke off of a burnt out Chas banger if
your banger is all black and
funky-looking need some attention
that's called its Chas and he kind of
[ __ ] it up and a lot of passion absorb
angers and nail styles that I can think
of right now I'm sure I missed a couple
I'm sure something has come out since
I've made this episode I'm sure I'm not
on top of everything but that's a lot of
what you're gonna see also we've got
nectar collectors nectar collectors are
kind of like a rig but instead of
dropping the dab into the nail you heat
up the tip of the nectar collector and
you put your concentrate into a dish and
the nectar collector is made to be held
vertically so it's up and down and you
hold the dish in your hand and then you
kind of smoke it like an anteater you
look like an anteater it's like you're
using a giant straw just to suck up a
DAB you heat up the tip of it and you
press that hot tip up against the dad
and you get a huge dab out of that a lot
of people love a nectar collector it's
like basically a dad straw it runs
through water a dab straw is just a
piece of glass it's tapered at one end
you heat up that one in real hot you
press that up against your dabs and you
suck through the other end it's a way to
take a DAB but it's really hot it's
really uncomfortable for me a nectar
collector is a very upgraded way to do
that because it filters your dab through
water I always prefer my dab to go
through water to cool it down a little
bit for me so I guess that's a good way
to segue into rig selection I prefer a
small rig there's no reason to smoke
your dad's out of a big ass bong you're
not so let's think about the reason
you're smoking through a bomb you pack a
bowl you like that bull you've got a big
12 18 2 foot bong right you're 24 inch
bong you're smoking you fill that
big-ass chamber with all that thick
smoke you can see that cloud coming out
it's coming up at you you're looking at
it through the tube like all that smoke
is about to go into my head and then
once you get it all filled up with as
much as you think you can handle you
pull that carb and you suck all that
smoke in and you get that loud water
noise
you try not to splash it upon your face
and you get a big old bong hit you cough
then you put the bowl back in their knee
pass it to your friend you're like I'm
[ __ ] stoned bong kids feel great
that's a great thing I love a giant bong
hit but I don't wanna take a dab out of
a big ol bong head because as soon if I
heat the nail as soon as that dad
touches the nail I carb cap it and I'm
starting to get smoke already the smoke
is coming there's no need to start
filling a chamber I don't want to suck
12 inches 18 or 24 inches of glass of
air of oxygen to my lungs before I even
get my dab I'm not trying to smoke a
gallon of air I'm trying to smoke a gram
of concentrates so I don't need a big
bong I want a little tiny piece I like
what they call a sidecar the rig I'm
hitting right now is made by hitman
hitman doesn't sponsor the show a lot of
people hate on hitman I like the way
this rig functions I could it doesn't
matter to me who made this I like the
way this rig hits this rig is probably 5
inches tall it's about the size of round
it's the size of Round of my torch it's
almost the same diameter of my torch
it's like perfectly the size it fits
right in a cup holder you guys the base
of this fits right in a cup holder I
didn't say that but it fits right in the
cup holder okay it's a little smaller
than the diameter of a Pepsi can it's a
little thicker around in my torch if
it's really nice and a cup holder it's
about 4 inches tall then it's got a
little mouthpiece coming off oh it's
just a can shape they call that a can
and it's got a mouthpiece coming off of
it that's another 4 or 5 inches long and
that mouthpiece I like a nice flared out
mouthpiece so that my lips fit into it
and I don't have to make that that
[ __ ] mouth to try to take a dad also
I don't like a skinny mouthpiece cuz I
taking big dabs and I feel like when you
take a big DAB with the skinny
mouthpiece and you got a mustache like I
do a lot of concentrate just gathers
right there in your mustache and it's
kind of funky to have sticky lips you
guys have heard me do podcast with
sticky lips from small mouthpiece rigs
so then it's got a male joint sticking
straight up off the top the very center
the main portion of this rig is just
shaped like a circle or a can it's just
a can it's a small can so then I
describe the mouthpiece now right on the
top and the dead center of that can is
where the male joint sticks up and on
that joint I have got a it's a
14-inch joint and I've got a 14-inch
thermal banger on there and I'm using a
bubble cap tonight so that's basically
my dad setup and I'm using a little just
a glass pencil as a dabber from tater
glass shout out to tater I prefer a
small rig II guys nothing too big
something that's kind of like hands
sighs you don't want anything much
bigger than that
there's no need to smoke a gallon of
oxygen before your dad gets to you so a
little rig is best in my opinion a
little sidecar is best let's see what
else do I want to mention we're getting
close to an hour and I've still got a
few notes that I want to make sure let's
talk about the evolution of rigs when
rigs first came out most of them had
what was known as an 18 millimeter joint
that joint was 18 millimeters around
it's kind of a big joint the way that I
used to remember the size of that one if
I went to the store to go shopping and
they didn't know the difference in the
14 or the 18 that was the one that kind
of fits right over the tip of my pinky
finger that's the 18 millimeter joint
then we went a little smaller we went to
14 millimeter joints 14 millimeter is
about the size of Round of a Bic pen
without the cap so if you can just fit
your big pen in there that's probably a
14 millimeter a joint there you got a 14
millimeter male or female joint then
everybody wanted to go smaller everybody
thought that a little tiny teeny tiny
rig was best so people started going
with 10 millimeter
those are really tiny a pen won't fit in
there you got to clean that step-down
stem out with a q-tip if you want to
clean it so we evolved from 18 to 14 to
10 and then I think most of the people
went back to a 10 to a 14 is about where
we stayed the 10 got clogged up and you
can't take a giant dab off a 10 mil rig
in my opinion someone's gonna argue with
me but I don't like doing it I'd rather
have a 14 that's my preferred size 18
that's not bad you just get a lot of air
flow a little restriction on the air
flow is not bad
but I don't want that 10 mil so we went
from 18 to 14 to 10 I think that kind of
covers a lot of the evolution of rigs
you guys rigs can be anywhere from $30
to $30,000 I've seen a hundred and one
thousand dollar rig before so get one
suit to you don't be out there trying to
impress people with your rig get what
works this rig I'm hitting out of right
now was a hundred and fifty dollars to a
lot of people you're gonna say holy [ __ ]
that's expensive
a lot of people are out there gonna go
really bro that's all you're smoking out
of your Rasta Jack
150 man yeah it works perfectly this rig
has a perfect perk inside of it I like
the way it percolates I like the way it
fits on my face it's comfortable I like
holding it I like the way it goes in my
hand the way it fits to my hand to my
face when I'm dabbing I don't have to
reach awkwardly I like this rig it
doesn't splash in my mouth get a rig
that's comfortable for you don't buy
something to impress your friends don't
get something that splashes water up in
your mouth don't get something that you
got to get all cross-eyed trying to take
a hit out of get a rig that's
comfortable for you one more thing I
want to rant on and then we're gonna
wrap up this hour-long 710 episode of
this podcast you guys a lot of people
ask me what temp do you set your email
at I like to set my temp on my email at
what works for me I can't make a
recommendation for you because you've
got a different unit than me you've got
a different box that box is sending a
frequency up that cable to that coil to
the top of your nail there's no way that
that box knows what the temperature is
on the top of your nail so setting that
number on your box is just like setting
the number of volume on your car stereo
you find what it sounds really good I
know that in my car stereo about 2425
sounds pretty nice when I heard start
hitting 26 it gets kind of crackling 27
28 it sounds like [ __ ] it's not even
worth going there so I rock about 23 24
all the time find where your dab
temperature is comfortable with your dab
nail maybe you got to go to 500 maybe at
500 the dabs not melting properly maybe
you got to go to 600 maybe at 6 it's
still not going maybe you got to go to
700 maybe around 7 or 800 it starts to
burn right where you want it dial it in
it may take you a few dabs it may cost
you a couple of grams to get that email
dialed in but I can't recommend a number
for you I could say start at a certain
number and then dial up or down from
there but you kind of have to dial it in
to the way that you like it so that's my
rant on dialing in your email
temperature we don't all have the same
unit we don't all have the same box we
don't all have the same nail and we're
not all dabbing the same stuff so dial
it into the way that you like it maybe
you want that dab and use a carb cap
always use a car cap it's gonna help you
out
dial it in to where when you drop that
dab on there it starts to melt a little
bit and put the carb cap on there and
give a good draw through it if you're
not getting any smoke turn it up a
little bit if you're getting way too hot
way too thick too fast
down you'll figure it out it'll only
take a few dabs to get yourself in the
right ballpark and then you can dial it
in and get it perfect from there and
then just remember the number here's
here's a quick idea that I just thought
of maybe if you're dabbing and you've
got an email you've probably been
dabbing off a normal nail before heat
that nail up heat it up and then feel it
with your hand and when you go that's
where I want to be that's where I would
normally dab get your email and plug it
in and heat that [ __ ] up and play with
it put your hand up to it and when they
feel about the same you're kind of close
in the right ballpark right so get it to
the same temperature that you would heat
it with your torch
and it's a different nail keep in mind
it's a different nail it's a different
nail surface it could be a different
kind of metal it could be one could be a
bang or wonder what could be courts 1p
could be glass and now you could be
messing with a titanium
email keep in mind that you're gonna
have different surfaces to work with but
heat went up with the torch and then
plug in that email and dial it in and
see if you can get them close if you can
get that email to the familiar feeling
of how you would do with the torch
that's where you want it drop a DAB on
there hit it see if it works for you you
can always turn it up or down that's not
gonna be your last dab hopefully
hopefully you got plenty of more dabs
coming your way you got plenty of time
to dial it in so that's my rant on email
temperature you guys a lot of people ask
me what temp to set the email at and I
really don't know to tell you because I
don't have your email and now that's a
perfect segue into the next and final
part of this podcast hot dabs versus low
temp dabs a lot of people talk a lot of
[ __ ] to me because I like to take really
really hot dabs that's just my thing I
take bigger dabs in the average person
also I feel like to take the big dab
that I need I need a little extra heat
when I put that oil onto the nail it
immediately starts cooling the nail I'm
not using an email I like to use a
quartz banger I heat it with a torch so
as soon as something hits it before
something hits it when I quit applying
heat it starts cooling I let it get kind
of cooler it's still pretty hot then I
put my dab on there that rapidly starts
cooling it I've got to get my card cap
on there and start swirling it around a
lot of times the nail cools before I get
to consume all of the dab so I've got to
go a little bit hotter that's just the
way I like it when you go a little
hotter you also get this little punch in
the chest from it it's just a little
extra a lot of kids like to go a little
low temp they don't mind wasting a
little bit they get a q-tip and they
clean out the bang or when they're done
that's not my style so if you like load
dad's they see you get more flavor out
of it I may agree with that if that's
your thing
go for it if you're all about the hot
dad's if that's your thing go for it
just don't go so hot that you cause
yourself health problems you guys be
careful I know I joke around we talk
about glow ease and glow squad and we
say red means go that's kind of an
exaggeration don't [ __ ] your health up
because of a hot dab be careful you'll
notice one day you'll take too hot of a
DAB you'll get you'll get in a hurry
you'll get impatient you'll heat it up
you'll have your dab ready you'll be
talking and you'll go in and you'll go
all [ __ ] I didn't wait it'll be so hot
just learn to time your dad's eat it up
let it cool until it's not scorching hot
then hit your dad when it's comfortable
for you how you like it don't worry
about what anybody else thinks Debbie
your temperature all right you guys
that's all I've got for this 710 episode
thank you for hanging out with me this
was an hour-long show I thought it was
gonna be a quickie thanks for hanging in
for a whole entire hour I do appreciate
that make sure you guys check out the
patreon page
it's patreon.com slash Grover from your
heart also follow me on all of the
social media you can find me on Facebook
simply search for the girl from your
heart podcast you can find me on
Instagram search for Irie underscore
genetics come hang out watch my
Instagram live videos maybe I'll answer
some of your questions in the Instagram
live feed I invite you to follow the
podcast on Twitter simply search for @g
fyh podcast if you'd like to follow my
personal Twitter account
it's at Rasta Jeff 4:20 give me a follow
I would appreciate that
if you've got something you'd like to
say you're not into all the social media
or perhaps you've got a product you'd
like me to review or you'd like to
sponsor the podcast you can send me an
email my email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com you know I would
love to hear from you don't forget that
the podcast is available on iTunes
stitcher and every single episode is
available on YouTube just search for the
girl from the heart podcast ladies and
gentlemen I want to thank you again for
listening to a long and rambly 710
episode I really hope you learned
something from me today I want to give
you a huge shout out to all of my
friends in the 710 community big shout
out to task rock big shots a big D shout
out to dougie from hit man glass tryna
to giddyup
shut it to dead and granny big shout-out
to Kevin and a big shout-out to Spence
and Maddie and also a big black market
shout out to our boy max from TNT
extracts keepin it real on the streets
big shout out to everybody out there
keepin the 710 community moving do
something for the industry doing
something for the movement much love
much respect you guys I'll be back
Thursday with the brand-new episode I
hope you join me them and until next
time take a phat dab and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]