yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for another episode of the
grow from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right up here a new
grower if you're a professional grower
if you're a new smoker or a dedicated
dabber if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who is just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Roscoe
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me this episode of the podcast
is brought to you by my friends at the
hell a dank seed company if you need new
genetics for your gardening I highly
recommend the hella dank seed company
you can find them at dank seed dot store
ladies and gentlemen roll up a fat joint
pack up the bong or start heating up
that dab rig because it's time for
another episode of the grill from your
heart podcast what's up internet world
it's time for episode 333 of the girl
from your heart podcast thanks again for
joining me this episode of the podcast
is brought to you by our friends at the
hell a dank seed company if you need new
regular or feminized seeds for your
garden I highly recommend the hell a
dank seed company and you can find them
at dank seed dot store all right you
guys know I like to start these podcasts
off by letting you know what I've been
dad and on today it is 7:10 so I've been
dabbing on a little bit of everything I
started off with some East Coast
strawberries ambrosia I had a little bit
of Holy Grail batter
I've had some Durban Kush sauce and now
I'm dabbing some clementine ambrosia
sauce with gigantic crystals gigantic
chunks in here it just smells like a big
bag of fresh clementines or some orange
candies it's got a really juicy wet
smell to it it smells amazing you can
smell it from several inches away from
your face this jar is quite Turkey it's
a a nice sized jar it smells delicious
and the dabs just taste incredible the
flavor doesn't go away when you take a
dab of the Clementine you can take a
drink of water five or ten minutes later
and it kind of reactivates the
Clementine flavor in your mouth it is
delicious so that's my 7/10 that's what
I'm dabbing on I hope you guys had a
great safe seven ten and I also hope you
enjoyed this 710 episode of the podcast
if you haven't checked that out go back
and listen to the last episode and learn
all about 710 all right speaking of 710
there were some celebrations happening
here in Colorado on Saturday I was lucky
enough to attend the elevat-- oil spill
and chill party our friends at elevate
glass in Colorado Springs hosted a party
they have a beautiful glass shop with
some great glass in there if you need a
new rig a new pipe a new bong or a new
smoking accessory and you're in Colorado
Springs
I suggest elevate at 5:17 South Tejon
make sure you check them out they've got
great glass great prices great customer
service they threw a party the store was
packed with great sales and great deals
and also in the back of the building
they had several booths with great
vendors they had fire spinners there was
a DJ there was live painting there were
plenty of games to play there was a
giant Jenga game there was a giant
Kinect for there were folks playing
cornhole it was a great party there was
a little dab tent where he could hang
out take some dabs
the folks from elevate were showing off
a bunch of their new products it was a
really well-organized event I got to see
a bunch of great people elevate gave
away a bunch of great prizes and I had a
great time so big shout out to Beca big
shout out to the entire elevate crew
thanks for a great party
so that was Saturday then Sunday was
ambrosia days at apothecary apothecary
is a dispensary in Colorado Springs its
apothecary farms they host an event
called ambrosia days apothecary is known
for their concentrates they don't carry
any flour in their dispensary they carry
concentrates
several different styles they've got
their ambrosia they've got batter
they've got shatter they've got waxes
you can get HC FSC you can get the HTF
se you can get sauce you can get pucks
you can get diamonds they've got all
kinds of different concentrates they've
got a few edibles available they have a
few vape pen cartridges they have turd
pens available but they don't carry any
flowers so it's a very quick shopping
experience they have a bunch of
concentrates to show you the everything
is all in one little display so you can
check it out really quickly anyway they
have their ambrosia days party where
they have everything on sale for
amazingly low prices they save up a
bunch of great inventory and they
release a bunch of great products on
those days they have their specials and
they're rare releases on those ambrosia
days then they throw a party at another
place off-site this time the party was
at a place called vibe
I was able to do some shopping then I
had to go run some errands in Colorado
Springs had to go hit the guitar Center
and spend a bunch of money there that's
one of my favorite things to do then I
got to go over to the ambrosia days
party and link up with some friends that
was a good time because as soon as I got
out of the car I ran into our buddy Miho
dabbin I ran into all of the New Mexico
crew whatup huggy dougie
what up DS and the whole crew I'm not
gonna list all you guys cuz I'll miss
somebody and then I'll feel like an
[ __ ] but right into the whole New
Mexico crew got to see a bunch of great
people at the ambrosia Days party and I
got to check out a place called Strictly
vibe for the first time really cool
place I'm sure if there are more events
there I will be hanging out the place is
totally Rasta themed everything is red
gold and green it kind of felt welcoming
there so that's how my seven 10 pre
seven ten weekend went I picked up
plenty of great concentrates I had a
nice variety to dab on throughout the
weekend uh hung out with Mike a little
bit yesterday I had a nice 7/10 today
than a nice little Instagram live video
and now here we are recording a podcast
late in the evening on 7th Ann let's get
into the point of this podcast you guys
have been going for almost six minutes
now and we haven't even talked about
anything so let's jump into it this
episode of the podcast is going to be
about keeping a journal for your
cannabis grow keeping notes keeping
track of what you've done and having
sort of a notebook to look back through
when something goes right or something
goes wrong so let's talk about
journaling your cannabis grow now before
we talk about keeping notes and taking a
journal for your grow let me say that I
can't promote people growing cannabis in
illegal places if it's illegal for you
to grow maybe you shouldn't be doing
that where you are I can't advocate that
legally I've got to say if it's illegal
don't do it but if you insist on growing
cannabis in an illegal place
maybe you shouldn't keep as careful
notes as the people in Colorado and
California and other legal locations are
going to keep maybe you're keeping
incriminating evidence maybe you want to
skip keeping a journal maybe you want to
create a Google Doc and use code words
or something maybe you don't want to
have this evidence laying around but
like I said before I don't promote you
growing
illegal area so that's something to
think about now with that being said if
you live in a location where it is legal
to grow and produce cannabis take
excessive notes write everything down
because those notes will come to use in
the future now before we start talking
about taking notes let's talk about the
actual journal I'm not too picky about
what kind of journal you use I've got a
large notebook here a college rule
notebook on the table this is what I
take notes in for the podcast this would
work fine as a journal open it up start
writing in it whatever you do in your
garden write it down we're gonna talk
more about what to write down it doesn't
have to be broken down into categories
it doesn't have to be looking like
homework just write down what you do
just open up the notebook write the date
right what phase of the girl you're in
maybe write this stream of plants may be
on the front page write a paragraph if
you feel like like how many plants
you've got how many lies to run and just
right just right in there then turn the
next page and when you go in the garden
write down what you do today I did this
and then just write that [ __ ] down
you'll start designing your journal the
way you want it over time it will morph
into what you want it to be so I've got
this College rule notebook here also
next to me that I've got another little
side project two notes going on it's
just a little tiny nine and a half by
six inch notebook it's a smaller
notebook that would work just fine for a
grow journal I've seen guys use little
tiny flip books little notebooks I've
seen guys use fancy binder notebooks or
you don't have to even use paper you can
use a Google Doc if you want you can use
the note application in your phone if
you'd like I would write rather cuu
something that can't get lost that note
application you can delete that that's
gone once you delete that he [ __ ] up
it's gone forever have something maybe a
hard copy you can hold on to I like that
better but like I said if you're in a
legal place that becomes evidence in the
worst case scenario so if you need a
digital copy that's the way to do it
something you could delete really
quickly if you need to that may be key
something that's password-protected if
you need to anyway keep a journal it
doesn't matter how the journal is kept
something that works for you all of our
brains work differently all of us set up
our thoughts and projects differently as
long as you're taking notes and keeping
track of things you were journaling and
it doesn't matter how it's done as long
as you can read that [ __ ] don't scribble
down a note thinking your cue
writing just some quick shorthand stuff
seven initial letters and then a number
and then milliliters next to it and
you're gonna come back here you cannot
even write like write clearly write
legibly right what you're talking about
and then when you go back to read those
notes in the future you'll be able to
repeat what you did before and you'll
have a repeatable outcome it won't be a
guessing game so keep a simple journal
keep a detailed journal as long as
you're keeping a journal on either paper
or digitally I'm happy now let's
actually talk about journaling let's
talk about the advantage of keeping
notes
what is the advantage why do I want to
write this stuff down there are several
advantages to keeping a grou journal and
keeping grou notes one of the biggest
advantages is let's say we're trying to
dial in a new nutrient system I've been
trying to get everybody addicted to veg
bloom let's say you just started using
vegetable um it's your first run you're
dialing it in you know you don't know
how those plants are gonna react to veg
bloom so let's start a grow journal for
the veg bloom grow on page 1 you say I'm
in veg I'm using this much of edge bloom
you write down everything you put in
there and then you grow you run the
whole cycle you write down everything
you do and at the end if you're happy
with it you can look back and you go huh
that's how I did it and you can repeat
that if you're not happy with it you can
look back and see where you screwed up
or you can see where you can adjust and
make it better that's the main point of
keeping notes you can repeat it if
something goes right or you can correct
it if something goes wrong you have got
records and at the same time you're
creating an SOP which we'll talk about
in a little bit let's say you're growing
and you're in flour and about week four
you start seeing an issue you can use
those notes from the past to help you
correct and identify a problem you can
look back and you can say oh I fed it
cal-mag too many days in a row and
you'll know because you wrote it down
and now instead of wondering what the
problem is you've got a note that says
right here I fed it cal-mag on Monday I
also [ __ ] up and gave it cal-mag on
Wednesday it's probably got too much
cal-mag and now you've got a record all
so hopefully this will prevent you from
feeding it too much cal-mag because you
wrote down in the journal all you have
to do is turn back to pages and see what
you fed it two days ago see what you fed
it the past few days and you know oh I
gave it cal-mag she won't need cal-mag
for a few days she'll be just fine so
that's some of the advantages of keeping
notes also you've got data
the future if you love the outcome you
know what you did you can do it all over
again if you're not satisfied with the
outcome you can try to fix it and then
here's the best part grow again and
change something and then see how you
like that outcome and then compare the
two notes see what you did differently
and see what you did the same then you
can create a test sample you can create
a base and you have somewhere to work
from
you just need data we were creating data
for the future is what you're doing with
journaling and you can use that data to
identify and correct problems and
prevent problems I almost overlooked at
that part we're using the data to
prevent problems at the same time now
from a business person's point of view
if you're trying to open a grow or
you're trying to run a grow or work at a
grow for somebody maybe you're trying to
start your own business as a grow is the
guy with all of the notes and details
gonna be more likely to get financial
backing or is it gonna be the guy with
pictures of his plants which one of
those feels more reliable from a
business standpoint so notes show
accountability and responsibility and
initiative at the same time also science
is all about taking notes any sort of
progression is about keeping notes how
can you know if you're doing better or
worse if you don't have anything to
compare to so that's another thing about
taking notes it's a very once you get
into the business world it will be
required so start getting used to it now
all right let's get focused again I'm
just talking to me when I say let's get
focused I get rambley it may be all the
dabs
alright so we're talking about taking
notes what do we note note everything
note what you were feeding your plants
know what you are mixing how much water
are you using to feed the plants how
frequently are you feeding them when
you're mixing what is in the mix what
are you putting in there how much of you
what nutrient and how much of it are you
putting in there how often are they
getting fed back the way I would do this
I would open up a page of the notebook
and I would write whatever it is if
you're in veg whatever July 10th
veg week 3 today I fed 5 gallons of
water I mixed in 5 grams of Base
nutrients per gallon I mixed in one gram
of plus life per gallon and then I gave
it 2 mils of cal-mag per gallon and then
I pH dit I would write down
what went in there I would write down
the EC I would write down the pH and I
would write down the temperature of my
feed solution before I even carry that
container of water to the plants to
water it all of that would get written
down then I would water the plants to a
point of runoff tour at least a little
bit of water is coming out of each plant
I've got a catch tray under the plants I
would catch some of that water and I
would put my EC meter and my pH pin in
that runoff water and I would document
that runoff water as well if you've got
multiple plants in large containers I
would check several of them I would
check them all if you feel like you have
time to do it and document this when
things go wrong those runoff numbers may
be indicators of when and where things
went wrong and then you can look back at
your other notes and you can see what
you fed it and then we can compare that
EC running off and we can see what's
going on and what it's not eating and
why the pH is fluctuating we can figure
all that out through the notes you're
keeping all right so we're taking great
notes of our feet we're measuring what
goes in and what comes out so you've got
a notebook and it says veg week 2 or
whatever I'm just being hypothetical
here veg week 2 July 10th fed this pH n
was this EC n was this temp in was this
runoff measurements were this EC was
this pH was this I don't measure the
temperature of the runoff that doesn't
matter to me maybe it should but it
never has it's never come into play so
write down what goes in write down what
goes out keep that document every time
you feed and then if you feed it water
or something next time just write that
down write down almost everything you do
in that grow almost think like it's an
accountability sheet so if if somebody
were to say hey what the [ __ ] did you do
all day then you could say oh I did this
I water the plants I gave them this new
have got details and then you've got
everything written down write down
everything that you do in the grow so
we'll move on to sprays write down your
sprays if it's a foliar feed if it's a
pesticide application if it's a spot
spray of one plant write that down and
buy a spot spray I mean if you're not
spraying the entire room if you just see
one area where you're you see some
spider mite damage but it hasn't sprayed
and you don't feel like you want to
spray the entire crop yet maybe you just
makes up a small batch of pesticides and
apply that to one small area that's what
I call a spot treatment I just hit that
hot spot get in there and make sure it
doesn't spread
I just if you happen to see something or
if you've got a specific strain that you
know gets mites treat that [ __ ] to
pretreat it so anyway
write down every spray every application
whether it's a pesticide a feeding a
preventative whatever it is write down
what you spray it write down the product
write down how much of it you applied
write down how much you mixed up say you
probably makes up a half a gallon or a
gallon if you're a home grower put I mix
up a gallon of water
what pesticide did you put in there did
you put thirty milliliters of evergreen
in there
did you put five milliliters of smite in
there what did you mix up is there also
25 or 50 milliliters of push in there
write it all down did you check the pH
of that some folks check the pH oh
they're full of your feed some folks
don't some products you should not
adjust the pH some products you do need
to adjust the pH write it down if you
did or did not write down when it was
applied write down if it was applied
right before the lights came on write
down if you turned off the lights and
applied it write down how long those
lights were off check the plants before
you turn the lights on and make sure
they're dry note that you did that write
down why you sprayed why were you
spraying what was your purpose write
that down
like act like there's another person
that's gonna come check your notes
mm-hmm
acts like I'm gonna come check your
notes he's like so I see that you
applied as a max today why and then I
should see right underneath that oh I
see why I identified spider mites or
thrips in the garden today and I felt
that it would be best to apply a product
so something like that write down why
you applied some products then later on
write down the results did you see any
results were there dead bugs hanging off
of the leaves were there dead eggs
somewhere in the grow room that the
plants look like [ __ ]
did the plants look better write down
the results what did you do and write
down the results write down why you did
it
what you did and how it reacted to it
and then you're gonna have to pay
attention because sometimes a pesticide
application won't show you problems for
a couple of days so pay attention to
that
write that down also if you rinse the
plants off a lot of people will apply a
foliar application some products it's
ideal to rinse them a few hours later
write that
down also detailed notes also if you put
in sort of a surfactant maybe you're
using some wet Betty or some Coco wet
inside of your foliar feed write that
down also everything that goes in should
get written down as my point so we're
writing down the feeds we're writing
down the sprays that's just about
everything that is going into the plants
if you're making your own soil mix I
didn't write this down if you're making
your own soil mix if you're making a
super soil write down everything you put
into that that's crucial right back down
to the cup if you're scooping cups or
spoonfuls or whatever write it down
grams if you can highly detailed write
that down your super soil mix should be
dialed in that's gonna take you a couple
runs to get it perfected and if you
don't have notes it's gonna be a [ __ ]
to dial that inks you might not remember
what you did we're smoking cannabis you
guys we forget a lot of [ __ ] take a lot
of notes so let's move forward more
notes to take room and environment notes
document the lights maybe you don't have
a lumen meter but pay attention document
the temperature document the humidity
and if you can pay attention to the co2
there are several ways several devices
it'll document all these things for you
if you just need the cheap hydrometer
and a pen and paper do that write it
down
pay attention see if you've got spikes
see if you've got valleys see if you've
got swings and your temperature and your
humidity in your co2 hopefully you can
get something like a pl minder unit in
there from PL Gro systems and you can
pay attention to what's going on at all
times but we don't all have that ability
so you're gonna have to write it down
and pay attention use one of those
hygrometers and thermometers that gives
you a high and a low and it lets you
know what the high got to and the low
was do the best you can with what you've
got but take notes of that because if it
was too hot for too long your buds will
show you that if it was too cold for too
long your buds will show you that if it
was too humid for too long your buds
will show you that in the end and if you
don't write it down if you're not aware
of it then you can't correct it and
you'll go why are my buds so fluffy you
won't realize it was because they were
too hot for too long you may forget so
write down the room and environment
notes that you see the temperature the
humidity and the co2 and if you can
measure the amount of light in there if
you've got a lumen meter do that not
required just helpful that helps you
know when to replace your
and when it comes to commercial growing
that that really makes a huge difference
on you moles and para watts and how much
lighting per square foot it really comes
into play on the commercial grow anyway
let's move forward with what we're
focused on and keep me focused today
write down schedule notes are you in veg
are you in flower write down when veg
started write down when flower started
write down what time the lights are
coming on and going off I've had
situations now I use a digital timer so
if the power goes out there's a backup
battery in there and it'll stay on the
correct time a long time ago before I
was smarter than that I was using old
analog timers if the power went out the
timer quit spinning so it is now wrong
for however long the power is out my
timer is that many hours off sometimes I
didn't remember what time the lights
came on that I have those lights coming
on at 7:00 a.m. or did they come on at
9:00 I ain't 9:00 a.m. I don't remember
so now you got a guess write that [ __ ]
down take some notes have some
accountability notes will save your ass
in the long run one day you're gonna go
oh I'm so glad I wrote that [ __ ] down
and just write that down every little
thing you can think of schedule notes
what time to the lights come on what
time do the lights go off what time is
my AC come on what time does that hydro
pump come on just write down everything
if you're running hydro and stuff and
you've got to do different cycles if
you're running a flood and drain or some
sort of ebb and flow write down how long
it takes for that stuff to wet and dry
and how frequently you're watering they
may help you out in the future when
you're trying to plan future grows so
staying on the same note of scheduling
write down when you cut your clones
write down when you sprout your seeds
write down everything you can you guys
write down Windows clones came out of
the cloner and into dirt write down
every transplant and a pot that you can
transpire that you can write down keep
notes on everything that way you can
keep track when you're looking to grow
in the future you can say hi I don't
have a lot of time which plants veg the
fastest out of my selection do I want to
run this og or do I want to run this
Strawberry Hayes and you're gonna look
back and you're gonna see in your notes
that that strawberry Hayes only needed
two weeks to veg and that og cush needed
four because it's a slow veg er and then
you'll say oh [ __ ] let's run the
strawberry so notes are gonna help you
so then of course you're gonna want to
write down when you start your veg cycle
you're gonna definitely
want to write down when you start your
bloom cycle also write down your
anticipated flush date if you anticipate
a flush date
write that down also it's wise to create
a feed schedule in advance and try to
stay on top of it if you're gonna grow
for nine weeks write yourself out a
seven week feed schedule and tasks to do
throughout those seven weeks and then
when you turn the page one day when
you're going to work you're gonna water
the plants that's gonna say flush today
and you're gonna go oh cool I'm 10 to 14
days away from harvest I should start
flushing so prepare that write yourself
a schedule along with your journal then
also write down when you started
flushing also you're gonna be paying
attention to the trichomes every day
when you're looking in there with the
scope write down what you see why not
write down today on July 10 I looked at
my Strawberry Fields plant I looked at
the top buds all that all the trichomes
were milky but towards the bottom there
were a couple of amber trichomes on the
bottom of the plant
write that down why not write that all
down so you're writing down everything
you guys I know I'm being redundant but
do you guys might forget some of this
stuff and I point out things that you
guys may have missed so write down the
day you started flushing that way you
don't forget because I forgotten you'll
be in the grow room link did I give him
nutrients last time or have I given him
straight water you'll be flushing for
two times and you'll [ __ ] up and pour
nutrients in the plant you're like oh
yeah [ __ ] up so write it down pay
attention just have yourself some solid
notes also document any sort of
defoliation and popping and topping and
lolli popping write that stuff down
because some plants are going to react
poorly to it some plants are going to
love it if you write down everything you
know when you pissed off a plant you can
look through the notes and go so this is
OG kush plant got pissed off around week
three what happened and you look at your
notes and you go oh we d foliated the
[ __ ] out of it on week three and we also
fed it too much cal-mag you'll be able
to look at your notes and you'll have
some sort of a an idea of where you went
wrong and that's gonna be really helpful
for when we go to grow that same og cush
next time we'll go look in week 3 bro
don't do foliate the [ __ ] out of it and
don't OD it on cal-mag it'll be much
happier than it was last time and then
you'll learn how to dial it in notes
will help you out with that a lot now as
a breeder and a Fino hunter
this is one of my favorite parts
document any growth details and anything
notable does that plant make pretty
colors does that plant grow weird did it
do something strange did it spit out
extra nodes did it spit out extra
branches or the branches really closed
and compact together did anything
strange happen anything notable write
down growth details do they get really
tall that it's a remarkably short
did something happen when you topped it
did something happen when you did some
lollipop
write down anything you notice that is
notable about the growth of that plant
whether it's colors whether it's just
extra branching anything you see that
may get your attention write it down
also if anything happened in that room
environmentally when that weird change
happened document that on a side note
and let's pay attention to that over the
next couple of cycles so let's say maybe
I got maybe the air conditioner didn't
go off one night or maybe you got a
little extra cool just because it cooled
down tonight and it got cool in the grow
room and it rained and the room got a
little cooler and more humid
the next day you noticed that some of
the some of the leaves are turning a
little bit purple and then we're gonna
note that it got a little cold in the
room and the leaves were purple next
time we grow it we're gonna pay
attention does it have to get cold to
get it purple or around this same time
period does it purple up on its own and
we'll start knowing those leaves get
purple because of cold or do they get
purple because there's great genetics
and then if we want to make it purple in
the future and it's just genetics we can
add that purple again or add that cold
again and bring out the purple well know
that it's something that we can control
just taking notes will give you more
ideas and sometimes you find things in a
plant that you want to repeat sometimes
you find things in a plant you don't
want to repeat and this is the way to
know how to do it so a moment ago I
mentioned the air conditioner failure
maybe the air conditioner didn't turn
off maybe the heater didn't come on
maybe the [ __ ] air conditioner didn't
come on and it got real hot document any
incidents or accidents that you may have
in that grow room even if you [ __ ] up
its your grow room it's okay yeah I said
earlier I'm gonna come check your notes
that's alright I'm not gonna get mad at
you I have [ __ ] up in grow rooms I
have fallen asleep with the grow room
with the flower room door open before I
guess what you got a seed or a crop full
of seeds I just cut it down and threw it
away as soon as I saw the seeds forming
I was like nope
I [ __ ] up just threw it all the way a
hole it was just one small room is like
nine plants under one light but I fell
asleep with that door open I think I
went got myself some food I went ate and
then I fell asleep and I'd left the grow
room door open because I was just
letting to get fresh air I had the fan
blowing in there you know you don't want
to stifle the room all day and we can
give it some fresh air you can but a
pizza got stoned fell asleep and I woke
up later and I was like oh you know what
and I walked in there and it was [ __ ]
dark in the room and the door was open
and the light from the hallway was just
shining right in there so I knew there
was a problem but as soon as I saw the
seed pods form this plants got killed
so I've [ __ ] up so write down if you
leave a door open write down if you
leave a light on write down if something
goes wrong write down if you did
something wrong maybe you [ __ ] up in
overfed something write it down it's
gonna help you identify a problem in the
future and it will help you not do that
mistake again
also write down if you adjusted any
equipment did you change any air
conditioning settings did you change any
timer settings did you mess with that
fan in the corner did you change
anything
make a little section on your notes for
today of any equipment that you changed
what did you adjust because small
adjustments can create huge problems
over several hours in a grow room maybe
you turned that fan from low to high and
though that one bud that it's just been
kicking the [ __ ] out of every time it
rotates that one bud is gonna get dried
out the leaves are gonna start looking
leathery and crispy it's gonna start
talking up or it's gonna get back claw
and start clawing down it's gonna start
looking like a leather leaf it's gonna
look like a fake plant instead of a real
plant that buds gonna get all dry the
plants gonna be trying to send all of
its moisture up there to keep that one
one piece of plant living and happy and
it's not gonna do it it's gonna make
that whole plant struggle document that
[ __ ] you could be like uh yesterday I
put that fan on three that's why it
looks like [ __ ]
and just document things like that any
sort of update or adjustment that you do
did you change a timer did you move a
fan did you do something to the AC did
you change the co2 anything like that
make sure you write that stuff down now
here are some other things that you may
not think about write down whenever you
change your bulbs a lot of people forget
when the bulbs are changed it's a good
idea if you've got a bulb there's that
little white part the ceramic part at
the base of the bulb you can write the
date right on there on the
or I've taken little stickers just a
little green yardsale sticker or a piece
of duct tape or whatever and write the
date of that bulb on there and stick it
to the reflector changed all these bulbs
on 7:10 2018 boom stick that sticker
right on the reflector and then you've
got some sort of note but put it in your
journal that way you've got it all right
there in one spot have some
accountability know when those bulbs
were changed cuz bulbs don't last
forever also write down when you change
your carbon filters your air
conditioning filters if you're running
any kind of hydro or also if you're
running an RO system write down when you
change those filters write that [ __ ]
down in your journal so that it's a
never a question so if somebody says hey
how long have you had that [ __ ]
carbon filter you hold on it's in my
journal you can scroll to the the
equipment page and you can go oh I put
that in here on the 4th of July in 2016
and go OK it's time to replace that
[ __ ] then you just have some
accountability with that also I would
recommend documenting when all of your
meters are calibrated your pH meter your
EC meter your ppm meter whatever type of
meters you are using calibrate those
things make sure you calibrate them and
write that down also here's something
you may not think about write down if
you're using a respirator when you apply
pesticides and you should be write down
when you changed those cartridges the
cartridges do not last forever they've
only got so many hours depending on what
type of pesticide you were applying the
life of those cartridges can be
shortened by different products they
don't last the same amount of time for
each product if you've got a more
volatile product I don't know the
correct word but if you've got a more
dangerous product then that cartridge is
absorbing more junk and it's not going
to last as long so write down each
application that you have done with that
cartridge and when it was inserted into
your respirator and pay attention to
when it needs to be replaced now since
we're talking about safety gear let's
write down the last time we checked our
fire extinguisher have you checked the
fire extinguisher lately you should have
one of those have you checked your smoke
detector you should have one of those
check the batteries in your smoke
detector and write down the last time
you tested it that smoke detector won't
do you any good if the batteries are
dead and it doesn't make any noise all
right
guys I feel like I have talked about a
lot of stuff we could journal how you
want to journal how you want to organize
and arrange everything is up to you I'm
sure I've made my point of write down
everything that you can now let's say
you see a problem let's say that you're
walking into the grow room and you see
that in the middle of week six of flower
these plants just look like they have
totally gone to [ __ ] they're clawed up
some of the leaves are yellow
the leaves are facing down they look
like look like a claw like a monster
claw and they're yellowed out oh crap
what happened it's probably a nutrient
problem it's probably from about three
to seven days ago let's get out the
notebook let's scroll back and look to
see what we did three days ago what did
we feed them anything weird
let's look yesterday did we spray
anything didn't spray anything let's
look the day before do we spray anything
no spray let's look before that oh here
we fed a whole bunch of stuff let's look
through here okay it doesn't seem to be
like that's the problem let's look back
okay we started seeing that the runoff
was different the runoff the pH of the
runoff started getting really low and
the EC of the runoff started getting
really high about seven days ago what
did we feed it about eight or nine days
ago and you can start doing that math
and you can say oh [ __ ] look about 12
days ago maybe 10 days ago we fed this
plant way too much of something or we
did we applied something that did it and
you'll just be able to use those notes
as a map backwards and now it has become
a math problem just to figure out
through deductive reasoning with your
notes what went wrong and if you wrote
her enough notes and you're paying
enough attention to the plants and
you've got the connection that you need
you'll be able to find the problem then
once you find that problem write it down
in your journal then when we grow a G
khush again we know that in week 5 not
to try to feed it way too much bloom
boosters so this is what we call dialing
in your grow this is why a lot of
experienced growers are sought-after in
commercial facilities we can dial things
in much more quickly because we're more
familiar with these types of things we
know that some plants want some things
you know that some plants are gonna
react certain ways and we've got an eye
to identify those things and we develop
that skill through taking notes through
practicing through observation and
through repeating this process also you
guys if you think about it Oh
several crop cycles if you take good
enough notes you were reverse
engineering SOPs for yourself you were
creating a standard operating procedure
for your grow you were dialing it in you
were starting to get a streamline work
process you're starting to dial in the
cost you're starting to dial in the
efficiency and you can streamline it a
little better every grow by taking notes
and seeing exactly how much nutrient
you're using seeing each step that
you're doing where you could kind of cut
some time out by say it by doing oh
maybe I'm doing this wrong you can save
time here you can save time here you
could save a few dollars here you can
learn how to not [ __ ] up your crops you
can learn how to prevent problems you
can see which pesticide applications
worked you can see which pesticide
applications did not work you can see
when to time things better
keeping these notes will help you create
standard operating procedures that will
work in a small scale grow it will also
be expandable to a larger facility now
here's one last thing that we should
keep notes of in any sort of grow
situation and that is your harvest you
want to keep notes on your harvest Waits
per plant per strain per room however
you want to do it keep notes also take
personal notes on how you feel the
quality is of your product if you can
get it lab tested do that and keep notes
on that that way we can see if we are
increasing our harvests increasing our
quality also document how many harvests
you get per year and let's see if we can
maximize your room maybe if we time
things properly we can pull a whole
nother crop out of that room per year
let's see what we can do for you the
only way we can do that is take notes
and see if we can repeat our processes
and see where we can improve you guys so
that is my episode on journaling and
keeping a grow journal I hope you
learned something if you feel like
there's something I missed that you'd
like to contribute I would love to do an
update episode you can send me an email
my email address is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com you know I love to hear
from my listeners ladies and gentlemen
thanks again for listening to a long
podcast I would appreciate it if you
support the podcast on patreon patreon
is a service that allows you as a
listener to financially contribute to
the
Podcast what that would do is help me
pay for the website that keeps this
podcast free for everybody
it helps me cover the cost of this
MacBook that I bought to keep the
podcast coming to you it helps me
replace these little microphone covers
so that when Mike comes over he doesn't
have to spit into the same mic cover
that granny was spitting into the whole
episode small things like that do help
me out if you want for more information
you can go to patreon.com/scishow doubt
to everybody who has contributed to
patreon in the past and who will
contribute in the future thank you that
is definitely appreciated all right you
guys I would appreciate it if you follow
me on all the social media make sure you
follow me on Facebook simply search for
the girl from your our podcast you can
find me on the Twitter's it's at g f YH
podcast if you'd like to follow my
personal account is a trusted Jeff 420
check me out on there also check out my
Instagram account it's Irie underscore
genetics check out my cannabis
photography join me in my Instagram live
feeds come talk about canvas with me
like I said before if you've got
something you'd like to say and you're
not into all that social media stuff you
can send me an email let's grow from
your heart at hotmail.com if you'd like
to sponsor the podcast or if you've got
a product you'd like me to review please
reach out I would love to connect with
you you guys don't forget that the show
is available on iTunes it's usually
available on stitcher when it works and
every episode is always and forever
archived on the YouTube channel if you
haven't subscribed to the YouTube
channel yet please do that simply go to
youtube and search for the Grove from
your heart podcast and click Subscribe
alright podcasts world I know I asked
for a lot of stuff at the end of every
episode here I'm like go follow me on
patreon go stalk me on social media give
me an iTunes review there's all kinds of
stuff I always ask for at the end of the
show but I would really appreciate it if
we could get my strain arise on Leafly
the way to do that is to go to Leafly
and go to the submit a new strain tab
and then just leave a review on a rise
if you have ever smoked smelled grown
consumed anything about a rise and you
feel like you're qualified to leave a
review on there I would appreciate that
let's get a rise on Leafly go to Leafly
calm go to the add a new strain tab you
may have to create an account that's
always fun then once you've got your
account set up go ahead and type in some
information about my strain arise it is
golden
go to Daybreaker it is a hybrid and I
think it deserves to be listed on the
website Leafly alright you guys I want
to thank you again for listening to this
podcast I'll be back in just a couple of
days with fresh new content I want to
give a huge shout out to my boy max from
TNT extractions for keepin it real so
shout out to max and until next time
take a phat dab and give your mom a hug
for me
[Music]