you hit a welcome-back cannabis
community it's time for another episode
of the Grove from your heart podcast
your source for cannabis news education
and conversation let's write up here a
new grower if you're a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
dedicated davor if you're a cannabis
activists or even someone who is just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me this episode of the podcast
is brought to you by my friends at the
hell a dank seed company if you need new
genetics for your gardening I highly
recommend the hella dank seed company
you can find them at dank seed dot store
ladies and gentlemen roll up a fat joint
pack up the bong or start heating up
that dab rig because it's time for
another episode of the grill from your
heart podcast welcome back podcast world
it's time for episode three 34 of the
girl from our podcast thanks again for
joining me sitting across the table from
me is white Mike welcome back to the
show bro thanks forever oh man thanks
for coming out kind of doing a late
night podcast I'm fixing some equipment
knobs as I talk I apologize for that
we're dropping the sound we'll get it
going just decided that one knob needed
to be turned to show what a professional
podcast will get there we go I think I'm
better now we took it felt like a couple
more doves and we usually do before the
show
well you I needed that cigarette and
that I smoked a cigarette
we went outside and came back and I look
I'm not even high anymore so we got to
restore so and the second session kind
of rebrov that first session back if you
like
Wilson to show you guys this shows
brought to you by our friends at the
hella dank seed company if you need new
regular or feminized seeds I highly
recommend the hella dank seed company
you can find them at dank seed dot store
support them send them our love all
right we'd like to talk about what we're
smoking onto the start of the show Mike
and I were already talking about how
dabbed out we are we started off by
taking dad's of some Clementine HC FS e
big ol chunky diamonds with a lot of
Terps on it just delicious then we
switched to some Holy Grail Kush which
was even more delicious in my opinion
it's cuz I don't smoke a lot of that I
was kind of
oiled with it it was really nice that's
a really nice flavor then Mike threw
down some Lucinda Williams HC FSE
crystals I dunk that into some
Clementine Terps that was really nice
that was really nice then after the
break we smoked more of the Holy Grail
Kush after Mike's little cigarette break
he's probably a good choice before we
got got into record and we were I don't
know there was a slowdown that needed to
occur yeah yeah we might have been too
amped up after all that Clementine that
sativa type dabs yep all that Clementine
had me racing got me chilled out got me
ready for a good podcast got me ready to
go hey Mike you ready to jump right into
it let's do it all right let's go right
starting with Oklahoma Oklahoma so a
couple episodes ago we talked about
Oklahoma legalizing medical marijuana
yes we did shout out to all of our
friends in Oklahoma we got quite a few
friends out there they listen to the
podcasts that support us big shout out
you know who you guys are one of my
friends sent us a message he's like hey
dude Oklahoma just legalized and then as
soon as they announced the rules we
realized that it totally sucks so we did
some investigating I did some
investigating there's one thing I
noticed there is no list of qualifying
conditions it's just up to your doc to
decide if you should get medical
marijuana or not as it was originally
yeah Oklahoma you guys have some really
interesting rules the no list of
requirements is just the one what you've
got a list of some others you've got
good notes on this I just scanned
yes article this morning so they
mentioned the first thing that I noticed
was no list of qualifying conditions so
I guess we found a negative and a
positive to that the doc can assign your
medical marijuana recommendation if
you've got a hangnail and he thinks that
your medical marijuana may help with
that so that's kind of cool
it does open it up that's gonna be up to
the doc or the docs gonna be liberal
with that are they gonna be kind of
tight with that I think it's that's
gonna depend wildly on implementation in
practice if
just basing what other states have gone
through like I want to say it was
Michigan that when the news got footage
of five hundred people in a hotel lobby
waiting in line to see the only two
doctors in the state that were signing
cards the story was about how to doctors
signed up five hundred people in a
weekend not how only two doctors in the
state are willing to do this and so
people have to jump like the way the
story was presented led to a backlash
that completely imploded their system
and they've had to restart like three
times now and with no patient list at
this point in time it's not gonna be
like California where there's people set
up everywhere where you can walk in get
your card walk across the street and
shop medically and that systems been in
place for twenty years now it's
currently being rebuilt from the ground
up under legalization which apparently
they weren't quite ready for but
California you'll get there but if the
doctors like is a group started getting
backlash because people are like certain
members of their community are over
prescribing for stuff that the rest of
the community doesn't see is worthy
there might be some push and pull on
different substances
different recommendations for different
ailments the way I was just thinking of
it though is in Colorado we've never
been able to expand our list there's a
list of conditions several other
conditions have been presented and
pushed through the process and at the
last step they get denied and they all
get denied for the same reason and it's
because there's not a big FDA backed
double-blind studies showing that
cannabis is an effective treatment
option for Blanke there's a lot of
anecdotal evidence but until that last
big study happens [ __ ] off and now
Oklahoma won't have to deal with that if
evidence starts to point to some some
treatment option that we're not
currently utilized in cannabis for they
can just start recommending right off
the bat
for that they don't have to tell that
whole population pretend you've got
cancer right rule yes we can get you in
there it'll take three years to do it
yeah all right it simplifies that
process all right so that that's gonna
work to some folks advantage and it's up
to the doc hopefully your doc is liberal
and I'm you're gonna find good doctors
there trust me stuff happens
another thing that popped out was they
banned all smokeable medical marijuana
so you can't smoke flowers yep that's I
don't like that because I'm gonna be a
very odd rule yeah yeah and they're not
the only place to do that Florida's
currently being sued in there if I sorry
guys it's been a crazy chunk of my life
listeners of the show for a while know
that my life's nuts right now but I'm
like 95% sure Florida patients just won
the right to smoke their meds in court
that that that provision of their law
was struck down finally in court but
Oklahoma won't be the first to have that
rule and I think a lot of the rules were
about to cover from this point forward
if I remember right the governor of
Oklahoma was against the legalization
initiative originally which likely means
they've been listening to a lot of the
national anti-pot people it's one of the
things governor's do if if they've got a
position on something from the onset
they look for other people arguing for
their position and get the arguments
from those people and I think that's why
we're seeing the list of rules we're
seeing or that we're about to go over is
because national Anti Fog groups are
trying a couple of different things to
[ __ ] over the industry they've tried in
a couple of states where legalizations
already happen or medical has already
happened and they haven't been
successful but he with Oklahoma they're
gonna get some of them implemented from
the get-go and we're gonna see how it
plays out all right they're supposed to
have another meeting soon there's a
deadline set for this meeting I know a
lot of people in Oklahoma
pissed over this is what I was reading
yes we've got friends that brought this
to my attention which is why we're
talking about it so shout out to our
friends down there
so no smokeable flowers which I I think
that's weird because in my opinion I'm
not a doctor in my opinion smoking is
the most immediate and effective relief
you can smoke and you feel some by the
time you're exhaling you feel it if
there's a flower smoker by the time you
blow up that flower you you feel it if
you're buzzed AB smoker by the time you
blow out that dab you feel it if you
can't consume flower you're taking
medicine away from people like the most
effective obvious old-school traditional
way of consuming it is now removed I
think that's ridiculous
and they do allow edibles you can have
edibles which isn't that where we find
all of our problems like 90% of our
problems are with people [ __ ] up with
edibles yeah the the path to edibles in
1998 was a lot safer than it is today
like just being able to walk it and buy
it it's like teenagers with booze like
it's it's just not something you should
do without a guide I think or at least
like a pamphlet yeah
and a friend to sit there and be like
dude you're you're just really baked
calm down also been where a lot of the
stupid problems happen every place that
legalizes they get a big wave of poison
center calls the Knights yeah yeah and
some of that's because people are stupid
and irresponsible with edibles but a lot
of that's because these are exposures
that were happening before and are now
just being reported because of
legalization like it's right it's a good
thing health-wise but it's a bad thing
pro-legalization data wise I think I
just found it weird that they allow
edibles they're easier to hide they're
easier to have too much of I just but
you can't smoke a little bit of flour I
just didn't like that people seem to
think of him as safer right it's smoking
like that's a main reason why that
markets so popular
I get it you're not smoking not ruining
your lungs which brings me to another
part they limited potency on flowers to
20% and concentrates at 12 percent THC
potency 12 percent on a concentrate
that's the way I read it in the press
article didn't make a lot of sense how
do you have a concentrate with 12
percent in this Lizzy what I mentioned
just a minute ago that I think the
governor of Oklahoma may have been
listening to some of the National
anti-pot folks limiting THC potency is a
big thing project Sam's been pushing
they tried it in Colorado and failed
they tried it in Canada and failed
they've tried it in a couple of other
states and failed um and it looks like
they might have succeeded somewhat in
Oklahoma and Colorado they were going
for 12 or 16 percent o no cap for flower
yeah I do it would have reset the whole
industry right this is gonna the way I
read it had the plant potency and it
specified it is like your plant potency
can be 20 it didn't specify flower but
it made it seem like flower was included
in the 12% limit okay so when I've got a
plant at the end it can be or that plant
contested 20% but my final product
they're not gonna release flower because
flowers are illegal right or can you I
honestly don't know the rules in
Oklahoma or the proposed rules in
Oklahoma well enough to know if they
allow flowers to be sold for like with
the sticker on a this is to be vaped
only okay because like tabletop vapes
and flower shapes have been a thing for
a decade or right like well it sounds
like your flowers can only test it 20%
and you've got to turn them into a
concentrate that only tests at 12
percent THC what kind of sounds like
they allow home gross and so like so
there's gonna be plenty of flower out
and it's not like there's gonna be a
possible system for testing flower from
home grows that's going to take a long
time
that's a 20-year project folks so why do
you want to limit the amount of potency
I know because they don't want people
getting getting too high it's the
drumbeat that the anti pot one of the
the notes that they found that resonated
with people is the the weed of the 60s
was 1% G the we did today is 30 and the
concentrates go to 90 plus yeah I mean
it's a [ __ ] argument because the we
to the [ __ ] 60s was not 1% if you're
curious that number is comes from
including all da seizures which include
feral hemp in so like in 1964 they
rounded up a lot more feral hemp than
then rounded up pounds of Colombian herb
being shipped in and sold freely across
the country and that number got reported
down the chain to us today and so now
anti-pop people like it was 1% in 69
right here it says so in the book and I
bet they're testing labs back then we're
phenomenal well yeah in what gets tested
the stick the stand they just put the
whole thing in there yeah I have no idea
do they test it like they weigh it and
they're like we found this pound of weed
before an f-150 this [ __ ] 3500 pounds
of marijuana they tested it with the
f-150 attached to it we ground up the
f-150 and it came out 2.0 1% THC but its
THC that's how they do it but the [ __ ]
was I even talking about yeah but some
traits so much percentages the THC
potency we're getting way higher now
it's not our bombs we yeah the it's just
a [ __ ] argument that they've made
that resonates with people and my
argument against that is if I'm trying
to medicate and I'm just gonna make up
numbers here I don't I don't know the
numbers to my medication you know what I
mean this is just hypothetically if I'm
gonna medicate and I need to get to
let's say a thousand right would you
rather me take 10 inhalations of
something that's at a hundred or would
you rather me take
to inhalations of 500 as a medical
marijuana patient do you want me to
inhale and exhale smoke or vapor ten
times or two times which is healthier
for my lungs and body that's literally
like 50% of the reason concentrates
exist is the community wanted a way to
get rid of the actual combustion the
unhealthy part of the smoking yeah and
we found a way to do that and keep the
immediate kick of inhalation we get that
that immediate me it and you can titrate
it perfectly you take a puff you give it
30 seconds at most and nope I would like
another hit when the joint comes around
I'm gonna hit it again by the time the
joint comes around again you know no I'm
where I want to be nope I want a little
more nope that was a little too much yep
it's it's a beautiful system and we kept
it with vaping and we've it's just
gotten cleaner and cleaner and cleaner
and cleaner and healthier and healthier
and healthier it's also gotten a lot
scarier
and so the anti pop people are able to
get footage of somebody doing a DAB and
they go on the news and they're like
they're smoking 99% pure THC crystals if
they have to smoke with a blowtorch and
then they show that b-roll it scares the
[ __ ] out of church folk and then you get
12 percent THC limits because I'm
wondering how the [ __ ] they even do that
like if the flowers allowed at 20 like
the plants allowed at 20 what do they do
with that 20 percent product they've got
to cut it right yeah yes like keep
pouring propylene glycol on it until
it's a 12 so what is something like that
yeah I don't I really don't know how you
reduce your tomans like time for like if
this is gonna be real I know this is all
still in the process but if they're
trying to really go with some of these
rules you all might want to just pick a
day that's not 420 or 710 and get
together at the Capitol
just don't smoke don't [ __ ] wave
potli flags just show up let him know
why you're there and just [ __ ] sit in
the [ __ ] way for like three days but
they need somebody it takes a lot to get
these people to notice and if they some
of these rules are as far along as I
think they are like the day for writing
op-eds isn't past but like they have
another meeting planned but not
scheduled at the time that I wrote this
they had the meeting planned but not
scheduled to talk with the committee
that's working on this you know the
article I read said I want to say it was
like the Oklahoma Department of Health
and Human Services or somesuch
Department Oklahoma State Department of
Health yes that one when they release
these rules they kind of admitted that
they're not sure that they have the
authority to make a couple of these
rules like they might be totally out of
the scope of their purview but yeah so
if you guys this applies for everywhere
that is working on legalization and
we're running out of states that are
working on it we're getting it's a good
thing we're getting two more states that
are have got some sort of legalization
but if you're working on getting
cannabis legalized wherever you are get
somebody like Micra myself involved like
convince one of us that mikes easy to
get to a city council meeting to help
you write rules you need somebody that
is actually a consumer that's actually
doing this you wouldn't you wouldn't
call I'm trying to make a weird weird
[ __ ] analogies you wouldn't call your
math teacher to teach you how to work
the buzzsaw and you wouldn't call your
shop teacher to teach you how to do math
get them get some people that are in the
industry up here talking about cannabis
with these people that are making the
rules so when they say so we're gonna do
plants at 20% concentrates at twelve I
can laugh and shake my head and go wait
you guys have no idea what the [ __ ]
you're talking about we can straighten
them out before it gets this far so we
got to get we got to get somebody on our
team in these meetings everywhere when
we did the the Oklahoma in Canada
episode I stressed like the time to get
involved is now in in Oklahoma the time
to get involved like now is now past
tense
yeah it's that was like a month ago you
might have to deal with it right now
you're late but continuing to not act is
still a bad choice start writing op-eds
to any local paper any state paper you
can contact the governor you can contact
the state deported out the Board of
Health or whatever that committee is you
can email all these people directly and
let them know hey I voted for this these
are the reasons why these are why
explicitly these specific rules are bad
here's what I would like to see instead
you can do it like three or four
paragraphs you don't have to do the hi
my name is here's why I give a [ __ ] you
can just get right to the meteor issue
hi governor so-and-so I'm writing to you
about blank law
I don't like blank rule I think it
should be this instead so I don't like
the THC caps I think there should be no
limit like it isn't at most of the other
functioning medical marijuana states if
you want help wording that feel free to
contact me on mobile for sensible
cannabis laws on Facebook there you go
follow them on pablo for sensible
cannabis laws on facebook support that
you can get updates from Mike speaking
of updates I've got another message from
our friend in Oklahoma that's telling me
what's going on he says there is another
meeting in August the Health Department
will meeting get meet again and then
they will have elections coming up in
November so I'm betting before that
meeting there will be a period for open
comment and then at that meeting
there'll be a portion for public comment
and it will be one of those fun public
meetings that goes for twelve and a half
hours but during the portion for open
public comment you just email them and
then your email gets distributed to the
whole committee and everybody's supposed
to read them and getting messages across
that way if you get a group of people to
do it and most of them are functional
communicators you can get a lot of good
change made that way
folks in Oklahoma now's the time to
start emailing those folks find who you
need to email in your locality in your
state find who you need to email in the
state your state rep and let them know
that how you want these medical
marijuana laws adjusted now's the time
to start doing that so start sending out
the emails start going to the meetings
if you hear anything about a meeting
about medical marijuana go attend it be
a part of it
rally the troops just go and listen like
that's all you have to do to start is
just go and listen and start writing
emails please he also says no grows or
dispensaries until August which means
most of the zoning rules and all of that
haven't been finalized yet either which
means people need to start watching for
those briefs in the local paper if
you're in Oklahoma right now you should
be able to like look up your city or
town or County or whatever they call it
there and find your government's webpage
and say you live in Tulsa you should be
able to look up the Tulsa City
government's webpage and on there
they'll have their agenda listed for
every week and scanning through those
agendas is where I found the meat of all
of the zoning rule making hearings here
in Pueblo that stuff didn't make the
paper until the day of usually or if it
made the paper at all it would be in a
past tense like by the way on Monday you
missed right this happened at this
meeting you didn't get to but after two
or three weeks of just checking back
with the Pueblo City the city of Puebla
webpage I figured out that when they
uploaded their new thing every week and
then I just checked back
I can't think it was Monday's check back
Monday at like noon and scan through it
real quick to see if they had anything
that pertained to us and when they did
I'd made sure I was there to the point
where I haven't been in a while and City
Council members that have been there for
a while
been asking about where's Mike is he
okay you just disappeared Mike's got a
kid and a brand new kid so Mike's a
little bit distracted folks that's where
he is yeah two kids it's a lot there's a
lot to keep you moving will do thanks
for coming and doing a podcast with us
oh it's good to have you here every so
often the folks do like your presence on
the show they like it when we ramble so
potency what what the hell with the
potency is a [ __ ] up rule y'all yeah
and that's it just isn't it doesn't just
suck for customers the reason the
anti-pop people are pushing that is
because it cripples businesses when you
grow out of a strain of cannabis the
potency can vary wildly based on a dozen
different factors your 30% killer arise
like what if I grow it it just there's
so many things that go into it when want
to crop harvests you have no idea if
you've got a 16 or if you've got a 30
and if you send half of your crop off
too early to send off all your testing
samples and half of them come back over
20 if you've got to destroy all that
product yeah
like business can't operate like that
especially not with the federal tax laws
on top of our throats and that's part of
what sets business apart here in
Colorado it's I'm not like this because
it's not how I shop but when you walk
into a dispensary you hear half the
people say what's your highest testing
product what's got the most THC a that's
what I want to buy it right now give me
that I don't care what it looks like I
don't care what it smells like I want
the most THC a that I'm leaving so
that's kind of a selling point you want
those 30s those 32 s 33 and 34 such it's
hard to find but when you find him that
that's what the people want to buy yep
so that's like kind of a you're taking a
strategy away from the market right
there yep it uh it's not just a strategy
away from the market it's just because
then the sales pitches we've got 1999
like come get your 1999 with us come to
chair eleven nine nine with us I would
have to make mistakes to grow 20% THC a
flowers right I just not feed it any new
tree we'd have to cut it down weeks
early
yeah I really cut it down a week seven
but uh none of the genetics would be
able to work there
it's a rule they're pimping by design
like it's this is a thought out strategy
it's not something they've stumbled upon
because they're scared they're able to
sell it because it scares people that
won't look into it very deeply but
that's I mean it's just one of the rules
that they're pushing right now they they
they also want it like the skull in the
crossbones and the three pages of
warnings right product yeah yeah yeah
well if they get it figured out down
there let's move on to the socionics you
guys forgetting I figure it out I hope
you guys keep going to meetings and get
it dialed in because what you got right
now is gonna be a challenge yep let's
move forward I've got another subject
here a while back there was whoa I just
let's make sure we didn't just kill that
recording we're still going saying well
back there was a chain of dispensaries
that got in trouble for doing a thing
that was called looping what looping is
is basically in the state of Colorado a
recreational cannabis purchaser is
allowed to buy one ounce of recreational
cannabis per day one uno i'ts one out to
get one and if so what was happening
these guys were buying their one ounce
they were going out to the car I don't
know what was really happening but then
they were coming back within the same
business day and they were buying more
ounces well and for a long time in
Colorado the law specifically says I can
sell you one ounce of marijuana per
transaction
the law says transaction that's the word
in the law and so four years in Colorado
transaction was the practice to most
stores didn't care if you came in bought
your limit came back in five or ten or
30 minutes bought your limit again and
left they just enjoyed the extra sale
that's that's what looping is that's
where this stemmed from eventually the
marijuana Enforcement Division and the
Colorado Department of Revenue realized
the
this was kind of a loophole so they sent
out a memo saying you cannot do this
anymore
at that point most dispensaries stopped
they formed they formed a group to
change the law and make the one ounce
per day official law and then they sent
out a memo saying the law that we're
gonna pass in January goes into effect
in August and the marijuana industry
operating under the rules that they do
most of the industry complied because
when we get a memo from the meed we just
say sir yes sir how many would you like
sir yeah like we don't ask questions we
don't ask for clarification we just try
really hard to do whatever they say
that's a great segue into the article
that I'm about to read this is why the
industry kisses the Emmy B's ass a
little bit this article comes from a
website called Mary Jane comm it's Emmy
rry Jane comm Mary Jane excuse me for
the throat-clearing in this episode we
talked about all the dads really this
article is written by a person who was
named Chris Moore and it goes like this
sweet leaf lost all of its been fur
based cannabis licenses for looping or
selling more than weed per customer yeah
26 licenses I read the article one of
them caught one of Colorado's largest
cannabis enterprises just lost the right
to do business in Denver after getting
busted for selling unlawful amounts of
weed to their customers sweet leaf this
is successful can a company operating a
number of legally license cultivation
and processing facilities as well as
dispensaries all across the state was
the subject of a year-long investigation
by local authorities working to track
down on loop to crack down on looping
the practice of selling customers more
marijuana than state law allows I'm
gonna kind of skim over this cuz it's
longer than I wanted to go but I've got
to get you all the main points we talked
about Colorado customers can only buy
one ounce per day sweet leaf argued they
reportedly use justification to let
customers purchase more than legally
allowed police raided eight stores in
Denver in March and in April Denver
officials held hearings on disciplinary
actions against stores accused of
looping Siddeley City Attorney showed up
with
of evidence against sweet leaf including
video of undercover cops purchasing
prohibited amounts of weed from their
stores as well as interviews with the
company's employees he estimated the
attorneys estimated that one single
sweet leaf dispensary made over one
thousand looping transactions netting
the company an additional four million
dollars
there's a reason companies were willing
to do this yeah for million dollars it
sounds like a decent reason but look it
bit him in the ass then it says this
week the Denver department of excise and
licenses revoked all 26 of sweet leaves
medical marijuana and recreational
marijuana licenses effectively
preventing the company from continuing
to do business in the city of Denver see
that's what happens you guys we're not
[ __ ] around everyone thinks we're
just hanging out getting high the G can
come in and buy a bunch of weed and then
just hang out take a couple of dabs in
the back with the people that work there
no brother you [ __ ] up they'll come in
and take all of your licensing is in
Denver is five thousand Alliance so they
were paying one hundred and thirty
thousand a year to the city and one
hundred thirty thousand a year to the
state for those licenses they lost just
to have the licenses just I have yeah
they were making an additional four
million through looping what were they
making through those twenty six
facilities without looping they were one
of the largest outfits in Colorado yeah
they were huge everybody knew who
sweetleaf was several grows several
stores the company does have the right
to appeal the decision they also still
have licenses not in Denver yes that is
actually they have a location in Oregon
somewhere they've got one in Aurora I
think they've got one in Thornton there
might be one in Colorado Springs anyway
I'm gonna keep reading the article
there's like two short paragraphs left
it says enforcing rules when violations
occur occur is an essential part of
Denver's successful regulation of one of
the largest legalized marijuana markets
in the world
Kilroy said in a statement reported by
the westward suite leaves the illegal
actions undermine the entire regulatory
framework created by amendment 64 the
journal Assembly and the Denver City
Council the decision supports the will
of the voters for a regulated legal
Merrill
on a market safeguards the legal
marijuana industry and protects the
safety and welfare of the public
like Mike said sweet leaf still runs
three other dispensaries in the state
which are not affected by this ruling
and will remain open many of the
company's bud tenders have been arrested
in connection with the investigation but
the majority of them have now been
released without criminal charges so you
guys if you mess around with em Edie
they will come rager stores it will take
the bud tenders to jail a lot of people
were taken straight to jail a lot of
them were released some of them did face
charges then they will shut down your
business there's a lot of talk that this
story isn't over yet this was sort of a
death blow to the company but they still
have several locations they I'm guessing
they've still got at least one or two
grows going they're certainly not
completely dead right ah and with that
many bud tenders arrested that many bud
tenders set free with no charges and
currently no management or ownership has
been charged with a single thing like
this story definitely has the potential
to go on for longer if they're just
compiling and thinking still giving in a
minute and letting the Rope sit there
and waiting to see what kind of knot you
tie at the end of it all right well if
anybody sticks their head through the
end of that knot we will definitely let
you guys know sweet leaf no more in
Denver nope
did do you see the story this week you
saw that the public consumption buses
got [ __ ] with in Denver right yes
there was one day where Denver somebody
I think it was a multi-agency Saudi PD
and the meed and a couple of other
groups got together and they raided two
of the buses and they gave everybody
public consumption tickets and [ __ ]
cited the driver and cited the company
for basically hosting an unlicensed
consumption event and then left like
there weren't like mass arrests the
company didn't have to bail for
tourists on every County or anything but
it was announced this week that that was
because of the CNN footage from New
Year's Eve oh that makes sense where CNN
reporter was flashing the [ __ ] gas
masks bong and [ __ ] Mike said
consumption bus some folks may not know
what those words mean like that
consumption bus what so a while back
Colorado decided that it was illegal to
consume links drivers blocked off like
they're in their own airtight chamber
away from the rest of the fun bus so
Colorado outlawed smoking in a public
place you can't we can't smoke at
gatherings anymore that are indoors
that's not allowed
but you can rent a private bus and pull
it up right outside of the club and let
people that are 21 and over onto that
bus and then they can bring their own
concentrates and they can smoke out in
the bus or at least that's been
happening on the regular for five years
now yeah we thought that that was cool
but on New Year's a reporter came and
did a little article and featured one of
the buses and was like hey look we're
doing this
and so that triggered the marijuana
Enforcement Division the Denver
Department of the Denver Police
Department and whoever else decided to
jump in that day they decided one night
to go and take down a couple of the
private party consumption buses so they
were they were working on this big case
for like six bucking monster took him
six months to go hit the consumption bus
yeah they take their time when they're
busted stoners they knew they weren't
going anywhere on the bus who knew where
to find him it's it's one of those
things where it was so poorly done on
law enforcement it's part of like the
companies are [ __ ] through suing the
city and hourlies threatening to they're
not at all amused their lawyers are
pissed right this has been going on for
years now if somebody had a problem with
it a letter in the first six months of
operation would've taken care of it it
has lessened the need or desire for me
to illegally consume cannabis inside
a venue if I'm seeing a reggae band and
I know that the dab bus is right outside
and I'll just go out there and take a
DAB you know there's no need to smoke a
joint illegally in the reggae show I
just go out there and take a quick dab
between bands and come right back in and
see the concert I'm part of me still
just kind of pissed that we have to have
this fight still yeah right like we've
we legalized marijuana it's been common
practice to consume marijuana it big
public gatherings for I can't even tell
you how long literally every [ __ ]
concert I've ever been to since the time
I was five there ought to be a place at
every concert venue where it's like oh
you want to smoke a joint can you please
just go over to section K right like yep
it's it shouldn't be that hard like Oh
reggae band playing at the bar tonight
[ __ ] if you want a smokes run up to
the roof yeah like it's we don't need
[ __ ] special buses but apparently we
needed special buses and now they're not
even sure if we can have the buses like
it's just such a headache
yep so again guys I know I always talk
about writing rules and being involved
in legislation sure there's consumption
room make sure there's somewhere that
you can consume when you write your new
rules bring that up get that on the
books all right I don't have a couple
shout outs big shot it's my friend Matty
II a special shout out to Sam and a big
fat shout out to Justin Aldridge
thanks for all the love and support you
guys I know that was random right good
segue right there
nice looking me like why you shot people
randomly just got to show some people
some love and tell them thank you you
know why the other awesome you'd
probably earned it they know what they
did alright so you guys gonna get get
some consumption laws on the books when
you guys go right in the rules for your
locality it might be got anything else
to say well you've got a whole bunch of
people listening to you I'm just city to
check then because once again the
takeaway from the white Mike episode is
get involved yes always get involved get
involved get yourself involved because
uh when you're not involved people write
[ __ ] rules like xx so easy to do with
the technology you have in your pocket
when you get home from work after
listening to this show and you've got
two seconds
you can just fire off a quick email to
all of your elected representatives in
support of whatever legalization laws in
your area it's literally that simple it
takes three minutes and like a minute
and a half of that is trying to pick
which two words to Google to get you the
right governor it's not hard folks just
we need more of the community to get
involved like we were too good at hiding
for too goddamn long yeah now it's time
to speak up you know time to speak up
dude they they can't come for all of us
like yeah like when it's just one dude
standing up talking like that guys
[ __ ] like but there's 30 million of us
like if we all stand up and we all fight
just a little bit like we win so quickly
there you go I like Mike style let's all
stand up and fight email whoo you need
to show up to the meetings you need to
go to let's speak out you guys make sure
you follow Mike he's got a Facebook page
it is Pueblo for sensible cannabis laws
check him out send him a message let him
know that you found him through the girl
from our podcast he loves the
interaction also stalk him on the
tweeter he's at Nemo punk 15 I like
seeing people tweet him on there that's
always certainly and tagging the show
and Mike it's always fun
hey dude thanks for coming and hanging
out I know you got two kids and a wife
at home so this was awesome late night
podcast might be the way to do this yeah
it was kind of fun super quiet out there
too yo Oh
shout it to the rain yeah it's raining
for the guy feels like the second time
all summer it's probably like the fourth
time so hot we needed some rain when I
felt the rain out there it was so
relieving all right quit talking about
the weather we'll start wrapping up this
podcast have a great night everybody
thanks for listening you guys make sure
you support the show on patreon you can
find that at patreon.com slash girl from
your heart make sure you follow me on
Facebook simply search for the girl from
our podcast stalk me on Instagram look
for Irie underscore genetics also follow
the show on Twitter it's at g f YH
podcast you can also stalk me on the
tweeter if you'd like to it's a trusted
Jeff 420 if you've got something you'd
like to say and you're not into the
social media or perhaps you've got a
product you'd like me to review maybe
you'd like to sponsor the podcast you
can send me an email let's grow from
your heart at hotmail.com ladies and
gentlemen make sure you subscribe to the
podcast on youtube that's right just
search for
the girl from your heart podcast on
YouTube give me a little subscribe on
there I would appreciate that I think
that's all I've got for you I'll be back
in a couple days with a very highly
detailed episode I think I got six pages
of notes for the next podcast again this
one looks intense folks there's a lot of
notes for that one so thanks for hanging
out for this one thanks for letting Mike
and I ramble at you thanks again to Mike
for hanging out big shout out to Mike's
wife roulette might come play judge the
little guys for kind of giving him the
free moment I hope they're resting I
hope they're being cool for long god I
hope so this is a when we start to
record I put my cell phone on silent and
I try not to look at it and I haven't
touched it this whole show I have no
idea what's happened to way from finding
out if there's a tornado in your house
or not yeah
alright you guys we're gonna wrap it up
I wanna give a huge shout out to my
friend James but ursin and until next
time take a phat dab and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]