yo what's up podcast world it's Rasta
Jeff before we get the show started let
me make a quick disclaimer and sort of
an apology I feel like I recorded a
solid podcast episode I put my heart and
soul into this I wrote a lot of notes
it's been a lot of time recording this
show as I was listening back to edit
parts of the audio files started
disappearing I don't know what was
happening to my computer or my software
but the words I was saying we're
disappearing from the [ __ ] screen as
time went on the more I tried to play
with the computer and edit and figure
out what happened the more [ __ ] was
disappearing so it was making my podcast
vanish
one paragraph at a time you guys the
podcast you're gonna get has some
missing chunks and I don't know what
went wrong I apologize I'm embarrassed
I'm frustrated it's nearly 130 and I owe
you a Thursday episode I want to put
this out so that you know I at least
tried and I didn't let you down ah if
you really want to know what I said in
those parts that are missing I'll do my
best to go back and kind of piece it
together but honestly it's driving me
nuts so this is what I've got to offer
you and I apologize for the half-ass
podcast there will be times when the
audio drops out just be patient
keep listening it'll come back hopefully
you don't miss too much this episode is
all about building a drip system or an
automated water system excuse me for
that also it's getting late so if you're
not into that you're not gonna miss a
lot if you're really into building an
auto water system and you miss stuff in
here let me know and we'll try to get it
together for you you guys my throat's
burned out it's late
I'm gonna take some dabs and get some
sleep I love you here's my podcast yeah
welcome back cannabis community it's
time for another episode of the girl
from your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
I try to fear a new grower if you're a
professional grower if you're a new
smoker or a dedicated dabber if you're a
cannabis activists or even someone who
is just curious about the current state
of cannabis this my friends is the
podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me this episode of the podcast
is brought to you by my friends at the
Hell a dank seed company if you need new
genetics for your garden I highly
recommend the hella dank seed company
you can find them
thank seed dot store ladies and
gentlemen
roll up a fat joint pack up the bong or
start heating up that dab rig because
it's time for another episode of the
grill from your heart a podcast yo
what's up weed world it's time for
episode 335 of the girl from your heart
podcast thanks again for joining me I've
got a lot to talk about in this episode
so I'm going to try and make this intro
quick I like to start the show off by
letting you know what I'm smoking on
today I've been taking dabs of the cam
Brule full-spectrum extract from our
friends at Green Dot labs this is the
copper chem cross two lemon brulee it is
described as rotten lemon rind and sour
fuel and I think that is a perfect
description it tastes delicious the dabs
are nice and smooth the high goes
straight to the eyes it's a straight
head high I love what it did to my head
the dad was super smooth it tastes
really good and the consistency the
appearance and the texture are perfect
so big shout out to our friends at green
dot labs for the chem Brule full
spectrum extract it is Rasta Jeff
approved all right you guys we've got a
lot of stuff to talk about I am going to
run you guys through building a drip
system or an automated or assisted
watering system for your grow I'm going
to do two different versions I'm gonna
do a setup using kind of like a water
wand to set up to where you have a wand
and you water each plant with this wand
but it will be set up to a reservoir so
you're being fed then we're also going
to run through a set up using emitters
or sprinklers in each plant both of
these setups could be useful to you it's
up to you to decide which set up you
like in veg I usually use the water wand
in flower that's when I switch to the
auto or assisted watering system a lot
of what I'm saying will need to be
customized for your grow this will need
to be custom tailored for your setup
everything will need to be custom
measured for your grow this is going to
be a very good guideline on how to get
you started building a drip system all
right this will be useful for any size
grow anywhere from one light to 500
lights these ideas will work for you
they just may need to be modified again
I'm gonna talk about two different
setups I'm gonna talk about a drip
system with the emitters for each plant
and we're gonna talk about a water wand
a reservoir on a pump style setup once I
get into it it will be more clear which
setup is best for you they've both got
their benefits they've both got their
downfalls let's talk about benefits of
using a drip watering or assisted
watering system one of the first obvious
advantages or benefits to using a drip
or auto watering or assisted watering
system is that it simply makes watering
more efficient and it takes less time
which will free up a grower to do things
like work the canopy or defoliate or
scout for bugs or simply clean up things
that have been getting overlooked so
building an auto watering system will
free up time no matter how big your grow
is this should save you some time so
that is the first benefit in a large
facility this will free you up a lot of
time if you've got a thousand plants
you'll go from spending all day watering
plants to just a couple of hours
watering every single plant you'll have
to mix up solution it's probably two
hundred and fifty two maybe a thousand
gallons of water in some facilities you
have to mix it you have to adjust the pH
you got to make sure your PPM's are good
you got to write down everything you put
in there make sure your filter is clean
and then he hit go on the pump and you
turn the valve for the right room and
make sure that water pumps into the
right room and then while it's pumping
you run up and down the rows and make
sure that each emitter is spraying out
some water and as long as every plants
getting water you're good you let it
spray until all that water is empty
while those plants are getting fed you
walk through and you make sure all the
emitters are working but also be looking
for pests be looking for powdery mildew
be looking for something that just
doesn't look right
find the problem in the room there's
always something that can be fixed or
corrected be in the room looking for
that while the sprinklers are running
also catch a little bit of the water
catch some of the runoff that comes out
of the plants the stuff that comes out
of the bottom of the pots gather that
measure the pH measure the EC of that
and start writing that down and in the
future we've talked about this we can
diagnose problems by what you have
written down we talked about in the
journaling episode so while the
sprinklers are running that's why you
need to be doing checking on the plants
and catching a little bit of water
now we've freed up a lot of time to work
the canopy check for bugs do some
defoliating you don't have to spend all
day watering and while the plants are
getting watered we're actually in there
looking for bugs and making sure the
emitters are working
so we freed up a lot of time and we're
still getting plenty of work done while
we're watering another advantage to
having an automated or assisted watering
system is this will make sure that all
of your plants get evenly watered you
won't have one plant that got two
pitchers of water dumped on it cuz
somebody got a text message in the
middle of watering and the rest of the
plants only got one pitcher of water you
won't get a row of plants that got
skipped because you were doing a job and
then you saw something that had to be
fixed and you went corrected that and
then came back and moved on to the next
row and totally forgot to water a row
things like that won't happen the plants
will get evenly watered this will also
help reduce waste and water and
nutrients when you're running a large
facility you're using a lot of water and
a lot of nutrients this will help reduce
waste and this will also help you save
on nutrients you won't have a an
employee spraying like I said earlier
two gallons into this plant three
gallons into this pot four gallons into
this one when they all honestly only
needed to they'll be consistent and you
won't have guys wasting water which is
wasting nutrients all right another
thing that will help not only are they
going to get the same amount of water
but they will get evenly watered you
won't have a guy just watering one spot
of the plant what I've seen a lot is
when you have a crew watering plants
with watering wands and it takes them
all day to water the whole room they
start working and then eventually they
just set the tip of the wand right on
the plant right on the soil they just
hit go they know how long they gotta
count it's about 30 45 seconds you count
and then the plant will be sufficiently
watered then you move on to the next one
the type of [ __ ] won't happen if you use
emitters the guy won't set his water
wand right there and water that one
circle real heavy the emitter will spray
the entire surface you'll get water
throughout that whole pot the roots will
grow through the whole entire space of
the container and all of the media not
just down low where all the water got
saturated so that's a big advantage
they'll get evenly watered they'll get
watered all the way through where they
need to be they'll get saturated and it
will reduce your amount of waste another
advantage to using one of these systems
is that the emitters and the water wand
actually do add a little bit of oxygen
to the water all of those bubbles are a
good thing the more oxygen in your water
the better the more oxygen in your root
zone the better the roots will of the
oxygen so the emitters they put out that
little mist those are little bubbles
there's a lot of air in there
a lot of air making it a lot of space
between the bubbles means there's a lot
of air making it down into the root zone
even the watering wands they make a
couple of nice little shower patterns
those get a lot of air down into the
root zone that is very helpful the
plants do enjoy that you can also add an
air pump if you want to add some sort of
air stones to your reservoir or to your
trash can we'll talk about that in a
minute
you can add oxygen to it the plants will
thank you for it you can never go wrong
adding more oxygen to the water in my
opinion all right those are the basic
advantages to using an automated system
using an automated system or a drip
system or an assisted watering system is
not an excuse for laziness like I said
earlier there's plenty to inspect and
look at and check on while the watering
system is happening you can also inspect
the watering system itself you need to
make sure there are no leaks make sure
the filter is clean make sure the
emitters are spraying where is the water
draining to do you have a drain set up
is that clogged are you getting water
all over the floor there are so many
other tasks available that you just made
time to get done by creating this drip
system now sometimes people have an
automated system or a drip system setup
to water the plants for when they go on
vacation or if they've got to leave for
an extended amount of time or if they've
got an emergency or something so like
imagine being sick and you're not able
to water your plants like one time I had
the flu real bad and I couldn't even
stand up every time I stood up I would
puke it was a real challenge watering
the garden that day for a couple of days
if I had an auto watering system I could
have just filled up my reservoir and
then hit the button
and those plants would've got watered
and I could have went back to bed and
not felt like [ __ ] for those hours it
took me to water my plants that's just
kind of a random use I'm just trying to
throw out examples of why they're useful
imagine if you wanted to go away you
wanted to go to Vegas for a few days and
have a little bit of fun you want to go
on Phish tour for a week and have a
little bit of fun but you got a crop at
home that might die you don't trust
anybody around to water it you don't
need anybody coming in and out of your
house maybe nobody else knows about your
grow you can set up a small watering
system it will take care of those plants
for you while you're gone also Auto
watering systems could be helpful for
people with physical limitations imagine
if you're unable to lift a lot of water
you can't carry the water maybe your
mobility is limited maybe you're in a
wheelchair and you can't
between each plan maybe you've got
limited mobility in some sort of way I
don't know what's going on but this
could be a way that you can grow some
cannabis you can have somebody come help
you once a week maybe set up your girl
for you get your drip system set up get
your reservoir set up and then all you
have to do is go in there and press the
button and you can water those plants
every day and that way you can tend to
your garden you can minimize the
physical work that has to be done and
you can still grow a little bit of
cannabis for yourself if you're
physically limited so this would be
useful for that sort of a situation also
these setups are customizable and
expandable everything I'm going to teach
you is just from my limited experience
building drip systems and commercial
grows and in-home grows don't think that
these are rules you can expand on this
any way you'd like you can customize
this any way you'd like I may be totally
wrong for your setup maybe I've sparked
some ideas maybe I've started an
argument I'm just trying to show you
what I'm doing and get you started and
then you can build it perfectly for your
grow it's honestly easier than you might
think
to build an auto watering or an assisted
watering system the first step to
building anything or upgrading anything
in your grow is to have a plan do you
have a solid plan can you put this plan
on paper if so write it down draw the
plan let's see what you're thinking so
that you can share it and we can work on
it together and we both know the goal so
have a plan have a goal and also have a
reason why are you doing this so what's
your what's your purpose why are you
trying to build a watering system now
you know why okay
what's your goal are you trying to make
it easier you're trying to be able to go
on vacation there we go now you know why
you're doing it and what your goal is
know let's build a plan on how to do it
let's think about how many plants you
want to water are you watering one light
do you have nine you have twelve you
have sixteen plants are you trying to
water a whole bunch of stuff do you have
a four by eight table with maybe 12 or
24 plants in there you have a whole row
of [ __ ] with a hundred and 25 plants
let's think about how many sites were
gonna need how many emitters do we need
let's also think about are we going to
use emitters or do we want to use a
water wand if you've got a small system
and you liked being interactive with the
plants a water wand is not a bad idea
it's always nice and personal if you're
going from hand watering to a water wand
you're still gonna save
and you're still gonna get that
interactive feeling with your plants
they're gonna be in there touching each
plant watering each plant we get near
each plant with the water wand you'll
have to move the leaves off the bottom
surface you can get to the soil then
you'll have to water you'll still get to
play with the plants if you use the wand
if you've got a small system that's a
great way to go if you've got a bigger
system I would definitely recommend
using the emitters so once you've made
your decision on the water wand or the
emitters then it's time to draw and
design and actually build your watering
system I'm gonna start with building a
watering wand and a can watering setup
this is real simple this is what I would
recommend for a small to medium-sized
home grow or a small commercial grow or
maybe a small or large veg room for a
commercial grow but this is how I would
do it for my reservoir I use a brute
trashcan from the hardware store it's a
brand new cleaned out trash can I think
it's a 25 or 32 gallon I think it's a 32
gallon it looks like a Rubbermaid trash
can it says brute right on the side of
it I measured out to where 10 15 20 and
25 gallons go so I know exactly how far
I'm filling it at the hardware store
right next to these big trash cans they
sell the little wheels that attach to
the bottom get those wheels now you can
fill your can up and you can roll it to
wherever you need it you can get it
closer to the plants or you can get it
over to the nutrients it's just much
easier to handle when you've got that
thing on wheels I found that sometimes
it can be hard to fill this big-ass
trash can because your bathtub
the [ __ ] what is it the bathtub water
comes out real low I don't know the word
for that thing or the bathtub water
comes out the past of water the [ __ ]
faucet there we go that thing is real
low right it's down there by the bathtub
so it could fill the bathtub then up top
the shower heads up real high and you
can only adjust the angle so much unless
you've got the kind that comes off and
you got the the master baiter showerhead
but otherwise you're gonna have a hard
time getting the water into this
reservoir at the hardware store I found
a thing that is used for washing your
dog it's a the dog washer screws in
where the shower head goes and then it
adds an extra port with a hose coming
off so you take off the shower head you
screw in the dog washer then you screw
the shower head right back on it only
adds about an inch worth
get on to it I don't even notice that
but then it's got a pork coming off the
side that's where this dog washer hose
comes off of this other dog washer hose
has a shower head on it with an on and
off switch so you basically turn on the
shower and then the water starts coming
out of this dog washer basically the dog
washer is just a shower head on on us on
a [ __ ] hose so that you can move it
you can drop that right into your
reservoir and you can fill it up it
makes it so much easier for me because
my shower
it wouldn't spray into the reservoir
without hitting the floor and the
bathtub want is way too low right now I
feel like I'm trying to describe
something crazy and I probably sound
like it but once you get to this point
you're gonna go oh that's what he meant
this one's eight feet off the ground and
this one's two feet off the ground and
my trashcan is about four feet tall so I
get it also I should mention this thing
didn't mess with my shower at all once
you pop off the hose for the dog washer
and your showers becomes a normal shower
it won't disrupt your shower setup at
all I do recommend that you remove the
dog washer attachment a little the whole
hose part just take it off up there at
the the port because if you leave it
hanging for too long that tension that
it creates just from gravity just swing
in there for so long after a while it
will develop a leak right there where it
connects so that's my advice you guys
it's gonna be so much easier to fill
your reservoir I also use this thing to
clean things because my showerhead and
that shower doesn't come off it's it's
attached to the wall it's affixed so I
needed one that I could pull off and I
just clean stuff with it I kind of use
it like a little dishwasher and I just
wash a bunch of [ __ ] I put a thing in
the bottom of that shower so nothing
goes down
I guess that's a random sidenote you
guys be versatile be a [ __ ] MacGyver
in your grow room you don't always have
to buy something that says grow room on
it you don't always have to buy
something from one of the grow companies
it doesn't always have to come from
Hydrofarm or Sun systems or something
like that you can reappropriation tight
um's I just used a dog washer to clean
my pots and fill my reservoir and guess
what I also did I cleaned the dog with
it all right I better stay focused
because I've got a lot of notes and I'm
only through the first page here let's
keep going the dog washer the next part
if you're using ro you'll need to get
the water into the reservoir that you
can drop your Maundy pump into we're
gonna talk about a Maundy pump here in
just a minute
but if you're using RO water for either
system the water wand or the emitter
system you're going to need a way to get
that water into your reservoir that
we're able to get a pump into that we
can mix the nutrients into and then feed
the plants from there so you may already
have it pumping into a large reservoir
I'm not sure what you've got setup I
have no idea what your girl looks like
now but you're gonna need to collect
that RO water if you choose to use RO
water you're gonna need to get that into
this big reservoir that will then feed
to the plants so think about that while
you're designing your set up getting the
source water to the reservoir is
something that is often overlooked by
grow room designers by contractors
everyone's like so then we run the water
from the res to the plants and then you
go where does that water come from they
go oh [ __ ] we never piped water into
here so I'm just trying to remind you
now think about how you're going to get
either your municipal water or your RO
water into your reservoir so that we can
mix it up and then finally get it to
these plants alright so we've got the
water to our trash can which is we're
gonna be calling that a reservoir now
that is now a reservoir maybe you're
using a fancy expensive reservoir that's
up to you whatever you want to budget
for whatever you can fit through the
door some of those reservoirs don't fit
through the door make sure it fits
through your doorway make sure you can
get it into your gross space so get your
res get it filled with water know how
much water is in there now this is how I
get the water to the plants I get a
small sump pump the growth stores carry
the pump called the Monte that I keep
talking about it's a Mon D half
horsepower sump pump those pumps are
great because they come with a 3/4 inch
garden hose
Gromit attached to it all you have to do
is screw on a garden hose and you're
ready to rock so I like those Maundy
pumps you've got a trash can on wheels
but the Maundy pump in it I attach a
standard garden hose based on the length
that you need to reach your plants I
remember the cans on wheels so we can
move it but also the pump needs to be
plugged in you may need an extension
cord you may need a longer hose this is
where you've got to do thinking on your
own are you gonna roll that can down the
aisle with you or are you gonna have a
whole bunch of hose to coil up and drag
that hose all over the place where is
your electricity for the pump coming
from those are things to keep in mind
right now so you got a rolling can
that's marked for volume so you know how
much water is in it you've got a Maundy
pump it's the half horsepower Maundy
pump they're yellow they're really
common at the gross part if you search
Maundy sump pump half horsepower you'll
find it pops up on Amazon it's all over
the internet it's at every gross store
these are easy to find so you got your
rolling can mark for volume you got your
pump in there you've got your regular
garden hose coming off of there
now you need some way to control the
flow and direct the water because once
you plug in that pump the water is just
gonna shoot out of the hose there's
gonna be no control of it you can't turn
it off you can't stop it you can crimp
the hose but other than that it's just
gonna keep flowing so we need some way
to control this water this part is where
we get the water wand it's basically the
thing at the end of the hose remember
when your old man would be out there
water in the lawn at the beer in one
hand cigarette and the other and that
sprayer
just water in the lawn just spraying the
one was wet he's just not there sporanox
he didn't want to be around everybody
he just got their water remember that
thing that he had to water the lawn with
it's basically that thing but longer
it's got a longer nozzle on it that you
used to aim the water and control it to
get into the pot so that you're not just
spraying randomly it directs it into the
pots it's got an adjustable head or an
adjustable shower head on it you could
put it on a fan you can put it on shower
there's mist there's always flood
there's just a bunch of different
settings on it I usually like the shower
version if you want it to go faster
take off that unscrew the cover that
changes the settings and it'll just come
out real hard and we call that the dump
truck just let it just flow just cut
down the flow it's still useful because
use that water want as an off-and-on
switch and it reaches into the plants
it's got a nice extended arm so that's
what that's for
so use that thing the water wand
basically you can get them on Amazon you
can get them at the gross store you can
get them at the hardware store excuse me
for the throat clearing you can get
these water wands in a lot of different
styles one thing I think is you really
get what you pay for when it comes to a
water wand if you get a cheapo it's
gonna fall apart the off and on trigger
is gonna break on you really quickly if
you get a good expensive one you'll feel
the difference in the quality in the
trigger and the off and on switch and
the overall construction you'll just be
able to tell it's better made and it
will last you longer keep in mind that
some of them are adjustable a lot of
times where they're adjustable they like
to become lis Keable some of them are
too short some of them are too long I
like the kind that you can pivot the
head or not pivot but at least change
the angle of the head
some of them are kind of hard to squeeze
now that I think about it so if you
don't have a good squeeze power if
you're not uh if you're not in a
squeezing a hard trigger you might want
to find one that takes a little less
squeeze power I kind of like the one
that's got the lever you pull it up and
then it's on and then you'd push it down
and it goes off you adjust the flow by
using that lever how high up and down
you go it's not just a trigger I turn it
on to about three-quarters of the way
and I can get excuse me I can get from
this pot to this pot quickly enough for
I don't even have to turn it off for I
don't feel like I spilled enough water
on the floor anywhere to actually be a
problem so I've got it set to about
three quarters and I'm just water this
plant give it as long as it needs and
there just jump right over to this one
without even turning it off but then
when I'm ready to go when I'm done and I
want to carry the wand back to the hose
I just hit that off switch all the way
and I'm not spraying water on the floor
or if I've got to do some work on a
plant if I decide to defoliate that
plant while I'm looking at it or
reposition I can just turn it off real
easily
the water ones are really handy you guys
that's my point there are a lot of
different varieties available go to the
gross store go to the hardware store
look at the one you like or order the
one that looks the best to you on Amazon
so basically my auto watering system
with this water wand is I've got a trash
can on wheels I've marked it for volume
I fill it up to my desired level I add
and mix my nutrients I pH my solution
that means I adjust the pH to about 6-4
6-3 depending on what I'm feeding what
plants are getting fed I adjust my pH I
assemble the pump and my wand which
means I've got a pump I've got a hose
and I've got a water wand if you want to
put a little bit of plumber's tape in
there anywhere on any of those threads
to make sure they seal up real well feel
free to do that then drop that pump into
the water and plug it in and you can
water your plants in half the time I may
suggest that before you drop that pump
into your reservoir that you're gonna
water plants with maybe you put it in
another container and run water through
it just one time just to see if there's
any oils or anything left over I don't
know maybe there's something in there
from the manufacturing process that you
don't want getting into your plants
maybe clean it off one time I kind of
recommend cleaning [ __ ] out one time
before you use it in your grow anyway so
run some clean water through it just
make sure it's not gonna get oil or
anything in there I've seen one of these
pumps not a Maundy it was a different
and I saw it burn up in a reservoir and
a bunch of oil came out of it we saw it
all float to the top of the water
if Brian and I weren't paying attention
we may have fed that water to the plants
could have [ __ ] up an entire crop so
just a good idea to rinse that pump I'm
not saying it's got something on it but
it could so put everything together drop
that pump into the water and plug it in
now you can water your plants by picking
up that water wand and squeezing the
trigger and pointing it right into the
pot of the plant now you don't have to
go back to the reservoir between every
plant you don't have to carry a pitcher
of water from the reservoir to the plant
every time which is trips back and forth
which is you spilling water which is
inconsistent watering which is you
getting in a rush which is where a lot
of problems can go wrong you guys excuse
me for all the throat clearing I'm
trying not to do a lot of pausing and
editing on this show but my throat is
kind of burning so we're gonna take a
break here in a second take a drink and
a dad and we'll come back but I've been
talking a lot about consistency with
Auto watering here is a way to dial this
in with your water wand what were you
watering with before were you using a
pitcher we're using a jar we're using
one of those fancy watering cans from
Target ah whatever you were using get
your watering wand set that container on
a table and set a timer or a count just
count because you're gonna be doing this
hero on your own and your head anyway
when you're out in the grill when you're
when you get away from all the stuff and
you got your ear buds and you're gonna
be doing in your head so get that
container and use your water wand and
just start filling it and count how long
it takes count at your own pace but
count it the same pace all the time
you're not if you count it 1 2 3 4 5
make sure you always count like that but
if you count it 1 2 you can count it on
pace right now you're just measuring at
your own thing to make sure you count
the same all the time so see how long it
takes to fill it up 1 2 maybe it'll take
45 seconds to fill up that container if
that's the container you were using to
water your plants now you know it takes
the count of 45 to water your plants
with that water once you got to go stand
there for 45 1 2 3 but make sure you're
moving that water wander around the
plants the whole time so that your
moistening all of the medium the old
container needs to be evenly watered so
that's a good way to dial in how much
water you're giving per plant with the
water wand system so our basic shopping
list
to set up this trash can water wand
system
is a trash can wheels a Maundy pump a
good hose and a solid water wand you
should be able to set this up for around
$200 depending on where you find the
pump how long of a hose you get the
quality of the water wand and do you
need the dog washer attachment to get
that water to your reservoir so for
right around 200 bucks you can be
watering your plants with much more
efficiency you guys
my throat is mad at me I'm gonna press
pause for a couple of seconds I'm gonna
take a couple gigantic dabs at this Ken
brulee sauce I'm gonna get some water
and then I'll be back to talk about
building a reservoir and emitter style
drip system for your grow
[Music]
all right podcast world I am back let's
talk about building an auto watering
system in a commercial facility we try
to automate as much as possible to allow
for more canopy work defoliation bug
scouting whatever else needs to be done
that day a lot of cleaning and whatever
else we come up with on the daily to-do
list we'd like to have time to get all
of that stuff done so I use a water wand
and it can set up for our veg and moms
in a large but once we move into the
flower rooms every plant has an emitter
or two for automated watering designing
your watering system is going to vary
greatly depending on your current Gro
setup and your ultimate goals remember
earlier we talked about having goals
this setup should give you a good idea
of how to start your design you will
need to modify and adjust and adapt to
your situation I don't know what your
grow room looks like I don't know what
your room is shaped like I don't know
how many plants you've got you may need
to make some decisions on the fly
because your grow rooms and the hardware
store are going to be different than
mine I don't know what's available at
your hardware store maybe you're not
shopping on Amazon I don't know what
you've got access to that day maybe you
live somewhere that ace is the place and
you can't go to Lowe's or Home Depot and
they've got different stuff than what I
recommend you may need to do some
adjusting so this is just going to be a
good guideline in my opinion now let's
start with a little bit of a plan how
many plants do you plan on watering and
how often to those plants need to be
watered how much water will that require
and now we need to start with a
reservoir large enough to water the
garden the amount of times so let's say
you're going on vacation let's just
hypothetically say your goal is to get
this through a week you're leaving
Monday you'll be back Friday you need
the plants to survive through the week
how much water will that take how many
times are your plants going to be
requiring water to last Monday Tuesday
Wednesday Thursday Friday and you're
probably not gonna get to him until
Saturday right so you get to water him
Sunday you got five full days how many
gallons of water do you need for those
plants to survive
make sure your reservoir that you select
is large enough to handle that much
water if that is your goal if you plan
on filling your reservoir everyday and
mixing nutrients and just feeding your
daily feed make sure it's big enough for
one or two feeds and you should be just
fine but if you plan on leaving town
you're gonna want a big reservoir so
that's why I'm talking about it now so
think about the reservoir size that you
need maybe a small brute trashcan is
enough maybe you want 50 to 100 gallons
that's up to you also keep in mind it's
got to fit through the door it's got to
go somewhere in the house it's got to
get into your facility somehow so make
sure you've got room for a big-ass
reservoir those 250 s of square 250 s
they don't fit through a standard door
so you need a rollup door or something
to get that [ __ ] in the facility so
keep in mind also that you're gonna need
to get water to this reservoir and like
I mentioned earlier sometimes that's not
as easy as it sounds now if you've got a
250 gallon reservoir that may end up in
the garage that may end up in an easier
place to access and the girl may be down
in the opposite into the house and the
basement they're gonna have to get that
water you're gonna have to get water to
the reservoir then you have to get it
all the way back to the basement just
think about these things so it all
starts with a reservoir and a way to get
water into our rez now you may need to
heat or to cool that rez depending on
where it is stored if it's out in the
garage the temperatures are gonna
fluctuate it's been a hundred and
something degrees here that water would
have been really hot we would have
wanted to cool it down in the winter
here [ __ ] in the indoor facilities here
I'm heating water it gets so cold
outside that the water that comes in
through the pipes is ridiculously cold
it comes in at like 50 degrees stick
your hand in that 50 degree water no
thank you it's so cold at almost [ __ ]
Hertz we got to heat it up we gotta get
that
water around 70 75 degrees before we
feed it to the plants that makes them
much happier if you're using a hydro
system yes you do want your water cooler
don't correct me there we're just
talking about this drip system for today
so we want to get the water to the right
temperature you may need to heat or
chill it get yourself a chiller or a
water heater and be careful with those
things dial them in to the temperature
that you do desire also you may need a
smaller pump inside of your large
reservoir to help keep your nutrient
solution mixed properly and to prevent
that water from getting stagnant just
put a little like a fish tank pump or
something in there just to keep the
water moving around a little bit all
right so now we've got a reservoir that
we can mix our nutrients into we can
fill up with either RO water or
municipal water we can get water to it
now that's the first part is having a
reservoir filled with water our next
step once again we need a pump your pump
size is going to depend on the amount of
plants the amount of emitters and how
far your water needs to travel to get to
those plants if you're going up if you
have to pump uphill straight up you need
a much stronger pump than if you're just
pumping horizontal if you're pumping
vertical you need a stronger pump it
takes a lot of pressure to push water up
but if you're just going horizontal or
down you can use a less powerful pump
your pump is going to depend on like I
said the distance and the amount of
plants so do you more emitters you're
gonna need a stronger pump longer travel
stronger pump vertical climb much
stronger pump you're gonna have to think
about this when you're designing your
room do a little research on horsepowers
of pumps
it's better to have too much pressure as
opposed to too little pressure low
pressure won't work at all too little
pressure those emitters basically
regulate themselves unless you're going
crazy then you're gonna blow it apart
but just a little bit too much pressure
and those little emitters will regulate
your cell themselves and you'll be just
fine
so so far it's pretty basic you've got a
pump and you've got a reservoir and make
sure that reservoir is fillable maybe if
you've got a way to clean that would be
a good idea also just keep that sort of
stuff in mind from the beginning so this
is where it starts getting into some
work I would run PVC from that
submersible pump to an inline filter so
most of the time this is how I do it
I run PVC coming up directly up appa off
of the pump then you use two 90 degrees
to make it go back down it comes up and
then it goes around to the edge of the
reservoir the trash can and then it goes
just straight back down now you may need
to add some distance here if your
reservoir is wide or if your pump is in
the middle and then it comes up and then
you go a 90 degree and then you may have
to go a couple feet to get off the edge
of that reservoir and then you do
another 90 to go down toward the ground
and then on your way to the ground
that's where you're going to put that
filter that filters
so that shine or whatever sediment
you've got coming through the line the
thick stuff will get caught by the
inline filter and it will make it down
to your emitters and clog up your
emitters so now the line the PVC line
that was coming to that filter was
running down toward the ground just keep
running back to the ground until you get
to the floor and then use a 90 to point
it whichever direction you need it or if
you've got a long way to go or if you're
going into another room just simply use
PVC to route it to where you need it
just do some plumbing work build
yourself a little a water line to
wherever you need it use 90 degrees 45
degree angles just make sure you prime
and glue every spot carefully so that
you don't get any leaks so just build
yourself a little pathway to get that
water to where you need it now this PVC
I'm talking about can vary in size based
on your watering needs anywhere from one
inch to one and a half inch to three
inch PVC could be used depending on the
size of your garden and how much water
flow you need if you're using a large
facility you may be pumping this water a
long distance just from your reservoir
all the way down the hallway all the way
to the grow room around the corner out
to where it gets dispersed and then down
to each table you're gonna need a
stronger pump for that so make sure your
pump is equipped for how much water
you're moving and the distance that it
has to go if you're going to set up
different rooms with the same pump just
use ball valves so that you can turn off
so you'll have a it'll come from the
pump up to one valve and then you'll
have three on and off switches and you
just turn the ones off where you don't
want the water to flow and the water off
where you want it to go so you can
select which room so just use ball
valves to control the flow to each room
use tees and ball valves that way you
can have one pump that you can water
every room from but you'll have to do
one room at a time all right so we've
got a big reservoir we have got a pump
inside that pump has hose coming off of
it that gets us to a filter that filter
will save your life in the future by the
way it's gonna save you so much trouble
so you got a res with the pump leading
to a filter from the filter we've got
PVC leading us to the plant area now
this description is how I do tables we
can talk about building the tables and
adjusting this to a floor plan or other
options once we get the general idea
down
but this is how I do it using greenhouse
style irrigation tables the plants are
in three gallon pots they're in Cocoa
they're sitting on tables the tables are
slightly slanted toward the water runs
down to one end and it drains out of the
end so I never have water city
so we've talked about getting the pump
pumping water into the room usually I've
got the water coming into the room about
seven feet high so it's above my head
I've got a pipe running horizontally
across a lot of the facility just
running water all over the place seven
eight feet high then it comes into the
grow room about seven or eight feet high
this is just for my set up I'm telling
you how we do it in a commercial
facility about eight feet high the water
there's a water line you could just see
it a PVC tube this is a thick PVC tube
because we're running a lot of water
yours doesn't need to be this big then
for each table there's a tea coming off
of that main line so what tea comes off
and off of that tea I use flex hose that
fits off of that intersection and that
flex hose arches from the eight foot
seven or eight foot spot above my head
it creates an arch down to the end of
the table now that is out of my way I
can walk under that because it goes
right at the end of the table it just
bends perfect like I'm just walking
under a little bridge it's perfectly so
it's seven or eight feet above me and
then it is arches to the end of the
table where it comes to another tea
section
you
that piece of flex hose then reaches
another t-intersection where I have
about a three foot section of PVC that
lays on my table my table is five or six
feet wide I use about a three three and
a half foot section to start building my
table watering system there is a tee and
the very center of this three-foot
section of PVC where my
so that PVC just rests freely on the
table it basically sits centered it's
not the width of the table but it's
close the table is five or six feet long
this piece of PVC would be about three
three and a half feet long and it would
sit the width of the table and that is
basically the start of my water
distribution now if you're doing
multiple tables here is an important
detail between the Flex hose and that
t-intersection where do you meet the PVC
give yourself a ball valve to turn that
off and on so if you're gonna water more
than if you've got two or three tables
in there maybe you only want a water
table one or table two or table three if
you've got ball valves to each table you
can turn off each table and you won't
have to worry about watering the wrong
table with the wrong nutrients so that
will come to your advantage
wherever you can put a ball valve to
control water why not do it wherever you
can put a little union like a if you
when you start building PVC stuff you'll
you'll learn what unions are wherever
you can put a union why not do it to
save yourself some time in the future so
think about ball valves and unions those
will come into mind once you built a
couple of these systems if you've done
some PVC building that already rings
stuff to you but it's just advanced
stuff that's gonna help you out so
you
so now I've got my intersection where my
water feeds it leads into my table I've
got my ball valve so I could turn it off
and on let's not forget that like I
almost did it branches off a foot and a
half maybe two feet on you
you
now onto that you're going to
I know it sounds a little sketchy to
start but once you see how it works it
totally makes a lot of sense so you need
poly tubing depending on the size of
your grow the PVC and the poly tubing
you use may vary anywhere from a half of
an inch to one and a half inches you're
just gonna have to think about how much
water you need to move and how big of a
pump you want to use in your setup so to
get back where we were we've got our
line coming off the wall we've got our
t-intersection then we've got our 90
degrees with our little inserts glued
into there and everything is glued
everything has been primed and glued all
the way back to the wall we're doing
this as we go so we don't get any leaks
everything is primed and glued we've got
our 90-degree angles
pointing down
you
right down between the pots just so
right I'm gonna run mine down the length
of the table because that's what I'm
doing I'm gonna get it down the table
then I'm gonna put two more of those
90-degree angles at the end you use the
90-degree angle you have to put an
insert in one end of it prime it and
glue it then that pops into your poly
tubing you can either prime and glue
that or put a hose clamp on there I do
both because that's where it's gonna
come undone when two different kind of
materials meet that's where the glue
likes to fail so I Prime and glue it I
put a hose clamp on there then I just do
another piece of PVC across the same
length is the one I used at the other
end probably three feet long do another
one and then do repeat my 90 degree
angle again and then I roll my poly
tubing out to match so now I've built a
square so now basically I've got water
coming from the reservoir it comes along
the wall comes into the room comes from
eight feet above me branches off the
wall goes down the Flex tubing goes to
the ball valve that I can turn off and
on then it goes to the T section of PVC
then it runs down the length of my table
then it goes back and meets itself at
that square because it cuts off there's
nowhere for the water to go now this
helps create pressure instead of just
having one line running down the middle
with lines coming off of it we've got a
little bit of equalized pressure and
this will help spread the water out
amongst the plants a little more evenly
also since we've got such a long table
we'd rather have two lines coming off so
that we can have emitters off of two
different lines and not have really long
spaghetti lines we've just got two mains
to pipe off of
you
here is where having a solid plan will
come in handy hopefully you drew all
this out before we started building
hopefully you measured twice cut once
before we lay it out all the tubing
hopefully everything went well with that
but now you really need to think about
where you're going to place your plants
if you need to place the plants now
before you start making your punctures
to insert your emitters it may be a wise
move to have the plants in place if
you've done this before if you know how
many plants fit and how much space then
you can probably do the math on that but
I would set the plants in place if
you've got a table I know that this
section this I think it's a six by now
it's got to be 8 by 6 section I think I
can fit 15 to 18 plants in there
depending on the strain so I would think
about I need to get 15 emitters in here
where am I gonna put these plants I
would put 3 rows of 5 right so I'm going
to need 15 minutes I do 7 coming off of
this side
so before you go puncturing think about
how many plants on each side and think
about how far apart they're gonna be if
you do make punctures you decide you
don't need they do sell little caps that
just pop right into those holes or you
can just run spaghetti Lyon off of it
and then crimp it and put a hose clamp
around it you'll be just fine but it's
easier to not punch extra holes so the
emitters are gonna be coming off of
quarter inch tubing there are little
sprinklers those come off of quarter
inch tubing that quarter inch tubing is
attached to our mainline that line
you've got running down the table that
poly line the emitters come out of there
you
and the steak you need to insert it into
the plant all preassembled
you
pretty close to the same length that way
you can keep all the water pressure the
same everywhere you don't get any weird
over or under watering because you've
got some lines that are too long all
right I got way sidetracked let's try to
get back to where I was we've got the
the poly tubing we're gonna puncture a
little hole and that poly tubing with
the tool that they sell it's really easy
you just smack the little you can set it
right on the tubing and hit it with your
other hand if you want to to make a go
through or just push it right on through
it takes a little bit of strength but
you should be able to get it so you
puncture the tubing then you basically
insert the Barb it takes a little
pressure it might hurt your thumbs they
do sell a tool you can use pliers get
that little barb in there determine how
long you need your tubing and cut it to
length try to cut them all similarly
like I said or buy pre-cut that's always
more convenient then insert your chosen
emitter onto the end of that tubing that
emitter like I said a minute ago is
going to need a steak or some sort of
platform to be inserted into your soil
or cocoa or medium of choice to keep it
in place it's not just gonna stay there
by itself a sprinkler head on a tube it
needs some sort of a support or some
sort of placer so all this stuff is in
the irrigation section at whichever
hardware store you choose but let's talk
about the emitters to get because there
are a ton of confusing options and I'll
tell you exactly what I buy and then
this may help you out I like the maxi
jet Maxx cone fan 360s and those are
available at www.att.com/biz em a b-36
d1 so I guess major alpha Bravo 36 Delta
one just to make that super clear
because I do speak with the weird tone
sometimes but that's the part number you
need there is a riser recommended on the
same page that matches that emitter I
would recommend that that's what you
need to insert your emitter into the
soil
there are similar emitters on Amazon but
they are blue and they are twelve
limiters for 1995 I think those are the
same thing but the discreet
doesn't give me as many details as the
others I recommended from Maxie jet so
maybe that'll help you out if you don't
want to buy as many as they sell on
Maxie jet I think you have to buy fifty
or a hundred from their Amazon you can
get twelve of them that should work for
you the Maxie jet are the emitters I
recommend but there are tons of other
options that may work better for you
they do sell kits that you can buy to
irrigate your garden the little kits
that they sell to irrigate your outdoor
flower garden those are work in your pot
garden at home if you have a small
garden and you want to experiment with
something like this you don't have to
build everything this is kind of a fun
way to do it this is what we would do in
a commercial facility those little kits
they sell that wouldn't work for me in a
long 45 foot table that may work for you
and your small home grow look at those
before you go building all this they're
gonna be right next to all this stuff
that I'm telling you to buy anyway so
you'll be in that department anyway
let's get back to where I was emitters
there are several emitter options I told
you what I like I told you what I buy I
told you what I use like I said earlier
this is all customizable if you like
something different I encourage you to
use what you like maybe you want to
experiment with emitters maybe once you
get your whole system set up before you
start puncturing a bunch of holes
maybe you just puncture one hole and you
have one grommet or one nipple
with one line coming off of it where you
just try a whole bunch of different
emitter style you can just put one on
turn on the water and see what it's like
see if you like it or not turn the water
off pop another one on let's just start
comparing see which one you like the
best know when you're doing that keep in
mind that when you add multiple emitters
and multiple punctures you're gonna lose
water pressure because you got pressure
coming out of more spots but you should
get a general idea of what the emitters
are going to do so figure out what kind
you're gonna use before you start punk
puncturing a bunch of holes in your in
your poly tubing and once you've found
and selected the appropriate emitters
that you like and that you're
comfortable with and confident in find
the appropriate risers or stakes insert
those emitters into your plants I insert
one emitter per plant when I'm using a
three gallon pot and I usually need to
water once or twice a day and I grow
pretty large plants in a commercial
facility under double-ended Gavita
lights so that's a lot of light there's
a lot of action one emitter is usually
enough for me now let's talk about
placing the emitter we want to
the entire pot we don't just want to
water the left side or the right side so
try to stick that emitter as close to
the center of the plant as you can get
try to get it right next to the stock I
know that may be hard you don't want to
puncture the roots you don't want to
tear up the roots a whole lot but you
want to get that stake right in there
close to the center of the plant so when
you turn on the sprinklers it waters
that whole pot as much as you can think
about that when you're placing them if
you've got a crew if you've got a staff
out there replacing sprinklers try to
train them on placing them near the
center that's important all right I feel
like we've covered most of building a
drip system or an auto watering system
we've gotten all the way to placing the
sprinklers right near the stock of the
plants let's recap a little bit and then
we will dial this system in before we
start like I said measure everything
multiple times before you cut anything
if you've got tables make sure you cut
your tubing to the right length if
you're growing along the floor make sure
you cut your tubing to the right length
measure twice cut once then you'll have
to buy the supplies one time how many
times if you cut something too short and
had to go back to the store and buy a
new [ __ ] don't do that to yourself maybe
dry yourself a good plan before you get
started if you've got a helper go over
the plan with them so you both know the
goal once you're confident measure cut
and assemble your system make sure you
glue everything if you're confident
everything is primed and glued and all
your hose clamps are secure and that
you've got all your emitters in place
properly then it's time to test your
system ah fill up your reservoir plug in
your pump and then go run down to the
grower room and see if the water is
coming out of the emitters check for
leaks all along the way
start at the pump work your way all the
way down and see if anything is leaking
look for water on the floor look for
spraying listen you'll know if it's
leaking pay attention then go pay
attention to every emitter make sure the
water is coming out of every emitter now
is the time to identify and correct your
problems if you haven't already put the
plants in the room to judge your spacing
now is the time to put the plants in the
room and start sticking those emitters
in the plants and now you have basically
completed setting up an auto water
system let's talk about a couple of
different things now do you want this
system to water at a certain time in the
morning without you there you can have
this just when the lights come on you
can make this water or do you want to be
there when this happens to make this
happen when you're
there is really easy makes up your
reservoir with the desired nutrients
have your pH and your ppm say how you
want to have a mix pump in there so that
[ __ ] keeps stirring through the night so
nothing gets settled so that it just
stays stays cycled up all the time then
have a timer on your pump your light
comes on at 9:00 and 9 o'clock have that
pump trigger - and now it'll just run
that water and it'll water your plants
for you while you're at work while
you're on vacation while you're sleeping
right through it now the thing you're
gonna have to do is dial in how long you
run that pump because if you just turn
it on and let it run it will run until
it's out of water if you've got 20
gallons in there and it only takes 10
gallons to water your room you're gonna
overflow so here's what you got to do
start keeping a timer every time you
water your plants get those emitters in
there set a little timer hit go on the
you
now sometimes your emitters are going to
get clogged we do have that filter down
at the end sometimes little [ __ ] passes
through there and it builds up in that
emitter that's not a big deal
simply turn off the water take off that
emitter get something a little tiny and
just poke it out you just put a little
pokey in there just something like a
wire brush bristle just poke it out
oftentimes I buy them in bulk so I just
have another emitter ready to go I pop
one out pop a fresh one in I put those
dirty ones in a pile when somebody
doesn't have something to do that's when
they go along and just clean all that
kind of stuff maybe just throw that in a
bucket with some fisa and some water let
it kind of clean up for you while you're
not even there go back and give them a
rinse and they're clean you can use
those as your replacement emitters next
time so those are gonna have to be
replaced to pay attention every day to
clogged emitters because your plant will
not get watered if that emitter is
clogged also pave
- a clogged emitter over all your plants
should really love an automated watering
system it's going to be more consistent
it's gonna be more even the plants are
gonna get the right amount of water you
should like it because you're gonna save
time you're gonna save energy you're
gonna save water
you'll probably save nutrients you'll
see an increase in production and your
plants you'll see an increase in
performance and your plants and you'll
have time to do some of those details I
tell you about that you say when am I
gonna ever do that you're gonna do that
right after you get this drip system
dialed in
you
you can set up as many of those in a row
as you want you can set them up as many
wide as you want just a basic 4 by 8
botanic air flood tray on cinder blocks
the cinder blocks are a little bit
taller than a five-gallon bucket so you
could slide the bucket under there to
catch the runoff and then you can just
run your poly tubing right down these
four by eight tables like I was talking
about earlier you guys you can make
these as ghetto or as fancy as you'd
like and they're still gonna do the same
thing if it works for you that's what
matters you can build a trellis system
around it by putting PVC pipes in a
five-gallon bucket fill that five-gallon
bucket up with cement just go get some
quikrete from Lowe's or Home Depot pour
it right into the bucket I just let it
harden right in the bucket there with a
pole a PVC pole six or eight feet tall
sticking right out of it and now you've
got a steady pole put those in each
corner and then just run your trellising
on there
and that's a really affordable way to
make yourself a greenhouse style flood
table with an auto watering system and
then you can go ahead and throw
trellising bars up on there and it's
really affordable and it'll work for you
it doesn't have to look super fancy it
will get the job done all right you guys
don't be afraid to adjust adapt and
customize any of the things that I said
in this episode you might need longer or
shorter tubing you may need thicker or
skinnier tubing you may need more
emitters you may like different
sprinklers than me this is just a good
idea of how to get it started do what
works for you experiment and have fun
this does sound a lot like a lot of work
and it does sound kind of intimidating
but I promise that once you go to the
hardware store and you get started and
you get that pump in your hand and
you're like I've got the start then it's
all going to come together so easily and
it will be a fun project for you and a
friend I hope so don't let a little work
scare you away from automation it's
really not that hard and it will pay off
huge in the long run are you guys I've
got a lot more stuff written down but
this episode is going to be an hour long
so I'm going to wrap it up please
support the patreon campaign that's
right if you feel like this podcast was
worth a couple of bucks if it was
educational and/or entertaining you can
go to patreon.com/scishow and I would
appreciate your support I wanna give a
huge shout out to everyone who has
supported me in the past and everybody
who will support the show in the future
it does not go unnoticed thank you I do
appreciate it you guys I would also
appreciate it if you find me on all of
the social media
you can find me on Facebook simply
search for the girl from your heart
podcast you can find me on Instagram its
Irie underscore genetics on Twitter its
@g f YH podcast also if you've got
something you'd like to say and you're
not into the social media you can send
me an email my email address is grow
from your heart at hotmail.com you know
that i would love to hear from you don't
forget that the show is available on
iTunes and stitcher and every single
episode is now available on YouTube
simply search for the girl from your
heart podcast on YouTube don't forget
that this podcast is brought to you by
my friends at the Hell a dank seed
company if you need new regular or
feminized seeds for your garden I highly
recommend to the hell a dank seed
company and you can find them at dank
seed dot store I want to thank you guys
again for listening to this long and
rambly episode I do appreciate hanging
out with you guys I'll be back Monday
with fresh new content I want to give a
huge happy birthday shout out to my
friend the one and only the Christ
killer the Flying Jew happy birthday and
big shout out to my friend Lisa @ and
until next time take a phat dab and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you