yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for another episode of the
grow from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation let's right up here a new
grower if you're a professional grower
if you're a new smoker or a dedicated
dabber if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who is just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me this episode of the podcast
is brought to you by my friends at the
hell a dank seed company if you need new
genetics for your garden I highly
recommend the hella dank seed company
you can find them at dank seed dot store
ladies and gentlemen roll up a fat joint
pack up the bong or start heating up
that dab rig because it's time for
another episode of the grill from your
heart podcast what's up internet world
it's time for episode 3 36 of the girl
from your heart podcast thanks again for
joining me you know I like to start
these episodes off by letting you know
what I'm smoking on today I'm taking
dabs of the chem Brule full-spectrum
extract from Green Dot labs
I love the chem Brule I think I bought
all of the chem Brule they had in my
local dispensary I'm gonna have to find
a new place to get that or wait for a
fresh drop I went today and they did not
have any more they had plenty of other
things to offer but the chem Brule has
been my favorite it tastes like lemon
peels lime peels and gasoline and then
there's this after flavor but I can
barely figure out what it tastes like
but I really enjoy it the high is
perfect for what I'm looking for today
so the chem Brule full-spectrum extract
from Green Dot labs that's what I'm
smoking on but the best part is I'm
smoking out of a brand new rig somebody
was sweet enough to gift me a brand new
rig it's got a sweet Rasta colored Star
of David with a Star of David shaped
opal on the back of that the rig of
course has red yellow and green line
work in it because of course I love the
red yellow and green work it is a little
banger hanger style rig it's adorable
this was made by TW glass being shot up
to the person who gifted me this rig
they would rather remain anonymous
I truly appreciate it this is beautiful
this is so me this is perfectly what I
would want for a rig
it's the right size it is Rasta colored
and it hits like a [ __ ] truck so
thanks a lot I truly appreciate this
gift so much love and appreciation also
Big Shot it's my friends at elevate
glass today I went to elevate and I
picked up a new banger for this rig I've
got a brand new thermal banger it's nice
and clean
I've been trying to q-tip it and keep it
clean I also picked up a sexy new red
yellow and green a carb cap it's got
some white and there also but it matches
the rig pretty nicely I think it looks
really good I also got some butane I got
a new dabber I got nice and laced up at
elevate glass they do not pay me to talk
about them they just took really good
care of me today big shout out to Mike
over there big shout out to Becka big
shout out to all the elevate dolls much
love much respect also big shout out to
Mike white Mike for riding up with me
today we got Mike out of town you guys i
kidnapped Mike
I took Mike up two Springs and we spent
most of the day shopping around in
Colorado Springs hey Mike thanks for
hanging out bro I had a good time with
you we need to get you out of the house
more often alright what's next
yesterday I had the honor of recording a
live podcast with the folks from growing
with fishes that's right I was on the
growing with fish's podcast it's a live
podcast on YouTube the episode is still
available on YouTube if you want to go
back and watch my guest appearance I
recommend you just go follow the podcast
those guys have a great setup going on
there are four or five maybe five or six
dudes that all join together through
Google Hangouts and they go and just
talk about cannabis and cannabis growing
they've had a bunch of great guests on
they've had Edie Rosenthal on they've
had tad hussy on I recommend the podcast
I think it's a great show and the guys
are just great dudes to hang out and
talk with and listen to so if you
enjoyed this show I recommend the
growing with fish's podcast make sure
you check them out and if nothing else
check out my live appearance on there on
their YouTube channel you guys I just
did a quick little search for you just
so that you don't have to do any
searching if you go to youtube and then
search for growing with fish's podcast
episode 97 a Rasta Jeff that'll be the
quickest way to find the episode I'm on
if you just want to watch random
episodes as soon as you search growing
with fishes the first episode that pops
up is tad Hussey I would just go ahead
and listen to that episode tad has
another great podcast about cannabis he
speaks very well he knows what he's
talking about
to cannabis and it is a great episode so
that would be a very good introduction
if you don't want to start with the
Rasta Jeff episode I understand that so
go check that out big shout out once
again to my friends at the growing with
fishes podcast I think I made six new
friends while being on that show
yesterday alright the next thing on my
agenda to talk about is an apology once
again I like to think I put out a pretty
high-quality podcast I think I put a lot
of work into it personally I write a lot
of notes I do a lot of thinking I do a
lot of preparation when the mic comes on
I try to be in a good mood I try to have
a nice flow I try to put out information
that can be absorbed by people that
learn from multiple different learning
styles not everybody learns the same so
I try to teach you two or three
different ways that's why you hear me
kind of repeat myself a little bit but
I'm trying to paint the picture so that
everybody can visualize what I'm trying
to do I try to be really thorough I feel
like the episode I wrote about building
a water system an automated or assisted
watering system that was a really good
episode there were like seven pages of
printed notes and when it came time to
record it I thought I did a really good
job and then when it came time to edit
it my computer started eating the audio
file I think I have diagnosed the
problem I have unplugged the piece of
equipment that I think was giving me
[ __ ] and I have replaced it with another
piece of equipment and so far I'm about
six minutes into this recording and I
haven't heard a glitch a pop a buzz a
hum I think I've identified the piece of
equipment that has gone rogue on me what
I think has gone to [ __ ] is my tascam
u.s. 1200 USB interface the part that
turns my audio signal into a digital
signal that lets me shoot it into the
computer that lets me shoot it to the
Internet I think that part has taken a
crap on me so I have unplugged that
I've plugged in the zoom h6 and I'm
using the h6 as the interface right now
it sounds good to my ears and the
recording seems to be working smoothly
the software has accepted everything
honestly I didn't start seeing problems
in the recording last time until about
20 minutes in so I'm gonna record an
episode here with the zoom h6 this is
not going to be a grow intensive episode
I'm going to read some iTunes comments
and read a couple of emails that way if
something happens with this file I'd
feel like a highly detailed grow lesson
got ruined and wasted and I don't have
to redo that for you so this all started
off with me saying I'm sorry I'm sorry
for that piece of [ __ ] episode that I
put out last time I worked really hard
on it I promise I think you can tell by
what was presented but the audio file
disappeared and the more I tried to
search and figure out what was going on
the more stuff just kept disappearing
from ITAR from GarageBand and I didn't
want to lose more so I put out what I
had I apologize for the incomplete
assignment I know you guys expect more
than that from me and I know that I'm
better than that I just want to say I
was embarrassed to put that out but I
was also frustrated it was 1:30 in the
morning I was exhausted I was frustrated
I just wanted to put something out and
give up and move forward so that's what
I did here we are with the next episode
it sounds good so far I've given you a
solid apology I hope it doesn't happen
again I can't promise because I am NOT a
USB device I can't promise you that I
may not just go rogue at some point and
start recording in a different bit rate
or just start deleting chunks of the
file I can't promise you but I can
promise you that I will do my best to
keep bringing you the best quality
podcast I can present you guys thanks
for bearing with me for a crappy podcast
it kind of kind of made me feel bad to
tell you the honest truth it made me
feel guilty I you guys count on me for
some [ __ ] and I delivered crap so I feel
like a bad waiter I feel like a bad host
but I'm recovering let's move forward
from that crap I apologized
you guys are all giving me hugs and
forgiving me I appreciate it thanks for
supporting me like I said I don't want
to put out a crazy grow episode in case
this recording goes wrong I think that
my tascam device was the problem
everything feels really smooth right now
the zoom h6 is working I just want to
record a couple of episodes before I go
super intense on gross stuff make sure
nothing's gonna screw up on me again
in fact I noticed my problem started
happening during playback so what I'm
gonna do before I read some iTunes
comments I'm gonna press pause I'm gonna
play back this part of the show that
I've already recorded I'm gonna see how
it sounds make sure everything looks
good sounds good and feels good then if
it works well I'll keep recording while
I'm listening back I'm gonna take a
bunch of dabs I'm gonna get lit as [ __ ]
this episode I usually don't do that I
usually don't take a lot of dads during
the show we're gonna see how this goes
we're gonna make sure the equipment
works we're gonna make sure the new rig
works we're gonna make sure the new hash
works we're gonna make sure we're just
gonna have fun we're not gonna go all
crazy on this episode you guys but
please hang out we'll listen to some
itunes comments we may read a couple of
emails hang out with me
I'm gonna take some dabs I'm gonna
listen back a little bit I might drop a
song in right here you never know what
could happen I do promise that if you
bear with me through a couple of funky
episodes then we're gonna get real crazy
on Gro lessons I've got so much growths
gross stuff written down that I can't
wait to get to it but I really want to
make sure my equipment works before I
start doing that so maybe one or two
episodes just some random stuff and then
we're gonna go hard on Gro lessons I
know you guys love the lessons a lot of
you guys love hanging out please bear
with me and also while I'm thinking
about it big shout out to everybody who
supports me on patreon because of the
patreon support having a broken piece of
equipment is not a financial struggle I
can replace this I need to decide which
one I want and then I can order it do I
want the tascam to in two out or do I
want to get the one that fits in the
rack I'd like another rack-mounted
device kind of debating if that's
necessary I honestly just use two
channels for the USB I run a Mac II
mixer into a compressor the compressor
has a left and right out and I run that
left and right out into channels one and
two on my tascam USB device so I
probably just need the - but it's not
rack mounted and that's frustrating to
me I like that it all fits in this nice
rack I've got here yes I did say nice
rack
you guys I'm [ __ ] rambly I am going to
press pause I'm gonna take a bunch of
dads I hope you take some dads with me
I'm gonna listen back to everything I've
recorded make sure it sounds good and
then I'll be right back to keep going
with the show
[Music]
all right podcast world I am back I hope
you loved that funky cowbell groove you
guys I took a bunch of great dabs I dab
some of this Ken Brule I also dab some
of the soul cleanser the soul cleanser
tastes like gatorade powder and Windex
kind of it's delicious and weird all at
the same time I really enjoy that took a
bunch of dabs made sure this new rig
works it seems to be passing quality
control standards so far the part I've
recorded sounds pretty good other than
my voice being in there the recording
works pretty well
thanks for hanging out with me you guys
I'm having fun today I've had a great
day I'm having fun recording with you
guys I hope you were enjoying this weird
episode it's not gonna be a normal
episode it feels different to me because
I'm recording with different equipment
I'm waiting for something to go wrong
hopefully nothing does go wrong to me it
kind of feels like school on a rainy day
or like I've got a substitute teacher
I'm just my eyes are bouncing back and
forth from the computer screen to the
zoom h6 to the mixer to the compressor
I'm just making sure all the correct
lights are flashing at the right time
just kind of making sure the gear works
I will get this dialed in we're only
gonna have to do this one more time when
the new replacement piece comes in I'll
have to dial that in and then we'll have
the podcast right back up to speed we'll
get into those killer Gro episodes like
I've been talking about because I'm not
bullshitting you I've got an episode
about germinating seeds I've got an
episode about cutting clones I've got an
episode about putting those seeds or
clones into soil I've got an episode
about transplanting those once they get
larger I've got an episode about
vegetative phase I'm sure that's enough
to let you know I've got a whole bunch
of great [ __ ] lined up for you also I
have an episode planned to talk about
seed vs. clone if you're not sure if you
want to grow from seeds or clone when
you start your fresh garden I've got an
episode all about that we'll talk about
the pros and cons of each so that's
coming up in the future but let's get
the equipment dialed in before we start
putting out super intensive grow lessons
and then the computer fails and it makes
me want to just go crazy so
let's get that dialed in and we'll work
on that in the meantime let's get to
some iTunes customer ratings and reviews
if you'd like to leave a rating and
review on iTunes I would appreciate it
it's really easy if you're listening
through iTunes on your computer or if
you're listening on an Apple device open
up the podcast app find my show
you're probably subscribed to it already
if not search for the girl from your
heart a podcast click Subscribe then
scroll down where it says available
episodes keep scrolling past that it'll
show you the ratings and reviews that
are already there then at the bottom it
will give you the opportunity it will
say write a review just click right
there when you click on there it gives
you the opportunity to give one through
five stars of course I would appreciate
five stars but give me what you feel I
deserve be honest go ahead then I would
appreciate it if you type in a comment
and let me know what you think about the
podcast again be honest that's the only
way ratings and reviews work is if
you're honest so go ahead and type in
the truth let us know what you think of
the show and I will read your review on
a future episode now let's get into some
of the reviews we have received through
the month of May up till now who this
review was left on April 26th I don't
remember if we've read this one or not
this is from April 26th of 2018 this
review was left by our friend Frankie
four-five-six and the review says I look
forward to this podcast every week
thanks man hey Frankie you're welcome
thank you for listening to the podcast I
appreciate that I appreciate the support
and twice a week I'm hoping you're
listening to both episodes I put out
every week I put out two now so please
make sure you catch both episodes fill
your ears saying weird [ __ ] on this
episode but it's good fill your ears
that's not bad I'm not even gonna edit
that fill your ears with podcast magic
my friend
all right this review was left on May
7th by a person who calls themselves
madcap v2 madcap v2 s review has a
headline that says great vibe of course
you left us five stars and the review
goes like this I've been listening for
about a month I love the show I would
enjoy more strain reviews keep it up
really makes my Monday morning drives a
lot better thank you Jeff a madcap thank
you for the great review and thank you
for listening and once again I hope you
guys are listening to the Thursday
episodes I'm putting out shows on
Mondays and Thursday I hope you're
catching those so you say you've only
been listening for about a month
hopefully by now you've been listening
for two or three months this was left in
May but all the way up to July now
hopefully you've caught on there is a
Monday and Thursday episode please
listen once again fill your ears that's
gonna be a new thing you guys hashtag
fill your ears all right I've got
another hey dude thanks for the great
review I've got another review on the
screen if the iPad will cooperate here
this one also was left on May 7th of
2018 by a person who calls themselves
red house grows their headline of the
review his awesome podcast of course
they left 5 stars the review goes like
this
I love the podcast i'm currently at
episode 250 and catching all the way up
at 4 to 12 hours a day of listening to
your show and the dude gro shows keeps
my sanity at work and for that i thank
you rust and jeff from red house grows
hey red house ah man i keep your sanity
I hope you keep your sanity you listen
to me for four hours to 12 hours a day
and it helps keep your sanity I'm not
sure that what you've got qualifies as
sanity if my voice for four to 12 hours
a day keeps you sane no dude honestly I
do appreciate it thanks that's a lot of
listening to me I hope you've caught up
with all of the episodes by now if
you're listening to four to 12 hours of
us a day you're probably getting pretty
close to caught up I'm curious if you
just listen to the hundred episodes that
are available in the feed or if you've
gone all the way back to YouTube and
started at episode 1 episode 1 is
available on a playlist that is on the
grill from your heart podcast channel 1
through 20 are on a playlist then 21
through current are on my youtube
channel so if you want to go listen to
everything it's there it may seem weird
because back in the day the show was
called the iGrow culture podcast I came
to find out that I grow culture is
already taken that is the name of a an
educational institution they teach about
Agriculture on the college level over
the internet go figure right I thought
it was original
I wasn't trying to steal a name but as
soon as they told me that name was taken
I changed my name to the girl from your
heart podcast much more appropriate
anyway I hope you're listening to the
old stuff dude seriously thanks for
listening thanks for catching up I hope
we really are making your day better and
also thanks for supporting my friends
the dude grow show if you guys are not
listening to the dude grows you should
check that out they're friends of mine
it's another great cannabis podcast I
feel like we should be listening and
supporting all of the cannabis podcasts
because we're all out to do the same
thing there's no competition in my mind
it's all the same goal so let's all
support each other you guys I am rambley
today I hope you're having as much fun
as I am with this podcast hey red house
gross thanks for a great review thanks
for the 5 stars
I'm gonna move forward this review comes
from our friend nanner boy what's up
Nana boy I can't see the headline
because the review is short there's no
button to press more but I can see that
there is a headline and I think it says
thank you I can see fan I'm gonna hope
that's the start of thank you if I typed
in fan my autocorrect would say thank
you or Happy Thanksgiving
but this came in May so I'm going to
assume it says thank you anyway it's
from May 31st from nanner boy and it
says met you at the D G C cup thanks for
hanging I just mentioned my friends at
the D G C cup the dude grows crew man I
had a good time hanging out with Nana
boy I remember you guys I hope you guys
had a safe trip and I look forward to
seeing you at the next dude grows cup if
that's a thing that happens this year
big shot to both my friends all three of
my friends the dude Scotty and Guru hope
everybody's well the dude has moved to
Canada Scotty's having some health
issues and the Guru is holding it down
so big shout out to all three of them I
hope they're all doing well I hope dudes
move is going well I hope the transition
is happening well I hope Scotty's coming
along with the health and the Guru man
keep killing it bro I love what you do
super smart always on top of your [ __ ] I
love it when you step in and shine some
light on subjects that the boys are just
way in the dark in that's my favorite so
chefs are those guys I should keep going
with these reviews told you guys I got
high and rambley so have fun with me so
far nothing has gone wrong with the
recording equipment I keep looking at
everything and I'm happy we're almost 20
minutes in and nothing is caught on fire
no spring
have flown out like it does on the
cartoons how come when something breaks
on the cartoons Springs fly out Boing
and Springs and sprockets fly out it
could be a computer it could be anything
it could be somebody's heart and springs
fly out I think it's so [ __ ] funny
right let's keep going
this one was left on June 17th from
somebody who calls themselves Mateo
505 I'm gonna guess that's one of our
Albuquerque friends big shout out to our
New Mexico friends this review says
Rasta Jeff is the jefe that means I'm
the boss
he gave us five stars the review goes
like this Rasta Jeff is the man I look
forward to the knowledge he freely
shares every week and goes into detail
instead of skimming over subjects keep
up the good work there's a lot of stuff
in there he looks forward to the
knowledge I freely share yes it is free
I do ask for patreon contributions but
that is if you're able to if you're able
to throw down on patreon please do that
it's patreon.com slash bro from your
heart you're not required to do so
I appreciate the folks who do the people
who have been contributing to patreon
upgraded the MacBook Pro I'm using the
people who contributed to patreon are
going to be the people I have to say
thank you to when I replace my tascam
device patreon has been very kind to me
you're not required to pay for this
podcast it's free I want to put this out
because I love recording I love cannabis
I love you guys and I think it's kind of
my duty I know it sounds weird but we're
all put here for something and I've got
a few solid purposes that I know I'm
meant to be doing and this is something
that I know like if if they came to
something if whoever you believe in you
know you guys know what I believe in my
name is Rasta Jeff if Jah came to me and
said you can only pick five things
recording would be recording this
podcast would be one of the five things
I know I'm supposed to be doing you know
I wouldn't cut this out cuz I know it's
right anyway I'm [ __ ] rambling you
guys sharing the knowledge freely that's
because I feel like it's my gift that I
need to give back to you guys to the
cannabis community the cannabis plant
and the cannabis community has been
super kind to me and super generous to
me so I just turned that back around and
just put that right back out as what I
feel like I'm doing also uh he says I go
into detail instead of skimming over
subjects I do kind of pick one subject
to beat the [ __ ] out of it for an entire
episode but like I said earlier pee
don't all learn from the same thing the
same type of teaching that's why in
school the teacher used to bore the [ __ ]
out of me because she would teach 5
different ways and I caught on the first
way I'm sure there were kids at that
first the way she taught that didn't
click she had to teach at the second way
there were probably some kids weren't
velcro shoes that needed the third
teaching I just want to make sure that
everybody can figure it out we all don't
have some of us think in cartoon some of
us think with [ __ ] graph paper in our
brain some of us can think an autocad I
just want to make sure that the people
thinking in crayons the people thinking
in autocad the people that have done
this a thousand times I wanna make sure
everybody feels included in the show I
don't want to lose anybody
I want the if the missions are first
grow I want this to make sense to you if
you've been growing commercially for a
hundred years and you've done it all I
still want this show to be entertaining
to you so that's why I hid things at
different angles and a lot of the other
shows just skim right over stuff they'll
be like what's the best kind of light I
like HBS's okay let's move forward and
I'm like ah there's so many things you
[ __ ] skipped right over and I'm good
at finding those things and documenting
them and making sure you guys don't miss
detail so thanks for noticing that then
he goes on to say keep up the good work
amen keep listening and keep growing
quality cannabis for me and I will keep
putting out the best podcast I can yo
Mateo 505 thank you for the great review
thank you for the five stars and thanks
for noticing the hard work brother I
appreciate that and keep repping the 505
down there I hope you're hanging out
with our friends from organic ax alright
I've got one more iTunes customer review
this one was left on July 3rd this one
was from my friend Juan Zilla
what's up Juan's illa Juan comes it
hangs out in my Instagram live feeds
quite often we interact quite a bit
Juan's a cool person I like Juan's
personality he's a great dude he left a
five-star rating of course the headline
is such a great tip he says if you were
even curious about the work that goes
into growing listen to Jeff explain
everything ranging from light cycles to
fee nose and everything else in between
Mike who is a regular guest is always a
great addition to any episode hey that's
a really cool review of my show I
appreciate that
aw that that's inviting that makes
people want to listen to the show if
you're even curious about the work that
goes into growing list
to Jeff but that means that you trust me
that I could tell you what's going on
that you know I've done it enough and I
figured out how to word it properly that
you trust me to explain it to the new
folks which is my goal so thank you uh
explain everything from light cycles to
fee nose to everything else in between
that is pretty cool because light cycles
is like the first [ __ ] you need to
figure out and then fee nose is like
some advanced stuff so you've you've
highlighted that we're doing it all
thank you and then everything in between
that covers it all and then you shout
out white Mike who white Mike and I had
a lot of fun today so that's cool that
you acknowledge that Mike is a regular
guest and always a great addition Mike
likes to get us rambling and talkative
and he opens up a whole new point of
view and a whole new perspective on the
way that things are done so I appreciate
having Mike on here and it sounds like
you guys do too so hey one thank you for
the great review man thanks for the
loyalty thanks for listening to the show
thanks for the five stars and thanks for
hanging out man you guys I mentioned the
Instagram live feed where Wan hangs out
if you want to follow my Instagram live
I answer live questions right there on
the Instagram live feed you can type in
a question I'll read it and then if I
know the answer off the top of my head I
will give you my best answer sometimes
honestly I don't know things there are
things that I haven't studied there are
things that I haven't researched
sometimes I'll say I don't remember
asking me that in a couple of days and
I'll try to read about it then I'll hit
you back with it but if you follow me on
instagram its irie underscore genetics I
RIE underscore genetics on Instagram
give me a follow turn on your
notifications when I go live your funnel
ding you'll be able to open it up you'll
get to watch me go live I just hang out
a chat I ramble I'm really interactive
with the audience I take dad's answer
grow questions sometimes we just get
real goofy and hang out have a good time
but I think you would enjoy it if you
like the podcast you would like the live
feed it's a little less formal we kind
of [ __ ] a little bit I get super
stoned on there there's no editing so
you can see what's really going on I
think it's a lot of fun anyway
one Zillah shout out also big shout to
everybody who left a rating and review
today and in the past I appreciate it
that helps us out on iTunes and if you
haven't left a rating or a review yet I
would appreciate it if you head right
over to iTunes type in a little review
let me know what you think about the
show I would love to hear from you
all right you guys the show is creeping
up on 30 minutes we're at 26 minutes
here we have not had any technical
difficulties I've noticed that the
previous issues would happen when I
would stop the recording and go back and
record over a messed up track I've done
that a couple of times on purpose now
just to kind of mess with the recording
software and see if that was where the
issue lies the issue does not seem to be
within the computer the issue I'm 90%
certain was with this Tascam device so
I'm going to replace that I think
everything should be just fine
I'm not sure why I feel like I have to
tell you about all of my tech issues but
now we're on the same page together and
we're all friends all right you guys
before I start wrapping up this podcast
let's talk a little bit about my most
recent breeding project a lot of times I
come on here and I share what I'm
working on in my garden recently I
decided to make more lemon Jeffrey
feminized seeds and more golden goat
feminized seeds golden goat is just a
golden goat female reversed I turn it
into a boy I used that pollen on another
golden goat clone and that makes golden
goat s1 self seeds that will make
progeny that'll make offspring they look
just like gold and go for the most part
you will have golden goat s1 feminized
seeds that are reliable golden goat
looking seeds then I took that golden
goat feminized pollen and I threw some
of that on my favorite lemon skunk plant
that makes
lemon Jeffrey feminized r1 seeds those
will be giant colas it smell like lemon
candy that are just coated in trichomes
the buds are usually bright green and
super sticky and it makes amazing
concentrates but the lemon Jeffery and
the golden goat feminized seeds are
almost done I know I kind of quit
talking about it for a minute it seemed
like I was just hyping up a product that
wasn't going to be available and a lot
of people were asking you guys they
should be harvested very soon the seeds
are hard I pulled a couple seeds out
gave them a squeeze most of them are
hard enough to my satisfaction I will
cut them down very soon and we will have
lemon Jeffrey and golden goat feminized
seeds available in the very near future
alright you guys I want to thank you for
listening to this podcast I know there
was another podcast it's not up to par
with what you expect I'm getting my
equipment all dialed back in
then we will get on those grow lessons
like I keep talking about just bear with
me keep coming back I promise you I will
at least entertain you if you don't
learn a lot from me I had a lot of fun
on this episode so thank you for hanging
out you guys please leave me more iTunes
reviews leave me more reviews on
stitcher and please I would truly
appreciate it if you could leave more
comments on YouTube just go to youtube
search for the girl from your heart a
podcast click on subscribe and then just
leave comments on the videos that you
watch I would really appreciate that I
love hearing from my audience you guys I
appreciate it also if you follow me on
the social media you can find me on
Facebook search for the girl from your
heart a podcast you can find me on
Instagram I talked about it earlier it's
IRA underscore genetics you can follow
me on the tweeter on Twitter it's at G
fyh podcast if you'd like to follow me
personally it's at Rasta Jeff 420 that's
pretty easy to remember if you've got
something you'd like to say if you've
got a product you'd like me to review or
if you'd like to sponsor the podcast you
can email me my email address is grow
from your heart at hotmail.com I know I
mentioned it earlier but I would
appreciate your support on patreon if
you'd like more information on how to
support the podcast on patreon you can
visit patreon.com slash grow from your
heart make sure you check out all the
rewards that I offer that if there's not
a reward there that works for you make a
recommendation and I'll custom-tailor
something just for you
ladies and gentlemen I'll be back in a
few days with the fresh new episode I
want to give a huge birthday shout out
to King Haile Selassie I the first Jah
Rastafari and until next time take a
phat dab and give your mom a hug for me