welcome back podcast world it's time for
episode 337 of the girl from your heart
podcast your source for cannabis news
education and conversation if you're a
new grower if you're a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
dedicated dabeh
if you're a cannabis activists or even
someone who's just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you ladies
and gentlemen put some fresh water in
the bong because it's time for the glow
from your heart podcast welcome to the
show everybody it's time for episode 337
thanks again for joining me as always
this episode of the podcast is brought
to you by my friends at the hell a dank
seed company if you need new genetics
for your garden I highly recommend the
hell a dank seed company and you can
find them at dank seed dot store all
right that's all the advertising for
this episode you guys know I like to
start the show off by telling you what
I've been smoking on today I've been
taking dabs of guava papaya nectar from
Green Dot labs this is Kim 4 and papaya
mixed together is labeled as sour fuel
and soft fruit flavors it's got sort of
a sour fuel and then there's a weird
like a green gummy bear or a green gummy
worm sort of a flavor to it I was
enjoying it it's got a nice rip and a
head height to it it's got me kind of
slowed down it feels like I feel like
I'm just kind of chilling like I could
be more hyper like I could use some
caffeine or something but the guava
papaya nectar from Green Dot labs tastes
great it's got me nice and stoned that's
what I'm dabbing on today and today I've
been dabbing in style because our
friends Adam ill and hem Perko sent me
the highest host collab gift box it's a
very cute collectible pink box it's got
Adam Hills face on it and it says what
all over the box because Adam L likes to
say what it's got some cool branding all
over the box and you open the box up you
are styled out and ready to dab there is
everything you need to dab inside this
box except some dabs and a torch other
than that you're pretty much ready to go
I busted the box open there is a rig
inside the box it's a very cute little
rig it's shaped like a cup it looks like
maybe a small cup that you'd get some
maybe if you ordered orange juice in at
McDonald's or something or some fast
food joint it's that style of a cup
shape it's got a straw coming out of it
for a mouthpiece the best part
is on the front part of the rig there is
a picture of my boy Adam ill he's just
looking at you you can see him going
what and then it says Adam he'll times
hamper on the bottom there it's got a
disc perk which was actually done in an
amber color and then the straw itself
was done in an amber color also I like
the way that the mouthpiece kind of
flares out I like those flirt out
mouthpieces great little rig from our
friends at Adam ill and hemp er CO and
then also they threw in a banger so it
came with a 14 millimeter banger a male
banger that fits right into the rig this
thing is super thick I'd hold heat
really well so pretty much all I needed
now was a torch and some dad's and I was
able to dab and of course I've got that
but wait there's more
they included a whole bunch of sweet
accessories I'm not gonna go over
everything but there's a pack of q-tips
in there to keep the new banger clean
and then one of my favorite things was
random there are some snap cap alcohol
swabs they've got alcohol q-tips so
they're a q-tip that you crack the tip
and then it becomes wet with alcohol
what so you know you've got some alcohol
so q-tips to clean your banger to help
clean your stuff up super helpful there
there were some papers in there there's
some stickers in there there's a
wristband with a stash pocket on the
back of it that's gonna be useful and
then also my favorite part there's an
atom ill air freshener for your car
there are a few other cool items in here
there's a silicone ashtray with a cone
in the middle of it so you can catch
your bowls on that there's a small torch
lighter so that you can light your
blunts there's a hemp lake in here there
are a couple other small accessories but
it's a really well put together package
I think this was well thought out and I
wanted to make sure to say thank you to
hemp Perko and my buddy Adam hill and
also big shout out to dab and granny for
making sure I got on the list for one of
these boxes so big shout out to
everybody for taking such good care of
me
all right chairs one more thing to talk
about before we get into the main topic
of this podcast a couple of episodes ago
I talked about my strain arise and I
requested my audience to go to Leafly
and help me get a rise posted on the
website Leafly Leafly is a website that
many people go to to find strain
recommendations they list a lot of
strains there you can click on the
strain you can read reviews from other
consumers you can see what it smokes
like you can see what the high is like
you can see how it smells and tastes you
can also click on the strain and get a
bunch of information about how it grows
about how it was bred Leafly is a great
resource for a lot of people who are new
to the cannabis industry and want to
discover new strains without having to
go to the dispensary and buy a gram of
everything so it's a good place for them
to find out what they're interested in
and what may get their attention and
also what may work for them medically so
I'm trying to get a rise listed on
Leafly com all I did was say hey guys go
do this for me and I gave vague
instructions on how to do so since then
I've gotten a couple of messages saying
hey dude how do I do this I've noticed
that it is hard to figure out where to
create a new strain review if you're not
familiar with Leafly so this is a brief
explanation on how to do a review on a
strain that does not exist on Leafly
these instructions are based on using
the website not the application I don't
have the app in my phone I open up a web
browser
I go to Leafly calm then either log in
or create an account it's really easy to
create an account it won't take you that
long you have to have an account to
leave a review or to create a new strain
so create a new account log in then from
there you will click on your name and it
will bring a menu with other options on
that menu it'll say profile activity
it'll have your location it'll say
settings then it says add strain review
that's where you want to click add
strain review that will take you to the
page where you can actually add a new
strain so it says create a new review it
says enter name in box 1 right there
just type the word arise arise is not
currently in Leif Leigh's database so on
step 2 where it says select item to
review you will have to click Add arise
then step 3 is select type it is
strain you are not reviewing an edible
or a topical this is a strain number
four select category arise is a hybrid
it is a sativa dominant hybrid but it is
a hybrid now once you've clicked on all
of that it will take you to the next
page which is where you can type a
review it will ask you to rate this
strain overall review one through five
stars
of course I encourage you to give five
stars but be honest if you don't feel
like it was worth five give it what you
feel like it deserves then it says what
do you think about this strain talk
about the appearance talk about the
aroma talk about the flavor talk about
the effects type in what you like about
the strain then you get to continue on
with the review the next question is
flower or concentrate are you smoking
buds or was this dabs then the next
question is smoke or vaporize did you
roll one up or did you put it in the
vaporizer that's your next option then
the next thing you get to answer is you
get to talk about the effects did this
get you aroused were you creative were
you energetic click on any of the things
that you feel like apply to you then
there's a box for other you can type in
any words there if it had some sort of
an effect on you make sure you list that
then the next option is medical effects
if this had some sort of a medical
effect if it eased some sort of a
medical condition for you type that in
there it's already got cramps depression
eye pressure and things like that list
it if it did something for you
medicinally please type that in there
then it's got medical conditions if it
worked for your Alzheimer's your
anorexia your anxiety if it worked for
anything on this list please click on
that and it'll highlight it and that
will add that to your review there's
also that box where it says other type
in anything they worked for you that is
not listed there I would appreciate that
then it says add potency information if
you happen to know the potency if you
bought it at a dispensary in Colorado it
will have the potency listed just go
ahead and type that in it will say add
flavor information when you click on
that tab it brings up a bunch of things
that all you have to do is click on them
and highlight them and if they're
highlighted it will be added to your
review and I really like it it's got
ammonia Apple berry butter there are a
bunch of great things listed on here
honey lavender it gives you a lot of
options for listing the flu
you can really get specific it'll let
you click on a bunch of them so feel
free to click on as many flavors as you
taste it in there click on those then
the next question is dispensary if you
remember where you picked it up go ahead
and type that in there if you don't
remember that's okay if you got it on
the street
if you grew it if you don't want to
reveal where it came from you can leave
that tap blank and that will be just
fine
then at the end you just click Save my
review and now you have successfully
reviewed a rise and you have helped me
get one of my proudest creations listed
on the website Leafly comm you guys
thank you for the support I truly do
appreciate all of your help I know I
asked you guys to do something on every
single episode I either ask for patreon
help or ask for iTunes reviews and now
I'm up here asking for you to go to a
totally different website and create a
new account and review my strain for me
but I do appreciate all the support and
I couldn't do what I'm doing without
your guys's love and support so thank
you for that you guys I'm only 9 minutes
into this show and my throat is starting
to sound like crap my voice is starting
to get funky so I'm gonna press pause
I'm gonna pound a bunch of water and
then when I get back we're gonna talk
about watering our cannabis plants
[Music]
all right podcast rolled I am back while
I was gone I took some dad's of some
Doctor Who full-spectrum extract from
Green Dot labs this stuff tastes like a
strawberry Kiwi Snapple the package says
passionfruit guava and strawberry taffy
but I got more of a kiwi strawberry
Snapple sort of a flavor kind of woke me
up snap me out of that little mellow
buzz from the other tabs I approve
now before I press pause and took a
break and hydrated and medicated I said
I was going to come back and talk about
watering our plants something that we do
every day something that seems so simple
something that we can really do wrong if
we're not paying attention so let's get
right into watering our plants I'm gonna
talk about something that I call one
through five water tech it's something I
use to train new employees it's
something I go over with anybody who
waters plants they get trained on one
through five water tech it's something I
could recommend to every commercial grow
that's something I can recommend to
every home grow if you're watering with
a pitcher if you're watering with a
watering one if you're watering with an
automated drip system however you have
chosen to water your plants this will
work for you now keep in mind when
you're watering the plants we need to
saturate our medium we don't want to
leave dry spots in there we want to wet
everything but we don't want to drown
the roots so you need enough water in
there to get everything wet you want a
little bit of runoff but then you don't
want it so much water in there that
they're spongy and the plants are
drowning and you forced out all of the
oxygen so it's a nice balance that you
need to find it takes time this will be
a way to help you dial it in also think
about this Jorge Cervantes taught us a
very long time ago in one of the very
first Grove videos I ever watched Jorge
said water should be abundant but not
excessive so keep that in mind you want
an abundance of water but not excessive
water so the idea behind that is to
water them thoroughly give them me a lot
of water to where the whole medium all
of the cocoa all the soil is saturated
there's a little water coming out of the
bottom now the water is abundant now
don't water it again until it needs it
and that is not excessive you've got
abundance and not excess also focus on
not getting all of the water directly in
the center of the pot the roots are
growing outward your freshest hungriest
most vigorous roots are out there at the
outer edge so water the outer edge of
the plant and let the water work its way
in don't don't go just pour in the water
dead center try to try to get the whole
pot saturated I keep saying you want the
whole pot saturated and that's our goal
if you're pouring nutrients into your
solution you're pouring that water into
that root zone you want that everywhere
so that every root can eat you don't
want it to have to go digging around to
try to find whatever you just fed it
wears the plus life where is it you
wanted to just go uh yeah there's plus
life you just want those roots to be
saturated or you want that dirt to be
saturated so those roots know right
where it is it's right here I'm just
touching it already it's been
hand-delivered to me they just brought
it right to me on a cafeteria tray I'm
gonna eat up this plus life I'm going to
eat up this shine I'm gonna eat up this
HD and some fulvic and we're just gonna
take it up is they don't have to go
anywhere for it so saturate your medium
that is my point now let's actually talk
a little bit about 1 through 5 water
tech 1 through 5 is a good way to
balance out your wet and dry cycles in
your pots if your plants get too dry or
if they're too wet you will have pH
fluctuations you will have slow root
growth your plants will stop eating you
will have diminished yields if your
plants are too wet or too dry for too
long you will definitely see problems
you've seen what happens if plants get
too dry right you know what happens if
they get too wet I'm sure some of you
have seen what happens it's the same
thing as if they get too dry so we
always try to keep our plants right at
the sweet spot we don't want them dry we
don't want them soggy we want them right
where I call number 3 so let's just get
right into 1 through 5 now for this to
work you're gonna need all of your
plants in the same size and shape pot
with the same amount of medium so that's
really gonna help you out you'll you'll
learn from this you'll learn how to
adjust that but if you want to teach
this technique you need everything to be
the same you need it to all match up you
need a uniform that makes it a lot
easier to teach this and to keep this
into production with your crew so
get the pot that you're gonna use get
the medium that you're going to use fill
that pot just like you were gonna fill
it with a plant put your plant in there
just like you're gonna transplant a
fresh plant in there pack it down just
like you would do not water it get done
get it all the way done have it just
where you're gonna water it have all the
amount of cocoa or all the amount of
dirt that you're gonna have in there be
done I keep shaking the pot that's in my
hand that is invisible but I'm shaking
it to get all that dirt back down to the
bottom twisted a couple times to get all
that dirt moved into place pack the
plant down in there nice and tight it's
nice and snug it's ready to go all you
need now is water right don't pour the
water set that pot down now get another
pot and do just the same thing put a
plant in there fill it with cocoa or
soil or whatever you're gonna use do it
the same as you did the other one the
same exact method the same technique
pack it down make it match if you do
that thing where you pick up the pot and
tap it on the ground a few times to get
the dirt in there I'm sure you just
heard me hit the table just tap that in
there a little bit to get it into place
get it to settle shake it into place do
the same thing to all of the pots now
you've got one you did not pour any
water through now this other pot that we
just potted for the sake of this
training let's say that we're using
three gallon pots push the one pot aside
it doesn't get any water right now yeah
that plant is gonna start looking angry
in a few minutes but we'll rescue it
don't worry it'll get CPR in a little
while after training classes over but
this other plant that we just put in the
pot let's soak the [ __ ] out of it let's
pour like 2 maybe 3 gallons of water
through this pot until water is just
gushing out of the bottom we may kill
this plant but this is the sake of
training so we're gonna just pour water
through it until it's saturated and then
when you think it's saturated with water
pour a little bit more in there just to
where it is just pouring out of the
bottom uncontrollably to where you've
made a mess on the floor and you're like
what the hell is happening we kind of
mad at me about it now I don't have all
this water on the floor this is for the
for the sake of training we want to soak
that plant to death now well all that
water is running out of there I want you
to pick that pot up if you're using a
fabric pot it's gonna be heavy you're
gonna have to grab it with two hands by
the edges and it's gonna try to stretch
on you it's gonna be real heavy and all
the dirt it's gonna act like a big
grocery bag all the dirts gonna cave to
the bottom it's gonna get real
cumbersome if you're using a plastic pot
you're gonna need two hands you're gonna
have to grab it under the lips on the
edges and try to pick it up it's gonna
be really heavy remember the weight of
that that is a five that's how we're
gonna start teaching one through
five water tech that's saturated
overwatered that's a number five that
other pot that we push to the side that
we didn't put any water in that isn't
number one pick that pot up when you go
to pick it up you might accidentally
throw it up into the air after picking
up that number five it's gonna be super
light that is a number one now let's
talk a little bit about the range of one
through five water tech the idea behind
water tech is picking up each and every
single plant and deciding is this a one
is this a - is this a three as this a
four is this a five and then
understanding how to water it
appropriately based on your professional
assessment yes you'll be a professional
after this training so number one when
you pick up the plant and you almost
throw it up into the air because it's so
dry that's a number one you should be
able to tell by looking at the plant
that it is at a number one the leaves
are drooping they're hanging down the
plant looks sad it's starting to tip
over a little bit the top soil or the
top of your Coco the surface is starting
to look a little crispy and crunchy you
can tell that it is visibly dry that
isn't number one that is a sign that
your plant is slowly dying
it is not eating and it's got the risk
of death and also you were absolutely
going to have diminished yields you were
losing time the whole time that plant is
sitting there looking like death you
were wasting time you were moving
backwards with your girl you're not
making any productivity you were
torturing that plant and pissing it off
and wasting time so number one
undesirable also another result of a
number one you're [ __ ] fired if you
work in a commercial grow and I'm the
manager and I walk in and those plants
are number one whoever was in charge
that day is coming to the office we're
gonna talk about it and you may not come
back after that so that's number one
don't be scared I'm not gonna fire you
guys number two number two is when the
plants need water you can see it they're
just starting to droop they're like hey
uh can we get a drink now that's number
two right when they start to droop you
can see the difference in the top soil
that top layer is just starting to
change to brownish it's not totally it's
not black anymore like when it was moist
and it's not gray because it's totally
dry or it hasn't turned that cork color
because it's cocoa we haven't gotten
that far number two it's like hey we can
do
some water that's pretty much the prime
time to give it some water so number two
the growth is kind of slowing down the
roots are going hey man we could use
some water pretty soon but that's right
when you want to give it some water
right when it hits to number two number
three number three is when it is perfect
and thriving
number three is where you want to be to
get to number three though you're going
to have to water either a four or a five
and let it dry down to that three and
then maybe just a little bit pass to
that two now it sounds really easy if
you've got a home grow but what if you
work in a large facility and you've got
to leave overnight in a lot of
commercial facilities we clock out at 5
or 7 p.m. and we don't come back until
7:00 or 9:00 in the morning
the plants are still gonna be the lights
are still gonna be on for a little while
when we leave if we work an eight or a
nine or a ten hour shift the lights are
on for twelve hours so we're still gonna
have two hours of lights on they're
still gonna be grower if they're in veg
they're still gonna be on for way longer
but the plants are still gonna be on so
they're still gonna be active then
they're gonna be drinking and you're
gonna have the night cycle to deal with
they're gonna have to last that shift
until we come back to work whatever it
is if we leave it will say five then you
have six seven eight nine ten eleven
twelve one two three four five six seven
eight in the morning you got ten solid
hours tell anybody comes back and checks
on them they have to stay wet so that's
why I say maybe water them at a five and
let them chill out and work their way
through let them cycle through overnight
and then by the time you get there in
the morning hopefully they're right at a
three or maybe a tattoo so that you can
water them so that's why it's an
important thing to think about you may
have to overwater at that five just so
that by the time you come back to work
the next morning they're not air21 and
everybody goes home because there are no
plants to take care of so I'm gonna
continue on with the number three is
where I was three is perfect that's
where we would like to stay all the time
there's the right amount of oxygen in
the root zone the pH is correct the
plants are eating the plants are
thriving they're growing everybody is
happy three is where we would like to
stay but we've got air flow and
evaporation and science and nature to
work with so we can't stay at a constant
at a constant three three is kind of if
you poke your finger down into the dirt
just about two inches and you feel some
moisture in there that's about a number
three
they're not soaked they're not dry the
plants are just going crazy you can tell
that is a number three when those plants
are happy so that's a number three you
guys try to you're gonna have to dial
this in and practice like I said this is
gonna take some practice in your own
garden that's why I gave you a number
one that's why I gave you a number five
to see and then you're gonna have to
watch them a little bit and see where
that fine line for number three is watch
your plants see when they're super happy
pick up the pot feel the weight of that
that's probably at number three so let's
move forward to number four number four
is when you're just a little bit too wet
but honestly number four is where I
water my plants too right when they're
watered as I'm watering I aim for number
four like that's just a little bit too
much water I've got 10 to 20 percent of
my water that goes in is dripping out of
the bottom of my pots but I'm making
sure to water in a circle I don't just
pour the water right into the center I
go around the edge of the pots and watch
the water fill into the middle as it
goes it really works very well so I
water until about ten or twenty percent
is coming out of the bottom that's in
number four the pot is heavy but they're
not goopy and muddy there's not mud in
your pot it is just really wet and I
know you're gonna have to play with this
to figure it out it depends on how much
perlite you've got in there it depends
on how much cocoa you're using it's
gonna depend on a few things but you'll
be able to dial this in and customize
this to your grow you'll be able if
you're a if you're the manager this is a
good way to teach your staff on one
through five if you're the manager
you're touching on does that make sense
if you're the manager you're bright
enough they trusted you and you're
bright enough to be able to catch on to
what I'm saying by now if you're a home
grower this is a good way to teach your
back up maybe you've got somebody that's
gonna come help you grow when you go on
vacation maybe you want to get your
girlfriend into there and you're kind of
leery on teaching her how to water this
is a way to involve your other half into
the garden maybe you want to get the
kids in there maybe you got a new grower
whoever it is this is a good way to
teach people one through five technique
so number four is where I water my
plants to right in the morning when I'm
giving them that fresh first feed I aim
for number four they're a little bit too
wet but if you watch them an hour or two
later they've hit number three they're
just fine by the time the lights go off
they're just about to hit number two but
they don't cycle through much through
the night so the plants are gonna be
just fine overnight when the lights come
on in the morning they're either gonna
be red
low into number three just getting a
little bit dry or right at the top end
of number two just like hey you should
water us you guys I'm not sure why but
at this point in the recording for about
thirty seconds the file just started
making a hissing noise and it sounded
terrible so you only missed about thirty
seconds of this episode I'm going to
figure out why this keeps happening and
I'm going to correct the issue but it
was only about thirty seconds I cut out
the annoying hiss so let's get back to
the show and also if you've got more
than like ten or twenty percent of what
you're putting in coming out of the
bottom then you're starting to overwater
we only want about ten or twenty percent
coming out of the bottom now let's talk
about the dreaded number five if you
were at number five your medium is soggy
there's just water gushing out of the
bottom of your pot it may be sitting in
stagnant water we never want that that
isn't number five those plants are
drowning they're not getting any oxygen
they're struggling the leaves are
drooping they're probably starting to
get kind of soft at the base where the
stick meets the soil you're gonna get
mushy there because they're starting to
rot we're risking root rot we're risking
stem rot we are risking death when the
plants are that moist also you were
certainly slowing down your growth and
diminishing your yields when you get
your plants to a number-5 level of
moisture so try to avoid that you guys
pay attention to our number four is and
stop there water the plants wait for
something to come out of the bottom if
nothing comes out porn a little bit more
if nothing comes out porn a little bit
more if you're using a three gallon pot
maybe just pour in a half a gallon of
water and see what happens that's a good
start then if you need more you can
always add more remember you can't reach
in there and take water out of that pot
now that's one through five one will
kill the plants five you run the risk of
killing the plants three is right where
you want to be you've got to figure out
how to keep those plants right around
two three four as long as possible and
when they get too dry you gotta water
them again without over watering them
now this is gonna be challenging based
on the size of your plants if your
plants are smaller they're much more
critical through that one through five
phase it means a lot more to them when
they get bigger they can handle a lot
more stress they can handle a lot more
abuse once that root ball gets developed
in that pot they can definitely take
more excessive water so if you've got
big plants and you do need to go away
for a long time you can soak those up to
a number five just be careful just make
sure that you're not keeping them too
soggy for too long like in a large grow
I'm running three gallon pots we've got
plants that weigh two thousand grams
when we harvest them those plants right
before we leave I soak the [ __ ] out of
them I soak them to a five but I'm
confident that by the time I get back to
work the next day they're only gonna be
a tattoo so you've got to learn how to
dial in those cycles with your pant
plants the bigger plants will be more
forgiving the smaller plants are always
going to be less forgiving they will let
you know when you make mistakes right
away and their cycles will not be as
long so if you've got to be away from
the grow for several hours make sure you
water those little plants right before
you go because they could dry up
overnight if you're not paying attention
you guys that is one through five
watering tech I tried to keep it as
simple as I could
you're gonna have to get a pot and fill
it and make that at number one you're
gonna have to get another pot and soak
the [ __ ] out of it and make that number
five maybe get another one and get water
running out ten or twenty percent that's
your number four then you'll be able to
figure out where the three and the two
live from there then you'll be able to
dial it in then if you're setting up an
auto water system that will help you
dial in how much water to give it and
how often it'll also help you to teach
the new people how to dial in that
garden perfectly and keep in mind
cannabis is very picky and
strain-specific
so some plants may want a lot of water
and some plants may not want any water
so pay attention to each cultivar not
just each table you may have to think
about which plants go on which table if
you're gonna set up an auto system
because durbin poison wants barely any
water where a golden goat will drink all
of the water so you're gonna have to
plan on that and pay attention and
adjust and adapt
all right you guys that's what I've got
for you on one through five watering
tech I hope you guys learned something I
hope you're able to teach somebody else
something about one through five water
tech I know it sounds simple but it's
probably something a lot of people are
making mistakes on and overlooking it's
also something that managers will be
able to train grow Tech's on which will
be very helpful for the cannabis
industry
ladies gentlemen only thank you guys
again for listening make sure you
support my friends at the hell a dank
seed company you can grab new seeds at
dank seed dot store I would appreciate
it if you follow me on all of the social
media you can find me on Facebook simply
search for the girl from your heart a
podcast you can find me on Instagram its
Irie underscore genetics on Instagram
you can stalk me on Twitter you can find
the show it's G fyh podcast or you can
follow my personal account it's a trois
to Jeff 4:20 and as always if you've got
something to say and you're not into the
social media or if you've got a product
you'd like me to review or if you'd like
to sponsor the podcast you can always
send me an email it's grow from your
heart at hotmail.com I would love to
hear from you there don't forget the
show is available on iTunes stitcher and
every single episode is available on the
youtube channel just search for the girl
from your heart podcast ladies and
gentlemen I would appreciate it if you
support me on patreon if you feel like
this podcast was educational informative
and/or entertaining and you'd like to
contribute to the show financially you
can do so by going to patreon.com slash
grow from your heart all of the
information that you need will be right
there big shout out to everybody who has
been supporting the patreon campaign I
do appreciate all of that you guys don't
forget to go to Leafly and add a rise to
the Leafly database I'd appreciate your
help with that just leave a quick review
if you've smoked it grown it consumed it
smelled it seen it anything like that go
ahead and leave your review there I
would appreciate the help I want to
thank all you guys for hanging out I'll
be back Monday with the fresh new
episode I want to give a huge shot it's
a grim bolt - drew it and until next
time take a phat dad
[Music]