[Music]
welcome back podcast world it's time for
another episode of the girl from your
heart podcast your source for cannabis
news education and conversation that's
right if you're a new grower if you're a
professional grower if you're a new
smoker or a dedicated davor
if you're a cannabis activists or even
someone who's just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jack I want to thank you guys again for
joining me this episode of the podcast
is brought to you by my friends at the
helideck seed company if you need new
regular or feminized seeds for your
garden I highly recommend that holiday
exceed company and you can find them at
dank seed dot store
ladies and gentlemen roll for fat spliff
with some fresh water in the ball or
start heating up that dab nail because
it's time for another episode of the
girl from your heart podcast ladies and
gentlemen welcome to episode 338 of the
grill from your heart podcast thanks
again for joining me as I mentioned
before this episode of the show is
brought to you by my friends at the hell
a dank seed company if you need new
regular or feminized seeds for your
garden make sure you check out dank seed
doc store you guys know I like to start
this episode off by letting you know
what I am dabbing on today I just came
back from the dispensary with some fresh
dabs I picked up some blue cheese full
spectrum extract it is UK cheese and
blueberry the description on the
container is berries and cheese I got a
lot of cheese a little bit of berries
and then a little bit of dirty feet at
the end which I really appreciate in my
concentrates I also picked up more of
this orange Earth nectar it's orange oh
gee and orange juice bud the package
describes the aroma and flavor as
ammonia tangerines diesel and hibiscus I
get the orange I get the diesel but the
hibiscus I'm not sure if I would
recognize that if it punched me in the
face so that's what I'm dabbing on today
you guys I got the blue cheese and I've
got the orange earth nectar both from
Green Dot labs I also picked up a grab
of the Doctor Who full spectrum extract
it's described as passionfruit guava and
strawberry taffy
I haven't busted this gram open yet I've
tried this it is always a satisfying
concentrate I also picked up a little
bit of the guava papaya nectar described
as sour and fuel and soft fruits
not sure what soft fruits they're
speaking of but it did have the fuel
even astute and then it had the
aftertaste of maybe a green gummy worm
or something in that green candy sort of
a flavor so great concentrates from our
friends at Green Dot they have been
killing it lately that's what I'll be
smoking on on this beautiful rainy cool
weekend it's been so hot in Colorado you
guys and it's been raining for a couple
of days now it has been so nice it's
been a hundred degrees every day it is
77 degrees outside it was so nice to go
for a drive getting a little bit of rain
on the windshield it's actually a nice
relief all right you guys don't want to
hear about the weather let's talk about
podcasting a little bit of an equipment
update you guys know that I had some
equipment failure in the podcast you've
heard it in the past couple of episodes
everyone says quit apologizing but I'm
honestly sincerely I'm sorry that it
sounds like [ __ ] that's not my style I'm
going to record an episode where I'm
going to read listener emails that way
if something craps out we're not losing
too much technical information I don't
feel like I put together a really
intensive episode and had a tech failure
I'm gonna do a couple of email episodes
until I get things solved and once I'm
confident in the equipment again we will
get back to those intensive gorilla
lessons I promise they're coming you
guys have already got some of them
written out so I want to put them out I
just don't want to frustrate myself by
putting them out half-assed so bear with
me while I work through some email
episodes a couple of random topics we'll
have a couple of fun episodes here and
then we're gonna get back into it
we'll get back into those really
educational and intensive episodes I
just want to make sure that everything
works and I can get it to you guys in
the rasta Jeff expected style all right
that's enough rambling about equipment
and updates where else are we you guys
I've been talking about the lemon
jeffrey and the golden goat feminized
seeds that are coming those plants have
been chopped down they are drying
they're hanging it will take several
days for those plants to become dry
enough for me to even think about making
them smaller so that I can start pulling
the seeds out I've gotta let the plants
dry they've got to get cut down into
smaller pieces the buds have to get
chopped into tiny tiny pieces then I
sift through and get every single seed
out and remove it from the material then
they've got to get packaged it'll be a
little while before they are available
but they have been harvested there are
very few seeds in this patch I talked
earlier that it took me a few extra
spray
to get that golden go to reverse this
time it just did not want to go for me I
had to hit it a couple extra times more
than I usually would it finally reversed
I got Paulin out of it I did not make as
many seeds as we would have hoped for I
know what went wrong I know what
happened I just don't know why so I will
make more again in the near future there
will be a regular seed run then I will
consider more feminized lemon Jeff and
golden goat seeds based on the sales of
this current batch so those are done
they'll be ready in just a little bit
they will be very limited in this batch
stay tuned if you're interested alright
let's move into some news before we get
to some listener emails if you've been
following the podcast you know that I've
been updating you on a chain of
dispensaries in Colorado known as sweet
leaf I'll give you a quick update then
we'll get into the current situation
sweet leaf had several dispensaries in
Denver they were charged with what was
known as looping in Colorado a customer
is allowed to buy one ounce per person
per day sweet leaf was breaking the rule
and letting people come back multiple
times a day to buy more than one ounce
which was deemed to be illegal the
dispensary was raided and shut down
their licenses in Denver were taken they
had a few stores with remaining licenses
until we read this article this article
comes from the westward it was written
by Thomas Mitchell and it goes like this
the headline is sweet leaves three
remaining Metro dispensaries suspended
by the meed
sweet leaf isn't out of the law
enforcement and regulatory crosshairs
just because it's been four stores are
no longer open its licenses for the
three remaining sweet leaf dispensaries
in the metro area were all suspended by
the state marijuana Enforcement Division
as of today July 26th you guys I'm
recording on the 27th meb signs on the
doors of sweet leaf dispensaries and
Aurora federal heights and Thornton all
say the store's licenses are suspended
for alleged violation of state medical
or retail marijuana codes while the meed
communications director Shannon gray
confirmed the closures
she declined to go into further detail
other than noting that sweet leaf is
part of an ongoing investigation and
that any further
meb disciplinary action will depend on
the results of the investigation she did
note that the local law enforcement
agencies helped the meed sir
the suspension so you guys there's more
to this article but it just basically
updates us from what happened in the
past so sweetleaf had a few more
dispensaries and now they have been shut
down sweet leaf is really struggling you
guys I will keep you updated with what
goes on with the sweet leaf closures as
things progress all right now let's
shift gears a little bit and work on
some listen or emails if you guys want
to send me an email to read on the show
my email address is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com I do appreciate the
interaction I do apologize I have not
responded to emails on the show and
quite a while I've been working on those
groans as you have heard but I've got an
opportunity for some email so let's get
right into it several days ago I was on
a podcast called the growing with fishes
podcast and they asked me a question
about what was coming up for my podcast
and what I had planned for the future my
response to that question was that I
wanted to learn how to interview
breeders better and have more people on
the show that didn't mean that I wanted
to abandon the format and totally change
everything I just meant that it would be
nice to be able to call up my buddy sub
cool and talk to some cool and get him
on the show it'd be cool to go up to
Denver and see Colin from the ethos
collective and get him on the podcast it
would be cool to get mr. Sol because
they all live just right in Denver
they're not too far away from me it'd be
great to have them on the show but I
need to practice on people who aren't uh
who don't intimidate me who I don't have
so much respect for I guess and get
better at actually interviewing people
so one of the things I said is that I
wanted to become a better interviewer
and interview folks on the show that
inspired this email this is from
somebody who I've interacted with
several times I'm not sure if they want
their name set on the show so I will
just read their message and the message
goes like this he said I just want to
tell you you're doing a great job and I
enjoyed the show growing with Fishes
this morning please do not change
anything please do not change your
concept we enjoy learning from you an
interview show every now and then is
okay but keep doing the good work that
you do I have learned so much from you
and my product is so much better my
patients love my product now that I've
been learning by who it feels is one of
the greatest teachers out there I have
listened to other podcast and other
shows and none of them compared to yours
then he also asked for some suggestions
he said I just wanted to know if you
have any suggestions with one of
plants and then he sends me a picture of
a scarlet begonias plant it looks
beautiful he said I grew up from seed
it's about four feet tall now but it is
stopped growing and just flowering out
thanks for all of your help and keep up
the good work in this community and let
me back up there are a lot of great
things to touch on first he says I'm
doing a good job dude thank you for the
compliments I appreciate that I was
struggling for a couple episodes with
the show but I feel like we are back on
track thank you for listening to the
growing with fishes show I hope you
enjoyed that that is available on
YouTube for everybody else to listen to
if you didn't catch it the first time
Benny says do not change anything don't
change your concept because you enjoy
learning I do not plan to change
anything I just want to add a couple of
more things to what I can do I need to
be more versatile in my podcast imagine
how many people would listen if we had
sub cool on here imagine how many more
people would it would expose the show to
so things like that or advantageous for
a podcast you've got the right idea an
interview every now and then would be
cool and I do plan on keeping up the
grow lessons in the grow episodes that's
my goal and dude you said you're
learning by who it feels is one of the
greatest teachers out there thank you I
appreciate that that means a lot to me
it means a lot that people are learning
from me that your garden is getting
better that your patients are enjoying
your garden better and that you were
probably just enjoying growing more
because of a little bit of time that I
put into this show so thank you for
listening thank you for the great email
and thank you for the support didn't you
say you listened other podcasts and none
of them compare that means a lot to me
bro thank you then let's get into this
plant that you're talking about he said
I grew that from seed it's about four
feet tall do you guys this plant is a
monster it is 4 feet tall it is
definitely sativa dominant he's got it
behind a brick fence it is going to grow
way over that block wall before the end
of the season it says I grew it from
seed is about 4 feet tall but it has
stopped growing and just flowering out
thanks for all of your help and keep up
the good work um its flowering out
because it has reached its critical
period it is getting a long enough night
cycle now where that plant knows that
fall and winter are coming and it needs
to flower it is doing exactly what it is
supposed to do it is a photoperiod plant
that means that when the fall starts
coming when the light cycle starts
getting shorter we have longer and I
in shorter days that plant goes oh and
it's time for me to start putting out my
buds because it wants to flower out it's
an annual plant these are only supposed
to live for one year so now it's gonna
put out its buds the whole goal of this
plant is to get pollinated it's gonna
put out buds with big sticky pistols
those are the hairs its goal is to get
pollinated it won't get pollinated
hopefully hopefully no one in your
neighborhoods got a male outdoors so
it's not gonna get pollinated it will
just keep stacking up calyxes which are
basically where the seeds would go
because it wants seeds it wants to
create seed so at the end of the season
it can dry up it would still be standing
there on the stock at the end of the
season if it weren't disturbed by any
people or anything if this were nature
it would dry out on that stick and then
those seeds would fall into the dirt and
then it would freeze over over the
winter then all that moisture would thaw
out in the springtime and then it would
germinate those seeds all that warmth
and that water would tell those seeds
hey it's time to go and they would start
sprouting up and then he'd repeat that
cycle it would veg out through the
spring then it would get nice and tall
like your plant here is in the backyard
and then about this time of year it
would start flowering out so your plant
is doing exactly what it should do I
think your plant looks pretty good it's
going to be taller than that block wall
I'm already warning you if you're trying
to hide it behind those other plants
that are there and that block wall
you're gonna have to start doing some
tricks you need to tie that thing down
maybe get some string or some fishing
line or something maybe something softer
than that to attach it to the plant
maybe like a couple of twisty ties a
bread tie a fuzzy stick do a couple of
things to attach it to the plant so it's
not all pressure on one spot and not too
tight but tie it to the plant and then
just bend it over like a fishing pole
just bend that [ __ ] over don't break it
just bend it over you'll know you'll be
able to feel when you're pulling too
hard just bend it over until it's gonna
arched over and then it'll start growing
straight up again but bend it over and
then if you have to keep bending it keep
doing it because that plant is gonna get
tall out there in the sunshine and it's
got quite a ways to go it's not gonna
come down until probably Halloween so
you've got a long ways to grow that
plant outdoors but your question sounded
like you were worried about it honestly
that plant is doing exactly what it's
supposed to do so hey bro thank you for
the great email thanks for the
compliments don't worry we won't change
the format and please keep the good
pictures and emails coming all right
this next email I thought was
I thought I'd read this one on the show
it says Rasta Jeff please don't use my
name on the air if you read I won't do
that I'll be cool for a bro then he says
long time listener and cannabis
enthusiast here I love the show and I
look forward to the new episodes Mondays
and Thursdays of every week anyway I was
looking into some clones in Colorado and
I was wondering if you had any
recommendations as far as nurseries go I
have a friend who loves granddaddy
purple to help with his insomnia so a
nursery that carries these would be
great thanks for always putting out
fantastic information and helping to
educate people across the country stay
Irie Hey Dude thank you for the
compliments he looks forward to the
episodes that means a lot to me that
people are just looking forward to it
that means you're enjoying it means I'm
not just rambling to the air um so this
one kind of put a weird visual in my
head for some reason I envisioned
somebody walking into like the home
depot nursery area or like whatever
Jeff's Gro Emporium if you want to go to
the mom and pops type type style shop
and they walk in and the guy's like oh
how you doing ma'am are indicas are over
here or sativas over here we've got our
hybrids placed over here if you're
looking for the head stash we've got
that over here and our elite cuts are
kept back here and somebody walks easier
this little fancy area um dude I [ __ ]
wish it was like that it is not like
that at all finding clones in Colorado
is not going to be as easy as you think
it is there are no nurseries like you
speak up you have to go to dispensaries
and those dispensaries may have a tray
or two of okay-looking clones that may
be labeled properly and I know that
sounds very cynical and that doesn't
sound very positive and it may sound
kind of discouraging but to tell you the
truth I have purchased clones from
dispensaries several times I'll say 10
times that's probably close to accurate
and I'm gonna say six out of ten times
those plants were not labeled accurately
back in the day I went to a dispensary
that no longer exists they used to carry
a strain that was really hyped at the
time it was brand new it was when
medical marijuana was just getting super
popular and all these hype strains were
really coming out the strain was
featured in high times it was in several
of their magazines this is
three only offered small batches of it
they had a batch that was supposed to
drop on my birthday the dispensary was
two hours from my house I went up there
there were some I called them the night
before I was like I would like to buy
the limit of this strain that you sell
and I would like to buy the limit of
clones that I can purchase and they're
like sure we'll do that for you come on
in
so I showed up at this dispensary when
they're supposed to open it started
snowing that morning ah so not a big
deal but I had to drive to Denver in the
snow that was kind of a [ __ ] then we
get there I realized it is daylight
savings time it's the first day that the
time moved forward so the dispensary
opened an hour late I sat in front of
the dispensary in line with other people
for an hour because they announced that
they were getting this drop of this
strain that would go on sale that day
and it just happened to be my birthday I
called him I was like bro save me the
limit the limit per customer was a
quarter so they had a quarter of that
saved for me I won't mention the strain
I won't mention the dispensary cos will
but it doesn't need to be said right now
but that a quarter they're supposed to
have I think the limit that I could get
was six clones so I get in there and I
was like man I'm uh this guy called last
night he goes oh yeah the notes right
here I'm the one that talked to you but
I sold all that strain last night I
almost said the name of the strain I was
like bro I drove up here from Pueblo to
get that bag for my birthday it's my
birthday too I came up here just to get
that and you're supposed to have six
clones for me to and he goes oh he
didn't bring the clones yet and I was
like so what am i up here for man and
he's like I'll tell you what dude I'll
go to the car and I will get you this is
way back in the day you guys the rules
are way different now you went to the
car and got his head stash of this
strain and brought it into the store and
weighed me out seven grams for myself
and sold it to me out of his bag because
it was my birthday and he didn't want to
[ __ ] over the stores reputation cuz I
shop there quite frequently for it being
so far away then he called his buddy to
bring me the clones the clones arrived
they were all in rapid Reuters they were
barely rooting they kind of looked like
[ __ ] he told me if I bought all six of
them that he would only charge me for
three since it was my birthday and that
I'd kind of had a shitty experience and
he made me sit in front of the
dispensary for an hour so I got six
clones for the price of three and I
bought the bag of the hypes train that
I'd been looking for
I brought the plants home I potted on my
flower to mount you guys there were
three different [ __ ] plants
that batch of clones and none of them
were the strain that I paid for okay bad
dispensary was in Denver I went to
another dispensary in Colorado Springs
and I purchased what was supposed to be
lemon OG and blueberry they were selling
this amazing lemon OG flower
it was delicious every time I would buy
it it would be bright green buds with
these bright orange highlights in it it
was just frosty and it smell like lemons
it was amazing so I bought the clone I
was like I can grow the [ __ ] out of that
no matter how I drew it it wouldn't come
out like that that was not the same
clone they falsely advertised that that
clone was that strain it was not they
just wanted to sell more clones they
probably had some [ __ ] they realized
this sucks and I just wanted to clone it
out and get rid of it and make a few
bucks off of that plant so they just cut
it stuck it in rapid Reuters barely got
it rooted and [ __ ] sold it to people
the blueberry they sold me was actually
tremendous and I really loved that but
that lemon thing they sold me was not
what was advertised so that's two prime
examples of being duped and sold clones
that were not labeled properly and not
what I expected and not what I paid for
and also you can't just go looking for a
specific strain they don't cut there's
not a dispensary that just cuts a bunch
of a certain strain to put out on the
Shelf to have them for customers that
kind of that's counterintuitive for a
dispensary they don't want you growing
because they want you shopping and
buying from them so they're not gonna
give you their head stash there are a
few dispensaries at which you can
purchase clones I don't know what they
will have ever they don't know what
they'll have you can't order them from
them you can't make requests the grow
will cut clones they will manifest it in
a transfer to the store the store will
receive it they'll put it on the shelves
hopefully someone at the store will have
some knowledge on how to take care of
the clones I don't know where to send
you because if I recommend a facility or
a dispensary and you go there and you
buy a clone and they give you some ship
it's got mites on it or turns out to not
be what it was labeled then I feel like
it's partly on me because I recommended
the place however I did buy a Durbin
poison clone from kind love several
years ago and it was absolutely Durbin
poison it was absolutely bug free also I
got a platinum og clone from the clinic
it was absolutely platinum og and it was
absolutely bug free but honestly not to
bust your bubble dude
like you're expecting something that
doesn't really exist there is a place in
Denver that advertises that they have a
ton of clones available I drove there
one time with a lot of money in my
pocket and a couple of friends in the
car because we're limited on how many
plants we can buy we all knew the drill
we were all gonna buy our limit they
were all going to one garden this place
had nothing but [ __ ] spider mites
powdery mildew and embarrassing clones
available so I don't even want to say
the name of their place I don't want to
send you there to go [ __ ] up your garden
because that's basically what you'll be
doing all right in the same email you
mentioned that your friend loves
granddaddy purple and you would love a
granddaddy purple clone the GDP is
readily available in seed form so what I
would recommend is that you order some
seeds I would check with dank seed store
and see if they've got the granddaddy
purple seeds available and get yourself
a pack maybe two packs of those and grow
them out grow out whatever your legal
limit is if you're allowed six plants
grow six dry them cure them then take
samples to your friend label it GDP 1
GDP - you know what I mean so that you
know what he's smoking so that you know
which each plant is so I guess grow it
keep a clone of it then flower it out
then let him smoke it and his favorite
it'll have two favorite so be two that
you got to narrow it down from keep
those two and grow them again and then
give him a blind test does this one or
does this one work for you and then see
which one works best and then you've got
the best granddaddy purple phenotype
from seed that is perfect for your
friend that's what a good caregiver does
that's what we do for patients that some
of the difference between just being a
cash crop er and a commercial grower and
being somebody that is growing to help
somebody heal and improve the quality
and enjoy their life a little bit better
so I recommend getting some seeds bro
and growing out some granddaddy purple
seeds they are not hard to find my
friend it will be easier to find than a
clean granddaddy purple cut hey bro
thanks for reaching out thanks for the
great email and dude good job trying to
take care of your friend I hope he is
able to find some relief from his
insomnia says he's smoking for insomnia
is why he likes the GDP
alright Jays let's move on to the next
email this next email comes from let's
see they don't want their name said so
we're gonna get right into it it says
hello Rasta Jeff long time listener of
the wonderful podcast writing for
prohibition land in India
Annagh it be careful out there it says
thank you for all the great knowledge
that you have given me
you're very welcome please bring more
Gro talk I'm doing my best bro I got to
get this equipment fixed and we'll get
it going then he says I've recently
started an indoor grow and I'm having
some issues with a few of my plants the
leaves old and new are starting to curl
under and wilt not to the point where
they are falling off and dying but they
just don't look the happiest like I want
then he describes his setup quite a bit
and he says one thing I'm thinking maybe
the issue is when I adjust the pH the
tap water seems like it takes a lot
maybe six to nine mils of pH adjusting
solution to get from 7.2 to 6.4 so maybe
it could be my starting water equality I
am letting it sit a few hours before
using it if that matters my humidity
stays between 50 and 65 percent temps
are between 78 and 80 degrees all of the
plants are not affected only a few all
leaves aren't affected only a few on the
plants which are affected I've attached
some pics which I have looked at we'll
talk about him then he says what the
strain is supposed to be I says he's
growing in a 10 by 10 room 600 watts of
light it's got a nice setup he's
describing the setup am i overlooking
something should I not worry about it
then he asked could this be chlorine
chloramine or other octet other toxicity
from the tap water anything you can come
up with could be helpful thank you so
much and I've attached pics stay I
really says you can't say my name from
Adam hey Adam thank you for the great
email um and from looking at your
pictures and from what you've said there
are a couple things that get my
attention first off I would calibrate my
pH meter if I were you it sounds like
that pH meter could be off I don't know
what you've got I don't know if you were
using drops I don't know if you've got a
blue lab I don't know if you've got a
Milwaukee I would calibrate it that
would be the first thing I do if you
can't calibrate it yourself maybe if you
take it to the grow shop I know my local
grow up and be happy to help you out so
if you just take the pin to the gross
store and be like hey can you guys show
me how to calibrate this or maybe they
can check it for you and they can say aw
dude you've been so far off and that's
why it's taken so much to adjust
honestly I don't know how much water
you're adjusting ah you said I take six
to nine mils I've been in a facility
where it took an ounce to adjust our pH
to the proper solution because we were
using so much
water to start with so it I'm not sure
how that doesn't sound too too crazy to
me six to nine mils doesn't sound like a
lot to move it a few points um also from
looking at your plants it could be a pH
issue it does kind of look like they're
stuck there's something and not getting
fed and something is stuck also from
looking at the plants it looks like they
are a little bit possibly over watered
that's what the leaves do when they're
over watered they curl down and they
start to make what I call the claw the
Handy claw they're just squeezed in
there look like they're angry they kind
of have that so it could be pH it could
be an over watering which could be
coming together if you're over watering
it's gonna disrupt your pH it's gonna
really throw off everything there in the
root zone also the leaves have a
leathery tough wrinkled look to them I'm
going to say that you should listen to
the episode about vapor pressure deficit
it looks like those leaves are possibly
a little crispy a little dry like the
air around those specific plants is too
dry I want to know are they getting over
watered is your pH meter accurate and
are these plants sitting right in front
of the fan the plants that are getting
problems are they near the fan is that
where you've got some ventilation coming
in is there a different air right there
that's what I think could be causing it
so it's pH it's over water or it is
extreme airflow disrupting the vapor
pressure deficit right there around
those leaves we're gonna have to do more
research that's how cannabis works
you're gonna have to figure out what
you're gonna have to investigate you're
gonna have to dial it in a little bit
and see what is going on yeah I really
do appreciate the great email Adam I
hope we solved some problems thanks for
listening to the show I look forward to
some feedback I look forward to more
pictures and I hope we're able to get
your garden back up to speed
honestly dude most of the garden looks
pretty good if you've only got a few
leaves like that you're okay but if it
starts spreading and going rampant we're
gonna have to figure out what's causing
that and we're gonna have to fix it and
correct it very quickly so keep me
updated keep me posted
hopefully we can get your garden back up
to a plus condition all right you guys I
think that is enough emails for this
episode if you've sent me an email
recently or in a long time and I haven't
read
don't worry I have got a pile of emails
printed out I haven't been doing
messages on the show for a while but I
will get back to it and I will work my
way through this stack of emails please
be patient and keep the emails coming
don't be shy the email address is grow
from your heart at hotmail calm I love
the interaction and I would love to hear
from you please send me all of your grow
questions and I will get to them it just
may take me a little bit alright real
quick I want to throw out some quick
shout outs to Jade angel Aldridge and
Tanner EM you guys before I start
wrapping up this episode I've got one
more thing I want to rant about I was at
a friend's garden the other day I was
kind of helping him do some things kind
of teaching him some tricks and tips
trying to get his garden up to speed and
he was mixing up his nutrients and he
simply picked up the bottle off the
shelf and he picked up a little
measuring device that He pours it into
and he measured how many mils he needed
in there and then he threw it right into
the gallon or the five-gallon bucket of
water and then he just did the next one
the same way and I was like bro shake
the bottles man he's like what and I was
like dude think about it all the good
stuff is in the bottom of that bottle
all the heavy stuff that we're paying
for all the stuff the plants want to eat
that's probably sinking right to the
bottom of your nutrients so if you've
got a bottle whatever it is if it's your
grow your micro your bloom whatever
solution you've got there shake that
bottle up before you pour it out because
there's a lot of water in there that
thing's like 90% water you want to at
least spread those inert ingredients out
right you don't just want to give it the
top little water to earth at the end of
the crop you're feeding at all the
chunks
have you ever finished a bottle of
nutrients and then just had a bunch of
chunky funky salty [ __ ] in the bottom of
it that's probably because you weren't
shaking it hard enough or enough often
enough before you were using it when you
were mixing up your nutrient solutions
and all the salts just stayed in the
bottom you just poured out the water and
he fed your plants 30 mils of mostly
water instead of 30 mils of NPK so shake
those nutrient bottles before you pour
it into your measuring device and then
as you're pouring the nutrients into the
water I would just pour one in there and
then give it a little stir and then pour
the next one don't pour them to where
they touch without being diluted by a
bunch of water the nutrients are sold in
two different containers for a reason
try not to let them mix until they hit a
larger container of water you don't want
the too content or
bottles those two products touching they
will bond there's a reason why they're
sold separately just shake em and then
Parman separately that's my advice you
guys all right let's start wrapping up
this podcast don't forget to check out
my friends at the Hell a dank seed
company at dank seed dot store I would
appreciate it if you find me on all of
the social media on Facebook just search
for the girl from your heart a podcast
on Twitter it's @gf wih podcast if you'd
like to follow my Instagram its Irie or
genetics check out my cannabis
photography and my Instagram live feeds
also don't forget about patreon if you'd
like more information on how to
contribute to the podcast on patreon
check out patreon.com/lenguin
thanks for hanging in with me I want to
give a huge shout out to TW glass and
until next time take a phat dab and give
your mom a hug for me