welcome back podcast world it's time for
episode 339 of the grow from your heart
five cast your source for cannabis news
education and conversation that's right
if you're a new grower if you're a
professional grower have you're a new
smoker or a dedicated dabber if you're a
cannabis activists or even someone who's
just curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff want to thank you guys again for
joining me ladies and gentlemen this
episode of the podcast is brought to you
by our friends at the Holiday exceed
company if you need new seeds for your
garden I highly recommend the hello tank
seed company and you can find them at
dank seed dot store ladies and gentlemen
in this episode of the podcast I'm
joined by our friend Jesse and we sit
down to talk about indoor growing we
talk about outdoor growing we talk about
commercial growing and then we hung out
and had a good time you know I like to
start the show off by letting you know
what I'm dabbing on today we took dad's
of orange earth nectar from our friends
at Green Dot lads super delicious
concentrate put me in a really good mood
ladies and gentlemen with no further ado
let's get right to the podcast with
Jesse and myself
all right podcaster well welcome back to
the show we are here live with Jesse
welcome back to the show bro hey thank
you it's been a long time man how things
been it has been a very long time ladies
have been pretty good I've been loving
your pictures your your Mexico pictures
your garden pictures from other places
those are very entertaining to me thank
you thank you dude congrats on the
adventures and on the anniversary yeah
thank you yeah it's just four years nice
nice to the to the wife for letting you
come play for a little rocker so we've
been hanging out [ __ ] and we took a
bunch of dads guys so you'll have to
excuse the slowness that will wear off
eventually hopefully and then as soon as
it does we're gonna take more dads but
uh I wanted to bring Jesse on because
somebody asked me a very interesting
question and I tried to politely not
laugh at them when they asked but it
kind of made me giggle a little bit
there were a lot of things that I was
like oh this guy then I thought I'd
talked about on the show with Jesse
somebody asked me why is it so hard to
grow indoors when it just happens
naturally
outdoors and that sparked a lot of
thoughts in my head
Jesse looks like he's already got stuff
to say
let it go bro it looks like you want to
launch something off no man it's been so
long I forgot how to podcast for sure
for sure nothing is easier to grow
inside nothing you're trying to recreate
a natural environment and even in a
harsh environment it's still a harsh
outdoor desert environment I don't know
why I'm assuming desert but it's still
gonna be harder or what am I trying to
say
even that is more loving to a plant then
uh then in a rocker indoor environment
that's not getting fresh here has hot
lights beating down on it the thing I
really thought you were gonna laugh at
is that they actually thought it was
easy to grow outdoors I think people
think we can just throw a seed out there
and pour some water on it and hope that
we have good buds at the end of the
season for sure I understand you know
the the notion though that it is a
little easier you know you don't you're
not trying to balance environmental
differences you know so but yes still
definitely not easy you know unless you
live somewhere where it rains about an
inch a week time and then it dries out
in the fall and you don't have any
humidity and you know yeah you have dark
deep beautiful soil so like maybe Hawaii
yeah I was gonna say Hawaii is about the
only place for that so if we're gonna
grow outdoors we've got to be out there
every morning we've got a supply water
if there's not water being supplied for
sure you gotta put water on it we have
to protect it from the elements if we
don't have some sort of cover out there
we have to prevent bugs we have to do
all of the maintenance it is not as easy
as a lot of people would like to think
it is to grow outdoors no yeah
everything he said do your arms are huge
you're [ __ ] sunburned he's got a
sweat line on it you are a physical
description a depiction of what and how
door grower looks like my I feel that I
have definitely stepped it up to I
proudly call myself a farmer now so I
would agree that you've got that farmer
tan going on for sure
but so it's not as easy to grow outdoors
as some people
would like to think so when our friend
said why is it so easy to grow outdoors
why is it so hard indoors when it
happens so easily others my first thing
was like I love this dude thinks it's
easy to grow outdoors like I'm glad he
didn't say that in front of Jessie it's
not that easy to grow outdoors you have
to you have to dig holes you have to put
or at least fill giant pots and you've
got plants out there in the heat which
means they're thirsty which means you're
out there in the heat giving them a
drink
you're getting sweaty yeah later hauling
water you tend in irrigation systems you
know whatever it is
top Chesson plants mixing feed you know
however you do your thing
thinning of the plants throughout the
season topping trellising you know a lot
of the work is identical to what you do
inside you know so but it's outdoors
yeah yeah and that makes a huge
difference
and then you've got elements to deal
with maybe it's gonna rain this morning
maybe it's gonna rain late tonight
it's Colorado it has been straight up
hail season season yeah I've seen a few
farms vegetable and cannabis completely
wiped out this year Wow yeah we'd be
surprised I mean just completely [ __ ]
wiped out nothing left it's also powdery
mildew season outdoors right now it is
hot as [ __ ] during the day and moist as
[ __ ] at night it is beautifully
conditioned for powdery mildew right
there so that's that's my first side of
the coin is it is really not that easy
to grow outdoors it's a lot of
challenges there are a lot of challenges
yes the light is free but the heat is
excessive and you have to water and you
have to go out there and do it so you
have to be out there in the heat it's
not as easy as one might think so now
let's talk about why indoors is such a
challenge we're trying to bring all of
that stuff outside into a room let's
just say most people are gonna pick a
bedroom in their house probably a
basement maybe an attic those are the
classic places you go so you've chosen a
bedroom right hang up a couple lights
that's always the first step right hang
up a couple of lights lights plug them
in what's the first thing that's gonna
happen gets hot as hell gets hot as hell
in that room it's gonna run up to 90 110
degrees pretty quickly if you got a
thousand watt light going on in there
and there's zero Erichs
just zero air now now we got to get some
air out and some air in so now we've
we've got the light that's what the
plants want but now we're heating it up
now the plants are just roasting in
there now we've just created basically a
little oven we're just putting OSH
whit's plants in there cooling or some
sort of airflow so now you're adding
another piece of equipment let's say we
decided to put let's put a blower in
there to remove some of that air and
pull in some fresh air now it stinks now
you gotta add a carbon filter because
that air is blowing out to the neighbors
the neighbors are gonna smell your crop
that's still not cooling enough now we
need to add an air conditioner every
time you start adding something the
power is gonna need to be pool D be more
efficient so now you're gonna need to
upgrade the power if that's why it's not
so easy
indoors every time you add one element
you're gonna add heat you're gonna add
something so now we've got lights in
there
we've got some air conditioning going
we've got a little bit of a blower
what's gonna happen the first time we
water those plants humidity is gonna go
crazy so now we gotta add it the
humidifier the humidifier wait where'd
this water come from exactly yeah yeah
now we gotta figure out where to get all
this water and we spilled some of those
yeah and where's it gonna go yeah where
is it gonna go do you have a floor drain
or you a lot of it's gonna become
humidity yeah yeah a lot but the plants
are gonna suck up a lot of it we're
gonna spill some on the floor they're
gonna run out of the bottom of the
plants if you have a floor drain do you
have a bunch of saucers you're gonna be
shot backing that out or you gonna dump
the shot back yeah outside you just pour
water on those [ __ ] the ground
doesn't say nature makes it happen for
sure so I mean like I said I can
definitely see you know why someone
would think growing outdoors is easier
than indoors so but at the same time you
know and as an indoor grower I totally
feel that it is a struggle the whole
entire season outdoors because it's so
unpredictable for me it is you have the
same vibe oh yeah you wake up and you
walk out there and go we don't run
overnight like normally we get pretty
good rains in the in the spring and we
did not get those this year yeah
most of July has been just incredibly
[ __ ] hot and [ __ ] we went what six
weeks without any noticeable Wow we did
and then here recently hell storms and
you know Colorado style monsoon storms
sideways rain yeah flooding out your
field knocking down plants you know I
mean it's it's a challenge here at the
you know you're at the whim of Mother
Nature for sure absolutely yeah so we're
trying to make that mother nature
indoors so we added a dehumidifier and
water that do you humidifier is gonna
make heat a little bit more I hate those
damn things is gonna make condensation
dripping out of the back also the
dehumidifier make it more water so now
we got to get rid of more water it's
like the old joke about the humidifier
and the dehumidifier side by side
Eastham I can't eat the mic sorry you're
good it's that low sexy voice recording
equipment it's like the old joke about
putting a dehumidifier in a humidifier
side by side who's going to win that's
basically what we're doing in a grow
room to die in in my dry and cure room I
will put a humidifier and a dehumidifier
on opposite ends and I'll set them both
at 50% and I will watch them fight each
other all day long you know don't turn
either one of them off all day and then
you get that nice squish technique blows
people's mind that people in climates as
dry out stars put humidifiers into the
grow into the dry room yeah yes we have
to dust people in the East Coaster like
whitey whatsit dehumidifier or a
humidifier why do you have one of those
our rooms are so thick that we can't
even can't even get the plants to dry I
was actually talking with an employee at
worked the other day about how I would
rather grow in a drier climate when it
comes to drying than a wet climate it's
with humidity spikes here this last week
our crop took longer to dry out than
normal and there was no you know not
much we could do about it right and it
just made me to think you know [ __ ] man
how do they do that you know and humble
too
no or anywhere on the west coast main
down in a swamp Florida yeah where they
have humidity how the [ __ ] do you guys
drive your butt out well you don't ever
hear about the Florida crunch or the
California crunch but you do rephrase
Colorado crunch when they talk about our
wheat because it is it will get crispy
here fairly very quickly most growers
around here
or let's say most shops around here
especially a few years ago no one knew
how to dry their weed now it's you know
I've seen some shops that know how to do
it right but we here recently we quickly
went from a bunch of dudes growing in
our basements taking it to the store to
sell it that way and then we bought some
bigger buildings and kind of put a
couple more air conditioners than usual
you know we didn't know what we were how
to commercially scale it so when it came
to cut down all that product we still
didn't know what we were doing it the
same way we did it in the basement back
in the day so we had to scramble and
figure out how do I Drive 50 pounds of
herb at one time this big old building
then we had this giant room that we
didn't know how to control so yeah as an
industry we've taught ourselves how to
do so much stuff so it's pretty [ __ ]
amazing actually come a long way yeah
we've shot ourselves in the foot a lot
we don't own dicks quite a bit for quite
a while for sure but we've come a long
way in this industry we have we have we
spent way too much money on nutrients
way too much money on the wrong HVAC
yeah oh [ __ ] I've seen that so many
times I think I think the HVAC companies
had a meeting and the growers come to us
sell them this and then it's wrong so
just just sell them this and then in a
couple months we'll come in and we'll go
oh yeah that other company whichever
whoever gets the sale will just blame
you we'll come in and we'll go on all
those guys are [ __ ] [ __ ] you need
this equipment we'll sell them that and
then in about eight months
bill bill do you want this sale okay
bill and you just throw a wrench in all
of it and you tell them oh no it all
fails we have to replace all of them
we'll just use all three of our techs to
install it they'll never notice I think
they did something there's some sort of
a scam because he
Veck is the biggest [ __ ] joke in the
commercial growing industry right now I
think a lot of electricians are running
the same scam too unfortunately here in
this town they're all the same business
HVAC and electric are pretty much the
same damn companies and the guys it's
such a small hiring pool that if they
fire bill from a and B he goes and works
at C &amp; D the next week but now they
brought this guy he hired got hired at
the other place that you hired and you
brought the idiots back dammit it's kind
of how growers in this state go to you
mention it I wrote down that we should
talk about why growers bounced from
facility to facility oh man that's a
trilogy boy right there yeah I think the
most diplomatic way we could speak about
it is just growers and owners have a
different approach for sure the owners
so there's usually an investor and an
owner and then a lead grower is Canada
basically the and then there's also a
metric manager who's got to make sure
all the rules are a compliance person
metric person make sure all the rules
are followed they're kind of the referee
because they know the grower wants to be
[ __ ] gung-ho because we used to grow
in the basement didn't care about the
rules we just want to cut as many clones
as we can and not write it down and do
whatever compliance person is like hey
write down all the clones
anyway the dynamic usually goes an owner
and an investor they got together and
they wrote a business plan and this guy
gave this guy money but this guy that's
got the money just has ideas he doesn't
know how to grow a moat usually they
kind of have a vague idea enough of an
idea to [ __ ] everything up is usually
about how much they know how to grow
just he's keeping his mouth shut because
he's got a job in the industry right now
and he would like to keep it so I see
him nodding and smiling occasionally but
he's gonna keep his mouth out of this
one it's business people business people
but they don't and then you've got a
grower like Jesse and I who when we look
at the plant there's some love to it
like something inside of us tingles when
we see a happy [ __ ] row of plants
just pray in I'll trellis tout
beautifully we all started doing this a
long time
when money wasn't really the main
motivation right yeah we've risked our
families our freedom our rights and for
this these other people came in after
the rules changed and they're not
risking what they're risking their money
but that's basically what they're
risking is their financial future
they wrote business plans based on
current trends and a lot of stuff has
happened that you know some people may
have seen the majority of people didn't
see it happening I mean I've seen
business plans written on selling pounds
for thirty five month old and now the
average grow you know so in somewhere
between like six and a thousand dollars
most of those pounds gone somewhere
around eight and then that you know
there's a hefty tax in there you include
payroll and you know I mean and yeah so
it leads to a messed up situation a lot
of people in different states just took
a giant [ __ ] in their car or their
cubicle or wherever this he did say six
hundred to a thousand dollars a pound
for top shelf
indoor or at least high-quality
greenhouse hand trimmed product that
Jesse and I would smoke if he drops them
on the table we'd grind it up and we
[ __ ] smoke a fatty of it right now
it's quality product it's going for $600
to $1,000 a pound commercially this is
not person-to-person this is this is in
wholesale bulk orders we won't talk
about how many but you got a lot of them
that's going and they're paying all at
once and they're paying six hundred
thousand dollars a pound and people I'd
say three years ago weed was thirty two
hundred dollars a pound about three
years ago Oh easily yeah yeah a lot of
those business plans got written on
twenty five hundred pounds which was
right you know that was the normal for
quite a while for I never saw it going
less than two thousand I always say
thousand because once you go down less
than 2,000 on a home grower scale that's
when he's you don't it's not really
that's why everybody in Colorado
basically all the cash propers they gave
up yes it's all dispensary weed now if
you're a cash crop and it's going
somewhere else which I don't condone
promote support but that [ __ ] happens
it's worth anything here and if you live
in one of these states you know is
building a program and going through
this thing you don't think this is gonna
happen to you you are wrong yeah it will
happen and it's gonna go even lower and
businesses that can't adapt large-scale
indoor places that have twenty thirty
thousand dollar-a-month
electric bills they're they're not gonna
survive you that's the challenge of
being a head grower right now is
learning to adapt and to grow a quality
product the same amount of it for
cheaper yes the exact same thing is big
AG on a large scale and do it over and
over again on a schedule predictable
results never have a room empty for more
than 12 hours you know if you're
cleaning it getting it ready that's cool
but by the time you come in for the next
shift start putting plants in there so I
want to wrap up the part I was talking
about why we jump around because
basically that investor wanted his money
returned yesterday that owner told that
investor we'd have money in nine weeks
the grower told the owner we'll have a
crop in 12 weeks so now there's all this
[ __ ] that has to be played
the owner says well I want it in 10
weeks then and then the investor says
well then I want it in 8 weeks the
grower has to save but it's still gonna
take 12 weeks to grow these plants and
so it gets weird they want you to cut
we'll cut off a week on each end it
doesn't you can't cut off a week of
hedge and a week of flower it's just not
gonna work so then then you don't have
the harvest weight that you want so then
you have to have these weird arguments
with them and then they're like why
didn't the weight you wanted because you
cut me off two weeks and it tastes funny
yeah why does it taste funny cuz I
didn't get to flush for the week because
you've decided we're gonna cut it down a
week early and and odds are this guy I
used to work for this guy I think his
name's Dave odds are he forced you to
wet trim too that has happened that has
happened so yeah that's why you see
Jesse understands exactly where we were
forced to do things we don't want to do
we don't agree we come to it with heart
they come to it with dollar signs in
their eyes and it just doesn't work you
gotta put what you got to grow from your
heart that's the name of the plant
that's what we're doing if you're too if
you're a bit too busy thinking about
money when you're in the grow you're
contaminating the plants if you're mad
at your girlfriend when you're in the
girl you're contaminating the plants if
you're thinking about porn when you're
in the grow some of us might be
contaminating the plants if you're
thinking about what you're gonna name
that cross you made you're probably
[ __ ] up the plants focus pay attention
what you're doing feel the vibe of the
plant to be in a good mood put some
music on dance around feel the plants
love that get that vibe going in the
grow it's much better than dollar signs
dollar signs dollar signs at this point
in the market if you're looking to make
money do not invest in marijuana
there are your cannabis there are a
million different better ways to make
money if you insist on being part of the
cannabis movement and you're not already
in the Colorado market invested in
possibly an ancillary market but that's
already filling up also sure and I mean
like I've got these q-tips on the on the
table from hemp errcode they cover us
with all the the rig cleaning supplies
maybe you can make something like a
company like that this sells us the
q-tips and the alcohol swab q-tips maybe
you can make glass maybe you can open up
a head shop maybe you can open up a
grossed or a company that buys waste
product from the all the grows and takes
it and turns it into an amazing compost
and resells it that would be amazing
yeah yeah and it's needed grows in the
cities have huge problems with people
breaking into their trash cans distill
their waste even though it's not worth
[ __ ] yeah they still the pots so you
could probably actually charge the grows
to take away the stuff yeah yes so
you're making money two ways they're
also another business that kills it we
have a company that delivers compressed
co2 we have co2 tanks outside of the
back of the building giant co2 tanks
like six or twelve of them depending on
the size of the facility and there's a
regulator inside and then there's a
computer attached to that and it runs it
to each room and then each room's got
its own sensors and it triggers when
it's needed sirens and flashy lights
yes stupid accessories to be sold to us
and then they'd had to train us on all
the warnings and [ __ ] on it did they
show up once a week and the guy gets out
of his truck and hooks up a tube to our
tube and hits go to the truck and stares
at his phone yeah seriously heats
breakfast in his truck I watch him
spread his McDonald's smorgasbord all
across the page and just grubs down and
plays with his phone it takes like 45
minutes as loud as [ __ ] it sounds like
yeah
pompona closely yep yep everyone in the
crow can hear it and can't wait til he
[ __ ] Lee yeah yeah I liked it I
learned a trick go to every great
flowering room and just crank up the
[ __ ] co2 put it up to 2,000 he'll
just dump into the whole room while he's
filling you so you can really crank up
those rooms that I'm not sure why their
tanks won't fill up they were really low
today order delivering water that'd be a
good one oh yeah delivering those so
here in Pueblo County both these
businesses there's only there's air gas
or no not air gas something green clean
or some [ __ ] that does the co2 and then
there's only one water company that's
curry transportation I mean [ __ ] is
everyone hates curry delivery water yeah
yeah that's so and the dude yeah I'm not
gonna say too much but he doesn't have a
lot of fans out there but they have no
other choice
yeah he's got water yeah that's like the
number-one thing all right so yeah don't
if you're gonna get into the industry
don't uh don't try to get into the
cannabis industry in Colorado if you're
doing it to make money because it's kind
of late is kind of I think our point but
I mean I'm not trying to discourage
people this is just the truth I agree is
going to be a constant uphill battle for
you
there are too many businesses right now
if you don't own the dispensary the grow
and maybe something else like an
extraction or a concentrate company or
some sort of other way to run it you're
not gonna make any money that's a ten
million dollar bill right there and a
weird piece of advice that I don't even
know if I should share but I love the
listeners and I love the community this
is something we should warn everybody
about when cannabis becomes popular and
I don't wanna say mainstream because
it's almost mainstream here now it's
like just the thing here it's one of the
things pretty much when everybody gets
into it and it becomes part of the daily
flow and people start understanding the
products they enjoy and they start
picking dispensaries where they want to
go and they start experimenting with
what's new and then they start coming to
Colorado and checking out the culture
here your market is going to turn 225
to 35% concentrates yeah definitely yes
people don't see that coming they're
gonna have all this flour sitting there
and people aren't gonna want to buy
flour they're gonna want high-end
concentrates if I was gonna start any
kind of marijuana business here in
Colorado with how that dough it would be
a lab yeah that's their uh one of the I
talked about him a lot and when they
opened I had a couple of friends who
were business minded they said that
place will never happen there's a
dispensary that only sells concentrates
they don't have any flowers they have a
small grow and they run their grow they
cut down the growth they turn it into
top-shelf concentrates because they grew
it they knew exactly how to grow it to
produce the concentrates they want they
harvested it specifically for these
concentrates in their facility
they froze it they prepared it then they
ran it and they make very high quality
concentrates and there's a line every
time I go there and they never sell any
flower they do carry some edibles that
are outsourced but they've got
concentrates they've got batters butters
HC FSC HT FSC they've got them mixed
they've got big 22 grand pucks from the
bottom of the jar that's just 222 gram
diamonds Jesus it's so yeah it's 50
bucks a gram and they don't break the
pucks up you gotta buy the whole 22
grandpa if you like it yeah but it's
available if you want it and they
obviously sell them because they have
them yeah they've got each high
cannabinoid full-spectrum extract
diamonds that weigh three and four and
five grams oh yeah and the stuff sells
they there's I go there I shop there
quite frequently so yeah I remember when
they opened people said their business
model wouldn't work a lot I heard that a
lot I was even doubting so yeah they're
hundred-percent concentrates and it is
working it is working so if you guys are
trying to build a business plan keep in
mind that the market will turn to
concentrate it's available smokeable
concentrates also something I don't know
why I'm giving you all kinds of business
tips that we should keep to ourselves
but we're already here we're past this
step in this market so this is just
things that I've learned people are
gonna love those and I almost use the
word that I'm trying to take out of my
vocabulary people are gonna love those
whack-ass pens everyone's into the pens
now they're huge
yeah it's we saw a lot of her
like that it's that's all it's for yeah
I mean yeah it's sad to see you get off
no again trim wow wow there are some
companies that are making some really
high-quality pens and they're super
popular you know I'm not a big fan of
them but one time we were driving home
in a snowstorm and the car is in front
of me I'll [ __ ] spun out and I was
having a little bit of a like [ __ ] in
the car and somebody just reached down
and they handed me a pen and I like here
this will help I was like oh yeah this
with one good ripoff of that pen and set
it down I was like oh the nerves are
better if I can focus on driving again
go ahead they're great when you're
travelling yes we're not condoning maybe
taking a rip off a pen in the car or
while you're getting in the airport or
whatever but maybe something like that
does happen people love the Pens depends
are super handy so girls love the pens
they're pretty inconspicuous at this
point to yank because of all the other
vaping devices right so if you're going
to a concert or whatever you could just
take your your dab vape in right on in
go take some waxy hits while you're in
there my problem is I just pretty much
cook them out like two or three good
hits roasted and gone but most of them
just don't I mean they're great in
certain situations but like just as a
daily use thing most of them don't do it
for me right myself as well
I'd rather have a Deb I feel like
they're like half a Deb if you're a
normal flower smoker if you just smoke
flowers like if you're just a normal
work Jessie and I are kind of expert
level pot smokers a little more than the
average bear if you're just a normal
smoker those pins since it's
concentrates when you're hitting that
pan maybe if you hit that on a lunch
break or while you're on a bike ride
you'll notice that they'll wreck you
yeah you'll definitely notice just for
the distillate in them is very potent
yeah green dots actually selling a pin
that is made all with the full-spectrum
extract now they're putting their silver
label yeah there's silver lamé
full-spectrum extract in there and
they're pretty nice from what I've heard
everyone's been giving them a rave
reviews green dots the [ __ ] yeah that's
what I've been buying lately green dot
and apothecary that's my to go to
concentrate companies to your contraband
they're the in-house company for a
cuddle
okay yeah they've got some Durbin Kush
sauce that is always on point and
there's star child oh gee sauce is some
of my favorite but it sells out so
quickly and they they're 45 minutes away
so I don't like to drive up there to
find out if they have it for sure I've
actually never been to apothecary or cut
above I'll go check them both out in the
experience been a few years since I had
a mid car I was gonna say if your
shopping sprees you got to have that
paperwork yeah it's not even paperwork
anymore it's uh you can have a PDF on
your phone that works just pretty handy
I've seen it my dad got keeps his yeah
he is non-smartphone so he's getting a
paper he had to wait like [ __ ] 60
days or some [ __ ] to get the piece of
paper in the mail that I couldn't print
it off like I just I didn't you know
yeah when he goes to renew I'll be like
just let me go with you right back in
the day you would go to the doctor they
would fill out your paperwork you would
mail some paper to the state the state
would take for [ __ ] ever then they
would mail you back your card and then
you would have this card then you could
go to the dispensary if you lost that
card or it got stolen or whatever
happened to it now you can't shop the
dispensary you have to mail email or
message or write to the state and then
they would send you a replacement card
if you could prove you were who you were
in the truth heart was valid and that
was yes
now they put all the registry online so
you go to the doctor the doctor types
all your info and while he's visiting
you and he hits and by the time he's
done hitting send your stuff goes to the
state the state reviews it for approval
I've never seen anybody get declined
with a new doctor set up they send you
an email you send in a payment and then
it says print your card is the next tab
that pops up and you hit print and it
sends it right to my printer and you can
print your card out now on regular paper
if you would like to have a paper copy I
actually keep one in my glove box in
case my phone dies or something goes
weird I got a paper copy in there cuz I
like to shop when I'm out of town I like
to be able to just go ship it's much
cheaper to shop at the the medical
stores by the way definitely and then
I've got my I've got a PDF of my card on
my phone and honestly all the stores I
shop they know me so I just flash it
they barely even look now you show your
ID in your car and they go okay come on
in Jeff so yeah it's a much simpler
process now we don't have to deal with
the mail
so much we kind of touched on it a
minute ago and it got abandoned cuz we
were talking about like four things at
once but before we start wrapping it up
let's talk about a couple of the major
things people are gonna notice when they
go from growing in their basement to a
large-scale facility I like that look on
your face I don't even know where to
start with that one I don't mean to
sound like this [ __ ] we know it's a
completely different ballgame totally
right and I don't have any notes in
front of me so that all of this episode
has all been off the top of my head
today so I'm not keeping track of where
we're going a lot of times they keep
notes so I know where we've been a lot
of there are a ton of inefficiencies in
basement gross you guys I don't mean
[ __ ] I sound like such an [ __ ]
basement growers of waste an
extraordinary amount of time and an
extraordinary amount of money to you in
my opinion yes so you're gonna notice
going from like a basement to say a 1500
plant grow or something like that if you
water that 1500 plant grow the same way
you possibly water your basement it's
gonna take you a day and a half and when
you get to the end guess what they're
gonna need water yep start over
things like D leafing and topping take
so much more time you wouldn't believe
what it takes to say top 250 plants or
something like that I when I have guys
do that I'm normally I'd probably say
3-4 hours and these are guys that do
that you know what you know once a week
they're professionals and it still takes
you know a while it's just average the
workload is so so much bigger little
insect problems turn big very [ __ ]
quickly very quickly man there's just
it's a completely different ballgame
it's like you know having a backyard
garden versus having you know two acre
garden yeah that's a good way to put it
yeah it's uh you know around like week
four five and six
but there's a lot of video game time you
got a pacemaker Oh like week four or
five and six are it [ __ ] to do I mean
you go to some D leafing and whatever
but all the toppings been done the
lollipop has done all the trellising is
in place you're just making sure now
you're in that like fingers are crossed
kind of no powdery mildew home stretch
open sure that or making sure that no
spider mites pop up now at the end it's
like week four or five six seven [ __ ]
play an Xbox you know what I mean like
selling the last crop is what we used to
be busy [ __ ] smoking and selling the
last one weigh it out bags and meeting
up with people we used to do that
doesn't happen anymore there's none of
that video game time that video game
time now you're cutting clones for the
crop that's coming up in two weeks and
then when you're done cutting clones you
have to get the other clones that were
already cut and put them into the
six-inch net pots or the four by four
pots listen through their rotation yeah
as soon as you're done with that you
have to go up pot the ones that were
already done into the three gallon pots
and then once those are done you have to
move those other three gallon pots into
that room that's empty now and it just
never stops and then not never there's
never a diff you fall behind one day
you're two days behind because you have
to do today's work tomorrow and then
what are you gonna do about tomorrow's
work you're gonna have to do that
sometime also so you're either gonna
have to work some overtime you're gonna
have to catch up so it doubles the pace
and Jesse started off the best way that
shows that Jesse and I have evolved a
long way from BB being basement growers
to becoming business minded professional
growers we did it gradually because when
we started the average commercial grower
room didn't look too much different than
a basement right absolutely my first
couple of commercial grows were yeah
just expanded basement grows we didn't
know I've seen clone air he is bigger
than two right yeah yeah it's but you
have people that have been around as
long as me and Jeff kind of grew into it
organically right don't jump into don't
don't think your first facility needs to
be a hundred lights figure out how to
kill one light worth of plants before
you figure out how to kill a hundred
lights we're at the plants for sure for
sure
I've been then he said you're wasting a
lot of time you're wasting a lot of
money think about when you're in that
grow
there's the licenses or
expensive the heating is so expensive
the lighting is so expensive the
air-conditioning is so expensive and
you're in there all day staffing is way
expensive room the rent water bill water
bill oh my god the water bill taxes you
know when you go this this may sound
racist but maybe it is you know when you
go to youtube and you watch people doing
their jobs and it's always people from
other countries it's some other very
cultural country the dude's got a knife
and a mango and his job is to peel
mangoes the [ __ ] doesn't blink but his
right hand just makes this motion this
left right left right left right and the
mango in his left hand
just [ __ ] spins yeah nobody blinks
and all these mangos are peeled gonna
have to get processes like that down in
your facility I told our all of our guys
get Asian on it bro like get Asian turn
into an Asian factory worker but you
still have to be mindful at the same
time I've accomplished a lot in the last
couple years at this grow with with the
help of great employees but um or mostly
great employees but they're not there
anymore so good ones always move on no
no no the good ones have stayed the
shitty ones have moved on thanks go ya
know it's pretty fortunate well I can't
say that about everyone that's moved on
from there I'll just shut my mouth
sometimes in it developing the systems
that we have developed is like one of my
proudest achievements there and it's
like it's something that I really
consider carries a lot of weight on my
resume you know if if another serious
business grow type was to look at it you
know that that's you know that's what
I'm gonna be put ya thrown out there
it's you know the yeah it's just you
this industry along we Wow I didn't I
don't think about it that much we're
kind of pioneers we were here well like
I was part of met amar the first
dispensary in town here first
dispensaries in the state yeah it was
the first was the first one in this city
there were some outside of our city
limits but it was the we're right in the
heart of downtown just doing it loud and
proud that product was grown in my
basement on in another part of town here
in another house that's where that used
to come from
then they bill another little thing in
their building there was a little bit
bigger and then we had some other
friends I don't know how much I could
talk about it's in the past
throw people under the bus we had
somebody that built a fairly semi large
warehouse that needed help and they let
us come you were there for a while I
went and helped out some times and we
both had other people build greenhouses
and other things and we got to go see oh
it got bigger and then people in Springs
needed help and I got to go see even
bigger places and I was like wow it's
getting bigger and now you can tell who
has been in big facilities if you take
somebody with you and they walk in
places and their chin hits the floor or
they just not like they either pass out
and get shaky or they're just like yeah
whatever another grow it's easy to get
jaded about a lot of things but when I
do a tour it they grow and I get that
jaw hitting the floor like it just it
takes me back a little bit it makes me
smile so you know to see someone have
that kind of passion for for all of this
you know it just kind of reminds me of
where I came from right we put in blood
sweat tears and more blood sweat and
tears a little differently but you know
I try to never try to never lose I try
to still love my photography you love
growing the plant like I you can see it
in the photography that I'm still still
in love with those girls
yeah it's I've still you know I'm not
completely jaded the day-to-day process
I'm like it's I hate it because I used
to talk to him about it but her talk
[ __ ] about people that thought this way
but it's a lot to just move in widgets'
from one place to the other yeah it's a
it's a production it's a conveyor belt
you just got to keep that conveyor belt
going we'll get a new clone I always get
jazzed about that you know pop a pack of
seeds here and there [ __ ] that's the
kind of [ __ ] that's just all it takes is
a new cut in the garden a new pack of
seeds or just that new opportunity for
something or you find out this new grow
tech you're like oh we're gonna try that
in the hole next cross the hole next
crop is super exciting just because of
some new idea that you got yeah it's
always fun yeah testing product so you
test a bunch of new stuff for a couple
companies we use so that's always fun I
like side-by-side tests is the best it's
easy to do when you've got 3,600 and you
tell two companies yeah I'm gonna run
your stuff on this many plants and then
like oh [ __ ] and they help you fill it
in and you get your schedule figured out
with them and then you do the other
company and get it dialed in with them
and then you just go head to head and go
see what happens
wait on the way the weights at the end
test the potency at the end it's kind of
like being a Roman Emperor man
I mean you create victors and yak terms
because someone's always gonna be sad
when that happens I like the look on the
Rotex faces when new clones come in it's
like they come in in a box and it's
covered you know cuz nobody can see
anything as it's being transferred and
then you open the box and it's like the
suitcase on pulp fiction gather around
like Santa Claus were like it's
blueberry cookies and someone in the
back is like blueberry cookies yeah it's
always so much fun to see people and you
get new cuts in the facility even the
trimmers they're like what the trailers
more so sometimes then they grow Tex
yeah because they've been trimming that
[ __ ] ghost dog for the past seven
days and they cannot wait to trim
something that's not ghost dog
whatever's next problems tired of
looking at this one when it comes when
you have a commercial facility you just
cut down we've been throwing out huge
numbers we used to cut down 40 lights
worth of plants at a time it would dry
up to be about 75 to 85 pounds of weed
imagine trimming that like yeah where
are you going to hang it to dry it and
this is part of why it you have to have
space you have to have a dehumidifier a
humidifier and air conditioner and a fan
all fighting each other see there's
always
problems gonna grow this size because
either you're not new stuff always comes
up even if you're doing your job
especially if you're doing your job very
well new problems come up hey you know
it's you always got problems we gonna
put all this weed problem
yeah yeah and you can't back crops up in
the drank your room because if you've
got this one that's almost ready to go
into the containers and then you bring
in this fresh one that just got cut down
you're just gonna remoisten all of those
other buds no there's so many challenges
things you're gonna have to think about
when it comes time to build your large
facility you guys this episode let's
start it off with an idea of talking
about the differences between why it's
so easy outdoors it's not and why it's
so much more challenging indoors because
every piece of equipment you put in
there you got to put another piece of
equipment if you put in a light you got
to put in a cooling a piece so when you
put in cooling that makes heat outsides
and now you got it just it all backs up
on itself then you gotta make sure the
power is safe please don't burn down
your house trying to run too many amps
on one breaker please we've seen some
scary things melt and [ __ ] like that
then it turned in us kind of talking
about just random grow industry stuff so
I hope you guys enjoyed hanging out
listening to this podcast Bri you got
any stuff you want to ramble about since
we've got you here on the podcast and
you don't come over often enough for
sure I'm actually really stoked about my
market farm business
me and Derek from the Colorado podcast
the summer for years I listen to podcast
a lot while I'm working in big gross and
it kind of turned towards some podcasts
that were centered on urban farming and
small farming and Derek would listen to
him with me and I always talk [ __ ] and I
was like I could do that [ __ ] [ __ ]
you know this and that and so this
spring I decided to put my you know to
to actually do it
shut up saying I could do it and show
that I can do it so we've been farming
800 square feet yes I said farming and
800 square feet counts rough [ __ ] dude
we've had we've had some beds have
turned over four times I had produce
available and for sell before most of
the commercial farmers
out in the county even [ __ ] had seed
in the field nice
we've probably grown about 300 pounds of
food so far they excellent he brought me
a nice some groceries it looks like I
went shopping I was nice and lush nice
and green sticking out all the bags that
looks delicious that's gonna be part of
my dinner tonight so thank you man I
appreciate that I appreciate you oh it's
always nice eating things that were
grown right across town by somebody that
you know put some love into it seems
better super organic although I can't
use that word because the government
stole it from us but it's fueled by
compost and worm castings nice it's it's
you know that's pretty much it
I put down a little bit of bio live from
down to earth okay we threw some a
little of that down early in the season
a little kelp meal to Exxon but yeah
that's it so where I work in locals find
you I've seen you set up at Thea the
farmers market they're working people
come find you your produce we do we've
got one more market this year that is
already planned
it's the Belmont Market at the Christ
Congregational Church here in Pueblo
other than that like we didn't make a
commitment to a full-scale farmers
market this year because it was our
first year I didn't know what to expect
I didn't want it most the time farmers
markets they don't just want vendors
coming you know they need a commitment
from you for the full seasons they know
that boots salt and yeah so I you know I
had some doubt myself about a few things
and you know just the nature and
learning a new business I didn't want to
commit to that so we're not at a steady
market yet but we have a Facebook page
hit us up there and we will totally ship
you over some veggies anywhere here in
Pueblo that's all my three-day farms
that's a LM a preferred a like color
green so check it out you guys support
the local local vegetables for sugar
produce it's good stuff my buddy
next year we're gonna be on an acre ice
pretty much finished up a deal to rent
an acre that's got water on it out in
the county so yeah we're if we get our
funding figured out because this stuff
is not cheap right people forget that
farming costs a lot
money yeah we get our funding figured
out we're gonna be farming anywhere from
a quarter to a half acre with plans for
a third year to expand into the full
acre so excellent yeah I wish you luck
with that one Bravo because well I look
forward to more of those fresh veggies
for sure hey man thanks for coming and
hanging out Congrats on the four-year
anniversary shout out to the wife again
thank you you're still doing the call
rod no podcast no no well I'm sorry guys
far too busy yeah he's got a lot going
on I was gonna say you're doing so much
stuff we weren't that good anyway
[Music]
thanks for coming and hanging out we'll
wrap up this section for sure make sure
you guys stock Jesse on any of the
social media make sure you follow him on
Facebook on the alma Verde Facebook page
check out his work yeah do you want to
shout out any of your other social media
yeah give me a follow on Instagram Jesse
goes Jesse grows on Instagram I still
occasionally post stuff there so
occasionally it's not if you follow me I
definitely still scroll it at lunch time
and went on the pooper so I'll
definitely like your pictures and have
followed back thanks for coming and
hanging out you bet you bet thanks for
having me you guys we're gonna wrap up
this part and I'll be right back all
right podcast rolled I want to thank you
guys again for listening to this episode
I want to thank Jesse for coming and
hanging out for a long time you guys I
just took a dab of coffee nectar it's
labeled alien cush and alien og the
flavor is described as a dark roast
coffee and watermelon candy I definitely
get the dark roast coffee there's no
watermelon candy on my palate but it did
taste like a creamy mocha coffee it was
really delicious I've never had a dab
that tasted like coffee before great
work by Green Dot labs that was
delicious you guys once again thanks for
listening make sure you support our
friends to hella dank seed company you
can find them at dank seed dot store I
would appreciate it if you follow me on
all of the social media you can find me
on Facebook simply search for the grow
from your heart podcast you can find me
on instagram it's IRA underscore
genetics you can follow the show on
Twitter it's at G fyh podcast and you
can follow me on Twitter if you'd like
it's at Rasta Jeff 4:20
if you've got something you'd like to
say and you're not into the social media
or perhaps you'd like to sponsor the
show or maybe you've got a product you'd
like me to review you can send me an
email it's grow from your heart at
hotmail.com you know I would love to
hear from you don't forget that every
episode of the show is archived on
YouTube make sure you subscribe to the
YouTube channel simply search for the
grow from your heart podcast on YouTube
also if you feel like this podcast was
educational entertaining or informative
and you would like to make a financial
contribution you can do so by going to
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
all the information that you need will
be right there and I do appreciate all
of the patreon support you guys know
I'll be back in a few days with a fresh
new episode I will get back to those
grow lessons I think I have got the
equipment dialed in as long as nothing
went wrong with this episode I think I
have got it figured out then I'm gonna
order the replacement part and then
we'll get that one dialed in it's all in
fun ladies and gentlemen thanks for
sticking by my side I do appreciate the
support that's it for this episode I
want to give a huge shout out to Hoosier
bud and until next time take a phat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]