hey everyone it's three toks and you're
tuned in to the growth in your heart
podcast yeah welcome back podcast world
it's time for a fresh episode of The
Grove from your heart podcast your
source for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower if you're a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
dedicated dabber if you're a cannabis
activists or even someone who is just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you I'm your host my friends call me
Rasta Jeff I want to thank you guys
again for joining me this episode of the
podcast is brought to you by our friends
at the hell a dank seed company if you
need new regular or feminized seeds for
your garden I highly recommend the hell
a dank seed company and you can find
them at dank seed dot store
ladies gentlemen boys and girls smokers
and growers roll up a fat spliff and
bust out a pen and paper because it's
time for a fresh episode of the grill
from your heart podcast welcome to the
podcast everybody just a quick intro
today I have a lot planned for you you
know I like to start the episodes off by
letting you know what I'm smoking on
today I'm taking dad's of member berry
nectar from Green Dot labs member berry
is from our friends at the ethos
collective member berry is skunk berry
cross to the mandarins sunset that's a
great cross the description on the
package says it will taste like cheese
Smarties candies orange peel and
overwhelming fruit punch you know I
would have to agree with that as soon as
you open the concentrate container a
smell of cheese hits you right in the
face it's not it's kind of like a a
sharp cheddar comes right out of the
package right into your face you get the
sharp cheddar then you lean in and you
smell more and that's when the candy
flavor kind of comes in you get that
Smarties
maybe a fruit punch flavor there then
when you dab it that's on the Smarties
candies the overwhelming fruit punch
takes over and then after the exhale
that orange peel kind of kicks in so
it's a really complex flavored
concentrate I really enjoy it and now
this Graham is not gonna last long I'm
gonna smoke this [ __ ] out of that so
ladies gentlemen I'm smoking on the
member berry nectar from Green Dot labs
and his great concentrates I've got a
lot of information to pack into this
episode so let's move right into the
I'm sure a lot of my listeners already
for a deep dive into some grow lessons
so let's get right into it and let's
talk about enzymes in growing cannabis
all right before we get into this I do
need to give some credit I always shout
out to green culture magazine.com I
wanted to give my brain a refresher and
enzymes before I recorded a show I typed
in growing with enzymes on my google
browser and the first article that came
up was green culture magazine.com
I honestly went through several articles
and this article explained it the best
the most thorough accurate simplest
understandable description so I borrowed
a lot of the information from this
website please don't accuse me of
stealing it telling you straight up this
was my source so green culture
magazine.com is where the bulk of this
information was updated from in my brain
so I owe them a shout-out there is my
footnote to start the show all right now
let's talk about enzymes what is an
enzyme now don't worry if I lose you
here in the beginning because eventually
this will all click and I promise it
will make sense by the end what is an
enzyme enzymes are proteins made of
complex chains of amino acids folded
into shapes that resemble a pacman now
that doesn't mean a lot to a lot of us
right now you've got you see what it's a
protein it's a complex chain of amino
acids and it's shaped like pac-man
okay now that pac-man idea triggers
ideas in my head really quickly on how
to teach things enzymes are in your root
zone they're in the soil eating the bad
[ __ ] they're packed Manning up all the
dead roots they're packed Manning up all
the things we don't want in there the
enzymes are eating that stuff and
basically just in they're eating the
ghosts and the dots that's what these
pac-man shaped proteins are in there
doing now let's talk a little bit more
about enzymes enzymes help break things
down they also speed up the breakdown
process enzymes can also modify and
create other organisms enzymes occur
naturally and are necessary to all life
forms without enzymes life as we know it
probably could not exist
in nature bacterial microbes and fungus
excrete enzymes that live in symbiosis
with other living things until recently
scientists could not create enzymes they
can only harvest them from living
sources so now let's talk about some
actual uses of enzymes the most common
commercial uses of enzymes other than
alcohol production you need enzymes to
create alcohol enzymes are heavily used
in the alcohol industry but other common
uses enzymes were heavily used for
making laundry and dish detergents are
the enzymes and get in there and help
break down the old food or the organic
matter or whatever is stained on your
plate but the enzymes will wipe that
food right off of there or if you've got
some dirty clothes the enzymes will get
in there and break down that dirt and
that funk and get that [ __ ] right out of
your clothes so enzymes were used in
making laundry and dish detergents
enzymes are also used in septic tanks to
help break down the waste even further
so if you live in the mountains and you
don't have plumbing you've got a toilet
hooked up to some piping that goes to a
big tank that's buried underground and
basically when you flush the toilet all
your poop goes into this big tank and it
sits in this tank underground and it
does decompose over time but they fill
it with very specific enzymes and those
enzymes eat your poop and it dissolves
that poop right up so you don't get an
overflow from your septic system so
that's the sort of stuff that enzymes
are good for I've seen enzymes sold as
supplements in health food stores to aid
in digestion they offer the most common
that I've seen is a papaya enzyme it
comes in a tube or not a tube but a roll
it looks similar to like a tums or an
antacid of some sort and it's got that
foil thing around it and you unwrap it
you break one out of that and you chew
on it and they don't taste too bad
they're kind of chalky kind of powdery I
think there were mango and papaya over
the flavor that I had you chew on those
and the enzymes that are in there are
supposed to aid in food digestion it
helps you digest your food more smoothly
more quickly and it also is supposed to
help you uptake your nutrients more
thoroughly I didn't notice anything when
I ate it but I worked at the health food
store and they were samples so that's
I tried but that is another use for
enzymes all right I feel like now we
were becoming more familiar with an
enzyme we know what the enzyme actually
is and we understand a few practical
applications of the enzyme so it
shouldn't sound so foreign to us at this
point now let's talk a little bit more
about enzymes in cannabis growing
enzymes are very limited on function and
what that means is a cellulose enzyme
can only break down cellulose and
nothing else so you need specific
enzymes to do certain functions now an
enzyme can repeat its function millions
of times but it can also be deactivated
or destroyed by other enzymes by pH
swings by temperature or by a myriad of
other options that could happen in a
grow environment enzymes are fairly
stable but they are also slightly
delicate so let's talk about why we use
enzymes why are we buying enzymatic
products to add to our feeding solution
why are we doing this enzymes aid and
simple tasks like getting rid of dead
roots or more complex tasks like
accelerating plant growth and assisting
in hormone biosynthesis the most common
reason for adding enzymes to a high
performance garden is to keep the medium
clean no I talked earlier about using
enzymes in our septic tank and I talked
earlier about using enzymes in laundry
detergent and then I also talked about
using enzymes as a dietary supplement to
help people digest food and absorb
nutrients better now if you think about
all those uses we can kind of see how
that would transfer to our cannabis
plant if the enzymes are helping people
digest food and absorb nutrients better
that's probably gonna happen to our
cannabis plants now let's think about
that septic tank the enzymes are in
there breaking up the poop breaking up
the dead stuff that we don't want now
when your plants are growing some of the
roots are gonna die that is natural
you're gonna have Deacon decomposing
matter in your root zone those enzymes
are gonna get in there and eat that
stuff up and turn it into usable fuel
before it's able to become a problem
that is a vector for problems pathogens
and disease when you've got something
decaying in your root zone so these
enzymes will get in their own logo hey
look at that [ __ ] nom nom nom nom and
they'll chew it up and they'll turn it
into plant energy for your plants now
the same thing with the laundry
detergent it's getting in there breaking
things down it's cleaning it up it's
gonna get in there and break things down
and clean up your root zone so in short
terms these enzymes are getting in there
and acting like those Scrubbing Bubbles
remember the old commercials with the
scrubbing bubbles at Scrubbing Bubbles
and pac-man getting in there and eatin
the ghost eating the dots scrubbing the
bubbles getting the dead poop out
getting those dead roots out and keeping
your root zone healthy and clean so
enzymes kind of acts as a protectant may
be a security guard of sorts against
disease and pathogens within the root
zone so they're acting like those
Scrubbing Bubbles there and they're
scrubbing the problems out maybe those
dead roots are ghosts and little
pathogens and disease are the little
dots and they're just pac-man in the
[ __ ] out of those little things in there
just miss pac-man and pac-man just in
there to live in there pac-man Midway
life just chasing those ghosts around
alright let's get back on track you guys
earlier I mentioned that specific
enzymes can only perform specific
functions some enzyme products break
down dead roots some enzyme products
break down bad bacterias some enzyme
products help improve soil health by
breaking down dead material into useful
sugars and minerals now how do I know
which enzymes I need and which enzymes
I'm getting each company has their own
proprietary blend of enzymes that they
put in the bottle I'm gonna talk about a
test in a few minutes on ways we can
tell if there are a couple of enzymes in
there but basically unless you can do
these tests we've just got to trust
these companies but we'll talk more
about that in a minute so basically
enzymes act as an accelerator for
chemical reactions that are produced in
the soil and they do that by breaking
down or speeding up the breakdown
process of dead root matter of bad
bacteria of things that are unwelcome
and unwanted and they turn that into
usable sugars and minerals for the
plants so they're in there turning funk
into food for you is basically what your
enzymes are doing now most of your
commercially available bottled nutrients
are going to be made through
fermentation they ferment vegetable
which creates a Trichoderma which allows
the enzymes to spread they keep that
production happening then they collect
the enzymes into a bottle then they
dilute it then they sell it to us well
then they sell it to a distributor who
sells it to a gross store who then sells
it to us after it's been shipped across
the country so it's hard to know if the
enzymes in that bottle are even alive by
the time it makes it to us and it's hard
to know what's even in there
so you can make your own enzymes you can
make enzymes with a Bokashi bucket i've
talked about the Bokashi bucket before
some of that leachate stuff that comes
out that juice that terrible smelling
vomit poop smelled juice that comes out
that is loaded with enzymes there's a
lot of great stuff in there it's a good
portion of enzymes I've used that stuff
if you have a clogged drain the enzymes
in that boat Kashi bucket will dissolve
a funky clog in your drain so that tells
you about the enzymes that are in there
if you're gonna use that in your plants
use it very sparingly a very little bit
per gallon of water I put maybe an ounce
and a 25 gallon container of water so
you don't need a lot of that stuff but
you can make your own enzymes through
the Bou Kashi bucket they're just as
effective and they were basically free
and they're actually I think you're
making money doing that because you're
putting food scraps that would have gone
into the trash into the bowl Kashi
bucket so now you're making money
because you're not putting something
into the trash or reusing a product
you're turning it into something that
you're gonna feed your plants now you
and your plants are eating the same diet
it's gonna make you think a little more
about it and it's gonna make you take
better care of yourself and your plants
and it will encourage your dietary
decisions when you're shopping because
you'll go to buy something and you'll
say oh I can't put that in the bowl
Kashi bucket and he'll start eating more
raw healthy foods it'll be good for you
so it's a chain reaction when you
started loving the plants and realizing
what goes into these plants you say why
do I spend all the money on the best
nutrients but then I stop at [ __ ]
McDonald's and feed myself [ __ ] you're
gonna start feeding yourself the top
shelf nutrients also so let me figure
out where I was in this rant and we will
get back on this you can make your own
enzymes with the Bokashi bucket if
you're not familiar with the Bokashi
bucket it's really easy to find do some
simple research on that it will change
your growing life also another very good
use of bottled enzymes
is if you are going to recycle cocoa or
if you're going to recycle your soil I
highly recommend you mix up some water
and while that cocoa or that dirt is
still in the pot let's say you've
harvested the plants you've got that
little nub of a stick sticking out
you're gonna carry those pots off to
wherever and then that soil is gonna get
recycled if you don't have a container
to dump all of that soil into while it's
still in the grow room run a strong feed
of water and just enzymes through those
plants mix up if it says 2 mils per
gallon do 4 put 4 mils in there and just
water those plants till you get a bit of
a little bit of runoff there's no plants
in there it's just a pot with dirt in
there those enzymes are gonna get in
there if you plan on recycling that soil
or recycling that cocoa that's gonna get
in there and break down all the dead
[ __ ] all the leftover [ __ ] that you
don't want it's gonna clean that stuff
right out of there if you're gonna
combine it all together into a giant
container if you can do that
stir it up get it all combined then run
the enzyme water through there do that
but that's gonna be a much larger
container of water to deal with you're
gonna have a much larger mess you're
probably used to watering 9 or 10 3 or 5
gallon pots already so that's probably
easier for you to do so that's a good
way to recycle your soil now earlier I
mentioned that we were going to talk
about a test to determine which enzymes
are actually contained within the
bottles that we are purchasing I'm not
gonna talk about any branding because
that is up to you to do your shopping do
your research just buy quality enzymes I
don't know who to recommend right now
because I'm making mine with the Bokashi
bucket there are several brands out
there I'm not sure if you're getting
anything extra when you buy those really
expensive brands there may be selling
you the exact same thing as the lesser
costing brands I don't know what's in
there but we're gonna talk about a test
to determine what is in our enzyme
bottles now this test will tell us if
the enzymes we purchased are able to
break down cellulose and Hemi cellulose
which are two components of route
material now the first test pour some of
your enzymes into a small dish and
simply drop a small square of paper into
that dish
now the enzymes have to cover and coat
this little piece of paper now once that
happens if the
paper is destroyed and eaten up by the
enzymes that is proof positive that
there are enzymes in there that are able
to break down cellulose now the second
test will be done to determine the
presidents of hemi cellulose and i may
be saying that wrong if I'm saying hemi
cellulose wrong please do correct me so
that I can sound smart in the next
episode here's what you do
get some applesauce and pour some of
that enzyme product right into the
applesauce
don't pour into the whole jar you guys
get a little dish just a little
container of applesauce and pour some
beer your enzyme product into the
applesauce now if the apple sauce
becomes liquidy if it eats up the chunks
of apple and just makes it a liquid you
can see that there are enzymes in there
that are able to break up hemi cellulose
so you can visually assess that those
enzymes are there and working now this
may not work with all products and if it
doesn't work it does not mean there are
not enzymes in your product it just
means that cellulose and Hemi cellulose
are not present or active in the product
which you purchased now we talked about
it earlier there are many different
kinds of enzymes and each has its own
specific function or a specific target
now we also know that plants create
their own enzymes so if the brand of
enzymes you're purchasing doesn't
contain a specific enzyme don't be
afraid to get another product an
enzymatic product and back it up with
that one I don't think you can overdose
these plants with enzymes they'll all
balance each other out they'll all be
used for something if one isn't needed
another enzyme will probably destroy it
and turn it into something that is
needed for the plants at that time so
some products that are sold as enzymes
are not even enzymes but they're blends
of microbes and fungi
but when they work properly they will
populate and secrete the enzymes that we
need but that's only possible if the
microbes are still alive and they're
able to reproduce fast enough to be
useful and like I said earlier you don't
know what's in that bottle until you do
a test on your product yourself at home
alright you guys that was about 17
minutes worth of information on enzymes
again I'm not going to recommend an
enzyme product for you do your research
find the one that fits your budget there
are bottles of enzyme
all the way from $13.99 all the way up
to $399 for the same sized bottle so
don't get sticker shock do a little
research find out what's in there find
out what's gonna work for you once
you've selected a product I recommend
use either half or the regular
recommended dosage on the bottle if you
want if it says pour in 2 mils per
gallon try it out pour in 2 mils per
gallon you probably don't need that much
they want you to use extra so that you
will buy more but like I said earlier I
don't think we can OD the plants on
enzymes so if the bottle says mix 2
milliliters per gallon into your feed
solution just makes up your nutrients
like you normally would put your base
your [ __ ] micro your bloom boosters
put it all in there then add the
required amount of enzymes just go ahead
and pour that into your measuring
container drop it right into your
nutrient solution mix it up now adjust
your pH just like you normally would go
right down the day you started adding
enzymes to your mix and feed your plants
just like you normally would and now
start paying attention start seeing if
the plants are any more vigorous start
seeing if you get new root growth see if
you have more shoots see if your buds
are bigger just pay attention to this
grow and see if there's any noticeable
difference in the performance of your
plants or the potency or the harvest
weight just pay attention to what
changes when you start introducing
enzymes to your feeding schedule all
right you guys I know it was a short
episode but I don't want to start
another topic when I'm 19 minutes into a
show so we're gonna wrap it up here I
want to thank you guys for listening to
this podcast I hope you learned
something if you've got something you'd
like to add or if you've got questions I
would love to hear from you my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com please reach out do not be
shy also don't forget to support our
friends at the hello tank seed company
if you need new regular or feminized
seeds for your garden I highly recommend
the hella dank seed company you can find
them at dank seed dot store also I would
appreciate it if you follow me on all of
the social media you can find me on
Facebook simply search for the girl from
your heart podcast you can find me on
Twitter it's at G fyh podcast if you'd
like to follow my personal Twitter
account it's at Rasta Jeff 420 and you
know I would love it if you follow my
Instagram on Instagram I use my other
company name it's Irene or genetics i
RIE underscore genetics check me out on
you can watch my live feeds I go on
Instagram live I answer Gro questions I
take dad's I talk about what's going on
with the day
I just hang out with my friends and
chill out it's a little less formal than
this and it's a lot of fun so I invite
you to follow me on Instagram and check
out the live feeds again that's Irie
underscore genetics like I said before
if you'd like to reach out and you're
not into the social media or perhaps
you've got a product you like me to
review or maybe you'd like to sponsor
the podcast you can send me an email
again the email address is grow from
your heart at hotmail.com I'd like to
remind you again about the patreon
campaign if you feel like this podcast
was educational informative and/or
entertaining and you would like to
contribute to the show financially you
can do so by going to patreon.com slash
grow from your heart all the information
that you need to sign up will be right
there
you guys when you become a patron of my
patreon campaign I offer several tiers
of rewards I will do things like give
you a shout out on the podcast I will
make sure to put your email question at
the top of the list
I also offer things like FaceTime garden
consultations if you'd like me to look
at your garden all you have to do is
contact me message me through patreon or
send me an email and I will take a look
at your garden through FaceTime and if
you've got a problem or if you'd like to
make some improvements I can look at
your garden through a FaceTime
conversation through a Skype call
through a Google hangout call some way I
can see what's going on your grow maybe
you can show me your plants and we can
talk about how to improve your setup
and/or situation I'm not sure what else
to offer as my patreon rewards or my
gifts or my returns whatever you'd like
to call them but if there's something
you'd like to request don't be shy reach
out to me my email address is grow from
your heart at hotmail.com or you can
simply go to patreon and send me a
message through that service and I will
get back to you
maybe you need your outgoing voice mail
greeting recorded - hey it's Rasta Jeff
and you just reach Bobby and he can't
come to the phone maybe need some [ __ ]
like that or maybe somebody you really
love or care for has a birthday coming
up and they're a fan of the podcast or a
fan of IRA genetics maybe you could get
them like a video birthday card maybe I
could record them a message be like yo
what's up Billy
I heard at your birthday take
fat dad and give your mom a hug for me
and take a dad and blow some smoke at
him maybe you can do something like that
let me know what you're thinking reach
out I would love to accommodate your
needs and put a smile on your face
all right podcast rolled I think that's
all I've got for this episode I want to
thank you guys for listening I know it
was a short episode but I think it was
packed with enough information to make
it worth putting out this short episode
I don't want to get started on a whole
new topic right now I wrote a lot I said
a lot my brain and mouth are done so
thank you guys for hanging out I'll be
back in a few days with the fresh
episode I want to give you a huge thank
you shout out to my friend Roger and
until next time take a phat dab and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]