what's a podcast world it's time for
episode 343 of the growth from your harp
podcast your source for cannabis news
education and conversation let's write a
prune new grower if you're a
professional grower if you're a new
smoker or a dedicated dabber if you're a
cannabis activists or even someone who
is just curious about the current state
of cannabis this my friends is the
podcast for you I'm your host my friends
call me Rasta Jeff I want to thank you
guys again for joining me this episode
of the podcast is brought to you by our
friends at the Hell a dank seed company
if you need new regular or feminized
seeds for your garden I highly recommend
the hella dank seed company and you can
find them at dank seed dot store ladies
and gentlemen Rowlf a phat spliff pack
up the bong or start heating up that dab
nail because it's time for a fresh
episode of the grow from your heart
podcast welcome to the show ladies and
gentlemen it's time for episode 343 of
the girl from your heart podcast thanks
again for joining me this episode of the
show is brought to you by our friends at
the hell a dank seed company if you need
new seeds for your garden I highly
recommend the holiday exceed company
once again you can find them at dank
seed store I recommend you check them
out because they have got a fresh drop
of Irie genetics all right you guys know
I like to start the episode off by
letting you know what I'm smoking on
I've got a fresh new pick up of some
concentrates I grabbed some lemon
Versace nectar which is a mix of lemon
oh gee and skittles when I brought this
home and took a dab of it I hadn't read
the package yet to see what the flavor
description was I was just excited I was
like a lemon Versace I want to dab it
that psycho home it took a fat dab in
the lemon Versace
it tasted like I described it as a burnt
marshmallow with lemon juice on top of
it it was pleasant and I enjoyed it but
it was very unique so then I grabbed the
package and I looked at what it's
described as and it says unique lemon
profile sweet sour candied and burnt so
I definitely picked up on the unique
lemon profile and I got the burnt the
sweet sour and candied I didn't really
notice much of but that burnt
marshmallow flavor was kind of pleasant
I've never had that and a dab before so
that was nice the thing about the lemon
Versace it didn't do much for me high
wise it didn't get me high it did not
medicate me it didn't really do a whole
lot i had taste amazing it taste
really good but it doesn't do much for
what I'm trying to do I'm trying to get
high I'm not just trying to taste it I
also picked up some infinity Oh G nectar
which is a combination of underdog og
and i-95 this is described as a gas and
earth I popped this open it took a fat
dab of this and it was tremendous
earthy gas all over my tongue all in my
face the high was incredible the
infinity og nectar was really nice so
what I decided to do you know me I took
a good sized a dab of the infinity og
nectar and then I dunked that right
inside of the lemon Versace nectar and I
took a dab of that combo and that is
like a lemon gas punch to the face and
it gave me a super nice flavor it had a
tremendous face high too and it went
right to my face right to my head that
was an amazing combo so the infinity og
put the punch in there and put that gas
in there and then that lemon Versace put
that lemon Skittles candy Terp it kind
of washed out that burnt marshmallow and
brought out more of the candy flavor it
was a really good idea I thought to mix
them so that's what I'm dabbing on you
guys the infinity og nectar and the
lemon Versace nectar combination from
Green Dot labs obviously it's got me
nice and rambly which is good because
this is going to be a long podcast I've
got a great topic to get into but first
let's talk a little bit about what I did
Thursday evening well you guys were
hanging out listening to the new episode
of the show I was in Denver
seeing wheeler Walker jr. at the Gothic
theater now if you know who wheeler
Walker jr. is you're probably going what
Rasta Jeff went to a country concert and
if you don't know who wheeler Walker jr.
is let me explain to you that Rasta Jeff
went to a country concert I've never
referred to myself in third person like
that that was awkward
anyway yes I went to my very first
country concert I saw wheeler Walker jr.
and two other acts at the Gothic theatre
in Denver Colorado ah I went to see
wheeler because I think wheeler Walker
is hilarious he comes out dressed in
full cowboy [ __ ] rebel cowboy outfit
he's got his boots and his tight jeans
and his [ __ ] belt buckle that you
could use as a dinner plate then he's
got a long-sleeved flannel shirt tucked
in and he's got it buttoned up all the
way to the top and then he's got the
cowboy beard that's well-kept you know
to me
it's just long enough to say I'm a rebel
[ __ ] but then it's kept nice and
tight also he's got that big bushy
mustache
he's got them cop glasses looking at you
and he's got his big wheeler Walker
junior cowboy hat on and he comes out
and they started playing this if you're
I'm not into country music necessarily
but I don't hate country music I'm a
musician I've been I've been hired to
play in country bands before and you
learn to appreciate it and it's not bad
especially the [ __ ] wheeler does it's
kind of it's the fun kind of country
it's that rowdy [ __ ] I guess it's
called rebel countries what they call it
I'm not a country fan but I think so he
comes and he does this like rock and
roll country [ __ ] right then he starts
singing lyrics that are just ridiculous
and we'll get into that here in a minute
let's talk more about the show and then
then we'll top this off with some of the
song titles and some of the lyrics so I
Drive up to Denver I park as I'm walking
in I realize I am the only dreadlocked
guy in the building I'm the only one
there that is not a country music fan
and so far I'm the only one I've seen
that is there for the joke that is
wheeler Walker jr. and I'm kind of
feeling a little bit out of place the
first band was straight-up country they
were [ __ ] good you guys they were
really good they were so soulful the had
a singer that played acoustic guitar had
a full band bass drums lead guitar but
the senior played acoustic guitar and
they had a female singer that sang with
him that I'm going to assume they were
related they had to be brother or sister
somewhere along the line they've been
singing together for years cuz they
sounded rich like the sound that came
out of them was real they sounded really
good so I don't know the name of the
opening act I apologize for that I
didn't pay any attention to that I was
just trying to get comfortable in the
environment I've never been in that
environment it was a lot of country
fancy guys it was folks in tight jeans
and flannel shirts and [ __ ] beards
and a wad of chew and a hat in their
face and that's not my environment I
don't know how they're gonna take me
encroaching on their show so I'm just
trying to walk around and like you know
get a feel am I welcome and I was I was
so it was kind of silly on my part to
feel that these country fans may not
want me there they didn't give a [ __ ] I
got a few looks well I've got dreadlocks
to my ass I get looks but nobody gave a
[ __ ] that I was a weirdo at the country
show so that was cool then the second
act came on and
spent the first since I just snuck in
during the first ban I don't like to go
walk right in front of people while the
band is playing so I just went toward
the back of the club and got a big view
of the whole Club and then as the first
band picked up their gear
I walked closer to the stage and got a
little up closer and then the second
opener came out and he was not very
entertaining the crowd was talking over
and then kind of they were they were
bored with him and he could feel the
vibe but then someone lit a joint in the
crowd or some weed somewhere and the
country crowd got really weird about it
and the funny part is it was bad
smelling weed it smell like a shitty
Roach or it just didn't smell like good
weed and someone lit weed in that
country crowd kind of got uptight you
can see there kind of some of them are
like someone's smoking weed and some of
them like Oh someone's smoking weed but
it was kind of a it was way different
than the shows I'm used to when someone
smokes weed nobody even notices because
we're all smoking weed but it was just
really funny to smell somebody light
some schwag weed and then watch the
whole crowd kind of look around a couple
of them looked right at me like no I
could see both his hands I knew better I
was gonna [ __ ] smoke weed in there be
the only one in there and they run you
through a pretty rigorous security thing
on the way in but it turns out that
second opener that came out it was one
guy he came out and played a couple of
songs by himself he ended up actually
being wheelers bass player so when
wheeler came out that was the bass
player for wheeler Walker juniors band
anyhow so the first opener was cool the
second opener was awkward it was just
one dude singing songs playing the
guitar he played bass and sang a couple
of times which that's not really a
popular thing to play bass and sing
someone like weed then a couple as the
night went on and things got later more
non country fans came more people that
look like they discovered wheeler
through Joe Rogan's podcast more people
that look like they discovered wheeler
Walker jr. through Joey Diaz his podcast
or Chrysler's podcast which are all
places where I've listened to wheeler I
first found wheeler through the Joe
Rogan experience podcast and I really
liked his songs I started listening and
I thought it was funny and then he was
on Diaz a show and so I listened there
and I just kind of like solidified the
songs were in my head and the dude's
attitude was kind of funny so I had to
listen from there anyway more people
started piling in as the night went on
that were obviously not country fans or
at least they weren't dressed in the
tria tire that some of the earlier
arrivals were dressed in nothing against
them it's just obvious country attire
and I'm guess I'm ordering hippie or
look at tire whatever you want to call
it you could you could spot the
differences in the folks so a couple of
younger cats stood in front of me and
I'm wearing a girl from your heart
podcast t-shirt and one of the younger
bros turns to me and he says whose
podcast is that I was like oh that's my
show bro it's all about weed and we
start talking for a few and they're like
what other shows do you listen to and I
was like ah dude I listen to Doug loves
movies Ellison to Diaz actually they
asked me if I listened to the Church of
what's happening now and my answer was
probably [ __ ] yeah [ __ ]
because if you listen to the Church of
what's happening now that's your answer
if somebody asks you if you listen to it
you say [ __ ] ya [ __ ] so that
started conversation two young dudes
named Doug and Daniel they were a good
time to hang out with I went to the show
by myself so it was cool to have two
dude show up right in front of me that
were fans of all the other stuff I
listen to they were fans of wheeler
because of the funniness not because
it's the new kind of country music and
they also are exposed to the podcast now
so shot it to Doug and Daniel I hope you
guys are listening to the show so our
conversation gets interrupted because
[ __ ] wheeler Walker wants to come out
and do a concert right so the lights go
down a wheeler comes out and he starts
playing honestly what might be my
favorite wheeler Walker song it's called
songs actually called sit on my face
we're gonna get into that in a little
bit here and I posted a couple of really
cool videos to YouTube I hope you guys
enjoy that so wheeler comes out he plays
his first song at the end of the first
song he's like why are you flipping me
off and some girl in the crowd has been
flipping him off for the whole first
song so he kicked her the [ __ ] out which
kind of made it awkward but then he went
right back into the show which was kind
of cool he played a bunch of great songs
- guys I've got a list of the songs on
my phone I'm gonna pull it up here but
he played a brand-new weed song he's
like hey since I'm in Colorado I figured
I would debut my new weed song and I was
smart enough to pull out my phone I got
a pretty sweet recording of that so
that's up on the YouTube channel then he
played more songs they were listed on my
phone I'm gonna read some of those
titles let's do that now let's see some
of the songs he played her aha finger in
my butt he played a song called eatin
[ __ ] and kickin ass and the Encore
was [ __ ] king and then the other one of
the encores
I'm not even gonna say the [ __ ] name
of the song because it's kind of
offensive I don't even want to say that
on my show so you could tell he comes
out and he plays his country music right
the whole band is dressed country it
looks like you're at a [ __ ] serious
country show and this dude starts
singing and he starts singing about like
I said the first song is called sit on
my face this song is straight-up about
sitting on my face and it's really
hilarious the way it does it because
it's it sounds like you're gonna hear
some of those 20 [ __ ] truck broke
down dog ran away girlfriend left me
kind of [ __ ] rebel rock and country
things coming out but it's not it's it's
really hilarious so one of the things
that I really laughed at he does a song
and he at the start of the song he goes
this one is for your whole family and I
knew it was gonna be it's a song called
family tree and it is a filthy song
about [ __ ] his way up your family
tree and that's literally what it's
about and one of the lines is if I had
my druthers I'd but [ __ ] both your
brothers yes that's what this man wrote
for his country song I didn't write
these lyrics I only laughed to them and
reported them to you but he says if I
had my druthers I'd but [ __ ] both your
brothers then I'd find your sister and
take her out back and fist her and the
funniest [ __ ] part of the evening was
when this theater filled with people
dressed in country folk attire they
looked like great hard-working people
including they're really cute those
little country girls are adorable little
jean shorts a little tank top and a big
old country smile and they got that
sweet accent they just smile at you
those country girls are [ __ ] adorable
but then they when he says take her out
back and fist her the entire theater
every person in there did their own sort
of animated motion of a fisting motion
there were a couple of uppercuts there
were a couple of like the guy did the
move like he's putting on a rubber glove
there everybody did some sort of fisting
motion and it made me laugh so hard it
was some of the funniest should I've
seen in a long time it was unplanned it
was uncor graft but just imagine a
country looking audience everybody looks
all nice right they got a beer in their
hand their shirts are all nice they look
[ __ ] good tonight and then this dude
says take her out back and fist her and
everybody made the goddamn fist her
motion it was hilarious
it was truly hilarious to me that's
I was therefore I wanted to go see what
that was like live in person I honestly
thought it was gonna be a sausage fest I
thought there's gonna be like 40 dudes
up in the front but that place was
packed I was a very toward the end of
the night it was quite a diverse crowd
it wasn't all country fan folks there
were a lot of people that I would assume
found wheeler through the podcasts like
myself and just wanted to go see this
it's kind of comedy it's hilarious I
love music I love comedy when you mix
the two that's some of my favorite [ __ ]
and just seeing a theater full of people
singing along to songs like drop him out
drop him out is about letting me see
your boobs and redneck [ __ ] it's just
about redneck [ __ ] and eating [ __ ] and
kicking ass was one of the funniest to
see just seeing these little country
girls singing and eatin [ __ ] and
kicking ass was so hilarious you guys it
was really funny so it was a really
affordable show I couldn't believe how
cheap it was I definitely got my money's
worth they cost me more in gas than it
costs to get in the show so that was a
good time I know a lot of people are
gonna say country music I can't stand
country music it's it's just a thing in
your head that has a label and you
decide you don't like it because it's
got that label on it if you can if you
can appreciate the [ __ ] rhythm and
then you can go listen to the words that
are happening on top of it and put the
whole picture together it will make you
giggle it will make you laugh at some
funny [ __ ] so that's my experience in my
first country show I don't know if that
totally counts cuz it was a wheeler
Walker jr. but it was pretty damn close
it's as close as I think I'm gonna get
but I had a good ass time so Shantanu
wheeler Walker jr. and his band and also
shout-out to the gothic theater you guys
this podcast may get long because I am
going to do a long talk after I take a
DAB and a drink I'm gonna do a talk
about genetic drift we're actually gonna
change the terminology we're gonna
change your mind we're gonna change your
thought process on genetic drift stay
tuned I'll be right back
[Music]
all right podcast world I am back I am
well hydrated and heavily medicated
thanks for being patient with me while I
got my life together momentarily while I
was gone I took some dabs of this custom
oh geez nectar it is a blend of skittles
and half go and Larry oh gee the flavor
is described as assorted hard candies I
didn't really get the assorted hard
candies at the label describes it's more
of a it's kind of a fruity sort of a
thing which I guess could could
translate to fruity candy but it's more
of a fruit kind of a floral nectary kind
of a thing I'm enjoying it I this is a
good high kind of mellowed me out not as
super high speed as I was before so that
should be good for this portion of the
podcast before we took a break I tease
that we were going to talk about genetic
drift and I said we were going to change
your mind about genetic drift let's get
right into it I've got a lot of notes on
the iPad for this one so let's start
with what is genetic drift or what do we
think genetic drift means some growers
believe that cloning plant over multiple
generations will lead to a loss of plant
vigor health or potency so imagine if
you've got a plant and you want to grow
it again right so you can take a clone
off of it then you flower that plant out
now you've got a clone that plant grows
up you take clones off of that you
flower that out now you've got clones
and preservation you just keep repeating
that process some folks believe that
over time that will lead to problems
which is known as genetic drift now
cannabis is an annual plant meaning it
would only live for one year or one
season naturally our natural growing
season outdoors is dictated by the Sun
the natural cannabis plant life cycle is
usually about six to eight months long
without any human interaction
depending on where those plants are
located from the from the equator in
relation to the equator they may be
shorter or longer just based on where
they are so to keep our select the
genetic library available we keep mother
plants some other plants are clones of
select cultivars that are kept in a
perpetual vegetative state by keeping
that slight cycle on for eighteen or
more hours per day
now those mother plants act as preserve
for our genetic stable and also to
provide clones for production whether
it's for flowering them out for
production or for breeding whatever
you're doing that's where the clones
will come from for the future now we're
able to grow out a large mother plant
and we can take 50 to 100 maybe even
more clones from a single mother plant
and run those for production now that
ensures that all of my plants in that
production run are the same thing
they're all tried true tested reliable
potent female plants that I've ran
before I know that they've got
resistance to pests they've got
resistance to pathogens and I know how
long it takes them to flower I know what
to look for I know when certain things
are gonna happen in the growth phase so
I'm running fifty to a hundred of the
same thing this makes my garden easy to
manage I've grown this specific cultivar
plenty of times so I know what to expect
I've got a relationship with it now so I
know that I've got a hundred of the same
thing to work with so there are no
variable so now I can hit my goals and
that makes everybody happy me I'm happy
because I've hit my goals the grow team
is happy because we likely get a bonus
the owners are happy because they're
making more money because the store has
quality product the customers are happy
the patients are happy because they're
buying a quality product and there's
plenty of it
so it makes everybody happy when I hit
my goals as a cultivation manager now
over time these mother plants we work
with they get too large and you can't
really just keep cutting them down
smaller because they get misshapen and
they become a difficult mess they do
just have the plant with a super thick
stalk on it this just got two arms
coming off of it it's got a whole bunch
of mini arms coming off different
directions they just get messy and hard
to deal with so after a while it's time
to replace your mother plant that's a
simple process I replaced my mother
plants every three to six months ish
depending on the state of my garden and
depending on which cultivar I am working
with some things that grow super fast
like the redheaded stranger it's got to
get replaced more frequently than
something like probably the chem for the
chem for doesn't grow super fast that
redheaded stranger grows super fast the
chem for it doesn't get his root bound
as quickly that redheaded stranger will
grow up into the whites I'll top it a
couple of times it'll Bush out real wide
I'll top it a couple more
it'll push out even wider it'll start
tipping itself over I want a bigger pot
it's got to go it's either got to go in
a bigger pot which I don't really have
room for I don't need that big of a
mother plant so then it just gets
reclone doff of I cut a couple of clones
anyway we'll keep talking about that
it's time to replace your mother plants
it's a simple process Irie clone all of
the large bombs and create fresh new mom
stock so just go to all of my mother
plants and pull off like one row like
five or ten however many you think you
need for one row of your clone er just
pull off enough so that you've got
plenty of clones for that keeper pull
them off of there or if you need a large
batch like a hundred or whatever extra
take those hundred clones I'll kinda
like a hundred if I need a hundred I'll
cut a solid hundred plus a twenty extra
for backups that way if something goes
wrong then I've got some better
selection then I'll cut as many clones
as I can get off that bigger a mother
plant and then I'll use one of the
really good-looking clones as my
replacement mother now sometimes I keep
the old mom around until I've got roots
on my new clones but my clone skills are
pretty reliable so those those all those
clones I cut I'm pretty sure something's
gonna root but if you don't have super
good clone skills maybe take a few extra
clones in case something happens or the
the always the [ __ ] clones in the
corners of the trays they're always a
challenge so cut a few extras just so
you know you have a survivor if you're
cutting new mothers stock you want that
to survive so cut as many as you can and
then maybe consider leaving a little
portion of that plant alive just like
one or two small branches leave yourself
one or two more clones to cut in case
you failed and you've still got that
mother plant you can still keep that
cultivar you've got a little preserve
over there that it totally looks like
[ __ ] but it's there it exists so that's
basically my process of keeping and
replacing a mother plant it's fairly
similar when I'm doing it in a small
home grow if I'm doing it in a private
grow if I'm doing it in a breeder grow
it's fairly similar if I'm doing it in a
commercial grow when I say a hundred a
hundred and twenty plants consider that
the commercial grow all the time the
home grow it's very small numbers
nowadays they've limited us so
ridiculously in Colorado that's taking
like three clones at a time just to make
sure I've got a copy of that plan so
when I say 120 that's the commercial
grow kind of scale don't get confused
when I say smaller numbers that's the
home girl but it's all a similar process
when you're keeping
they're plants you've got a plant you
need to keep it in veg perpetually then
eventually you need to replace it so now
when we're replacing these plants we're
cutting clones from it and then we're
gonna take back clone and we're gonna
grow it up big again and then we're
gonna cut clones from it like I said
earlier if that one's gonna grow then
it's gonna we're just gonna keep cutting
clones off of clones off of clones that
starts to lead us into where genetic
drift is suspected to start happening
through several rounds of cloning and
vegging and then creating new moms and
then clones and then vegging like I said
we give the opportunity for what has
been referred to as genetic drift a lot
of growers suspect that these plants get
tired or their that their genetics
change over generations and the
subsequent generations become less
vigorous less potent and more prone to
pests and pathogens at acts now I
personally have always been skeptical of
genetic drift and I always blamed it on
poor Plant Health where I blend it on
the grower or the person who cut the
clone and I feel like most of your
genetic drift issues are probably caused
within the first 24 hours of propagation
it's probably from an experienced clone
techniques poor vapor pressure deficit
improper lighting lack of nutrients or
the presence of pathogens we're usually
my assumptions on what was causing what
people were calling genetic drift
because we would see it early on when
people were saying that they had it so
I've always been skeptical I've had my
flow plant since 2007 or 2008 I'm not
sure exactly when I got that time frame
is kind of fuzzy and of course I got a
traumatic brain injury but I know where
I was when I got it I know who gave it
to me
so I know it was about 2007-2008 ish I'm
actually running that same flow plant
for her very last time now there's
nothing wrong with her I'm just i've ran
it for so long it's been crossed with
everything it's been there done that and
like I keep saying that they've changed
the rules in Colorado it's where our
numbers are limited I would like to play
with something new and if I want to do
that I have to retire something old and
flow it's time for her to go so I'm
running flow for her last time right now
she is just a few days away from being
pollinated by King Solomon to make one
batch of piranha seeds so she's had a
long fun run but I need to move on to
something new anyway I got that flow
clone from my friend in two thousand
seven or eight ish now imagine how many
times I've had to reclone and REE mom
this one cultivar over the past ten
years it would be at least twenty times
if I've done it every six months so I'm
sure it was more I'm sure it was more
than that because there were times when
I've moved I've moved different houses
I've moved different facilities I have
taken it from the house where I lived to
the new house to the other house then I
took it from the house to the house to a
grow facility to another facility and it
still looks amazing
it still looks the same it performs
exactly as I remember in all of those
conditions it does the same thing since
I got her in 2007 somebody else was
growing her in 2007 and gave it to me
and it looks like the way that person
grew it still so again I've been
skeptical of genetic drift and I've
played with a lot of plants but since
I'm writing a podcast I have to come at
it unbiased and open-minded so I didn't
want my opinion to get in the way of the
opportunity to learn and also teach so I
did some Google research to open my mind
and I totally rattled my current opinion
I found a wonderful article on cannabis
industry institute dot-com by a guy
named Randy Robinson about genetic drift
and I wanted to share what I learned
this article says the true concept of
genetic drift started in the 1920s this
was several decades after Darwin had
already revolutionized biology with his
theory of evolution but scientists still
didn't know how certain traits were
passed on we had some clues from
Mendel's pea studies excuse me but
Mendelian genetics and Darwinian
evolution hadn't been combined yet in
the 20s biologists recognized that
certain genes and traits changed a
population without any adaptive or
environmental pressures so let's that's
where we need to make a note biologists
recognized that certain genes and traits
changed a population without any
adaptive or environmental pressures for
example let's say there are two types of
the same bird species on an island
somewhat silver
others and some with gold feathers the
color of their feathers confers no
special survival advantages and the
colors don't harm the birds either so
these colors are neutral mutations after
studying these birds for several years
we noticed that the ratio of silver
feathered Birds to gold feather Birds
begins to change there used to be a
ratio of one silver to one gold but now
it's ten Silver's to one gold nothing
happened on the island that should have
selected one color of bird over the
other
it just happened randomly this is what
is known as genetic drift today
population geneticists referred to
genetic drift as sampling error this is
something that happens with real-world
populations
no sampling is ever perfect and that's
what we're seeing with genetic drift the
sampling error happens over and over
again until it's amplified and becomes
the most prevalent or in some cases the
only gene now what does genetic drift
have to do with cloning probably nothing
because pay attention to this part
genetic drift only applies to
populations of organisms that produce
sexually so when we're talking about
cloning cannabis we're dealing with only
one organism of course we may produce
thousands of copies of that individual
plant but it's still only one plant so
genetic drift does not apply so you guys
all this time we've been saying genetic
drift from cloning that's not even
possible
because genetic drift only applies to
populations of organisms that reproduce
sexually so we are not doing that we are
cloning there's no sexual reproduction
here so that can't even apply genetic
drift is not even a label that can be
applied to this situation so that's
where we're gonna change some things
today and this was not my knowledge this
is our friend Randy and this article
that wrote this here so let's keep
moving forward the question of why all
of plants clones aren't 100% the same is
not easy to answer mainly because we
haven't studied cannabis as much as we'd
like especially in large scale grows
most of the research was performed in
labs on lower potency plants and small
sample sizes however we have taken a ton
of Rhys
on other plants it is possible that
clones are themselves producing new
genes or deleting old genes back in 2011
his study from Oxford University showed
that no clone was a perfect copy genetic
analysts showed that when genes
regenerate new tissue they tend to
spontaneously create new genes you guys
hear that when genes regenerate new
tissue they tend to spontaneously create
new genes it hasn't been confirmed
whether or not cannabis does this but it
is possible now the Oxford study called
the phenomenon regenerative mutation
some genes would be duplicated in the
process while other genes were deleted
from the clone altogether however this
study looked at the Thale cress plant
and as similar as regenerative mutation
and genetic drift may seem there's still
not the same thing so that thing we've
been calling genetic drift you guys we
have got to change the word I think that
is more appropriately known as a
regenerative mutation is what's
happening there so let's move forward
with this article it says another reason
we may see changes in some clones is
stress stress doesn't change the genetic
makeup of a clone but it can change how
its genes are expressed through a
process called epigenetics a relatively
new field of biology over the last few
decades we realized that DNA and genetic
expression are not set in stone
the experiences of a parent can change
the way their DNA is expressed and they
can pass those changes on to their
offspring epigenetics may explain why
people who experience severe trauma such
as war might be get children who are
more prone to disease and mental illness
the stress changed the way the parents
genes were expressed and those changes
were passed on to their children
again the DNA itself didn't change but
little control mechanisms such as
chemicals produced to the body are
produced by the body excuse me changed
whether those genes were turned on/off
or set to overdrive what are these
stress culprits and our cannabis plants
sometimes a mother plant just gets old
sometimes her feeding cycle has changed
or she gets sick or injured or both some
growers suspect the head
use of synthetic fertilizers or hormones
may epigenetically alter their mothers
causing the clones to lose some desired
trait when it comes to making clones
remember this the act of cloning is
Astra's a stressful act you're damaging
tissue by severing part of the plant
from itself
clones also get transplanted and
transported all over the place which can
induce stress once this happens dozens
if not hundreds of times to a series of
clones we may end up with different
qualities in our clones than we started
with
again that article was from cannabis
industry Institute calm by Randy
Robinson I hope you guys learned as much
as I did because I thought that article
got right to the point it taught me a
lot and I really enjoyed it so we can't
say genetic drift anymore because
genetic drift only happens in something
that produces sexually the new word is
regenerative mutation regenerative
mutation you guys dropped that one in
the clone room tomorrow when you're
working and watch the lead grower look
confused watch I'm looking timid ated
like ah [ __ ] this guy knows more than me
also keep in mind they mentioned the
phrase sampling error
that's from people taking shitty clones
or taking clones improperly or improper
care of plants or taking a clone from an
unhealthy mother plant that's a sampling
error and also another cause for what we
used to think was genetic drift now
we're gonna call it regenerative
mutation so that's a new conversation in
the grow room have fun with that
tomorrow now what we thought we're
seeing may be happening but we were just
identifying it incorrectly again it's
not genetic drift but a regenerative
mutation I would assume the health of
the donor plant the stress and
experience of cloning the environment
it's all got a lot to do with this
process I still suspect most of what we
see is grower error or plant reaction to
poor stress or poor environment or a
poor cloning technique or unclean
cloning area it's usually a vapor
pressure deficit issue or pest or
pathogen issue I have not some sort of
shock during the cloning process we
basically we're grabbing a plan weren't
amputating the arm and we're trying to
make it regrow so we give a lot of
opportunity for problems during cloning
imagine if I cut off your arm in the
cloner O'Brien goes think about wherever
you take clones stand in the middle
there and I'm just gonna grab a giant
[ __ ] knife and I'm gonna cut your arm
off now would you feel
clean and safe with an open wound in
that room are you cool with that like
you're gonna be like yeah this is
totally sanitary you go ahead and set my
arm on that table like do you think that
table where you set your clothes do you
think that's cool for your freshly
amputated arm like do you think that's
gonna be all right do you and then also
would you want me to cut your arm off
while you're feeling strong and healthy
like let me give you a month to work out
and get [ __ ] software when you cut it
off you still got like some strength to
you maybe we could get it
stapled back on or something and we can
get it to regenerate because you're
still young and you're still healthy and
you just got super strong and you've
been eating well or do you want us to
wait till you're 90 years old and cut
your arm off and try to superglue and
staple that [ __ ] back on when you're
using most of your energy just to live
because you haven't been eating well and
your body's all frail by now so think
about where the clones come from the
best way to prevent regenerative
mutation is to keep healthy mother
plants take your clones from healthy
mother plants have a sterile cloning
area and a solid cloning method right
some SOPs go read some cloning
techniques I'll put out another cloning
podcast a very soon here I've got one
out already I plan on putting out a
revised cloning episode here in just a
few weeks so if you see your mother
plant getting weak cut some clones right
away for safekeeping as soon as you see
you're looking shitty just take a few
clones I'm always pulling clones off the
plants all the time anyway just to have
fresh mother plants just to keep the
cycle going sometimes I know that I'm
gonna want a whole bunch of this plant
so I'll cut like four clones of that and
I'll veg those out to get them kind of
big and then I'll take all my clones off
of those four and they just become
sacrificial plants they die but then
I've got tons of clones from just get
good at cloning get good at identifying
problems and your mother plants and have
timing and know when that mother plants
starting to burn out but you also have
to be able to tell if you've got issues
you have spider mites do you have
Russert mites you have something eating
at the roots do you have a problem
making that mother plant get tired so
figure that out and if it looks like
she's healthy and she's just burning out
on you clone off of her get some plenty
of clones and then get those clones
rooted put them under a lot of light
feed them very well and get those back
to super health and then clone off of
those for your next run also if you're
doing the clone off your veg plants
clone off your veg plants going off your
veg plants again same thing just make
sure your veg plants are super healthy
you know what I mean if you're doing it
you grow your veg stock up Alone's off
of those those become the next
generation you put everything into flour
except your little clones the clones
root those become the next generation
you take a couple clones off of those
put them into the flour room you guys
understand how it goes so that's how a
lot of Perpetual groves work you guys
you're not going to get problems if you
do things correctly if you keep
everybody healthy it'll take a long time
to cause regenerative mutation problems
all right you guys that is my report on
genetic drift now known as regenerative
mutation I hope you learned as much as I
did visit the website where I found the
article that is cannabis industry
institute dot-com they have a lot of
great informative articles this was the
first time I visited the website but it
will not be the last
all right podcast wrote I'm gonna start
wrapping up the show and thank you guys
for hanging out make sure you support
the hell a dank seed company you can
find them at dank seed dot store I would
appreciate it if you find me on all of
the social media on Facebook it's the
girl from your heart podcast on
Instagram it's I read genetics ireon der
score genetics on Instagram on Twitter
it's at G fyh podcast if you want to
follow my personal Twitter it's at Ross
to Jeff for 20 give me a follow I would
appreciate that if you've got something
you'd like to say and you're not into
the social media or if you've got a
product you'd like me to review or
perhaps you'd like to sponsor the show
you can send me an email email address's
grow from your heart at hotmail.com you
know I would love to hear from you don't
forget about the YouTube channel all of
the old episodes are available on
YouTube just simply search for the girl
from your heart podcast you can find
every single episode if you guys feel
that this podcast was educational
informative and/or entertaining and you
would like to contribute financially to
the show you can do so by going to
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
all of the information that you need
will be right there
and I do appreciate all of the support
thank you ladies and gentlemen my throat
is burning out so I'm gonna wrap up this
show I'll be back in just a few days
with a fresh voice and some fresh new
content I'm gonna give you huge
happy birthday shout out to my buddy
Gibbs and until next time take a phat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
so we do that by having a mother plant
holy [ __ ] a spider just fell out of the
sky at me well that's a little clip
we're gonna have to [ __ ] save for the
end of the show or put some water that
was interesting