[Music]
welcome back cannabis community it's
time for episode 344 of the grow from
your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
let's write a few new grower after a
professional grower here a new smoker or
a dedicated adder if your cannabis
activists or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me this episode of the podcast
is brought to you by our friends at the
hell is dank seed company if you need
new regular or feminized seeds for your
garden I highly recommend the hella dank
seed company and you can find them at
dank seed store ladies and gentlemen
boys and girls smokers and growers roll
the fat split put some fresh water in
the ball or start heating up that dab
there because it's time for a fresh
episode of the drill from your heart
podcast
what's up podcast world welcome to
episode 344 of the girl from your heart
podcast thanks again for joining me you
know I like to start the show off by
letting you know what I am smoking on
today I'm taking dabs of the fatso
nectar from Green Dot labs we've talked
about the fatso nectar on the podcast
before it is a combination of GMO and
legend og it's described as dark roast
coffee garlic and fuel I think it's got
a maybe a dark beer sort of a flavor on
the inhale it's definitely got the dark
roast coffee then it's got the feel on
the exhale I leaves a little bit of a
creamy flavor a dark kind of a dark beer
sort of a thing and then that garlic
breath kicks and it's got garlic and
cookies at the end I really like it it's
got a great head high a face high it
goes to the highs I really feel it so
the fat so nectar is what I'm dabbing
today earlier I was taking dabs of some
cherry slider full spectrum extract also
from green dot it is a combo of cherry
pie Kush and joseph OG the flavor on the
label is described as cherry cola I
thought it tasted like a packet of
cherry kool-aid or maybe grape kool-aid
with no sugar it's a little lie it's a
little strong
powerful in the flavor it really hits
the tongue with that cherry candy kind
of flavor but there's no sweetness to it
but it didn't have the the medical
quality or the high I was looking for so
I followed that up with a fatso nectar
and it worked out to be a beautiful
combo so that's what I'm dabbing on
today I hope you guys are taking dabs of
something delicious up you're smoking a
blunt of something wonderful if that's
your thing I hope you're smoking a fat
joint maybe you've got the vaporizer
going wherever you are whatever you're
doing I hope you were getting heavily
medicated with me
today all right you guys let's get into
a podcast I want to start the show off
by reading a couple of iTunes customer
reviews I've got two fresh reviews since
the last time I read them on the show
and if you'd like to leave an iTunes
customer review it's really easy if
you're using your iPad or your iPhone
simply go to the podcast open up the
podcast like you're gonna play a fresh
episode click on the available episodes
tab and then scroll down and eventually
it will bring you a menu that shows the
iTunes ratings and reviews and there's a
little tab it simply says write a review
click on that and type in a review let
me know what you think about the podcast
and I will read your review on a future
episode while you're there it gives you
the option to give me an amount of stars
it's a 1 through 5 star rating so far
everybody that has left a written review
has given me 5 stars I encourage you to
give me the amount of stars which you
feel I deserve so I look forward to
seeing your iTunes customer review and I
look forward to reading your review on
the show so let's get into some of these
reviews this one comes from somebody who
calls themselves AB in hope I hope I
said that correctly this review was left
on July 26th the headline is a podcast
that leads by example of course he gave
me 5 stars and it says if you're
interested in the cannabis scene this is
the podcast for you rhasta Jeff and Mike
take a deep dive into multiple cannabis
topics each episode is guaranteed to
educate and entertain
I love rasta Jeff's authentic excitement
and passion for cannabis Mike and Jeff
help keep me up-to-date on the cannabis
scene while helping normalize cannabis
in my own life they promote family
honesty and much more respect from Cali
hey big up from California thank you for
the great review a couple things I want
to touch on there first of all you said
Jeff and Mike hey thanks for
acknowledging
that mic comes on the show Mike's got
two kids now so it's hard to get him out
of the house sometimes when he comes
over he's not in the mood to record he
just wants to chill out take some dabs
and have a good time so shout out to
Mike for being on the show when he wants
to and for putting his energy into that
i--dude thanks for acknowledging our
deep dives into the topics cuz I kind of
do go deep I want to I usually focus one
episode on a whole topic and try to get
you educated on that and then we move
forward I try not to cover too much in
one show as for multiple topics try to
get that one topic thorough so I'm glad
you notice that thank you and then he
said guaranteed to educate and entertain
that's what I'm here for I was not a
good student in school because I was
bored if my teacher would have taken a
minute to make that class entertaining I
would have learned so much more so I
feel like I keep your entertain your
attention and keep educating you by
staying entertaining throwing a couple
of jokes here say some silly [ __ ]
occasionally and that's just my
personality anyway so it works out well
so I think my learning style is probably
similar to a lot of cannabis consumers
we have to have a joke here and there we
have to have some some light to the
heavy to make it enjoyable so I try to
throw that in there so thanks for
noticing that and do thanks for noticing
my authentic excitement and passion for
cannabis that is true that will never go
away thanks for noticing that so and
also we keep you up-to-date on the
cannabis scene and help you normalize
cannabis in your own life that's very
interesting I'm glad that we keep you up
to date I kind of think that a lot of my
listeners may live vicariously through
Mike and myself and the other folks that
come on the show so that's why I try to
give detailed descriptions about what
I'm smoking and some of the weird things
that I do so thanks for noticing that
man I appreciate that and once again
shout out to Mike and normalizing
cannabis in your own life that's uh
that's an interesting statement I'm not
sure how you mean that but that is
really interesting I'd like to know more
about that also he said they promote
family honesty and much more yes it's
all about telling the kids the truth
about cannabis and doing what needs to
be done correctly so dude thanks for the
great review and for the five stars I
really do appreciate that if I can get
the iPad to cooperate we will move into
the next iTunes customer review it goes
like this this one is left by somebody
whose name is I'm the dude what's up the
dude this was left on and this is not my
friend name to the dude I do have a very
good friend known as Rob the dude this
is not from
rob the dude but either way shout out to
rob the dude the headline says ramble on
brother it sounds like you do listen to
the show because sometimes we get quite
rambley here anyway the customer review
goes like this Jeff my man I love the
podcast in all of the pictures I think
they're referring to my Instagram
pictures if you want to follow me on
Instagram its Irie underscore genetics I
post a lot of wonderful cannabis
photography I just posted a picture of
black cherry Kim that has gotten over
400 likes in about 7 hours so that's a
quality photo there on Instagram anyway
the review goes I'd love to get some
shots myself dude all you've got to do
is grow your plants take good care of
them get yourself a nice piece of
material from that's just I know I know
we had a listener say I shouldn't shop
at Hobby Lobby if you've got a fabric
store
maybe Karen's fabrics or whoever Suzanne
fabric I don't know the who the lady
with the fabric store near town but find
her get a just a nice yard of fabric
hang that up put a light right above it
get a decent camera I'm just using a
Nikon d3200 I've learned the settings on
it real well I've learned where to put
the lights put your plants in front of a
couple of really colorful tapestries or
backgrounds take some great shots and
practice man you'll get there it's just
practice it's learning the lighting the
angles and honestly the settings on your
camera once you get the camera figured
out you'll be taking great shots
he also says your show is incredibly
informative and helpful
hey that's what we're here for man thank
you and then he says keep it up man it's
always cool to find a fellow musician as
well stay Irie and rock on then he
signed his name Mike hey Mike it sounds
like we could be friends bro let's hang
out take some dabs play some music
anyway thanks for the great five-star
review and guaranteed I will ramble on
and I will keep it up dude thanks again
for listening to the show and thanks to
both of you
for the five star iTunes customer review
and again you guys I'm looking at the
tab right now if you go to the girl from
your heart podcast where it shows that
you're all caught up on listening to
episodes mine says I'm all caught up I
honestly don't listen I just delete them
but I've got to have the show in the the
queue so that I can see when the shows
pop up and I can get the links to tweet
them but if you go where it says that
you've listened to everything of any
scroll up you will see ratings and
reviews and you'll see that Todd is at
the top here he left a review four years
ago
and then right next to that it says
write a review you just clicked right on
there and it brings up the little screen
to write a review and at the top it
gives you the amount of stars so you can
right away click on five stars or
however many you feel like that deserve
type in a title for your review and then
go ahead and leave your customer review
right there then hit Send and it will
post and I will read it on a future
episode now that I'm caught up on iTunes
reviews let's work on some emails and I
want to knock out a bunch of emails
because I do have a large block of grow
lessons coming up I know I keep talking
about it I'm trying to get a few other
random topics covered get some emails
out of the way get a few loose ends tied
up and then we're going to really dive
into a long block of lessons but in the
meantime let's catch up on some emails
I've got a great message this one was
just at the top of my inbox and it goes
like this hey Rasta Jeff my name is Adam
you can say it on the show and I've been
listening to the show for a little while
now I just have to say you do an amazing
job yeah thanks for listening but I do
appreciate that
thanks for the compliment he goes on to
say I'm going through my first growth
cycle seems to be going well but I
listen to you talk about the humidity on
the podcast and I was just wondering
where you were testing your humidity
from is it floor level plant level light
level or above the lights I'm getting
low to mid 70s around the plants mid
60's above the lights it's a 5 by 5 room
with 7 Girl Scout cookies plants inside
and I'm using a 1000 watt LED light and
I have an oscillating fan in the corner
on low thanks for any help and we'll
definitely take a DAB and give my mom a
hug for you you're already on the right
path my friend so let's talk about the
humidity in your grow environment this
is a really good question because you've
probably got just a small hydrometer
it's got the temperature and the amount
of humidity it's probably there's
several different versions of this
device but it's usually about the size
of like a pack of playing cards like a
deck of playing cards maybe the size of
your iPhone
they probably hang somewhere in the room
it's got a little sensor on it that
measures the temperature and humidity in
there and it just hangs and it displays
and he probably only measures just a
small area and most people aren't
thinking about how many readings that
thing is taking and the amount of area
that is measuring in so it's a really
good idea that you
write that up I bet a lot of people are
thinking wow I've never thought of this
so they're gonna go move there a
hygrometer right now they're gonna go
change it to canopy level or they're
gonna go put it at another area anyway I
would recommend mostly paying attention
to about canopy level about the top of
the canopy down is where you really
mostly want to focus where the plants
are is where you want to focus on the
humidity level it's going to vary
throughout the room like you're saying
but it's most important about canopy
level down in through the canopy of the
plants that's about where you want to
focus on the proper humidity of course
it's gonna be a little more humid down
low because you're watering the pots and
that's where all the water is starting
it's gonna be drier up above the lights
because the water is going to rise
toward the light but it's not gonna go
past I'm talking about the evaporation
the condensation it's not gonna rise
past the light because there's no key
point up there you may get a little
pocket of stale humidity up there but
it's not gonna be as humid above the
light is it will be near the plants and
down low so I would focus more on the
humidity near the plants that's where it
matters most is right around the plants
so if probably from the top bud down to
about 18 to 24 inches down through the
whole section of the canopy you probably
got like a four by four a five by five
area in which your plants are taking up
square footage area that's where I would
mainly worry about it now I'm gonna kind
of shift gears I would check the vapor
pressure deficit of the entire room I
would move my equipment around and see
what it is throughout the room because
you may have a hot pocket in one room
you may have not that kind of hot pocket
you guys I know you're hungry and you're
stunned but not that kind of hot pocket
you may have a hot pocket in one part of
the room you may have a humid pocket in
one part of the room you may want to
move that hygrometer around that
thermometer around you want to remove it
around the room and see what's actually
going on in there you may be clueless
that you've got one corner it's not
getting any airflow and you've got a
bunch of humidity back there and it's
getting real hot back there but the rest
of the room seems just fine so this is a
great thing to bring up don't just leave
that hygrometer and thermometer in one
area move it around
and try to get the whole room ideal and
the way you're gonna get the whole room
ideal is by more airflow if you've got
it pretty good over here and it's just a
little bit off over here you can
probably balance it out by moving air
you may need to bring in more air or
evacuate more air but if you're doing
pretty close over here and you're just
tape a little bit if it's just stale on
this corner just put air flow in that
corner and get the air moving so you
quit building that humid pocket over
there you quit cooking hot pockets over
there whatever is happening so the
humidity and temperature are good things
to pay attention to in the room but also
that's going to add up to a vapor
pressure deficit that you're going to
have to pay attention to that's a math
equation that I covered on another
episode there are websites on vapor
pressure deficit if you're not familiar
with that that's something else to check
into now something else I want to think
about in this message is you're saying
that you're getting low to mid-70s
I present humidity around the plants and
mid-60s above the lights that makes
sense to me it's about 70% humidity
right around the plants and 60% humidity
up above the lights now I'm curious how
long had it been since you watered when
you took that measurement when you've
got that reading did you just water or
is it time to water because if you just
watered and you've got that 70 and 60
you might be okay but if it's time to
water and you're still that humid in
there you're gonna run into problems
you're going to have a little bit too
much humidity in there and you're gonna
want to bring that down before you get
into late flour or you run the risk of
powdery mildew of bud rot and also
you're just gonna slow down the overall
growth of your plants so it totally
makes sense to me that you're getting
two different measurements one by the
floor probably three or four
measurements one by the floor one by the
pot level one a canopy level and one up
by the lights you're gonna have
different humidity levels there you're
gonna have to use air flow techniques to
balance that out if you've got a grow
tent or a small room it shouldn't be too
hard a couple of small fans will make
that work for you
also you're gonna have to lower that
humidity you either need to evacuate
some of the stale air and get fresh air
in there you need to get a small
dehumidifier in there some way you need
to bring that humidity down
maybe minimize the amount of water you
were watering the plants I don't know if
that's an option it's just something you
can think about doing but you need to
get that humidity down before you run
into problems as I look further into
your email I'm just sitting here reading
it again as I'm talking do you have
anything on top of the grow room sucking
out stale air it says you've got five by
five rooms seven Girl Scout cookies
plants a thousand watt LED and an
oscillating fan in the corner on low
is there anything sucking that humidity
out you may need a can fan up top
evacuating cold air that's gonna be my
first recommendation now while your
humidity is that high pay attention to
your leaves
if those leaves start sweating if you
see moisture coming out of the leaves
heavily then you're getting too humid in
there if they're started getting dry and
looking leathery it's too humid in there
if you've got a spot where two leaves
are overlapping and they start sticking
together because it looks like they've
been pasted together Moisture came out
of the bottom of one leaf and stuck to
the top of the other leaf and now those
leaves have kind of pasted themselves
together that's cuz you've got two too
much humidity in there so it's going to
cause you problems and you need to get
that reduced as soon as possible because
if you get into flower that is going to
cause you problems and if you're growing
Girl Scout cookies man you're already
fighting an uphill battle because Girl
Scout cookies is not the easiest strain
to grow but the best part about cookies
is when you do it right it is phenomenal
it will sell it will move off the shelf
it will come right out of the bag into
people's pipes and you will do just fine
if you do it properly so I hope I
answered that question man ahh I want to
take readings from the entire room but
if you can't get the whole room dialed
in focus on the area where the plants
are in a small 5x5 area it shouldn't
take a lot of effort to get the room
dialed in just a couple of fans
honestly I keep talking about that
evacuation fan you need something to
pull old air out of there once you start
pulling that old air out you will see
much more performance from your plants
so good luck Adam let me know how that
goes and if you have any more questions
feel free to send me a backup email and
you guys if you'd like to send me an
email my email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com I would love to
hear from you so let's get right to the
next message
this one says what's up Rasta Jeff I
enjoy your podcast thoroughly
you definitely display a bunch of
knowledge and love to share it with the
public absolutely that's what I'm here
for man thanks for the great compliment
thanks for noticing he says highly
appreciated by many I'm sure because I
think that your inbox is insanely busy
I'll get to another question have you
ever thought to reverse a mail and then
have it pollinated by another mail yes
we've thought of that but I'm gonna keep
going with your email he says for what
reason maybe it will increase the
chances of finding crazy keeper mails
and perhaps maybe for some reason
increasing the potency of the females
due to genetic gender limitations I'm
sure you'll understand what I mean hit
me back if you don't I'm looking forward
to hearing more about the strains you've
bred and don't say my name on your show
bro Thanks
no dad's around here but I can give my
mom a hug for you the next time I see
her love peace and cannabis grease I'm
gonna scroll this right quick and make
sure that there's no opportunity for me
to have said your name I don't think you
included your name so I think we're
doing all right cool I did not say your
name now let's get into your message
here he asked if I have ever thought to
reverse a male plant and have it
pollinated by another male plant now
let's talk about what that means
reversing a plant is when I treat a
plant with a I'm using silver
thiosulfate is when I'm spraying my
plants with I use dried components to
make my own silver thiosulfate
concentrate and then I dilute it to the
proper ratio and then I apply that to a
plant and that will create a reaction in
the plant that will trigger a female
plant to produce pollen it will make
pollen sacks and pollen and that female
plant will produce pollen that does not
have any male chromosomes so we will use
that pollen to put on another female
plant and that is how we make feminized
seeds that's the short version the very
short version of it so this listener is
asking have I ever thought to take a
male plant and apply silver thiosulfate
to a male plant to turn it into a girl
so that I could do further experiments
with that female plant
now the answer is I have done the
reversal part I have actually flipped a
boy plant into a girl to give myself an
idea of what that plant would look like
as a breeding female to where if I made
and have to generation or if I use that
male to breed to some of my female stock
it kind of gave me an idea of what its
traits would be what its floral clusters
would look like what type of aroma it
would give what kind of trichomes it
would give it gives you a very good
representation of what the offspring is
going to look like and what its gonna
bring to the table
genetic wise in this new cross so I get
to see kind of an advanced look into the
genetics of the plant so I have done the
reversal to turn a male into a female
now once I got that far I did consider
experimenting but I decided to reach out
to a couple of peers and our friend
Colin Gordon at the ethos collective has
already done what you were talking about
doing and what I was considering doing
Colin is a little bit ahead of me in the
breeding game I don't mind saying that
Colin is more advanced than myself he's
done it more he's got more space and
he's got more testers he's just a little
bit surpassed me in the breeding game
I've got nothing but respect for the
dude in his company he's just been at it
a little longer than me
and I keep my stuff I do everything
myself and he's got kind of a team so
just a different approach to stuff
anyway Colin took a male and he reversed
it and then he played experiments with
it by pollinating it with a regular male
and by pollinating it with a reversed
male he played several experiments and
he said that most of the progeny came
out weak and undesirable so I'm not sure
if he was doing inbreeding or out
breeding or back crossing or what he was
trying to do with these wacky
male-female combinations and I don't
know if he was applying feminized pollen
I don't know if he was applying pollen
from the same male that had been
reversed from the same cultivar I'm not
sure his combinations but I trust
Colin's judgment most of the time well
when it comes to cannabis I trust
Colin's judgment like 99.9 percent of
the time there are some other times I've
questioned him but when it comes to
cannabis I I trust Colin's judgment so
he said that the offspring was
undesirable and I don't want to produce
more
desirable genetics and I don't want to
waste time in space so I am going to
believe Colin that it wasn't something
that would be worth my time and energy
again but I have done the first step and
the reason I reversed that mail was to
see what it looks like as a female I
wanted to see what traits it would bring
to a breeding project and that's a
really good way to get a preview so
that's a really good question and I
completely understand what you mean and
I hope I answered your question
appropriately the email goes on to say
I'm looking forward to hearing more
about the strains you've bred that's
good because I've got a lemon Jeffrey
planned to be coming up very soon
lemon Jeffrey seeds have been
re-released at the hella dank seed
company so I'm going to do a talk about
that strain very soon don't see my name
on the show do don't think you said your
name anywhere it's not even in the from
because it's just got your initials up
there so that's cool then you say thanks
no dabs around here but I can give my
mom a hug the next time I see er hey bro
it sounds like you have caught on to the
routine so thanks for the great email
thanks for the great question I'm sure
that's sparking a lot of people's minds
right now people that aren't super
familiar with cannabis and breeding
they're sitting in their cubicle or
they're driving in their car they're
going what the [ __ ] that's pretty
entertaining stuff to me that's the
stuff I like to experiment with
reversing plants advanced breeding
techniques that's the stuff I like to
get into that I don't talk about a lot
but if you've got questions on that send
me the questions I grow from your heart
at hotmail.com I'd love to hear from you
dude thanks again for the great email
and thanks for sparking my brain I do
appreciate it
you guys let's get into another message
this message comes from somebody who
calls themselves roasted and toasted
4:20 and it goes like this hey Rasta
Jeff get roasted and toasted 4:20 here
coming from deep in prohibition land
what's up out there a prohibition land
be safe and be careful please then he
says I've got a question for that pot
friendly cop so if you guys have been
listening to the show for a while you
probably remember that several episodes
back I got an email from a cop and I
read the email on the show and then he
replied and I emailed or I did email
from a cop part two as an episode and he
said he would be happy to answer
questions honestly I've had a lot of
podcast content so I haven't harassed
him about answering questions but one of
our listeners here has a question so I'm
going to read
I'll talk about it and give you my
opinion and then hopefully our cop
friend is listening or maybe another law
enforcement professional is listening or
a legal professional will hear us and
they can reply to grow from your heart
at hotmail calm and they can give us
some guidance on your question anyway
the question goes like this I've always
heard you can lock your glovebox and if
you get pulled over the cops can't
search the glovebox or trunk without a
search warrant
I've always been unclear because if they
have probable cause and such such as a
dog you know I'm not certain on that
rule I've never put my anything in the
glovebox because that's where my license
registration and proof of insurance are
I guess my license is in my pocket but
my registration and proof of insurance
are in the glovebox and I always figured
if I tried to stash something in there
I'm gonna get pulled over and that's the
first place I'm gonna reach so I've
never put stuff in there but I know a
lot of people who have this same mindset
that if it's locked they cannot go in
there that sounds accurate from my
little trust me I am NOT a lawyer
I don't even claim to play one on TV I
don't know [ __ ] about the law other than
I've watched cops a lot and I've been
pulled over a lot and from what I know
if that's locked they technically cannot
go in there also they're cops if they've
got any probable cause they can now
search if they say well I smell weed now
they can invent the odor of marijuana
and they can go through your car and
then they can ask you to unlock that and
then I don't know what happens if you
refuse I really don't maybe they if
they've got probable cause they can
probably get a crowbar and break that
[ __ ] open if they want to I really
don't know the rule the dog if the dog
hits on your car they've got probable
cause and they can go through your
vehicle so the dog is definitely the
loophole there for law enforcement and
what I've noticed is if you've got like
a quarter a weed and they say hey bro
just give me your drugs before I call
the dog because if I call the dog I'm
gonna [ __ ] you every way I can if you
got like 1/4 or 1/8 maybe just give it
to him because once they call the dog
out you're wasting a lot of [ __ ] time
and they're pissed
so sometimes it's better just if you got
a couple of grams or maybe just throw it
out I don't know what state you're in I
don't know who you are I'm not sure
your your demographic I'm not sure if
that'll work for you but it may be
better than getting the [ __ ] dog
called and going through all that
sometimes you just piss him off doing
that stuff anyway I don't know the
bottom line here if you lock like I had
a van that had a drawer underneath the
passenger seat that you could put Maps
and [ __ ] in that's where I kept all my
paraphernalia and my smoke because that
little drawer under the seat could lock
I didn't know the technicalities on that
I don't know if I got pulled over if
they could say open that they probably
could because they would just say well
you smell like marijuana we think
there's marijuana in there now that's
probable cause and that that's how it
would work I really don't know hopefully
somebody out there will chime in and
make me not sound so ignorant so grow
from your heart at hotmail.com is where
you can chime in and update that if I've
got cannabis in my glovebox and I get
pulled over can law-enforcement require
me to open my glovebox what's the
situation there show me a couple of
examples let me know how that's gonna
work all right so there is more to this
email and it goes I also want to thank
you for reading my email on your
Thursday show as well as some advice I
took from your vapor pressure deficit
podcast I've been keeping my rooms at 68
to 72 degrees and after I heard your
podcast wall at work I called my wife
and asked her to adjust the air
conditioner after she adjusted which was
a week ago I have seen my plants
completely turn around and now they are
looking super healthy at least the best
they can
since this round I tried my hand at
monster cropping so this listener
listened to the vapor pressure deficit
episode and decided to make some
adjustments based on my advice and his
plants have completely turned around so
that's great news
glad your plants are working out I'm
glad my advice worked for you and it
means a lot to me that people have
enough trusted me to go change their
entire grow based on some stuff that I
say but it always feels good to get a
message saying hey dude I did your stuff
and it worked so that feels good to me
I'm glad your plants are looking better
bro I'm glad I was able to help you out
and get you back on course then he goes
on to say during the two-month veg cycle
for the first week of flower the leaves
were mostly single leaf bud structure
type and now while budding they have put
on normal
growth that's great that means that the
hormones have all leveled out and
everything's going the way that it
should and you should have a decent crop
and the reason is plants were acting
funky you guys I don't know if he caught
that he said monster cropping that is
when you take a clone from plants that
are a little bit in the flower a little
more than a week maybe up to 14 days
I've seen him go a little later I don't
recommend it but a lot of people are
doing it and it seems to be working for
our friend who is calling himself get
roasted and toasted for 20 so in the
email with thanks great for 20 and of
course you can use my name PS I really
appreciate helping me out with my recent
germination problem and I'm looking
forward to getting roasted on that sweet
date hey dude I'm glad you're listening
to the podcast I'm glad with my help you
were able to get your grow back up to
speed and I'm glad everything is working
out for you and I hope we get some
answers on this glovebox question dude
thanks for the great email once again if
somebody wants to send me an email the
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
you know I would love to hear from you
all right I've got one more email I'm
gonna read tonight but before I do that
I want to give a couple of quick patreon
shoutouts I owe a huge shout out to john
bend it adam kay i was shot up to tyler
and a huge shout out to brett Cormier
thanks for the support you guys I do
appreciate it now let's get back into
these emails
this one says hey Ross - Jeff my name
I'm not sure if they want their name
said my name is Justin I've been
listening to your podcast for a few
months now and I am just about caught up
hey man thanks for listening to all the
old episodes have you gone to YouTube
and listened to all the way from episode
1 that's quite embarrassing but there's
a lot of knowledge there so go check
that out they continue to say I want to
say thank you for the wealth of
knowledge that you continue to bring to
the table on a regular basis hey you're
very welcome thanks for acknowledging
that I am a New York MMJ patient for
about six months or so now unfortunately
we only have pills teachers and vape
pens but I'm hopeful we will be able to
grow and smoke our own flowers very soon
hey good luck with that man that's kind
of weird that the thing that works the
quickest and most directly you aren't
even allowed to use I guess it's great
that you've got medical marijuana but
it's kind of weird without flowers I
think that's just law enforcement being
afraid
anyway let's keep moving with the email
it says listening to you and white mic
on a regular basis has inspired me to
join my local normal chapter and that's
the N o RM L chapter the National
Organization for the Reform of Marijuana
Laws and try to push for reform anyways
I've been also moved to research as much
about this glorious plant as possible I
have aspirations of being a grower and
breeder when it becomes legal here after
I got home from Iraq I had trouble
sleeping so I turned to alcohol I've
heard that story too many times and also
thanks for your service man by the way I
became overly excessive causing me to
lose multiple jobs that's an
all-too-familiar story thanks to my
friends that introduced me to the plant
hey great friends that's who you need it
and finishing up my term of service as I
no longer needed to take pee tests I was
able to stop drinking completely along
with other substances I was abusing and
I also quit smoking cigarettes I truly
think cannabis has saved my life I would
agree with you that cannabis has saved
your life I have several friends who
have similar stories to this I'm not
sure if you've ever listened to the
episode with Steve de Fino Steve de Fino
is a veteran who's got a
grapefruit-sized hole in his back you
can you could put a grapefruit in there
and put a piece of duct tape over it and
you could smuggle a grapefruit and on
this man's body where he got blown up
and I'm not making fun of the guy not
being disrespectful he would agree with
you that you could smuggle a [ __ ]
grapefruit on this man's body he takes
it very well but he takes it well for
the same reason as you because he is
able to consume cannabis to ease his
PTSD symptoms which is what was keeping
you up at night the feelings the
thoughts the nightmares cannabis is
helping him with that it sounds like
it's helping you with that I'm sorry if
I'm bringing anything back while I speak
about this but those are the things that
cannabis will help you find relief from
and it doesn't have the punishing
effects on your body your social life
your family life and your wallet as
alcohol does alcohol has a lot of long
lasting problems and it says here that
you were abusing other substances so the
alcohol was kind of your gateway drug
into some other [ __ ] because once we
get drunk we let down our inhibitions or
limits we're like I'm already hammered
why not just do this other
level dumb [ __ ] like I already did level
two done [ __ ] let's level three it and
it just starts going so it sounds like
having good friends
what's that supported you and also
introduced you to cannabis really turned
your life around so man thanks for
joining the green team also thanks for
your service once again because it
sounds like you really put it in and it
kind of messed you up so thanks for that
thanks for coming out alright and then
thanks for being on Team green with us
we do appreciate that
then he says but I digress which hey
that's just fine for this show this is
the ramble stoner podcast we don't mind
a little digress he said I actually had
two questions for you regarding
information sources and your opinion on
them he said first I enrolled in a
horticulture program at the local
college but I wanted some more specific
a some more industry specific education
so I've also enrolled in cannabis
training University I was wondering if
you've heard of it or if you can shed
your opinion on their master of
marijuana certificate alright I do have
a couple things I can touch on there I
feel like the horticulture program at
your local college is going to be more
useful than your cannabis training
university education cannabis is turning
into a commercially produced crop this
is commercial horticulture it is a
higher commodity a higher value
commercial horticulture product but it
is a horticultural product I think
taking a horticultural program is going
to be key I do find value in the
cannabis training University because
you're going to learn specific terms
hopefully they're teaching you market
stuff not just like not just grow things
hopefully you're learning the dispensary
side the terpenes the cannabinoids
hopefully you're learning body
interaction and stuff like that um then
you said I was wondering if you've heard
of it or if you can shed opinion on
their Master of marijuana certificate
I'm not that sounds a lot like a master
grower certificate that looks really
good on a resume but in social circles
here in V so Colorado kind of has a
group of stuck-up cannabis industry
people the growers breeders industry
folks there's a group of elitists
and they slash we kind of laugh a little
bit at the term master grower its Jen I
know it's just a label it's what your
paycheck says or it's what your job digs
and designation says but the term master
grower here is kind of laughed at that's
kind of a douchey thing to say it's a
bigoted ista cool thing I'm the master
grower over at this facility it just
sounds really funny to say don't say I'm
the master grower even if that's your
title on your paycheck even if that's
your title and the company in which you
work don't just don't just say leader
cultivator it sounds a lot better or
grow manager anyway I digress at this
point it looks really good on a resume
and if you were learning and you can
actually apply what you were learning it
is great but in social situations it's a
little bit awkward so put that on a
resume that will be helpful that will
help you out I don't know enough about
their curriculum to know what they're
teaching you I don't know if they're
teaching you how to grow I don't know if
they're teaching you how to clone I
don't know if they're teaching you the
evolution of the market I'm not sure
what you're learning there hopefully
it's a broad education and it's not just
too focused if it's gross stuff you'll
learn more through just getting in a
grow in doing it and by taking that
horticultural program at the college but
it's gonna look really good on a resume
if I were hiring that would say hey this
guy took a little extra and probably
already knows how to cut clone so I
don't have to teach him how to cut
clones he probably already knows what
micro and macro nutrients are he
hopefully has a little bit of pesticide
training that comes with that I really
don't know
but I would assume that you have a
little advanced training so it's gonna
look good on our resume so that may come
in handy but as for the curriculum and
what you've learned I really don't know
what they teach there so I don't really
have an opinion but any education looks
good on a resume when I'm hiring and I
would ask you questions about it while
we were in the interview room so the
second question says I want to become
more knowledgeable on as many different
strains as possible and I was wondering
where you thought I should look for
reliable info is Leafly a good source
and if not any light you can shed would
be great now Leafly is a decent source
Leafly is not the best source but they
have a lot of strains there and they do
their research pretty well they've
actually got a cup
of my strains up there and they pulled
the descriptions from magazine articles
and websites that featured my stuff and
they got it accurate I think what they
put is mostly accurate my Kabletown is
up there and lemon Jeffrey is up there
and soon a rise should be listed up on
leaf Lee if you guys haven't gone and
submitted a rise for a strain review on
lethally please do that I've done a
whole episode on the arize strain I'd
appreciate the support there but leaf
Lee is not a bad source of information I
like what I do like about leaf Lee is
that you can read customer reviews on
how it treated people if somebody bought
lemon Jeffrey you can see that people
wrote this is the best cannabis I've
ever smoked and this relieved my anxiety
and people list things I like that
however when things are crowd-sourced
there's the opportunity for
misinformation so it's great on one hand
it could be a problem on the other you
sound like an intelligent person the
Internet is a great tool for people who
are smart enough to filter out the
[ __ ] so I would start it Leafly then
I would venture out to other web sites
like seed finder dot-eu seed finder is a
great website that lists most of the
major brands and it's got like a family
tree if you want to learn about a strain
you type in we're just gonna say lemon
Jeffrey because that's where my brain is
type in lemon Jeffrey it'll show you
that lemon Jeffrey is a cross of golden
go and lemon skunk then on the same page
it's also gonna show you that that
golden goat is a cross of Hawaiian sweet
skunk or Island sweet skunk Hawaiian
sativa and Romulan then right under that
it's gonna show you that lemon skunk is
a cross of this and this and then it's
gonna keep breaking it down for like 25
or 30 lines so you can see the breakdown
the lineage way back and see how it was
made so I like seed finder EU for doing
research on strains and finding what
crosses are and finding the genetic
lineage of things also I like going to
seed vending websites like if you wanted
to buy some IRA genetics seeds or you
wanted to know something about IRA
genetics if you go to the hella dank
seed company and just click on the
strains that are available there and
they should have pretty good
descriptions because they want to sell
that and they've got a relationship with
the breeder so the breeder probably told
them that
this and this and these are the details
so they've usually got fairly good
information most of the time with that
same caveat that it's the internet and
you've got to be smart at filtering
through the [ __ ] on the internet now
another place that I can highly
recommend to do research on genetics is
breeder websites if you know what
breeder created that strain go to their
website now not all the breeders have an
up-to-date website my website looks like
[ __ ] not all of my current strains are
up there
I am not versed in internet stuff I've
got a couple of friends that do that
that are working on it for me it will be
updated I focus on the grow I focus on
the podcast my website looks like [ __ ] I
am sorry but some of the more
established and guys that have been
longer around for a longer time they've
got great websites sub cool has a great
website greenhouse seeds has a great
website of course DNA genetics has an
amazing website folks like that have
great websites you can rely on the
breeder website because we're putting
the info up there ourselves
and why would that be wrong so Leafly is
not a bad place to check out strains
seed finder dot edu breeder websites and
vending websites the places that sell
seeds holidaying seed company i don't
endorse buying seeds from overseas but
the atitude seed bank has all the new
[ __ ] listed if you want to go see what
they've got listed there you can
probably find a lot of genetic
information there but again always
cross-reference your research when
you're working with cannabis because
people are stoned and people will
believe [ __ ] anything honestly if I
told you I got this clone from DJ Shore
and DJ short got that clone from edy
Rosenthal in 1972 and then I took that
clone and I bred it to wedding cake
yesterday and I've gave you seeds you're
gonna believe it people will believe
[ __ ] anything so people are really go
about and you can tell them anything so
the stories get really convoluted and
[ __ ] gets really convoluted and
distorted in the cannabis industry and
there's a lot of egos and dick swinging
a dick slinging and [ __ ] talking and
backstabbing so stories get mixed up a
lot so if you want to know about
genetics get as close to the breeder as
you can for the information because the
closer you are to the source the less
that telephone game has been played like
by the time you say it's a it's a
blueberry cookies s1
then somebody else says it's a blueberry
cross two cookies and it's a r1 so
they've already [ __ ] it up you know
what I mean and then you're like yeah
it's blueberry cookies - that's a
blueberry cross - cookies it's an f-1
and you're like oh now it's really
changing it just takes three or four
conversations before you've got a
totally different cross with different
traits and different colors and a
totally different conversation with
somebody who's never seen or grown the
plant that's just how the cannabis
industry works so I hope we do a lot of
research and cross-reference things but
Leafly seed finder breeder websites and
of course vendor websites are great
places to do research and it just
occurred to me that I should not
overlook the power of social media if
you want to know about the newest
hottest most current strain that came
out today social media is where you're
gonna find that so I would follow some
of the bigger accounts on social media
follow all the guys I mentioned DNA
genetics greenhouse seeds maybe you
don't support them maybe you're not into
what they've got but if you're
interested in genetics those are the
guys to follow and then once you follow
DNA genetics greenhouse seeds TGA sub
cool all the other seed breeders are
gonna start popping up in your
recommendations follow all of them then
you'll get to see all the new stuff guys
like coma guys like the jungle boys and
there are probably 10 or 20 new breeders
that just popped up on Instagram just
now while I was recording this but
you'll want to follow that it got the
brand new hype [ __ ] if you want to stay
on top of all the brand new current
strains but it sounds like you're a
really intelligent person and it sounds
like you know how to do research and it
sounds like you know what you're looking
for so I think with a few links I gave
you I think you're off to a great start
and I think you're gonna be a great
asset to the cannabis industry once it
becomes a viable option where you are so
he wraps up the email and he says thank
you again for all that you do for the
industry it's very uncommon these days
for people to share information so
valuable free of charge you are truly an
inspiration hey man thanks for the huge
compliment thank you for listening it is
free because I feel like if I didn't do
this podcast I might explode something
would go wrong I've been a musician for
most of my life and I feel like if I
don't play music every so often that I
just get angsty and my body gets tense
and I feel weird I feel like the podcast
is
an extension of that if I don't put out
all this knowledge and all this info I
feel like I'm just selfish and stingy
and something's gonna just blow up
inside me so I got to put it out there
and share it with you guys so thanks for
noticing and thanks for the great email
if you have any more questions man send
me an email it's grow from your heart at
hotmail.com all right you guys that's
all the emails I am going to read on
this episode before I start wrapping up
the show I owe a huge thank you to a new
friend of mine
I got a great painting in the mail if
you follow my breeding work I recently
bred a couple of new strains there's a
pair of strains in there called bebop
and rocksteady one of my friends got a
pack of the bebop and a pack of the
Rocksteady and grew it out and they were
happy with the results so they were kind
enough to paint me a picture of bebop
and rocksteady they're kind of stared at
me right now you can tell they're nice
and stone they're kind of surrounded by
weed leaves but it looks exactly like
the bebop and rocksteady that we
remember from being kids and the
painting is great it's got a lot of
purple going on I really love the color
scheme they did a really good job so I
want to give a huge shout out the dude's
name is Matt Mar Sango and on Instagram
he is mm a RS ang om Mar Sango on
Instagram so make sure you check him out
dude once again thanks for the great
painting that thing is awesome and I
truly appreciate the gift all right you
guys now is the time when I start
wrapping up the podcast make sure you
support our friends the hell a dank seed
company if you want new regular or
feminized seeds you can find them at
dank seed dot store if you're listening
to this episode when it comes out on
August 20th
they should have lemon geoffery seeds in
stock at dank seed dot store so hit them
up I would appreciate it if you find me
on all the social media you can find me
on Facebook simply search for the grow
from your heart podcast you can also
find me on Instagram it's ireon der
score genetics and on twitter it's @g f
YH podcast if you want to follow my
personal account it's a trois to Jeff
420 I would love the follow and if you
felt like this podcast was educational
informative and/or entertaining and
you'd like to make a financial
contribution to the show you can do so
by going to patreon.com slash grow from
your heart all of the information that
you need will be right there and I would
appreciate your support and
give a huge thank you to everybody who
has been supporting the show through
patreon thanks a lot for all of the love
and support you guys again if you want
to send me an email or if you'd like to
sponsor the show or if you've got a
product you'd like me to review once
again the email address is grow from
your heart at hotmail.com do not be shy
ladies and gentlemen that's all I've got
for you thanks for listening to a long
episode I'll be back in a couple of days
with fresh new content I want to give a
huge shout out to my friend LS love from
medical marijuana radio and until next
time take a phat dab and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]