welcome to the show cannabis community
it's time for episode 345 of the grow
from your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
that's right if you're a new grower if
you're a professional grower if you're a
new smoker or a dedicated davor
if you're a cannabis activists or even
someone who is just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host my friends call me Rasta Jeff I
want to thank you guys again for joining
me this episode of the show is brought
to you by my friends at the hell a dank
seed company if you need new regular or
feminized seeds for your garden I highly
recommend the hell a dank seed company
and you can find them at dank seed dot
store ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls smokers and growers roll up a fat
spliff put some fresh water in the bong
and start heating up that dad nail
because it's time for a fresh episode of
The Grove from your heart podcast
what's up podcast world welcome to
episode 345 thanks again for joining me
you know I like to start these episodes
off by letting you know what I'm smoking
on I just took a ridiculous dab of some
infinity Oh G nectar from Green Dot labs
this is a combination of underdog og and
i-95 the label describes it as gas and
earth and I completely agree it's gas
and Earth and a little bit of a punch to
the face I'm always a fan of underdog og
that's also known as a lupus headband
and I've always been a fan of the i-95
both of those strains have got a gassy
fuelie funky kind of Kimmy kind of smell
and aroma and flavor to him and that's
right up my alley so the infinity og
nectar is a beautiful blend I definitely
approve you can tell it's got me rambly
but that's a good thing because this
episode is about one of my favorite
things a lot of my audience has shown
that they really enjoy when I do strain
reports if you're not aware already I am
i read genetics I am the breeder and
founder and sole proprietor of I read
genetics Colorado I do all of the
breeding work I do all of the selection
I do the mail selection the female
selection I do all the pollination I do
all of the seed collection I do all of
the packaging I handle all the emails
and social medias just about everything
except distribution is all on me but
over the years working as I region etics
I have developed quite a few notable
strains and I keep mentioning that you
guys like it when I do strain reports so
that's where we are we are going to do a
report on lemon Jeffrey let's talk about
one of my proudest and favorite crosses
and let's just do a side rant because
I'm famous for that [ __ ] also somebody
asked me what my favorite strain was and
I said I couldn't decide on my favorite
strain they were asking my favorite
strain I've bred I could not decide I
said I would give them my top three
favorite my top three favorite strains
that I have bred in no particular order
are the lemon Jeffrey arise and of the
grateful dog and I can tell you really
quickly why those are my top three
favorites the lemon Jeffrey is my
favorite because that lemon flavor that
limonene flavor that smooth lemon candy
the high - it is beautiful it makes my
eyes
it's fun to grow it's really easy to
grow it's really photogenic it makes
great concentrates and it really does
what I want and a plant overall so it's
got that lemon candy and I named it
after myself
lemon Jeffrey at the time that everybody
was naming strains after themselves
Arion had a strain scott had a strain I
wanted a strain and instead of just
doing a Jeff Shoji or something like
that I went with the lemon Jeffrey so
the lemon Jeffrey is one of my top three
favorites then on the same totem pole
there or on that same pyramid we have
got the arise arise is one of my
favorites because I did exactly what I
was trying to do with that cross I
thought what if I take a really indica
dominant wide leaf shorter stockier
plant and I cross it with this really
skinny leaf and the other male that I
used was like gassy and cushy and feet
smelling and the female that I used was
tropical and sweet so I was like what if
I cross those two it should make
something completely in the middle that
is totally unique and it did exactly
what I was trying to do so and and it
tested amazingly high it's not rare to
see a rise testing in the 27 to 30
percent area so a rise test super high
and it tastes really good and it's a
beautiful blend of that indica sativa
mix which is kind of what I was trying
to do there so it worked out beautifully
than the Grateful dog that was my first
feminized project and it went well and
the aromas and flavors that came from
that were just amazing the colors that
come from those plants were just amazing
and being my first feminized project
that I worked with and the first thing
that when we're at a party and nobody
had any herb but me and some buddies
like anybody got any weed and I was like
sure let's smoke some weed now like we
got to go in the backyard and I win the
backyard and I sat down on the steps to
it bust up my weed and put some in the
pipe and they're like holy [ __ ] as soon
as I cracked it open everybody at the
party was like damn that smells so good
and it was I felt the same way but I
didn't know it was that potent yet until
I had taken it out in the public and
everybody in there in that area was a
smoker we had all smoked plenty herb and
they all reacted heavily to the aroma
and flavor and the potency of that
grateful talk so I knew I had something
special there there's a whole nother
story that I'm going to share with you
guys about grateful dog in the future
but that's a great
Bulldog episode we're gonna focus on
lemon Geoffrey so the top three would be
lemon Geoffrey arise and the grateful
dog now let's continue and let's talk
about that lemony goodness my namesake
lemon Geoffrey lemon Geoffrey is only
available in feminized seeds lemon
Geoffrey is a cross of lemon skunk and
golden go my lemon skunk is from
greenhouse seeds my lemon skunk plant is
a beautiful plant it produces super
frosty buds that smell like lemon candy
and I always describe it as if you take
a box of lemon heads and pour the candy
out and then just smell the inside of
the box that sweet soft smooth lemon
candy smell that's coming from my lemons
skunk plant I've had this lemon skunk
for probably seven or eight years and
I've used her in a lot of crosses so she
smells amazing
but this lemon skunk plant grows kind of
tall kind of stretchy kind of extra
branchy and she doesn't put out enough
yield for how much space she takes and
she also flowers for too long but she
produces a lot of resin and she smells
amazing and I love the way it smells so
I chose to breed with her I chose to
breed it to my golden goat I have a
golden goat female let's talk about
golden go for a little bit golden goat
is island sweet skunk Hawaiian sativa
and Romulan it is a tropical smelling
sativa dominant plant that doesn't get
super tall it stays short and stout
because of the romulan in there if you
don't give it enough light it will
stretch and get tall on you but golden
goat will stay short and stocky if you
top it and give it plenty of light and
room to spread out if it doesn't have
room to spread it will go up but if you
have space for it to go out it will go
out and if you teach it to go out if you
train it it will spread so golden goat
likes to finish around eight weeks you
can let it go nine weeks if you really
want the lemon skunk on the other hand
that sucker could go ten weeks you could
let it go longer if you wanted and it
would really pack on the weight but the
romulan in the golden goat side of
things really keeps the flowering time
down so the golden goat has a tropical
delicious flavor it's shorter it's more
stout and it produces a lot of weight
some of my heaviest harvest
have come from golden goat I used to run
just lights of golden goat because I
could just pull huge harvest I could get
almost 3 pounds per light under the old
school single-ended bulbs back in the
day when everybody else was striving for
- I was pulling 2.6 and three pounds of
light with crops of golden goat in seven
gallon pots so those are the two parents
they're both females we'll talk about
that in a second my goal in this cross
was to take that lemon skunk smooth
sweet flavor and mix it with that
tropical flavor of the golden goat while
making more robust plants I wanted to
put some vigour and some beef into that
lemon skunk that lemon skunk is so
dainty and skinny and it just takes off
and grows straight up into the lights
but it doesn't produce a lot but the
aroma and the frost were so phenomenal
that I just had to work with it so I was
trying to make my own feminized golden
goat seeds because I had posted pictures
of my golden Goa crop and everybody went
nuts and wanted golden goat seeds so I
was making golden goat feminized seeds
now when I make feminized seeds
I always think why not put a couple
other plants in here do some thinking
about it and make some unique feminized
crosses while I'm at it I knew that this
lemon skunk and golden goat would pair
well I just knew it's something it's
like being a chef it's like being an
artist it's like being a musician being
a breeder sometimes you just know and
I've noticed that a lot of great
breeders are also chefs there's just
something with the palette you just know
that this and this are gonna make
something phenomenal and I hit the nail
right on the head with this one so now
let's talk about I said earlier both of
these are females the lemon skunk is a
girl it came from a seed the golden goat
is a clone only there's no male if the
golden go unless you get a back cross or
unless you reverse it which is what I
did I mixed my own solution of silver
thiosulfate and I applied it at very
specific rates and intervals and
dilutions and I turned my female golden
goat plant into a male that produced
pollen they only contained female
chromosomes so that when I pollinated my
female plant all of the seeds that came
out our only females and that cross is
the lemon Jeffrey that lemon skunk
female cross - the golden
go reversed male is the lemon Jeffrey
and that would be known as a lemon
Jeffrey r1 because it is technically a
reversal you see a lot of packages
that'll say whatever arise f1 or rise f2
or golden goat bx1
this is a lemon Jeffrey r1 alright
that's enough about the background and
parents of lemon Jeffrey let's talk more
about the plants themselves you won't
see a lot of morphology or different
phenotypes from the lemon Jeffrey it's
basically that perfect 50/50 mix of
lemon skunk and golden goat the plants
grow like those short stout Christmas
trees and if you cut the top off the
lower branches meet up at the top nice
and even and make a very beautiful nice
canopy you can leave that top glory bud
and it will produce a giant but up there
at the top but if you cut that main top
out and let all those bottoms catch up
you'll produce a big sea of beautiful
colors it'll produce nice long Spears
and it likes to be topped and it likes
to be trained and spread out so most of
the phenotypes are gonna have that
Christmas trees sort of shape to them
they're gonna be kind of branchy but
they're not gonna have a super dominant
top that apical top isn't gonna try to
stretch way above the rest of the plants
until late flower it's gonna turn into a
giant bud but through most of veg and
early flower it's not gonna take off
real tall late in flower that sucker is
gonna be a giant baseball bat up on the
top there but if you top that one you'll
get a whole bunch of arms just sticking
up and they'll be huge now there will be
a couple of weirdos in the mix you'll
see some weird leaves because that
golden go passes on some weird traits
but I've noticed in golden go across as
those super skinny leaves often have
more THC they've got more potency to
them the thinner the leaf the more
potent also the longer they take to
flower so you may see some weirdness
from the golden goat in some very rare
phenotypes you may also see phenotypes
that produce extra nodes and extra
branching I really like those phenotypes
those are great for commercial
production because I feel like more
nodes and more branching is room for a
more production you'll see what I'm
talking about when that pops up that is
a good sign if you see that I describe
it as most plants put off nodes at the
north south east and west positions
sometimes golden go across
we'll throw out a 5th and 6th set of
branches so instead of just a cross up
the stem of the meristem you've got more
of a spiral happening like a spiral
staircase of branches and it gives you
the opportunity for more production so
those are the basic Fino typical traits
of the lemon Geoffrey it's mainly a
50/50 mix of the lemon skunk mom and the
golden goat dad being a feminized cross
there's not a lot of room for a whole
bunch of variation in there however I
did mention there will be some mutants
from the golden goat background now
let's talk about the height of lemon
Geoffrey lemon Geoffrey will be fairly
tall at the end of flower but you will
have giant buds if you're not using any
trellising or sticks or netting of some
sort it's got the opportunity and the
potential to double in size through the
flowering cycle so be prepared for tall
plants maybe flower early if you're not
going to use a trellis or a straw or tie
these plants down in some way also if
you're gonna have that giant glory but
in there you're gonna need to flower
early because they're gonna get tall
that middle bud is gonna get huge if you
don't cut that main top out so the
plants will get fairly tall with
moderate stretch and flower they will
stretch on you if you don't take that
main top out I recommend spreading the
branches out if you're just using
individual pots put a bunch of sticks in
there around the perimeter of the pot
put them outward and then just spread
those branches out so that the whole
plant gets a lot of light clean up the
bottom quite a bit and let those long
arms develop long giant spear buds so if
you don't have some sort of trellis or a
tomato cage use some sticks and spread
out the plants real wide lemon Geoffrey
can cover some distance and it likes a
lot of light the more light you give it
the happier it will be if you take care
of lemon Geoffrey you should get fairly
generous yields I can get huge harvests
off of it in 3 gallon pots I can get
huge harvests and 7 gallon pots I've ran
it in private grows I've ran in-home
grows I've ran it in commercial grows
I've bred with it
this plant puts out generous harvests
even if you're a beginner grower you
should be able to get great harvests off
of this plant
now being a sativa dominant hybrid I
would recommend letting this plant go
around 70 days it may be ready around 63
I would recommend closer to 70 days you
will have better results of course
that's up to your schedule it's up to
your nutrients it's up to your
environment it's up to your lights
everything will make a difference there
but 63 to 70 days is what I would
recommend be patient because right at
the end there they may pack on a little
extra weight the lemon Geoffrey may bulk
up for you get a little chunkier right
at the end of flower and also she looks
so pretty right at the end of flower
when you're flushing her out and she
starts getting all chunky and those the
ends of the leaves just start turning
yellow and they start to curl down cuz
that's what she does at the end the
leaves get long and they just curl down
toward the end and they get real pale
and those buds are giant and bright
green it just looks so pretty at the end
if you let it go ten weeks so 63 70 days
that's what I would recommend for a
flowering time let's talk a little bit
about feeding lemon Geoffrey I have fed
the crap out of this plant and she seems
to be able to take a feeding although
all of my feeds are very well balanced I
do go high in PPM's but I'm not over
doing any one particular nutrient but in
my experience lemon Geoffrey can take a
heavy feeding and I would start off
feeding or strong because like I said
she goes 70 days and she'll need some
nutrients for the end so make sure you
get her fired up in the beginning our
plants uptake about 90% of their
nitrogen during the vegetative phase so
make sure you're feeding your plants
plenty of nitrogen in the vegetative
phase before flower to give them plenty
of energy you want to get that plant
ready to go don't OD your plants don't
think well Rasta Jeff said to feed them
a lot so I need to go in there and
[ __ ] slam them but make sure they're
getting fed appropriately at least make
sure you're giving them enough n P and K
and maybe some cal-mag and then
definitely take care of the roots put
something in there for the roots some
sort of root inoculants some sort of
microbial some sort of root booster you
want something that works on the roots
for your plants that's what I recommend
as a bare minimum but make sure your
plants are healthy before they go into
the fly into the flower phase especially
with a longer flowering plant like the
lemon Jeffrey it's gonna take 70 days
you want it to have plenty of nitrogen
you don't want to be chasing it you'll
see around week three for maybe week
five it starts fading already and you're
feeding it right but you're like what
the [ __ ] it looks like I've got a
deficiency it's because it just went
nitrogen deficient on you because it
took off you weren't prepared you
weren't giving it enough nitrogen late
in Flour or late in veg and possibly
early in Flour so feed your plants at
linden Jeffrey can take a lot of feeding
is my point to that rat also make sure
your pH is on point lemon Jeffrey and my
experience likes to be somewhere between
six point two and six point four in
cocoa or soil so when you mix up your
nutrients get everything all mixed up
the way you need it then get your pH pin
see what the pH is use your pH up or pH
down put a few drops in there until you
get it somewhere between six point two
and six point four that's where those
plants are going to want that solutions
where they're gonna react the best for
you they're gonna go crazy when you get
it dialed in pay attention to them and
write it down
write down the pH and then pay attention
to how they grew and then the next time
maybe if you went six to this time write
it down and see how the plants reacted
the next time adjust your solution to
six four and water the plants and write
down six four and see how the plants
react if they go if they if you can see
a difference
stick with what worked better right
obviously it's trial and error when
you're learning with cannabis anyway
make sure you get the pH correct make
sure you get the feed dialed in then for
sure got a sound like Brendan Schaub for
sure make sure you flush the [ __ ] out of
your lemon Jeffrey plants this strain is
known for its delicious lemon candy
flavor let's not ruin that by failing to
flush our plants at the end and making
it taste like burnt ash or something
funky like how much molasses did you put
in here at the end some [ __ ] like that
how much worm castings was in this mix I
don't want anybody to say that how much
cal-mag did you feed these plants you
don't want that make sure you flush it
you want it to taste like sweet lemon
candies not like botanic hair at the end
of the harvest so that sounds like a
good way to segue into the flavors and
aromas of lemon Jeffrey I know I say it
a lot but I think it smells and tastes
like if you took a box of lemon heads
and you poured those lemon heads on the
table and you just smell the inside of
the box if you squeeze it that soft
lemon head lemon sorbet kind of candy
smell that comes out it's also sort of
like country time lemonade powder if you
take the cut
time lemonade powder and you pop it open
and just stick your head in there and
give it a light smell don't inhale too
hard you don't want to snort up any of
that [ __ ] that's gonna burn ponies smell
that country time lemonade powder that's
kind of what the lemon Geoffrey smells
like or also maybe a lemon car air
freshener or also some of that
lemon-lime Gatorade powder and maybe
it's got a hint of sweet tarts in there
it's got that aftertaste that after
aroma of sweet tarts that's usually the
flavors that I experience with lemon
Geoffrey now let's talk a little bit
about the effects of lemon Geoffrey I
really prefer like a sativa heavy high
THC lemon-lime flavored kind of a strain
for my daytime smoke some people may
find lemon Geoffrey to be too potent
attests in the high 20s consistently 24
to 28 I've seen 28% THC a sometimes
that's too much for people I think it's
great it makes me feel euphoric and
talkative and energized some people it
makes them a little anxious I've noticed
that the people that are already going
kind of fast the people that are real
talkative and that have a lot of
thoughts and have a lot to say and are
always speaking a lot I feel like the
strains with limonene things like lemon
Geoffrey and lemon skunk I feel like
those strains sort of even those people
out it balances their conversation it
slows them down and it puts them more on
a focus thing instead of just being in a
spin it kind of gives them a target and
they can kind of quit talking at
everybody and kind of look at a person
and talk to a person I think that the
lemon Geoffrey and the lemon skunk kind
of do that but that's just for the that
fast minded talkative kind of a person
with that creative just non-stop kind of
a mind people that don't consume a lot
of cannabis and people that are already
kind of quiet people that can get
jittery and anxious sometimes the lemon
Geoffrey may kind of give you a little
bit of the sweats and a little bit of
the nerves because it is a quite potent
strain for me it's a beautiful morning
smoke I love that lemon flavor in the
morning it wakes my brain up it puts all
the pieces of my puzzle I feel like
overnight my brain just fell apart the
puzzle pieces went everywhere I feel
like the lemon Geoffrey just puts the
puzzle pieces right back together for me
so for me lemon Geoffrey puts me right
in that sweet spot for other
it could be too much I could make you
super giggly it could make you super
paranoid it will definitely make you
talkative and energetic so let's talk
about some of the medical effects of
lemon Jeffrey I am NOT a doctor I am
reading these effects off of Leafly so
the effects that have been reported to
Leafly about lemon jeffrey are it's good
to relieve stress which i believe
because limonene the terpene found in
lemon Jeffrey has definitely been linked
to stress relief they are actually doing
scientific research on terpenoids and
limonene has been proven to help with
stress relief so that definitely is
believable the next thing on the list is
depression of course if you're not as
stressed you're not as depressed and if
you're giggling and smiling you don't
feel depression so I believe that lemon
Jeffrey could help ease the effects of
your depression also it says here
headaches I know for sure that golden
goat crosses will help with migraines
I've seen it work on multiple people so
it says here that lemon Jeffrey will
help with your headaches I completely
believe that also lemon Jeffrey has been
known to help prevent seizures in folks
with epilepsy so that is a great medical
quality of the lemon Jeffrey again I am
NOT a doctor these are just things that
have been reported by consumers and
patients to Leafly I am just sharing
that information with you your
experience may be different that's my
little disclaimer here so those are some
of the effects reported from lemon
Jeffrey while I'm here on the Leafly
website let's read a couple of their
reviews I just saw they have a bunch of
reviews on lemon Jeffrey the first one
says lemon Jeffrey is an awesome
energetic and chill mode strain
depending on your mood I'm speaking for
serious smokers that can smoke and
harness the effects of high THC levels
that's a great review this one says
great strain this has been so helpful to
start my day and helps my pain and keeps
me focused and increases my appetite
which I need hey that's a cool review
this one is the best though this one
says best strain I have ever tried made
everything so uplifting that's a really
cool review to see on a strain that you
bred so all those are from Leafly big
shout out to our friends Ely fleet comm
for having lemon Jeffery up there I'm
hoping they will put a rise up there
before too long all right you guys
that's a quick breakdown on the effects
and flavors of lemon Jeff
free I think that covers most of the
details let's talk about a little tips
and tricks with lemon Jeffrey lemon
Jeffrey is great for concentrates if
you're trying to make BHO or rosin or
full-spectrum extracts lemon Jeffrey is
a great strain for extraction I'm
looking at a lab test on my phone and
I've got a concentrate test from a
friend who I'm not sure if they want
their name mentioned on the show they
know who they are shout out for the
great word bro I've got a lab test that
is showing eighty six point six total
cannabinoids with seventy five point
four percent THC the terpene test is
showing three point four six percent
terpenes and that is from a lemon
Jeffrey concentrate sample so the lemon
Jeffrey makes wonderful concentrates it
always tastes super good it always gives
me an amazing high the lemon Jeffrey
concentrates make my eyes jitter they
make my eyes jump up and down like
remember when you were a kid and used to
ride the school bus and he'd lean your
head on the window and your eyes would
jump up and down a little bit and
everything would move around real weird
that's kind of what it feels like when
you first take your dab of lemon Jeffrey
everything goes you got to grab the
table and get your [ __ ] together it's
real nice I really enjoy it so it makes
great concentrates one great thing about
lemon Jeffrey is it takes heat very well
lemon Jeffrey is known to get kind of
tall so it's gonna grow right toward
those lights it will take that light
heat fairly well I'm not saying put it
up against the light but if it gets too
close and it gets kind of warm it's not
gonna get too crazy and get too mad on
it
I feel like limonene is a heat reaction
and a heat response it's a stress
response in the plants and I think if we
stress it with light and heat a little
bit it will create a little more
limonene in the plants have you noticed
if you put your plants too close to the
light sometimes they'll tastes lemony
even if they're not a lemon strain well
if you do it with a lemony strain it
will even more lemon it so they take the
heat very fairly well they are kind of a
sativa dominant so they're not super
tight they don't have gigantic leaves so
you're not running a lot of problems and
that higher heat they can take it all so
I've never seen powdery mildew on a
lemon Jeffrey plant before so those are
a few tips those are a few pointers with
the lemon Jeffrey run it for
concentrates run it for flowers make
sure you take pictures and make sure you
flush it so that you get that delicious
lemon candy flavor
all right you guys that's all I've got
for you about lemon Jeffrey thanks for
hanging out thanks for listening to me
ramble about one of my creations if
you're looking for lemon Jeffrey seeds I
recommend the hell a dank seed company
and you can find them at dank seed dot
store and make sure you tell them but
you're listening to the grow from your
heart podcast ladies and gentlemen I
would appreciate it if you find me on
all of the social media you can find me
on Facebook simply search for the girl
from your heart podcast you can find me
on Twitter it's at G fyh podcast if you
want to follow my personal Twitter
account its at Rasta Jeff 420 give me a
follow I will follow you back also I
recommend you follow my Instagram feed
on Instagram it's Irie underscore
genetics come follow me on Instagram
check out the Instagram live feeds come
hang out with us I take some dads I do
some grow talk you can throw me
questions in the Y feed I will do my
best to answer your question on the fly
I don't do research I don't have any
notes people ask gro questions I do my
best to answer the questions off the top
of my head and it's a lot of fun
sometimes we get silly sometimes we get
goofy sometimes we talk about growing
sometimes we talk about random [ __ ] so
come hang out it's Ayari underscore
genetics on instagram please give me a
follow if you'd like to say something
you're not into the social media you can
send me an email let's grow from your
heart at hotmail.com you know I would
love to hear from you also if you feel
like this show is educational
informative and/or entertaining and
you'd like to support the show
financially you can do so by reaching
out to us on patreon all you have to do
is go to patreon.com
we'll be right there I want to give a
big thanks to everybody who has
supported the patreon campaign thank you
your contributions mean a lot to me you
guys I'll be back in a few days with a
fresh new episode my throat is burning
out I want to give a huge shout-out to
my friend Scottie real from the dude
grows Scotty's had a couple of medical
issues and I just want him to know I'm
thinking about it so shout out to Scotty
and until next time take a phat dab and
give your mom a hug for me