[Music]
welcome to the show ladies and gentlemen
it's time for episode 346 of the Grove
from a heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
that's right if you're a new grower if
you're a professional grower if you're a
new smoker or a dedicated dad er if
you're a cannabis activists or even
someone who is just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host my friends call me Rasta Jeff I
want to thank you guys again for joining
me ladies and gentlemen this episode of
the show is brought to you by my friends
at the hell a dank seed company if you
need new regular or feminized seeds for
your garden I highly recommend to the
holiday exceed company and you can find
them at dank seed dot store ladies and
gentlemen boys and girls smokers and
growers roll up a fat spliff put some
fresh water in the bong or start heating
up that dab nail because it's time for a
fresh episode of The Grove from your
heart podcast what's up everybody
welcome to episode 346 thanks for
joining me you know I like to start the
show off by letting you know what I am
smoking today I'm taking dabs of the
copper Tim nectar from Green Dot labs
the copper chem is a combo of chem 4 and
star dog it's described as perfumey chem
with assorted fruit candies you know
when I smelled it it smells like like
chem dog to me it smells a lot like chem
dog but then there is a hint of copper
or pennies inside of there it's like you
ran a batch of chem dog hash you had the
chem dog nectar and then you just poured
some copper pennies right into it is
what this smells like to me then when
you dab it it's got a tennis ball fresh
tire sort of a smell Plus that copper
penny kind of stays on your tongue at
the end I do enjoy it and the high from
this is amazing it's got me going it's
got me talkative it's got my eyes
bugging out of my head this should be a
great podcast also I should give a shot
it's my friends at elevate glass today I
picked up a new banger I was taking dabs
of the copper chem nectar out of a brand
new banger with the insert and I got
smart I took one of my we call him
Turtles or turf spinners it's just a
little glass bead basically I took an
eight millimeter glass bead and I put
that inside of my insert where my insert
the insert that drops into the Banger so
I put my dab in there then I dropped the
tert pearl the spinner on top of the dab
inside of the insert then I heat the
banger then I drop the insert inside the
banger with the dab and the Terp spinner
in there then I carb cap it give it a
couple of seconds for that dab to start
melting then I start drawing on it and
moving the carb cap around and I noticed
that that Terp pearl or that Terp
spinner inside my insert dish really
helped to move that concentrate around
in there the more I wiggled that carb
cap I could watch the Terp spinner move
and then it would just push the puddle
of oil from one spot to another and I
feel like it really made my dad it
didn't burn it vaporized much more
evenly at a nicer speed at a nicer
temperature and I feel like none of it
settled on the bottom and started to
singe there because that Terr pearl was
moving it around so much so I did an
insert dab with the tur pearl inside the
insert I did not use the appropriate
carb cap to make the pearl spin but I
was able to move it around enough with
my carb cap something I have noticed you
guys just a change I've made in my
dabbing most of my carb caps have a semi
large opening for the air to flow
through my newest carb cap has a really
small opening it's really restrictive
and I feel like I'm getting better dabs
with a more restrictive carb cap I was
really satisfied with a thermal banger
but I think I am kind of slowly making
the switch to these insert dabs they're
a little more work they take a little
more to to prepare and a little more to
clean up but you don't need as many of
them and sometimes I actually enjoy the
ritual I think a lot of cannabis users
pot smokers we just enjoy the ritual of
getting our stash and spending a moment
with your stash whether it's grinding up
a little bit of weed to roll a joint or
maybe your old school maybe you're still
picking the seeds out of your herb
that's part of the ritual you get your
stash out your little secret stash and
you got your album cover or whatever it
is that you use to work on your stash
and then you go through the little
ritual actually enjoy the ritual of
which tab do I want to hit I grab a
little container and like ooh the copper
cam and then I pick myself out of dab
and which-which rig am I gonna hit I'm
gonna do an insert dab so I put a little
dab in the insert and then I thought ooh
I'm gonna put a pearl in there and then
I'm gonna heat up a rig and it's just a
really nice ritual I've been enjoying
the new rituals of preparing the insert
tab then enjoying the insert tab and
then of course there's a little bit of
cleanup you got to pull the insert out
then you got to clean up the insert then
you got to clean up the Banger and then
hopefully you just repeat the process
and take a couple of more dabs but
insert dabs have been a lot of fun for
me I've really been enjoying it getting
a lot more flavor and I feel like it is
conserving my concentrates a little bit
better since I'm not burning that first
initial part of the dab off as soon as
it hits the Banger I feel like I'm
getting more I'm getting to consume more
of my dad's that I'm paying for so
that's what I'm smoking on today you
guys I'm taking dad's of the copper chem
nectar I'm hitting a hit man
hammerhead sidecar rig with a quartz
banger I'm loading the dab into an
insert I drop a Terp spinner or a pearl
inside of the insert a Heath Ian or heat
the bangor drop the insert into the
bangor then i cap it with a bubble cap
that is also very restrictive and i give
it a couple of seconds to start melting
and you guys i've been getting some of
the most satisfying dads i've had in a
long time so that's the long version of
what i am smoking on today's shout out
to my friends at green dot labs what up
Tim Martin I hope you're doing well and
also shout out to everybody at elevate
glass for taking such good care of me
all right I've got one more quick thing
I want to talk about before I get into
the main topic of the show a lot of
people listen to the podcast on stitcher
radio stitcher radio is an application
if you're not using stitcher that's fine
you're not missing anything your life is
probably better for it already
if you're listening to the show on
stitcher and you are still experiencing
problems I do apologize I've been in
contact with stitcher quite frequently
over the past couple of weeks and we are
working to resolve the issue we are not
sure why my show is having problems on
stitcher radio what I would recommend if
you were a stitcher listener and you're
having issues I would recommend you just
jump over to youtube and watch the show
on youtube every episode is available on
YouTube episode 1 through 346 is up on
youtube so you can watch everything
there YouTube does not compress my sound
quality so it probably sounds better on
YouTube anyway and the loading issues
that people are experiencing will not
happen on YouTube like they are on
stitcher so if you've been listening on
stitcher and having issues again
do apologize I encourage you just to
jump right over to YouTube and if you're
not already subscribed to the YouTube
channel I encourage everybody to go
subscribe to the Grove from your heart
podcast YouTube channel I'm getting a
lot of subscribers and I do appreciate
that support alright you guys I feel
like that's a solid intro for a podcast
I'm gonna press pause I'm gonna take one
of these insert dabs and when I come
back I'm going to talk about the
function of carbohydrates in your
cannabis grow take a dab with me you
guys I'll be right back all right
podcast world I am back I am well
hydrated I am heavily medicated I took a
big old dab of that copper Kim I had to
go chill out on the couch for a second I
had to go get some Instagram time in
after that that was a little bit more
than I bargained for thanks for hanging
out with me I hope you took a fad I hope
you're smoking something delicious just
know that if you're stuck at work if
you're in a cubicle or something I'm
probably high enough for both of us
right now but that's okay I'm not
driving I'm sitting in a chair I'm safe
I'm not at work so nobody can fire me
and hopefully when you get off work
you've got a big fat joint rolled up at
home so you can get as high as I am
right now now let's turn down that music
a little bit and get into a podcast
about carbohydrates let's start right
off at the top what are carbohydrates I
guess I should be more specific because
these are carbohydrates in plants in
cannabis plants even more specifically
carbohydrates are compounds produced
during photosynthesis and plant
carbohydrates have two main purposes
their first purpose is to provide
building blocks for plant structural
components such as cellulose which is
important in building cell walls the
second purpose of carbohydrates is to
deliver energy for plant growth plants
make food in the form of carbohydrates
by combining carbon dioxide and water
and using energy from either the Sun or
our grow lights now our plants can
immediately use or they can store the
carbohydrates and those stored
carbohydrates can be converted to
cellulose or other
structural carbohydrates now excess
carbs are stored in the plants roots and
leaves and primarily are stored in the
form of starches the plants store those
carbohydrates to use during the
flowering phase when the daylight hours
are reduced the plants aren't able to
produce as many carbohydrates because
the lack of sunlight or grow light
energy so they have it stored up for
when that time comes now
most of the carbohydrate production and
our plants will happen during the
vegetative phase and it will taper off
during the first three weeks of the
bloom phase so basically by the end of
the third week the start of the fourth
week of bloom the carbohydrate
production in cannabis plants basically
has stopped without our assistance if we
don't step in and add something there
will be no carbohydrate production
through the rest of this plant's life so
that's when we step in and we add
carbohydrates now just because the plant
stops producing its own carbs around
week three or four a flower doesn't mean
you have to wait until then to start
supplementing the carbs you can add them
early on in the plant's life you can
start them when the plants get big when
they're in veg because the carbs do have
another function that I'll talk about a
little later in the show so you don't
have to wait until the plants stop
producing their own carbs to introduce
your own now we understand that
carbohydrates are a source of energy and
also major building blocks for our
plants and we also understand that our
plants stop producing them on its own
around the third or fourth week of
flower now that's right when our plants
really start taking off we start seeing
bud set happen that stretches over and
we're starting to get chunky buds right
around that time so that's when we need
a lot of energy that carbohydrate energy
is used to produce big buds big robust
stems lots of trichomes and then a lot
of essential oils so our plants running
out of carbohydrates right at that
crucial time that essential time is kind
of detrimental to a cannabis grower now
most plants aren't designed or expected
to perform the way we expect our
cannabis plants to perform
we want the biggest fattest most potent
product we could possibly create in the
shortest amount of time in the smallest
amount of space with the best resistance
to bugs and the best resistance to
pathogens but nature didn't intend for
this plant to become a rocket ship or a
Formula One race car nature intended
this plant to survive and be good enough
nature made this plant to where it would
grow and get an apical dominant top that
would receive pollen more likely than
the lowers so where it had that that
huge hey look I'm right here to
pollinate me and it made a tour of the
male plants grow taller it's where it
would drop pollen down and it knew if I
do this I should survive so cannabis
evolved to be a survival plan we
manipulated it and bred it to be this
high-performance plant that we're trying
to get out of it nature never intended
this from the cannabis plant it evolved
fir the tons of years I don't have any
idea how long honestly but the plant
evolved for thousands of years by itself
without humans touching it it survived
we're trying to push it to do something
it was never expected to do of course
we've done some breeding to create
genetics that were ideal for our indoor
environment we've done breeding to find
the high testing cultivars we have bred
it to be a high-performance machine
because we've realized that it's a
commodity and so now after realizing
it's a commodity we want to push our
plants to the extreme and we expect them
to outperform themselves crop after crop
you always hear a grower would you pull
this time I got two pounds perlite cool
bro you better get two and a quarter
next time you're like oh [ __ ] not only
is that a lot of pressure on the grower
that's a lot of pressure on that
cultivar maybe that plant can't do that
maybe like if you've got some of the
older more finicky og cush is two pounds
of light you should be happy you know
what I mean if you're like I got two and
a quarter
you're [ __ ] you're Jesus of growing
back in the day if you were doing that
with some of the og plants and some of
the equipment that we had and then you
were expected to do even better on the
next grow so that's crazy so we've got a
lot of expectations for these plants and
we've bred them to try to meet these
expectations so now that we've bred
monsters we've got to feed them like
monsters we've got to meet their
expectations which is now more energy in
the form of more carbohydrates so to
keep our plants running strong after
their natural carbohydrate production
has ended we step in and we add our own
carbohydrates if you ever seen your
plants slow down like right around week
four maybe the start of week five a
flower and you can't figure out why like
your pH is on point the co2 is cool
the lighting is just fine you got enough
airflow in there the VPD is good maybe
those plants were lacking carbohydrate
energy that's why they just slowed down
just a little bit they could have gone a
little bit faster you've seen them go
faster before maybe they just ran out of
energy so consider your physical
performance right now like just think
about what you do your physical
performance level on a daily basis
consider your nutritional intake and
what it takes for your body to perform
the way you do what do you have to eat
to keep your body in shape to do that
how many calories do you have to consume
to have the energy to perform your daily
tasks now you're performing at your
normal natural level your expected level
now let's say if I expected you to
increase your performance by thirty
percent I want you to work 30% harder
30% longer and I need a production of a
minimum of 30% more do you think I'd
probably have to increase your feed and
your pay I don't have to increase your
pay also but but I'm gonna have to
increase your feed by a minimum of 30%
to try to get 30% more production out of
you or you're gonna burn out now keep
that in mind with your cannabis plants
it's the same sort of thing with your
plants when we start introducing things
like high end nutrients double-ended
Gavita bulbs co2 supplemental LED
lighting and then we start implementing
things like pruning the bottoms off and
then we do things like cracking the
stems we're expecting a lot from our
plants and we need to provide those
plants with the proper nutrition to see
the results which we demand alright now
that we understand what carbohydrates
are and what they do in our plants and
why we need them and why we need to add
them ourselves let's talk a little bit
about how we can add the carbohydrates
our
don't try to fool your feed a
carbohydrate product to your plants if
you go spraying carbs onto your plants
are just gonna clog [ __ ] up it's gonna
be a gross mess don't do that the best
way to feed carbohydrates is to add a
carbohydrate product to your water and
your nutrient solution just like any
other bottle nutrient and water it in
carbs are best absorbed through the
roots now right away a lot of people are
gonna tell you to add molasses to your
feed solution to increase your
carbohydrates I have used molasses in
the past but I wouldn't recommend just
store-bought molasses I wouldn't do that
back in the day yes I did do that maybe
back in the day I have said to do that
but I wouldn't do it anymore
store-bought molasses is really
unreliable it's very inconsistent not
only from brand to brand from region to
region but you could buy the same brand
you could buy two bottles and you could
pour that molasses into two bowls and
there'll be two different consistencies
two different colors two different
smells and we like a little bit of
regulation in cannabis growth so that we
know what we are feeding our plants that
way if we see a problem we know it was
that and maybe not maybe that I don't
want to say it could have been the
molasses so stick with a horticultural
product you organic guys they like to go
all organic you're gonna probably just
want to use molasses that's fine you
know what you're doing go for that in my
opinion the molasses is a little bit too
thick it also invites other problems you
can kind of suffocate your roots with
too much molasses in your feed solution
and it also molasses contains other
elements a lot of molasses will contain
sulfur and like I said earlier we don't
want to add a random feed to our plants
we were only trying to add carbohydrates
not sulfur so the molasses is not a good
idea that's gonna disrupt your feed
program throw off your plants health
it's gonna be hard to monitor because
you don't know what's in that molasses
it could be a myriad of things messing
up your process so if you're using any
hydro definitely stay away from the
thick molasses II type syrupy kind of
products those are really just gonna
clog up your entire hydro system so be
very careful with that also if you
overuse the molasses
you can't flush it out and your buds
will burn like [ __ ] in the end like I'll
admit it a long time ago I wasn't always
a really good grower I had to be a
shitty grower to become a good grower in
a long time ago I wouldn't always read
the internet I wouldn't do the proper
research but I did have a grower friend
that I trusted and he said bro just pour
this much molasses into your 5-gallon
thing a [ __ ] nutrient solution mix it
up get all that molasses mixed in there
then water the plants with it and it
will be great I weigh over did the
molasses in my opinion because when I
smoked those plants they burned like
[ __ ] I it was like smoking a charcoal
okay you put it in the grinder and he'd
grind it up in the grinder would like
skip because the buds were so hard and
that was I'm certain it was from the
molasses and when they burned it was it
just all stayed there there was no white
ash crew in there that was black
charcoal ash and it was from way too
much molasses so I recommend not using
molasses but if you're going to use it
use it sparingly and if you're an
organic grower that's probably going to
be your first option for a carbohydrate
sweetener type of project product is the
molasses just read a little bit and see
if there are any other options that will
satisfy you for your organic grower I
understand if you want to go completely
organic and molasses is your thing don't
let me stop you make yourself happy I'm
just giving you my two cents and if you
want to take it go for it if you want to
grow your way I encourage that grow your
way that's one of my favorite things
about cannabis is that my grow is
totally different than your grow and
they both work we both put a product on
the table at the end of the day that is
a top shelf product that people enjoy
and it works for our needs so that's the
beauty of growing cannabis do what works
for you this is just my uh my input so I
know I said I wouldn't use molasses and
I try not to pitch products too much on
my show but here are three products that
I am familiar with that I have used that
have worked great for carbohydrates in
my grow a long time ago one of the best
crops I ever grew I used a product
called Humboldt honey
Humboldt honey has yucca extract
Humboldt honey has a lot of great things
in it and it really made my product
taste nice and sweet humble honey they
have regular humble honey and they have
a humble honey hydroponic blend which is
a little thinner so you're not gonna
mess up
your lines so humble honey is a great
product also I like high bricks high
bricks is from a company called earth
juice I really like the way Hybris mel's
it's mostly molasses another product I
really do enjoy is called suka nat sugar
cane natural suc ca na t suka nan i
learned that one from our friend sub
cool probably 10 years ago and those are
three products that you can use for
carbohydrates again I don't get paid by
a carbohydrate company those are things
I've got experience with it worked for
me
I like the hybrids because it's very
natural it doesn't have a lot of
additives
I liked the Humboldt honey because of
the additive I like that
yucca extract in there I feel like it
did a little something for my plants the
sukkah net that's old-school I was using
that a way long time ago
now some of those products will be a
little molasses C and earlier in the
show I said don't buy molasses now why
am i recommending molasses-based [ __ ]
because this stuff has been filtered and
it's a little more consistent than the
stuff it's being sold for a
horticultural product it has to meet a
standard it's not just food food can
have a little variation because it could
taste different it can look a little
different its food we expect that as a
horticultural product they put a little
different standard to it I would like to
think I can't promise you that I can't
assure you that but the consistencies
are a little better to work with when
you're buying them as a horticultural
product the botanic air blackstrap
molasses is really thick and a pain in
the ass to work with if that's what
you're thinking you're gonna do I'm not
gonna try and discourage you that stuff
is a pain in the ass to work with you
get a big old container of just it looks
like tar and it's really hard to work
with but back in the day I went through
several containers of it and it was all
very consistent so that's what I'm
saying about don't buy molasses from the
store like the grocery store don't go
buy granny's blackstrap molasses go to
the Hydra store go to a gross store and
get a horticultural product that is more
homogenized more regulated and more
uniform and more consistent so that that
way you can dial it in and that's
usually the opposite of what I would say
usually I would say if you can find that
product and not at a gross store go get
it
at a gross store but for this one
occasion I'm gonna recommend that you
get an actual growing product now I just
did a quick google search just so I
could do some price checking and it was
funny because I was ended up on a forum
and everybody says that the blackstrap
molasses is a pain in the ass because
they end up wasting half of it because
of the stupid container that's what I
said before I even went for the Google
search now what comes up when I look for
high Brix and when I look for Humboldt
honey
high Brix is mostly molasses it's a
little bit diluted so that it works
better they don't say that they add
anything to it they just say that it's
been thin to where it works for your
plants the Humboldt honey has additives
and it is quite pricey compared to the
high Brix if you've got a little money
to spend I would say throw it at the
Humboldt honey if you're trying to go
low budget I think that high Brix would
make you and your plants just as happy
and like I said earlier if you're trying
to go all organic I think the hybrids
may qualify I think it is listed as
organic but if you want to stick with
just molasses that is up to you just
keep in mind if they do add things or
there could be things in the molasses
that you're not aware of and if you do
choose to use either the blackstrap
molasses from the store or the botanic
hair kind stir it up make sure it gets
diluted or dissolved or whatever because
it's really really thick and it's gonna
take a long time a lot of stirring to
break that stuff down so that's another
reason just to work toward either some
humble honey or the high Brix it'll make
your life a lot easier and you'll find
yourself spending less time cleaning up
sticky [ __ ] honestly I'm using the
Hybris right now because I stopped at a
local grocer and they did not carry
Humboldt honey and the hi brick was
quite affordable so that's the product I
chose and I've been using the Hybris off
and on for several years shot it's my
friend Donovan from way back in the day
who introduced me to earth juice
nutrients all right you guys earlier I
mentioned that carbohydrates had an
additional benefit to our grow that they
would be useful from early on in our veg
stage all the way through the end of
flower so let's talk about that added
benefit that I hinted about earlier
another added benefit of carbohydrates
is that they will feed your microbes in
your root zone all that recharge or that
mammoth pee or that great white shark
that you've been pouring in there
it needs to be fed all that beneficial
fungus is hungry and it will use these
carbohydrates as food and fuel to keep
living and reproducing so your carbs are
working double-time they're giving your
plants extra energy and they're also
feeding your microbes which are keeping
the roots healthy keeping the roots
happy which are also helping the plants
absorb more carbohydrates which are
making the plants healthier you see how
it all works it's all in symbiosis here
when we get everything dialed in
everything works together so well in the
garden all right you guys that is my
podcast on carbohydrates I hope I taught
you something today I can't wait to hear
your input on me talking about not using
molasses I'm sure a lot of people are
gonna have stuff to say about that I
really do look forward to your feedback
my email addresses grow from your heart
at hotmail.com or you can find me on
twitter it's at g f YH podcast I would
love to hear your feedback
all right podcast rolled before I start
wrapping up the show I have got one
question for you if you could smoke a
joint with any one person dead or alive
who would you choose send me a tweet
it's at g f YH podcast let me know who
would you smoke with I will read your
responses on a future episode and then I
will share with you who I would choose
to smoke a joint with alright podcaster
well I think that's all I've got for you
I would appreciate it if you find me on
all the social media stock me on
Facebook simply search for the growth
from your heart a podcast find me on
Twitter it's at G fyh podcast if you
want to follow my personal Twitter
account it's at Rasta Jeff 420 I would
love to have your follow I will probably
follow you back don't forget about the
patreon campaign if you feel like this
show is educational informative or
entertaining and you feel like you would
like to contribute to the show
financially you can do so by going to
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
it's patr yo n.com slash grow from your
heart all of the information that you
need to sign up to contribute to the
podcast will be right there and I do
appreciate all of the patreon support
big thanks to Zach big thanks to Steven
Fletcher and a huge thanks to Jake
Jordan thanks for all the patreon
support you guys also if you'd like to
hang out more you can follow me on
Instagram and check out my Instagram
live videos I go on
Instagram and I talked about growing I
smoked some dabs I take questions from
people who were in the live feed and
then I try to answer your cannabis
questions on the fly I don't have any
notes I don't have any preparation you
can come in there you can ask me your
question and I will do my best to answer
your question live on the feed right
there so I encourage you to join me on
Instagram lies my Instagram is Irie
underscore genetics I RIE underscore GE
and ET ICS come find me on instagram
join me in a live feed get your question
read on the live feed I will give you
some answers you just come smoke dabs
with us and hang out sometimes I'm super
chatty sometimes I don't have [ __ ] to
say and I let the audience kind of
dictate the conversation sometimes it
gets really fun in there so come join us
I encourage you to hang out on instagram
live ladies and gentlemen that's all
I've got for you for this episode I'll
be back in a couple of days with a fresh
new episode I look forward to joining
you again I want to give a huge shout
out to my friend tip-top Magoo and until
next time take a phat dab and give your
mom a hug for me
[Music]