yo what's up podcast world it's Russ -
Jeff and it is time for episode 348 of
the girl from your heart podcast no
fancy music or intro this time we're
gonna do a quick episode as you were
listening to this I am probably still in
Denver having a good time from the
holiday weekend
my favorite band Phish was in Denver
Friday Saturday and Sunday and as you're
listening to this on Monday I'm probably
still in Denver hanging out with some
friends so I hope you had a great
holiday weekend I hope you got to party
with your family I hope you get to party
with some friends maybe you got to
consume cannabis with a family member
which you've never smoked before maybe
you found out somebody in your family as
a cannabis consumer and you guys snuck
off and had one of them barbecue joints
together I love that sort of [ __ ]
whatever happened I hope you guys had a
great weekend I usually start these
episodes off by letting you know what I
am dabbing on right now I am loading up
a fresh dab of custom OGIS nectar from
Green Dot labs this is of course a combo
of Skittles and afghulis it is described
as assorted hard candies on the aroma
and flavor when I cracked open this
fresh jar of concentrates I made a
little noise like a little boy that just
got a fresh box at Ninja Turtles or some
[ __ ] I went ooh when I opened this this
gram of concentrates is beautiful this I
I really think this is a heavy gram
there's more than a gram of hash in here
this is super chunky lots of crystals
very little Terp liquid which is what I
prefer I'd prefer lots of crystals and a
very minimal amount of the turkey liquid
I get enough chirps just just enough to
add the flavor that's all I need this
gram is glorious caused me to make a
little Robin Williams noise when I
opened it so I'm getting myself a little
chunk of this custom oh geez nectar
scooped into my insert here I'm gonna
take an insert dab and then after that
we're gonna get into a podcast I think
we're gonna talk a little bit about CBD
and then we will probably read a news
article and then we may read a couple of
emails and then we're gonna wrap it up
and get out of here this is not gonna be
a super long episode but I wanted to
make sure to have a quality show
prepared for Monday because I haven't
missed a week you guys I've been doing
the show for close to five years I think
and I have not missed a Monday in five
years there was one Monday when I was
super sick I had a head cold I sounded
like [ __ ]
I wasn't a Monday but there was a show
coming up and I wasn't able to really do
a good show so I called the crew and I'm
sure you guys remember everybody came
over Adam Jesse and Mike all came over
and we recorded a hilarious podcast
while I was sick I basically sat at the
table and ran the equipment and
everybody talked over me for the whole
show but I have not missed a single
episode in approximately five years so I
had to make sure to come give you guys a
quality Monday show because I'm heating
the [ __ ] out of the banger while I'm
talking if you hear the torsion in the
background I apologize if I Sun slightly
distracted it's cuz I'm paying attention
to the torch in the nail I'm getting
this sucker nice and hot I feel like
it's almost there I just want to heat it
up just a little bit more than a little
actually a little black mark of an oil
stain on the banger I'm gonna heat it
until that goes away and then as soon as
that's gone it looks like it has
disappeared turn off the torch then I
drop the insert right into the banger
then I get a carb cap I place the carb
cap right on top of that and now I'm
just gonna let it sit here until I see
it actually starting to smoke a little
bit once the banger fills with a little
smoke and maybe a little too smoke comes
out of the top of the carb cap there it
goes that's what I'm gonna hit it so
let's debut guys dab with me that's like
the perfect size the first bull was
super thick nice and chunky then I got a
nice little backup pull off of that get
nicely medicated from that it's leaving
up like a UH
I taste Apple candies right away it
tastes like a sour apple Jolly Rancher
but it's kind of changing into something
sweeter and fruitier as it goes that's
gonna take a couple of seconds for that
one to work through my brain you guys
excuse me while my brain swims around
like a little goldfish in my head right
now I'm getting dad the [ __ ] out that
was a beautiful dab hey one thing I want
to mention while I'm high and just
rambly I see people taking dad videos on
Instagram and I love it keep doing your
big dads on Instagram but when you cap
the banger leave that [ __ ] carb cap
on there so I'm gonna grab my rake and
kind of just so that I can
myself a better idea what I'm seeing so
when you hit you put the carb cap on and
then you hit it right and then you're
gonna lift the carb cap off a little bit
to kind of carve it and let yourself
clear the rig and get that smoke when
you're when your lungs are full we do
that
you can hear the noises I'm doing it I
think I think it's coming through on the
mic so you pull and you get this right
you get this little a couple of moments
you lift the cap off to where you can
get oxygen through there so you can
clear the rig and get all that smoke
into your lungs and then you fill your
lungs in and you exhale then you go back
in and repeat the process write
something that I don't know why it
drives me [ __ ] crazy it just bugs the
[ __ ] out of me when you're exhaling
you're dab don't take the carb cap off
the banger just leave the carb cap on
there there's no reason to keep removing
the carb cap you're letting the heat
escape the whole idea of putting that
carb cap on there is to trap the heat
inside that nail inside that banger and
every time you lift the carb cap you're
allowing all that heat to leave so just
leave that carb cap on there yes I get
it you want to lift it up to pull this
to clear it but then put it back just
like it should sound like this and now
when I'm exhaling my carb cap is still
on the banger now I'm gonna go back in
and those little whistles that you hear
the little lift up the bang or the carb
cap to let air flow that's all you need
just a couple of just carb it don't
leave I don't know they think it's silly
to cap it trap that heat in there then
let the cap off let the heat escape then
try to recap it and reget that heat
going if you leave it in there your dab
will be better that's just my opinion
for some reason it drives me [ __ ]
nuts watching people take the cap off
and leave the cap off and exhale their
dab and look at the camera all silly and
blow a kiss and then put the cap on and
go back in just leave the cap on there
bro but now on the other hand when
you're done with the dab take the
[ __ ] carb cap off because when you
set that rig on the table or when you
try to set the rig on the table and the
carb cap falls off and lands in the
carpet and gets all that carpet fuzz
stuck to the sticky carb cap or even
worse when the carb cap rolls off and
lands on the [ __ ] tile floor and
shatters that's terrible so take the cap
off when you're done and set the cap
down on an oil slick pad or
pay attention to where people are
setting the tools so that you have just
like it one designated sticky spot don't
go sticky up the whole table pay
attention to how other people are doing
it but set the carb cap down then set
the rig down you guys if there is a mood
mat or some sort of a mat for the rig
try to set the rig on that mat because
some of the collectors and the heady
boys if you set your glass rig down
directly on the wooden table ooh
that's offensive to some people I don't
really care because I understand it's a
glass pipe that I bought that is likely
going to get broken but a lot of people
spend a lot of money on really nice
glass and this sound right here oh
that's a rig just touching a table
that's that's a hitman rig just send
down on a wooden table that sound drives
people nuts this is what they want to
hear you hear that now you didn't that's
cuz I set it down on a little mood mat
it's nice and smooth and protected so if
you see the mood mat try to utilize it
because your Hetty boyfriend's may get
frustrated with you if you do not that's
just a little tip you guys so that you
look cool the first time you go to the
social club and smoke with all the heady
boys what social club oh that's a great
segue into this news article that I've
got I've got a news article from the
cannabis the headline says Denver's
second license social marijuana business
to open this fall as a vaping bar and
lounge this article is written by a
person named John Murray we're gonna get
right into it and it goes like this
Denver's licensing directors signed off
Friday on the city's second license for
a marijuana consumption area in a
business paving the way for a vaping bar
and lounge to open this fall the owners
of vape and play plan to open the 21 and
over social lounge and entertainment
venue in November or sooner depending on
the timing of a renovation of the
building at 1753 South Broadway
co-owner Taylor Rosen says the lounge
will be centered around a multi station
saloon style vape bar though customers
will have to bring their own marijuana
per the rules of Denver's 2016 voter
past initiative 300 so there's more to
that article but I think we got the
point Denver is opening a second
consumption bar this is great this will
be a place for tourists to go and
consume this will be a place for people
who live in apartments we are not
allowed to smoke
be able to go smoke there this will be a
cool social lounge we'll be able to have
events they said it's going to be an
entertainment venue that means we may
have music there that means we may have
live comedy there we may do podcasts
from there you never know what could
happen at a venue like this these places
are great and they said it's the second
place I can think of two others and I'm
not sure if I should say both of them
because that means one is unlicensed and
we go dab there and they may get in
trouble if I mention it
so I'm snitching on one of them if I say
- and I'm not sure if I want to do that
now that I'm thinking about it there are
several places where we go and consume
so I'm gonna click over to Google right
quick and see what the first place was
okay the first place is I've never even
been there so that means that the places
where I am going and dabbing you're not
supposed to be dabbing there but I
they don't stop me I go in and I sit
down and I just pull out the rig and
take dabs and nobody has ever said hey
bro you can't dive in here
but anyway the place where you are
allowed to dab is called the Coffee
joint that was the first legal and
officially licensed adult use
recreational cannabis lounge in Denver
Colorado so shout out to them once again
they are called the coffee joint and
just to give them some love they are on
what's their address here it is 11:30
you McCourt in Denver Colorado
so now visitors to the Denver area
residents of the Denver area adults in
Denver visitors guess people have a safe
place to go consume all of the cannabis
that are allowed to go by at the
dispensaries now we just need for this
to spread through Colorado now so that
we can have lounges all over the place
and have safe access and safe places to
consume for everybody this is good
progress again you guys I like this also
let me rant about this if you were
working on legalizing cannabis
recreationally or medically in your area
make sure you include some sort of place
to consume your medicine or your
recreational cannabis when you're
writing the rules if you don't write it
into the rules from the beginning the
opposition will create rules for you and
we never like the rules they make for us
so that's super cool another smoke
lounge in Denver hopefully we get them
all over Colorado before too long at the
top of the show I mentioned we were
going to talk a little bit
about CBD I don't have a big scientific
talk about CBD I have more of a warning
about CBD products I was hanging out
some friends a few days ago and one of
the guys girlfriends I am not familiar
with this couple they were new to the
group she was saying that she was having
some back and leg pain one of the other
guys girlfriends reached into her purse
really quickly and was really eager to
give her some CBD products me being Who
I am I was like what you got there can I
see the bottle and she politely gave me
the bottle I was just reading out of
curiosity the label looked a little
generic I looked like they just peeled
the label off of another product and put
their own shitty paper label around it
and tried to pass it off and just
replace something but the label said
that each capsule contained 100
milligrams of CBD it also said that it
had MCT oil which i think is just fancy
for coconut oil and then it also said
that it contained fish oil now as soon
as I saw the words fish oil I got super
suspicious so I asked her if I could
have a couple there were like a hundred
of them in the jar and she was super
sweet and she's like yeah take as many
as you want so I'm thinking yeah I'll
just pop them in the lid and get a
couple so I pop off the lid and it just
wreaked a fish oil and she's like take
as many as you want it was kind of a
large bottle you guys they're probably a
hundred of them in there so I dumped
that two or three for myself and I had
no intentions of eating them I if you
listen to the podcast a lot you know
that I'm not a CBD consumer I prefer
high THC the CBD seems to kind of ruin
my THC high so CBD isn't really for me
but I took a couple of them because I
just wanted to to play I wanted to see
what the heck she had because she just
pulled him out of her purse and was
passing him out they couldn't have been
very expensive the way she was sharing
them with everybody and the label looks
like she might have got them at like
Walmart or something by the looks of
this label cuz it didn't have any sort
of medical marijuana labeling it didn't
have any sort of warning it was just CBD
oil capsules is what I think it said it
said 100 milligrams each capsule and
they were gelatin caps and then I
flipped it around and it was fish oil
was the first ingredient listed and then
CBD oil and they did not define or give
any details about the CBD source so as
soon as I got away from the group they
didn't
to be rude and is cracking open and tell
this girl your product is [ __ ] but I
could tell her product was [ __ ] and I
just had a suspicion I cracked it open
and I smelled it and you guys I think
that they're just selling fish oil pills
there that's the only reason I can think
of why they would say there's fish oil
in there because why the [ __ ] else would
you put fish oil in CBD pills so I'm
thinking they're just relabeling some
fish oil pills and they're selling them
to this very sweet young lady who's very
gullible and very young and she's buying
them thinking that she's got CBD now the
added benefit to taking this fish oil is
it's probably giving her some sort of
physical benefit it's probably good for
her joints it may be good for her brain
it's probably good for all kinds of
stuff in her body and she's attributing
that to the magical effects of CBD
so she's not getting a placebo she's
getting an effect so she's going to keep
buying this product I can't prove to you
that there's no CBD in there I didn't
eat the pills I threw him away they kind
of melted in my car to be honest with
you after I cracked one of them open I
forgot about him in the car the other
two melted in the car
but I'm very suspicious of what they're
putting in that capsule and telling us
is CBD I don't think for the cost of
that bottle that could have been CBD I
don't think for how generous she was
with that bottle that those were CBD
pills cuz that would probably be really
expensive for a bottle of that big of a
hundred milligram CBD pills so what it
leads me I'm what I'm trying to say to
you guys is when you're buying CBD
products be very leery be very
suspicious of any CBD products right now
you guys try to find out about the
company you're purchasing from try to
find out the brand do some research on
the brand find out where their products
come from are they coming from America
are they coming from Canada are they
coming from the United States so I said
that one already are they come in from
China is what I'm getting out I didn't
want to say China first if it's coming
from China be afraid if it's coming from
Canada you're probably okay if it's
coming from America it's hard to say
what you're purchasing I would recommend
you buy your CBD products from a very
reputable vendor we had giddy up on the
podcast recently and he represents can
tech labs so I can stand behind that
there are also several other reputable
companies out there I'm not gonna throw
out a bunch of names cuz I haven't done
any research and as soon as I say a
brand name especially the two that are
on the tip of my tongue if I say those
I'm going to get ten emails about why I
shouldn't have said them so I'm not
gonna say anybody other than our friends
at can tech labs because giddyup was on
the show and I've actually seen those
products work it he gave me a few
samples of their CBD products and I pass
them out to people who needed them and I
did watch that product work
I saw it work for somebody I can't talk
too much about it because their
employment would probably frown upon
their CBD use but I got to see somebody
get relief from a CBD product so I can
recommend that one it's can techlabs and
they're based out of Oklahoma so big
shot it's a giddyup and his crew know
another thing I want to talk about is I
wonder what other people are taking that
they actually think is CBD what are they
buying if they're getting their CBD from
China if they're getting like a little
vial of tincture or a little medicine
bottle filled with some syrup that they
think is CBD I wonder what these people
are putting into their bodies how many
people are simply taking doses of fish
oil every day how many people are taking
water with a little drops of hemp oil in
it every day how many people are paying
good money and thinking that they're
treating themselves well and treating a
condition when they're actually being
duped into spending their money on a
product that could be causing them more
harm that scares the [ __ ] out of me you
guys even if the CBD isn't real even if
it's just fish oil that's shitty to do
to people but what else is in there
that's the super shitty part because I'm
not gonna say that
China is unscrupulous is that the word
unscrupulous scruple yeah try and I'm
not gonna but I mean they don't care
they're just trying to make some money
they're putting some [ __ ] in a bottle
and they're putting it in a box they put
a label on it they ship it off they have
no idea where it ends up or what its
gonna do to anybody they don't give a
[ __ ]
well they got paid so who knows what
they're putting in there do you remember
a long time ago Chinese toothpaste was
killing people so imagine like what
Chinese CBD might be all right guys I
think I've rambled on long enough about
that pay attention where your CBD comes
from find find of this source find out
learn about the company are they a
reputable company are they a piece of
[ __ ]
honey find out if they are American
Canadian Chinese who knows where they
could be from try to find out our friend
Scottie real will always remind you you
vote with your dollars man so pay
attention to where your CBDs coming from
don't give your money to a company that
doesn't give a [ __ ] about you and then
do give your money to a company that
actually cares and offers a quality
product all right you guys I said this
was gonna be a quick episode I'm already
creeping up on almost 20 minutes so
let's read one quick email this email
says hey Jeff I'm growing in my closet
for the first time and I was listening
to a veg podcast of yours talking about
turning off the lights and letting the
plants sleep during this time could I
also keep the fan off or is the fan okay
to run during that time thanks that's a
very good question I've recommended
giving your plants some sleep time a lot
of people like to run the plants I was
24 hours of a veg light so where do they
grow but I think the plants really like
some sleep time they do some processing
in the sleep I'm not gonna get too much
into Dex I'm trying to keep this short
also roots develop in the dark time you
get a lot of root growth at night so I
think a little bit of dark time is good
for the plants you really encourage them
growth and who doesn't want to nap
occasionally also illiterate whites cool
down save you some electricity save you
some bulb time it'll help ya now this
guy is asking should I leave the fan off
or can I keep that on during the dark
cycle I would leave the fan on during
the dark cycle you want airflow you're
gonna get more humidity as soon as those
lights go off the vapor pressure deficit
is going to change in that room the
relative humidity is going to spike it's
gonna go crazy in there you're not in
there so you don't notice it but it
happens every time the lights go off it
changes drastically in there so if
you've got that fan in there that will
help prevent any sort of bud mold and
powdery mildew and also those leaves
just like to move around the leaves want
to get rustled around all the time if
they you're not beating the [ __ ] out of
the plants with that fan if it's just a
nice rustle yeah go ahead and leave that
on I think that will like it maybe think
about turning it off and on
intermittently just have it come on for
maybe on for 15 minutes off for 15
minutes on for 15 off for 15 or
something like that that way if you've
got a couple of leaves it's always that
front row of plants right that front row
right in front of the
they always leaves look just a little
bit shitty from getting beat up by the
by the fan there the win
that's the vapor pressure deficit
getting just thrown out of whack by that
fan maybe don't beat the [ __ ] out of
them all day maybe give them a little
bit of a rest so that they can actually
function so that those leaves can do
their duty you can have the vapor
pressure deficit correct around those
leaves for at least half the day but yes
if you want to leave that fan on if it's
not too strong if it's not whipping the
[ __ ] out of your plants if it's not
causing any problems yes leave it on a
little bit of stimulation is not a
problem
throughout the night cycle for those
plants that was a great question dude
thanks for the great email if anybody
else out there
has a question you can send me an email
it's grow from your heart at hotmail.com
I will get to your question I know I've
got a stack of emails I'm trying to work
my way through them I like to do the
grow lessons I like to do the emails I
also like to have a social life it's a
lot of things to try and balance out but
keep the good emails coming I will
answer them over time ladies and
gentlemen I want to thank you guys again
for listening to the show I'm gonna wrap
it up I hope I had fun at Phish
I hope you guys had a great weekend I
hope you have a great rest of your week
I will see you Thursday I'm pretty sure
I'll be back to get an episode together
on Thursday half an episode doesn't come
out on Thursday
don't worry I'm just having a little bit
of fun taking a little bit of a break
and I promise you I will be back Monday
but the way I work I should be able to
get a show going Thursday for you with
no problems yes thanks for hanging out
make sure you follow me on all the
social media on Facebook it's the girl
from your fire podcast find me on
Twitter it's at G fyh podcast don't
forget to follow me on instagram it's
ireon der score genetics on Instagram
also there's a YouTube channel every
episode is available on youtube go to
youtube and search for the grove from
your heart podcast if you guys feel like
this podcast was educational informative
or entertaining and you'd like to
contribute to the show financially you
can do so by going to patreon.com slash
grow from your heart all the information
that you need will be right there
and I want to give a huge thank you to
everybody who has contributed to the
patreon campaign I do appreciate it you
guys that's all I've got for you for
this episode
I want to give a huge shout out to
keepers of the fire and until next time
take a phat dab and give your mom a hug
for me
the shoulder that I leaned on was carved
out of stone but when I'm done freezing
[Music]
the child
the shine
[Music]