what's up cannabis Community my name is
rosta Jeff and it's time for episode
number 35 of the Agro culture
podcast in the last episode I talked
about a proposed regulation coming down
in poblo Colorado we talked about going
to a city council meeting to prevent
these regulations and city council has
changed the date of their next meeting
the city's agenda did say the meeting
was on Monday but recently they have
changed the date the date is now on
Tuesday October 14th at 700 p.m. so come
down to one city hall place in peblo
Colorado Tuesday October 14th at 7:00
p.m. public comment will be allowed
during the public forum for those who
sign up before the meeting so if you
plan to speak show up around 6:30 and
sign up please come and help fight these
regulations what they're trying to do is
not allow us to grow in our homes or in
our backyards they're trying to require
us to make an out building to grow in
which I don't find fair so please join
us at a city council meeting Tuesday at
7:00 p.m. if you want to speak please
show up around 6:30 I'll be there Mike
will be there Jesse will be there there
should be quite a few of us there we
hope to see you there all right let's
get on with the podcast uh Jesse came
over actually I'm waiting for Jesse
while I record this to be honest with
you Jesse will be here any minute now
and we are finally going to do the
episode about drying and curing your
cannabis so hang on just a second while
I do some ads and hopefully Jesse will
show up by the time I get done with
this where do we want to start this
episode is brought to you by our good
friends at Highly Educated titanium if
you're dabbing high quality concentrates
you deserve a highquality titanium nail
don't trust chinese nail or an American
knockoff made of cheap Metals trust the
industry leader trust Highly Educated
titanium for more information about
Highly Educated products visit Highly
Educated ti.com or if you just want to
buy something right now check out
aqualab technologies.com
this podcast is also brought to you by
Natures green remedies.com visit Natures
green remedies.com for gag genetics L
Plato Labs Sin City rare dankness mile
high can Adventure alphac chronic bog
MTV I said MTV it's MTG the Cali
Connection iy genetics and many more
trusted Brands Nature's green remedies
is running a special for our podcast
listeners guys they change they've got a
new coupon code check this out do me a
favor when you go to Nature's green
remedies to buy your beans type in
coupon code Helping Hands it's two words
Helping Hands and when you use that
coupon code you'll get 133% off your
order and what that's going to do
they're going to send a percentage of
your order let me make sure how much I
don't want to lie to you I've got the
message right here scrolling through for
the message it says that you will get
what this is going to do they're going
to send a portion of their proceeds to a
homeless shelter in the area where
Nature's green remedies is located uh
what it says is it's to help a homeless
shelter in my area three bucks from
every order goes to help so if you want
to help out a homeless shelter keep some
folks warm for the winter use coupon
code Helping Hands and you'll get 13%
off and you will actually be helping
somebody so use that coupon code at
naturegreen remedies.com I lost my
rhythm don't know where I was in that
read so let's move on to the next one
this podcast is brought to you by Hy gr
indoor growing supplies H gr indoor
growing supplies has two locations to
serve Colorado visit the Denver store at
6271 Beach Street or stop by the peblo
location at 618 East 4th Street in peblo
Colorado check out hyro for competitive
pricing and a great selection of indoor
growing supplies guys I shop at hyro I
wouldn't advertise something that I
don't trust in speaking of not
advertising something I don't trust in
I'm talking about this Highly Educated
nail I deserve a dab take a dab with me
and hopefully by the time I get done
with that our good friend Jesse will be
here to talk about drying and curing
your
cannabis all right guys I'm back after a
couple of tremendous dabs forgot to do a
couple things I want to give a huge
shout out to Joey Coco Diaz and also my
good friend Clint uh Clint and I went up
to Denver to the Denver Improv on
Thursday night and we saw Joey KOCO Diaz
do an amazing set of Comedy Joey's one
of my favorite comedians he freaking
crushed the Denver Improv and it was
awesome uh after the show he took a few
minutes to hang out with Clint and I
well he hung out with everybody but then
uh Clint said something to him that got
his attention so he hung out with
Clinton I for quite a while and
bullshitted oneon-one uh when he was
walking away he patted me on the
shoulder and he said uh Ross the Jeff
you know I love you right [ __ ] and
uh for Joey Diaz to call you a
[ __ ] is is actually an honor so it
was great and I had a good time so big
shout out to Joey Diaz thanks for the
great amazing show thanks for hanging
out with me for an hour after the show
hey Clint thanks for going with me dude
that was a good time we need to go to
more comedy shows together also make
sure you check out the wild cousins
that's Clint's comedy group that he is a
part
of so if you are a uh listener a regular
listener you'll remember that around
episode 30 I said that I would uh start
paying a dollar every time I say the f-
word because I'm trying to not say the
f- word on the
podcast I need somebody to go back and
listen from episode 30 to 34 and let me
know how many dollars I owe there's a
sick child in need and I had a
conversation with one of his parents I
think it was his uncle and I said that I
would help them out when the time came
up and so this is my uh my obligation to
them I know it's only a dollar but what
I'm going to do now starting on episode
35 every time I say the f word it costs
me $5 I will donate $5 to this sick kid
the sick child and try to help out their
life a little bit um what I'll need
though is I need somebody to tweet me or
email me or let me know when I'm doing
it so the way you can do that you can
tweet me IG culture you can email me
ulture hotmail.com you can Facebook me
uh it's just igro culture and just let
me know how many times I'm saying this
and from 30 to 34 it's $1 from 35 on
it's going to be $5 and it does not
count to the guests the guests can come
and they can say whatever they want so
somebody start tallying it up for me and
send me a bill um I'm going to contact
these people once I've got a total and
then I will let them know that I want to
do this and if they accept the donation
I'll send it to them and also if they
are willing or if they uh want me to
reveal their identity I will and that
way you guys can see who I'm helping
out all right I got one more ad to do
this podcast is brought to you by our
friends at tree Thugger dcom tree
Thugger dcom live music lifestyle
magazine for concert Festival news and
reviews check out tree Thugger tocom I
want to send a personal Shout out to
Ryan from tree Thugger dude I see what
you're doing with yourself and I'm proud
of you man I wish you the
best you guys I am still looking for
that theme song if anybody has made a
theme song for me please shoot it to me
you can send it to me at ulture
hotmail.com if you just want to send an
instrumental I can do all the voiceovers
and say the name of the show and all
that stuff I would appreciate it and I'd
definitely make it worth your time guys
I'm going to take a couple more dabs and
when I get back we'll do a lesson on
drying and curing your cannabis I just
got a text message and it's Jesse and he
says he will be here five minutes hang
on you guys all right what's up ladies
and gentlemen guess who finally decided
to show up our good buddy Jesse Gro is
back how you doing tonight bro pretty
good fashionably late fashionably late
you got a lot of fashion in you tons of
it no worries bro I was just chilling
out putting together a really nice
episode the people have been asking for
the dry and Cure episode uh I think they
will be proud of what we bring them
today awesome Jesse actually said that
he could use a little uh what is it a
primer lesson is that what it's called
on how to how to cure some herbs I've
never uh never been real happy with any
of my cure jobs so I mean I've been told
they're great but
um um you know this I always I feel that
I have a lot of room for improvement
there so your standards on your own
product are always higher than everybody
else's your own expectations you know
what I mean I'm never satisfied with my
my herb or anything and everyone's like
that was amazing yeah especially when I
play music I'm like that could have been
better and they're like no dude you
nailed it like no that was sloppy I can
feel the same thing snowboarding as well
yeah U me on a snowboard it's like
trying to put a telephone pole on a
snowboard and it's just a lot of me
rolling down a hill on my face oh man I
thought you snowboarded actually I I do
but I spend more time on the lift and on
my ass than I do on the actual board I
can't do it anymore the left knee
disagrees with the snowboard now oh that
sus it feels like uh feels like my left
knee wants to fly out of the socket the
entire time I'm strapped in that I can't
ski for a similar reason
they told me to move to skis they said
it wouldn't hurt as bad if I skied
possibly maybe I'll try that this winter
case to case my snowboard friends have
moved away miss you guys hope you're
listening so uh we're here to talk about
curing herb not talking about curing
ourselves actually I guess curing herb
will cure ourselves I'm talking into a
circle cuz I'm really dabbed out really
dabbed out really yeah we uh setting a
new record for dab we burned out the
enail I think and had to switch over to
the regular rig uh the enail couldn't
keep up with the puddles we were putting
on it and I think it took a [ __ ] today
so hey giddy up uh remember what you're
telling me uh shout out to Giddy Up I
ran into giddy on chat roulette that was
amazing and you said something about
sending me a gnail homie so don't forget
cuz my nail just took a [ __ ] so that'd
be great timing um we want to cure some
weed that's why everybody's listening
you doing good bro by the way I just
kind of skipped right over introducing
you you having a good day you look like
you're working hard kind of busy very
very hard well take some dabs take a
break we'll record it'll be awesome y so
if you're going to cure some
weed um you're going to need a few
things you should have a dehumidify
maybe you should have an air conditioner
maybe you for sure need fans at least
one fan you need what I call a
hygrometer that's a uh it's a
thermometer with a humidity reading on
it also then you're going to need some
kind of jars I prefer glass mason jars
uh if you're going a little bigger
there's a company I think it's called
quickvac they're little suction vac lid
jars they sell them at most of the head
shops those are pretty chill to cure
your weed in a lot of people don't like
them because those are plastic I don't
think they leave any taste or smell
those don't if you're going bigger I
like to buy those rubber made uh 32 CT
containers I think that's what it is
it's a big container uh it's like a
two-handed container uh you could fit a
lot of Herb in one of those to cure it
those work perfectly so you're going to
need something to cure it in and a room
uh to get it started to cure
in uh Ed Rosenthal actually taught me
that curing begins at the start of
harvest um I'm not sure how much I
subscribe to Ed's teaching but in a
sense that is is accurate uh the minute
you cut down that plant you're starting
the curing process you need that herb to
dry
uniformly uh not too fast not too slow
and you don't want it in a hot room you
don't want it in a cool room so we're
going to kind of go from and one of our
lessons before we talked from where we
talked about harvest and drying uh and
we ended drying as when where the sticks
on your buds snap that's pretty much
where we decided we were entering cure
so if you've done everything right
you've got all your leaves off uh your
buds have dried evenly in a nice room
that was temperature controlled not too
fast not too cool and now the sticks are
snapping and the buds are a little bit
damp a little bit juicy if you squeeze
them uh they kind of stick to your
fingers but they kind of spring back to
life they don't you don't crush them
when you squeeze
them you want them to have a little
spring left into them for sure all right
so I guess I should read and don't be
deceived by um the crunchy layer some I
guess it goes strain to strain but
sometimes there's a lot more leaf on the
outside
oh yeah um you know
it's you could get tricked either way
you know sure by letting it over dry and
uh also by thinking it's dry too soon so
right uh the weed dries from the outside
or from the outside in so even though
the outside leaves are crispy and dry
the inside could be really juicy still
so you got to be careful and little buds
are uh going to dry quicker than the big
buds right I feel that's a um I like to
cut When I grow a big butt I actually
cut that all down into the little uh the
little golf ball size nuggets if you if
you're one of my patients you usually
get a bag full of golf balls is what I
give you I do when uh when I'm doing
like the final Trim um sometimes when
they're hanging you know the the bigger
buds are a little harder to break down
sometimes so um nothing to do with them
yeah you don't want to put them on a
rack you got to let them hang okay well
right before we're before we're going to
cure this is when the sticks will pop so
everything's all trimmed up now we don't
have any leaves left uh they look pretty
they're manicured the way you want uh
when you grab one of the buds you pick
it up and you bend the stick it should
snap you don't want it to bend like a
straw you want it to actually break pop
you don't want to leave it until it like
explodes and breaks cuz then you're a
little too dry um too dry or too wet of
cannabis will not cure properly if
you're too dry you've already missed
your point uh you're going to get stale
buds you're just going to put it in the
jar and waste time if you're too wet and
you try to cure it you're actually going
to Pro uh promote mold so you want it
about right where those stick snap and
that's when you're going to start the
curing process um let me read you what I
wrote of what curing actually is and
what the pro uh the purpose of curing is
this is what I just what I wrote down to
give an actual reason curing is used to
remove excess moisture to convert
complex uh to convert complex carbs back
into sugars while removing chlorophyll
chlorophyll is green pigment and
chlorophyll makes your buds taste harsh
and smell bad and it also makes your
buds burn portly uh if you guys ever
smoked herb that kind of maybe tastes
like you just stuck your tongue in a
light socket and you just want to scrape
your tongue off or you need a drink real
bad that stuff was not dried and cured
properly probably not flushed properly
either uh also as THC dries the THC
dries in your buds if it dries more
slowly uh the more slower it loses its
water moisture the more psychoactive it
will become once the water comes out of
that THC that's when it's ripe and nice
and Prime for you to smoke so by curing
it you slowly let that happen and you
don't destroy the THC you don't destroy
your
tpin um essentially curing allows
aerobic bacteria to consume the
chlorophyll in the plants chlorophyll is
what we want to remove um aerobic
bacteria sounds like a bad thing it's
actually a good thing in this instance
um aerobic bacteria is made from air
light and moisture being sealed inside
of that jar so what I do I actually take
my buds that snap I fill my mason jar
about 90% of the way full I don't want
want to squish them in there I just want
to lightly set them in there then I seal
that jar um as soon as that jar is
sealed the aerobic bacteria begins to
form and that aerobic bacteria will
start eating away the chlorophyll in
there um so when you open that jar
that's when the reaction will restart so
what you want to do what I do is I put
the buds in the jar I seal it up and
then I wait about 2 hours and then I go
open the jar and that first time I'll
pour the buds out onto my little tray
and I want to feel the buds and make
sure they're not they haven't gotten
really moist or they haven't if you can
see sweat inside the jar get them out of
there immediately you you [ __ ] up get
them out of there right away uh once so
I take them out of the jar and I start
squeezing them and I want to feel a
little bit of moisture at the edge cuz
it's coming out of the middle on the
surface but I don't want them to be damp
and sticky to where I'm afraid they're
going to get mold so I'll leave them out
this first time I dump them out and
check them all out I leave them sitting
out for a couple minutes if I feel like
they need it then I'll put them back in
the jar and seal that jar up if they're
uh properly dry like I'm hoping they are
at this point I'll leave it closed for 4
hours this time and I know this sounds
tedious but this is where this is what
separates the the pros from the regular
Growers this is where you get that super
high-grade cured cannabis uh that's
stuff you're getting at the dispensary
that tastes kind of hayik and I don't
mean to call out the shops but they
don't have time or space or Manpower or
the patients to cure herb uh your
caregiver or your private grower or you
are the only way you're going to get
good cured herb the dispensary is not
going to do it it tastes you can taste
the nutrients you can taste the leaves
you can taste whatever other planet was
growing next to or hanging next to in
the dry room you can taste that in these
dispensary buds in my opinion there are
very few shops that are actually curing
their Herb in my opinion I don't work
there so I can't tell you what they're
doing I thought you were going to say
there's very very few shops flushing
their stuff that too that too curing it
well you're going to have to let me know
when we that's that's where we'll we'll
go there and get some herblin day
so where I uh so you got to put you put
your buds back in the jar you seal the
jar you wait four hours uh that's when I
open it again and then I want to check
the buds and make sure that they're not
getting uh too much moisture is not
coming out of there if I feel like it's
really humid inside of the jar I said
humid if it's not too humid inside of
the jar uh I'll put them back in there
seal it up and let them sit for like 6
hours um I pretty much increase the time
just by a couple hours until I get to
about 12 hours uh and then once you're
checking them twice a day so I'll do 6
hours and then I'll do like 10 hours and
then I'll wait till about 12 hours and
then I'll usually open them like every
morning when I wake up and then right
before I go to bed that's about 12 hours
usually in my world so you pop open the
jar make sure it's not too moist let it
sit open for just like 10 or 15 minutes
you just want to exchange the air and
then seal it back up and let it sit
there uh once you've got it to a point
where you know it's not going to get any
mold in it that's when I like to just
seal it up and leave it I won't open it
anymore um go ahead it it'll it should
burn really nicely at this point correct
it should burn nice and smooth um and
you can tell um I don't know if you guys
have ever had perfectly cured herb it's
hard to get honestly very but it there
you know that herb you can smell down
the block you're going oh man that stuff
was slowly dried and cured it let all of
the chlorophyll sneak out and it let all
of the flavor that should have been
there uh when the chlorophyll disappears
that's when the other colors the Reds
and the purples start popping up and you
can start seeing those and that's what
gives you really pretty Buds and that's
when the THC is allowed to dry slowly
that's when it becomes more psychoactive
I'm not completely sure about the
terpenoids but it sounds like we need to
give these terpenoids a little bit of
time to cure in there also so they're
not getting destroyed or taken out along
with the chlorop filler with the
moisture if we let it go slowly I think
we're making it smell better because
we're doing something to the turps and
from what I know about them they seem
very fragile too so this is you know
mild or moderate temperatures and
darkness I think are all very key to
this I think I read that terpenoids uh
evaporate at approximately
85° um we read on another on another
episode about 106° was I think where we
said so I think it's right around 100
degrees and some your guys's drying and
curing rooms are getting that hot excuse
me I need a sip
nice all those dabs got me all dried out
and thirsty dude we took some monster
dabs before the show that was pretty
killer uh so you need to keep opening
those jars until you're
confident that it's not going to mold up
in there you want a little bit of
moisture Kyle kushman prefers a bud he
likes to open his jar and take out a
couple of nugs and set them on the table
and he would have sat here and talked
for 20 minutes before he would have been
able to roll them up he would have had
to give you a lecture about veganics
and then after that the bud would be
almost dry enough to roll up sorry Kyle
I'm just picking on you bro you're great
but so Kyle likes his buds a little more
moist our buddy Adam will take a nicely
dried and cured Bud that I've given him
and he'll set that [ __ ] out all day
until it's crispy dry and then he grinds
it up in the grinder towards dust and
takes heroic size bong hits out of it
cuz that's what he likes to
do but the what you want to do is I like
to get it to where it's it's not fluffy
but it's it's got some squishy to it so
if you've got a nice hard dense nug you
want to be able to give it a squeeze and
it just pops back up you don't want to
crush it and you don't want dust you
definitely don't I don't want that dry
Dusty buds no God no um how long do you
try to store your
cannabis um some of it gets stored for
up to 9 months I suppose but you know
some of the outdoor stuff um some of my
patients I can give them their whole
year Supply at once and they're fine
with it some of my other patients ask me
to hold on to it for them so um and then
you know some of them went indoor Bud
throughout the year so you know it's all
a balance but yeah okay um the last
couple years my stuff that's gotten 9 10
months I just I really wasn't happy with
it um by the time it was that age Let's
uh let's work on curing a little better
and I bet that those buds will store
longer I think I messed up in the
beginning um
I do pretty much you what you do for the
the 2hour pull it out of the jar then
the 4 Hour but then it normally it'll go
24 hours 18 hours before I I mess with
it again you got to set some alarms I've
got my iPhone full of alarms just
ridiculous beeps people think I'm doing
something crazy cuz every two hours I
got to run away I I'll be back dude and
got to go somewhere and go pop open a
bunch of jars and then go back and get
them for sure if you're using larger
batches I guess I should have covered
this what I like to do is get one of
those big uh they're like purple
Tupperware containers rubber made
containers uh fill that up with your you
can leave it on the sticks a little bit
if you have to it's easier I prefer it
off the stick for this curing process
fill those containers and then I
actually flip them upside down and take
the container off the lid instead of
taking the lid off the container so you
leave more exposed area and then just
pop that container back onto the lid try
not to squish any buds I hope that makes
sense you pop it open Lift the container
off the lid sitting there like a tray
full of buds for sure yeah that gets a
lot of air flow in there yeah I like to
use those uh actually those same ones or
same samier size uh but they're they're
like the size of a brownie pan yeah and
that's those work for uh short-term
storage pretty good okay now in the
beginning I talked about we should have
a dehumidifier an AC unit fans a
hygrometer uh I'm going to back up and
talk a little bit about how Ed Rosenthal
says curing starts at Harvest wait hold
on I got one thing uh let's do it I like
it how you pack your jar um ah yeah I
don't like to overpack it this something
I um am am learning but I think there's
a lot of validity to
it you uh I think when you overpack it
you create you know possible different
little microclimates in there uh you
almost prevent the aerobic acid from
being able to form in there when you
don't have enough oxygen for sure what
creates IC acid I think I said before
was oxygen light and moisture and so we
need plenty of that air in there nice
nice don't worry about giving it light
you guys a little bit of light will
start it off and once you get it started
it's going I'm fixing the Echoes In Here
we are in a really small space that's
real echoe today there's a fan that
we're fighting with but I'm going to
make it happen I think I got it just
there sweet all right so like I said Ed
Rosenthal says that curing starts from
pretty much when you cut it down so if
your buds have gotten too dry they're
not going to cure they're going to
crumble if your buds are too moist uh
you still have a chance but hopefully
they didn't dry too quickly uh you got
to cut down the Plant and get all those
leaves off and let it dry nice and
slowly that's why we're talking about a
room with a dehumidifier with an air
conditioner and some fans in a
hygrometer you want to keep your plants
between 60 and
75° at about 50% humidity until you put
them in this jar until they reach that
stick snap in Period uh yeah that's how
you keep them from not drying too fast I
had a guy that uh a long time ago I used
to have to buy some herb and this guy
usually had the greatest Bud a long time
ago and I was bugging him I was like
dude you got any more of that LA
Confidential do you have any more of
that LA Confidential and he didn't and
he kept telling me I harvested it it's
almost ready I harvested it's almost
ready and I was getting eager and so uh
I asked him and he's like sure man I'll
bring it to you tonight and he brought
it to me and it was it was a really
weird texture it felt like a pine cone
uh it was hard but it was also squeezy
but the outside was really hard and then
you broke it open and the middle was
soft and it was kind of fluffy on the
inside so I immediately called him I was
like what the hell happened bro and he
said that he dried it by opening the
oven and setting it next to the oven so
that it would dry it out all night oh
[ __ ] yeah so that is a prime example of
what not to do to dry your herb I could
taste it smell it uh it made the weed
smell like spaghetti sauce like it
smelled like marinara for some reason
was the first thing that came to mind
yeah it's going to kill all the turbs
yeah yeah you know some sort of tomatoey
paste or something it was terrible that
sucks so you got to get that herb dried
properly and slowly you don't want to
dry it up too fast you got anything to
add to curing bro I feel like we went
over that really super quickly yeah um
I'm just really stoned it's uh me too me
too it's hard to project a lot of my
thoughts do you need
crayons um so the dehumidifier the AC
unit the fan
and uh the hygrometer you need that
regardless of where you're at um yeah
you got to keep you need a proper room
for drying a lot of guys are just
throwing it in their closet or something
you need a good area for drying uh you
want to keep the air moving the reason
for a dehumidifier what we're trying to
do is we are pulling water out of these
plants that water ends up in the
atmosphere around your plants and then
it has nowhere to go so you got to suck
that water out of there the dehumidifier
is a perfect place for that water to go
and you can reuse that water to water
your plants later
oh yeah that's some good water yeah
however um I do know if you're if say
you're drying uh not a lot of plants in
a large room in the
southwest um you might actually want a
humidifier to help slow things down
right I I'm trying to you know kind of
help out people regionally yeah that's a
good idea we're kind of talking about
Colorado but yeah yeah as long as you
you need to keep it uh about 60 to 75
degrees that cool actually I think will
make your buds dry a little more dense I
think it hardens them up a little bit
also I got to mention dark uh you want
that dry room dark yeah uh drying and
curing should happen in mostly a dark
area I feel like literally a room exact
two same climates one that's dark and
one that's light uh the room with
light's going to the plants are going to
dry
faster it's yeah just kind of experience
I have with my dry room and keeping a
window open sometimes and
not and I know nothing else changed so
so guys it is going to take a little bit
of practice to get your drying and
curing method down right uh you may have
to ruin a jar or two um seal that jar up
go to sleep open it the next day and you
open it and it smells like ammonia you
might have just kind of killed that crop
if it's not moldy if you don't see any
mold break it open as small as you can
get those buds pour it out on a tray let
it dry uh taste it give it a smoke see
if it tastes all right it might be all
right it might be smokable if you left
it in there too long and it molded up
throw it away
remember what you did fix it next time
don't do that same [ __ ] again yeah uh
always start with clean jars clean jars
yeah uh I spent a lot of time today uh
cleaning jars and thinking man this
really sucks this isn't you know but
it's you know every little thing counts
has anybody tried to cut off their feet
and stick cloning gel on their ankle so
that we can clone ourselves cuz we need
to make more more Growers it's hard to
be a a good grower sometimes there is so
like you got to do the growing work
you got to do life and then you got to
clean up after yourself and that's
always the part that gets skipped and
then you got to go start by cleaning
tomorrow guys keep your Grow rooms clean
cuz it builds up quickly and then you
got to clone yourself cuz you just can't
keep everything going I could two of me
would crush yeah yeah yeah if you have a
lot of money and you have no shame and
you want to clean pots and scrub floors
and all that and come to Colorado learn
how to grow weed get in contact with us
did you just make did you just offer an
apprenticeship almost yeah but but they
got to pay to start the company they're
going to pay to start it and then
they're going to be the employee that uh
carries buckets and sweeps floors and
mops up the [ __ ] for us yep and someday
they'll be the bombest dispensary owner
there is yeah we'll teach them how to
grow definitely I need to pass on these
skills to people cuz one day I'm going
to be not here I was going to say get
hit by a truck or something but I didn't
want to J myself one day I'm going to
get hit by a bus you know and I'm not
going to be able to grow weed anymore
the bus just flies through the house
isn't that a line in a Sublime song or
something like
that I don't know yeah something
bulletproof Fest ran over by a truck so
yeah I can't remember off the top of my
head you can't remember most things off
the top of your head anymore well yeah
but I'm the second biggest Sublime fan
in the world so the second the second he
didn't try to take number one yeah yeah
never do all right guys I feel like
we've covered curing I don't know what
else to add to this
uh you're going to mess up some stuff
that's where I was it takes practice and
patience you're not going to get it
right the first time yeah what you can
do is uh go you can open it too often uh
that's a good thing leaving it closed
too long will screw you up so go in
there and open it if you think maybe I
need to open it do uh and then if you
have another jar next to it don't open
that one and just kind of compare take
notes that's the best way to become a
good grower and a good curer and dryer
is to buy practice it and take notes
what's your thoughts on rehydrating dry
weed um you know I'm not a uh I'm not
sponsored by this company but the humid
packs the humid Packs work great for
rehydrating your buds I've been
wondering what they'd be like for
longterm long-term storage as well um
I've seen a lot of people throw their
Herb in a sea vault which doesn't
sponsor me either with a couple of
humida packs and leave it for a really
long time um but back to the dried out
herb don't put lettuce or orange
bags please that's kind of what I was
getting at yeah yeah that'll make mold
yeah that'll make your stuff not taste
right it doesn't add flavor it it will
but not the flavor you want added yeah
yeah it'll be funky flavor unfortunately
it doesn't work that
way um what else was I uh a curing uh
herb that you've possibly purchased from
someone you know just trying to help out
uh listeners here TR to ask them so if
you've got an herb that you don't feel
is dry enough um if you've got some
patience you can cure it if it's sticky
you can leave it in the jar and let it
let it kind of dry real slowly in the
jar leave it in there overnight open it
up check on it in the morning and leave
it open for like 15 minutes and just
repeat that every day until it's good or
open it every 6 hours and check on it if
you're impatient yeah yeah brown paper
sack possibly brown paper sacks are
great because they kind of I did this
when I was just starting I kind of think
that they kind of make a little bit of a
flavor in my buds now I do too and I've
also lost a nice amount of weed a whole
brown paper sandwich bag to mold I Feel
Like It sped up the mold process I kind
of feel like they may absorb oils Asos
to very true but it if you can time it
right it's a great step between the
hanging process and the jar yeah it's
that one if you have to leave it out for
if you've got to be a away at work all
day but you know it should be in the jar
but it's not dry enough for the jar that
bag is probably going to work for you
there's a uh a company ideal for
someone come up with a brown paper sack
that doesn't have all those issues we
just mentioned it's a canvas bag yeah
those uh Vitamin Cottage the old Vitamin
Cottage shopping bags I've cured Urban
those before that's been great yeah I've
seen it done in a 5 gallon bucket as
well oh oh yeah yeah I've done and seen
that too I just prefer I prefer the
glass I feel like it doesn't give me any
flavor for sure uh if you're doing five
gallon bucket
um get the try to find the good Lids
that have the rubber seals in them yeah
um and black buckets from the grow store
if your weed or sure on Williams if your
weed came in a turkey bag it was not
dried and cured properly no no it was
possibly dried and stacked in a corner
yes with all of the others before it got
shipped off to wherever
it's in Colorado Springs so I mentioned
this at the beginning of the episode
guys I'm going to say that we've covered
the dry and curing for the most part if
you have any more questions specific
questions please send me those questions
there's a listener that this episode was
for I don't know if she wants her name
said on the air but she just recently
emailed me uh saying she was excited cuz
I told her it was coming she said she
was excited if I missed anything for you
please let me know anybody else let me
know also I want to I want to make this
work for you everybody needs to be a
good dryer and curer um I know I skipped
a whole bunch of grow lessons we were
doing grow lessons on the show uh we got
all the way through veg we're in like
mid veg phase just before we're going to
flower and we've jumped all over the
place we've harvested we've done outdoor
grow we're now curing we'll get back to
the lessons I've just been trying to do
what's current and what's relevant not
trying to mess you up throw you around
we'll get back to the
lessons um at the beginning of the show
I mentioned that the city council
meeting has been moved city council
first planned the meeting for Monday
they knew it was a holiday they still
wanted to meet but uh they changed their
mind the meeting will now be Tuesday at
7:00
at City Hall it's at one City Hall Plaza
I wrote it down I said at the beginning
of the
show here it's on my phone I better make
sure but go there uh Jesse are you going
to be there bro oh you not I will be
there I'm committing right now I got a
little posy coming with me you got a
posy nice Tuesdays are actually much
better for me Tuesday was kind of hard
or Monday was kind of hard so Tuesday is
way better so it's one city hall Place
Tuesday at 7:00 p.m. if you want to
speak you have to be there about 6:30
and sign up please if you're going to
speak
um try to have some education about what
you're saying don't go in there and cuss
them out don't give them the finger I've
seen people yell at city council before
trying to prove a point and that doesn't
help go in there and try to be if you've
got a suit and a jacket wear that help
us out make some notes that's you know
if you just will most stay on if we do
it right nobody will have to speak if we
do it right a lot of us will show up and
we've got a spokesperson I know who I
would rather speak for us Mike get there
first you go every week get there sign
up speak our part Mike knows exactly
what to say so if we need a spokesperson
he'll sign up and he definitely will
speak hopefully after he speaks they
just deny the thing what they're looking
for hasn't even been submitted to or
what they're talking about hasn't been
shown to them yet we're going to preempt
this so they'll be like oh [ __ ] then
maybe we shouldn't do that we don't want
to see that yeah they don't want to mess
with all 60 of us sitting there at the
city council meeting telling them why it
sucks they'll just go okay you're right
they're pretty sometimes sometimes
especially on a Tuesday after a holiday
no one's going to be in the mood to sit
there this works big holiday so you guys
come out please come out and support us
at the city council if you're in Pablo
Colorado and you are not working or
babysitting or supporting your own
children or uh harvesting your own
plants or something like that you need a
really good excuse if you smoke pot if
you grow cannabis in the city of PUO uh
or the county you need to come to this
meeting cuz this applies to you please
come support us yeah this is a chance to
be this is real activism uh this you
know not Facebook or Instagram [ __ ]
this is you know and come meet Jesse and
I yeah yeah uh that doesn't sound like a
real huge deal but I mean that's some
incentive we'll shake your hand you can
talk to us you can give me show ideas
for sure yeah I'd love to meet you guys
I like to meet the listeners it really
it's fun I've met a couple of people but
yeah so I yeah I'd love to meet more
sometimes it's
awkward sometimes I'm just too damn high
for my own
good all right guys I really appreciate
see I'm too high I can't even say
appreciate I really appreciate you guys
for listening to The Cure lesson like I
said if you've got questions please let
us know cuz we're as dabbed out as you
and we may have gone over stuff we're
kind of experienced and sometimes we
forget the small details yeah still
furiously trying to think of something
that we skipped and Oh They'll email me
they'll tell me my Twitter will light up
and they'll be like you missed this part
bro this episode will actually be posted
in like 3 hours uh people will have
listened to it within 4 hours we'll have
a comment almost live pretty close my
friend that's listening late at night I
hope you're doing well all right we're
going to wrap up this part you got any
shout outs or anything uh what's up
baby what's up hyro peblo yeah hyro
peblo come see me down there still
waiting on someone to come dab me
up yeah I got punched in the arm like
when uh burn was listening to the
episode last time so I just throw that
in there again
I'm a bad influence on Jesse I'm a bad
influence guys go to hyro Pueblo check
them out it's a really great shop also
support Highly Educated titanium don't
forget about the uh new coupon code at
Nature's green remedies uh your purchase
at Nature's green remedies helps keep
homeless people in the Detroit area warm
it's getting coldish [ __ ] up there also
don't forget I need somebody to go and
count how many times I said the f word I
don't think I said it at all in this
episode so we're making progress [ __ ]
yeah see we talked about it ear the
guest can say whatever they want cuz I
like you to be yourself but I got to be
a good host and be a good little boy
what was that coupon code again uh oh
yeah I never said that did I it's coupon
code Helping Hands nice yeah so you can
be a helping hand give a helping hand
it's two words helping hands hands
plural so type that in at Natures green
remedies.com that works for any brand um
I genetics is currently sold out I
apologize um they're cooking right now
the popcorn is popping so give it just a
few weeks here and I'll refill them and
everybody will be happy there will be
new
stuff um guys join the Forum at iry
genetics.com I tried to say iy gentics
color.com but the cotton mouth made my
face stick together so bad I don't know
what even came out I guess I'll just do
this wrap-up part of the show while
Jesse's sitting here usually I play some
music and come back and end it but
there's no reason to take a break cuz
we're on a roll um hey please go leave
me some comments on Stitcher and iTunes
and give me a festar rating on there I
really like that stuff make sure you
follow us follow Jesse on Instagram and
Twitter it's a Jesse grow on Instagram
it's Jesse grow OG on Twitter follow him
he's a good dude follow iy genetics on
Instagram and Twitter follow I culture
on Instagram and Twitter make sure you
follow us on Facebook just participate
we like the interaction we get a lot of
show ideas we got a lot a lot of info
from you guys and it just feels good to
know who's
listening um here we go here's the part
that I always
say oh I already said that kind of here
we'll just say don't forget the show's
available on iTunes Stitcher and also IR
genetics colorado.com I am still making
those videos for YouTube I've posted 11
videos now they are nothing fancy but
they get the point across so that people
on YouTube can catch the show I think
the more people listening the better I
want everybody to listen and grow great
cannabis huge huge shout out to my ninja
Spence and everybody at the Garden of
Weeden they got big plans and I'm stoked
to see how that comes out I'm proud of
you guys big big plans big big plans
don't be afraid to message us guys
thanks for listening take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me