welcome to the show cannabis community
it's time for episode 351 of the Grove
from your heart podcast thanks for
joining me no long fancy intro today
we're gonna get right into this podcast
this episode is brought to you by our
friends at the hella dank seed company
if you need new regular or feminized
seeds for your garden I highly recommend
the hell a dank seed company and you can
find them at dank seed dot store you
guys know I like to start the show off
by letting you know what I'm smoking
today I've been taking dabs of whammy
bar nectar this is a combo of lemon
essence and papaya the flavor is
described as honeysuckle lemon candy and
lemon candies we've talked about this
one on the show before I think the dab I
just took tasted a lot like kiwi
strawberry Snapple so that's what I'm
dabbing on today let's move this podcast
forward I have got a lot to talk about
today I have been talking about doing a
series of episodes that run my listeners
from the very beginning of a grow all
the way to the very end of a grow I want
to talk about selecting your growth
space I want to talk about sprouting
seeds and cutting clones all the way
through the veg phase all the way to
flower all the way up to harvest and
then we'll talk about drying and curing
once again I want to go from beginning
to end I'm gonna do a long series of
detailed episodes and this will be the
first episode in that series in this
episode we're gonna talk about planning
your garden we'll talk about setting
goals for your garden and it will also
give you a few tips on how to stay out
of trouble and avoid common mistakes
people make when setting up a new grow
so now that I've got a solid intro laid
down I'm gonna press pause I'm gonna
take a couple of dabs while you grab a
notebook and when we get back we're
gonna talk about planning your cannabis
garden all right podcast rolled I am
back I am well medicated I am well
hydrated I hope you grabbed a pen and
some paper because there will be a lot
of information in this episode let's get
into planning your new garden before we
start shopping for lights and seeds and
planning for your first harvest there
are a few things you can do to make your
growing experience more enjoyable the
first piece of advice I have for anybody
who is planning to start a new grow is
to buy grow books from reputable grow
authors authors I can recommend
Edie Rosenthal or his servantes Greg
green Robert Connell Clarke Andrew West
now the second piece of advice is to
open those books and read them I
recommend you read the whole book before
you start growing that way you know what
to expect before problems arise that way
if a problem does pop up you know what
you've got because you've seen it in the
book
you know how to diagnose it you know how
to treat it that way you don't make the
problem worse by diagnosing the problem
under pressure and making the wrong
decision so get yourself a grow book
from a reputable grower and read that
book once again I like and rosenthal or
his servantes Greg green Robert Connell
Clarke drew West there are a ton of
great cannabis authors out there reading
books will give you an idea of what to
expect and you'll have an eye for things
when they pop up you won't have as many
surprises you can find books from most
of the authors I listed on Amazon you
can also find a lot of great free PDF
files if you do a quick Google search
another great way to increase your
cannabis knowledge is by listening to
cannabis podcasts if you're a new grower
I recommend shows like the dude grows
and free weed if you're in advanced
grower I recommend shows like cannabis
cultivation and Sciences and shaping
fire another great way to learn about
cannabis is through YouTube there are a
lot of great cannabis YouTube channels
out there but you don't have to watch
cannabis specific videos to learn about
growing you can watch basic plant
biology and basic horticulture videos
and most of that is going to apply to
your cannabis garden so learn about the
plants learn about the way that they
function and learn why they do what they
do through those YouTube videos one
thing I would avoid is cannabis forums
there is a lot of crap in cannabis
forums that's part of why I started this
show I saw people giving terrible advice
on cannabis forums and I wanted to come
on here and correct that so be really
careful if you're taking advice from
cannabis forums I would recommend you
avoid them completely and stick with
books podcasts and YouTube channels from
reputable growers
so my first piece of advice is to buy
and read grow books from reputable
growers then supplement that education
with knowledge from YouTube and podcasts
now before we go too much further with
our plans to grow we've got some things
to consider an important thing to think
about is legality is it legal to grow
where you're planning to set up if it is
illegal I can't recommend you grow there
I've got to tell you to obey the laws if
you do choose to grow in an illegal area
keep in mind you are now committing a
crime that could result in a
life-changing experience for you your
family and everyone in that household if
you are suspected of running an illegal
grow in your home the police possibly
the SWAT team possibly the DEA will kick
in your door and drag you and your
family into your front lawn and your
underwear while they destroy your entire
house they go through everything they
will take all of your money they'll take
your firearms if you have any they will
probably shoot your dog they may shoot
you if your family is home they will be
detained and possibly shot if they don't
react properly to police instructions
your house is now a drug house they come
in ready for war your wife and kids will
never forget the morning the door came
off and armed men came in and took you
to jail and destroyed the house your
life will never be the same think about
this before you choose to set up I know
that sounds dramatic it is dramatic and
it will be traumatic for you and
everyone involved I can't stress this
enough think about this before you hang
up your grow lights think about this
before you order your seeds also keep in
mind that you are producing a high-value
product start thinking now about what
you're going to do if somebody tries to
come in your home and take that from you
while you are there think about it now
so that you know what you're getting
into before the time comes now that I've
made that important disclaimer let's
move forward let's think about why you
are growing are you going to supply
yourself are you going to supply is sick
remember are you trying to be the next
neighborhood hookup are you trying to be
the next Pablo Escobar of cannabis think
about the real reason for your grow and
have a goal in mind if your goal is to
supply yourself think about how much
product you need every 60 to 90 days and
set up a grow that will supply that for
yourself plus maybe a little extra in
case you have an issue or a delay in
your next cycle growing enough product
to supply yourself should be an easy
goal growing enough to supply the whole
neighborhood is when it starts to get
risky every time you hang up another
light you increase your chances of
trouble exponentially in my opinion so
think about the risks involved before
you expand and I always recommend
starting small learning how to grow and
then expand from there so think about
what you realistically expect from your
grow and set a goal for yourself your
grow is going to be limited by the
amount of space you have the amount of
equipment you have and also the amount
of electricity you can provide to that
space one of your goals is to figure out
how to maximize the yield from the
amount of space you have got a
reasonable goal is one pound per
thousand watt light and a thousand watt
light usually is good for about a four
by four to a five by five space so you
would expect about one pound per every
four by four or five by five foot space
now don't expect that right away you've
got to learn how to grow you've got to
learn the genetics you've got to learn
your nutrients and you've got to dial in
the room but to give you guys an
estimate and help you design and set up
your room and understand how to reach
your goals you can reasonably expect one
pound per thousand watt light once you
get good at growing now once you really
get good at growing you should increase
that goal to closer to two pounds per
light and if you move into the
double-ended bulb technology you can
certainly increase your expectations
much more with more lighting of course
all of what I'm talking about is with
high pressure sodium lighting
high-intensity discharge lighting I do
not have enough experience with LEDs to
give you any estimates or expectations
and again this is all just rough
expectations rough guess
it's about a pound per thousand watt
light is your general goal once you
learn how to grow don't focus too much
on yields when you're getting started
focus more on learning the needs of the
plant understanding the cycles of the
plant and learning how to see what the
plants are telling you focus more on
that when you get started then the
yields will come the quality will come
when you develop a relationship with the
plant everything will fall into place so
learn how to grow I'm just giving you a
rough idea of what you can expect once
you get dialed in now let's get back on
track with things we need to think about
when planning our a grow the next thing
I've got written down is safety and
security we're gonna talk about that in
detail in the next episode which is
going to be selecting and planning your
space this is going to be overall
planning your grow the next episode will
focus more in on your space so for
safety and security we're gonna go
quickly you need to worry about the law
I already talked in depth about that you
need to worry about thieves and
criminals I already talked a little bit
about that so safety and security will
be discussed more in the next episode
another thing I've got is water is water
accessible and affordable where you plan
to grow also do you have an excuse for
the extra water consumption the next
thing on the list is electricity when
you're planning your grow keep in mind
that you will be very limited by the
amount of electricity you can pull from
a home most homes have a one or two
hundred amp service depending on your
location if you've only got a hundred
amp service you will be very limited on
how many lights you can run if you've
got two hundred amps of service you'll
still be limited in my experience when
they put the electricity in your house
they did not consider you adding
thousand watt grow lights they put just
enough for you to run all of the
appliances and things in your house and
also plug in the blow dryer and the
microwave they don't give you a lot of
extra amperage because they never
thought you were going to plug in these
high-powered devices so you're going to
be limited by the amount of electricity
before you go out and buy 4,000 watt
lights maybe buy 2 and plug them both in
and see if you start flipping breakers
I'm sure you won't be able to plug in to
1,000 watt light
into the same receptacle in one room
that little plug-in right there it's got
the plug-in on top to plug in on the
bottom you got your phone plugged into
one you got the computer plugged into
the other you cannot plug in two 1000
watt lights into that that will flip the
breaker you're gonna run out to the
garage or wherever you're gonna flip the
breaker you're gonna make it come on
again it's gonna start heating up the
receptacle it's gonna blow the
receptacle or it's gonna catch the wires
on fire don't try to plug in 2000 watt
lights into the same plug in you might
not even be able to run to 1000 watt
lights in the same room if both of the
plugins are on the same breaker most of
the breakers in your house are going to
be 10 amps maybe 20 amps and maybe 35
amps if you're really lucky older homes
are gonna have tens and twenties more
modern homes you may have up to 35 amp
breakers most of our thousand watt grow
lights pool about 8 to 11 amps when they
fire up they want to pull 11 amps to get
started as they're running they'll drop
down to around 7 or 8 amps so you have
to keep that in mind when you're
designing and thinking about your grow
how much amperage is available in the
space in which you plan to grow and
don't expect to run a bunch of extension
cords because they're gonna get hot
they're gonna melt they're gonna catch
on fire they're gonna start flipping
breakers that's going to cause more
problems just realize that you either
need to upgrade the electrical or you
need to settle for less lights also keep
in mind that for every light you hang
you probably need a blower or a fan or
some sort of electricity's so allow
extra amperage for your accessories and
you've also got to run the house you
have to turn on lights in the
refrigerator and what if somebody tries
to run the microwave and it blows up the
whole grow keep that sort of stuff in
mind don't burn down the house with your
grow so we'll talk more about
electricity and the selecting your space
episode as well also airflow you're
gonna need air flow we will talk in
depth about air flow in the next episode
trash you guys people don't consider how
much trash they will create when they
are building and running a grow you're
gonna have boxes that say high pressure
sodium grow light on them you're gonna
have to think about how to get rid of
that discreetly you'll have empty
nutrient bottles that you need to figure
out how to get rid of discreetly then
when we harvest we've got to figure out
how to get rid of that old root ball all
of the sticks and all of that dirt so
that's something to start thinking about
before we start buying grow lights and
buying our seeds another thing to think
about is the odor and aroma of your grow
you don't want to snitch on yourself by
having a stinky garden if you do a good
job your plants are going to stink you
will need some sort of carbon filtration
to prevent the whole neighborhood from
smelling your a grow something a lot of
people don't think about is when you
start cutting down your first grow it
really stinks when you start chopping
into those plants you start breaking
open the turps that's when it really
stinks if you thought it smelled good
around week 6 7 &amp; 8 wait till you cut
them down and you start chopping into
him that's when it's really gonna stink
so be prepared for that harvest stink
also at harvest time you've got to think
about that trash you've got to think
about all that soil and then you've got
a lot of herb to learn how to dry and
cure and store how are you going to dry
it how are you going to cure it you have
space for that where are you going to
store it do you have space for that so
those are things to start thinking about
before you hang up any lights and buy
any seeds now here is a huge thing to
think about when you're planning your
grow what kind of nutrients are you
going to use are you going to go organic
or are you going to go synthetic are you
gonna go a living soil or are you gonna
go Coco are you gonna do no-till or are
you gonna do hydro all of that stuff is
up to you you've got a lot of decisions
to make everything has its advantage and
everything has its disadvantage through
this long series of episodes I will try
to go over the pros and cons of organic
and synthetic of hydro and soil I'll
talk about cocoa I'll talk about dirt I
will try to talk about all of that stuff
and help you make those decisions but
now's the time to start thinking about
it do you want to go organic do you want
to go synthetic along with that decision
comes pest control integrated pest
management do you want to apply spray
applications of pesticides do you
want to use predator bugs all of these
options have their pros and cons and
they're all up to you you'll need to
find a pest management system that also
works with your nutrient system if
you're running a full organic system you
don't want to go in there and apply a
toxic pesticide that could disrupt the
environment you've spent so much time
creating so one of your major things to
think about will be your medium do you
want to run soil soilless mix coco
perlite do you want to run rock wool
cubes
it is all up to you along with that
decision you get to decide what you're
going to feed those plants do you want
to go all organic do you want to go full
synthetics do you want to do a combo
that is up to you
then another major part of that decision
is how you are going to prevent pests it
will all work together your medium your
nutrients and your integrated pest
management will all become one big unit
so think about that in-depth before you
make any decisions and again as this
series continues I will do a lot of
discussions on most of those topics and
try to guide you and I will try to
remain unbiased I will talk about how I
grow and I will also try to give you
unbiased information on other options
and other methods that will work just as
well as the way I have chosen to grow
you guys that's part of the beauty of
setting up your own grow nobody can tell
you what to do there's no right or wrong
way the wrong way is when your plants
die the right way is when you were happy
and you're getting what you want out of
it grow if it's producing the quality
the amount and you're satisfied you're
doing it correctly you could probably
improve a little bit but you're doing it
right and nobody can tell you you're
doing it wrong if you're happy with it
it's your grow like I said you're doing
it wrong when the plants die or when you
get a bunch of bugs but it's your grow
make yourself happy now once you put a
lot of thought into your medium your
nutrients your pest control and if you
want to go organic or synthetic a few
more things you should think about are
do you want to grow from seed or from
clone I will do in depth episodes in the
very near future on the advantages and
disadvantages of starting from seed or
clone and then I will also talk about
how to sprout seeds and we'll also do
episodes on
cutting clones so I will go in-depth on
that subject but start thinking about
that now do you want to grow from seed
or do you want to grow from clone so
those are a bunch of great things to
think about before you even buy a grow
light buy a grow book and read it
find more podcasts that you find
educational and entertaining and listen
to those podcasts then maybe find some
YouTube channels to teach you about
basic Plant Sciences and watch those in
your free time and get a good
understanding of the plant then you've
got a lot of other things to think about
legalities safety and security water
electricity do you have a good excuse
for how much electricity you're about to
start consuming that's something to
think about
think about your trash think about the
aroma you're going to create then you
get to make that big debate nutrients
medium organic versus synthetic and
pesticides that's something to think
about now then you get to think about
seeds or clones that is a lot of stuff
to have on your mind the next thing is
to think about where to put all of this
stuff where are we gonna put the lights
what room is this gonna go in I can
already see the wheels turning in your
head in the next episode we will go
in-depth about where to put your grow
planning your gross space we'll talk
more in depth about choosing the correct
lighting we'll talk more in depth about
air flow and we'll talk more in depth
about all the specific needs you need to
think about when planning your specific
grow space in the next episode now I
also told you I would give you tips on
how to stay out of trouble
the number one tip to stay out of
trouble when working in a grow is to
keep your mouth shut if you were in a
legal area if you're in in illegal area
keep your mouth shut
why does anybody need to know you're
growing cannabis why does anybody need
to know you've got a high-value product
somewhere in your home why does anybody
need to know you've got an extra stream
of income keep your mouth shut all right
you might think what about my best
friend that's the best way to turn your
best friend into somebody you can't
trust what about your girlfriend bro she
might not be your girlfriend forever and
you
don't worry about that [ __ ] when you
guys break up don't tell anybody
your family is shady your bro is shady
your girlfriend is Shady everybody
changes when there is a high-value
product sitting on the table and
nobody's looking so the best way to keep
yourself out of trouble is to not tell
anybody another piece of advice is to
not stink like herb all the time before
you go places take a shower change your
clothes put on some non herb stinking
clothes also don't always have a bunch
of herb don't start selling herb and
making a bunch of extra money don't
start smoking excessively in front of
people don't give anybody any obvious
signs that you have got access to an
excessive amount of cannabis suddenly
don't raise any eyebrows and don't draw
any extra attention to yourself just
stay out of trouble so that's my quick
advice on how to stay out of trouble
when you were starting a new grow just
don't tell anybody don't show off don't
suddenly have too much money and too
much herb stay low-key stay the person
you were before you started growing just
stop paying for herb and start growing
your own Ari ladies and gentlemen that
was the first episode in a long series
of grow lessons thank you for listening
I hope you learned a lot from me I had a
good time teaching you if you feel like
this episode was educational informative
or entertaining and you would like to
contribute to the show financially you
can do so by going to patreon.com slash
grow from your heart that is patreon
patr yo n.com slash grow from your heart
all the information you need to sign up
will be right there
I do appreciate all of your support I
would also appreciate it if you stalk me
on all of the social media you can find
me on Facebook simply search for the
girl from your heart podcast on Twitter
it's at g f YH podcast if you want to
follow my personal Twitter account
it's a trois to Jeff 420 also check out
my Instagram it's Irie underscore
genetics follow me on Instagram check
out the live feeds I go on Instagram
live hangout with my friends take dabs I
answer your grow questions right there
it's a really good time I encourage you
to check it out if you've got something
you'd like to say in your
the social media or perhaps you'd like
to sponsor the podcast or maybe you've
got a product you want me to review you
can send me an email the email address
is grow from your heart at hotmail.com
you know I would love to hear from you
ladies and gentlemen this episode was
short and sweet but I think I got right
to the point
thanks again for listening I'll be back
in a few days with the fresh new episode
I'm gonna give a huge shout-out to Jon
bend it and until next time take a phat
dab and give your mom a hug for me