welcome to the show everybody it's time
for episode 355 of the Grove from your
heart podcast thank you for joining me
this episode of the show is brought to
you by our friends at the hella dank
seed company if you need new genetics
for your garden I highly recommend the
hella dank seed company and you can find
them at dank seed dot store you guys
somebody has been smoking all of my
concentrates but I'm pretty sure it was
me
I've been going pretty quickly through
this blueberry citron fan brochure this
stuff is delicious I've described it as
oranges coated in sugar with a hint of
the purple Laffy Taffy maybe a hint of
blueberry in there it is blueberry and
Clementine so that would make total
sense it gives me a really nice head
buzz it keeps me nice and energized and
it certainly makes me nice and talkative
so it's great podcast Deb's
the only bad part is it tastes really
good so I always want to dab more of it
so it's almost gone the good part about
that is I'll open a fresh concentrate on
the next episode and we will get to talk
about a brand new flavor alright in this
episode we're gonna get back on track
with the grow lessons this will be the
fourth episode in a long series of grow
lessons that will take us from the
beginning of a grow all the way to the
end we've already done planning your
grow we've worked on selecting your grow
space we also talked a lot about
planning your equipment we talked a lot
about planning your lighting your air
conditioning and how to handle air flow
now in this episode we're gonna talk a
little bit about how to control all of
that stuff and what to plug all of those
things into so let's jump right into
selecting your equipment part two the
first thing we'll probably need to think
about is what are we going to plug the
light into sure you can plug it directly
into the wall now it's gonna be on 24
hours a day
don't rely on yourself or your high
roommate or maybe your girlfriend
don't rely on anybody but technology to
turn that light off and on at the same
time every day we need consistent light
control so let's talk about a controller
for that light the easiest route to go
is just a basic on/off timer that you
can program to be on from a certain time
and off at another time I recommend
timers I like a timer with the battery
back up think about this you've got an
analog timer an analog timer you plug it
in and you spin it to the correct time
and then you push pins down for when you
want the light to come on and then you
leave pins up for when you want the
light to go off now you set it to the
correct time and while it's plugged in
that dial spins and then when the time
comes it clicks the lights to the
appropriate on or off and then it keeps
spinning if you have a power
interruption that timer stops spinning
so whatever time the power goes out that
timer thinks it's that time if it goes
out at 3 o'clock it's always 3 o'clock
until the electricity comes back then it
starts back up at 3 o'clock the lights
will come on they'll run until they're
programmed off cycle if you have a
digital timer with a battery back up if
you have a power failure the power goes
out at 3 your clock and your timer keeps
ticking so when the lights come back on
your grow room is still on the regular
schedule and your lights yes you did get
that dark period from the light
interruption but you were now back on
your regular gross Eiko so you're not
gonna throw your whole grow system off
so I recommend if you're going to buy a
basic plug-in timer
I recommend a digital timer with a
battery backup also make sure you get a
timer that is rated to support enough
amperage or voltage for your grow light
so for one light a small plug in timer
it goes straight into the wall you set
the time on that timer you set your off
and on scheduled times and the light
will go off and on when you expect it to
for one light that's a really easy basic
setup you can plug 1,000 watt into that
with no problem in most homes or they do
make another timer that has two outlets
on it with that timer you can plug in
probably two six hundreds definitely two
for hundreds maybe in a 4 and a 6 but I
would not recommend attempting to plug
in 2,000 watts unless you've done some
electrical upgrades in that home that
will flip the breaker if you try to plug
in 2000 watt lights into one outlet
without any upgrades you're gonna flip
the breaker I know I've said that a
couple of times in these episodes but I
want you to keep that in mind when
you're thinking about building your grow
a lot of people say no my house will
probably be able to do it no it won't do
your house isn't special you don't have
magic breakers you didn't buy a magic
ballasts
you're probably gonna flip breakers if
you put too much electricity through
them and you also start running a risk
of fire everything starts getting weaker
the more time you flip that breaker the
weaker its getting which also means
you're heating up the receptacles which
also means you're heating up the wires
you're stressing everything over time
that equals fire so just quit pressing
your luck reduce your amount of lights
settle for having less lighting or pay
for the electrical upgrades that are
required and here's another idea that
people get they plug in the timer then
they plug in the power strip and then
they plug in their light and other
accessories into that power strip make
sure if you're gonna do that that that
power strip is strong enough and rated
to support the voltage and amperage for
all of the electronics you're plugging
into there also you can't plug in
another light just by doing that you're
gonna blow up that timer it's gonna
short out or you're gonna short out the
receptacles I've already talked about
the things that are gonna happen you can
plug in an extension cord or a power
strip into your timer and provide
multiple plug in spots so they all come
on at the same time but do not overload
that power strip maybe have the light
and a fan come on at the same time with
the power strip that's not a bad idea
maybe a light and too small fans would
work for you maybe a light a blower and
a fan but don't think you can outsmart
electricity don't think you got smart by
plugging in a power strip and then you
were able to overload that that timer
that timer will just crap out on you and
then it'll be dark or it'll catch on
fire they may just melt all right so let
me get back on track for one light a
timer plug directly into the wall then
the light plugged in to bat that is
perfect for one light you can also
possibly run two lights if you're
running for 600 watt lights with a dual
timer they do make that it is available
at your gross store it may be available
at your local hardware store I'm not
sure what's available to you it is
certainly available on Amazon of course
we always recommend you shop locally at
a mom and pop shop avoid those big box
stores recently I've said things like
Lowe's and Walmart I say that because I
know you guys have those but if you have
a smaller local shop go there that does
help out all right now we know how to
control one or two lights we just use a
basic horticultural timer plug it into
the wall plug your light into there
that's real easy now what if we want to
run three maybe four maybe six or eight
lights what do we do then the first step
to that is Electrical up
I'm gonna talk about that a lot when we
talk about these lessons because I don't
want you to put yourself or your house
in danger so electrical upgrades if
you're gonna do four lights in a room
you will need electrical upgrades now
when you're doing the electrical
upgrades is the time to start thinking
about your lighting controllers some of
them have a plug it looks like the plug
that plugs into the dryer some of them
are sold with just bare wires at the end
you have to hardwire in keep that in
mind when you're designing your space
and selecting your controller do you
want to hardwire your controller in is
this going to be a permanent fixture or
do you want something you can plug into
a dryer type plug in and then maybe you
can upgrade or downgrade or replace that
unit in the future think about this now
while you're planning your grow so let's
talk about lighting controllers while
we're here what do I mean by a lighting
controller a lighting controller is
basically a large timer that like I said
it either plugs into the dryer plug or
it's hardwired right in and it's got
multiple plugins on it to where you can
plug in 4 6 8 I've seen 12 lights on one
of these devices I've seen 24 lights on
a flip box on lighting controllers a
Gavita master controller will run 48
lights at one time I believe let's focus
more on something you may find in a home
grow now for a lighting controller and a
small home grow you may find a box with
the timer in it with a bunch of plugins
in it with a cord that comes out like I
said that plugs into the 240 or it's
hardwired in now that one timer will
function all of the plugins on that box
there may also be a switch it will allow
a couple of those plugins to operate
independently so they can stay on all
the time or you can flip a switch and
they work with the timer some of the
boxes have that some of them don't the
power box is what I'm speaking of
specifically so basically instead of
plugging a bunch of timers in and trying
to sync them up and plugging all your
lights into for individual timers you
put up a light controller you set the
timer on that you set the light schedule
you want on that you either hardwire
that in or you plug it into the dryer
fixture then you plug your grow lights
into that controller and then when the
scheduled lighting cycle comes on all
four lights come on at once when it goes
off all four lights go off at once you
don't have to deal with a bunch of
timers you don't have to try to sync up
four different timers
have to try to fit four timers in one
spot and plug lights into them it's all
easy to program with one unit with one
timer there are a lot of different
brands of lighting controllers available
earlier I recommended a digital timer
with the battery backup I would also
recommend something similar with your
controller they do offer a light
controller that has a timer with the
battery in it so if the power does go
out that timer stays on the same cycle
that is always advantageous so whether
it's digital or it's analog on your
lighting controller try to look for one
with a battery backup so if you do have
a power failure it doesn't throw
everything off schedule for a home grow
or maybe a small garage grove or
something like a shed grow I would
probably recommend a power box or a
Titan lighting controller I know I don't
recommend a lot of brands I try to stay
away from brands but those are gonna be
the two that are most affordable for
somebody trying to get into a medium
sized grow I often talk about a four
light room that I work in in that room
it is controlled by a power box DPC 7500
it's got the dryer plug that plugs into
a dedicated dryer type plug in that room
then the unit has spots for four plugins
that are synced up with the timer then
there are two plugins that you have the
option of pressing a switch and those
plugins either work with the timer or
they are on continuous which means they
never turn off so in those four main
plugins that work with the timer I plug
in four lights and those other two
plugins I've got a fan and my main
extraction blower running so it's all
operating off of that one unit there are
a lot of options when it comes to
lighting controllers so start thinking
about that as we design our grow room
we've got to plug our lights into
something and we've also got to keep our
lights on a schedule so a lighting
controller will be a huge decision in
designing your grow now let's talk a
little bit about your air conditioner
how are you going to control your air
conditioner are you going to plug it
directly into the wall are you gonna
plug it into one of those accessory
switches on the power box that it's
constantly on and then at that point are
you going to use the thermostat on the
air conditioner and rely on
that or are we going to plug the
air-conditioner into another trigger
device that has a sensor that hangs in
the middle of the room and pays
attention to the temperature there those
are a few things to think about so when
you are buying your air-conditioner if
you plan on plugging it into another
triggering device make sure you buy an
analog air conditioner with analog
controllers like a knob that clicks like
a high medium low some of your digital
air conditioners won't work if you try
to trigger them with another device so
here's how it will work you will have a
switch that plugs into the wall that
switch will have a setting that says I
want this device to come on when the
temperature gets this high I want this
device to go off when the temperature
gets this low so it's just a little
range that you set then that thing has a
cord that hangs in the center of the
room with a thermometer so now we're
getting the temperature from the center
of the room instead of where that air
conditioner is located now we can
actually take a reading from the plant
area instead of that one wall where the
air conditioner is sitting so now the
air conditioner is plugged into this cap
switch the switch is reading from the
middle of the room now what's gonna
happen it's gonna say oh it's reached
the temperature we want let's turn it
off it doesn't reach up and hit the off
switch on the air conditioner it simply
cuts off the power so now there's no
power everything has reset on your
digital device when it comes back on is
that digital air conditioner gonna come
back on in the previous setting or is it
just gonna come back on and blink and
wait for human interaction to tell it
what to do that's the downfall of
digital devices if you only plan to
trigger your air conditioner with the
air conditioners onboard controls you
can get a digital air conditioner if you
plan to run your air conditioner through
another triggering device I recommend an
analogue air conditioner I will make the
same recommendation when it comes to
humidifiers and dehumidifiers if you
want to plug them into the wall and let
them work off their own functions off
their own settings you can do that and
that will be just fine for a tent or a
small room if you really want to dial it
in I recommend something that can take a
humidity measurement from the middle of
the room
I talked about earlier with the air
conditioner you would have a cap switch
that plugs into the wall this would have
a humidistat controller on it it would
say when the humidity gets to this point
activate this power this device it
doesn't even know it's plugged into
there it just knows that it needs to
power that switch when the humidity gets
below here turn that switch off that cap
switch then has a humidistat
on a cord that we can hang in the center
of the room that way we can get our
humidity measurement from a more
appropriate place instead of down on the
corner on the floor where the humidifier
or dehumidifier is located so we've got
a cap switch it's plugged into the wall
it's got settings on it it's got a
courted humidity reader on it that hangs
in the center of the room then we plug
our humidifier or dehumidifier into that
cap switch and it is activated by
readings from the center of the room
these extra controllers are not
necessary but if you really want to dial
in your room to a precise humidity range
and the temperature range and get that
vapor pressure deficit dialed in for
your plants these types of devices are
what you're going to need they make cap
switches to trigger everything you can
trigger your fans your blowers you can
set up cap switches to trigger any type
of grow room equipment if your equipment
is compatible you need the type of
air-conditioner dehumidifier and/or
humidifier that has a knob where you can
set to high and then you can plug those
into other devices that will control
them that way when it they're necessary
they just come on if their highest and
they activate it and then when you reach
the parameters you need they turn off
for that to work we need devices that
can handle power interruptions it won't
reset their settings when they come back
on now that's the basic equipment to set
up an analog grow room now let's talk
about automating things a little more
and also giving ourselves the ability to
make adjustments from a remote location
and also turn off and on equipment from
remote locations we'll be able to
monitor our grow and make changes on the
fly with some of the advanced technology
that is available for our grow rooms
let's talk a little bit about that stuff
there are several options for setting up
a more odd
made a grow room through technology I'm
trying to avoid pitching specific brands
and specific products here but for this
example I'm going to use a specific
piece of equipment and a specific brand
of equipment to paint a picture of how
we can set up an automated grow room I
have a lot of experience with this
device and with this equipment so it
makes it easy for me to draw the plan in
my head which makes it easier for me to
kind of convey the idea to you this is
an example of how I set up the
automation at a recent facility I worked
with and I'm gonna try to stay away from
mentioning brand names and proprietary
specific names of their devices but this
is how we do it this brand comes with
their product comes with a brain that
brain syncs up through Wi-Fi to your
cell phone you set up an account you
create a password then you design your
grow rooms if you've got a bedroom just
go make veg room if you've got two
bedrooms make two bedrooms give them a
name then you enter your flower rooms
flower a flower B flower C however you
want to do it you just type them in and
you create the rooms then you select a
room on the application if you're doing
a small home grow it's probably just the
flower room the one room that you've got
now that's where the next fun piece of
equipment comes in the next piece of
equipment looks like a basic power strip
it's got a plug that plugs into the wall
and then it has four available plug in
spots it plugs into the wall and now it
connects wirelessly to that brain unit
that is connected to your phone now that
power strip has four slots in it that
are numbered 1 2 3 &amp; 4 now you open up
the application on your phone and it
will show you that you have plugged in
that power strip it knows it's there the
app is found it the brain says hey this
is here what do you want me to do with
it you add it you say that is in room 1
you assign it to a room number now
you're already got a room started with a
piece of equipment in there now it's got
4 slots on it you can assign each of
those 4 slots to be a different piece of
equipment so I would say slot 1 is my
lights and now you just it's really easy
to scroll through there's a little dial
it says what is plugged into slot 1 is
an HVAC
in a light is it irrigation it's real
easy it's a light cool no problem
you just hold it slot number one is a
light slot number two is an air
conditioner slot number three is a
blower and slot number 4 is a
dehumidifier we're just being
hypothetical here so once you've got all
of the devices assigned to that power
strip you go to the room and set
settings for the room so our light is
plugged into spot number one you just go
to lighting and you set a lighting
schedule and you hit save and now slot 1
will act accordingly to the schedule you
have just set so the air conditioner at
slot 2 you just go to HVAC then you tell
it I want it to stay this temperature in
here so if it gets too hot it'll fire up
slot number 2 on that power strip and
each spot on that power strip will act
as program now you're gonna say how does
it know what to do because there's
another device in the box that hangs in
the very center of the room and this
device has a light temperature and
humidity sensor that takes a reading
every 15 seconds so every 15 seconds it
takes a fresh reading and it sends the
information back to the brain unit and
the brain says ok so it's 9 a.m. which
means the lights need to be on so I'll
keep that switch on it's gotten up to 84
degrees in here so I need to turn on the
air conditioner and let's check on the
humidity humidity is cool so we don't
need to turn on that device and the fan
that goes with the air conditioner so
that came on to probably so now your
lights are on the air conditioners on
the fans blown around that dehumidifier
doesn't need to be on so it's just
chilling and every 15 seconds that units
gonna keep taking measurements and then
once it sees that we've gotten down to
the parameters we've programmed in then
it will turn off that air conditioner
that fan will turn off the lights will
stay on and that dehumidifier will be
right there on standby for when we need
it the unit I'm talking about also has
the ability to measure the moisture
content in your medium if you're running
rock wool cubes if you're running cocoa
if you're running soil whatever type of
medium you're working in this device has
the ability to measure the moisture
content in your medium that means you
can set up automated irrigation when the
plants reach a certain dryness how does
that work it's fairly
you put these little sticks in your
medium and you calibrate them they link
up to the water content sensor
controller which wirelessly hooks up to
the brain which wirelessly relays to
your phone so that moisture content
meter is constantly every 15 seconds
taking a moisture meter in your medium
it's sending that reading up to the
little brain which is sending it back to
the main brain which is sending it to
your phone now if you have the equipment
installed you can go to that room you
can open the irrigation tab on your
phone and you can tell it to water that
room when it gets to a certain dryness
and you can tell it to water for a
certain amount of time or until it
reaches a certain moisture level
basically the way you would do that you
would plug your irrigation pump into
that power strip I spoke of earlier or
you can add another one of their
specified power strips that syncs up
wirelessly to the brain which then syncs
wirelessly to your phone so you plug
your irrigation pump into that you go to
the irrigation tab in the application
and you tell it when to water and then
when the plants get dry it simply sends
electricity to plug number four or
whichever plug you assigned as
irrigation it'll activate that it will
start watering once it gets wet enough
it will know because it's got a moisture
content sensor in your medium and it
will say wet enough and it'll send a
signal to the brain and it will
discontinue powering your irrigation
pump now there are a lot of ways to
irrigate your system maybe you're
running a flood and drain system maybe
that will just tell it when to flood and
drain maybe you're running pots with an
automated drip system like we talked
about in another episode however you do
it basically you were just triggering
the pump to come on and it knows when to
come on because we've got those moisture
content sensors pressed into our medium
at specified intervals and the unit I'm
talking about allows you to have six
different water probes in different
locations hooked up to one unit so there
are six wired probes that go back to one
unit that one unit then wirelessly sends
the data back to the brain that brain
relays it to your phone so once we've
dialed in automated lighting automated
air conditioning automated
dehumidification and humidification and
now we've got automated irrigation we
have almost got a fully
automated grow room with very basic
equipment and honestly not a huge budget
if you shop smart I know it's exciting
to get everything automated you want it
all dialed in you want it just to happen
it's fun watching the Machine happen I
would just stand in the corner of the
grow room and look at a timer and go so
in about 10 seconds and you would know
that that's gonna switch off that
thing's gonna go that's gonna happen all
the bells are gonna happen the whistles
are gonna happen it's like a big game a
mousetrap it feels really great to watch
with all that being said some of my
favorite advice is keep it simple stupid
I know I'm calling you stupid but that's
the way the saying goes keep it simple
stoner how's that does that feel better
keep it simple stoner we don't need to
make everything elaborate a small grow
does not need a lot of equipment the
more electronics you have the more knobs
and dials and bells and whistles you've
got the more [ __ ] can go wrong if you've
got a light and a fan and an air
conditioner and some way to pull stale
air and heat out of that room you have
got all you need of course it is fun to
trick out the room it's fun to have
accessories it's fun to have toys and
it's also going to improve your quality
if you dial it in properly don't spend
money on a bunch of toys just to have
them think about what you need think
about what's necessity and think about
the order in which you need your new
toys I'm gonna kind of skip off of my
notes here and I'm gonna say instead of
spending a whole bunch of money on some
automation why not buy yourself a better
pH pan I was gonna talk later about pH
pins and EC meters but now's a good time
instead of spending a lot of money on
automation you need a quality pH pen
your plans are gonna look like [ __ ]
without proper pH so if you're putting
together a budget and you're trying to
include Auto watering and you're trying
to decide between a quality pH pin or
maybe some fancy auto watering stuff I
highly recommend you go with a good pH
pen you need that from the beginning
you can add auto watering later you can
buy fancier toys later if you're on a
tight budget get the necessities first
and then we can expand in the future if
you don't have the right stuff you're
not gonna have a quality product and
it's all going to be a giant waste of
money
all right we've talked about controlling
everything
here's something that I want to include
but I'm not sure where it fits in so I'm
just gonna tag it in right here
what about co2 augmentation maybe you
want to add co2 to your grow room this
is probably going to require you making
extra trips to either the gross store or
the commercial gas place our local place
here is called air gas you're gonna have
to buy or rent a container you're gonna
have to get that refilled as frequently
as you need it I don't know how often
it's going to need to be refilled in
your environment I don't know how well
sealed your room is I don't know how
much co2 your room starts with I don't
know how much co2 you're trying to get
it to I don't know how often you'll need
your containers filled but for co2
augmentation you're going to need either
those big tanks or a co2 burner which
will have to be hardwired into your
natural gas line so tanks are probably
the easiest way to go you'll have to get
the tanks get them to the room if you're
not an able-bodied person this could be
challenging the larger tanks are hard
for me to move the smaller tanks are not
light either so once you've got the
tanks to the room now you require a
regulator this screws on to the nozzle
on the tank it'll be obvious when you've
got the tank in the regulator you will
see where that goes you screw on the
regulator there are a couple of knobs
you've got to turn you've got to open
the tank turn the gas on to the tank now
it's gonna be flowing to the regulator
that regulator has a valve you can turn
it will allow gas to flow through the
lines there are lines that attach to the
regulator hang those lines high in your
grow I like to hang them right about the
height of the lights co2 is a gas that
is heavier than oxygen that co2 is gonna
pump through those lines and it will
fall right down onto the plants and
become available for the plants now how
do we know how much co2 is in the room
that's when co2 gets expensive you need
a co2 monitor you can get a standalone
co2 monitor or this will work right into
the automated system I was talking about
earlier there is a tab for co2 so we
need a co2 monitor whether a standalone
unit or unit that's combined with our
other monitoring and triggering system
now your more expensive co2 monitors
will also have a co2 controller the co2
control
work very similarly to the cap
controllers I talked about earlier there
are a lot of different brands and styles
available most of them will have a
screen on that screen you can set the
level that you want the co2 to reach in
that room some of the more advanced
models will also give you the option to
set a schedule so that it comes on only
when the lights are on and it does not
come on when the lights are off we don't
need to add co2 when the lights are off
so you'll be able to set the level you
want the co2 to reach and you'll be able
to set a schedule now this co2 monitor
has a cord hanging off of it which plugs
into the wall or your power source now
the plug that plugs into the wall has a
piggyback that you can just plug your
co2 regulator directly into so now that
thing's going to monitor the level of
co2 in the room and when it needs
electricity triggered to the co2
regulator it will just fire up and let
that co2 regulator know to come on the
co2 regulator will pump gas down those
lines that you've got hung above the
canopy and then once that co2 regulator
says oh it's enough it'll turn that
right off for you so that is the best
way in my opinion to set up co2 in a
small grow that's very similar to the
way it's done in a large commercial grow
we do the same lines above the canopy of
course the lines are much longer and of
course we're not running to the growth
store to refill our canisters all the
time we have a truck that comes and they
actually link up to a giant set of
canisters outside there are about a
dozen six foot tall canisters outside
that the truck fills for us that lasts
about half a week maybe a little less
depending on how many of the rooms are
in full flower but it's very similar to
the way it's done in a commercial
facility now if you don't want to use
the co2 monitor I understand they're
expensive you can put the regulator on a
timer but when you do that how do you
know how much co2 is in that room how do
you know if you even need to add co2 how
do you know if you haven't overdone it
and you're not wasting co2 at this point
I think a co2 monitor is really worth
the money you're gonna spend because
then you can save on co2 in the long run
you won't be overdoing it you won't be
wasting co2 you won't just be blasting
co2 into the room and wondering what's
in there I like knowing what's happening
my grow rooms if they're big if they're
small it's always better to take good
notes and understand what is happening
in there instead of just blasting
something that you're paying a lot of
money for and not understanding any type
of results so if I'm paying money for
co2 I would like to have a co2 monitor
just to see some sort of number go up
just to see my money turn into something
even if it's just a number on that
monitor I want to see some kind of
result so that is my quick sidebar on
co2 augmentation and co2 equipment I
feel like that fit perfectly right there
I feel like this series of grow lessons
is off to a great start we've got some
goals in mind for the grow we know what
to expect from the grow we know where to
put the grow we have a good
understanding of what equipment we need
for the grow we've learned how to set up
our lighting we've learned how to set up
our air conditioning we understand what
type of humidifier and dehumidifier we
might need we've got a good
understanding of how to set up our co2 I
think we are off to a really good start
in the next episode I plan to talk about
selecting the appropriate pots soil and
nutrients for your grow and after that
we'll work our way into integrated pest
management before I start wrapping up
the show I really want to thank you guys
for listening to these grow lessons
thank you for hanging out if you've got
any feedback or any questions about
these lessons please send me an email
it's grow from your heart at hotmail.com
also if you feel like these shows were
educational informative or entertaining
and you'd like to contribute to the show
financially you can do so by visiting
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
and all the information you need to
contribute to the show we'll be right
there
I want to thank everybody again for
listening I'll be back in just a few
days with a fresh new grow lesson I want
to give you a huge shout out to my buddy
Tommy dubs and until next time take a
phat dab and give your mom a hug for me