y what's up ladies and gentlemen it's
time for episode number 36 of the I gr
culture podcast they call me rosta Jeff
and I'm your host joining me at the
table today we got our good buddies tall
Clint hey guys and our good buddy Nemo
Punk what's up folks it's actually Mike
over there but try to advertise his
Twitter a little bit godam too loud temp
the Twitter wow who put the music so
high jeez all right how you guys doing
tonight I'm great brother how are you
you look like you're in a great mood bro
you got a big old smile over there it's
cuz it's Thursday it's Thursday
Thursdays have been great for us lately
I don't know why Thursdays have been
pretty damn good how you doing tonight
Mike I'm doing pretty good it's been a a
stressful but fantastic week it's been a
very stressful week uh man speaking of
stressful I owe you a huge thank you uh
guys we've talked about these uh City
Council meetings for the past uh few
episodes dude Mike
I thought he was going to stand they've
got a nice little seat for you there
like a real cushy chair and a microphone
and [ __ ] you look like a boss it's nice
but Mike presented a nice statement to
city council and uh he actually uh had
some success in what he was trying to do
but we'll talk about that a little bit
uh because I really want to spend some
time on the city council meeting topic
that was there's a lot of stuff to talk
about there yeah it's been a crazy week
in uh marijuana ordinance news I suppose
so we'll get to that in a few minutes
folks we for sure will uh we talked
about this a little bit on the last
episode but Clint wasn't here yeah Clint
and I got to go see Joey Coco Diaz Joey
Diaz Joey Diaz I skipped a part I really
want to say also today we are
celebrating Clint's 8thy year
anniversary of sobriety from alcohol
yeah there you go man dude thanks guys
congrats seriously you said it's nothing
to to toot about but that is eight years
is that's strong well it's it's easy now
it was tough before yeah I'm sure well
congrats bro thanks for sticking with it
cuz I don't think we hang out if you
were the drunk you were before Oh I was
a piece of [ __ ] I mean I'm still a piece
of [ __ ] I just uh don't showcase it as
much yeah alcohol really displays your
shitty side doesn't it [ __ ] yeah that's
why I don't drink too that's why I don't
drink you've seen the South Park I'm my
trash now I'm in
trouble you can keep pretty much
anything under wraps until you get a
couple beers in you and then all of the
Demons come just pouring out that was my
thing well that's the thing it's a
depressant and it is a depressant that
doesn't help me much you know I quit
drinking when I got my medical marijuana
car
and I my life is easier happier when I
wake up I know where my money is I know
where my car is parked [ __ ] I appreciate
it I still drink occasionally like I'll
have a dois but for the most part I quit
like five or six years back just CU I
got really good at throwing up in bars
and I distinctly remember walking up a
flight of stairs it uh think it was the
Celtic in downtown Denver thinking like
yeah man like you didn't get any on you
you're a pro and I got about halfway up
the stairs and it dawned on me that
that's not something I wanted to be pro
at and like yeah this is just one of
those like now I feel weird cuz I'm like
25 and all my social life revolves
around the bars and the bar scene and it
was a little weird to step out of that
for a while but now it's just where I
live alcohol doesn't play a big role
yeah uh once I moved away from my party
town it was a lot easier for me to quit
drinking I lived in Lawrence Kansas for
a little while and it's just really easy
to be a spun in there and then I came
here where there's a lot of drinking and
I know everybody so that sucked me in a
little bit but once I realized what I
was doing uh I just gave it up I can
smoke all the weed I can handle I took a
gram dab last night like why would I
even need alcohol in my life at all he's
going to do another one tonight I'm
going to do it again tonight I filmed
myself taking a gr dab last night and
the video was very disappointing I put
the dab on the Dabber kind of wonky and
it just I it wasn't really that was not
an impressive video we're going to try
it again it'd be a fun video if we could
have like the account from Sesame Street
like photoshopped in there on one dab
two dab yeah it took me several inhales
and exhales to get that dab just
partially because the way I dropped it
on the nail I didn't time it right it
was my breath and the dab right get the
get the right nail the right rig out you
were using a teeny rig practice love big
dab on a teeny rig dude there's
something about it something about it
speaking of big dabs on teeny rigs this
podcast is brought to you by our good
friends at cannabis Grand crew what's
Grand crew you ask you got to check out
the website cannabis grandc crew.com
it's spelled grandcru like the mly crew
is an a private cannabis event in Aspen
Colorado hosted by the grimy Gatsby and
several of the industry leaders I'll
have a lot more information but please
check that out and support the grimy
Gatsby cannabis grandc crew.com so we
were going to talk about Joey Diaz
before I got on this really huge
Sidetrack but I knew where we were I
knew where we were I know what we're
doing I know what we're doing dog just
like Joey knows what he's doing brother
man it was so good so that was I seen a
lot of Comedians and um Anthony jelnick
was one of my favorites but every second
of his act from the time he walks out to
the time he says thank you every second
of that is calculated yeah um I can see
him counting between jokes I can see his
mouth going one two three and he counts
to 11 and then he tells another joke
really yeah but I and so there's that
style you know what I mean he comes out
and that's like uh if that was a band
who would I compare that to that's like
Rush every note is they know they're
doing tonight every single note all the
way through jelnick did that uh Joey
Diaz came out and kind of had an idea of
what he was going to say and just
leveled us just being himself oh it was
so good most of that maybe he's told
those bits two or three times one of the
bits he told I swear I heard him make up
on accident on the podcast just a few
days before he flew to Colorado yeah
he's a [ __ ] Pro and he took that like
something like just right now we'd be
saying something and he'd be like oh my
god dog that's tremendous dog I'm
writing that [ __ ] down dog and he makes
15 minutes out of it brought yeah
brought it to us in Denver several days
later and ruined the club with it my
stomach and ribs and this part of my jaw
right here was sore I was laughing so
hard I had to tense up my back because
it was hurting I had to move my muscle
tension somewhere else you were sitting
back like a little I realized cuz I was
sitting forward on the edge of my seat
the whole time I loved it and and we I
was just sitting forward and just
excited it was so fun and and just every
word he was going to say was going to
make me laugh and Jeff said it he goes
Clint you were laughing harder than
anybody else there it was good because
you appreciated the show and we talked
about being a good audience Clinton is a
performer and we know what it's like and
I'm a musician so I know what it's like
to have a stale audience yeah and it
wasn't us kissing his ass either Joey
was on fire [ __ ] yeah he was well that
was the thing is uh so we he does about
maybe an hour hour and 15 he somewhere
in there yeah and he and he crushes
there was no point in there when I was
bored or anything and then afterwards
we're like oh can we meet him you know
we we wanting to like get backstage you
know we just want to say thank you bon
spoiled you too well I took a bunch of
weed for Joey Diaz also I ain't no chump
yeah bring key for the door we were
going to try to give him a little bit of
weed and so then all of a sudden he he
talks to every single person that wants
to talk to him yeah he came out to the
hallway of the club and just hung out
the only exit that you could take and
he's just standing there and you could
shake his hand get a picture he took a
picture with everybody everybody
everybody uh he asks you your name and
then addresses You by name in the
conversation that's so cool yeah yeah he
remembers your name for that talk he's
he's that kind of guy if you listen to
Diaz you know if he probably still
remembers our names if we see him again
he'll be like oh [ __ ] Clint right
Clint right dog CU he calls you dog
every other word is dog and [ __ ]
did you stand up and out of the crowd
just a teeny bit on your own yeah like
it helps that he's cool but like you
guys have an extra little leg up there
you're both memorable on site we need to
get some ski caps bro and be Opie and
Jacks for
Halloween I could do that man I looking
I'm looking like op a little more every
day every day yeah that's a man beard
over there bro just got to get my wife
killed somehow and then uh hook up with
a prostitute and I'm setad I uh I'm just
kind of awkward silence for a second get
the get I get it you sent out a tweet
this week about your beard that just
crushed me it was the like you with a
beard like this you can't pee
indoors I spent about 5 minutes laughing
at that like that's sort of true
like yeah so you guys if you find Beard
trees growing along the Pacific
Northwest Clinton was plucking beard
hairs out of his beard and throwing them
out the window and hopes to plant Little
Beard trees I'm just trying to get back
to the community guys let's know how let
us know how that worked if you're in the
pnw yeah um but we hung out with Joey
for probably an hour yeah afterwards so
everybody hangs out takes a picture he
Taps me on Joey Diaz Taps me on the
shoulder and walks away and says Ross
the Jeff you know I love you right
[ __ ] and I was like holy [ __ ] [ __ ]
he just called me [ __ ] and Clint
was smooth about it he stuck out his
hand and wanted that one final like this
is my oneon-one he goes hey I'm a stand
I'm an open mic comedian and what you
did I think you told him something about
what you did just changed my mic or
something like that well it just it was
real inspiring is what I think I told
him and he goes dog you're an open micer
dog come here dog and like just took
like seven steps away from where we were
into this little like kind of just off
to the side ambient area and had to talk
with Clint about open mic and standup
comedy yeah and do you want to tell him
tell the world what they told what he
told you or you want to keep that to
yourself no it was so cool it was so
cool just to have this like one-on-one
with a legend in my mind he's a legend
and I you know I don't get Star Struck
or stuff like that because he's a cool
[ __ ] guy and he just he was so
personable but he was just like dog you
got to write an hour a day that's all
you got to do maybe for two weeks you're
not going to get nothing but you just
got to write and you got to write and
you got to keep after it you got to get
on stage and I you know and I was just
sitting there just listening you know
and that's cuz I'm not trying to tell
him anything I'm just Joey this is
awesome and then you know and I was he
was trying to get out of there too so I
was like hey I appreciate it man we're
gonna let you get out of here I hope you
have a great time in Denver and uh was
great he didn't want to leave he liked
hanging out and just having a
conversation you know what I mean he was
like I got to go dog guy I don't want to
but I you can see like you could see he
was a little tired but he was just like
God damn I don't I don't want to leave
he was a great guy and uh so uh if this
gets back to Joey Diaz uh thank you for
the great show thanks for hanging out
thanks for the advice um we love you and
and you got you gained a fan for life by
just hanging out for that hour times two
[ __ ] yeah uh and also dude thanks for
just taking a minute like you're a busy
dude we know you had to get to the hotel
and smoke that blunt they gave you [ __ ]
yeah and those Edibles that you got eat
themas yeah dog so thanks for just
hanging out that's [ __ ] cool you took
a minute and that means a lot you're
he's been in the longest yard he's on
Joe Rogan's podcast he's got his own
podcast if you can uh take an ear
bashing if you've got some balls listen
to the Church of What's Happening Now
with Joey Coco Diaz and Lee sayat it's
not for Gentiles uh not he'll tell you
to go [ __ ] yourself in the first episode
you listen so be prepared but if you can
get past that it's a great show no he's
funny as [ __ ] and then and and if you
get a chance to see him live there's
there's if you miss out you will be you
will regret it if you have an adult
diaper wear one I wanted to piss my
pants I was laughing so hard and the
thing was is I had to piss the whole
time he was up there and I was like I am
not leaving for one moment I will kiss
myself if I I I was so happy to be there
and the tickets were reasonable we saw
him at the Denver Improv beautiful Club
beautiful Club I'd love to go back there
we will be back there also we made a new
friend that night his name is Abdullah
Abdullah you just traveled to
Mississippi and I hope you're doing well
there my friend I hope everything worked
out for you yeah brother shout out bro
find us find us on the internet uh find
me on some social media you said you
don't do that but he actually downloaded
the podcast while he was sitting next to
us so there's a good chance he's
listening find me bro pleas what's up
bro hope everything worked
out all right um I want to talk about
the city council meeting for a minute
but first I got to do this part this
podcast is brought to you by Highly
Educated titanium I said educated it's
educated sorry uh if you're using
high-grade concentrates you deserve a
high-grade titanium nail don't trust a
chinese nail or some American knockoff
made of cheap crappy Metals trust the
industry leader trust the brand that
rosta Jeff
uses God damn I'm getting choked up it's
such a good ad trust Highly Educated
titanium more information on on Highly
Educated products check out www.h Highly
Educated ti.com Highly Educated products
are available at aqualab
technologies.com and also if you're in
Colorado Illusions glass has them and I
also heard JP Wellness has some uh
Highly Educated stuff they don't pay for
ads but if you're in Colorado go shop
there and tell them that that's where
you heard about this we'll do another
quick ad just while we're at it this
podcast is brought to you by Natures
green remedies.com check out Natures
green remedies.com for many of your
favorite
Brands uh mile high can Adventure Gage
green iy genetics they're there check
them out uh when you shop at Nature's
green remedies use coupon code Helping
Hands for 133% off your order and
Nature's green remedies will contribute
$3 of every order to a local homeless
shelter in their area to keep some folks
warm so help keep some folks warm this
winter using coupon code Helping Hands
at Natures green remedies.com got a
couple more ads but I'll sneak those in
in just a little bit uh there was a city
council meeting on Tuesday there's some
hilarious [ __ ] to talk about about from
that
meeting there there's a lot to talk
about from that meeting what part caught
you was hilarious oh
the so I go to every city council
meeting uh for the most part everybody
there knows me I'm used to the police
chief and the fire chief and the city
manager and the City attorney and the
council members coming up and saying hi
or waving or giving me two minutes to
talk to him about whatever um not
everybody in our community is and I was
sort of early to the meeting I had
signed up to speak and from the seat I
usually sit in I can't see the doors
that people walk in from but I can see
uh the city staff and the city council
real well and they're kind of Milling
around waiting for the meeting to start
and their decorum all just they freeze
like when somebody I don't know runs
through a room naked and the rest of the
well-dressed people go wait did that
just happen and everybody freezes for a
second
everybody froze for a second so I swivel
my head and I see two and a quarter sets
of dreadlocks walk in the
door um Jeff and uh two supporters he
brought to the meeting I don't know if
they want to be named by they're
supporters thanks for coming guys Adam
and Angela thank you guys a lot for
joining me to the city council meeting
your numbers made a difference we'll
talk about that in a minute thank you
very much for coming but yeah as you
guys walked in everybody was sort of
like what hippies it city council two
people were
Jedi staring me dude I could feel one
guy's eyes cooking a hole through my
shirt and reading my soul like I was
like H I like looked at him and nodded
like uh-huh I'm not sure why you're
staring like this is weird am I
translucent right now is he seeing a
ghost and so like people start speaking
and I go I look at them while they speak
right and then I get the creepy feeling
again and I look to my left and that
dude is like this at me and for the
listeners it's an intense stare but like
this just intense and sort of angry
flat-faced yeah and I never met the man
it's I've I've met I know him enough to
like say hi and shake his hand but uh
the city manager could not stop staring
at you there's another guy who fits the
exact description of rich white guys uh
like rich white councilman he's Who
You'd think of if I saw him I'd go yeah
city council guy run some [ __ ] okay uh
oh the City attorney yeah the city
manager looked at him and goes who's the
guy in the Hat and I was I saw him say
it like he didn't care that I was
watching him it was kind of awkward that
was funny through the whole meeting he
kept staring at my little group of
people so in a city council meeting they
do they have a little structure they
have their agenda meeting right at the
beginning and then they have like a
little they say the Pledge of Allegiance
and they pray and then uh they open up
the floor and they say they do public
comment and then right after that they
say thank you or they do City
contributions or something they called
it they call it public forum where
anyone from the public can speak for 5
minutes and then they have Council
commentary right after that where any of
the council members there was a part
right before that where the lady goes
this is the part where we would normally
say thanks to the people that have
contributed to the community last week
we did 101 luckily there are none this
week my little group chuckled and I go h
no shout outs on the episode this week
was what I said because I thought that
was funny so like Mike said after that
they let each council member speak so
the first council member speaks and he's
like so first off I want to say thanks
to this person and this person and I
chuckled a little bit I was like H and
the next one is like I want to say
thanks to this person so five people in
a row go and they all basically did
shout outs and by the fourth one I
giggled I giggled out loud and the girl
next to me Angela giggled and then Adam
leaned over and giggled and we were all
just like church giggling and Angela had
the balls to say it she goes shout outs
and we just couldn't even handle
ourselves anymore it was so funny Eva
Montoya wasn't at this meeting but her
little Council commentary for most of
the meetings
is it's blander than any advertising
you've ever heard it's just it's almost
a bulletin board reading session for a
bunch of random local events I mean her
shout outs are always come to The
Pinewood Derby or come down to the
softball game next week or we're doing
an East Side park cleanup like super
duper simple shout outs it's kind of fun
to watch every week the city council
does some shout outs bro there's like 20
minutes of solid like and big shout out
to and one one person goes and also
thanks to Mick it parks and wreck and
kept going and I was like oh they just
shouted out parks and wreck like they
did it like a real shout out it was
really [ __ ] funny so I thought that
was hilarious hilarious yeah if you're
there watching it's it's a play like
anything you would buy tickets to see
it's just a about stuff that's usually
really boring this may get me in trouble
but it's really funny um I don't even
know if I should say this you have to
address the president of city council as
Madam president you don't have to it's
not required the the city staff do it
out of respect like you call your very
condescending tone they they in a very
condescending tone a couple of them were
like yes [ __ ] Madam [ __ ] president
[ __ ] was like what they should have said
like they uh I owe a dollar I owe Five
Doll actually it's more now I wasn't
going to stop you earlier cuz you were
on a roll somebody Count Up Guys
somebody count him up I'm going to pay
that guy I promise $5 per episode on
this one teeny bit it's all right I
promised it it's going to happen I love
it may have to may have to come after
Nature's green remedies gets a refill
but it'll happen yeah well there's been
quite a bit of controversy and like I
don't know friction I suppose you'd call
it between the city council and City
staff and members of city council d a
couple of months ago the council
commentary thing was like the politest
[ __ ] you no [ __ ] you that you have ever
heard um one of the city councilmen was
in the paper saying stuff two or three
of the other ones was doing was illegal
and he kept using the phrase Shadow
government and like they were ready like
I seriously was waiting for him to rise
up with ice piics like as soon as they
cut the camera feed one
night cameras are gone stab stab stab oh
I was sitting in a seat where I could
hear the whole production crew too that
was really a privilege being a nerd like
loving tech gear I was loving it oh yeah
I could see all the sound equipment I
could hear the camera crew behind me it
was awesome they're in that just one
door between me and them and you could
hear them five four three we're live it
was just neat watching it uh yeah I
picked those seats for a reason maybe I
posted a picture I posted a picture on
Instagram of myself uh that was on the I
was on the news and someone's like dude
you look paranoid actually facial
expression was when uh the city council
president announced her resignation
that's the face I made that's the moment
that that picture was taken I can't
believe they used you and Angela as the
reaction footage for that shot though
like the whole room went and they were
like oh get the the dreadlocks get them
on
camera the guy I work in the camera was
one of my best friends from high school
nice yeah we played in the band together
in 1998 so yeah he knew me he walked up
and said hello it was really fun being
in the council meeting newscaster in a
suit walks up all hi Jeff good to see
you he uh I think it's the the same
newscaster that tried to get an
interview with me after probably yeah he
talked to you for a minute during in
there but you were you were kind of you
got shooken up dude you get a little
nervous right before you speak you go in
tunnel vision mode speaking so much but
it's sorted by default I am the guy that
has to stand up and speak because I've
got the squeaky clean everything youve
got the college education you got the
good vocabulary uh I've got the
dreadlocks in the beard they don't want
to talk to me they they stared me down
just just sitting in Council if I would
have walked up there they you got five
minutes and they would have pulled out
their phones and just started tweeting
like and if I would have went up there
they' been like H we're not going to let
the guy with the felony come on here
exactly and let let the security stand
up a little closer please yeah so city
council meeting uh Mike went and spoke
against the proposed ordinance that was
coming up uh we uh you want to tell us
how that went so that I don't have to
Fumble through fumble through it sure um
the proposed ordinance is still sitting
at the planning zoning level they are
what's called a recommending body um
they suggest things to the city council
and the city council can go run with
that idea or have them amend that idea
in some way or they can kill it all
together um usually city council tells
Planning and Zoning like hey we'd like
to see this and then they go work on
that it's my understanding that this is
not that kind of ordinance this is
something Planning and Zoning has been
working on as their own effort
to sort of show city council as a way to
solve some of the complaints they've
been receiving um essentially Planning
and Zoning is fired up because people
can see and smell pot and uh that's bad
as far as they're concerned and they
would like to come up with rules and
regulations so that no one ever sees or
smells pot and if you're trying to grow
your own marijuana or know someone that
is you can see how problematic that
might become if if you've got to get it
all the way back out of sight and out of
mind and you can't do that in your own
home um the problems with this ordinance
sort of spin out of control real rapidly
and uh we as far as the community goes I
think don't like it on every every part
of it as bad and uh so we tried to Rally
up people with the last episode and a
couple of other things to get down to
the meeting and this time we had a
pretty good show of support at the city
council meeting on Tuesday night um I
spoke during public forum and sort of
pleaded with him to think about how many
people in the city they're affecting
with these rules how many people's
rights under Amendment 20 or amend
amendment 64 would be restricted by
these rules I mean now all of a sudden
you've got roommates trying to figure
out who gets to exercise their
constitutional rights and who doesn't
because you can only exercise so many of
them at one time in a home with the plan
showed up with Statistics and counts he
told the city council how many patients
there are in the city and county he told
them how many of them have a caregiver
he told them how much it cost to make a
facility like they're required yeah uh
most of the people that spoke at city
council the city council kind of gave
them the look of yeah we've heard this
before and you're back again this week
thanks gotcha uh when Mike spoke they
all kind of sat up and they actually
leaned forward and listened I was paying
more attention to their faces and just
listening to Mike it uh they like it
when I speak a number of council members
have told me like thanks for having like
some data to back up what you're saying
or taking the time to read the entire
artic a difference they they get a lot
of rambling at them and like Angry
rambling and you know you're fired up
and you're passionate I'm not I'm not a
big fan of public speaking it makes me
incredibly nervous honestly I we did our
best to calm you down you said I'm
nervous as [ __ ] and so we just started
talking to him just
random what do you think about bacon you
just to focus out of it and nah but
somebody's got to do it and I've been
the one that's been biting that bullet
lately so I went down Tuesday night and
said my piece and honestly like usually
when people bring supporters down for
their issue like lately when the the
trash haulers speak there's like five or
10 trash haulers behind them that really
take a minute to cheer and clap um as
soon as the whoever's gotten up to speak
is done speaking and I have expected
what were there six or seven people
behind us with you guys maybe eight i'
say there's about eight of us eight plus
us I wasn't sure how well I did when I
get up and I start giving a speech
honestly I go into a weird little Zone
where I know what kind of what I'm
saying and I'm prepared to say you know
something specific but once I get up and
start talking there isn't a filter
between like brain mic and mouth mic
there's nobody being like don't cuss or
make sure you emphasize this it's all
there's too much adrenaline part did you
realize what you said at the end you
stood up and you said thank you for my
time and you walked away from him
that's um I mean that's the perfect
example like my heart's pounding so fast
and there's so muchen you me they knew
what you meant uh I know what you me you
meant hey you're welcome [ __ ]
essentially like you're welcome I I know
you don't have time to Google this did
it for you so by by coming out and
showing support and by you speaking and
there was another guy that went to
another meeting who spoke about his
family and how this was affecting them
in such a traumatic way uh do you did
you guys make a difference did we all
make a difference it's you said it's
been curbed for a while um okay guys so
Monday we had a city meeting or starting
Monday or since Monday we've had a city
council meeting a Planning and Zoning
meeting and a County Commissioners
meeting at each one of those three
meetings they were discussing rules that
would take away your ability to grow in
your own home limit the amount of plants
you're you're growing to an arbitrary
number that they just picked they
decided I that that'll be enough good
enough we'll capitate 12 in the city or
16 or 18 in the county um and if you
live up in Bula and have 400 acres in
all of that's one property you can only
grow 18 plants there it doesn't matter
how many different residents are set up
on your property and none of that I mean
they're just really terrible rules so
the community kind of tried to Rally we
did the podcast episode there was
another community meeting at The Daily
Grind and there's another one tomorrow
at 4:00 if anyone wants to come on
Friday the 17th at 4:00 uh this won't go
up till Monday morning so never mind
it's already happen you guys are late
sorry guys you guys didn't show up were
you guys oh we were waiting on you want
you to go back in time I'm all dabbed
and started think this was live we we
could put this out tomorrow if we wanted
um we just have to record another one
for Sunday but uh the progress we made
to gu everybody that could make it made
it everybody that um felt like they
wanted to speak spoke um I met the the
gentleman who was quoted in the
chieftain who he's a young guy he's a
little younger than me I'd say he's in
his maybe 25 he's got a wife who's sick
he's got a mother-in-law who's sick and
he's got a child with cancer and he's
there caregiver he has a job where he
can't consume so he's just taking care
of them and his testimony I mean it was
like I was throwing spitballs and he
rolled up in a tank like they they heard
what I had to say at all three meetings
and they appreciated me coming down and
saying my piece but when he got up and
spoke they hit the breakes hard and also
you opened up for this
guy and he was the headliner he was the
headliner essentially yes and uh so
what's come of your guys's work did they
stop it did they hesitate are they going
to rework it the county is They delayed
the vote again to do more
research
um I think for two weeks okay maybe
three watch the county commissioner's
website they post their agendas on
Fridays usually um their meetings are
usually Tuesdays so you get about five
days to check it out and it heads up um
the city has the Planning and Zoning
Miss commission delayed
presenting this plan to city council by
two months ni and they have given those
that came to speak at the Planning and
Zoning meeting a seat at the table while
these rules get reworked so a couple of
us that came to speak against and a
couple of people that came to speak for
will be sitting at the table while these
get redone that's something I kind of
wanted to ask you about that is huge you
said at at when you address city council
you actually said guys please find
somebody that knows what they're talking
about when you do this you looked them
straight in the face you're like you
guys don't know anything about we please
find somebody that knows what they're
talking about and put them on your
committee y uh I almost considered
volunteering or asking you how I get to
be a part of that because uh I am a
legal grower and I'm a caregiver I'm not
a black market guy I think I can set a
good
example more than once I've fantasized
about being able to like kidnap and Hood
a member of city government and like
sneak them through your backyard and be
like this is what it looks like when
it's done right this is what legal looks
like this is what following the rules
looks like Because unless you blown your
house up or you've set your garage on
fire or overloaded a Transformer behind
your house they've never come to your
home that was Mike's main point to city
council he said the guys you're messing
with are the not the medical caregivers
those are commercial Growers that are
making a weed crop you're making those
rules to enforce upon medical caregivers
and you're totally missing the point
yeah and I think they caught on I think
we've got more time to deal with it so
dude get on that committee work it out
let them know like yeah there's a
handful of us that are scrambling if
you're listening to this show and you
are interested in cannabis advocacy you
can find me on Twitter at Nemo punk5
just like it sounds n m o1 K15 or um I
just created a Facebook page it was
something somebody else at one of the
meetings brought up it would be great if
we had a Facebook page where we could
kind of kick out Community activism info
and organize people for when the
meetings are because all of that can be
very confusing and I know we're in an
anti- Facebook mood but uh I'm feel kind
of bad because I spaced the name of the
freaking Facebook page you can't
remember your own Facebook page I'm
pretty sure it's for sensible cannabis
laws or cannabis regulation I don't
remember how it worked saw I saw it the
other night I'm pretty sure that I don't
have a dab and there's one in Arms Reach
pull it up right my memories are further
than they should be let me let me cut
you off I know that uh for the listeners
this might sound like if you're out of
state or if you're out of peblo like
this is not like your you're like oh man
these guys are just talking about
Hometown stuff you guys got to watch
those City councilmen wherever you're at
a local politics is interesting because
it's the stuff that most affects you so
you should be kind of keeping an eye on
your local Council anyway and B if
you're trying to legalize marijuana on
any level getting the people that are
elected right above you is the place to
start yeah so that that was more what I
wanted to say I know that there's
probably some people like H cuz I know I
was no I just wanted to say speeding him
up I speeding him up didn't you see me I
I kep cranking I thrott him a little you
were cranking him I thrott a little bit
try to get it going little
throttle uh so Mike mentioned we're in
an f Facebook mode um I'm I genetics I
had [ __ ] you Facebook I had
5,000 5,000 Facebook friends and I had
close to 7 to 10,000 I didn't pay
attention to the number they're about 7
to 10,000 followers and Facebook decided
to close my damn page [ __ ] you Facebook
eat it Facebook God damn it I haven't
that was Clint over there with the fs so
charge him the five not me please don't
over charge [ __ ] just don't confuse the
voices uh but Facebook dude come on bro
eat a dick why' you do that to me come
on come on so I'm not on Facebook as
much as I used to be I was just going to
go look for Mike's Facebook page and
then I log into Facebook and all I can
do is look at [ __ ] that people that have
liked my [ __ ] I can't really go comment
I can't like I can't post oh post but
yeah but I can't like go comment I can't
Troll and have to fun of being on
Facebook is being a troll and you can't
go troll people anymore so you won't see
me on Facebook but sens cannabis laws is
the page that I created check it out on
Facebook we're rocking out at like eight
likes right now we're happy about that
um yeah you'll get there it takes a
minute I'm not on there yet I figure
it'll be about a year or two before it
starts really rolling and as soon as it
does they'll take it
away don't give him the password [ __ ]
them if you are on Facebook though check
out uh wild cousins wild cousins is my
comedy crew we do comedy in PUO and
Southern Colorado wild cousins on
Facebook just like it's sounds wild
cousins bunch of inbreds getting crazy
you godamn straight I'm the only white
one so I just have to do it to myself
it's definitely a Pueblo show um
speaking of Pueblo this podcast is
brought to you by Hy gr indoor growing
supplies Hy gr indoor growing supplies
has two locations to serve Colorado
seriously guys Hy gr indoor growing
supplies is the grow store where rosta
Jeff shops they give me everything I
need at a great freaking price uh check
them out they're in poblo and in Denver
6271 Beach Street f up in Denver or the
Pueblo location on the east side 618
East 4th Street don't be afraid of the
east side it's just right over the
railroad tracks you just go over the
tracks and then merge and park and
you're there pretty much yeah just be
careful little tiny tiny shop but
they'll get you whatever you want they
will order it they've got plenty of room
to stock it in the back until you come
pick it up check them out tell burn I
said hi tell Jesse I said hi when you're
paying tell them Yo I listen to the Agro
culture podcast and rosta Jeff told me
to make sure I tell you and we'll see
what they do for you they said they're
working on a special for me they don't
know what they're going to do yet but
get in there and tell them that you're
listening to the show um while we're at
it big love to tree Thugger tocom this
episode is brought to you in part by
tree Thugger dcom live music lifestyle
magazine seriously go check out tree
Thugger dcom for cool hippie concert and
Festival news and reviews it's all the
hippie stuff if you got dreadlocks and
you go on tour if you're wearing a pendy
if you got a hat pin if you listen to
sound tribe go check out this this this
website dude my buddy Ryan puts it
together Ryan's a great dude just go
check him out and support him please
thank thanks a lot Ryan all right that's
enough commercials uh I like doing the
commercials in the middle you don't like
overload them at the start that's I
think like listeners should like if you
listen to a lot of podcasts like I do I
like that you break it up and it's like
you know what we're going to talk for a
little bit we're going to get off that
subject here's some more commercials
it's like uh watching TV or something uh
I learned to do them at the beginning
like Rogan does yeah uh because uh if I
prefer you don't but if you want to you
can just skip right through them you
just go about 2 minutes in you're right
past all the five minutes unless he gets
on it
[ __ ] uh tent so if you look on my
table I've not been paid for this yet
but there may be in the future I ordered
Nature Box dude I approve of nature box
they do not sponsor the show in any way
yet uh but that shit's awesome it tastes
good it's good serving sizes uh I've
been replacing my sugary desires with
something from nature box and I feel
better man my teeth aren't going to rot
away as quickly my guts aren't going to
die I'm not going to get diabetes and
that [ __ ] is good it's tasty I wouldn't
go to the store and buy that because at
the store this it's not like a paid
commercial dude but this is the truth at
the store there's chocolate covered this
there's chocolate covered that there's
crispy this there's and oh man so you
just I want the chocolatey one I want
all of them uhhuh but then when Nature
Box sends you a box of like there was
tomato basil covered almonds in there
I'm I'm kind of into that well let's
crack One open all right that box
listeners uh don't go there yet because
we're going to get you a promo code on
the next episode because this is our uh
this is our promo for the commercial for
nature I really am not sponsored by
these guys but it's such a good idea I'm
all about taking care of myself yeah go
for it you just reached in and grabbed a
random delicious this one is called
coconut cashews oh yeah we'll all have a
couple of coconut cashews we'll eat on a
podcast like for Joey Diaz or something
oh I'm I'm not AR shapir I'm not going
to mouth [ __ ] the [ __ ] microphone did
you hear you got a comment from a
listener that said I'm not going to see
you tonight because you because you chew
on
mik oh that was on has his podcast all
right thank you brother nice yeah this
should sound great on a podcast and uh
while I take a couple of moment right
before I'm gonna ask Clint Clint came to
the show because he wants to talk about
not professional Grade weed he had some
questions he's like I'm not a pro and
your weed kills me dude I'm seriously
like I I'll take one hit off a bow and
that's good for me like I'm done like
even right now I took one you guys saw
how minimal I took of that one and it's
[ __ ] me up that's why I got all quiet
when you were talking you know I'm just
going to I'm I'm level with you cuz I'm
it's just it's too strong too fast I've
only been smoking for two months you
don't need Rocket Fuel yet no I need
[ __ ] uh give me that unleaded [ __ ]
that that that 309 [ __ ] number 85
[ __ ] the 85 octane and not the turbo
boost yeah please do not put nitrous in
my [ __ ] so you don't want to take a
half gr dab no I'm not touching dabs I
love you guys but you can go
shove it brother you can put that hot
meil in your ass boy I don't want to
touch it it's scary but the thing is is
I'm getting like a huge high off of one
hit and that's and and I know we've said
this since before I was smoking we said
start slow MH now if I think here in a
couple minutes like it it didn't hit me
well enough I might take another one I'm
not doing that today I got to work
tonight
but that's the thing is I need to know
how do I get my hand some on some like
mediocre weed unless I'm growing or
finding it in the ditch
somewhere my smartass answer is just go
to The Dispensary because it's
all just look at all their jars and pick
the one that's SMS like
hey or maybe you need something more
high in CBD that's but also but less THC
would be beneficial for you you're not
alone here there are a ton of people
that have either avoided marijuana
because of the legalities or you know
for whatever reason and are now walking
into a dispensary going hm and yeah
they've uh rookie cookie is the product
name that sticks in my mind there was an
article about it at The Denver Post not
too long ago is that an actual Colorado
product I'm pretty sure that is a a
product that's sitting on Colorado
dispensaries not to shout out something
it's just a spectacular name the rookie
cookie if I walked in as a 55-year-old
dude into a dispensary and hadn't really
consumed cannabis ever and I saw rookie
cookies I would like clap and laugh
laugh some of those please that's me do
you have rookie weed too and I they're
starting to stock it a numbered
dispensaries from what I understand the
demand is huge for they want regular
weed not back the amazing we got to be
21 to smoke weed you get all these kids
turn into 21 and they're like well it's
legal now I can go do it I can go out to
the bar I can join the military I can go
smoke some pot and that's fine but it's
just I don't want kids starting like
with with some goddamn Bruce Banner
that'll [ __ ] knock me on my ass
or that Bubba Kush that that'll that'll
kick my ass man that'll set you down for
a minute yeah and and it's like four
hours I can't do anything like I'm just
like all right I'm I guess I'm going
through the cosmos right now my mom used
to smoke occasionally not to bust my mom
out but back in the day my mom's [ __ ]
hippie dude Sheed smok weed back in the
day and she slowly quit and she hasn't
smoked for years now that she's got a
good job and [ __ ] but I joke with her
every occasionally you know like you
want to Smoke Joint mom and she's like I
would but your your weed's too damn
strong now she like the last time I
smoked with you guys it was just hell
she used to Lov it she was a pothead
dude she used to wake and bake like I
remember when I was little her and my
uncles that hang out and smoke joints
all day long and now she's like nope
that weed gets me too high and my uncles
are the same way too they used to be
that's where I learned my [ __ ] was from
my uncles that were potheads and party
animals and now now they're like dude
you're crazy that weed's too good like
it's too good that's kind of funny yeah
well and then you're going to get those
guys that used to smoke eight joints and
not get high back in the 70s because it
was dirt weed and then then they come
and they're like well [ __ ] I can smoke a
whole joint why why would I even be
worried about it and it's been 20 years
so they have zero tolerance and all of a
sudden they're thinking oh this is going
to be the same thing as that [ __ ]
dirt weed they go home roll a joint take
five hits and get halfway through it and
yeah by then it's too far the Colorado
rules the laws say that they're supposed
to have every product tested even the
buds so they should have a THC level
printed on the jars we're not there yet
a lot of the shops aren't complying they
just can't afford it and there's not
enough testing facilities yeah right
once we get to that point you need
something like closer to 10 what you've
been smoking is in the 20 range 20% yeah
I've grown herb that's tested in the 27s
Spence actually hit
29 uh did he grow that he grew that yeah
from was Ran's Rhino from seed The
Spence grew shout out to the shout out
to [ __ ] Spence yeah also shout out to
Steep Hill Halen labs are the ones that
test our stuff that was yeah they did a
good job but but that's what I'm getting
at is like there's just like I don't
know you know I guess was more my
question was like is there a strain that
you would recommend to a newbie FL no
flow oh FL FL sorry no it's cool I threw
it out real quick it just happens to be
the one that that I reuse to grow uhow
around around yeah it's a it's a perfect
high it's a nice it's like a 50-50
hybrid the cut that I have is I feel
like it's a 50-50 hybrid uh it's not too
overpowering it's got a good body high
it's got a good head high but for me it
doesn't hit me hard enough I almost got
got rid of it but a lot of my friends
are like dudee you got to grow the flow
so it's still here flow is what I liked
for days for a long time when you've got
a whole bunch of stuff to do but can't
be in pain all day I'd row up a little
flow for the morning and I'd be good all
day and it wasn't near as powerful is
what I wanted for evenings but maybe
like some Jil Bean Jill Bean might be
good for you yeah just something to
maintain you know like I'm not trying to
get all [ __ ] blasted and go take a
nap like I got to do the laundry right
you know like speaking of laundry these
uh cashews was that almonds or cashews
uh they're coconut cashews those are
really good those are delicious dude
Nature Box all day that's I set him down
because I wanted to have one at a time
because I was because I loved it so much
and now I'm a guy who has listened to
Rogan's podcast and everybody's podcast
that says oh go get Nature's box this
converted me right now it did I'm going
to go home and and uh if I can remember
and not be high I'm going to [ __ ]
order me you'll get the munchies and
you'll be like oh I should order Nature
Box oh what was the name of that thing
that we were talking about why doesn't
that episode come out already but that's
why it happened to me uh I hear Rogan
and Diaz talk about it all the time uh
and I think Nerdist even promotes nature
box so they did a free thing they're
like if you order now it's free you get
a free box I didn't pay anything for
this box of Munchies that were eating
they came straight to the door but now
every month I'm going to get a box for
1995 I think it's like proactive gotta I
think it's worth what I would go pay
maor's box like they used to sling crack
yep yep it's like the Columbia House of
snacks first one's free just wanted
everybody to know we all we were all
gonna stop for a second and eat and then
it was just like no dude this yeah it's
pretty delicious [ __ ] I approve Nature
Box hey uh nature box if you're
listening contact me for a sponsorship
because I support your product and it
would work well did you hear that
awesome ad we just did yeah we
accidentally just pumped you up a lot
all right we've been recording for a
long time and Mike has some news I know
we're going to put Mike on again um
sorry back by popular we'll try to keep
everybody awake while he talks um so
save me a couple of minutes to uh read a
couple of listener comments but tell us
about the new cannabis news that you
were uh telling me about when you first
showed up to the house the local uh
profits and such oh the the local PUO
City budget came out this week and the
city seems to think they're going to get
500,000 worth of marijuana taxes just
for the city next year yeah for the the
actual city of clo but wait for the
punch line the the punchline to that is
is the the number that they're going to
get next year is zero not 500,000 and
it's zero instead of 500,000 because we
don't have any marijuana businesses you
actually have to actually have to have a
marijuana business located in your city
to enjoy taxes from those businesses and
the PUO county has already made about
500 Grand this year between the wreck
shops and the medical shops the local
tax and the little Kickback that the
state sends on the Statewide tax now
I've looked most of City Council in the
face recently they seem like an
intelligent group of people where are
they predicting this money comes from if
we're not allowed to have a dispensary
the the city manager puts that budget
together and hands it to city council
that's part of the meeting we saw the
other night and so they're probably
looking at it thinking the same thing
everyone in peblo that read the
chieftain today and the three of us are
thinking is well if it's really zero
because we don't have any marijuana
businesses where's this 500,000 number
coming from well I heard him the irony
in that is I honestly I rarely go to
City Council meetings and I will now um
I'm an anxious person and I felt
intimidated to go I've broken the ice
and I'm not afraid anymore you'll see me
there more often thank you um I don't
know what I was going to say remind me
where I was headed with that oh right at
the beginning one of their first things
was and we're proud to announce it last
week where our budget was like
$484,000 or million dollar short but
we've presented to you a balanced budget
this week and that's one of the things
we fixed in our work sessions but they
didn't really present a balanced budget
now that they just revealed their secret
they added in $500,000 that they're not
going to get they made it up oh no what
I'm a little worried about is if that
500 Grand pot number was in there before
they carved out the three and a half
million or whatever that they carved out
over the last week like they might have
been 4 million short and they only
filled the whole three and a half
million worth because they're pretending
there's another half million that's
going to come out I don't know weedman's
ass I don't know you have to have a pot
store to get let a couple of
dispensaries build within City Limits
the license ing alone is 300 or I think
it's like $3,000 for one uh each license
you have to have several depending on
what you're doing is five grand to the
city and the state so it's essentially
10 grand to do just a grow 10 grand to
do the store 10 grand to do the hash
making so if they open five shops they'd
make 25gs right away minimum the city's
already taking in about five shops would
be 50 G's Oh you mean I see what you're
saying split it but the problem with
that though is is what they're worried
about is that you can't just allow one
cuz that's a monopoly and you can't just
allow five cuz that's still a monopoly
in my opinion you can't say oh you got
here too late you're not allowed to
start that's not the American way this
town doesn't really need more than and
this sounds ridiculous coming for me but
if a shop did it right three or four
shops would be more than enough for this
city I agree but that's that's on the
businesses to decide later like oh you
know I don't think we can make money by
starting one so yeah we're going to get
influx of five and then all of a sudden
it's going to be like wow we're we're
we're all not doing great but this guy's
not doing well at all and then he closes
down and it's we're going to see that
one of these days we're going to see the
first pot shop closed down we're going
to be like that's weird like if a liquor
store goes out we're like oh we get it
because there's a liquor store on every
every
corner excuse me you could do it bro can
single-handedly cleaning up the airwaves
for there we go no but what I'm saying
is like we see a liquor store on every
and there's a bar on every other one so
we see all these liquor stores and the
liquor store goes out we're like oh yeah
of course it did There's super
competition that's what's going to
happen with weed and so prices are going
to have to start dropping and that's
better for everybody yep that's in
Washington right now you're looking at
$60 and change for a gram of legal
marijuana what yeah the the look you two
just gave me is the look that you should
have given me cuz it's nuts but if
you're paying $60 for a gram of
marijuana you need to slap yourself in
the face with your own penis you need to
listen to a good podcast that teaches
you how to grow and provide your own
cannabis and then you need to go to
Natures green remedies.com and use
coupon code Helping Hands and Order
yourself some freaking highgrade seeds I
recommend iy genetics Gage green
genetics or maybe some Alpha chronic we
uh actually watched what you're talking
about uh with po stores closing and the
price dropping with medical over the
last decade and then went January 1st
that the whole clock reset they just
wound it back to
2004 pods back to 450 now this place
that's got $60 GS is that because of a
supply and demand thing yeah that's the
all all of the shops in Washington
there's a very few shops that are open
their supply is extremely limited they
didn't have the time to bring in the
crops before this all went live like
with the licensing you weren't allowed
to grow for very long before shops were
allowed to open so they just haven't had
any time in a year or two when you know
shop numbers have risen significantly
production numbers have you know had a
Time to come in all of that'll change a
bit but it's going to be a year or two
before you can buy a reasonable Graham
legally in Washington Seattle has no
idea what's coming to them I know a
little secret right now
Seattle sons of [ __ ] you don't
deserve it [ __ ] coming oh they deserve
it I'm excited and I'm proud for Seattle
and for what's happening that's going to
be a great thing luck I'm super excited
for who we're talking about I'm really
disappointed that it's happening now
we'll make the announcement closer to
the start of the Year guys we got some
cool news for you there's a lot of cool
stuff coming up it's not really our
announcement to make yeah we'll have uh
we'll have those people on the show
it'll be dope um dope so Mike you got
your news out Clint you got to ask about
well we didn't you just got to find some
shitty weed I guess dude you got to go
to uh man we figured it out man go to a
dispensary tried to bring you some H you
brought me some good weed I'm afraid see
that's the thing is I'm always
constantly afraid of like whatever I get
too I'm like so so is this going to kill
me like is this the one that sends me
into like a a panic or something like
that like unfortunately so far you know
I've gotten really [ __ ] high and it
has like I haven't had like this huge
bad trip or anything like that then
you're probably not going to no that's
the thing is I can talk myself out of
them because I know I'm on drugs right
now I understand it's not well yeah no
but I mean as high as you're getting it
probably feels that way [ __ ] up man
that's good you you need to be able to
remind yourself that cannabis can't kill
humans like no that's fine it's not been
my Mantra before when you're too high
now you're just killing cancer yeah [ __ ]
yeah I ain't got cancer for [ __ ] if
you're too high your Cancer's too high
also and it's just going backwards going
I don't know what to do I'm not cancer
anymore and it just starts dying I'm
making all of that
up he's Jeff is not a doctor surprising
guys know surprisingly you wouldn't you
would never not count as a medical
opinion so Clint is talking about
getting too wrecked off of like a bowl
of two good old weed and last night I
did a gram dab and I honestly have not
been that high since I did a half gram
dab
recently but it took me no you remember
on the show when I ate that 350
milligram edible yeah I was nearly I was
equally high but in a different way uh I
was like redyed and stoned I was Chinese
last night after that grham dab when I
ate that edible I was I felt like I was
on energy drugs I was jumping around and
giddy I couldn't jump around like there
was no giddy last night shout out to
Giddy up since I keep saying giddy what
up giddy up 710 I bumped into him on
chat roulette and it was really
funny he had his pants on it was cool
Stoners and people jerking off it's two
dudes staring at each other smoking weed
just what are you what are you doing
what are you doing well I was about to
hit this it's funny like we both came on
and we go Hey cuz we recognized each
other and then I held up my rig and he
held up his rig and we started laughing
like yeah taking dabs on chat roulette
like everyone else has their wiener out
on that channel and it's kind of weird
all right if you're into online chatting
with other Stoners there's a thing
called Puff Puff chat that I've heard
about a number of places but I haven't
actually attempted to enjoy trying to
keep up with somebody
just set a TV to fast forward just to
[ __ ] with you like they're just dogging
on these [ __ ] things you're like oh I
can't keep up oh this this little tiny
chick is kicking my
ass this is
[ __ ] I have no tolerance so it'd be
I'd be done I love puff puff what was it
I think it was called Puff Puff chat the
last time I got online for something
that was designed for stoners to come
together and get stoned on webcams
together it got shut down like an hour
after it started like the DEA showed up
and we're like What are yall doing
videoing yourself committing crimes huh
this sounds fun you can't prove it and
uh oregano oregano yeah my Facebook page
used to say this is all an illusion
nothing you see here is real like just
and then we live in Colorado I do live
in Colorado and I take dabs and I've got
the legal allowed amount of cannabis so
I don't give a [ __ ] right now um that's
right all right we got to start wrapping
it up we're close to an hour Mike you
got any plugs or any [ __ ] to wrap the
show up with
that's a Blank Stare Clinton you start
thinking I should have had some notes
about when the next commissioner meeting
or when the next city council meeting is
but uh I don't guys if you are a
cannabis supporter in the city of peblo
Colorado the county of peblo Colorado
please follow Mike Nikon not Nikon Nemo
Punk Nemo Punk 15 on Twitter he's Nikon
is what it it comes up on the name there
it's confusing and obnoxious and a
little Soph Mark but at this point I'm
proud of a handful of my followers like
a couple of major news outlets follow my
[ __ ] ass and I don't want to start
over that's it that's it so I'm just
going to kind of bear that Nemo Punk 15
cross TT implodes find him on there
because he will tweet when all of the
meetings are he is going to take that
responsibility the City Council meetings
that we need to go to the Commissioners
meetings the Planning and Zoning
meetings if it feels like there's a
cannabis presence needed Mike will start
tweeting that stuff out for us igro
culture will start retweeting that we'll
have a little uh Community Action tall
Clint will help tall Clint it's your
turn buddy let yeah uh find me on uh
Facebook and Instagram tall Clint
Twitter tall Clint it's all I I just
stuck with the same thing because I want
to Brand it I guess I don't know it
works well Tall Clint it works yeah yeah
and I'm tall and I'm Clint I hope you
don't think it's Cliff Griz Adams was
taken it looked like another word the
first time I saw it on there it did not
look like it said Clint there's no n in
the word you're thinking of or there is
an n in the world think of you're
thinking of when the L in the I become a
u yes yeah that one's the L and the eye
had United to a
uu if if it was going to be in my name
it makes complete sense that's why I
thought I think I said that word on the
show earlier actually yeah you did
that's funny I may edit that word out
that word never I've never said that on
a podcast I can I can't say the f one
but that one that's weird yeah well
we're not trying to offend people and
people get offended by that so if you
have a charity hit roster Jeff up to uh
to take another cuss word out of this
vocabul oh man um guys since everyone's
doing plugs check me out I no longer
have have the iy genetics Facebook page
that sucks so follow uh igr culture on
Instagram and Twitter Agro culture has a
Facebook page of course you can follow
me I've started posting dab videos and
weed pictures on rosted Jeff 420 that
was hard to say for some reason um I
want to give a couple of shout outs
people left me some really cool comments
on iTunes thank you guys for leaving the
iTunes comments uh this first comment is
from hippie nurse 17 what up hippie
nurse hope you're doing well you're
having a rough day I hope listening to
the podcast and hearing a shout out
makes you smile you've got a rough job
and I appreciate what you do um she's a
nurse at night dude God I have so much
respect for that she doesn't know how
much respect I have for it but maybe she
will now um her comment says and she
gave us five stars thanks for that her
comment says I've been a listener since
episode one I can hear a difference in
the tone quality and flow of each
episode as you progress you guys are
getting better and better with each
episode I love that you keep it light
and informative it makes it easier for
newbies like myself to understand keep
up the good work I love it yeah that's
what we're aiming for for so thanks a
lot hippie nurse thank you for listening
since episode one um she used to always
she would tweet me and message me like
when is the new episode coming when is
the new episode coming and I was like it
comes out at 7:10 in the morning on
Mondays and she said I work nights can
it come out at 4:20 a.m. and so now it
comes out that's why it pops up kind of
randomly late at night on Sundays so
that she can listen to it her Sunday
shift at work nice that's what we do for
the listeners and she sent us a nice
comment so thanks it works out well I
hope you're doing well hippie nurse yeah
we need some more five stars guys please
yeah well we got another one this guy
Billy Bob Ray no it's Billy Bobo Ray
Billy Bobo Ray
yeah Fett Ray that could be the guy
Charleson he's not just from Oregon or
South Carolina or a Bobo Shanti rosarian
all possibilities all of them I like
this guy uh or his middle name could be
Bobo also you might have the same
problem I have with a bad handle though
bro so uh he says roster Jeff is fun to
listen to but be prepared for some
Stoner moments like where was this
conversation going and what were we
talking about hey dude that happens we
are smoking smoking award-winning hash
award-winning flowers um I don't think
he was being disparaging on that I think
was trying to like here you go guys it's
fun great show that's going to happen
you're aware sometimes I don't take
offense to that that's accurate [ __ ] I'm
high that's going to happen [ __ ] yeah
that's part of the fun of the whole
thing though uh I sometimes random [ __ ]
is where the good [ __ ] comes out I used
to script almost everything I used to
type out like a lot of what I was going
to say and then I listened to the
episodes and it felt like this good
evening thank you for listening to Agro
culture podcast my name is Jeff and now
I write like bullet points and try to
rant on those bullet points and keep it
moving because it feels a lot better
yeah but that does create those Stoner
moments that's for
sure how's he doing Billy Bobo Ray yeah
he was say you were saying you were
gonna keep reading his thing oh that's
that's what he wrote that's what he
wrote and he gave us four stars so
that's cool enough four Works four Works
pass middle school with a 60 so so this
is way
better I like it I like it dude thanks
for uh leaving a comment Billy Bobo Ray
Billy Bob Bob Ray we apologize for
butchering your name repeatedly I'm high
making it fun it's cool I'm not
butchering it it's got me entertained as
[ __ ] I don't think we had anywhere is
this going moments this episode I think
this whole episode was a where the hell
is this going I felt like Jeff was
trying to drag me back to the point like
for an hour well just not an hour but
you know there was a couple good minutes
in there guys I hope you heard me trying
to put him back on track we got on
nature box for at least 10
minutes those [ __ ] almonds were great
all right don't go back don't go back we
got don't go back we already sold that
product front me there you go Bobo I
fixed it I saved it I wish that I could
get my nature box at Hy gr indor growing
supplies all right um we're going to
wrap this up guys um I have Jesse coming
back in a couple of episodes I'm not
sure he'll be back this week or in about
10 days he's hard to get here he's a
busy man he's married he works several
jobs he's an awesome dude he's worth
waiting for but we are going to discuss
building your grow room people have
asked also a listener said that they
have a $500 budget and they would like
to learn how to grow a small grow room
to supply themselves I have a couple of
good ideas on how that might work so I'm
going to work on that for you we'll put
an episode together I have a couple of
news articles that I did not read on
this show so they'll be coming up in the
next episode D thank you guys for
listening I'm going to read that part
that I read at the end of the show it
goes like this now that the show's over
please go to iTunes go to the iTunes
Store search for igro culture find the
review section give me a five or a four
star rating after that type in a comment
let me know what you think of the show
and I'll read your comments on the show
Stitcher listeners you guys can do the
same thing they've updated Stitcher and
the comments work now yeah uh don't
forget that the show is available on
iTunes Stitcher and every single episode
is archived on iy gentics color.com make
sure you browse around on iy genetics
colorado.com check out the gallery check
out the genetics page if you're
interested join the Forum I uh I will
communicate with you through that Forum
quite often since Facebook kind of gave
me the middle finger I spend a lot more
time on the Forum I'm also adding videos
to YouTube right now they're nothing
fancy as I get caught up the videos are
getting better and better and better so
if you uh can't listen through iTunes
Stitcher or the website you can always
check them out on YouTube I post some
pictures in there also that may be
interesting to you also a big shout out
to my ninja Spence I want to thank you
guys for listening thank you guys for
coming to podcast tonight taking some
time out of your night thanks brother
thanks for having me man yeah and if you
guys got questions like Jeff said just
ask him man that's a thing ask love to
answer the questions that's what I'm
here for you know I don't feel I'm not
here to entertain myself it does feel
really great to put this out but I'm
here to help everybody out I've got a
good grasp on this I love podcasting so
I'm here to help you guys out until next
time guys take a fat dab and give your
mom a hug for me
[Music]
it hurts so
much I know it's
right
[Music]
internal All I
Ask
ISE how deep is your cut dread it's
getting worse how much does it hurt
dread it hurts so much how de is your