welcome to the show podcast world it's
time for episode 361 of the growth from
your heart podcast this episode is
brought to you by my friends at the hell
a dank seed company if you need new
seeds for your garden I highly recommend
the hella dank seed company and you can
find them at dank seed dot store you
guys know I like to start the show off
by letting you know what I'm smoking
today I tried to kill our friend white
Mike with a nice array of dabs I think
we just hit the orange skittles ambrosia
from apothecary how you doing my face
tan that one how you doing over there
bro feeling the burn the feeling the
burn you uh it's nice and cold but
you're you're nice and sweaty over there
bro yeah it's like probably thirty
degrees outside and I am sweaty - I took
a dab of this orange skittles ambrosia
and my body temperature just went up
super fast
I felt it started like my toes my feet
got sweaty and then my armpits got
sweaty and then my forehead got a little
sweaty yeah it might just keep saying I
think we tried to give Mike a collapse
long you can go ahead and cop into the
mic bro that's kind of part of the five
of the show you can cop this one hmm you
guys this is not going to be a grow less
let me put you back everybody Mike's
back I think Mike is coming out of his
dad coma there you guys this is not
going to be one of the grow lessons that
we do we are going to talk about Canada
this episode will come out either the
day or the day after
Canada enters the world of legalization
welcome to the club welcome to the club
Canada in some ways bro they kind of did
it better than us they're definitely
going bigger they're going bigger that
is for sure some of their rules are
better some of their laws are better
some of their opportunities are better
well they had a lot of other people
blazed the trail for him true trad there
were several delegations that came to
Colorado over the years I'm leading up
to this looking at different rules we
had implemented other states that
implemented and seeing how they played
out in practice before they went ahead
with their law I think they're doing it
right most of what they're doing makes
sense to me let's talk more about what
we've been dabbing on bro we can went
kind of quickly over they did sort
that was a tease folks we've still got a
pile a hash to talk about ah so we
started off with some I think we started
with just sticking together so I took
some of the I'll talking to the
microphone I took some of the fat so
batter that I talked about that garlic
scented one and I dunked that into the
star dog terpenes that gave me I had
punch that was intense
that was my first dab in like a week and
a half well welcome back that that's how
we started the day then we followed that
up with the mochi gelato another
apothecary Farms product the smell
coming off that one just out of the jar
is something that speaks to my soul I
described it much differently than Mike
did I kind of said that it smelled like
the aroma of Girl Scout cookies plus
like a toasted marshmallow sort of aroma
Mike had a much more unique description
I thought it was uh it reminds me of if
you've ever had to like change the
string on your weed whacker
like the head of your weed whacker that
oil and green plant kind of smell mixed
together but not real fuelie it just
doesn't sound pleasant to me that takes
an odd odor
but it's really Pleasant and hash I
don't know alright I really like as long
as you like it or I guess as long as you
have some sort of opinion I guess [ __ ]
the hashes been delicious today and then
we followed that up with the orange
skittles ambrosia skittles with a Z via
this one when they showed me the jar I
was like and I have coming back and he's
like do you want this jar and I was like
I want that jar it just coats your teeth
oh yeah like my teeth and lips are just
sticky from it it makes your lipstick it
makes your teeth sticky but I think it
tastes so I talked about the Clementine
a lot the clementines got a sweet sugary
orange kind of a thing this is just
straight oranges not the sweet part this
is just the straight citrusy punch where
you going like okay [ __ ] cooked I
just you're holding the jar and you're
talking about it and I just want to
smell it but I leaned in and tried to
sniff the mic I saw you do something I'm
glad but yeah my bait desk just tried to
get the scent of that hash off the
microphone well
it's loud enough to where you just might
do it but you might want to check the
headphones is where it's gonna come
through here man take a smell of it that
is the orange y'all should see this
chart it's just like a pile of crystals
that's a four gram jar and it is it
looks like the it's not the color but is
the size of the row on the top of some
sushi is what it looks like it has got
that nice shiny texture and it's about
the same size of some eggs you'd see on
top of sushi maybe a little bit bigger
than that and I probably just ruined a
bunch of people's appetite by comparing
it to the stuff on top of sushi but it's
it's beautiful I think it I'm really
glad I went up there for that it was of
course apothecary or ambrosia days and
apothecary I had to go up there and
participate so those are my grabs the
orange skittles the mochi gelato and the
star dog ambrosia of course Nara is
always one of my favorites it's a grits
trim it's a four gram jar and it is just
two giant crystals and a little bit of
sauce in there
I prefer there's a little more sauce in
there than I would prefer so I've been
dunking other dabs into it it's really
nice ending using those troops yeah it's
really nice it's a really nice little
accent for other things I think the
Terps
give it a little bit of a turbo boost
all right so we went from not talking
about what we were smoking to way
talking about what we were smoking let's
uh let's talk about Canadia
oh all right before we get into the
Canada stuff might told me a really
funny story as we were setting up today
let's talk about this poor dude in
Canada that tried to hold an anti in
cannabis rally so the listeners of the
show will know that I follow the anti
cannabis community pretty closely yeah
this popped across my screen this week
it was another anti cannabis page like
lamenting that this is the way of things
and this dude up in Canada is just
really really teed off about
legalization and he was gonna host an
anti cannabis march on the 17th
Wednesday
is sort of a counter show a force to the
legalization of in Canada in he's
canceling his event
because of a lack of interest nobody
wanted to come nobody's interested
that's all and I just had to chuckle
they've the anti canvas communities
spent a lot of time over the last maybe
four years of really trying to make it
seem like there's this growing just wave
of people who have had enough with
legalization and her coming out to fight
it and it's really just like fourteen
people that each run three Facebook
pages and then Kevin Sabet and like the
five guys he pays that's it they're just
hate typing all day long yep no and it
just seems like there's a bunch of
groups out there when there's really
like a handful of people so not nobody
but those fourteen folks showed up to
protest in Canada well no the you have
those fourteen folks are spread out all
over the US and none of them felt like
traveling to Canada to help with this
protest so the dude got no interest
that's awesome and sorry
put a thing up saying the events
canceled no one's interested you guys
suck
it's a shame no one else's isn't fired
up about legalization and how it's gonna
destroy the country people are fired up
about legalization but I think they're
on the other side I think they're so
they're that's I've been fighting the
urge to do a post on my page about this
because I'm waiting for the shots of the
crowds of people that come out to
celebrate tomorrow
yeah dude I've been thinking about
January first fourteen and you have a
said about that I was cooking my
breakfast does like Canada it gets to do
that tomorrow that's gonna be pretty
cool I realized that my receipt from the
first day legalization is still packed
and looks like [ __ ] I need to get that
box out I really need to do that now I
haven't talked about this a lot but
because I was the first person to buy
recreational cannabis in Pueblo Colorado
when cannabis became legal here
recreationally and I still have the two
bags of weed that I bought still have
them you still have the herb yep I still
have them in the original packaging I
may have the receipt stapled to one of
the bags or next to it they're near each
other when I got home and it settled in
like how much I [ __ ] paid for that
it's like I have to smoke this [ __ ] it's
the most expensive weed ever paid for it
I realized I bought I bought weed on
camera I was on the news buying weed
they showed me buy the weed and pay for
it on the news and then I shook the
guy's hand and then they hit cut and
then we walked outside and they
interviewed me outside and I said my
name and they put my name on the screen
I was like I just bought weed from a guy
on TV but my full name out there but I
was the first person to buy recreational
cannabis in Colorado so people get to
experience that all over the place
Tomorrow People be the first one in
there their nation and there I'm not
sure how they break it down what are
they involved in yeah I think that's the
word I'm looking for in Canada you'd be
the first person in your province and
then you're even smaller and then even
smaller you know to me to get more
opportunities to be the first person in
your whatever at least in your
dispensary when Canada's gonna have kind
of a unique go of it no one's legalized
like they're about to and so a lot of
what we're gonna go over is their first
attempt at doing this right and then the
people involved know that there are a
lot of rural changes coming over the
next year three so these are not final
yeah everything actually a lot of the
articles I read say that they're pushing
to change the rules they just needed to
get some rules in place to be on time
yeah on Wednesday the rule will be this
but in the next year too we expect it to
change to this so we keep saying
tomorrow or yesterday this episode will
either come out on Wednesday or Thursday
I have not decided when I will put this
out it depends on how the rest of my
evening and recording progress goes I
may record another show that's not
relevant but what we are talking about
is October 17th 2018 Canada will
legalize adult use cannabis yep it will
be mostly legalized some municipalities
like in the state in Colorado will be
able to ban the use and sales but for
the most part it is legal one of the
coolest parts is I'm kind of skipping
ahead let's just stick to my notes here
I'm excited about one part it keeps
getting my attention they will allow
flowers they will allow dried and cured
flowers you'll be able to use topicals
and it said oils will be available but
concentrates are not available yet and
edibles are not available yet they have
a year to figure that out
so you can get your top
you can get your flowers but no no dabs
yet
I know edibles yet but they're in the
works of that they said about a year
it's available in dispensaries there
will be dispensaries available well
depending on where you live in Canada
there's been dispensaries for a while
under neither the medical program or
there's a system of illegal dispensaries
that operate like every other
dispensaries or front but no licensure
or any of that stuff there's a comedy
club that has one of those gray area
dispensaries above it and they allow you
to smoke in the comedy club so you go up
and buy your herb and you go down at
smoke and watch a comedy show I'm gonna
have to visit yes yes so another thing
that really impresses me is the online
ordering and delivery of cannabis you
can order online and have your in some
places that'll be the only legal outlet
it's gonna be coming through the mail
217 yes completely legal to order your
herb through the mail to send your
friends stuff through the mail in Canada
that is so neat to me I like that so the
California guys could just be growing
some of that California stuff me like
Ross and Jeff you want to try some of
these flowers I grew and just sent me a
pound of it and I could try it then I
could send them out a pound or whatever
I grew and then we could try each other
stuff who means legal in Canada's come
on legal they're doing it right that's
one of the things I really like is the
the mail and online stuff that they're
doing also it's going to be affordable
you're gonna like the price of cannabis
and then we'll talk about how much it
costs here ah cannabis will be about
seven dollars a gram in Canada I in
Canadian dollars and that is five US
dollars so five dollars a gram it's not
from what I've seen and heard and read
I've got friends in Canada and I do some
work with a couple of companies in
Canada it's not the quality of what
we've got here but it's close and I'm
sure there are some places they're
getting close to what some of our places
are doing you can't say that there are
no good growers in a place that always
sounds stupid when you do that it cracks
me up how that's swung back and forth
over the last 20 years oh yeah Canada
was way better than the US it growing
up until the point mid legalization
years where the u.s. stole the show
and now Canada's working for a comeback
they may just do it yeah they just may
do it so it's affordable it's very
affordable here in Colorado right now
it's about ten bucks a gram you can find
eight diagrams you can also find
seventeen dollar grams depending on
where you're shopping and what what
quality you're looking for or how much
advertising a place is done it's not
always about the quality unfortunately
sometimes the more expensive but is not
the best quality that's not always the
case some of the shops in Denver the
places I recommend they've got closer to
$15 grams but it's worth it I think it's
the stuff you're really looking for
right
photogenic frosty looking [ __ ] so it's
affordable of the ages they did it a
little differently they have a little
more trust in Canadian citizens Canada
is allowing ages 19 and up to
participate and can in cannabis in some
places I think it's as low as 82 that's
what I've got here in Quebec you can be
18 so that's pretty cool I hear you got
to be 21 I'm pretty sure the the
brackets I saw with the Quebec there
there's at least a group in Quebec
looking to push that to 21 here in the
next year too but at the start it'll be
18 that's got to be so frustrating to
start off at one age and then see people
going oh next year I get smoked and then
they change the rules on them there's
yeah there's definitely a group of
people that aren't old enough to enjoy
it this week when it goes legal but
we'll be in a year or two if they don't
change that law yeah it will be it'll be
rough for them if they change that law
in the middle of there but and
unfortunately they're gonna be the only
ones out there voting to keep it that
way
because they're the only ones that care
so that's a small demographic how did
Canada's been explicit about why they
have the age set there they're really
targeting the black market in Canada
it's been way too prevalent prevalent
for way too long in there that's they
know that the 18 to 24 year old
demographic are the largest can they're
like a third of the marijuana consuming
population is 24 year olds and so
they're targeting that whole bracket
with legalization at least in a couple
of parts of the country that's pretty
cool that is definitely a good a good
idea I agree with that it makes a lot of
sense there that's the black-market age
that's what it that's wouldn't you buy
from your black-market friends and then
that's when people become black market
dealers is that age because they have
the black market friends it's how it
kind of how it works they go hand in
hand
all those kids need some guys got so it
works out yeah they're gonna eliminate
that that's that's pretty cool
possession limits you're allowed to
possess 30 grams that's not bad nope not
bad at all it's two and that's just like
out that's out in the world it's one
point six grams over an ounce thank you
I'm glad you caught my call back there
so you can carry an ounce of weed with
you which if you're going out for the
night or the weekend or whatever that's
plenty over right and if you're going
out for the weekend don't take a whole
ounce with you just take a couple of
eighths with you in the in one container
so that you don't look like you're
selling it take a quarter so you don't
go smoke all your weed with everybody is
you'll get it you'll have too many
drinks and you'll smoke too many bowls
you let smoke or another board or set it
down on the table for a hockey team is
draining them back to just a gram left
in your baggie yeah yeah don't take all
your wheat up you'll smoke all your
wheat that's one thing I learned let's
see you were allowed to smoke where you
were allowed to consume cigarettes which
is basically yeah there are some places
that are gonna make their own specific
rules on that of course because that's
just how some municipalities go that's
how what they like to do some places are
uptight you're not allowed to smoke in
city parks or on city beaches but they
have said they will allow you to smoke
in their national parks at their
campgrounds so it's your campground
around the fire you are allowed to light
up here in Colorado you cannot smoke in
a national park so of you if you were at
the Pueblo Reservoir whatever reservoir
you were in you cannot take your
cannabis with you and if you get caught
you were on federal land with cannabis
you could get in trouble
honestly most of the Park Rangers are
pretty cool there are people there
humans too a lot of the time they're
pretty cool like hey bro you can't have
that here but there's always that one
guy it wants to like I always talk about
that one guy that wants to [ __ ] up
people's day and be a hero so be careful
of that guy there the
the US Park Service is having an issue
with funding so they're looking for any
anything good to squeeze an extra walk
and they're happy with the stuff he's
not supposed to have is definitely a way
to do that yeah he might dreadlock
that's out there in my hiking shoes in
my backpack researched let's check this
guy yeah so you can have your stuff
there when you're camping you can't have
that stuff in Colorado in a national
park is what I'm saying does it be clear
duty the National Organization is
there's no difference between like state
and federal there's little rule policy
changes but it's not like it's illegal
on this side of the line so far the
rules say for home grows you can grow
four plants four plants per home not per
person or per whatever its per house is
what I read so far from what I
understand you can have four plants
landlords can ban you from growing
that's up to the landlord some
municipalities are going to ban that
also of course that you already have I
believe yes yes
some places that have a lot of
dispensary presence have banned that
which I see is kind of a capitalizing
monopoly sort of a thing but different
parts of Canada have had major homegrown
issues for decades I reach erred the
Union recently a my my cannabis page
because a big chunk of that is like
early 2000s black market Canada
production when you said Canada and
black market I paused because I went do
I want to go that route and start
talking about the Union so it looks like
we are well it's it's if you haven't
seen it's a beautiful documentary that
gives you a nice little snapshot of the
black market in Canada and like the
early 2000s and it's that experience
that has the country where they are now
how come the part that stands out most
to them the most from that movie to me
is when they had a power outage for
several days and the guys are showing
their grows they're like I don't know
way I haven't had power for like four
days and they're still going I hope
everything comes on already and if it's
back you better you watching these guys
is that a different documentary I was
watching these Canadian growers freak
out haven't had power for so many days
and they're talking about their grows no
important it is that it comes through
because they put all this money into it
and they're like so far in I understand
that feeling
but I was just like oh man they've had
they had like four feet of snow outside
and hadn't had power for days and I was
like that crop dude is so close to being
done they were shining flashlights on it
and [ __ ] just to keep it just needs a
little bit of light every day it'll be
all righty Oh what documentary is that
what movie is that I can't remember off
the name I have off the top of my head
but I've seen there's somebody out there
is watch and send me a tweet it's @g fyh
podcast so you know what movie my brain
is is trying to remember I've got a
traumatic brain injury so it's in there
it's just not labeled accurately anymore
the contents fell out of the folder and
now I'm just reading a file and I'm like
you know here's a part about a movie
the one thing that is gonna drive people
nuts about Canada's legalization is the
little nuance rules like I know they're
a bunch of people that are annoyed that
concentrates and edibles they're holding
off for a year
and that's largely because of the anti
cannabis groups too big talking points
that have taken holder that edibles are
scary and bad for kids and concentrates
are super potent and we've never had
anything this potent before it's up to
99 percent THC now they rant about it
all the time it's total [ __ ] nonsense
the THC pill that's been legal since the
70s is 100 percent THC I wish I could
just explain that's just salt I wish I
could explain to them that if you give
me a concentrate that is 50% THC and a
concentrate that's 100 percent THC
probably gonna take two dabs of the
hundred and four dabs of the 50 I'm
gonna get the same high I'm just gonna
consume less dabs of the other one the
only thing the anti cannabis community
understands about concentrates is that
they look scary and the numbers sounds
scary yeah in the end of it they love
talking about the blowtorch but they
always [ __ ] it up they go this stuff's
it's it's not weed it's you don't have
to light weed with a blowtorch they
right they think that we're setting the
hash on fire with the blowtorch
yeah they don't at all understand that
we're heating a surface to vaporize a
concentrate and that it's just a
complicated tool involved way of hitting
a vape pen the hippie rant in me is like
they don't want you to
stand that man that makes it acceptable
man just if they took a moment to
explain it and they're like man so what
we're doing is vaporizing now the
newscaster never does that they go then
they eat the hash with a blowtorch and
smoke it like a crack rock just because
that sells more it's more clicks it
doesn't sound like the simple
explanation doesn't get any attention
you gotta create fear there's only one
or two of them that are capable of
higher-level thinking of that nature the
rest of them it's just seriously you'll
if you follow these people for more than
a week or two you start watching them
get confused by [ __ ] that like everybody
should know like one of them tried to
hand out her own print out literature
outside of the cannabis conference they
do every year here at PCC and she
couldn't understand why there was a
process she had to go through before she
handed out literature on campus oh yeah
it's it's a lady yeah it's and she's
like well I went here like four years
ago and the person she's talking to in
the videos why the [ __ ] don't you
understand what I'm saying
yeah I'm claim to have attended here and
graduated from here but you don't know
basic rules about this spaces like first
of all you don't go here you need to
leave money to be here by lady no you
don't have a permit to put out approved
pamphlets no you can't be here no I get
it what if she's passing out some sort
of like come join our cult that campus
could be liable on that cold is this
because I didn't white supremacists used
to do it all the time see I wasn't gonna
pick a group I didn't want to give
anybody any shoutouts I said call they
[ __ ] it up for everybody now
everybody's got to submit their form two
weeks in advance and have two heads of
whatever stamp it makes sense though I
don't want you to come and stand in my
front yard and passing out your white
power pamphlets that's totally not what
I support right come out there and have
a barbecue okay wait a minute bro we
know we got really far into this before
the rants happened tim horton's buy
stock in Tim Hortons get some booty nay
I've got a lot of friends out in Canada
so big shout outs all then thanks for uh
thanks for let me make fun of you guys
if you're in Canada listening to this
enjoy this moment um one of the coolest
things in Colorado I was watching how
little things change after legalization
like you don't see people buying weed in
the park is often true the glass that
you see in head shops changes rapidly oh
yeah um some products on the market
evolve very very quickly
I remember them when there was like one
company doing hash like we've got on the
table and now their site for tea oh yeah
and it's only been months six eight
months evolves so quickly years ago we
thought clear shatter was the most
amazing [ __ ]
yep when that dude holding the ice buck
from the hood of his car was the most
famous to manage the gram yeah but like
clothing the different parts of the
community like places where that like
the comedy club where you can go and
enjoy cannabis right you will see other
little places like that pop up and
there's several anyway let me mention
that kind of technically that is not
legal at this time the ones that are up
and running now the smart ones are
already lobbying local government to hey
there's a need for this we have a
customer base that loves us there's
clearly a need for this in our community
license it regulated tell us where to be
tell us when we can be open tell us how
we can be tell us what other stuff we
can do there and we're down I can't help
but think there was just a bar that got
in trouble for ax throwing oh yeah I saw
that um where they the local people
regulators from some segments that
covers the bar industry shut up and they
had like dudes and flip-flops throwing
axes at liquor bottles I don't think it
wasn't liquor bottles but that was one
of the violations is they were throwing
them empty liquor bottles and they're
like you can't have broken glass and
flip-flops and flying [ __ ] axes at
the same time with drunks what part of
Florida was this
I don't even remember but I mean when
you've got that in the world and you're
just talking about like I want to do
like good coffee some cheesecakes and
weed with some booths and maybe some
soft music like why is that so hard to
figure out rules for the children Mike I
almost said something I probably would
have laughed at later but you got kids
now well like if we can do guns and we
can do [ __ ] prescription drugs and we
can do cars and we can do [ __ ] air
travel we can figure out how to sell
weed and be objects for each other the
dangerous list doesn't include weed like
lawn equipment Tide Pods [ __ ]
snowblowers quicksand dry drivings like
the most dangerous activity humans
engage in regularly and we don't have
any sort of awareness of that and then
you see people talking about consumption
spaces or cannabis cafes look at some of
the articles I was reading about Canada
if you don't own your own property like
you're not a homeowner you rent an
apartment depending on the part of
Canada you're in and your landlords
preference there may be no legal space
anywhere within miles and miles of you
for you to consume cannabis yeah and so
you're just like a tourist in Denver
with a hotel that says no smoking
there's no legal place for you to
consume it's like you can see through
the computer and you can see my notes
because that's my hex bullet point that
was pretty good but when you sit down
and talk about regulating these kinds of
spaces people bring up the crazy [ __ ]
and I feel like such an [ __ ] when I'm
like but everywhere in the civilized
world already has an infrastructure in
place for adults to leave their home or
place of residence go to an outside
location a secondary location where they
don't live get very intoxicated and then
return home safely yeah and we've
designed this system in every part of
them
every part of Canada all over Europe to
get people from their house to the bar
and back again in one piece and because
we're talking about cannabis people like
well how they gonna get home yep and
it's like well cuz ubers still a thing
and like you can be high and work that
app it would increase Commerce you're
gonna go to a place the for what so you
go to let's see let's create Mike and
Jeff's little [ __ ] chill and smoke
lounge in the living room that's name
that's the official name of our business
Mike and Jeff's little chill and smoke
lounge over there in the living room
like it's - so cheesecake yeah coffee
and cheesecake I want um coffee cake
with little crumbly stuff on top yeah
maybe a muffin or something we got some
stuff like that available that's what I
want in there maybe so just the top or
am I getting too detailed
can we can you just order muffin tops oh
that's a that's a [ __ ] thing dude
Rover [ __ ] the muffin bottoms those yeah
you can send those to third-world
countries or they belong those are the
beer drinkers I'm just so the tops here
let's get back on track here so I'm
trying to put myself on track I got
pretty half those so we've got a smoke
lounge people walk in we offer we can't
offer concentrates because it's Canada
that's not allowed we offer bong rips or
vapes they will save Apes because clean
air it's easier so whatever you pay a
cover to get in or whatever you pay a
membership you come in you take a vape
what's the next thing you do need a
drink bro now you're gonna drink in the
snack if we offer you a good drink and a
good snack you're gonna spend a little
bit more money which we were gonna put
back in with taxes which goes back into
the community at the end of the day
maybe like well now I got to get myself
from here over to the Tim Hortons to go
meet up with Timmy and Miss cannabis and
Full Monty and all my other Canadian
friends and I got to get in an uber
there was a place that had good food and
drinks in our area that allowed us to
consume cannabis there we don't record
at least half of these shows I was gonna
say I'd record there and we'd have more
people meet us there and it would be
like a thing people Oh people would come
and go on to the podcast other kimba's
consumers would be like hey can I have a
seat here on the show yeah bro sit on in
it did I have to be so great but when
you talk about this stuff especially
here in the States
you have to overcome several [ __ ]
hurdles that are just insurmountable it
seems like and one of them is half the
population pretends like we don't have a
way to you know go out get drunk and get
home in one piece right they just you
you run into all this nonsense about how
everybody just enjoys the flavor of
alcoholic beverages it's like well we'll
just have one glass with dinner like
that's the social consumption norm and
it's like well then why the [ __ ] do they
have it at little league soccer games
there's literally booze everywhere we
can't just have like three or four
places around the city to go and I'm
maybe Bowl maybe watch a movie or see
throwback you would be way more likely
to get me to go bowling if I could go
bowling for bong hits if I could go roll
a strike and every time I got a strike I
wanted AB I would shoot to 60s I would
be a I would be a sharpshooter bro you
wouldn't want to [ __ ] with me at the
bowling alley I've got balls if they
just set it aside at night and they were
like Wednesday nights is it's cannabis
consumption that you have to be over the
legal age in this area to come in you
get an ID heart at the door bring your
owner
knock yourself out like I'd go at least
twice a month hell yeah bro yeah what
else could we do what would either be
the movie theater if I could just take a
dab in the middle there's always that
point about 45 to an hour and a movie
you probably started going I could use a
cigarette that's when my brain goes hey
you're gonna take it bad or what dude
like if I could just walk up to the
little it's got to be silent you don't
hear the torch in there like in 22 dudes
watching dazed and confused with the
torch going now but if I can walk up to
a little email station and stick it well
then go back to my seat bride be more
likely to go watch a movie if Walmart
had a dad station no let's not say
Walmart people don't want us to shop at
Walmart if my local family owned and
operated organically locally sourced
gluten-free vegan I say the butcher yeah
right I'm just trying to be silly and
socially conscious at the same time but
there's a dozen different businesses
that would increase their customer flow
if the skating rinks allowed it
there was a restaurant up in Denver that
wanted to do they were gonna do the
second-story they had a second-story
seating area that was just overflow and
they were just gonna permanently mark it
off as the cannabis section and people
freaked the [ __ ] out we had a friend
throw a birthday party at probably that
restaurant because they had an upstairs
section that was an overflow and when I
walked in they were open for a while
before I said there were rigs and it was
all of our stuff we brought everybody
brought a rig and a torch and there were
rigs so fancy dinner plates and wine
glasses and wine bottles and bread and
dads and we were between each course you
know we'd be like hey have you tried
this concentrate and we take a couple
dabs with each other we dabbed out the
waitstaff weed out the cook they all
came back and like you guys partying up
here like yeah it's her birthday and I
like cool take dabs we and it was a
great time they had a good time with us
we got them stoned and when I'm stoned
and I cook my food just tastes I don't
know if it's because I'm still it's cuz
I was stoned and I cooked it and I just
did something magical it's like uh I can
make a hell of a grilled cheese sandwich
and I can watch my mom make a week and
my mom and I could get the same exact
pan the same bread same butter same
cheese same everything and her grilled
cheese sandwiches just gonna taste a
little bit [ __ ] better than mine I
don't know what she does it just comes
out of its coz my mama made it and just
that little sprinkle it's like that's
what it's like when I get stoned and
make my food it's like puttin mama magic
in it's that little extra touch so you
get stoned with the waitstaff and then
go down there and they make a nice
stoned ass meal and then you're gettin
stoned and eatin - there's nothing wrong
with it there's no problem and then
you're eating so you're not lit when you
leave you hang out yeah and what about
the other people that are drinking wine
downstairs what's the difference I we
used to go to in college there was a
place where I can't remember the price
but it was a lot it was like for 60 or
70 bucks you'd sit down and get like
nine different tumblers of whiskey look
I never ordered that nine but they were
it was all little sample sizes but still
and they had like a little map but it
was like this was from here and this is
from here and this is from here and like
the thing I like there was their burger
but a number of my friends were really
into that [ __ ] the expensive booze
thing and if they can have that like are
we really asking that much and honest I
think Canada's
either way before we do Canada's got it
right Canada has got they've got some
ugly hurdles they're gonna have to go
over the next few years for sure yeah
but they're on the way on the
business-business path they're doing it
right on the consumption path I think
they're gonna do it right they're gonna
have import and export with other
countries only for two very specific
it's not recreational import/export it's
for medical research and for something
else okay but they're starting with
import/export everybody else is on
lockdown the the one or two rules that I
see that they're really gonna end up
fighting over our consumption spaces and
Dave's limit I think that the edibles in
concentrates they're just gonna end up
hammering out packaging rules like we
did here oh yeah that'll take two years
they say one year but they'll get on it
in about six months and they'll make it
happen in a year and a half after that
and they're their biggest hurdle is
probably gonna be the existing market
they've got a multi-tiered black market
gray market white market system in place
already and a lot of that's locked out
of the legal industry that looking to
create now my favorite thing I learned
from this episode was the idea of
allowing 19 and 18 year old citizens to
purchase and possess cannabis to further
eradicate the black market I think
that's a really good strategy when you
explain to me why what kind of dawned on
me is you started saying was like oh man
because that's when I was buying and
selling the most black market cannabis
was between the ages of probably I
shouldn't admit like 17 to 24 ish was
when I was really banging out the black
market product so yeah that's you could
probably change people's lives you keep
people out of trouble
keep people from taking that path and
also falling into trouble because their
friend took that path and they bought it
from them the the the real destruction
that kind of flows out from the black
market is the market part it's the
amount of employees threats secrets
shenanigans it takes to produce and
distribute billions and billions of
dollars of the cannabis it's just
[ __ ] nuts
and if you look at the size of the
marketplace it's huge and then you start
doing the math and you're like alright
so like a big GRU home grows like 2
million a year divided by 35 billion how
many house is that ok it gets crazy fast
and then you figure about you know how
many little dealers and [ __ ] all of that
market is is gonna start changing and we
watched it here in Colorado where you
had 10 friends that all solder and kind
of worked in the community where when
somebody was low they would buy from the
others and when somebody grew a strain
that was really good that other
consumers like they trade and one by one
all of those people started dropping out
of the game yep in converting into full
legal or leaving to someplace where the
black market was still thriving but we
completely eradicated the distribution
end of black market in Colorado yeah
they all got jobs it grows our
dispensaries or as trimmers or whatever
else you see people talk about oh all
they have to do is on you know just
don't charge the taxes and it's there's
still no [ __ ] profit in it right like
you can't make a living with three
lights in a basement in $5 grams and
it's not worth it anymore
there's so much competition there's yeah
there's literally no profit in it you're
barely making what it took to produce
back on it and if you're only doing that
at an at-home scale there's literally no
[ __ ] money in it you've got to do
100% of the work yourself there's no
wiggle room and your profit margins for
helpers or waterers or tremor Arizer
it's miserable that's the one by one
they all drop out
shrim all that [ __ ] yourself again yep I
don't miss those days
oh and for a dollar profit a gram when
it was twenty a gram all day long to
everybody it was worth it oh yeah but
that's all your profit that's gone now
pounds went from four thousand to thirty
five to thirty two they stayed at
thirty-two for a couple of years they
started getting like 27 and then they
were twenty-five for quite a while and
then the next summer
fifteen hundred you
oh [ __ ] my weeds not worth anything $100
an ounce if I'm lucky and now in
Colorado you can get a pound of weed for
1,200 maybe 900 dollars if you want at
low shelf not beautiful stuff but it's
available and a lot of heavy time of the
year in which market you're pushing in
give it a month from here you're gonna
see thousand-dollar pounds all over the
place a month we had two nasty cold
freezes at the start October but people
are gonna be early harvesting which
means their crop didn't finish right
when you add that into places that have
acreage in the legal market when that
hits the rack market the whole industry
just holds their breath for four months
until that [ __ ] supply is gone you
know you see a lot of hatch you see a
lot of different kinds of concentrates
but Canada's about to get all of this
you guys are lucky that's fun right yeah
it's so much fun to watch begin this
episode out as soon as I can so that the
candidate can enjoy this on their day of
legalization congratulations Canada hey
Mike we've been going for close to 45
minutes I know you've got somewhere to
be so I'm gonna cue you with your Mike's
moments if you've got any immigrants
let's get him a TV now so we can start
wrapping up the [ __ ] mohnish somebody
for trying to do a final stop because
only Terry gets to do that [ __ ]
if you're in Canada and don't dig the
rules that are rolling out in your area
by all means work to change them it's
real easy to get involved there are
several organizations already fighting
this fight in Canada all you have to do
is lend your support there are several
ways to do that really easy contact me
if you're looking for specifics and
enjoy it it's this is something that
thousands and thousands of people have
been fighting for their whole lives to
achieve in Canada's go and we go coast
to coast and not everyone up there
should get to enjoy this and all the
anti-pop people hahaha the harder you
fight the easier this fight gets I like
that
good good wrap up with Mike there hey
dude thanks for coming and hanging out
spending some of the late afternoon with
me oh yeah we're gonna get you out of
here so that you can get home on time
and not get yourself in trouble in five
minutes
at the time right ladies and gentlemen
from daycare get the kid from Dow I
didn't even realize you have to get the
kid from daycare I'm glad I was paying
close attention why me - wow that almost
got awkward
you almost / cry shirt that [ __ ] if you
listen to Bert you know what I mean all
right guys thanks for listening
Canada congratulations welcome to the
club enjoy it I hope you hope you like
it it's fun for you I hope it goes well
for you I'm sure it well we we got good
and baked in this guy Ram loo so thank
you all for listening a lot of people
really enjoy hanging out with this when
we get good and bake because they say
that they don't have stoner friends it
can just hang out and take a bunch of
dabs and ramble and hang out so they got
to kind of come hang out at the table
with us I've been doing a long series of
intensive girl lessons so a bit amazing
this is thank you bro this has been kind
of like those lessons aren't stressful
but they are not like I don't get to
just hang out take dabs during those I'm
like trying to stay focused and there's
some editing and so those are different
so this was kind of chill more like like
the substitute teacher was here like a
rainy day at school I got to kind of
goof off a little bit which was nice so
thank you for that bro yeah
listeners I've been extra busy in sick
lately and so I have not been on in
weeks and weeks and weeks and I will try
to get over here more and more often you
can just take that microphone with you
we're we're close to working on a
solution where I can join the podcast
from my little cubicle if in my world
but until then I have to actually get
over to the studio I know how to make it
happen yeah we just having more and more
often hopefully here in the near future
one small purchase we can probably get
mic lined up like that dude thanks for
coming thanks for hanging out thanks for
everybody yeah everybody thank you for
listening thanks for hanging out this is
how I wrap up the show all the time if
you feel like this podcast was
educational informative and or
entertaining and you'd like to
contribute to the show financially you
can do so by going to patreon.com slash
grow from your heart all the information
you need to sign up would be right there
I would appreciate your support with
that I do use those funds to cover these
microphone covers that Mike's been
spinning into for the whole episode now
I've got to replace it because he's a
little sick but you got a fresh one
we're gonna throw it right away
I also about a macbook that's what the
funding goes for not trying to get rich
off podcasting just asking for a little
support so that i can keep the podcast
free for you i do it for free
cuz I love cannabis and I love you and I
want you to grow the best cannabis you
can possibly grow for yourself and your
loved ones ladies and gentlemen thanks
for the support I would appreciate it if
you follow me on social media you can
find me on Facebook simply search for
the girl from your heart podcast on
Twitter it's @gf wih podcast and on
instagram i use my other company name
it's Irie underscore genetics check out
I understand Instagram check out my fine
cannabis photography you can also check
out my live feeds where I do
cannabis q and A's and I hang out take
dad's with my friends we tell jokes we
laugh I'll answer your girl questions
it's a good time I encourage you to
follow me on that platform on Instagram
it's Irie underscore genetics if you'd
like to reach out if you've got
something you'd like to say if you've
got a product you'd like me to review or
if you'd like to sponsor the show or if
you just like to say something and
you're not into all the social media
stuff you can send me an email it's grow
from your heart at hotmail.com
I would love to hear from you what else
do we have YouTube I think I've got 420
YouTube subscribers so thank you for
that you guys I appreciate that thanks
for all of the YouTube support I would
appreciate it even if you're not gonna
watch the videos just go click subscribe
on the YouTube channel simply search for
the girl from your heart a podcast give
me a follow get my videos a little boost
I would appreciate that ladies and
gentlemen thank you for listening shout
out to my friends in Canada thanks for
letting me make funny I do have a lot of
love and respect for you Canada guys and
gals even though I do make fun of your
poutine and Tim Hortons and all that
good stuff and I tell you to go drink
some maple syrup eh I love you guys so
much each and every one of you I'm not
gonna try to list you guys cuz I'll
forget somebody and then I'll feel bad
but you guys wanna who you are all my
Canadian friends Oh Mike you got
anything else to say I gave you your
final moments you're done I'm turning
off your mic my thoughts are completed
your thoughts are complete holy [ __ ] I'm
still getting back yeah we're gonna
we're gonna get even good and baked her
or at least I am you've got to go
somewhere so yeah Mike's gonna watch me
get good baked here in just a moment you
guys I'll be back when this one comes
out when does this one come out okay
yeah I may be back with another episode
this week
I guarantee you I'll be back Monday with
a fresh new episode I want to give you
huge shoutouts my friend James butter
sent and until next time take a phat dad
and give your mom a hug for me