hey what's up podcast world it's time
for episode 362 of the girl from your
heart podcast this episode is brought to
you by the hella dank seed company if
you need new seeds for your garden I
highly recommend the hella dank seed
company and you can find them at dank
seed dot store I like to start these
shows off by letting you know what I'm
smoking today I've been taking dad's of
orange skittles ambrosia from apothecary
farms I really like this as my morning
smoke I'm recording earlier in the
morning than I usually do and this
orange skittles has that orange juice
orange candy sort of a taste it's also
got my head going pretty quickly so it's
a great way to start the day I'm smoking
the orange skittles Fambrough Jie from
apothecary farms the only difference
between the ambrosia and the Fambrough
Jie is the ambrosia is a 1 gram jar when
they put it in the 4 gram jar that's
when they call it the fam brochure
that's for the fam so the orange
skittles Fambrough Jie the potency says
seventy three point seven percent THC
zero CBD total cannabinoids 84.6% it's a
great way to start the day it's got an
uplifting head high it's got that
amazing orange candy flavor to it and
it's got me nice and talkative and
energized so this should be a good
podcast this is going to be another grow
lesson in the last lesson I talked about
clones versus seeds now in this episode
we're gonna talk about regular seeds
feminized seeds and auto flower seeds
before we get into the seed talk I want
to give a few shoutouts to a couple of
our patreon supporters I want to give a
huge shout out to Angel Burtis how about
a big shout out to Myles Porter a super
shout out to Jade and an extra Viking
shout out to Grimble the druid thank you
ladies and gentlemen for all the support
on patreon if you're not already a
patron and you would like to learn how
to become a patron you can do so by
going to patreon.com slash grow from
your heart that's p80 re0 n.com
slash grow from your heart you can learn
how to sign up you can become a patron
and I will give you a shout out on the
next episode
all right podcast world this episode is
going to be about regular seed feminized
seed and Otto flower seed and deciding
what will be best for you and your new
garden a lot of people out there will
have an opinion about feminized seeds
a lot of people out there will have an
opinion about Auto flower seeds
don't let anybody stop you from growing
what makes you happy there's a reason
why regular seeds exist there's a reason
why feminized seeds exist there is a
reason why auto flower seeds exists
there are applications for all of those
types of seeds do what you love and
don't let anybody out there stop you
from growing from your heart when we are
shopping for seeds we are thrown a lot
of information some of it is very useful
some of it is just fluff for advertising
somewhere in that information we should
be able to tell if the seeds we are
shopping for are regular feminized or
autoflowering that should be clearly
noted somewhere in the description if I
don't see any sort of notation I
generally assume they are regular seeds
and that's a really good place to start
what do I mean by regular seed by
regular seed I mean they were produced
conventionally they were made with a
male plant and a female plant so in that
package of seeds you will find males and
females they are also not auto flour
which means they are photoperiod
now let's talk briefly about photo
period photo period means that a plant
is triggered into its flowering stage by
a light cycle in nature this light cycle
is mostly dictated by your location in
relation to the equator are you right on
the equator are you far north or are you
far south of the Equator
now as the seasons change as fall rolls
around regions on the equator will start
experiencing longer nights and shorter
days those longer nights and shorter
days tell our plant hey winter is coming
you need to start producing your flowers
so that you can reproduce before the end
of the season and that triggers the
plant to go into flowering that is its
photo period indoors most cannabis
plants require about a 12 hour dark
period to induce flower outdoors can be
different because the Sun puts off
different spectrums they trigger the
plants to go to sleep as the Sun sets it
puts off a red spectrum that tells that
plant hey it's a nighttime and then it
starts going to sleep as the Sun rises
it puts off a blue spectrum that tells
the plant it's time to wake up so you
don't need the 1212 outdoors you can
work closer to a 14
or day and more of a 10-hour night
outdoors because the Sun tells the
plants to go to sleep but that is photo
period the plants work off the light
cycle and the light cycle works with
nature outdoors indoors we're
controlling that with a timer so that is
basically photo period if your seeds are
marked regular seeds or if it says photo
on the package that indicates that those
plants will be triggered to flower by
reducing your light schedule to 12 hours
on and 12 hours off now regular seeds
also indicates that there will be males
and females in that package of seeds if
you're trying to grow a seedless crop
you will have to pay attention and keep
the males out of the flowering room
somewhere between 7 and 10 days those
plants will start showing their sex
you'll have to go through and pull out
all of the males if you leave one male
plant in there for too long it will
pollinate and all of the plants around
it will be seated and depending on how
long you let that male go and how much
pollen he released and how much wind
flow and how much movement you have in
that grow you may see the entire crop
with just one male so that is basically
regular seed they are regular seed they
were bred conventionally traditionally
with a male and a female plant they are
photosensitive which means they will
trigger into flower by reducing the
lights to approximately 12 hours on at
12 hours off some plants will work one
hour either direction you could go 13
hours on you can go 13 hours off you
could play with that but we recommend
1212 as the critical period also you
will find males and females in your
regular seeds if you're not looking to
do any breeding if you want to grow
seedless cannabis you do need to call
those males so that's the only major
downfall of regular seeds when you buy a
package of regular seeds you've got
about a 50/50 chance of getting males
and females it's hard to dictate what
you get with regular seeds now a lot of
people don't want to waste the energy
the time the space or the money buying
and growing seeds that could possibly be
males and need to be removed from the
garden now that is where feminized seeds
come into play a lot of people have
hatred toward feminized seeds because
they are misinformed a lot of people
have hatred or a bias against feminized
seeds because there were a few breeders
back in the day they put out a batch of
feminine
Zuber total [ __ ] and a few people bought
those and it put a bad taste in their
mouth and those people spread that taste
throughout the internet and i understand
when you get a terrible product you want
to tell people people believe you I get
that but that was way back in the day we
have come a long way since then we
understand how to produce feminized
seeds on a commercial scale and there
are a lot of breeders and producers out
there putting out reliable quality
feminized seeds when they are made
properly feminized seeds will produce
plants they give you 99.9 percent
females this is nature and science
together so there will be anomalies you
will find things that don't fall into
the chart that we drew because that's
how nature works that's why we say 99.9
percent if I do my job correctly when I
produce feminized seeds you will get
99.9 percent female plants I'll give you
a brief explanation on how I make
feminized seeds and how a lot of the
leading feminized seed producers make
their products I create a solution of
silver thiosulfate
that is really easy to learn how to do
all the instructions for that are
readily available on the internet you
can make a silver thiosulfate solution
from products that are easily attainable
on the internet for less than $30 get
these products I use product number one
and product number two I mix them into
water then I mix the two things of water
together now I've got my silver
thiosulfate concentration i dilute that
each plant that I'm using requires a
different dilution and application rate
there is a standard that I start with
the basic dilution that I recommend to
start with would be a one to nine ratio
of silver thiosulfate to water so you've
got nine parts water one part of the
silver thiosulfate concentrate mixed
into there shake that up real well and
apply that to the plant on the first day
of flower and then apply it every three
days for 21 days so you're going to give
the plant seven full applications and
spray it until it drips and get the
stalks don't just get the leaves get in
there and spray the stalks and be
careful when you're using the silver
thiosulfate spray because it may turn
some things purple if you've got a white
wall depending
which are up against whatever that hits
it could turn it purple including your
skin so be careful wear gloves wear a
mask when working with the silver
thiosulfate solution that is always my
recommendation so I take the silver
thiosulfate solution that I have created
then I apply it I mix it at a dilution
of nine to one nine parts distilled
water one part silver thiosulfate
concentrate then I apply it to the
plants every three days for 21 days it
gets 21 applications then usually around
day 25 to 30 it starts putting out
pollen that's when I start collecting
the pall and I put something usually a
piece of glass just depends on where I
am and what I'm working with and put a
piece of glass near the plant collect
some pollen as it naturally falls out
pick the male flowers out of there
gather that let it dry then when it
really starts getting dumping that's
when I'll move it right over by the
girls and give it a good shake and now
we have just made feminized seeds I've
still got six or seven weeks of
nourishing those seeds but if I have
done everything carefully and done
everything correctly I have created
feminized seeds and there should be no
reason why those should be problematic
unless I completely screw up the next
six or seven weeks which is very
unlikely because all I've got to do is
make sure the equipment functions make
sure everything stays on a 12-2 up cycle
I've got to feed it properly I know how
to feed plants that are pregnant I know
how to produce quality seeds I've got to
defoliate properly and I've also got to
make sure to keep everything pest and
problem free and I'm quite experienced
at all of that so far so there should be
no problem I also make sure to
thoroughly test run every batch of seeds
I make before they make it to market I
grow some out myself
I give up punch out to my friends I'm
sure you guys see on Instagram people
have the new stuff you're like how do
they get that it's because they grew
something of mine I was impressed by it
I reached out to them and I said hey you
want to run my next batch I need you to
take good notes take good photos send it
all back to me and then I'll know if I
want to release that line or not so I
have other people grow it I grow it
myself we test it before it's put out to
market that way I know that you're
receiving a quality product I'm gonna go
off way on a side right here that's not
even written down when I make a new
strain so let's just say I just pulled
some seeds out of a plant last night
that's a brand new cross nobody's ever
seen it I've never seen it I don't know
what it's gonna do before those seeds go
anywhere I'm going to throw a handful of
them in a paper towel and germinate them
and then in 24 hours I'm gonna pop it
open and I'm gonna see how many have
sprouted tails and I'm gonna make a note
and I'm gonna write down the ratio
however out of a hundred they sprouted
tails or they did not sprout tails then
I'll close it back up and I'll let the
other ones keep going and I'll see in 36
hours how many made tails and I'll take
good notes then I'll put some of those
the ones that did sprout tails and look
good I'm gonna put those into some cups
of dirt and I'm gonna grow them and I'm
gonna pay attention to them and I'm
gonna keep a lot of notes I'm gonna veg
them I'm gonna flour them I'm gonna grow
them I'm gonna dry them cure them smoke
them make concentrates out of them smoke
the concentrates we're at least 120 days
from even knowing what that product
tastes like probably closer to 150 with
the dry and cure phase in there then
that is my first grow with it if I
approve then I'll pass some seeds onto
gram if Grimble grows it and it looks
good in his garden I'll spread it out to
a few more people if they grow it well
that's when I'll let it go to a vendor
or for retail but I test the [ __ ] out of
my feminized seeds and my regular seat
so I stand behind my product and
honestly every feminized seed that I
produce sells
I can't keep feminized seeds in stock
and I don't get any complaints on my
feminized seed products so that's how
things are made that's how I make my fam
Gemini's seeds is there are no males to
remove from the garden you know that
every seed you plant will result in a
harvested crop you won't have to grow it
long enough to sex it you won't be
wasting any time that's advantageous for
people who live in medical states or
anybody who is limited by a plant count
so your feminized seeds are all going to
be females now you would say why would
people grow photoperiod seeds when they
can grow feminized seeds and guarantee
that everything they grow makes it to
harvest like I said a lot of people have
a bias against feminized seeds also a
lot of people like myself like finding
the males breeding with females and
reversed females and alpha females is a
great practice but I like working with a
solid male plant I've got a passion for
conventional breeding I do make
feminized seeds but I have more fun with
conventional breeding another thing you
may notice when you're shopping for
seeds is that feminized seeds are about
twice the price of regular seeds so you
you do get viable females that you can
take to harvest but that pack of seeds
cost exactly twice is what a regular
pack of seeds cost although you didn't
have to waste the time the space the
soil the energy and you didn't have to
have that extra plant count to add to
your numbers in your legal garden so if
the packaging says feminized seeds that
means that 99.9 percent of the plants
that come out of that seed package will
be females now here's something that is
kind of a side rant that I was talking
to somebody on social media about that I
want to include in a podcast I'm just
gonna give it a couple of seconds we
talked about the flip when we flipped a
flower feminized and regular photo
period seeds we flipped them to flower
by changing the light cycle either from
24 on and 0 off to 18 on and 6 off or
however you've got your light cycle set
up then you switch to 12 on and 12 off
you are now in flower or if you're gonna
follow the DJ short plan you go a
Lebanon 13 off that's a whole other
podcast
anyway we flipped a flower that is day 1
of flower your seed package will give
you an estimate of how long they need
the flower 9 to 10 weeks 60 to 70 days
whatever it says the day you initiated
that flip is day one not the day you see
buds set not the day you smell something
not the day the butterflies flew in and
did their magic dance the day you change
that timer is day one of flower that's
how you keep track of that that's what
we're talking about when we indicated
that on the seed package just wanted to
add that side note I'm not sure if that
was even relevant but there you go a
little bonus nugget for your brain all
right now let's work into autoflowering
seeds let's talk about Auto flowers what
do I mean by an auto flowering seed
earlier I was talking about your
location in relation to the equator most
of us live in an area where we see
seasonal changes and we also see changes
in day and night time but keep in mind
there are parts of Russia and Alaska
that will receive extreme stretches of
daylight and night time without
interruption there are some points in
Alaska when they will have full sunlight
for 80 days in a row they will not get a
night for 80 solid days cannabis is an
extraordinary plant and it has evolved
the
we're familiar with which is evolved
from these extreme conditions with no
dark is known as ruderalis these
ruderalis plants have evolved to flower
without any dark period after so many
generations they went hey it doesn't get
dark we need to do something about this
so through evolution they started to
flower without a dark period a lot of
those ruderalis plants have no desirable
effect when smoked but they have a lot
of desirable traits when grown some of
them stay short they stay squat they
push out really nicely and you don't
have to change the light cycle to
convince them to flower for you so
cannabis breeders got a hold of
ruderalis plants and they bred them
together they bred our autoflowering
ruderalis to our high potency cannabis
plants and the offspring resulted in
high potency autoflowering cannabis
plants most of the autoflowering seeds
available for most breeders now are
feminized so you'll get autoflowering
seeds that are all girls which is really
advantageous and we'll talk about that
in just a minute I should warn you that
when you're looking at seeds and you see
feminized seeds on there also look to
see if they say photo period or Auto
flower on there make sure they indicate
that if they don't they're probably
photo period all of the auto flower guys
like to let you know that you're working
with Auto flowers they clearly indicate
that on the package and earlier I
mentioned that feminized seeds cost
twice as much as regular Auto flowers
generally cost twice as much as
feminized so you got your regular than
their doubled then their even doubled
again so they will let you know if
they're Auto flowers just make sure you
read the package when you're buying your
seat that'll either say regular or
feminized or Auto flower just do a
little research before you buy your
seeds make sure you know what you're
getting now let's talk a little bit
about how these auto flower seeds are
useful if you've been listening to the
show for a while you'll love my favorite
example of these Auto flowers and use
several years ago there was a very large
grow discovered in a National Forest not
too far from here and it was discovered
that that grow was ran by a cartel as
the reports and pictures came out they
were saying that the cartel had three
different stages of growth happen
in their illegal grow area now that
really made me wonder how are they
growing different stages outdoors
because the Sun dictates what our plants
do if they put them outside they all
went into flower at the same time then
my brain went dude they're using Auto
flowers so this large cartel would set a
patch of auto flower plants then they
would wait a few weeks and they would
set another large patch of auto flower
plants wait a few weeks and set another
large patch of auto flower plants for
eventually they had a perpetual cycle
going to where they had people out there
in this national forest
camouflaged hidden growing a perpetual
grow packaging up and sending it to who
knows where I have no idea where it was
going but they were producing quite a
bit of cannabis out there by using Auto
flowers they had a perpetual grow under
the natural Sun they didn't have to veg
and then flower they could just throw
the seeds out there they would grow and
do their thing so that's one way where
Auto flower seeds were highly effective
now let's scale that down a little bit
let's say you've only got one grow space
and you want to produce a perpetual grow
you don't have a bedroom you don't have
a flower room you can't go buy clones
from a friend you can't have a friend
veg for you the way you could run a
small self sustainable perpetual grow is
with Auto flower plants in one room fill
up a quarter or half of the room with
Auto flowers as soon as they start
flowering plant more Auto flowers and
put them in the same room you'll have
veg plants and flowering plants in the
same room you can't do that with photo
period plants so if you're limited on
space if you've only got one room that's
a really useful method and a really
useful application for auto flowering
plants the major downside that I see to
auto flowering plants is you always have
to buy new seeds
you cannot clone an auto flowering plant
if you're growing with regular or
feminized photoperiod seeds you're
always able to cut a clone you can keep
that clone as a mother you can keep it
perpetually and then you can always
clone off of that mother and you can
keep that plant sustainable with Auto
flowers you're always going to be buying
new seeds and earlier I mentioned most
of the auto flower companies are only
putting out feminized so you're not even
able to breed your own Auto flowers with
males and females anymore you're gonna
have to reverse one and I have no
experience doing that all right you guys
that is my breakdown on regular
seeds feminized seeds and autoflowering
seeds the regular seeds are always photo
period I like them because we find males
and females
I like breeding with the regular seeds
that's a lot of fun for me
the feminized seeds can be photo period
or they can be Auto flower they are
probably well marked on the packaging
those are always going to be females if
they were bred properly I've done a
whole nother podcast episode about
marking feminized seeds with s or r1
generations I encourage you to listen to
that one that one is episode 331 and
it's titled selfing and reversals you'll
learn a lot about why we label the
packages the way we do also I recommend
you listen to an episode called seed
pack expectations and that is number 245
there's a lot of useful information in
that episode for anyone who is
considering purchasing new seeds then
we'll keep it moving we talked about
autoflowering seeds auto flowering
plants are unique to photoperiod plants
because they flower based on their size
or their age we can put them under the
veg lights we can have them in the 1860
and they will still flower and they will
still produce buds a lot of auto
flowering plants boast that they will be
completely done around ten weeks so
that's 70 days of a full cycle with a
photo period plant you've got closer to
a hundred and twenty days if you want
usable product so that is my lesson on
regular feminized and autoflowering
seeds I hope I made your decision easier
when it comes time to go shopping don't
be afraid to try regular seeds don't be
afraid to try feminized seeds and don't
be afraid to try Auto flower seeds you
just may fall in love with something you
never thought you would even like and
don't forget you can find your seeds at
dank seed dot store we're working on a
Black Friday sale you guys this should
get interesting you guys I've only been
gone for about 22 minutes but honestly
my recording gear has been giving me a
couple of technical issues and my throat
is obviously burning out so I'm gonna
wrap this up while I've still got a
quality podcast on the screen I don't
want to lose any of the stuff I recorded
so please do support me on patreon it
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
stalk me on all the social media on
Facebook it's the girl from your heart
podcast on Twitter it's at G fyh podcast
on Twitter I use the other company it's
Irie underscore genetics also you can
email me and grow from your heart at
hotmail.com don't forget about the you
Tube channels simply search for the girl
from your heart podcast on YouTube click
subscribe watch the videos leave some
comments I would appreciate your support
there you guys know I'll be back in just
a few days with a fresh new episode I'll
get all the equipment fixed up so I quit
getting glitches in the recording gear
and I don't have to wrap up the end so
quickly I want to give you a huge shout
out to my friend Roger and until next
time take a phat dab and give your mom a
hug for me