welcome to the show cannabis community
it's time for episode 363 of the Grove
from your heart podcast this episode is
brought to you by the hella dank seed
company if you need new regular or
feminized seeds for your garden I highly
recommend the hella dank seed company
and you can find them at dank seed dot
store I like to start the episodes off
by letting you know what I'm smoking I
just finished the last dab of the orange
skittles ambrosia that left a nice
orange flavor in my mouth gave me a nice
head buzz I followed that up with the
last dab of the bubble Jack
full-spectrum extract from Fuego
extracts that was delicious
the combo made me super rambley and gave
me a lot of energy so this will be a fun
podcast if you've been following along
you know I'm doing a long series of grow
lessons if you haven't been following
along I suggest you go back to episode
351 and start there and get caught up
that will give you a solid foundation on
planning your grow and getting prepared
for your new grow if you've been
following along you know that we've
selected our space we've selected our
equipment we've done a lot of talk about
genetics and now this episode is going
to be about sprouting our new seeds
let's not waste too much time let's jump
right into it
seeds can be expensive depending on who
you ordered them from
how many you bought what kind you
purchased you may have spent a lot of
money on seeds before you think about
germinating your new seeds I highly
recommend you have your veg area ready
to rock before you even think about
starting your seeds
you're gonna think oh I can just dremen
ate these seeds and then I'll build up
this veg room in the next couple of days
and then while they veg we'll work on
the flower room once you get plants
going you start time-traveling things go
so much more quickly than you anticipate
things pop up things get in your way
then you fall behind then those seeds
you just paid a bunch of money for start
growing funky they get out of control
and you've got shitty plants to start
with and you're frustrated from the
beginning
so before you germinate your seeds have
your veg space prepared that is my very
first piece of advice to you that will
save you a lot of frustration now my
second piece of advice is to start with
quality seed try to get your seeds from
a reputable vendor and all
from a reputable breeder don't fall for
hype when you're shopping for seeds
don't be sold try to find somebody with
a good reputation somebody that you have
heard of and also try to buy those seeds
from a vendor with the good reputation
somebody that you have heard of somebody
that has a good relationship with the
breeders and if you're going to buy
seeds online I recommend you buy from a
seed vendor in the United States that
way you don't have to risk customs of
course I recommend the hella Danks seed
company
I also recommend the seed Bazaar and I
can also vouch for Southern Oregon seeds
those are three quality seed vendors
that I trust and respect and I work with
them personally so I know they will take
good care of you I'm not bashing any
other seed company I'm just saying I
rely on these three companies I have
worked with them I've got a relationship
with them and I know they are rock-solid
so I recommend you start with a quality
seed something you know what the parents
of that seed were something you know
where it came from if you don't have
access to fancy labeled expensive seeds
grow what you've got in an ideal world
we would all go to the store and we look
at the shelf and we'd say you've got
that strain that was the best I've ever
smoked I want seeds of that and I get
that that's everybody's fantasy that day
is coming unfortunately we are not there
yet for everybody some people are going
to have to be resourceful you may have
bought a bag of weed ten years ago at
some random place and it had seeds in it
now you're gonna have to grow those
seeds you never know what you're gonna
get out of those seeds you could find
duds you could find hermaphrodites you
may find the next magical strain in
there so grow what you've got no matter
where your seeds come from whether
they're regular whether they're
feminized seeds pay close attention to
them pay attention for males pay
attention for hermaphrodite um pay
attention for problems you will have to
keep an eye out when you're growing from
seed now if you've got a bag of seeds
lying around and you don't know what any
of them are it's just a perhaps a
sandwich bag or a little mason jar just
stuffed with random seeds from bags of
cannabis you've gone through over time
and you can't decide what to grow I go
for the really healthy-looking seeds and
by healthy I mean probably darker
probably bigger a lot of people like the
tiger stripes that's always a good sign
some seeds will not make tiger stripes
no matter how long they grow no matter
how mature no matter how healthy and
strong they are
they just won't stripe up that's just a
genetic thing
I prefer the darker colored seeds the
harder seeds I give him a little press
on the table I hope they don't crack if
they don't crack that's probably a good
seed if it cracks it obviously isn't
gonna grow that's a dead seed a lot of
people like a larger cannabis seat but
I've noticed that a lot of strains
produce little tiny seeds so sometimes a
little tiny cannabis seed can produce a
seriously potent plant don't judge it
too much by the size judge it more by
the health of the seed a lot of the
grayer light colored seeds will grow I
don't put those in my packs because
people freak out I grow those myself but
those lighter gray the paler colored
seeds those will grow the white seeds
those are more questionable I don't
think the white seeds do as well the
gray kind of silver shiny seeds those
usually have a good take off the darker
ones those take off quite quickly
and then of course you get those bigger
harder tiger-stripe seeds those really
have a lot of vigor and they take off
really quickly for you so seed health is
important selecting healthy seeds if
you've got a big bag of seeds try to
select the healthiest looking beans out
of that bag maybe a couple of them just
call you maybe you've got a bag of a
thousand seeds and two of them risk oh
hey bro I'm the seeds you want to grow
right now listen to that kind of stuff
that is usually accurate all right now
we've got our veg space ready we know
what to look for in quality seeds we've
got some seeds on hand and it is time to
germinate our seeds what do I mean by
germinate that's just a fancy word for
starting the seeds we need to give them
the proper conditions to make them start
we want to crack the seed open we don't
want to do it we want it to happen
naturally we want the seed to crack
itself open and we want a little tiny
tap root to come fish it out and that is
the start of life in nature those seeds
would fall out of last year's but winter
would come it would knock those seeds at
those the buds would dry the wind and
the moisture would knock those seeds out
of those buds those buds would fall into
the ground winter would come and
everything would be frozen for a little
while as the spring came and the winter
frost or the winter moisture started
moistening down into the soil those
seeds would begin to receive moisture
and warmth from nature that would
trigger them to germinate then they
would sprout up they would find their
way up dig it up out of the soil they'd
start seeing Sun and they'd go Here I am
and then they would live and it would
become little baby cannabis plants now
human involvement will we
done we have collected the seeds before
they fall out of the but when I breed I
let the plants get done and let the
seeds get finished I cut the plants down
I let them hang they dry then I
basically crumble up the buds and I
manually remove the Caesar or several
methods of doing that that's not
important right now but that process
happened then those seeds were passed on
to you now you have to play the role of
Mother Nature
we have to give these seeds the proper
environment to trigger them to start
their life the two main things that are
going to start our seeds are water and
warmth the main thing being water warmth
very secondary to that warmth will speed
up the process and make them much
happier now there are countless ways to
start new seeds I'm going to cover four
or five methods here in this episode and
I'm going to start with the method I use
personally I like the old school paper
towel technique it is very simple I get
a plate out of the cupboard just a glass
plate like you serve a meal on or make a
sandwich I also get a paper towel just
like you'd use to clean up that meal or
that sandwich I fold the paper towel one
time then I fold it again now you've
just got a little rectangular paper
towel I set that paper towel on to the
glass plate and then I get a bottle of
water
I prefer bottled water for this because
I don't want the chlorine or whatever
else is in my tap water affecting my new
seedlings so I've got the folded paper
towel sitting on the plate I simply soak
that paper towel with water it will only
hold so much I simply saturate it then I
tip the plate to the side to make sure
all that excess water runs out of the
paper towel and off of that plate just
drain it right off into the sink that
water is gone so now you've got a soggy
paper towel in the middle of a plate I
place my seeds in the paper towel and
then I gently fold it one more time if
you want to fold it another time you can
and make a little tiny square that's
fine but I think that first fold will be
just fine just fold it up to where those
seeds are in the middle and they're
getting wet and they're not getting any
light the way that that wet paper towel
works it'll kind of seal itself up so
the seeds won't move around too much
there won't be any light in there so
you've got some seeds folded up in a wet
paper towel and those are sitting on a
plate now at this point you've got a
couple of options if you are able to pay
attention to those
seeds and be around them all the time
and make sure they don't get dry you can
just leave them on that plate and leave
them exposed if it's not too hot or not
too cold in your area they will sprout
just fine just left sitting like that if
you want to slow down the amount of
moisture leaving that paper towel and
try to keep it moist a little bit longer
without having to pay so much attention
just set another plate over it flip the
plate upside down and set it on top of
the first plate just like you do if you
had a sandwich in there and he didn't
want anything to get to the sandwich so
you just got two plates with your little
folded up paper towel in there you have
to keep it moist at all times do not let
it get dry if you feel like you're going
to get forgetful or if you need to go to
work for an extended period of time and
you cannot monitor the moisture of your
new seedlings you can always set them in
a baggie put your folded paper towel
with the moisture in it in a baggie this
will give the moisture nowhere to go it
will be trapped inside that little
environment just make sure you check on
them as soon as you get home from work
if you leave that wet paper towel folded
up in a baggie in a really warm spot for
too long you can create a mildew
situation so make sure you pop that open
get some fresh air in there and check on
that as soon as you get home from work
so it sounds really easy because it is
you are folding a paper towel into a
square you're moistening it you're
letting the excess moisture run off we
set the seeds onto that moist paper
towel and then we fold it to cover them
up and then if you need to place another
plate over it to slow down the dry time
if you're really forgetful and you're
gonna be away for a while put it in a
baggie to retain that moisture then set
it somewhere semi warm most of the time
if you are comfortable in that area your
seedlings are probably comfortable as
well room temperature is acceptable for
seedlings a great spot for seedlings if
you do not forget them is on top of the
refrigerator that temperature that
happens right on top of the refrigerator
is perfect for seedlings if you don't
forget them put them in a baggie
set them right on top they should be
ready in 12 to 24 maybe 36 hours if
you've got one of those old big TVs
nobody's got those big old TVs anymore
they used to get warm on the
back that was a great spot to set
seedlings and a baggie was on the back
of the old Sony Trinitron 36 inch TV
where it got warm from playing video
games all day that would be the perfect
temp for seedlings other than those
subtle heat sources like the top of the
fridge or the back of the TV I really
don't recommend a heat mat for
germinating new seeds or for your clones
I've seen more clones and seeds
destroyed roasted and barbecued than I
have ever seen assisted by one of those
heat mats but I'm gonna talk about that
more later in the episode I think so
let's skip that for now and try to stay
focused alright so we've got our
seedlings they are folded up in a paper
towel we're keeping them moist we don't
want them soggy we don't want them
dripping all the time we want to keep
them moist and comfortable so you've got
them folded in the paper towel and you
were checking on them every few hours if
you were able they're easy to check on
just set your hand right on that paper
towel don't crush the seeds just set
your hand on there gently and if the
paper towel is kind of cold kind of
chilly they're probably wet enough if
you don't feel like it's wet enough
moisten it up a little bit get your
water bottle and just pour the water on
there gently and then tip the tear that
plate over toward the excess water runs
off into the sink and then you've got a
moistened up for the rest of the day
they should only be in this paper towel
for 12 to 24 maybe 36 or 48 hours before
you see them starting to pop open it
will pop open on one side and a little
white tail will start coming out that is
exactly what we are looking for that is
the start of life that is a taproot that
is the beginning of everything that
little root is gonna dig down into the
pot once we pot it and it's gonna dig
down and start finding nutrients and
that's gonna be the legs that's gonna be
the foundation and then it's gonna start
shooting that seedling straight upward
toward the light and then it's gonna
shoot little leaves out of there and
that little seedling will fall off and
then you've got a little plant so that
is the start of everything happening
right there and you get to see it
because you've just got it right there
in that paper towel it's not buried
under anything so you can check on them
check on them about twelve hours if you
don't see anything check on them in 24
hours if you don't see anything go 36
you're gonna get impatient after 24
hours he'll be checking on them every 4
to 6 hours don't worry just keep
checking don't forget about them we only
need maybe an eighth of an inch maybe a
quarter of an inch of that tap root to
pop out before our seedlings are ready
to put into soil but
we'll get to that so I think I covered
how to germinate seeds in a paper towel
you fold it you wet it you drain it put
the seeds in there fold it again and
then you keep an eye on it and keep it
moist keep it slightly warm but don't
roast it if you think you might forget
about your seedlings place the paper
towel set up in a baggie and that will
keep them moist until you open it once
again don't forget about them make sure
you check on them then when you unfold
that paper towel and you've got little
tap roots sticking out that's when it's
time to get ready to put them into your
potting mix but we're gonna talk about
that a little bit later the only thing
left to cover in this section is what if
those seeds don't pop open after 48
hours the only thing you can really do
is wait a little bit longer maybe
increase the heat if you didn't already
set them on the fridge maybe set them up
there on top of the refrigerator where
it's a little warmer
maybe lessen the moisture maybe you've
got them a little too wet maybe just
keep that paper towel just damp maybe
you've still got a little bit of a
chance but if they haven't opened after
48 or 72 hours I would consider starting
a fresh batch of seeds at that point now
if it is really cold in your environment
it will take longer for your seeds to
germinate so expect that if you're
growing in the basement in Colorado
you've got them sitting right on a
concrete floor that's gonna take longer
consider your environment like I said
earlier the warmth will speed things up
but that too can go wrong in excess so
try to stay in the right area try to be
about 70 to 85 degrees ish and you
should be ok with rapid growth for your
seeds now let's talk about our next
method for sprouting our seeds our next
method is using rapid rooters or route
riots or whatever type of plugs are
available in your area
although I am NOT including rock wool
cubes in this section I don't like rock
wool cubes for sprouting seeds they do
not work well for sprouting seeds I
would not recommend that if it's what
you've got do it similarly to what I
recommend here with the rapid rooters
but before you use your rock wool cubes
make sure you clean them out and make
sure you soak them in a pH balanced
solution rinse them very well to get
anything out of them then soak them
either in clean water or a light
nutrient solution that has been pH
around 6 you don't want to use rock wool
without rinsing them and adjusting the
pH so this is all about rapid rooters or
root riot plugs when we start with these
plugs we need to soak them so I get a
container based on the amount of plugs
I'm going to use I'm generally using a
five-gallon bucket I think they're sold
in a 50 pack so most of the time I just
do all 50 and I either do 50 clones or
50 ceilings I just use the whole package
you soak as many as you need what I do
is I get a container it will fit enough
water to soak as many plugs as I'm gonna
use I adjust the pH to somewhere between
6 and 6 3 I usually place the rapid
Rooter plugs back into the rapid Rooter
tray if you're not using the tray that's
okay you don't need it but that's
usually what I do I put it right in the
tray then I take a seed and I insert the
seed into the rapid Rooter plug that
seed goes pointy and down if you look at
your seeds it's got a round end and it's
got a pointy end it will be obvious when
you look at it the pointy end goes down
this is important because of the way
that the seed grows pointy end down when
you are putting it into a rapid Rooter
or any sort of a cube or if you are
going directly in the soil pointy end
down also if you are going into a rapid
Rooter if you're going into a root Riot
cube if you're going into soil or if
you're going against my advice and
you're going directly into Rockwall it
is always suggested that you plant your
seeds about one knuckle deep just go
just the tip of your finger just push it
in until you press that first knuckle
right that first bend in your finger
that's far enough stop pushing that
seedling is deep enough into the soil
it's deep enough into that cube it will
live there it doesn't need to be buried
way down in there it stands a much
better chance if it's just about knuckle
deep is all you need to go so after I've
got all my seedlings planted and I've
got all my cubes labeled make sure you
label each cube if you're planning
different strains make sure you've got a
way to label each cube so you know what
you've got also label if you're doing
more than one paper-towel of seeds make
sure you label that paper towel some way
most of you are just doing one pack of
seeds or one strain but if you're doing
multiple please carefully label things
so we've got our seeds they are in our
rapid Rooter cubes they're carefully
labeled they are nice and moist they're
about
deep down into the end of the cube now I
place them under a very light light you
don't need very powerful lighting for
sprouting seeds a really weak LED or a
t5 kind of high up is plenty of lighting
a compact fluorescent is probably just
enough light you don't need to go
extreme for a ceiling just enough to
encourage it to grow once it gets bigger
we do need light but right now we don't
need ridiculous lighting for a small
seedling so place it under a light that
will give it warmth and that will
encourage it to grow now in about two or
three days maybe four or five days at
the latest you should see a little
sprout pop out of your cube and you have
now got a little seedling now that
seedling can live in that little rapid
Rooter for several days but it's going
to need a forever home it's gonna need
to go into either some soil or a hydro
setup fairly soon while it's in that
rapid Rooter we need to keep it warm we
need to keep it somewhere between 70 and
85 degrees and we need to keep that root
tube moist at all times once it dries up
that plant has no life source and it
will die so keep it moist and keep it
warm and keep it under a light and then
we need to think about getting it into a
good potting mix or into a hydro system
very soon so that it can thrive so that
is the basics of sprouting a seed in a
rapid Rooter or a root riot cube or
against my advice if you choose to use a
rock wool cube you would use a similar
method basically soak it with a proper
pH solution then press the ceiling in
pointy end down and only go about a
knuckle deep set it under a light and
leave it alone for two or three days you
should see a little sprout pop up if you
don't see the sprout pop up look in the
little hole and see what you see
sometimes the seedling simply gets
caught and it's bent over and it can't
pop itself up out of the root cube that
happens you can carefully get a pair of
tweezers or a chopstick and very gently
encourage that plant to grow straight up
don't pull it out of the seed casing
don't pull it out of the cube maybe
spread the whole of the cube open just a
little bit and encourage it to pop out
of there it just needs to bend up and
come out you can probably guide it out
if you're gentle if it's close to doing
it on its own don't touch it just
let it struggle and it will come out if
you feel like it's been long enough and
you're getting impatient just give it a
little tug it may pop out for you keep
in mind you're risking killing this
ceiling if you get too rough you're
going to destroy it if you get too rough
but you've got a good chance just use
your thumbs and spread that Rapid Rooter
open just a little tiny bit and you may
open it just enough for that seed to
unbind itself and be able to pop
straight up it may just be stuck it's
trying to move up in the two leaves on
the top they just got stuck somewhere
that happens quite a bit and I'll just
have to break itself free so pay
attention to that if it doesn't pop up
in four or five days if the others have
popped up and you've got one that didn't
pop up look in there that could be the
issue with that one seedling now let's
kind of touch on another method that is
very similar to the rapid rooters and
the root Riot cubes but it is also very
different this next method you cannot
put this into a hydro kit as simply as
you could a rapid Rooter or as simply as
you could a seed from a paper towel I'm
sure some people have done it I'm sure
some people do it but it's not as easy
it's much more challenging and it's not
as logical so let's talk about using
jiffy cubes jiffy cubes are great if
you're going to go into soil but like I
said you can't really use them going
into a hydro system I'm sure there's
somebody doing it gonna tell me I'm
wrong but it's not common so a jiffy
cube they're very similar to the rapid
rooters but they start off really small
any moisten them and they expand to the
proper size so you moisten them they
puff up you squeeze the excess water out
of them then from there they work just
like the rapid rooters or the root riot
cubes you place your seeding and sealing
in there pointing in down you go about
knuckle deep and then you've got to keep
your jiffy cube moist just like you do
with your other cubes now if you're
using rapid rooters or root riots or
jiffy cubes or if you're going against
my advice still and using the rock wool
cubes
make sure not to get them too moist for
too long if they are too moist it will
simply rot your ceilings they will turn
green
it will turn brown it will fall over and
die or they will not even germinate at
all there's a big difference between
being soaked and being wet and being
moist
want to soak them in the beginning put
the seeds in there when they are soaked
then just keep it wet from there you can
usually tell by looking at the rapid
Reuters how dry or wet they are when
they start getting that brown crusty
color they're too dry when they start
getting that Sheen to them they start
showing a little silver a little light
reflection that's just right when
they're really really black that's when
they are soaked so learn how to identify
soaked and saturated and wet and moist
and create a little scale for yourself I
did the 1 through 5 watering technique
maybe we need a similar thing for the
rapid rooters I kind of just did that if
they're totally soaked in black that's a
5 if they're dry and crispy that's a 1
we need to keep them about a 3 at all
times ladies and gentlemen so there we
go 1 through 5 tech on rapid rooters
just like we did on watering normal
plants so now we know how to germinate
seeds in paper towels we know how to
germinate seeds and rapid rooters we
kind of know how to do it in rock wool
cubes we know how to germinate seeds and
jiffy cubes it is just like doing it in
the rapid rooters you guys you moisten
them they expand you squeeze the excess
water out of there then you treat it
just like a rapid Rooter from there our
next option is to plant our seedlings
directly into soil that's the way it
happens in nature why wouldn't we do
that in our personal garden so let's
talk a little bit about planting our
seeds directly into soil or the medium
we are going to use if you plan to start
your seedling in soil I highly recommend
you use a very small container I would
recommend a beer cup or something that
size there's no reason to have a tiny
tiny plant in a large container of soil
so my first recommendation is a small
container with plenty of drainage my
second recommendation will be a good
soil for starter plants something with a
lot of aeration and something with not
too much nutrients added to it maybe
something with some mykos or maybe some
beneficial bacteria that's good but we
don't need a lot of boosts for our
little babies so start with a small
container of high-quality starter soil
so I've got my container and I've got my
starter soil now i'm oice in that soil
before I put my seedlings into there
just simply water that soil with the
pH adjusted solution you don't need
nutrients just water pH around 6-2 6-3
you should be just fine just water it on
in let it drain out once it's done
draining take your pointer finger and
just make a little tiny hole just
knuckle deep just like I keep saying in
the episode I may name the episode that
just go about one knuckle deep into the
soil then take your seedling and just
set it right inside that hole then
gently press the dirt right over that
ceiling just real gently you don't need
to pack it down just cover up that
seedling and then just let it rest and
then within 24 to 48 to 36 maybe 72
hours you should see a little baby plant
just pop it up right out of there you'll
just see two little green leaves just
popping right up out of that topsoil I
like to keep my little baby plants in
the beer cups under a t5 light I try to
keep the light kind of far out when
they're little and then as they get
bigger I move the light a little bit
closer I try not to let the seedlings
get too stretchy if they start getting a
little leggy I move the light closer I
like to put a fan on them while they're
a little that gives them a little
strength makes them a little more robust
so there are advantages and
disadvantages to starting them in the
beer cup the advantage they're already
in their soil you don't have to up pot
them you don't have to transplant them
you don't have to do any damage to a
little seedling the disadvantage is
sometimes you just completely lose a
seedling and a beer cup filled with soil
sometimes they just totally disappear
sometimes they don't sprout at all and
sometimes you totally drown them by
trying to water so much soil so starting
them in beer cups and soil is a little
trickier but it may be the only option
for some people not everybody is able to
order rapid rooters or root riot cubes
not everybody has access to a rock wool
cube and some people may just want to
try it because that's the way it happens
in nature so that is a rundown of my
basic methods of germinating seeds
hopefully one of those methods works for
you honestly I use the folded paper
towel method the most in a commercial
environment I may use the rapid Rooter
method next but I honestly do not start
seeds directly in soil anymore I found
that I can start a lot more in much less
space by using the rapid rooters imagine
the amount of space it takes to start
100 rapid rooters compared to 100 beer
cups it's a law
difference in the amount of space that
you need I honestly don't have any
experience with the jiffy cubes I've
never had to use those I've always had
access to the rapid rooters and honestly
I've just been sticking with the paper
towel method so that's what I'm doing
the most I encourage you to use the
method that works the best for you I
encourage you also to try different
methods if you think something works
great why not try another method if
you've got some seeds that you can spare
why not try something you may find that
something works better for you all right
so now we've got our seeds germinated
we've either got some seeds folded into
a paper towel or we've got a rapid
Rooter or a root riot or a rock wool
cube with roots hanging out of the
bottom of the root cube our next step is
to pot our new seedling into a pot of
soil or soilless mix in this episode I
will cover how to pot the seeds
germinated from a paper towel into soil
but my next episode is going to be about
cutting clones then shortly after that
we will have to pop the clones into soil
which means I'm going to do a combo
episode of planting our new seedlings in
the rapid rooters and planting clones
and rapid rooters into soil at the same
time I'm just gonna knock that out in
one episode so that part will be coming
soon but for now let's talk about
planting our freshly germinated
seedlings that are just sitting in a wet
paper towel I like to catch these seeds
when the new tap roots are very sure I
don't like to get it too long and too
out of control because I feel like that
gives me too much opportunity to cause
it too much stress so as soon as I see
my seedlings crack open a little bit and
that little tap root is sticking out
just a little tiny bit I'm comfortable
putting them into their soil or soilless
mix and I do that with a very similar
method as I did earlier when we talked
about planting seeds into the beer cups
I get a beer cup or a very small pot
with plenty of drainage I fill it with a
quality soil that is good for small
plants something with a lot of aeration
and plenty of drainage then I moisten
that soil with water pH around 6 to 6 3
then I do the same thing as we've been
doing the whole episode I make a
tiny hole about knuckle deep in that
soil then I simply place the germinated
seed in that little hole I do my best to
point it with that little white root
pointing straight down if your tap root
is nice and short
don't worry about which direction your
ceiling is facing when you place it into
soil it should be just fine if it's
really long you may want to make sure
you point that root down and the seed is
going up so gently place your seedling
in the soil brush dirt over the top of
it you don't need to bury it or pack it
down just cover it and then the tap root
will go down it'll start to spread out
and the little tiny plant will grow up
to the top and it'll push the seedling
with a little set of tiny tiny leaves
right through the top soil and you'll
have a little starter baby plant the
main thing to worry about when potting
your new seedlings is to not damage that
little white tap root sticking out of
the seedling do your best not to disrupt
stress or damage that little white tap
root they're very delicate so once I've
got it potted I put it under a t5 light
I keep the light a little distance away
so that I don't shock the plant as the
plant gets bigger I bring the light a
little bit closer once I feel like the
plant is kind of taken off I put a fan
on it and then once it gets its first
set of serrated leaves I start adding
very light doses of nutrients so that is
how I pop my seedling that was
germinated from a paper towel I
basically fill a beer cup with good dirt
poke a hole in the bottom go knuckle
deep in the soil on the top drop my
little germinated seedling in there and
cover it up and then put it under the
light and wait for it to pop up and then
it grows and grows until I see a set of
leaves with serration and that is when I
start feeding it a little bit of light
nutrients now let's talk about a couple
of things that happen quite often when
we are working with seeds sometimes the
seed shell will get stuck to the seed
and hinder the seeds growth and threaten
that seeds life that is not as scary as
it looks when it happens you'll know
what I'm talking about that seed hole
will just get stuck though the ceiling
will come up out of the dirt and you'll
see that seed the leaves are trying to
open up it's trying to live and it's
just trying to open up but it can't
because that seed casing is just
to it that is really easy to solve I get
a spray bottle with water and I moisten
that ceiling really heavily just spray
it with water just keep spraying it more
moisture more moisture more moisture
then see if you can just brush it off
with your finger it may just come right
off if not spray more water if that
still doesn't work get some tweezers and
just do a gentle dissection if it is
really moist you should be able to get
that seed casing off it is supposed to
come off of there that plant opens up
the way the plant opens itself up the
way that that seed casing spreads in
half it should pop right off of there
just give it a little assistance a
little moisture little tweezers maybe a
pair of chopsticks depending on how
skilled you are it shouldn't be too hard
to do don't be afraid to get in there
and pull that casing off earlier I
talked about not using heat mats I have
honestly seen people roast more seeds
with heat mat than I have ever seen
success with a heat mat from a seedling
the only time I have ever needed a heat
mat was when I was growing in a
warehouse in Colorado and it was really
cold during the winter other times I
don't use a heat mat for cloning or for
seedlings and I have great success if
you are comfortable in the area your
seedlings are probably comfortable in
that area also and I'm not talking about
some Colorado mountain boy who's outside
barefoot in the snow I'm talking about a
normal person room temperature is
acceptable for your seedlings now I've
got one more thing I want to touch on
before I start wrapping up the episode
and the note I wrote is called pre
soaked a lot of people like to pre-soak
their seeds before the official
germination if you've got older seeds
that have been sitting around for a
longer I may may recommend you give them
a pre soaked it's really easy you simply
pre soak them in water before you
germinate them I recommend 12 hours
maybe 24 at the most never go more than
24 hours on a soak because that will
drown your seeds my theory behind the
pre soaked is some seeds just have a
hard outer coating and they don't want
to germinate very easily soaking them in
water for 24 hours will definitely
soften that outer coating and encourage
easier germination so if you've got
older seeds that you've been having a
problem getting to germinate maybe
soak them for 12 hours then give them
the paper towel method if that doesn't
work try soaking some for 24 hours then
giving them the paper towel method if
that doesn't work then we're going to
need to try more scientific approaches
there are chemicals we can add there are
tricks we can do but that is much more
advanced science than what we're
prepared for today so if you've got old
seeds or if you feel like you've got
really hard seeds with a really thick
coating don't be afraid to give them a
pre-soak 12 to 24 hours never go more
than 24 hours I don't feel like that's a
good idea
all right you guys I feel like that is a
good lesson on how to germinate your
seeds I will not forget to teach you
guys how to pot those freshly sprouted
seeds that you've got in your rapid
rooters or your rock wool cubes like I
told you not to do or in your jiffy pots
we'll talk about that in a future
episode that is written down that is on
the schedule you guys I want to thank
you for listening to another episode I
want to encourage you guys to support
the patreon campaign if you feel like
this podcast was educational informative
or entertaining and you would like to
make a financial contribution to the
show you can do so by going to
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
all the information you need to sign up
will be right there and I do appreciate
all the support big thank you to
everybody who has been helping me out I
would also appreciate it if you find me
on all of the social media you can stalk
me on Facebook simply search for the
girl from your heart podcast on Twitter
it's at g f YH podcast if you'd like to
follow my personal twitter account it is
Russ to Jeff 420 also I encourage you to
follow my Instagram its Irie underscore
genetics iri e underscore g e and e t
ICS Irie underscore genetics on
instagram
give me a follow check out my fine
cannabis photography and also check out
my instagram live videos where my
friends come and ask me cannabis
questions I answer cannabis questions I
take some dabs we hang out sometimes we
get goofy it is always a good time I
encourage you to participate there I
recently just hit 19,000 followers on
Instagram so a big shout-out to
everybody for supporting my Instagram
efforts you guys don't forget that the
podcast is available on iTunes and
stitcher and every episode is available
on the you
Tube channel simply search for the girl
from your higher podcast you guys I'm
gonna wrap up this podcast I think you
could tell my throat is burning out I'll
be back in just a few days with fresh
new content thank you guys for listening
I want to give you a huge shout out to
my friend indica dog oh and until next
time take a phat dab and give your mom a
hug for me