welcome to the show cannabis community
it's time for episode 365 of the Grove
from your heart podcast this episode is
brought to you by the hell a dank seed
company if you need new seeds for your
garden I highly recommend the hella dank
seed company and you can find them at
www.nasa.gov
two day I've been taking dabs of this
bubble Jack full-spectrum extract and I
love the flavor and aroma of this stuff
it smells like bubblegum and cotton
candy when I dab it it goes straight to
my head it makes my brain go superfast
it makes my mouth go super fast so I
think this will be a great concentrate
for smoking before a podcast all right
before we get too deep into this episode
I want to give a few people a shout-out
I owe a big shout-out to my friend Jake
Jordan I owe a shout-out to Jade and
also a big shout-out to Grimbold the
druid and also a shout-out to Tanner
Martin uuk thanks for supporting the
podcast I really do appreciate all of
the support ladies and gentlemen this is
going to be another grow lesson I have
been doing a long series of grow lessons
I hope you have been following along if
you are interested I recommend you go
back to episode 351 that's where I start
this long series of grow lessons start
there and get caught up if you feel like
you're up to speed
welcome to the grow lessons in the last
two episodes we talked about sprouting
seeds we also talked about cutting
clones in this episode we're going to
talk about putting those seeds and those
clones into containers of soil or
soilless mix so let's start with the
seeds we talked about germinating in
paper towels I may have covered this
briefly in the previous episode but
we're going to talk about it a little
bit of a recap right here just to make
sure everybody is up to speed so we
started a few seeds that we folded a
paper towel we soaked it we put seeds on
the paper towel we folded it again to
secure the seeds inside maybe we put
that in a baggie maybe we put that in a
warm place the seeds have now sprouted
hopefully they've got little tiny tails
maybe a quarter of an inch maybe a half
inch hopefully you didn't go any more
than one inch long here is how I
recommend planting those seedlings I
generally try to stay away from
recommending products every time I
recommend a product I get emails from
people saying I did something wrong but
I want to make this easy for everybody
so I recommend light warrior soil from
far
Barnes for your new seedlings it is
readily available it is affordable and
it works very well I'm sure other people
will have other ideas and other
suggestions I am okay with that do what
you're comfortable with
I recommend this product because like I
said it's available it's affordable and
I know that it works I'm not gonna send
people on some crazy mission looking for
a product that's hard to find or
overpriced so we've got our medium you
can probably get away with one bag of
light warrior soil now we need
containers to put this soil in to put
our seedlings in I recommend small pots
for small plants there's no reason to
fill up a big three gallon pot and then
plant a little tiny seedling in there
and then you have to water that entire
space of soil you have to put water and
nutrients in all of that space just to
water that plant properly if you've got
your seedling inside of a little tiny
cup you only have to water that much
space you don't have to waste water you
don't have to waste nutrients and you
don't have to waste space a lot of new
growers really like to drown seedlings
in larger pots if they put a seedling in
a larger pot they've got a water all of
that soil so they go and they pour an
entire pitcher of water right on top of
that three gallon pot then that seedling
gets washed away in all that water who
knows where it goes sometimes when
people apply water they do it kind of
heavily the seed gets washed away it
gets lost in there they kill the seeds
they drown they fail with the seeds they
get discouraged so I highly recommend
starting with a smaller pot maybe a four
inch net pot maybe a six inch net pot
maybe a four inch square pot maybe a six
inch circular pot something that size
I honestly start my seedlings in a beer
cup I take a few beer cups I stack them
up on top of each other then I put a
drill through the bottom of them I can
go through about eight cups at a time I
poke one big hole through the bottom
then I'll do a few smaller holes on the
side just to give some proper drainage
and I feel like beer cups are the
perfect size for new baby seedlings the
seedlings can sprout in there they can
get a good start they can develop a good
root system and by the time they get big
enough you can just up pop them into
there 3 or 5 gallon pot and it works
really well so let's talk about actually
putting these seedlings into I'm gonna
go with the beer cup for this method
I've got my beer cup I've got my white
warrior soil mix I'm gonna fill my beer
cup most of the way up with soil I want
to pack it down fairly tight then I'm
gonna fill it up with soil and leave
myself about a quarter of an
so that when I water I've got plenty of
room for water and it doesn't just run
off the top of the cup so I fill it up
I've got about quarter inch of space
left on the top then I water that soil
before I even put my clone or my
seedling into it in this case we're
gonna put a ceiling in there so I would
water it since I'm going with the
ceiling I do not use any nutrients at
this time I'll water it I'll let all
that water soak through the bottom then
I take my pointer finger and I dig a
little hole just right to the first
knuckle of my finger then I put that
little freshly sprouted seedling right
inside that hole if the ceiling has
developed a long tail that tap root if
that tap root has gotten long you need
to make that be facing down and the seed
facing up you want the seed coming up in
the tap root going down so gently place
that seed facing down or the tap root
facing down the seed pointing up place
that right in the dirt dig the hole as
you need as deep as you need to dig it
if you've got a longer tap root just
push your finger in there as long as you
need to go then gently set that tap root
down in there and then you just want to
put the dirt right over it real gently
you don't need to pack it down just make
sure that it's covered up for the lights
not getting to it and it is packed in
there tight enough when you water it the
next time that water will probably pack
it just tight enough for you you don't
need to press it down too much at this
point you don't want to risk crushing
that seedling so if you've got a real
short tail just go knuckle deep drop
that little sealing right in there and
bury it if you've got kind of a long
tail you've got to dig a little deeper
of a hole set that tail down in there
and then just carefully bury that be
really careful not to disturb that white
tap root that is really delicate and
it's important that it is not disrupted
now your new seedlings are basically
potted in their cups of dirt I would
place them under a t5 light with the t5
light about 8 to 12 inches away I would
try to keep them around 75 to 85 degrees
and I would try to keep it quite humid
around these little tiny baby plants now
when it comes time to water these new
seedlings we have to be very careful for
the first few days I recommend using a
sprayer to water new seedlings I got a
tiny 1 gallon pump sprayer from the
local hardware store I mix it with my
whatever nutrient solution I'm gonna use
or just plain water that's been pH
balanced correctly then I pump it real
hard and I just spray the topsoil with
that water instead of pouring a heavy
dose of water in and risking drowning
those seeds or
RUP ting those seeds I just spray it
from the top I kind of spray it at a few
angles that way get all the soil
saturated and it works just like the
morning dew would so I feel like
spraying them is really gentle and it
works really well for new growers to not
drown these plants and not flood the
soil when they're starting baby
seedlings now let's briefly talk about
when to start feeding our seedlings I
like to start feeding when I see the
first set of truly developed leaves when
you see the first set of five or seven
or nine depending on what variety you're
growing when you see the first set of
full leaves that's when I like to start
adding nutrients depending on your brand
and your product I usually recommend you
start with about a quarter strength if
the bottle says to use 40 milliliters of
a certain product I would recommend you
start with 10 milliliters of that
product and then as that plant gets
bigger and stronger and more developed
then you can increase your nutrient
feedings to those plants but while
they're small let's feed them lightly so
we don't roast them now let's talk
briefly about what to feed them these
plants need a little bit of nitrogen
they need a very small amount of
phosphorous and a very small amount of
potassium oast of your basic grow
nutrients will be just fine for small
seedlings I would recommend adding a
root inoculant product something like
mammoth pea something like great white
something like recharge something like
plus life any of those products will
work for you do a little bit of research
find what's available in your area find
what fits your price range and get the
product that will work best for you
something is better than nothing when it
comes to root inoculants and microbes
and beneficial fungus and bacteria I
highly recommend it for small plants and
I highly recommend it throughout the
entire growing process so when your
plants are little they're not going to
need a whole lot of nutrients just a
base nutrient and I highly recommend
some sort of root inoculant they won't
need cal-mag probably until we
transplant them into the next pot if you
want to add a full Vic or a humic acid
that's always good for the plants at all
stages but at this point I mainly like
to focus on healthy plants with strong
roots so I really focus on root
development at this stage of the game
I'll add microbes and beneficial fungus
and then I'll also add carbohydrates but
at this point like I said I am mainly
focusing on root development until I
transplant those plants into their next
pots so we talked a little bit about
what to feed these little baby
let's talk about pH for small seedlings
I like to keep my pH around five point
eight to six point two once they get a
little bit larger I will increase the pH
slowly and I'll move up towards six
point three or six point four but for
these small babies let's stay closer to
five point eight or six point two now
really take your time increasing the
amount of nutrients you give these
plants and also take your time
increasing the pH of these plants they
need to grow they need to get a root
system to be able to process all of the
stuff you're giving them these little
tiny plants don't want a lot and you do
run the risk of burning them if you
overfeed them so pay attention and go
slow now after several days these
seedlings will start taking off they'll
start getting full-sized leaves and they
will start catching up to the same size
as the clones we cut once they reach
that size I consider them to be small
veg plants and I treat them just like I
do my small veg plants and we will talk
about caring for and feeding small veg
plants here in the near future next
let's talk about planting our rapid
rooters maybe we planted some seedlings
in Rapid rooters maybe we cut some
clones and rapid rooters and put them in
a dome and now they are sprouting roots
and it is time to plant them how do we
know when it is time to plant our rapid
Rooter ceilings or clones I like to
plant seedlings as soon as I see that
first taproot coming out of the rapid
Rooter I don't want to let that taproot
get too long too leggy and too stretchy
so I do my best to get those into soil
right away when I cut clones and rapid
rooters I like to make sure they are
sufficiently rooted before I try to put
them into soil make sure your clones are
properly hardened off we talked about
this in a previous episode we have to
expose our domed clones to fresh air for
durations of time and extend that
duration over a period of time to make
sure the clones are ready to not be in a
humidity controlled environment we need
to get them used to being in our regular
veg environment so we've been hardening
off our clones and they show sufficient
roots what do I mean by sufficient roots
I want at least five maybe ten or twelve
white thick roots popping out of that
rapid Rooter I want them to be just
busting out of there and kind of thick I
want them to look like they're just
little worms coming out looking for
somewhere to go if you've got more than
five maybe more than 12
and they start building up in there you
were really doing well we want to
develop a nice root system before we pot
it but there is a fine line between just
enough and too much if you lift that
little clone up out of that tray and the
roots have begun wrapping a round of the
Rooter you've gone too far
if those roots are hanging down inside
the root or tray and hanging into the
water we have gone too far we want to
get those into our soilless mix as soon
as possible I want just a little bit of
dreadlocks just hanging out of there not
a lot just maybe a little tiny mop just
a little fuzz ball maybe ten or twenty
of them just hanging out that is prime
time to pot those and I want them about
a half inch to an inch and a half long
is perfect now let's put these rapid
rooters into our beer cup full of light
warrior soil or whatever size pot and
whatever soil makes you choose to use
just make sure it's a quality soil mix
with plenty of aeration and make sure
whatever size or whatever container to
use has plenty of drainage we don't want
our plants to get muddy at the bottom
get stagnant water that will totally
drown and destroy our roots will get
root rot it will be a mess it will be
disgusting so quality soil pots with
good drainage that is a requirement now
just like we did the beer cups for our
small seedlings let's fill them up with
soil and leave ourselves about a quarter
of an inch of space for water now if I'm
putting the seedlings in the rapid
rooters into this soil I most likely
will not give them nutrients at this
time when i put the clones into the soil
at this time i do like to give them a
small nutrient feeding i use a light
vegetative mix about a quarter strength
of whatever brand you're using use about
a quarter strength of whatever they
recommend i also like to use a microbe
product again something like mammoth pea
something like great white shark
something like recharge something like
plus life from veg bloom anything with
beneficial fungus and bacteria that will
encourage root growth will be great for
your small plants so we've got our light
base nutrients we've got our root
inoculant let's talk about pH I like to
keep the pH for these small clones
somewhere between 5.8 and 6.2 so we've
got our base nutrients we've got our
root inoculant we've got our solution pH
now I water that solution through my
cups of soil just pour it right on
through until it drains out a little bit
you want to fully saturate that new soil
now
it's done dripping and that soil is
fully saturated I will take two fingers
and just gently make a little hole right
in the center of that soil and I go just
a little bit deeper than the height of
that rapid Rooter so if the rapid Rooter
is an inch tall I go maybe an inch and
1/8 or maybe an inch and a quarter deep
then I get the rapid Rooter out of the
little tray and I set it gently inside
of that hole and I do my best to not
disrupt any of those roots if it's a
seedling you've probably only got one or
two roots sticking out of that rapid
Rooter you need to be very careful
gently set that in the soil set it right
inside there then backfill that hole
really carefully over that rapid Rooter
I like to go right over the top of it so
you can never tell the rapid Rooter was
there and just a little plant is
sticking up out of the soil
be really careful if you're working with
the ceiling that one tap root is all
it's got to survive through at this
point if you're working with a clone we
still need to be very careful with these
roots by the way we're rubber gloves
when you're doing all this I highly
recommend rubber gloves whenever you're
coming in contact when you're putting
your hands or your skin in contact with
the dirt with the roots with the plants
just try to wear rubber gloves if you
can or latex gloves try to glove up
whenever possible I would still suggest
watering that rapid Rooter sealing with
the spray bottle just like I recommended
before until it gets nice and large
until you are confident that you're not
going to drown it just water it with
that spray bottle make sure you fully
saturate the soil but it's easier to not
go overboard when you're spraying with a
spray bottle because you can only spray
so much at a time if you're a new grower
and you don't have a lot of experience
watering plants and you're new at
watering the clones don't be afraid to
water them with the spray bottle also
just get in there and saturate that soil
keep spraying until you feel like it's
saturated and then wait until it's
fairly dry to water it again you'll know
when it feels real light when you pick
it up you'll say oh that needs water
then just soak it until it's mostly
saturated again eventually you'll
realize that you're spending too much
time using that spray bottle to water
the clones and you'll start using a more
efficient method but it's a great way to
learn how to not over water so I
basically fill my cup with soil
I'm oice in the soil I make a little
hole with my fingers and I set that
rapid Rooter right inside of that hole
really gently really careful not to
damage any
those new roots then I carefully bury
that wrap and Rooter with the moist soil
then I put that cup underneath a t5
light again I like to keep that light 8
to 12 inches above it when they're brand
new like this I don't want to scorch
them I don't want to burn them then I
like to keep the temperature somewhere
between 75 and 85 degrees and I try to
keep the room fairly humid when I have
new seedlings or young plants in the
room so that is really quickly how I put
my rapid Rooter seedlings and clones in
two cups of soil let's talk next about
putting our clones from an easy cloner
machine or a botanic air turbo cloner in
two cups of soil my method for potting
these clones into soil starts the same
as potting our seeds or potting our
rapid rooters I start by filling my cup
or my desired container with light
warrior or my desired soilless mix about
a quarter inch away from the top I then
saturate that soil the same as I did
with my other cloning method I use about
a quarter strength of my vegetative knew
and I like to use plenty of microbes
then I adjust the pH between 5.8 and 6.2
now when we cut these clones I said to
leave about an inch underneath the
neoprene collar into the water getting
hit by that sprayer that entire inch
should have roots popping out of here we
should have a nice little mop of roots
before we try to pop these so I've got
my cup of moistened soil I've got a well
rooted clone now I usually grab the cup
with my right hand I use the pointer
finger on my left hand and I just poke a
hole about an inch and a half deep right
into that soil now I may widen that hole
up a little bit depending on the root
mass coming off of that clone if there
are a lot of roots I need more room I
don't want to crowd or crush the roots
into that soil I like to lower the clone
down into the soil and let those roots
spread as far as they can get so if
you've got something hanging off try not
to squish them try not to coil them we
want to encourage those roots to spread
out as far as they can go if you've got
a lot of roots maybe make a small cone
of soil in the bottom of the cup a
little triangle so that the roots can
hit that triangle and spread out around
that instead of getting into a ball we
want the roots spread out that is really
important if we tangle them up if we
twist them
suffocate themselves and they will kill
the plant and the clone will not survive
at all now if your roots have gotten
excessively long I recommend you trim
some off if there are more than 6 or 7
inches long just go ahead and trim the
bottoms of those roots off your plants
will thank you for it they won't have so
much root mass twist it up in the bottom
of that cup trying to figure out what to
do you'll just have a nice thick root
mass started and it works a little bit
like topping your plants you've just
created more sections for that root zone
to branch out from so your plants will
appreciate it so you pop that clone up
out of the EZ cloner you've got the
neoprene disc you take the neoprene disc
off you put that back in the hole so the
water doesn't go sprint anywhere you've
probably got the cloner turned on while
you're potting the clones then you take
that clone and you just set it right
inside that hole that you've created in
the soil but as you lower it down into
there try to spread the roots out if
they're just short and stubby they're
gonna go the direction they want to go
if they're getting long enough to where
you can stretch them or move them and
encourage them which direction to go try
to make them spread out like an umbrella
we want to get them nice and far if
they're really long you can put soil in
the cup lower some of the roots down
into the cup then sprinkle more soil on
top of that then lower more roots down
into the cup and then sprinkle more soil
on top of that then no matter how much
soil you use no matter how long the
roots are we need to bury that clone
deep enough into this cup to give it
some support to stand straight up we
need to get the soil tight enough around
it and get it deep enough in there to
get the clone to support itself and
stand straight up but at the same time
we need to not bury it so deep that we
cause a root rot on that short stem that
is there so we put 1 inch of it
underneath the neoprene disc getting
sprayed by the water so we've got roots
about one inch then that neoprene disc
is about a quarter of an inch deep so I
would say probably plant it somewhere
between one and a quarter and one and a
half inches deep into your media now
we've already moistened the soil so the
nutrients are in there the next thing to
do is to move our potted clones
underneath a t5 light again for freshly
potted plants I like to keep that t5
about 8 to 12 inches away I will lower
that light as the plants get stronger
I just don't want to move them right
under there right away and scorch them
and burn them and give them the
opportunity to stress out for these new
baby clones I like
to keep the temperature between 75 and
85 degrees and I do like high humidity
it depends on how much airflow I've got
in the room it depends on my environment
it depends on the situation if I've got
plenty of airflow if I can have air
exchange I will put higher humidity in
the room if I feel like there's not a
lot of airflow and it will create
problems I will reduce the humidity
accordingly I know I keep stressing it
but the most important thing to think
about when you are potting these clones
from the easy cloner from the turbo
cloner is to not let those gangly roots
wrap up on themselves don't let them
bind don't let them smother themselves
don't let him suffocate themselves these
cloning machines can make roots explode
you look in there on day 5 and you won't
have any roots you'll look in there on
day 6 you'll be getting roots you'll go
away for the weekend you'll come back
over the weekend on Monday the roots are
hanging down into the water they go
crazy very quickly
you will see what I'm talking about when
you get it dialed in don't take those
fat clones with big crazy roots and kill
them by suffocating them by coiling them
up in your soil all right so at this
point we have got a bunch of seedlings
or a bunch of clones in small pots or
cups we've got them underneath t5 lights
or whatever light you've got available
maybe you've got an LED maybe you've got
a small HBS maybe a 250 or a 400 if
you're using something larger that works
just keep it further away just raise it
up real high so we've got it under an
acceptable light we've got it in a
desirable climate which is around 75 to
85 degrees with the appropriate humidity
hopefully you've got somewhere between
50 and 75 percent humidity for your
small plants
I would suggest either 24 hours on or
possibly 20 on and 4 off or a lot of
people like to do 18 hours on and 6
hours off for our new small plants also
I would recommend a light fan on these
plants just a fan to keep the air moving
around them will prevent the plants from
getting leggy and stretchy and I think
it just makes tougher more robust plants
when you put a little breeze on them so
at this point the clones are now in our
small veg phase in a very short time
those seedlings will catch up to what I
consider the small veg phase which is
when they're about 6 inches tall and
they've got a couple of nice sets of
leaves and they can start taking small
veg nutrients I plan on doing a come
Pleet episode on small veg here in the
very near future that episode will
include recommended light cycles for
your veg plants that episode will
include recommended nutrient schedules
for your veg plants I'll also talk about
optimal environmental conditions for
your small veg plants then we'll talk
about transplanting our plants into
their finishing pots and we will
consider that large veg and then we will
begin to talk about our large veg phase
ladies and gentlemen I hope you are
having as much fun with these grow
lessons as I am I would love to hear
your feedback reach out to me on Twitter
or through email on Twitter it's @gf wih
podcast and of course the email address
is grow from your heart at hotmail.com
and if you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
and you would like to make a financial
contribution to the show you can do so
by going to patreon.com slash grow from
your heart and all the information you
need to become a patron will be right
there on the screen and I do appreciate
all of the support from everybody who is
contributed ladies and gentlemen I want
to thank you again for listening to the
podcast I know this was sort of a short
episode but I feel like I did a good
lesson I taught you well how to
transplant your new babies I feel like
there was not a lot of fluff or a lot of
BS to filter through I feel like a lot
of people can learn from this one and
that is the point so short and sweet
right to the point we served our purpose
I think Mike is on his way over so we
will record a long and rambly episode
that will make up for the short episode
I did today you guys I want to thank you
again for listening I would appreciate
it if you find me on all of the social
media you can find me on Facebook simply
search for the grow from your heart
podcast you can find me on Twitter it's
at g f YH podcast if you'd like to
follow my personal twitter feed it's at
Ross to Jeff 420 I also recommend you
follow my Instagram feed on Instagram I
use Irie underscore genetics I post a
lot of fine cannabis photography I like
to go on Instagram live and hang out I
answer questions I talk to my friends I
take dabs if you come on my Instagram
live feed and you ask a question there's
a very good chance I will answer your
question there on the Instagram live
feed so follow me once again it's Irie
underscore genetics on instagram if
you've got something you'd like to say
perhaps you'd like to sponsor the show
or maybe you've got a product
like me to review maybe you're not into
the social media you just want to say hi
you can reach out through email my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com you know I would love to
hear all of your feedback also don't
forget about the YouTube channel every
episode is now available on YouTube
simply search for the girl from your
heart podcast on YouTube
give us a subscribe leave me some
comments I would love your support on
the YouTube channel don't forget to
visit our sponsor the hell a dank seed
company you can find them at
www.stanford.edu mama hug for me