welcome to the show everybody it's time
for episode 366 of the girl from your
heart podcast this episode is brought to
you by our friends at the hella dank
seed company if you need new seeds for
your garden I highly recommend the hella
dank seed company and you can find them
at www.sedar.com bro
thanks man thanks for hanging out it's
kind of late thanks for being here yeah
man managed to sneak out and record a
show dude I'm glad you did not freeze to
death on the way here rusty calls
Colorado night
I hate being correct with predictions
but I always say that we have to arrange
our Halloween costumes around the first
snow before we do this was actually the
third snow but we totally got [ __ ]
weather and we got snow on Halloween no
in Colorado if you're gonna do a costume
you need a winter insulated backup or
just plan for that and then just maybe
you got to be sweaty all night inside it
it's hard to be Tinker Bell or something
like that yeah like [ __ ] nurse has a
[ __ ] night in Colorado every year
because it's 20 degrees here on
Halloween I'm glad that you went with
[ __ ] nurse is the next option of
costume choices it's like I live in a
nicer part of town like it's it's not as
jacked up as other parts like in other
parts of town I live we didn't expect
trick-or-treaters we didn't get none
didn't expect none everybody knew that
[ __ ] was coming and my new neighborhood
wouldn't like you expect
trick-or-treaters pretty heavy we saw
maybe six kids there was not much that
was cold and there was nothing yep
luckily I was Chewbacca and that is just
a giant furry body suit says were over
Oliver wearing a shag carpet bodysuit
but with a big giant mask that is
basically like wearing the IPM suit all
day well I was in a had a show that was
quite warm they were they were blowing
glass right next to the building so a
lot of those glassblowing heat was
coming and then they had live fire
spinners at the party I went to the
heaven hosted by elevate glass I wanted
to get out there was such a good time
you know my life listeners I do we do I
think we do you guys if you don't know
he's got two kids which means he's
pretty
at home yet the sneaking out to record a
podcast is the only interesting thing I
get to do that's not childcare related
well I'm glad you made it you have a
good Halloween bro since we're talking
about Halloween [ __ ] awesome little
kids and howl right yeah yeah that
Halloween smile is magical yeah and the
mall here does the thing for the kids
and there are a lot of people dressed up
in fun costumes tonight it was a good
time that is awesome I like that the
mall lets you go trick or treat
it's a really cool especially in
Colorado where your Halloween can be
miserable and you know 2530 degrees
that's no fun we're five year old and so
having a place to go where you can
trick-or-treat for an hour and not
freeze to death is nice I know that
you're fairly safe there aren't car is
gonna run the kids over there in the
mall that's a lot actually kid got hit
in the West tonight oh that's terrible
I saw that is right before I came over
here so let's put this podcast positive
no thanks Mike
happy Holi and everybody I hope you at a
safe Halloween I hope not never mind
it's gonna make an edibles joke but
we're not even gonna make that a
tasteless joke let's keep going um Mike
I'm going to give Mike some time to talk
about election stuff here in this
episode mike is here we'd like to talk
about politics we like to talk about
elections we like to talk about getting
people involved before I turn it over to
Mike and we start talking about
elections and politics I want to talk
about a recent visit to a hemp farm I
was asked to come visit a hemp farm and
do a little bit of consultation to help
with the project they have coming up I
probably shouldn't talk about their next
project but there is plenty of other
stuff I can talk about so this hemp farm
is huge dude have you ever been to a
legal Colorado hemp farm I've never been
to an illegal Colorado hemp farm either
I just know have farms for Mike I have
never thought of working or being
involved in a farm that large all the
plants are harvested in their outdoor
field but the field that you can't see
the end of it I was like hey I'm looking
for this guy and they're like he's way
out there at the end of the field and I
was like that's him like yeah he'll be
out here like twenty or thirty minutes
cuz it took him like twenty or thirty
minutes to walk from that field to where
I was basically he was way out there he
was only an inch tall from how far away
I could see him that field is huge
they've got a lot of plants out there
they have a lot of age
massive farms and it's kind of hidden
it's kind of camouflaged it's on a hill
to where if you're not looking for it
you wouldn't even know it's there you
can see the buildings and the
greenhouses and the farms but the
outdoor grow space is kind of tucked
down in tor when you're driving up on
the highway that takes you to it you
don't even see where the plants would be
it's kind of neat yeah so you've got a
bunch of gigantic plants out there
they've got several greenhouses they've
got several barns they have got more
plants in that facility the capability
of more plants in that facility then
probably ten of the indoor environments
that we use to run the the size and the
plant counts that have farms are nuts
like I've seen the some of the
background info and I followed this
stuff closely enough in the press that
you know you catch some of this
tangentially but the numbers you see
forever insane a lot of plants and they
were huge they had a lot of product I'm
not gonna say where I was so that I can
say more about what I saw I feel like I
can't do both I don't want to reveal
right you tell us about Bob's rice if
you don't name Bob yeah so I saw I don't
know what the names of these containers
are it looks like you took a mail
carriers bag so that like durable canvas
worked yeah yeah but it was the size
that you could put a Volkswagen Beetle
into it and they filled these canvas
bags with ground material ready to be
turned into CBD oils and concentrates to
go into SABS and rubs and tinctures and
lip balms and anything you can imagine
you could put cbn CBD in to apply to
your body they've got that sort of
delivery method I saw a whole bunch of
extraction equipment that is beyond
where I've even thought of they've got
their own lab testing in there they can
do national yeah they are trying to be
prepared for when things go there that's
their goal they told me they're ready
for when the FDA comes that they can
already pass FDA testing there's strong
odds that happens well before high tea
HC cannabis and we can get into sort of
what exactly is happening that's part of
the glaad you want to go that way
the odds are strong that the feds lay
off hemp in CBD long before they lay off
can
this is a hole even Paul Ryan if you
follow politics not a pro cannabis guide
not a liberal guy was just in the press
touting CBD and industrial have been
lamenting the fact that federal law
still prohibits just like its I THC
marijuana I agree with you that CBD will
be more acceptable legally before THC
because it already it is if you look at
the production facilities if you look at
the way it's done if we have more than
0.3 percent THC in our plant it is now
considered cannabis and it can't be
grown in a hemp farm and that's a legal
distinction here yes yes that's the
that's what declares the difference and
we're gonna talk more about that in a
minute one of the first things I noticed
I am from the commercial cannabis
environment the recreational and medical
cannabis environment where you have to
have a badge with a long extensive
background check you can renew your
stuff online by the way and it's super
simple I just did it it took me fifteen
minutes bro I read up right after they
instituted that process and in the
office they were like you're dumb
there's an easier way yeah well anyway
you can do it online you guys if you
need to renew your meed badge it's super
simple online you don't have to have the
form notarized and you don't need the
fingerprints unless you were going for
an Associated ki badge or higher if you
just have a basic ki badge the lady at
the meed told me I do not need a new
fingerprint card she told me to turn in
the application and if I need it they'll
email me and let me know what I need she
was just turn it in everybody has
problems
she seemed confident that nine out of
ten people are gonna have issues and she
has to call them back and it's no big
deal
she's like just turn it in so I want to
get back on track here uh so to work in
the Colorado Marijuana regulated
marijuana business you have to have a
marijuana Enforcement Division badge
which you have to have a federal
background check you have to do at least
one fingerprint thing you have to fill
out a bunch of paperwork and if you have
any legal background you have to clear
that up and prove the Colorado that
you're gonna be a good kid and you're
not gonna go crazy in the industry I
know I know people that had to drive
across the country and go to the
courthouse they got sentenced and in
pull paperwork by hand that said this
[ __ ] was adjudicated he completed
successfully
it's an actual thing it's a nightmare
applying for that badge sometimes some
of the people that are in the IMP
industry are there because they have
been blocked from the cannabis industry
because of their colored past they are
not a lot is colored past racist is that
rude I'm Trent
don't be politically correct checkered
past what do you say there check chaste
right yeah they can't be in the industry
because of their checkered past sorry if
anything I said came across as
politically incorrect I'm trying to be
accurate lately ah play the TBI code
real quick right yeah I hit my head one
day I get words continuing ah so it
listeners if you're if you're confused
about what the difference between like
marijuana haven't been cannabis are I
feel like this is the time in the show
or we should cover we're gonna get there
but I wanted I was teasing okay I was
really teasing about what we have to
have a badge to work there then the
facility has to be you have to check in
when you go into the facility you ring
the doorbell you can't get in you ring
the doorbell my car I runs to the door
like oh it's you do you have a reason to
be in here I've had building inspectors
a little surprised that they were having
to sign in and put on a lane you do this
care facility you can't just open my
door and run from a secure facility is
the greatest words you have to sign in
you have to show me your ID that says
who you are you have to sign in then I
give you a lanyard that says whatever
the name of my facility is then it says
visitor so let's say Mike and Jeff's Gro
visitor and you have this big thing and
somebody has to be with you the entire
time you have to be escorted in visual
sight also nothing can be visible in a
marijuana grow in a cannabis grow if you
drive by and you can see cannabis
through the fence they are in violation
that is completely illegal in a hemp
grow dude
just a fence she was like a six foot
tall fence and 12 foot tall plant it
depends on the county and if you can see
it that's a hard and fast store rule but
with some of the production facilities
especially here in public County we
allow outdoor cultivation there's
fencing rules but if you can see over
the fence that's not what the rules okay
these guys there are no Emmy deer
acquirements and a hemp farm is worth it
that's one thing I want to see in
practice no badges no badges at all
nobody had to have a badge there
there were no cameras that I saw and I'm
they're trying to say go do anything but
there are no cameras you're not so in a
meed
regulated facility you can't walk from
one part of the building to the other
and have any gaps where you are not seen
you have to be fully on camera at all
times so if you are wiping your nose
picking your nose scratching your butt
itch in your balls
your on-camera redundantly it's not in
this room you can oh there's a camera on
that wall it's there's a camera on every
wall and as you want yes it's the camera
with the meed requirements for legal
cannabis in Colorado it is it's over
it's overkill but so there are no
cameras and the fencing like I said was
minimal so it's really it's really like
a relaxed environment it's not as
uptight it doesn't feel so like crazy
and government regulate the same time
I've learned bro feeling who just came
from that industry and the rules that
the MU D has a swallowing of all like
watching them adjust to those was was
really funny if you didn't have to do
we're gonna have to no matter if we were
emmy deregulated or not we would have to
tag plants we would have to keep notes
if you didn't have to do anything
involving the meed how much time do you
think you would save in a day I mean it
depends on the size of the building but
I'm just thinking of the last facility
that we kind of ran together is we're
talking about several people that aren't
on the payroll right you could just use
several payroll there's an the other
outside consultant that helped with
compliance probably wouldn't even be
necessary there's at least three people
yeah it was right underneath you the guy
that was right me the guy that was right
underneath me and the two people right
above me just be gone because there's no
amed there's no I mean the two above you
were high salaried people yeah yeah like
when not super high but I mean decently
salaried people okay but yeah so we can
get rid of four employees - hourly yeah
one level one managerial and then two
not consulting I'm thinking about grow
team I mean do have farms need to weigh
their waste leaf know that do they need
to pulverize their garbage how many
hours did we kill on that shredder
I mean man-hours in the facility so just
to let you guys know what we're talking
about in the a minha mãe deregulated
facility after you harvest a plant
you've got all the sticks and stalks
they've got to go somewhere we can't
just throw it in the trash that the city
picks up or that a private company picks
up we've got to run it through a wood
chipper to make it unrecognizable so
that nobody can identify what it is or
was the MEP wants it into tiny little
pieces we would also run a bunch of old
leaves through that chipper because we
didn't have anywhere else to put them
and they had to be shredded and
destroyed we would send Brian out there
with a pack of cigarettes and a wood
chipper and he would honestly spend
Saturday every Saturday just chipping
that was his old job towards the end
there we had it on a rotation and I'm
trying to remember how often we had to
run it it was once or twice a week a
week for at least five or six hours a
sesh yeah yep because when I was before
we we doubled our production once you
get the boy originals you have the bags
of material out there you've got the
chipper that run in you got it it's all
fired up it's out of the trailer it's a
lot of work to do it so yeah wait and
that's not required on a hemp farm when
you start researching the different
applications for industrial hemp one of
the things that they're not real
explicit about out front when you're
learning about this is that you have to
pick one if you're growing four seed oil
production you you run your harvest one
kind of way you grow a certain variety
of hemp that produces heavily for what
you're seeking if you're looking to make
clothes from fiber different genus of
hemp both of those two different
varieties are gonna have very low
percent THC less than 0.3% but they're
gonna produce a very different looking
plant yep and
you're gonna need very different
equipment very different retail markets
I mean all of its different you can't
grow for fiber and for seed oil and for
replacement seed and hempcrete this farm
actually a I'm not gonna say who they
were people may figure it out but I can
I feel like I can talk more about their
business if I don't say who they are
what I said earlier they received a
delivery from another farm that they're
going to turn into products and as they
were breaking it up they discovered
seeds in it and they realized that they
have to pull out every seed because if
they leave the seeds in there it will
change the spectrum of the oil they're
creating yep yeah so that was that's one
of their levels of quality control that
they go through out there there's so
many different things that you can do
with an industrial hemp plant but the
the setup to get into it and get it up
and rolling is very intensive they've
got a really nice setup so ah
can you imagine farming cannabis on the
lake high THC herb on that scale bro I
would love it what's the difference
between producing high CBD flowers out
there and producing high THC flowers out
there other than a lab test and a
phenotype right you said earlier you
wanted to talk about what constitutes
and and what constitutes cannabis if you
drove up and you didn't know the
difference you couldn't tell the
difference in those plants by looking
they look just like ganja plants they
look just like high THC cannabis plants
that we grew in a facility together
there is no visual difference when you
smell them they do have a Cherry aroma
that since I'm experienced and I know
what I'm looking for I can identify that
as part of what comes with CBD but
visually there's no difference they are
structurally the same they flower just
the same the leaves they were flushing
one batch the leaves look just the same
there's no visual difference the only
thing that gives you in Colorado the
only thing that gives you a variance
between marijuana or cannabis and hemp
is that left is that lab test that's it
if it's if your plant has 0.3% THC or
higher it is considered marijuana or
cannabis
without that 3% you're now working with
legal hemp that's what I'm not entirely
sure that I had put two and two together
in my head that they're extracting the
CBD from the bud material just like we
do with THC exactly for some reason I
was thinking something out of the seed
oil I
I probably knew this I just didn't
realize it and put it together now
they're growing full-blown flowers out
there to finish to maturity and then
they run I don't want to give away I
don't but I don't know how they do it
exactly but I saw several different
extraction methods out there I saw large
batches of crude I saw batches of
distillate I saw crystalline they
explained a few different ways that they
do it they explain the ways that they
prefer to do it and there are optional
methods that they don't like to do but
they will because it's required
sometimes they've got their own lab test
to make sure that there is no THC in
there then they've got the capability to
remove the THC molecules from the
products are they the oils that they
make the extractions that they say
concessions was gonna be are they
working with any other cannabinoids is
they they're kind of banned from working
with THC above what point three percent
point three percent yeah they could work
with any of the others right well not
THC a but I mean I don't know the
legalities maybe they can work with CVG
or CC and I don't know the lessee I was
thinking yeah I'm cuz CBN's the next
people are thinking that one's the Hat
plays a big part in anti-inflammation
awesome I mean so there are a lot of
people looking for a high CB answer and
right that's a good good way to a good
way to keep down the inflammation and
combine that with the CBD it should work
very well so yeah I I think the only
difference that we have decided is that
point three test I'd keep going back to
that for some reason but that point
three makes it cannabis lessen that
makes it hemp so they look exactly the
same dude they run it like you were like
you were saying they make the
extractions just like they would if they
were gonna run a THD extraction it is
all the same except they're aiming for
just a pure CBD product and no THC so
that is kind of a good section to segue
into my next to note my next note says
him CBD is
there are some people in the cannabis
community the recreational and/or the
medical community that will argue that
hemp derived CBD is less quality or
what's the word inferior to cannabis
derived CBD can you back me up and
saying that that's the same molecule and
then there is a very valid arguments we
made that knowing and trusting your CBD
supplier right now is crucial because
the place you just toured isn't the only
place producing CBD right now absolutely
there are countless places around the
u.s. in the different in [ __ ] there's
probably 12 or 15 different states that
I have a half industry right now on some
scale or another and there's countless
CBD producers that are producing god
only knows what and slapping CBD on the
label there's also Chinese CBD yep and
then there's stuff coming in from around
the globe and just some of these places
just right CBD on fish oil yeah yeah I
talked about that in another episode
other places your legitly getting
exactly what's on the label but
distinguishing the two is not something
everyone's capable of right some people
will believe in the placebo keep buying
it but buying Sam derived CBD from a
trusted supplier and buying CBD that's
been extracted from high THC cannabis
varieties there's no difference in those
CBDs other than one of them was grown in
a flower where it was in a higher
concentration and one of them was grown
at a flower with a lower concentration
they were both extracted to whatever
concentration the extractor wanted it's
it's just where they're getting their
source material that's part of the
reason CBD is so expensive in the
medical and recreational markets is
because they're growing high THC plants
and trying to extract the 1% of CBD into
a whole gram jar takes 4 [ __ ]
there was a big push from the I mean
when I say established industry at this
point in time then weren't much more
established than like your local hot dog
vendor but the established industry at
the time when Colorado first was like
well [ __ ] we might as well write the
hemp rules that were forced to write by
amendment six before we'll go ahead and
write those this next year when they
started to do that the medical industry
that have been around for a minute in
the emerging rec market were like yeah
it's totally different it's totally
different molecule it's totally
different you need to buy your [ __ ] off
our shelves still everybody got scared
it's not at all the same and that
argument flare back up big time when
that the FDA had to send warning letters
to some of the Chinese imports saying
knock that [ __ ] off and knock it off
with the bogus health claims you can't
prove I'm gonna heat myself up a DAB I'm
gonna take a dab of high THC medicine I
have got a high THC or if you would like
a high CBD dab I've got that to offer
you as well since we've been talking
about CBD so much I don't prefer to
consume CBD myself I would offer that to
you then once we take these dabs Mike
we've been going for quite a while so we
should wrap up this hemp farm talk and
we should start talking about all of the
political activism that you bring to the
table just before we close up I'm a
little jealous I'd like to go see huge
hemp farm I'm having fun picking it
apart in my head right now
well I'll be doing consulting for them
so maybe I'll just take you out there
and say that you're my assistant one of
these days you just carry on looking
right down weird [ __ ] just draw pictures
or weird stuff yeah just carry figure
out something I should there's high
likely that I'll go see you girl
tomorrow but it's not a hemp girl what
do you need an assistant I'm gonna hit
this dad I'm going to dab some copper
chem from green dot labs it's the copper
chem full-spectrum extract it is chem
foreign star Dawg the label says
perfumey chem assorted fruit bonbons I
don't get that I get fuel and funk so
I'm gonna hit it and enjoy the spikes it
smells like gas and all
fruit to me but that's a good thing I
don't its I wouldn't take that as a good
thing but I fully think it is while
you're hitting that davits dive into
election stuff ready for some politics
listeners go hit something on now finish
this data Jeff's real quick yeah I did
definitely didn't take all that so choke
if this episode drops on the night we
think it will do you never know I can
make that happen um we know a guy this
will drop Monday before Tuesday's
election hopefully everybody listening
is registered to vote hopefully most of
the people listening have taken
advantage of early voting in some
fashion in Colorado it's all mail-in
elections now it's so super easy your
register to vote when you do your
driver's license [ __ ] shows up with your
house you fill it out you drop it off or
mail it back in couldn't be easier but
uh cannabis is on the ballot in several
states including Colorado I just wanted
to take a minute on today's show to
encourage everybody regardless of which
way you lead in the political spectrum
to vote super important that people vote
we would not be led by an angry orange
cheeto if more people voted like over
half the country doesn't vote every
election and that just drives me insane
and it's not like half the country as
felonies and can't half the country
decides it's unimportant of their vote
doesn't matter right they come up with
some other lame-ass excuse to dodge it
and then we end up with [ __ ] who
want to be [ __ ] getting to make all
the rules
a lot of people say well my vote doesn't
matter then let me have it but the thing
is you got to go do it for me yeah you
say that like just listen to Mike and I
and we'll we want your vote your vote
matters to us so just do that for us
even if you're not doing it for you in
my younger years fine non-parent years I
would identify the people in my
immediate social circle who we're gonna
come up with one of those ideas and I
just show up on Election Day amulet
what up Jeff what are you doing today
let's fill out that ballot nice alright
get in the car
it's going to the polling place just
like the second thing we got over the
the social pleasantries when you got
here like hey buddy how's life I'm like
how are the guests really have you voted
did you fill out your ballot yet you
totally got on me and I'm like sorry
Mike there's one or two I'm still
thinking about do they word things so
backwards for you have to google at all
just so you know you don't vote against
yourself one of the things I love about
the mail ballot or the mail and election
is you've got your ballot at home for
like a month you've got all the time in
the world to sit down and go okay what
is amendment one do I agree or not agree
okay what's amendment two what does
billy-bob what has he ever done for
Colorado should I vote for him or should
I vote for [ __ ] Jimmy Bob yeah like
you can go through and check all of it
and there's no rush there's not some old
lady in line behind you you're not
trying to get to work in a minute or
trying to get home from work you can
just do it in your off time at home it's
so nice yeah that's but if you don't
live in one of those states you can look
everything that's gonna be up on your
ballot online you can see a picture of
your ballot how it's gonna look when you
get into the voting booth and there's
nothing that says you can't take a cheat
sheet that says I want to vote this
person for governor this person for
treasurer against a minute why can you
take your phone in there yeah employer
you just write yourself a note yep you
could totally do it no it's in your
phone yourself a note so did you have it
in your phone accessible we all know
where the text messages already open
that read the text from yourself and it
says vote for this guy for governor this
guy for a mayor and when I first started
doing this like you just had to know
yeah and he'd get in there and he'd have
the little quarter paragraph of legalese
and tiny type and you had to try to
figure out is so much easier now yeah
but uh I can't stress this enough
there's at least 30 million cannabis
consumers in the u.s. at least minimum
and these are a couple of times a year
or more people and if you look at the
hard data like twenty plus million of
them are more like you and me than
they'd like to admit to their parents or
authority figure like their boss right
but we don't have any political clout
anywhere until very recently and it's
still pretty Pitt Lee um what do you
think of a group like the NRA like them
or hate them they run politics if you
come out against something therefore
you're gonna face endless attack ads you
know it's coming it's a [ __ ] show you
don't want to get involved in different
politics they've got four million
members four as in one two three stop
counting cannabis consumers thirty
million compared to four and if you look
at our influence abilities those numbers
reversed because they vote and they make
sure everybody knows they vote and
they're really happy to be like United
yesterday about it you know I'm gonna do
tomorrow and vote again in a different
election when it's legal I'm not double
voting because that'd be bad but every
election um Colorado does the thing now
where I got it a couple elections ago I
got a thing after the election that was
like seven in a row buddy good job nice
and I was like that's a nice little
attaboy from our county clerk but shout
out to Bell it's uh do voting's pretty
easy even if you don't know anything
about politics you've never seen your
ballot you don't watch the commercials
you're clueless if you want to vote in
this election and you want to do it in a
way that's not idiotic and you want to
be a little informed about it you're
looking at half an hour with your smart
phone from going from totally uninformed
never heard of any of these people or
any of these issues to fully understand
what I'm voting for and why I'm voting
the way I'm voting you're looking at 30
minutes tops
and it's worth it it's very very much
worth it if you're listening from
Prohibition land and you wonder how we
got here we got here cuz we convinced
owners to vote and we convinced our
friends and family to vote with us by
talking to him about politics over
dinner which was uncomfortable just like
you think it's gonna be but this stuff's
really really really important and the
thing that drives me nuts about our
community is we've gotten really close
to federal legalization a couple of
times and the not so distant past we're
really close in 69 we were close again
in 71 we were close again in 96 and like
the community doesn't come together for
anything other than a concert and or or
a cannabis cup right a party or an event
but if we came together even a little
bit for a couple of elections in a row
we would run the country top to bottom
coast to coast
we'd be unparalleled with our ability to
fundraise and message distribute so how
much of it is people being afraid to
stand up for something that could get
them in trouble and how much of it do
you think is just lack of participation
because laziness or whatever reason
excuse it's just there's so many people
there's actually a huge chunk of
politics is convincing you voting this
pointless if I can convince you not to
vote my vote doubles in impact right
every person I convince not to vote I
get their power and once you convince
someone not to vote building that into a
habit is super easy
I don't shitload of people they're like
no one vote never changed anything or
it's all rigged there's only two parties
like I still run into people to think
Hillary and Trump were the same and if
even if you don't pay attention to
politics it should be [ __ ] obvious by
now
that [ __ ] would be different today if we
had gone a different way as a country
but well I'm a comedy fan so it's
working out pretty well for me that
we've got [ __ ] cheeto Bandito is our
president if we could just get even a
little bit of the community focused
enough to regularly vote in C I'm
encouraging you to vote if you're voting
against me I want everybody to vote just
participate cuz right now the people
that vote are angry and afraid in those
two things those two emotions don't lead
to rational decision-making most of the
people listening are probably they would
agree with us politically I would like
to imagine I either I'm not gonna get a
lot of super consumer thing be on your
side be cannibals do your thing love it
how you want we've got a worldwide who
knows but but a lot of us did not vote
and look what happened
yep in the cannabis community not voting
our is why cannabis is still illegal if
you don't vote for local people your
local rules always get chosen by people
who don't agree with you if you don't
vote for statewide elections the
statewide rules get created by people
who don't agree with you if you don't
vote in national elections it's the same
[ __ ] and I understand that one person in
Alabama doesn't feel like their vote
isn't gonna have the same kind of impact
that it would elsewhere or it's not
gonna sway anything or change anything
but literally every single vote does
matter and does change that mentality
seems to hover in a group it'll be like
the whole whatever it's by design Jeff
and his crew none of them are gonna go
vote they were all talking about it in
school look one guy can convince Jeff
and his crew hey you've got six people
that are all like minded that you're
gonna go vote the same way so that's
actually six votes that you were just
all gonna throw away so if you can
convince those people that are the throw
away I'm not gonna vote if you can
convince the leader of that so
grouping it a whole bunch of them to go
all votes getting people not to vote is
by design and depending on where you are
the design may look a little different
but there's a reason there's deadlines
for registering to vote yeah
and for some of these this was months
for some states as four months ago other
states you can register day of some
states you need two forms of state
issued ID other states you don't need
any ID
some states depending on what your
felony crime was you automatically get
your voting rights back the second your
your case is completed you don't get to
vote for the five years or you're on
parole or the three years you're
incarcerated but once all that's done
you're just a regular free person who
did some time and is now a free free you
get your voting rights back in other
states you never get them back at all or
you have to go through a long insane
process or a long insane process that is
also a hundred percent arbitrary if you
don't watch last week tonight with John
Oliver listeners you should he did a
great episode on some of this voting
rights stuff not too long ago but if the
fact that there are people spending
millions of dollars to convince you not
to vote because you're young and you
like cannabis doesn't that make you want
to go vote they're spending fortunes to
convince poor people and minorities if
you're a member of anything that can be
considered as subculture they don't want
you to vote because the odds are you're
gonna vote in your interests and not
theirs
and they don't want that it's been this
messaging has been so effective in
different communities and the cannabis
community got hit hard with it and the
was the tune in drop out or whatever
[ __ ] on drop out yeah culture um that
got taken way too far and even people
that are like more like me
you took a part of that to heart like I
remember a part of that of fighting it
when I was in college like I know that I
should vote and voting is important and
I should pay attention to politics but
[ __ ] you I don't want to be any part of
the system when I was younger I thought
it was stupid I thought it was waste of
time to go vote my friends would go vote
they'd come back from from school or
from launch and they'd have that I voted
sticker and I'm like yeah you wasted
your lunch I drove Ronen [ __ ] smoke
balls in the car and like I thought it
was just a dumb thing now that I am old
enough to see the effects that the
elections have either small or large
elections local or national I feel like
I may have wasted a lot of opportunity
by not voting when I was younger there
were probably several years of my life
that I skipped voting there were a
number of important elections where we
could use your vote bro yeah probably
but none of this has to stay true this
November 7th
we could see massive cannabis turnout we
have seen that across the country during
recent elections where one side or the
other really goes for the cannabis vote
knowing that it's gonna bring out young
more than likely liberal voters and it's
worked for some places it hasn't worked
in others like Platteville County the
last election of 2016 we like to Trump
we went for keeping the marijuana
industry and for Trump and there were a
bunch of places around the country that
went for Trump and for cannabis and
watching the pundits the day after the
election like so we don't know what the
[ __ ] happened yeah but this is the
results they it was fun to watch but at
the same time a little bit terrifying
and this election kinda has the same
feel to it like there's a lot of a lot
of important [ __ ] on the ballot right
all right North Dakota and I think
Michigan are both voting on legalization
I haven't seen much from the pro
legalization campaigns in those states
I've seen a lot from the anti cannabis
legalization groups in those states part
of that who I follow not the messaging
on the ground but
just to two states and there's at least
and voting on cannabis right now
Colorado's got a hemp hemp amendment X
um which is kind of sketchy I definitely
encourage people who haven't already
voted in Colorado to really look at
amendment acts before choosing yes or no
yeah there's a lot of important [ __ ] on
your about not just marijuana stuff
politicians too I received and I want to
actually give a shout-out to a
politician for the first time ever on
this show um and I don't this isn't
quite an endorsement
although cannabis community that
candidate I'm about to mention is very
Pro cannabis and his opponent is very
anti cannabis but jared polis of
Colorado who's currently a senator and
running for governor
I got a mailer two days ago one side of
it is just a pretty nug like it needed
to be trimmed but it was just a nice nug
on a high-gloss print just bright out of
fine high time fat but a we just won for
that bud that needed some sizzle oh
that's pretty cool
and on the other side it had it outlined
his pro cannabis stance and views for
the state I apologize if you guys can
hear the dab torch I'm heating up the
nail for Mike to hit this CBD about for
him and then we're gonna start wrapping
up man I'm [ __ ] 36 I never thought
I'd see that we're a serious candidate
for governor not a fringe candidate not
a green party candidate but like one of
the two who was going to get it would
put out something that pro cannabis
latent ly yes bliss Utley I mean he was
pretty Pro cannabis for his last Senate
run I never saw anything yes even a
little bit that was a big plan Wow yeah
this is your friendly reminder that
smoke burns ladies and gentlemen smoke
will burn whoa what smoke will burn that
was the leftover oil in that nail from
not burning the dad last time from being
a little bit too cool sorry all speaking
to the microphone like a damn podcaster
here Michael expiry listeners for those
you aren't psychic and didn't see what
we just saw I'm just heating the dab now
and my weak lungs took a cool dab last
time and left some residue in the Banger
I'm gonna grab the other torch he keep
talking it's within regencies it up it
produced a little cloud of smoke when he
moved that torch up a little bit the
flame hit the smoke and produced the
fireball the size of his dreadknight
smoke does burn ladies and gentlemen
there's also a reminder to keep a spare
dab torch or an extra can of tan around
whenever you're dabbing you're never
gonna never know when the torch is gonna
die that torch just quit lighting on me
I was braggin on it the other day said
how good it is and I just took a boo-boo
so we got to use the back-up plan I made
that mistake with the wife the other
night I told us man it's been three
nights in a row one of the kids slept
all the way through oh yeah so homie was
up twice that night probably within 5
minutes - you saying that that's just
the way it goes like an hour and a half
after I said it and then again at 5:30
in the morning when this nail is hot
you've got about 50 seconds to give us
your final thoughts anything else for
the podcast now's your chance
you know vote vote if you if you don't
get a chance to vote this election you
should feel like a piece of [ __ ] for
like at least three hours and then you
can let that go but get registered to
vote if you're not registered to vote
it's super simple to do google it you
can probably do it online if not a
15-minute visit to the DMV in your area
get it cleared up in most places unless
you're black in the south bro should I
edit that out no that's true okay there
are huge portions of the country that
make it super hard for different groups
to vote yeah that's true I don't at all
mind somebody coming to me in five years
being like do you remember you said it
was hard for black people vote now Obama
like no it's just true the [ __ ] thing
um yeah if you feel like yelling at me
for that it's at Nemo 15 on Twitter well
that's cool that's we're gonna be one of
the next things
Mike's gonna take a DAB make sure you
follow Mike on all the social media
he is Pueblo for sensible cannabis
cannabis laws not cannibal los pueblos
for sensible cannabis laws that's a big
difference that cannibal laws important
distinct two different totally different
group
don't follow this is delicious that's uh
mostly CBD don't follow the cannibal
well you do do follow the cannibal group
if that's your thing I'm trying not to
be judgmental I'm trying to embrace
everybody I don't think there's a Pueblo
for sensible cannibal laws but I'm kind
of wanting to start it now that would be
a fun troll but anyway support Mike's
Facebook group level for sensible
cannabis laws it's much more appetizing
it's not as awkward to follow I also
follow him I'm gonna leave his mic on so
you can hear him cough over there follow
him on the Twitter he's at an emo Punk
15 he is getting cross-eyed and small
tears I said I can't focus them and did
little eye movements superstar eyes hey
Mike thanks for hanging out good you've
got headphones and a microphone and that
CBD cherry flavor it's just phenomenal
I'm glad I thought of giving you a dab
of that oh you guys listeners thank you
for listening this long we really
appreciate it yes thanks for hanging out
it's been 45 minutes if you're still
listening we totally appreciate it
hashtag they like it when we ramble and
it'll be a couple days before I get back
over here again so there's definitely
more grow lessons coming after this
episode yeah we're gonna put a lot of
grow lessons up if you guys have been
following the show I've been doing a
long series of grow lessons thanks for
letting me take a break on those things
we'll let Mike hang out for a minute the
lessons will be back on the next episode
I know I've made promises and set
expectations and I will meet those
expectations for you thanks for
listening you guys um I think that's
pretty much what we've got the hemp farm
was cool the only difference between
hemp and cannabis basically in Colorado
is a lab test hemp CBD is CBD that works
with acting like quit pooh-poohing hemp
CBD it's great medicine for people who
are in need it's affordable and it's
reliable the vote get off your ass and
vote even if you're gonna vote against
us participate just get out there and do
it it's it's so important that everybody
votes
yeah just votes ridiculously important I
think that's all we got for today Mike
is that it that's it all right I would
appreciate it if you find me on the
social media you can find the podcast
it's at g f YH podcast on twitter you
can find me on twitter at Rasta Jeff
4/20 I think you would enjoy it if you
follow my Instagram feed it's ireon derp
scored
genetics I RIE underscore genetics on
Instagram check out my fine cannabis
photography and check out my Instagram
live videos also if you feel like this
podcast was educational informative or
entertaining and you'd like to make a
financial contribution to the show you
can do so by going to patreon.com
your heart it's patr yo n.com slash grow
from your heart all the information you
need to become a patron will be there on
the screen learn how to contribute to
the show learn how to support our
efforts in keeping the podcast coming to
you for free I don't have any notes
written down so I think that's all I'm
supposed to say here at the end of the
show thank you guys for listening oh and
make sure you support the hella dank
seed company you can find them at dank
seed dot store there are a few grow from
your heart podcast t-shirts available on
the website you guys the website is not
completely updated but it is functional
and that's the point at this time if you
go to I read genetics Colorado com click
on the website go to the higher e store
you will be able to find the growth from
your heart podcasts t-shirts there are
several other items on there some of
them are not available at this time many
of them are I'm working on replenishing
the stock at this time but if you're
interested in the shirt that's where you
go get them so please support the
podcast in all of the ways that you can
you guys thank you for listening
that's enough rambling out of me I want
to give a huge huge shout out to my
friend non-toxic yogi and until next
time take a phat dab and give your mom a
hug for me