hey welcome to the show everybody it's
time for episode 367 of the Grove from
your heart podcast this episode is
brought to you by the hell a dank seed
company if you need new seeds for your
garden I highly recommend the hella dank
seed company and you can find them at
www.ge.com to day I've been taking dabs
of screaming watermelon from viola and
when my guests showed up we took a few
dabs of the copper Kim from Green Dot
labs I've already hinted that this
episode will have a guest I know a lot
of you are looking forward to the grow
lessons I promise you that the next
episode
we will get back on the grow less ins
mic was available to record I had to
take that opportunity Jessie was
available to record I had to take the
opportunity I do like having great
guests on the show even if it does kind
of disrupt the flow of the lessons and I
think you guys will enjoy this podcast
so ladies and gentlemen with no further
ado let's welcome Jessie to the show all
right podcast world welcome back to the
show I am here with Jessie welcome to
the show my friend hey what's up thanks
for having me and thanks for hanging out
thanks for taking time out of your busy
life we're talking about I think you
said you had a staff of 15 people you're
in charge of now no at one point okay
all right all right we're still a busy
man yes thanks for coming and hanging
out taking time out of the day out of
the evening you bet it's getting cold
man how are you running outdoor grows in
this cold that's the most challenging
part well the place I work at the
greenhouse though you put a roof and
some walls on it yeah nice and easy all
right guys
Jessie is here because a lot of people
on social media have been asking him to
come back on the show and talk about
no-till beds so we're going to talk
about no-till you just want to jump
right into it bro sure cool
first of all maybe we should explain
what no-till is let's talk about maybe
what no-till is and how it varies from a
lot of the traditional methods that I
talked about and how most people are
taught how to well maybe not how most
people are taught to do if they're
taught if they're on a farm or if they
live in a way they were probably taught
no-till no-till in the cannabis industry
that turn gets confused so much
it's yeah there's a big misunderstanding
about it
no-till in real big AG is completely
different practices than then raised
beds and whatnot but not to knock you
know what we're doing it's just a
misunderstanding of the term okay
also permaculture that's one it's yeah I
see permaculture get just tagged on all
kinds of stuff that isn't permaculture I
think for a while I was using
permaculture wrong I think Ted Hussey is
the only person that actually
understands what permaculture yeah yeah
it's it's a design plan it's a way to
work a piece of land you know it's not
really something you know pull off in
your basement okay um you know it's it's
a whole practice
yeah she's got farming chessboard
essentially yeah yeah and I slightly
understand it from because of that but
yeah yeah it just biggest msconfig
that people are chiming in most of my
people they listen I have taught them to
grow with bottled nutrients because
that's what I'm mostly familiar with so
we need to tell them kind of what
no-till is and how it's different from
grown with the bottle of nutrients so
from what I see mostly in cannabis a
no-till
cannabis bed seems to be a raised bed
with a large amount of soil in it that
is you know good amended organic soil
okay and it you know it's it's awesome
what it is says you know it's no-till so
[Music]
tilling is not really something I think
a lot of pot growers actually do with
the rototiller you know I think a pot
growers version of tilling is to dump it
out buy new yeah finds a way somewhere
to get rid of all of this and then buy
brand new at the store is our version
for sure
so to me
what I see it means that they're reusing
their soil so they're you know they're
they're doing things to build soil you
know to protect it with cover crops
chopping chop and drop having worms in
there eating stuff you know all kinds of
biology in the soil not feeding it
bottled nutrients and you know top
dressing with amendments compost you
know feeding compost teas you know so
that's what I see
no-till is in cannabis okay but this
gives me a good start of places to ask
questions it sounds like it all starts
with our no-till bed and can we also do
this in large pots for sure I recommend
the beds it seems to be like what you
talked about a lot and that seems to be
what the people on Instagram are asking
about - yeah the bigger amount of the
you know the larger amount of soil you
can work with the better it's gonna work
trying to create in life so you need
more space for more life the more stuff
the more activity the more space more
life right for sure and I mean honestly
you could even apply these practices
directly to the ground - in ground
planted stuff and and honestly that's
where you're gonna make the most impact
as far as like restoring restoring soil
in this earth right you know long-term
okay so end of the world scenario this
would be the way to go for sure all
right
yeah you seem like the type of guy to
build your own raised beds definitely so
we've get out of the you know everything
I'm talking about pretty much is
representing the project that we got
going on it might work right now okay
so we've built their 5 by 8 and 5 by 16
linked beds out of two by eights
there's 16 inches deep so sure no my bad
hey they're not two by eights they're
two by two by twelves okay so yeah
pretty sturdy there yeah 24 inches deep
but it's just a basic box built out of
wood you know
square box things are they on wheels are
they stuck in place no no they're on the
ground okay so we covered the bottom
with the weed fabric to keep the soil
from running and falling out yeah
just stable with it to the inside of the
bed filled with our soil and rock and
roll basically just made a big wood pot
and made the use the weed film as the
bottom of the pot right easy enough
fill that up with your awesome soil yeah
do you recommend a certain type of soil
is there something that if they're gonna
go shopping or if they're gonna make a
shopping list certain kind they can put
on there just to make it easy for
themselves I mean get to get the best
you can you want something with a lot of
organic matter in it you know for a long
term and yep just just get the best soil
you can I mention that's a perfect I try
to avoid brand names unless there's
somebody that yeah that I really
recommend okay so we've got a raised bed
we've got a 5 by 8 or a 5 by 16 you guys
you can make whatever size raised beds
work well for you I saw a guy on social
media who is a smaller fella and he has
made some raised beds that are actually
5 by 5 by 5 but he put a little Inlet in
the middle so he can walk into the
middle of it because he can't reach to
work canopy and stuff he decided and he
can fit them together like Tetris pieces
yeah so it looks pretty nice and his bro
set up but they're on wheels also so you
can make whatever size and shape raised
beds you like you can do it in pots you
can do it in small pots you can do it in
large pots well we're gonna talk about
is mostly going to be in these raised
beds so we've got the bottom in there
we've got soil in there what else are we
going to put into our no-till mix what
kind of amendments are we gonna add in I
mean what we did is we just we use a dry
powder nutrient that before we were
every week when we were amending so old
toil at the end of a cycle you know you
dump it out of the bags we'd have more
compost and more of our powder nutrient
okay so we just we started with that
basic mix that we use of you know it's
like a five for two nutrient you know
once I'm not gonna mention names but
it's just
it's like kelp and [ __ ] crab shell
mill and that's what I'm looking for as
a Gill crab shell so we just use an
all-in-one you know just to agricultural
nutrients okay so there's something
that's available if they do a little
research they'll probably find that
product you're talking about
definitely yeah it's a it's got kelp
meal there's crab meal
there's azomite in there would you add
some worm castings there's that included
in this product no no so I would also
add you know we normally do probably
like a quarter yard of compost or worm
castings every week you know so you know
I'm talking about a like a 20 yard pile
of soil here so I think no no I'm
definitely talking about a 20 yard Bell
soil so we're adding in more like the
yard I'm gonna come Otacon this is stuff
you know it's been getting this week
after week after week so leave for some
room in your no-till bed you guys
because you're gonna need to top dress
and you're gonna be adding stuff in
there but at the same time the plants
are gonna eat that up so some of its
gonna go some of its gonna add in
believe some room don't fill all the way
up to the top I never recommend you fill
your pots all the way to the top anyway
you want water room you want more ahead
in space should you meet it so don't go
all the way to the top and you're
filling your raised beds so we've got
some compost we've got some worm
castings we've got this agricultural mix
or you can get the independent blends of
crab meal kelp meal blood meal fish meal
bone meal whatever you want to put in
there
boy stur shell meal you can add all
these other things to your mix at your
discretion if you would like you can
find tons of recipes online for making a
no-till bed i think bill the soil will
have a great recipe I'm pretty sure
Clackamas coop probably has some recipes
available you can design your own recipe
we're gonna leave a little work up to
you but we're gonna give you a good
guideline on how to do this I'm not
gonna point you in all the product
directions but we'll give you a pretty
good guideline don't get caught up with
trendy stuff it's it's not the the name
of the label of the product that makes
this work so I've noticed when you go to
the farm store and the big horticultural
store well that worked out hard there
aren't really cool logos on the products
there's no pretty babes on the
advertising it is a white van
and it says like potassium phosphate
that's what's in that bag it's not a
bunch of water and a bunch of other [ __ ]
so yeah don't be sold on trendy names
don't be sold on advertising don't worry
about that
get the things that we need for the
garden you want the these are what the
people who before they were farming to
survive before they ever had cool
labeling and these are the products that
the farmers are using so and farmers are
farming to survive they've got much more
on the line than a cannabis grower oh
yeah they're feeding the country you
know yeah yeah yeah but yeah I mean the
the I feel like the amount of soil that
you have is more important than then
what you put in it as long as it's well
amended okay um and end your compost is
key get the best compost or worm
castings you can find there you go the
best worm castings you can find but try
to find a local worm casting company so
they're nice and fresh they're nice and
alive
you should find a couple of live worms
in your castings if you've got a quality
company there will be worms in there
they'll still be wiggling around when
they get to you so we've got a basic
idea of what goes into our mix does this
need any cook time yes and no okay I
mean I yeah if you can let it let it
chill for a couple weeks
keep it well watered but you don't have
to I mean you throw plants right in here
and then it's gonna start doing its
thing and one of the things I hear about
no-till is it gets better every single
time in theory in theory if you do if we
do it correctly we should get better
every time okay so the first time we can
let it cook for a couple of weeks or we
can mix up our no-till bed and we can
throw our plants in on day one now if
we'd like to yeah okay we have we didn't
have any results
we're not the one of the main
differences here is we're not gonna
force-feed these plants like we would be
with bottles but the bottles you're kind
of force-feeding they don't get to
decide what they take in because
everything's been buffered and chelated
here it's organic the roots run around
they go huh oh look nitrogen I'm gonna
eat up some of that phosphorus cool I
don't need me so much phosphorus hey
guys do we need potassium up there no
we're good on potassium let's just
this nitrogen for now guys believe that
potassium behind we know it's here we
can come get that when we need it the
plant eats it will when you're feeding
it bottled nutrients you're basically
going eat [ __ ] and you're forced
feeding it
it's got eat what you feed it that's how
you get those burns so sounds like we'll
be safe just going right into our
no-till soil mix just don't amend it so
much that it would heat up you know so
with no-till you know you just were
constantly topdressing
we talked to us those beds at work every
other week so I think I may have been
going into this thinking it's too much
like a super soil in the beginning I
need to back my brain out of the super
soil idea and not put so much in in the
beginning and just going definitely okay
all right so I was thinking sort of a
wrong direction with this I had to
correct my thought process and I think I
just realized that the super soil I was
combining no-till and super sorry I mean
you could start with well I wouldn't
start with the de su personal recipe but
that's another term that has been
diluted so I you know back in the day
super soil mint sub cool but now super
soil could mean a hundred different
[ __ ] alright I've seen so many things
advertised as super soil and you know
it's just is so is confusing okay so
I've got to get my brain out of the idea
of thinking that this was similar to
building a that you premix and then you
just water basically till the end yeah
we're gonna be more amending and top
dressing to keep this going and keeping
it fresh for sure
okay let's that correct my thought
process and they'll change my line of
questioning for you a little bit too
awesome alright so you guys we all
learned something today that's the fun
of this podcast so I like the the beds
that we have at work that have been on
the steady top dressing regimen you can
dig down into the top just a little bit
and there are just millions of [ __ ]
worms that's eating that [ __ ] up yeah
[ __ ] and if you look underneath the
worms a little bit it's [ __ ] worm
castings I mean it's like a goddamn
[ __ ] worm casting Factory okay it's
it's amazing man it's I've never done
no-till with this success or on this
level before
every day I go in I'm just like [ __ ]
what am I gonna see today it's [ __ ]
exhaust man
and there's awesome diggity mushrooms
that grow out of it no no yeah no yeah
but maybe in the future you grabbed his
phone when I said that with excitement
that was cool
I don't have that type of charger yeah
it's even if you did I love when
companies do that now you have to buy
new [ __ ] alright so we've got an idea
what goes in at first we don't have to
cook it we can throw some plants in
there now let's talk about these things
we keep talking about should we go over
a cover crop or top dressing first oh
wow he's showing me the mycelium layer
is that alfalfa or clover growing there
that's clover he's got clover growing
out of the soil here he's got some stuff
that is sprouted there are things that
are ready to sprout so that's like
malted barley and the the mycelium just
grows off the valley and if you lift up
that barley there's just like all kinds
of little baby worms in there that's
amazing on his phone I think the area
that I can see is about a foot by a foot
square probably and there is a small
environment that is a life cycle
happening on that little photo yeah you
could take that somewhere and create
life if you took that to a planet you'd
have existence on that planet in a few
weeks
yes I totally would I'm all looking at
it think think that kind of [ __ ] yeah
that's I think that's where the weed
grows the people that think about little
microorganisms that's just where we've
gone now we've grown so much like oh
there's so much life right there yeah I
love it
our friend frosty would say life bro I
love it just so much like think of the
dude from Jurassic burg life always all
right should we talk about cover crop or
tea first
or top dress cover crop there are some
mainstream popular cover crop blends and
I don't like any of them they they have
plants in them that in my opinion don't
really work well with indoor cannabis or
greenhouse Canada
so currently I'm just using a white
Dutch clover okay clover at the
agricultural store by the pound I mean
yeah it looks like it works like four
bucks of pounders it looks like it's
working hey just sprinkle that in there
and it grows naturally out of the top as
you water in it falls in and works like
nature works definitely again right
before harvest we chop it and we mulch
the bed with it and I guess chill for a
week for him to come up eat it we put
the barley into the the Bart the malted
barley powder is like warm magnet
wherever we put it worm show up so
that's awesome yeah it's [ __ ] it's so
rad sprinkle some of that in and watch
the worms come do their work yep and
then it also grows the mycelium yeah and
it breaks down that waste to just I mean
I know these are just indoor beds but
we're literally building topsoil yeah
the picture you showed me is better than
any soil you can buy yeah okay anything
like that that's that looks like it but
the little area by the park about 20
feet away from where the little stream
runs through it's got that real moist
soil is soil kind of area it's getting a
little funk on it's kind of swampy
that's what you've built right there is
that type of environment so we haven't
made a lot of it yet but we're actually
making our own compost on-site out of
just chicken [ __ ] and cannabis waste
awesome I made about a half yard so I
think I saw a picture of it it really I
saw you looming through it and looked
really fluffy and it's everything that
we've put it on just yeah it's I love
your farm style yeah it's so far from
how I learned and how I was taught it's
fascinating to me I understand it but
I'm still like wow I want to play that
way just so far from all of every like
just how I learned you know I've learned
with bottles and I was taught with
bottle I mean tozai yeah it's like
leaving karate school and going to
jiu-jitsu after all around on the ground
this sucks
can't breathe all right so how about a
so we've got a little white some Dutch
white clover
we've got some malted barley
just sprinkle in that and there how
often do we want to do that about once a
week malted barley well the the clove
replant that once okay
I recommend well not just once but like
once per cycle okay once per cycle so I
recommend just planning it after you
then plant your your cannabis plants
okay so it'll just fill it around it
yeah yeah alright and you know look for
other plants you're interested in
growing and if you got a big enough
container to fit them in there man it's
this is a random question since we're
adding cover crop but we're also adding
we're adding cover so we're shading the
topsoil we're creating a little layer
we're also adding more plants that are
eating from that layer do we do you
water more or less frequently do you
find yourself in a no-till environment
the beds that have cover crop use less
water okay that's gonna help cuz you're
getting shade you're got something to
trap that water in there less
evaporation and then less light okay
that's a cool thing that's gonna happen
for you it's another day out of it yeah
people are going a whole day yeah in a
commercial environment bro a whole day
is changed yeah we might have talked a
little bit about that and then we're
gonna get irrigation on that too so that
it's it's going to be insane how much
how little work it's gonna take that's
awesome
all the works gonna be just like
specifically to the plant
you know not not worry about water and
where exactly where to put what top
dress and exactly how to time it and
then where to prune and lollipop and pop
into it can't do you do trellising and
stuff also so we're working on building
a trellis in game awesome we're learning
a lot we're getting we're getting better
at it I've loved trellising well if you
know some guidance just ask for Sean I
was taught by a person who's really good
at trellising I was very good at it yeah
I used to do six foot wide by 75 foot
strips if just one piece of net all the
way down yeah it was that's people hated
it I loved it gonna work them in it's so
much
all right so we've got some white Dutch
white clover we've got our malted barley
we've talked about worm castings in the
mix we have got some compost in the mix
Oh what else are we gonna need to add in
as things go on are we gonna be set to
jet until harvest time what that makes
in there so I make it tea every other
week okay
just basically compost and compost and
or castings and molasses
fungal dominant team and get in there
and get the roots all activated of
microbes and get it living up a little
coke yeah pretty much
that's it I think the kelp will help
with your your flavor and your density
and the aroma for sure
I always think kelp helps with flavor
and density and aroma yeah it helps
encourage mycelium good yeah nature I
like ocean products in the grow all
right so basically now you've just got
to keep it wet and then give it the tea
and make sure none of the top stuff
starts dying off on you yeah keeping it
healthy yeah and then harvest time comes
then you chop right yeah but what are
people gonna say about not flushing a
no-tell that's what I'm curious about
there's no flush time it's all organic
so we're not forced feeding it anything
so there's no built-up salt and residues
to flush out while my computer just went
into a screen saver we're still
recording that's cool we we quit feeding
teas you know a few weeks before but the
the plants are a few weeks before
harvest but the plants are going through
a fade and everything you know all right
just like just like they naturally would
because they're like I said earlier
we're not forced feeding them they're
just they're only taking up they go oh
it's probably the end of my cycle I
better start finishing up here I've been
flowering for nine weeks for sure all
right that makes sense to me so harvest
time comes we chopped down our plants to
plant disappears that's a whole nother
podcast episode you guys are harvest
drank your episodes to listen to you can
go listen to those we're gonna focus on
what happens to the no-till soil after
the trim crew has taken the plant out of
the room we've got a little stock
sticking up out of the plant you just
get like a little Spade and kind of cut
a tiny circle and cut that root ball out
or he does yank it out yeah just pretty
much Hank you don't yank it out distill
leaves because you want to leave organic
do in there okay so it's still leaves
plenty a root system behind you just let
the worm castings and everything else
does take care of that for you yeah all
that organic matter terms it turns into
warm food all right it gets broken down
and turned it back into nutrient and it
just is there any time between see we've
harvested everything we go through and
pull out all the basically pull out the
sticks now is there any time between
putting new plants in there we just put
them right back in I mean yes and no
okay so I'm divot you know the the true
spirit in no-till you would want to let
it rest for I mean at least a month okay
you know true spirit of no-till it'll be
more agriculture you know traditional AG
so it's gonna rest you know an entire
season yeah like a lot of the I won't go
to that but yeah I mean so commercial
no-till is a little different because
you know figuring out the balance he
keeping nutrient and health in the bed
plus keeping up productivity right cuz
you can't just have half your farm
shelling for a season with no gas yeah
yeah so can you tell us what you do to
how your house what's your uh what's the
word at your compromise so we're really
ideally we're shooting for a week arrest
okay we we cover the same day we harvest
we give a real nice layer compost we
chopped cover crop we we mulch
use it to mulch it okay so it just stays
right in there yeah and yeah and they
gets a healthy dose of barley that day
so everything just kind of starts
breaking down ideally we'll you know
we'll get at least a week so okay
hopefully see how that goes right
but yeah I don't know it's gonna work
we'll see I hope it goes well for you
yeah I'm seeing you're brainstorming I'm
like you know what if you really should
be Mart is still cooking and it's still
cooking all three
ideally you know I was like I'd like to
see like four weeks but you know that's
just not practical for for this
situation do you think that uh-oh it's
not because the things are breaking down
the dying root matter who's gonna ask if
you think that that whole four by four
or five by when we have a five by eight
that five by eight bed do you think that
thing is it looks like when you pull a
plant out of a pot oh it's got roots
just thick everywhere you think that
whole section is just Rudy like that
no because things are eating it and
decaying it right okay yeah all right
like I said earlier this is fascinating
together they envision what's going on
toward the bottom of that cuz I can
totally envision what's happening about
a foot in pusher two feet in I'm not
sure what's going on that far into that
soil yeah yeah yeah so that's like
another part of our talking about the
depth so I mean true true no-till I feel
like we'd be putting a clone in or I
shouldn't say true but the way most
people know till they so when they
replant the bed they're just putting a
little tiny clone when we replant it I'm
putting in you know of 24 to 36 inch
okay plans are it's ready to flower yeah
they're ready to flip yeah so so to put
you know they're in a two gallon pot so
basically we till the top foot of the
bed
and you know that that's gonna react all
kinds of you know the biological [ __ ]
right and built up but at the same time
you're introducing fresh stuff with it
right for sure okay so it's worth it
then you know that's another one of the
challenges of no-till commercial so in a
place that has to August 52 times a year
so it sounds like you've got a pretty
good hold on it a good idea of how to
make it work I'm faithful that as long
as you keep reom ending that you'll be
able to keep running that bed virtually
that should be forever
definitely I'm gonna work some soil test
being a grower that was growing in home
gross for a long time back in the day in
Colorado you guys we can run a lot of
plants you could go to the doctor you
could say my neck and my back my neck my
back and they would say well then you
need to grow 99 plants who's your
medical
and honestly you'd say my money and my
back well it's too fat it's [ __ ] my
back exactly they solve your problem
leave five of those hundreds at the
counter and you can have 99 plants in
your house yes sir imagine having 99
three gallon pots worth of soil to get
rid of every 60 days and you're trying
to be slightly discreet about it because
you don't need anybody in the neighbors
know that you've got 99 plants down
there yeah they got a little
nerve-wracking if you're running the
no-till you don't just leave that pot
right there forever I'll probably never
do another non no-till style girl Wow
Wow
it's uh it's super [ __ ] easy so it's
you guys heard it from Jessie it's super
[ __ ] easy yeah he's just I mean you
gotta have the right amount of soil
you're not gonna pull off real no-till
they're like a 20 gallon I'm thinking
like 50 200 gallons at least okay like a
kiddie pool in the closet maybe yeah
maybe
all right and a small she'd want to go
there's some of those companies that
make the Smart Pot style raised no-till
beds oh yeah those uh that build a soil
place I got a couple demo tents rockin
with with them that [ __ ] looks good you
know yes if you're in the area go check
out build a soil I don't work with them
they don't pay me it's just a cool place
yeah this growers working for growers
which is that sounds cheesy but that's
why it's cool because there are growers
yeah hey bro hey bro careful there I've
called out there couple times a bit we
went up on a Saturday to pick up soil
once many moons ago that was kinda it's
kind of funny I like some of the grow
checks
I've had a lot of fun let's see we've
covered most of the stuff bro we covered
cover crop we covered top dressing we
talked about feeding it a tee one of the
major questions that you've got was is
it cost-effective in a commercial
environment so far have you found it to
be cost-effective I know it's only your
first run I believe so okay definitely
you know in half a year
I'll have concrete evidence but you know
that's so far in your is so far in your
flowering phase does it look like your
weight is going to be comparable to what
you're familiar with in your original
your other styles that you grow this
harvest I think it's maybe just a little
bit bigger and you know and I didn't
really know I mean I knew what I wanted
to do but I hadn't worked out a lot of
the like the feeding schedule and stuff
like that
when we first started it I I started
really light you know I didn't want to
overload the soil or you know lock it
out or anything like that and that's the
exact opposite of what a lot of people
will do on their first try yeah yeah
more so or we definitely got yielded as
much as we did when we were going in the
pods so he's in a little bit of we used
by OBE is a little bit so okay yeah to
go product yeah
thanks Steph tastes real nice so in the
beds the reason three liquid products
and we didn't use any of those in the
bed so and you know so we've got
probably a little bit more all right
yeah you know that works out really good
it sounds like the cost of what you're
putting into it is way cheaper than
going and buying or having a bunch of
nutrients delivered you don't have to
pay for all the extra stuff that's in
the news that you don't need you're not
buying a brand name every commercial
girl around here is using one of three
very specific brand names probably for I
think of four specific brands that are
very popular in all the rows and they're
expensive as [ __ ] they'll get the job
done oh yeah but you got to buy them
right now to get them there's one brand
that you can't buy it as a consumer you
have to buy it as a commercial girl you
have to have a commercial account and
you have to order eight hundred pound of
minimum so you have to have and they
like to sell you a hundred and fifty
pounds because they come in a hundred
and fifty pound drum so you got to buy a
hundred and fifty pound drum and have it
delivered and yeah that's the pain in
the ass so it's good stuff though
is what I would go buy for a commercial
girl right now I know so much about it's
why I'm able to get it because I've got
150 pound orders for other places if I
just do a commercial any other way than
this okay I've had great success with
their problem
so yeah it's to varying ways of growing
and we're both totally satisfied with
what we're doing and we're both sitting
at a table smoking - yeah yeah you guys
don't have to fight about anything it's
a cannabis industry our point is to grow
the best weed we can it so we can all
smoke good we together I grow anyway
you know let's see something that we can
touch on that another person asked was
is it labor effective cost-wise yes
that's me I knew that was gonna be your
answers why save that one because I know
is gonna be short and quick less
man-hours and less we use less water
less man-hours and loss waters here
saving a lot of money there through the
most expensive things in the grow other
than electricity and you're in a
greenhouse so you just cut down all the
money nice bro is there anything else
you want to add about no-till before I
ask you this one last note that I've got
written down yeah I mean if you're
serious about it commercial go and hit
me up there you go how can you hit me up
on Instagram what you knew this
Instagram handle Jesse grows yeah just
Jesse goes all right Jesse grows on
Instagram what's your picture so they
know what they're looking for I think
it's Joe Dirt maybe that's overgrow who
at joder is this picture he's gonna take
a quick look for that support that makes
more sense yeah I will come see you I
want to set up some other big no-till
places so hit me up tattoos that serious
also dead serious we're not cheap but we
are worth what we charge you guys pay
your consultants what they're worth
don't try to cheap out on consultants
this is just a random rant but you could
pay a chief consultant to come and [ __ ]
everything up for you and then you can
pay us the correct price to come and fix
it or you could his pants the correct
price to do it correctly
the very first
I'm yeah that's up to you anyway
before we started recording Jesse made a
joke and said remind me to talk about
dirty mike and he doesn't mean white
Mike the guy that comes on the podcast
he means something about a microphone so
he's taking a drink right now but as
soon as he's caught up on that I'm gonna
let Jesse talk about his dirty
microphone story so back in the day I
played drums in a couple punk rock bands
and the best band I ever played for
which didn't last very long because I
wasn't very good but I sit down at
practice and the old drummer had sang
and I looked over it as his mic and his
his mic covers like covered with pieces
of food eilean [ __ ] just [ __ ] and
[ __ ] it was so so disgusting yes
horrible but he was like a well-known
drummer here in town and yeah it just
hit back that is kind of like like you
know like inferiority complex compared
to him and I saw that nasty [ __ ] like
that he's human too grody [ __ ] that's
so gross yeah unfortunately that's all
too common in the music industry if you
buy a pawnshop microphone you got to
take the the block the big box store
whose name I shall not mention that
everybody goes to to buy all their
musical equipment who was the musical
devil they're not allowed to buy in
microfilm vocal mics they can buy in
drum mics and like an i-5 or whatever
but they can't buy a new vocal mic so
these Sennheiser's they totally could
buy these because we've been spitting in
yeah disgusting that's a great story bro
beautiful beautiful and for the podcast
that's how people are gonna remember you
man
you've got a few listeners and you've
got a mic in front of your face anything
you want to tell the world while you're
here yeah I'm going down to Oklahoma
this weekend I don't think the show be
released by then I can put it out by
then yeah sure yeah I'll be down there
ninth tenth and eleventh hanging out
checking out trying to
some some clients to set up some no two
girls for him or any kind of girl I
don't care if you're an Oklahoma and you
need some consulting in the next weekend
hit up our friend Jesse grows at Jesse
grows on Instagram you can find him he's
easy to find he's handsome he's got a
deep voice reach out he will come set up
a no-tilled row in Oklahoma for you
outdoor light all kinds of stuff I can
help you with SOPs just cost projections
genetic acquisition yeah just about
everything you can think of we've been
in the industry long enough to know the
shifts and what to expect we know the
way your market is going to go I'm
selling us as consultants now it's so
funny but we know how the market is
gonna go we've seen this market here for
the past 12 years or so we've also been
in several groves we know what's gonna
fail we also know how compliance is
going to go for you in the next few
years so let us come in and set up your
growth to be Colorado compliant today so
that way in the future when they come
and make rules you're ahead of the game
and you can be an example and when the
whatever the control board is if they
like you it really helps out if you try
to be if you're the good kid in school
the teacher likes you the regulation
boards when it comes to cannabis they
like the same kind of people so hey look
we we already preemptively did this
before you made the rule like damn you
guys are good they'll don't really enjoy
coming to your facility and they'll be a
little more lenient when [ __ ] does go
wrong because one day something will go
wrong I couldn't say it better myself
that's almost my exact speech too yeah
if you get too many clients bro he let
me know no you know I also storefront
and accounting no I don't do that myself
but I got plenty of people they got a
magical lady that I'm working on a
business plan with her to do in front of
the house retail consulting I would
recommend her for anything so we got you
covered we can get your grog on we can
get your retail going I think that's
enough pitching us as consultants I
don't even think that's what we came
here for today good job good job
now I hit me up though you even if you
just want to get high I'm gonna be
staying
real close to where the two interstates
meet so central location in OKC there
you go guys find him get lit with him
he's a yeah you never know hang out see
anything weird now have to edit out
we're gonna skip all that dude thanks
for coming thanks for taking time out of
your evening let's hang out take some
dad's without these microphones for sure
awesome guys we're gonna wrap up this
part of the show I should be back in
just a couple of seconds due to the
magic of editing and then we will put a
bow on this [ __ ] what I think we say
thanks for hanging out guys I'll be
right back
all right podcast paroled I wanna thank
you guys again for listening I want to
thank Jesse for coming and hanging out
and teaching us about no-till if you
guys have more questions about no-till
gardening reach out to Jesse it's at
Jesse grows on Instagram or you can
reach out to me on Facebook you can find
me at the grill from your heart podcast
on Twitter it's at g f YH podcast on
instagram it's Irie underscore genetics
or if you'd like to reach out to me
through email you can send me an email
it's grow from your heart at hotmail.com
I would love to hear from you we will
answer your questions on a future
episode if you feel like this episode
was educational informative or
entertaining and you'd like to make a
financial contribution to the podcast
you can do so by going to patreon.com
slash grow from your heart all of the
information you need to become a patron
will be right there on the screen and I
do appreciate all of the support ladies
and gentlemen my voice is burning out
I'm glad Jesse came because I would have
sounded terrible doing a show by myself
so once again a big shot at that Jesse
you guys I'll be back in just a few days
with a fresh new episode we will get
right back on those grow less uns I'm
gonna give a huge shout out to my friend
John B and until next time take a phat
dab and give your mom a hug for me