welcome to the show everybody it's time
for episode 368 of the girl from your
heart podcast this episode is brought to
you by the hella dank seed company if
you need fresh genetics for your garden
I highly recommend the hella de exede
company and you can find them at
www.kencostore.com or our friends at
viola extracts the stuff has a really
nice flavor if you dab it too hot you
totally kill that sweet watermelon
flavor if you go in nice and cool it has
a sweet watermelon Jolly Ranchers sort
of flavor and I really like it the label
here says it is ninety four point five
percent THC a and zero percent CBD or
CBG for a total of eighty two point
eight eight percent THC that's a pretty
impressive lab test for something with
so much flavor so big shout out to the
screamin watermelon from viola extracts
and also big shout out to my friends at
the Colorado cannabis exchange for
taking good care of me
alright before I take us into the grow
lesson I want to give you guys an update
on my webstore I have added some new
merchandise to my website there are new
Irie army t-shirts there are I read
genetics t-shirts there are grow from
your heart podcast t-shirts there are I
read genetics hoodies and there are
growth from your podcast hoodies all
available on the website plus a plethora
of great stickers so make sure you check
out the website I read genetics Colorado
comm grab yourself some shirts grab
yourself some stickers get a hoodie for
the winter get yourself all styled out
with the fresh new eye region that excu
alright you guys let's work on a podcast
this is going to be another grow lesson
I hope you have been following along
with my long series of grow lessons we
started off by selecting a goal for our
grow we worked on selecting a proper
space we built a good grow room we
decided if we wanted to grow from seeds
or clones we acquired seeds and clones
we have got them sprouted now they are
potted into their little pots I think by
this time all of our seeds and clones
should be about the same size we've got
stuff any either a four inch pot or a
six inch net pot we should have clones
or seedlings with just a few sets of
leaves they're probably four maybe six
inches tall by now and that is what I
call small
vej so let's do a podcast about the
small vegetative phase of growing your
cannabis garden in my opinion the
vegetative phase of growing cannabis is
often the most overlooked phase of
growing people think they need to invest
all their time energy and money on the
flowering process that is very important
but I like to believe that you can't
build a strong building without a solid
foundation and that foundation starts in
the veg phase by the time we get these
plants to the flowering room we need
them to be healthy we need them to be
robust we need them the shape we want
them we need them the structure we want
them and we need them pests and pathogen
during the small vegetative stage is to
develop a strong root system for these
plants I want to get those roots thick
and busting out of that pot before I
transplant them into their forever homes
my second goal is to keep these plants
past and pathogen free now if I'm
working from seeds I'm also paying
attention for issues mutations problems
whatever a seedling may show you a
ceiling has a ton of options that can
occur through the entire growth cycle
you need to pay special attention to
your seedlings if you're growing from
clones you should know what to expect so
my main focus during this small
vegetative phase is developing a strong
root system my second priority is
maintaining clean healthy plants I don't
want any bugs and I don't need any
pathogens then my third priority if I'm
growing from seeds I want to pay close
attention to those seedlings and I want
to keep my eye out for any weird
mutations or weird problems now if
things go right we are only going to
spend two to four weeks in these small
pots in our small veg phase but in my
opinion this phase is equally as
important as the flowering process we
need to treat every step of the grow
process as an important process we all
want to focus on that flowering phase we
all get excited around week four we get
super pumped up at week five by week six
you're just ecstatic week seven and
eight you can't wait to cut it down by
week nine you're in there every single
day taking pictures looking at the
plants hoping you can cut them down
today or tomorrow just trying to be
patient why don't we put that much
energy into the starting phase of our
plants I know they're not as pretty
there's nothing
show for it but it is just as import now
let's get a little deeper into this
small veg phase what makes this small
veg what makes it small veg as my plants
are small they are in small pots now
what makes it veg veges the light cycle
cannabis plants are triggered by the
light cycle if they have enough light
they will not flower once we reduce the
light to approximately 12 hours on and
12 hours off every day that triggers our
plants to flower they think that the
fall is coming they think it's the end
of the season they start doing their
end-of-season business which is
producing flowers the parts that we call
buds are the cannabis flowers they are
dried flower tops from a cannabis plant
that is induced by changing the light
cycle so until we manipulate that light
cycle we are in veg since we are using
small pots and have small plants once
again we are back to small now let's
talk a little bit about these light
cycles we've got plenty of options for
light cycles in our veg phase from what
I have experienced the most common and
most popular veg light schedule is 18
hours on and 16 hours off in a daily 24
hour cycle there are other options you
can go 24 hours on and 0 hours off I
have seen great success with 2 hours of
darkness so that's 22 hours on and two
hours off every day in a commercial
facility and a mother room and in a veg
room I am known to do 20 hours on and
four hours off now I mentioned the 18:6
that is kind of a classic that's really
close to what nature does also there is
the sixteen on and eight hours off all
of these have their advantages also they
all have their disadvantage
what is the advantage of 24 hours and
zero hours of darkness 24 hours of light
means your plants are getting 24 hours
of light energy I usually recommend a 24
hour on cycle only for clones and tiny
plants or if your rivetting sometimes we
have mother plants that if they get root
bound or if they don't get enough light
or if they don't get the proper energy
they will decide to OTO flower on you
over time I like to keep those plants
under 24 hours of light that does
prevent them from flipping themselves
into flower because of another
environmental factor
so most of the time I would not
recommend a 24-hour light cycle unless
you were cutting clones or you're trying
to revenge or perhaps you've got a
mother plant it gets temperamental and
wants to try to auto flower on you
I like the 20 on and 4 off for a
commercial environment I like a little
bit of dark cycle I think every living
thing likes a little bit of dark cycle
I think roots develop in the dark I
think the plants like a little rest
also that is 4 hours of electricity not
being sucked up if you've got one light
you're saving a little bit of money if
you've got 50 lights you were saving a
lot of money that is 200 light hours
that you are not running right there
that's 200,000 watt light hours that you
don't have to pay for if you've got a
larger facility so 20 hours on four
hours off is always great for a
commercial facility you can keep your
mother plants in that room you can keep
your small veg in that room you can keep
your large veg in that room usually I
put the clones in that same room
underneath the t5 light in the corner so
there's just a little bit of light in
the room it doesn't really bother the
rest of the plants they're able to do
their thing that t5 doesn't do much in a
giant bedroom in a commercial facility
now I always like to mention the
downside of what I'm talking about
there's not much of a downside to a 20
on and 4 off cycle I guess really the
only downside is that you are always
running lights you only get four hours
of darkness
compared to my next method which is an
18 on and 6 hour off everyday cycle a
lot of growers prefer this because it is
closer to the natural cycles of life it
is closer to the natural rhythms of the
Sun outside it's a little closer to the
natural circadian rhythm that our plants
would be subject to in their normal
environment and it just feels a little
more natural in general so the pros to
an 18-6 cycle is it feels pretty natural
to you and the plants it also saves you
quite a bit of electricity having a six
hour night cycle that is six hours that
you don't have your lights on that's six
hours you don't have to cool the room as
much that's and multiply that by however
many lights you've got and you start
saving more and more money and I also
think the plants really enjoy a nice six
hour nap you can see a lot of
productivity from that 6 hour nap that
the plants get now our next option is a
16 and 8 cycle that is very similar to
the 8
six but some plants will show you some
differences some plants may try to
flower under that 16 8 cycle if they get
root bound if they become nutrient
deficient if there are any environmental
factors that stress those plants they
may decide to flower on you underneath
that 16 and 8 light cycle depending on
what part of the globe your plants
originated from they may have a
different critical period and let me
explain the critical period the critical
period is the amount of dark hours a
plant needs to induce its flowering
cycle some plants will flower with a 14
hour dark cycle some plants will flower
with a 10 hour dark cycle the reason we
go for that 12 on 12 off is it's right
in the middle and it seems to work well
with most of the plants that we have
bread for our indoor environment now
since some plants come from north of the
Equator and some plants come from south
of the equator we do have different
flowering times in tropical areas those
plants can flower for much longer
because they're not going to get snowed
on also in those areas we don't get as
drastic of a day and night cycle change
there may be as much as one hour
difference between your summer and your
winter day period in other areas we get
winter we get snow we get dumped on and
we get long dark periods so our plants
have evolved and adapted and climatized
themselves to those regions then we have
bred with those plants and we've created
hybrids and brought them indoors indoors
some of our plants will flower with a
tan our dark period indoors some of our
plants will flower with a 12 hour dark
period we have established that 12 on
and 12 off seems to work really well for
most of the plants that we have bred now
to prevent them from flowering early we
like to use an extended light cycle
that's we put them on 16 hours on at a
minimum that way we know they are not
going to flower I like to go that 18
hours because why not give them two more
full hours of energy every day light is
the number one desired nutrient from our
plants white is the number one desired
factor for growth from our plants so why
not give it that extra two hours now in
my mind I say why not give it that full
20 hours every day so that we can get
maximum growth and give our plants a
four hour a nap every day I think it
works really well
no another reason I like the 20 on and
four off is I find that when I move my
plants into the flowering room and I
take them from a 20-hour day to a
12-hour day they induce flowering very
quickly in other facilities where I'm
running shorter vege periods I noticed
they take a little longer for the plants
to start popping up bud set their little
pre flowers the little pistols don't
start popping up as early as if I were
to run those plants on a long day cycle
and then kick that 12:12 right away I
feel like the plants go oh [ __ ] it is
time to flower we have really had a
reduction in daylight they know it so
that's why I do 20 on and 4 off in my
veg and mom area of course I'm running
sometimes I've got 50 or 75 different
cultivars in a mom room so I've really
got to keep things happy and I found
that the 20 on and 4 off prevents
anything from auto flowering and again
it really triggers that flowering when I
put them into the 1212 room so those are
the basic veg schedules I would
recommend 24 20 and for 18 + 6 or 16 + 8
I wouldn't go much lower than that you
may notice problems you won't have the
desired robust vegetative growth that
you need and also you may get plants
that decide to flower before you're
ready alright I feel like we know how
long to leave the light on now let's
talk about what kind of light to put
these plants under we don't have to
throw these small plants under the
Gavita lights right away we may crisp
them up we may roast them they may not
be prepared for that so I like to start
my small plants under smaller lights in
most situations I think a t5 would work
for most people in most commercial
environments I use the 3 foot long t5
fixtures they're three feet long they
have 8 bulbs I feel like you can fit
quite a few small veg plants under those
in a commercial environment I like to
set up a two-tiered veg
system I get a Uline rack I put plants
on the bottom shelf of that Uline rack I
hang a light underneath the top shelf to
light those plants now I've got that top
shelf freed up I put plants up there and
I hang a light from the ceiling now I've
got two layers of plants and I'm
maximizing my space by using a
two-tiered veg system
I like to use a t5 fixture for the
plants on the bottom shelf and then for
the plants on the top shelf I either use
a Kavita or a metal halide either
somewhere between a four and a thousand
watt depending on my space depending on
my environment depending on how far from
those plants I am but those small veg
plants start off on the bottom shelf
under the t5 s then as I transplant I
move them up to the top shelf and they
go underneath the metal halides
sometimes those are kavita's it just
depends again on my environment now I
really find the t5 s to be
cost-effective I think they're efficient
and I think they do a great job if you
want to invest a little more money on a
better light I have seen great success
vegging underneath LED lighting small
plants really love LED lights and also
those LEDs don't produce much heat and
they don't use a lot of electricity
they are a little pricey up front but I
think they are worth the money if you
get a quality LED I personally don't
have much experience with LED lighting
but I have seen great things from LED
lights in small veg in large veg and
through flower the most important thing
about an LED in veg is the spectrum and
that's also important when it comes to
t5 let me back up because I overlooked
that part when I was talking about t5 s
I do not have any notes on this this is
all coming out of the top of my head
today so let me catch myself before I go
too fast
t5 lights are commonly available in two
spectrums most of the time you will find
them in a 3000 Kelvin and a 6400 Kelvin
for your veg phase I recommend the 60
400 Kelvin they will put off a more blue
light which is what we want for the veg
later on when we move the flower we want
more of that orange spectrum so that's
when he would switch to the 3000 Kelvin
t5 bulbs if you are going to flower
under them which I do not recommend but
they are great for veg so spectrum is
very important and I almost overlooked
that when you were selecting her t5
bulbs make sure that you get the six
thousand four hundred Kelvin bulbs those
are what I would recommend for your veg
phase I also recommend the bluer or
wider spectrum lights when it comes to
LEDs a lot of the new LED is give you
the option to turn on certain boards and
turn off certain boards when you were
vegging you want more of the blue and
wider spectrums again once we turn to
that's when we want those orange and red
spectrums so while we're in veg whatever
kind of light you're using focus more on
the white or blue spectrums so I've got
another option for lighting that I can
recommend but I would only suggest this
for a very small scale grow environment
maybe for one or two very small plants
maybe for a cabinet grow or something
this would be an effective grow light in
a pinch I have seen a lot of folks build
a small grow cabinet with a compact
fluorescent light those CFLs they put
off barely any heat and they use barely
any electricity so if you can get enough
of them around your plant to feel like
you're giving it enough light the plant
will grow don't expect huge growth don't
expect robust plants don't expect a lot
of harvest but you can make a plant grow
with a compact fluorescent light of
course the more light the better but
some people are very limited in space
and power and some people only want a
small grow for a small personal
experiment so a compact fluorescent
light may work for you that would always
be my very last option now let's talk
about a big-boy light a lot of people
are familiar with growing under
high-intensity discharge lighting a lot
of people are going to flower under an
HID light if we are careful to not roast
the plants a metal halide light will be
perfect for your small veg plants maybe
a four hundred maybe a six hundred a
thousand maybe overkill unless you keep
it a little distance away you can get a
four hundred watt light fairly close to
your small plants if you keep it cool if
you've got a ducted hood and you're
keeping air moving over that lights
where none of that heat is making it to
your canopy you can get that four
hundred watt light fairly close to your
plants just don't let that heat roast
your plants and dehydrate your soil I
would say maybe keep a 400 watt light 18
to 24 inches away from your small plants
the t5 s you can get those t5 s six to
eight inches away from the plants the
bigger the light we need to go a little
further because it's going to be hotter
and more intense and you don't want to
have super hot and tense light right in
your face all day you survive from the
Sun and you're happy with it being real
far away think about the plants and the
light and the Sun and yourself having a
similar kind of a relationship you need
plenty of it
you don't
want anything in the way but also you
don't want to get barbecue so you can
put a 400 watt light 18 24 inches away a
six hundred I would probably go 2030
inches away a thousand watt light you're
gonna want to be a few feet away from
those small plants it's going to get hot
it's going to be very intense but if
you've got a 400 watt light and it's
ducted which means it's got a duct
coming off of each end and you're
sucking air through it to move that heat
away from that bulb and you've got glass
between the bulb and the canopy you
should be able to run a 400 watt light
with very minimal problems if you pay
attention to heat and the distance from
those plants all right I think that
pretty much covers our lighting options
for our small veg plants let's talk a
little bit about the environment let's
talk about the temperature and humidity
for these small plants in my experience
my small plants appear to be happiest
when they are somewhere between 70 and
80 degrees Fahrenheit I really think
they like it
about 75 degrees to 77 degrees is right
about the prime spot for small veg
plants that's when I see the most growth
that's when I see the most production
that's when I see the most root
development that's when I see the
happiest plants so somewhere between 70
and 80 degrees or if you can dial it in
perfectly 75 to 77 is that sweet spot
they really seem to like it right there
now for that temperature to work
perfectly you need to dial in your
humidity temperature and humidity work
together there is a math equation I've
done a full Episode on it this creates
what is called a vapor pressure deficit
I encourage you to listen to episode 314
and learn about vapor pressure deficit
and now let's talk about humidity these
small plants would like to be in an
environment with the humidity somewhere
between 50 and 70 percent I have noticed
that when the humidity is too low the
plants do not produce there is no
production for the whole day when the
humidity is too low the leaves start to
droop the plants don't make any progress
they don't look as robust as they should
the roots are not growing
there's no productivity in that plant
and they also start to develop a woody
texture on the outside of the stems so I
encourage proper humidity too much
humidity on the other hand can cause
similar problems it can cause slow
it can cause rot it can encourage
powdery mildew try to keep the plants
happy by giving them the proper
conditions how much better do you
perform when you are happy with your
conditions if I made you go do your job
some of you are gonna laugh at me
because you have to do this if I made
you go do your job outside in 30-degree
weather and shorts and a t-shirt how
happy are you gonna be you're not gonna
get [ __ ] done if I put you in shorts and
a t-shirt and put you in a 77 degree
room and I dial that humidity back to
about 50% you're gonna be completely
comfortable in that room and you're
gonna get a lot done the plants feel the
same about life if we keep them
comfortable and we keep them happy
they're gonna produce for us and give us
what we want if we don't keep them happy
if we don't treat them properly they're
not gonna give a [ __ ] it's gonna be a
struggle the entire grow so again for
temperature I want somewhere between 70
and 80 degrees right around 75 to 77 is
that sweet spot from what I have
experienced and then again with humidity
I like to stay between 50 and 70 percent
too low he started slowing down growth
too high
you start slowing down growth so that is
the temperature and humidity again I
highly recommend you go listen to
episode 314 and learn all about vapor
pressure deficit all right you guys we
have talked about lighting we have
talked about environment I feel like
this is going to turn into a long
podcast I'm 20 minutes in I am going to
press pause for a moment I need to take
a drink of course I'm gonna take a
couple of dabs I encourage you to dab
with me I will be right back and we will
talk about nutrients and feeding our new
small veg plants hey guys well I'm
taking a couple of dabs I thought it
would be a good opportunity to give
thanks to people who have supported the
show on patreon I want to give you huge
thanks to my friend Sam how about a
giant thanks to Aldrich a big giant
shout-out to Tanner Martin oeq and also
a big shout-out to Todd Keller thank you
for all of the patreon support if you
would like to learn how to support the
show on patreon all you have to do is go
to patreon.com/scishow and I'm ready to
talk more about our small veg plants I
said we were going to jump into
nutrients I've got
one more thing I want to add to our grow
environment before we talk about what we
are feeding let's add a small fan to our
grow environment
I want to ruffle each leaf of our small
plants as they grow I don't need the fan
blasting the plants constantly I don't
need the fan making the plants bend over
I don't need a whole lot of fan activity
if you've got an oscillating fan that's
perfect put it on low and just let it
breathe across the canopy of those
plants that's gonna make the plants more
robust and it's going to make them
develop stronger roots and I think the
plants do better when we give them a
little bit of wind if there's wind
outside it would get blown around a
little bit I think that what happens
when I push you if I shove you a little
bit not super hard you know but if I
just give you a little nudge what do you
do natural instinct is to spread your
feet further apart to have better
balance I kind of feel like if we blow
on a plant make it wobble around a
little bit maybe it's gonna spread its
roots a little bit wider to get better
balance which will also result in a more
robust stalk which will result in an
overall more productive plant when we
move that plant into the flowering phase
so let's give the plants a little bit of
wind they would get wind outside let's
introduce a little bit of that to our
indoor environment again don't blast the
plants if some of the leaves closest to
that fan start getting dry or leathery
or crinkly or they start looking like a
potato chip they're getting blasted too
hard by the fan reduce either the fan
speed or the frequency that they're
getting hit by the fan they're getting
too much air movement and you're
disrupting the vapor pressure deficit in
that area so pay attention to the leaves
they will let you know if they're
getting too much wind but give them a
little bit of airflow and your plants
will really be happy for it you like a
nice little breeze don't choose nice
warm day a nice sunshine on your face
what's the next best thing that could
come along it's just a nice little
breeze I think the plants kind of feel
the same way so give them a nice little
breeze and I think they'll appreciate it
you'll make them stronger you'll make
them more robust and you'll give them
just some fresh air more frequently now
let's talk a little bit about nutrients
for our small veg plants we don't need a
supercharged nutrient regimen for these
little plants we don't want to burn them
we don't want to shock them we don't
want to stunt them while they're babies
we want to focus on a balanced diet and
I like to focus
I keep saying enroute development for
these small plants so I like a light
vegetative nutrient if you're working
with bottled nutrients there are a few
things to think about if you are working
in cocoa or soil or soilless mix or
hydro you need to pay attention to
whatever product line you decide to buy
and see if they offer a soil a cocoa or
a hydro variety the nutrients will be
show laded differently and they will be
in different ratios because your plants
will uptake things differently in
different mediums
many of the companies that make
nutrients offer a soil or a hydro option
when it comes to buying their products
if you are growing in cocoa I recommend
you get the hydroponic version of the
product you are buying cocoa is more
like hydro than it is like soil or a
soilless mix so if you're shopping for
nutrients and you're in cocoa I would
recommend that you buy the bottle that
is recommended for hydro now when you're
looking at bottled nutrients you're
going to find 3 numbers displayed on the
bottle that is the NPK value of that
nutrient the first number is nitrogen
that tells us the ratio of nitrogen in
that product
the next number will be the amount of
phosphorous then the next number will be
the amount of potassium when it comes to
veg nutrients we are looking for a
product with a high end ratio and lower
P and K numbers we don't need a lot of
phosphorus and potassium we want to
focus on that nitrogen for building
strong robust plants with a lot of
energy so we need a good solid grow base
nutrient let's talk a little bit about
base nutrients whatever company you
choose to work with
they probably offer a two or three part
base nutrient system a lot of them will
have a grow and a bloom that makes it
pretty obvious you use the grow for your
vegetative stage and you use the bloom
for your flowering stage a lot of
companies offer a two-part product which
will be an A and a B grow they also
offer an A and a B bloom but we don't
need those so let's talk about those
later you will take your grow a and grow
P and you will mix those into your water
to create your vegetative nutrient based
solution the reason they sell an
B is because there are things in bottle
a and things in bottle B that will bind
together typically if they are mixed
together without being diluted in our
water so you would fill your container I
generally use a five-gallon bucket in a
home grow you'd fill your five-gallon
bucket with water you would apply the
correct amount the appropriate amount of
veg a then you would apply the
appropriate amount of veg B then you
would mix it up then you would continue
to add the rest of the required
nutrients that is a two part vegetative
nutrient solution other companies will
offer their products in a different
format they will offer what is called a
base and then they will give you a grow
and a bloom to add on top of that with
that type of nutrient regimen you will
use that base product through the entire
cycle through veg and through flour then
you'll use that grow additive during the
growth phase and when you switch to
flour you'll switch to that flowering
additive and they've just put the
appropriate additives in those bottles
to keep everything running smoothly with
that base nutrient in there now whatever
brand you choose be sure you get the
appropriate veg nutrient set up if it's
a two part make sure you get the a and B
if it's the kind where you have to have
a base and a grow nutrient make sure you
get the base and the grow if you get
something simple where there's just a
bottle that says veg there you go you're
ready to go you've got that one strong
bench nutrient alright I feel like we
have a good handle on base nutrients we
need a good base nutrient with a strong
nitrogen value now I would recommend you
feed those plants maybe a quarter of the
recommended strength for the first
couple times you feed your plants new
nutrients give them a light feeding and
pay close attention write it down so
that you know exactly what you did also
write down the pH write down the EC if
that is an option for you the more notes
you take the more you can do research to
dial in where you went wrong a lot of us
consume a lot of cannabis some of us
consume cannabis while we're working in
the gardens sometimes you say I wonder
what I put in there and you have no idea
where you went wrong
that won't happen if you take notes and
write things down I've done an entire
episode on journaling and I suggest you
listen to that one as well so we've got
a reliable base nutrient we've decided
how much to use it started 1/4 strength
maybe work your way up to 1/3 maybe 1/2
you're definitely not going to need full
strength
nutrients for small plants a lot of your
nutrient companies will offer a feeding
schedule a lot of those feeding
schedules will have a small plant
recommendation I still recommend you
reduce that a little bit until you see
how the plants will react so we've got a
base nutrient with small plants I always
recommend some sort of myko product some
sort of root inoculants something to
make those roots go Kapow I try to avoid
recommending specific products here is a
long list of reliable products that will
work great for your roots
I like mammoth pea I like plus life from
veg bloom I like recharge from Scotty
real I like great white shark and Orca
and my coach um I think that is a great
combination some of those products are a
little expensive some are more
affordable I can also recommend a
product called mykos it is a very
affordable bag of micro products as long
as you are using some sort of micro
product I think you will see very
increased root production compared to if
you did not use it of course I like the
higher end fancier more expensive
products but if you can't afford that
get what you can't afford I highly
recommend a microbe or a Maiko or a root
inoculant product for your small plants
it will really speed up your production
and I think the plants will really show
a huge difference and you will notice it
and it will make you a happier grower
so we've got a reliable vegetative
nutrient with enough nitrogen in it we
have decided on a micro product that
would be enough for our small veg plants
for two to four weeks you may want to
add some fulvic acid to your mix I like
adding some folding I think it makes the
plants uptake the nutrients more quickly
and I think it's really worth the
investment just a small bottle of fulvic
acid will really improve your nutrient
uptake and your plants now if you've got
a good solid base nutrient and you're
feeding your roots your plants are
really happy you've added a little
fulvic acid that's increasing the uptake
as the plants get a little bit bigger
you may need to introduce some cal-mag
be careful not to overdose small plants
on cal-mag sometimes the young plants
really don't react well to too much
cal-mag so be careful now basically
we've got a veg nutrient we
got some mykos we've got a little bit of
fulvic acid and maybe around week three
we are going to add a dose of cal-mag
this feed should keep our plants super
happy one important thing we need to
think about is the pH of our feeding
solution for plants this size I
generally recommend we adjust the pH
somewhere between five point nine and
six point two and again we adjust the pH
after all of the nutrients have been
mixed in you've got your bucket of water
you add in the appropriate recommended
amount of each bottle of nutrients then
you give it a good stir make sure it's
nice and mixed then we check the pH then
we adjust accordingly so we've got a
solid veg mix we've got at pH adjusted
now it is time to water our plants I
recommend when you water you saturate
your medium thoroughly don't drown the
plants but make sure that all of the
soil or cocoa or whatever medium you are
watering make sure it is saturated we
don't want any dry pockets your roots
will not grow into dry spots so moisten
all of your medium now is probably a
good time to remind you guys of episode
337 where I do a lesson on what is
called one through five water tank if
you're a new grower and you haven't
heard the one through five water tech
discussion I highly recommend you listen
to that episode right after this it is
episode 337 and it will teach you a lot
about watering your plants correctly so
we have appropriately watered our small
plants with nutrients when do we need to
give our plants nutrients again that is
a really good question
in cocoa I like to feed nutrients to my
plants at every single watering every
single day I will feed my plants a solid
base mix then I will add a booster every
day and I will rotate those boosters
depending on what the plants may need in
this small veg case my booster would be
the cal-mag I would water the nutrients
I would put the base nutrient put the
full vet fulvic acid and I would put the
mykos in my nutrient solution every
single day then once a week I would put
that cal-mag in there that would be my
booster for these small plants now if
you're working in soil or soilless mix
you don't need to feed nutrients as
often because they stick around in the
dirt a little better I would recommend
you
feed with nutrients one feed then water
the next feed when you're feeding with
just clean water please adjust the pH
just like you do when you're mixing
nutrients fill your container with water
stick your pH meter in there see what it
says adjust it up or down accordingly
you need to adjust the pH at every
feeding so I would recommend you do one
feeding of nutrients one watering of pH
adjusted water then I would go back to
that basic nutrient regimen for the next
watering these small veg plants will
need frequent watering pay attention to
them don't let them get too dry don't
let them be over watered once again
check out the 1 through 5 watering tank
another thing we need to pay attention
to is over nutrient ting are we over
fertilizing these plants are we burning
them pay attention to the leaf tips if
the very tips of the leaves start to
look brown or the wrong color or if they
start to curl we are feeding too much if
your leaves look pale and yellow we are
not feeding enough if you have a mixture
of those two symptoms your pH is
probably off one of the very first
things I recommended in these grow
lessons was that you buy a book and you
read it hopefully you've already done
some reading hopefully you have looked
at some leaf charts and you know what
deficiencies look like so you know what
to pay attention to you know what a
healthy leaf looks like and you know
what an unhealthy leaf looks like and
it's gonna pop out in your head when you
see those leaves doing something weird
you're gonna say that's not what the
book said this should look like so
hopefully you've gotten the book
hopefully you have read the book so pay
attention to your plants if they are
showing you that they need more
nutrients increase your nutrients give
it a little more base nutrients you
probably don't need to increase the
amount of fulvic when it comes to mykos
I have learned that it is better to feed
small amounts more frequently than to
try to feed a whole bunch at one time
you're not gonna do any good by pouring
the whole bottle in there at one time
it'd be more effective to pour the
bottle in there
slowly over a course of time so maybe if
you see a deficiency just increase that
base nutrient which you're going to run
into a deficiency with and small plants
is either going to be nitrogen or
cal-mag
that is going to be your most common
deficiency so pay attention that those
two things and learn what that look
like the next common thing you're gonna
find is nutrient burn people are going
to try to feed too much to these plants
I heard somebody say the term [ __ ] I
just want to put more on it to make it
grow faster I thought it was hilarious
when I heard that I know a lot of people
like that don't be that guy now if
you're running a hydroponic system if
you're in rock wool cubes and you're
doing a top feed or if you're in some
type of ebb and flow system your small
veg phase will not be nearly as long as
us growing in cocoa or a soilless mix
your small veg phase zips right by
I think the hydro grows go much more
quickly in veg so your small veg phase
may be only about a week long you're
going to need to introduce more
nutrients at a higher rate sooner in a
hydroponic setup but pay attention to
the plants that is very plant specific
and very strain specific but since the
plants grow a little more quickly you
are going to need more nutrients sooner
one thing I'm going to remind you of in
your hydroponics is to stay on top of
your pH and your EC or your ppm s check
it every single day and adjust as needed
water is going to evaporate from your
hydroponic setup but the nutrients will
not evaporate so your pH and your ppm s
are going to fluctuate during that
evaporation also the plants are going to
consume some of the water so the water
is going to disappear throughout the day
which is going to cause changes in your
reservoir as a hydroponic grower you
need to be on top of that every single
day also I'm going to recommend you take
extra notes as a hydro grower reactions
happen a little more quickly and the
plants are a little more sensitive when
you're running hydro because you don't
have that big soil life system to work
as a buffer all right boys and girls I
feel like that is a good talk on small
veg we're going to leave these plants in
these pots for two to four weeks
depending on how quickly they grow
that's very strained dependent that's
very environment dependent one thing I
want to remind you to do is spread your
small veg plants out we do have them
crush together now because there are
small plants but as they get larger make
sure you spread them out give them more
space they want to grow they want to
branch out if you
got them all crushed together they're
gonna grow straight up and get really
really tall if you give them space to
branch out they will do so and then when
you top them you've got nice bushes but
that's coming up in the future you guys
I know I didn't talk about soil I didn't
talk about containers in this episode I
feel like I covered that in the previous
episodes so we were up to speed there
we're gonna leave these plants in these
containers for two to four weeks then we
will pop them into three gallon or five
gallon or perhaps seven gallon
containers maybe some of you out there
are gonna go huge and go into a 20 or an
even larger container but we're gonna
work on that on the next episode so
we've got a little time to let these
plants grow your job now is to keep them
healthy keep them happy
keep them pests and pathogens on those
roots if you see any yellow or funky
leaves make sure you pull that stuff off
just take good care of your new sweet
little babies make sure they don't have
any problems so that when we transplant
them into their bigger pots they're
ready to go they've got a fat root
system and they don't go into any shock
from a transplant I just realized that I
did not cover any pest management for
our small plants let's talk about that
really quickly
hopefully you have decided on an
integrated pest management system for
your garden before this point hopefully
that was part of your planning phase
hopefully we don't have any pests or
problems on our small plants some folks
will choose to apply a pesticide as a
preventative some folks will wait until
they see a problem to use a pesticide on
a plant this small I would like to wait
until I transplant these into their
three gallon pots before I put any
pesticides on them however in some
environments I don't trust the place and
I need to put a pesticide on it I would
use something like evergreen and I would
probably use it around 15 mils per
gallon I would make sure to apply it
while the lights were off and I would be
sure that the plants were completely dry
before I turn the lights back on and I
would probably do this approximately
every five to seven days while the
plants are little if I were in a place
that had a reputation for getting a pest
infestation all right I feel like that
should keep us pest free for the first
four weeks and then we can really start
implementing our integrated pest
management once we transplant into those
three gallon
pots all right podcast rolled I feel
like that is a solid show about small
veg if you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
and you would like to make a financial
contribution to the show I encourage you
to do so and you can do that by going to
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
all of the information you need to
become a patron will be right there on
the screen and I do appreciate all of
the support now while I'm talking about
patreon let me bring up something I keep
forgetting to mention on the podcast
recently patreon changed the way the
contributors cards are billed during
that process many contributors were
removed from content creators pages if
you feel like you are contributing to a
patreon campaign I encourage you to log
into your patreon account and check the
status of all your content creators
please make sure you were still signed
up and contributing to all the people in
which you have been supporting support
from our community means a lot to
content creators and it would really
break our hearts to lose contributions
because of a technical glitch so again
please check on your patreon campaigns
make sure you were contributing to all
of the creator's which you believe you
are creating and keep the vibe alive and
keep showing them love and support all
right you guys that's all I've got for
you for this week I would appreciate it
if you find me on the social media on
Facebook simply search for the girl from
your heart podcast on Twitter it's @gf
wih podcast of course I do have an
Instagram feed its Irie underscore
genetics find me on Instagram jump into
my Instagram live videos you can hang
out take dabs chat ask me some questions
maybe I will answer your questions there
on the live feed I encourage you to join
don't forget that I added some new
merchandise to my webstore go to I read
genetics Colorado calm slash I read -
store there are a growth from your heart
podcast t-shirts there are growth from
your heart podcast hoodies there are I
read genetics t-shirts and hoodies and
there are new Irie army t-shirts I think
they would all look great on you so
support the webstore if you've got any
questions you guys you can reach out to
me via email my email address is grow
from your heart at hotmail.com I do love
all of the interaction make sure you
support our sponsor the hella dank
seed company of course they are at dank
seed dot store you guys my voice is
burning out just in time so thanks for
listening to this episode I'll be back
in a couple of days with another grow
lesson I want to give you a huge shout
out to my buddy stabby mixed a Burson
and until next time take a phat dad and
give your mom a hug for me