welcome to the show podcast world it's
time for episode 369 of the girl from
your heart podcast this episode is
brought to you by the hell a dank seed
company if you need new seeds for your
garden I highly recommend the hella dank
seed company and you can find them at
www.cdxzipstream.com contraband
concentrates it's always got that nice
head buzz I feel like maybe that sharp
dryer sheet sort of aroma has something
to do with the head buzz that I get from
this concentrate anyway they always do a
good job big shout out to the fluffer
nutters sauce from contraband
concentrates it's obviously got me nice
and rambley this will be a great podcast
I do have a lot of great information
written down for you in this episode but
before we get to it I would like to give
a few people some shout outs let's start
off with Brett Gorman how about a big
giant shout out to Brett Gorman thanks
for all the support dude also a big
shout out to Aldridge once again I
totally appreciate that support and also
a shout out to Sam and Steve app thank
you for all of the support on patreon I
truly do appreciate that if you would
like to learn how to become a patron you
can do so by going to patreon.com slash
grow from your heart all the information
you need will be right there and once
again thanks for all the support
everybody it does mean a lot to me
alright podcast
in this episode I am going to do another
grow lesson if you have been following
along you know I've been doing a long
series of grow lessons in that series we
set a goal for our grow we found a safe
place for our grow we've selected the
appropriate equipment for our grow we've
also selected the appropriate nutrients
and pest management system for that grow
now we have either sprouted seeds or
potted some clones now at this point of
our grow we have got clones or seedlings
in small pots they are probably 6 to 10
inches tall at this point and they're
developing nice fat roots that's where
we are in these grow lessons in this
lesson I plan to talk a little bit more
about small veg we're going to continue
that conversation since time has
progressed since we put our plants into
the small pots then I want to work my
way into talking about micro products
and root development and the importance
of healthy roots and the benefits of
using a quality microbe product some of
this episode may feel like a recap some
of it will be a recap but we will work
our way right into our current state so
be patient sometimes I feel like it's
good to remind people not everybody
listens to every episode so I like to
get people up to speed before I move
forward I do need to correct myself I
made a mistake on the last episode in
the last episode I was talking about
ideal lighting for our small plants and
I feel like I completely overlooked
ceramic metal halide lighting ceramic
metal halide lighting is a very viable
and useful option for your small plants
if you feel like I left you out by not
mentioning the CMH lighting I apologize
those are quality lights and I recommend
new growers to use those lights for
small plants if that is an option they
are affordable they don't put out a lot
of light and they don't use a lot of
electricity so a ceramic metal halide
light is a very viable option for a
small grow for a new grower for small
plants also if you want to step up move
up from the 315 s to the 6 30s I've seen
great results with those in a flowering
room as well so don't let me forget the
ceramic metal halide lighting anymore
that is always a viable option in a
cannabis grow now let's get back on
track and talk more about continuing our
small veg phase again what I consider
small veg our small plants anything
basically from a cloner or a seedling
that is in a small pot maybe like a 4
inch pot maybe a 6 inch net pot maybe
all the way up to an 8 inch pot
but our smaller plants that don't have a
super strong healthy developed root
system are plants that are probably only
eight to ten inches tall those are what
I am considering my small veg plants now
up to this point we've mainly been
focusing on healthy pests and pathogens
free plants I suggest you check every
day for the presence of pests or
pathogens even as the plants are small
we still need to pay close attention
flip a leaf over see if you see any
weirdness on the bottom of the leaves
pay attention to the tops of the leaves
do you see any stippling that's a sign
of spider mites do you see any gooey
stuff that's a sign of thrips just pay
attention flick some of the plants flick
some of the containers do you see
anything fly out that is a sign of
either fungus gnats or white flies if
they're white they're white flies if
they're black they're probably fungus
gnats just pay attention for pests in
our small plants it's really easy to
take care of them if we do get them but
we need to identify our problems early
so that we can conquer them before they
get out of control so go in and check
for pests every day check for powdery
mildew you should be able to spot it on
these little plants very easily it will
start in the center of a leaf it will
usually start at the widest point of one
of your biggest leaves and it will look
like somebody just took a little drop of
donut powdered sugar and just dropped it
right on your leaf it'll look like some
sort of white powdery water it dried up
and just left a little stain right there
that is the first indicator of powdery
mildew it will probably happen in a
lowlight area we are not getting a lot
of light but there is a lot of moisture
oftentimes it will happen or that little
bit of water just hangs on that one leaf
in that one spot and it never quite goes
away that's where you're going to get
the PM so pay attention for bugs pay
attention for powdery mildew our main
goal right now is to keep these plants
pests and pathogens free and keep them
developing strong healthy root systems
so that we have strong healthy plants
when it's time to transplant them and
then later move them into flower now
that your plants are starting to grow
and you've spent some time with them
you've probably seen what happens when
you over and under water them a little
bit you've probably done one or the
other which has probably caused a little
bit of funky leaves I encourage you to
pull off all of the ugly leaves if
you've got yellowing crispy leaves take
those off those yellow leaves are an
invitation for spider mites
that's why we use yellow sticky cards in
the garden to help the pests go to those
cards we see them on the cards and we
can tell that they're there but the past
love to go to that yellow they think
that is a weak leaf imagine you're a
hungry spider mite and you see a big
healthy robust leaf that's got a really
thick layer of healthy vegetation to
chew through before you can get some
nutrients out of it or imagine just a
little lower on the plant you've got a
weak leaf it's yellow on the outside
it's got a real thin layer and you can
just poke right through it suck all the
juice you want right out of it like a
hungry little vampire bug you are you're
gonna go right to those weak yellow
leaves it's not as much work for food
you can get right in there and get what
you need the spider mites are going
right for that yellow weak part so pull
off all those weak parts pull off all
the yellow leaves that's where the
problems are going to start anyway
that's where the plant is the weakest
get that out of there
now while you're pulling off leaves you
may notice that the couple of branches
at the very bottom of your plant are
just weak and shitty and kind of in the
way if you've got a couple of leaves
that are hanging down into the dirt pick
that stuff right off we don't need that
very bottom crap on the plant by the
time it makes it to flower we're going
to clean up the bottom eight to ten
inches of that stalk anyway those bottom
branches will not even be there I feel
like if you take some of those little
sucker branches off the bottom now it
will encourage growth up to the top of
the plant we don't need that stuff on
the bottom the light's not going to get
to it that's where the problems are
gonna happen why not cut that stuff
right off if you're happy with the way
your plants look without pruning
anything off the bottom you don't have
to do it but if you've got two or three
branches on the bottom that just aren't
growing to reach the rest of the
branches if they look weak why not take
them off we don't need that weak [ __ ]
down there at the bottom of the plant
wasting energy wasting nutrients and
wasting water let's just cut it right
off and send that energy right up to the
top of the plant
now as the plants get bigger you'll
notice they're starting to branch out a
little bit on the bottoms of some of the
branches you may start developing shoots
if those little shoots are weak you can
pinch those off as well you don't have
to take off the entire branch you can
just take off the shitty shoots at the
bottom and you can still leave the ends
of those branches and you can still have
more bud sites and more branches don't
take off too much now you can always
take off more in the future
you cannot glue branches back onto the
plant and keep in mind the plant grows
out of
top so the [ __ ] you take off the bottom
will not replace itself you're cleaning
up the bottom that is gone it's going to
grow out of the top keep that in mind
now let's talk a little bit about
nutrients I always recommend starting
off with light nutrients if your plants
are showing any yellow or if they're not
growing as quickly as you would like
them to you may need to increase the
overall amount of nutrients we are
giving the plants I always recommend
starting low and increasing as time goes
on if your plants are a little bit pale
or yellowish if they're not as green as
we would hope it would be at this point
it is probably time to increase our
nutrients also it may be time to add
some cal-mag to the mix if your plants
are growing properly if they're nice and
robust if they've got a nice root system
in this small pot I would recommend
adding a small dose of cal-mag once a
week to your feeding regimen if you feel
like you're feeding your plants properly
you're giving them a proper amount of
nitrogen you're giving them the proper
amount of Calem AG you're also giving
them some beneficials for the roots and
you're not seeing the growth you would
like to see I would suspect that it's
probably a pH issue check the pH of the
solution you were feeding your plants if
your pH is off your plants won't be able
to uptake nutrients which means they
will not grow so once you have mixed up
your nutrients put your pH pin in there
and see what the pH of that solution is
before you feed it to your plants if
it's not in the appropriate range adjust
it this is such an overlooked step most
of the time when people send me pictures
of their plants they say what is wrong
with my plant
I ask them what was the pH of your last
feeding solution you know what most of
their answers are I don't know so I
usually tell them check the pH and get
back to me because I would assume if
you're not checking the pH that is
probably the issue you didn't even
bother to check how do I know if you've
got another nutritional problem how do I
know if you're overfeeding or under
feeding a specific nutrient if I don't
know what the pH of your solution is
you've got to dial in the pH I've done
an entire episode on the importance of
pH for these small plants I really think
they would be happiest with a pH right
around 6 1 or 6 - you can go 5 8 2 6 3
if you really want to have a wide range
but I think 6 1 or 6 2 in cocoa or
soilless mix is going to be ideal for
these small plants
we may increase that pH as we go along
the growth process as we pay attention
to the plants and see how they react to
certain things but for now I think this
6.2 is right about where we need to be
all right so we've got clean healthy
plants we don't have any bugs we don't
have any powdery mildew we have
increased our nutrients to increase our
vigor and increase growth speed it is
probably time to spread your plants out
if they are too pressed together if
they're too crowded they're not going to
branch out properly so if you've got
them crushed in there real tight it's
time to spread them out if it looks like
your plants are getting too tall and too
skinny and too stretchy it's one of two
things they either want more light or
they are too close together which
probably just means they want more light
if you've got branches pressed together
if you've got leaves pressed together if
you've got plants overlapping each other
if you've got one plant pressed up
against the wall they know they're too
tight together and instead of branching
out they're gonna go straight up and try
to get some light they are all competing
for light space and you're probably
running your small veg under smaller
lights which means they're really
competing for that space if we crowd
them in spread them out let them get
some light light is the number one
desired nutrient and source of energy
for our plants over their entire life
cycles they want light more than
anything light is the key
these plants think they're going to get
the Sun and we brought them indoors and
wired up little t5 bulbs and we're
trying to make them grow with that so
spoil them and give them as much of that
t5 lighting as they can get give them as
much space as they can handle so that
you can get maximum performance from our
small plants so now I feel like we've
got healthy plants that are pest free
that are probably about eight to ten
inches tall we're starting to get nice
branching on the bottom we've cleaned up
those crappy branches on the bottom
we've pulled off any funky leaves we've
spread them out so that they're not too
crowded we are probably going to
transplant these plants into their
forever homes within the next week or
two that's going to be the next grow
lesson that I provide will be
transplanting into our forever homes I
think one thing we should really focus
on until we transplant is fat root
development I like my plants to be
nearly root bound in these small pots
before I transplant them I like to have
to kind of break that root ball up at
transplant to make it explode
it sounds crazy but if you get that root
ball kind of tight in a small pot when
we transplant it into the next pot it
will really take off we will really see
explosive growth we will have a really
robust and healthy plant from the very
beginning with a solid foundation so
let's let these plants grow and get kind
of tight in their pots you may see some
roots coming out of the bottom of your
container that is a good thing if those
roots are nice and white that means you
were feeding those roots very well that
your plants are very happy that they are
getting a nice amount of moisture that
they're getting a nice amount of dry
time that everything is going well
inside here rhizosphere now if you want
to take a look at your roots and see
what kind of root development you're
working with don't be afraid to grab a
cup or a pot with a plant in it and put
your finger over the pot and kind of
make a spa Kent where you're spreading
your ring finger and your middle finger
apart put the stock of the plant right
between those two fingers and then just
flick that pot upside down and give it a
little bit of a shake if you're
confident you can pull that pot off and
you can look directly at the root
development if you start lifting that
pot off and the dirt starts falling out
like crazy and it's not compact and
pressed together push it back in there
and just leave it alone the roots are
not developed enough to try this
experiment if you start lifting that pot
off and all the dirt stays in one piece
and you can see those roots you can just
lift that pot right off and you can take
a look at the root development if you
can see those roots wrapped around
inside of there and all the dirt and all
the roots are tight into one piece that
is what we're aiming for you are almost
ready for transplant I like to let those
get almost rootbound
where the plant is almost filling that
container with roots to where it is
almost panicking time to put that into a
new pot I feel like if we wait that long
to put it into our next pot we get
explosive root growth when we transplant
it into the next container I also feel
like we get less transplant shock and I
feel like the plant is more developed
and more prepared to go into its larger
container so if you are experienced or a
confident grab a plant flip it upside
down and knock the container off of it
and see what comes out if all the dirt
goes flying and the roots come
unraveling and hanging out just plant
that back in there really carefully and
it will be okay if you're careful about
it do your best not to break any of the
roots don't disturb the roots you can
get them back in there while you've got
it out sprinkle a little bit of root
document powder on there sprinkle some
plus life or some great white right onto
the roots and put it back in there and
that inoculant will encourage those
roots to grow even more quickly than
they already were all right podcast
world I'm going to press pause for a
moment I need to take a drink I'll
probably take a couple of dabs while I'm
at it when I get back we will talk more
about developing healthy roots and we
will also talk about Michael Raizel
fungus so take a dab with me and I will
be right back alright podcasts rolled I
am back I am well medicated I am well
hydrated let's talk more about healthy
roots and mycorrhizal fungus before we
transfer our small plants into their
forever homes we want to develop thick
healthy white roots we want a big fat
root system so that we've got a
well-established plant to go into a
larger pot a good microbe product will
encourage explosive root growth let's
talk about some of the other advantages
of our Michael Raizel fungus the first
obvious advantage is more roots more
roots means our plants can eat more
which means our plants can drink more
which means our plants will grow more
quickly which means we will produce more
branching which means we will produce
more buds which is our main goal
so the first benefit more roots which
means more productivity overall from our
plants another great function of our
beneficial fungus is they work as a
protective layer or a security guard for
our root zone they protect against
pathogen problems and illness in our
plants there is already a colony of
beneficial fungus gathered around the
roots if anything else tries to get near
it those colonies say hey this is our
turf bro and they fight off any
potential pathogens that want to get to
your root zone some of our beneficial
bacteria work in a similar function as
an enzyme it will break down decaying
matter it will break down nutrients and
it will make it more bioavailable to our
plants so our plants can take that waste
and actually turn it into food and
consume it and use it to its benefit now
if you are using a microbe product I
don't recommend that you stop using your
enzymes I recommend you use them
together let them team up and create a
beautiful environment in your raizo
sphere that will also create a lot of
diversity you will have multiple things
in there breaking down the decaying
matter that should really encourage a
clean healthy raizou sphere another
function of some of our beneficial
bacteria
is the aid and the processes that
encourage branching and bud set so by
introducing these beneficial bacteria
you may see more branching and you may
see more bud sites in your plants now
another great thing that these
beneficial bacteria is do is they were
to increase essential oil production now
what are essential oils essential oils
are our terpenes and cannabinoids you
can increase the overall production of
your plants you can increase the overall
flavor aroma and potency of your plants
by using be correct mycorrhizal fungus
now I try to avoid recommending brand
names there are several great Michael
Raizel products available at your local
grocer or there are tons available
online I will list a few products that I
have had great experience with of course
I have to recommend recharge I really
like recharge recharge made my plants go
crazy one of the good things about
recharge is it contains dried molasses
which is constantly feeding the microbes
the microbes do need some sort of feel
it's already got feel in that container
another acceptable myko product is
called extreme mykos and they spell
mykos with a k' it's a great product it
is very affordable you don't have to buy
a very expensive micro product if you
want something that's affordable if
you're just gonna try it out extreme
mykos is probably one of the most
affordable microbe products on the
market if you want a liquid microbe
product you can get Hydra guard from
botanic care I really like great white
great white is a powdered microbe
product I like the powders because you
can sprinkle them directly onto the
roots we're gonna talk more about that
when we get to the transplanting episode
but during transplant I like to sprinkle
the powders directly onto the roots and
into the hole where I am transplanting
my plant I also trance prinkle some
right around the outside where it's
gonna grow these beneficial fungus do
not work unless they actually touch the
roots of the plant so they have to touch
the plant that triggers them to
germinate and become alive so they have
to come in contact so sprinkle those
powders right onto the roots I really
like that if you want to stick with
liquid and use something similar to the
great white they make a product called
orca orcas very similar to the great
white they took out two specific
beneficial funguses but I
think you'll ever notice they're missing
it's just easier to keep them in a
liquid solution without that fungus in
their great white also makes a product
called my coach um I spoke earlier that
I like recharge because it's got a
product that feeds their beneficials
that comes in one package the folks that
make great white and Orca have put out a
product called my coach um that product
will feed your beneficials it also
contains unearth other things that will
encourage root growth and healthy plants
the folks that make great white and Orca
and my coach um also make a time-release
granule if I'm working in a large
container I like to start that pot with
some of the time-release granules
already in the soil I'll mix up a large
batch of soil with my amendments with my
perlite with my purse alight and then I
will just pour a big bag of the dried
granules from great white right across
the top of that makes it right in put
that into the pot and plant right into
that the plants go crazy I feel like
giving them plenty of that beneficial
bacteria really reduces transplant shock
and it really encourages explosive root
growth
another powdered root inoculant i can
recommend is the plus life from our
friends at veg bloom many of the
commercial grows in colorado are running
veg bloom so i would encourage them just
to add the plus life product right along
the veg bloom base mix I have had great
success using be veg bloom product line
and adding the plus life root inoculant
powder along with that mix and I've used
that and grows of all different sizes
I've used it in for light grows and I've
used it in 400 light grows and I like
the way it works in all conditions
alright I've got one more product to
talk about another great liquid microbe
product is mammoth pea mammoth pea is a
great product one of the great things
about mammoth pea is it is highly
concentrated another great thing is you
do not have to add anything to feed the
microbes mammoth pea uses microbes they
can sustain themselves off of the carbon
in the breakdown happening within the
raizo sphere so that is a list of great
microbe products I would recommend they
vary in application rates they vary in
amount of microbes per container and
they are going to vary widely in prices
find what works best for you and your Go
in some of you are going to enjoy the
dried powdered forms more some of you
are going to like the liquid forms more
some of you simply cannot get the
overpriced expensive products some of
you will only buy the overpriced
expensive products I get it everybody's
got their style that's why I recommended
several products I have used each of
those products I've had great experience
with those products and I feel like I
can recommend those products to you with
confidence that they're going to work in
your garden under just about any type of
conditions or any type of environment
now keep in mind that you may need to
feed your microbes I mentioned earlier
that some of the microbes do contain
other additives it will feed themselves
I will still encourage you to feed the
microbes the microbes want to eat carbs
the plants want to eat carbs add a
little bit of carbohydrates the
carbohydrates will give your plants
energy and the carbohydrates will feed
your microbes it's a win-win situation
don't overdose the carbs trying to feed
them both I generally suggest starting
off with half of the recommended dose if
you buy a bottle of a carbohydrate
product and it says feed 40 I recommend
you start off with 20 pay attention if
the plant seemed happy you don't need to
increase the dosage if you want to you
can increase the dosage until you see
the plants react poorly that's what a
lot of growers like to do push it as
hard as we can and then back off that's
how you learn the limits of a plant but
if you're a newer grower if you're not
super experienced just feed it half of
that recommended dosage and the plants
will be receiving that nutrition even if
you don't see anything happening be
careful overdoing it with the
carbohydrate product late and flour
because it will make your buds burn like
a rock they'll just turn into a charcoal
briquette and they won't burn very well
if you overdo it with the molasses or a
carbohydrate product late in bloom now
earlier I mentioned my coach um if you
want a quality product to feed your
microbes and encourage micro growth and
encourage root growth and overall plant
health check out my coach um from the
same folks that make the great white
product line now when it comes to
feeding your microbes
I recommend more frequent smaller doses
now the first time I introduced microbes
to my feeding regimen I usually give it
what the bottle says if the container
says one gram or 25 milliliters I will
add that to my new
treant solution and i will water that
right in my goal is to get a good start
of a colonization of microbes I just
want to give it a good head start just
put them in there and get them going
then my subsequent waterings I will
probably give it half of the recommended
dosage but those products usually say to
water it in once a week instead of doing
it once a week I'll reduce the dosage to
half and water it every time I water for
a couple of weeks to build a nice solid
colony of beneficial fungus in my raizo
sphere now after I transplant into my
three gallon pots and I get the root
zone crankin and I've got a nice fat
root ball in that pot I will start
reducing my frequency of inoculant
feedings in a commercial grow when I'm
in flower I generally feed plus life
once a week and that's enough through
the flowering cycle once I've got the
roots nice and healthy and everything
has developed I will generally use the
plus life to keep problems away it keeps
the root zone nice and clean a nice
enzymatic product and a nice Michael
Raizel product again will work to keep
the roots clean and healthy and happy
and pathogen free so I'll just continue
the once a week feeding just to keep
everybody clean and happy and kind of
it's sort of like plant probiotics it's
like giving probiotics to a plant if you
take probiotics for your gut health it
just has it good you've got a good gut
biome we were making a good gut biome
for our plants by feeding them
probiotics which are actually Michael
Raizel fungus when it comes to the plant
world
all right podcast world I've got one
more thing to talk about and then we
were going to start wrapping up this
episode when you were listening or
reading or learning about Michael Raizel
fungus you will hear three words quite
frequently that basically mean the same
thing you will hear the word inoculated
you will hear the word vaccinated and he
will also hear the word infected these
words all basically mean that the root
zone shows the presence of a mycorrhizal
fungus we inoculate our root zone with a
fungus by adding it ourselves we have
now inoculated it once that takes hold
it is basically
vaccinated once it travels across the
root zone it is infected that is a
positive thing I know they sound like
scary words but in this situation all
three of those words are positive things
that we want happening within our raizo
sphere so when you hear the word
inoculated vaccinated or infected keep
in mind it just means basically the
presence of Michael Raizel fungus within
our root zone all right podcast world
that is my talk about continuing small
healthy feds that is also my lesson on
Michael Raizel fungus I want to thank
you guys for listening to this episode
if you were interested in learning a lot
more about Michael Raizel fungi I highly
recommend a podcast called cannabis
cultivation and sciences by tad Hussey
tad recently had Jim Egan on the show
and they do a deep dive into Michael
Raizel fungus and I highly recommend the
episode it was great timing I had
already planned this episode to come out
this week I was writing this episode and
then Monday this episode popped up it
was beautifully time so you've got a
nice introduction from me and then tad
takes it really deep if you're going to
listen to Tad's podcast I highly
recommend a notebook and a pen you are
going to learn a lot about cultivation
you will learn a lot about organic
cultivation you learn about
sustainability you will learn about
permaculture and he will certainly learn
about Michael Raizel fungi again the
podcast is called cannabis cultivation
and sciences and I highly recommend it
if you want to expand your cultivation
knowledge podcast world that's all I've
got for you for this episode I want to
thank you again for listening again if
you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
and you would like to make a financial
contribution to the show I would
appreciate your support and you can
contribute by going to patreon.com slash
grow from your heart all the information
you need to become a patron will be
right there on the screen and just a
reminder patreon recently did an update
that discontinued a lot of auto
subscriptions if you feel like you were
signed up to contribute to a patreon
campaign I encourage you to log into
your patreon account and make sure you
were still supporting all the content
providers which you think you were
signed up to give contributions to and
once again I owe a huge thank you to
everyone who is contributed to my
patreon campaign thank you all for all
of the support I would also appreciate
it if you find me on social media you
can find me on Facebook simply search
for the girl for me
our podcast on Twitter it's @gf wih
podcast if you want to follow my
personal Twitter account it's at Rasta
Jeff 420 if you've got something you'd
like to say and you're not into the
social media maybe you'd like to sponsor
the podcast perhaps you've got a product
you'd like me to review maybe you've
just got a question you can reach me
through email my email address is grow
from your heart at hotmail.com I would
love to hear from you don't forget that
the show is available on iTunes stitcher
and most reputable podcast services also
every episode is available on youtube go
to youtube.com and search for the Grove
from your heart podcast I would
appreciate it if you click Subscribe
maybe type some comments and some videos
show the podcast a little bit of YouTube
love and support I would appreciate that
all right podcast world I will be back
Monday with a fresh new episode we will
talk about transplanting our small
plants into their forever homes I look
forward to that episode I can't wait to
join you there I want to give a huge
shout out to my friend hot sauce Herman
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me