[Music]
anyway MJ up here my pocket I'm a rocket
$100 when you see me not part me and Sh
got to started in the max what we BR
$100 you see the house where we live car
that we drive a we get it $100 and night
yeah what's up ladies and gentlemen
welcome to episode number 37 of the igro
culture podcast it's me again Rost Jeff
thanks for joining me joining me on the
microphone today is Jesse from hyro how
you doing bro how's it going guys doing
pretty good dude thanks for coming right
on uh in this episode Jesse and I are
going to talk a little bit about
building your grow space honestly this
may end up being a multi-episode
discussion because I know we're going to
leave stuff out we're going to forget
things uh we took quite a few notes we
wrote quite a bit of stuff down and the
more I wrote the more I feel like we
were Miss missing so we're going to try
to keep notes on what we're missing
while we go and we'll keep this
conversation
going but before we get to that part we
got to pay some bills this podcast is
brought to you by cannabis Grand
crew cannabis Grand crew Aspen will take
place at the Sky Hotel in Downtown Aspen
Colorado Friday November 14th through
Sunday November 16th
2014 what is Grand crew I'm glad you
asked Grand crew represents cannabis
culture lifestyle business and community
in a premier event setting the event
includes Le lectures seminars
experiential learning and entertainment
centered around the Cannabis business in
the US and around the world industry
professionals and consumers alike are
invited to network and enjoy this year's
event in beautiful Aspen Colorado make
sure you visit the Grand crew Village an
area exclusive to ticket holders that
will host Colorado's best dispensaries
including Wellspring Collective from
Denver and Silver Peak Apothecary and
Aspen located at the sky hotel at their
legendary pull Deck The Village will
showcase the latest products from Top
manufacturers and companies in this very
intimate setting this is a members only
event due to the current nature of laws
in the state of Colorado attendance at
cannabis EV events must be by invitation
in order to protect the event and our
guests please complete the information
request at the bottom of their website
for your free membership members will be
sent information directly on how to
purchase tickets located in Majestic
Aspen and nestled in the Rocky Mountains
the event will take advantage of the
amazing community and provide networking
and fun for folks in the legal cannabis
industry new speakers are being
announced every day confirmed speakers
include Mason TT John Hunt and Meg
Collins check out cannabis grandc
crew.com for details want want to give a
big huge shout out to the grimy Gatsby
make sure you say hi to the grimy Gatsby
while you're at cannabis Grand
crew I'm not sure if I'm going to that I
might be there I might not if I cannot
make it I'll give away the ticket on
this show sounds fancy it's going to be
fancy it's an aspen it's a little far
from here and I have things going on
that week so I'm not I'm not sure I want
to go really badly but somebody may end
up with a free ticket so we'll keep
going this podcast is also brought to
you by our good friends at Highly
Educated titanium if you're using a
high-grade concentrate you deserve a
high-grade titanium nail don't trust a
chinese nail or an American knockoff
made of cheap Metals trust the industry
leader trust Highly Educated titanium
I'm dabbing Cup winning extracts and the
only nail I put my on my rig is a highly
educated nail for more information on
Highly Educated products check out
highly educated ti.com and highly
educated products are available at
aqualab technologies.com
this podcast is also brought to you by
Natures green remedies.com visit natur
green remedies.com for gag green
genetics L Plato Labs Sin City rare
dankness mile high can Aventure alphac
chronic bog MTG the Cali Connection IE
genetics and many many more trusted
Brands Nature's green is running a
coupon or running a special for the
podcast listeners type in coupon code
Harvest 14 for 15% off any order and you
always get free shipping at naturegreen
remedies.com that coupon code expires on
Halloween so check them out today this
podcast is also brought to you by our
good friends at hyro indoor growing
supplies want to thank Jesse for helping
us out big shout out to burn hyro indoor
growing supplies has two locations to
serve Colorado visit the Denver store at
6271 Beach Street or stop by the Pueblo
location on 618 East 4th Street in PUO
Colorado check out Hy gr for very
competitive pricing and a great
selection of indoor grow supplies uh I
shop at Hydro you guys I wouldn't talk
about a hydro shop that I didn't support
that's where I go to get all my goodies
uh I just got a new carbon filter they
took really good caring me on that I got
some ogt they've got all the Botanicare
stuff I need go check them out here's
one more quick ad big love to our
friends at Tre thug.com this episode is
brought to you in part by tree Thugger
dcom live music lifestyle magazine check
out tree Thugger decom for concert and
Festival news and reviews
www.re thug.com all right that's enough
commercials for today we're going to get
on with some show uh Jesse and I are
here uh last night Jesse hosted a small
gathering for Growers over at hyro uh
the party was a huge success dude yeah
yeah had a uh
great great response great turnout I was
really stoked about it we didn't really
advertise Jesse didn't advertise much it
was kind of a test run we just wanted to
kind of see what would happen uh he
wanted to see what would happen we had
about 12 people there for most of the
evening evening I'd say about 20 people
showed up for the peak of the night when
uh Spence and Maddie and Big Mike and
Michael showed up that made about 20
people in the room uh big shout out to
everybody that came the people that I
met the people that I already knew
thanks for coming and supporting
something like that big huge thanks to
bernon Jesse and hyro for letting us
Gather in the store that was a great
time yeah it was fun had some pizza we
had some pizza uh thanks for feeding me
dude that was great uh last night was
kind of just a test run to see how many
people we could get to show up so do you
plan on doing this more yeah yeah we're
going to set a date um real soon for
next month um probably on Monday cool
try to make it like a monthly event yeah
yeah sweet uh who's invited can anybody
come yeah yeah um it's 21 and up um but
uh you know um anyone's invited uh just
come down to the store and ask for you
know info or whatever so cool or uh
didn't you did you make a Facebook page
or anything for it yeah oh yeah yeah um
there was a Facebook event yeah so so I
will on my uh I don't think I can do it
from the iire genetics page or from the
igro culture page but I can do it from
my personal I'll make an event or I'll
share Jesse's event as soon as the next
the next one comes up and we'll talk
about it on the show and we'll let you
guys know uh we hope to get more Growers
from the pbl peblo area coming out to
the Gathering uh we'll announce it for
sure when we get it figured out
hopefully we can get some listeners out
there and meet the people they come
shake our hands and we can find out who
we're talking to for sure armo we want
you to come to one yeah yeah all right
so um we were talking about building
your Grow rooms and last night there
were actually some new Growers at the
party and we got to help them build
pretty sweet room it was kind of nice to
they're like we don't know what to do
and Jesse and I looked at each other and
it was neat cuz we had the exact same
idea in our heads we're like do this and
they pretty much are going to do that I
think yeah uh so in this show we're
going to talk about a few different ways
to set up a grow space uh that is
suitable for your production needs I
also o found a comment on the Facebook
page that asks for guidance in building
a space for
$500 uh that's a really tight budget for
a grow room but I'll see what I can come
up with I Googled a few items uh to try
to save some pennies but that's a
challenge dude 500 bucks um how big is
the space well she just said help me out
teach me how to build a space for 500
bucks she said she's uh on a very low
budget uh I have her Facebook comment
I'd have to read to remember exactly
what she said but I think she's also
disabled so we're going to have to build
her something that's not heavy that's
not a lot work yeah I have an idea
that's accessible and I want to build
like a PVC frame and then wrap it in
some sort of myar type thing and then uh
maybe hang a small T5 light in there
yeah and that'll get her going you know
we'll talk more about that we'll get
that going once we get into the uh the
building the grow stuff a little more uh
let's talk about building grows uh
there's a few things to consider when
you're going to plan your grow before
you even go to the hardware store before
you ever go to the hydro shop there's
stuff you got to think about the first
thing to think about in my opinion is is
it legal where you are uh I'm not going
to help you break the law the first part
of this is uh move to a location where
Canabis is is legal if you want to
follow my rules so don't do this in an
illegal State move to Colorado go to
California or even better do what you
can to get cannabis legalized or
decriminalized where you are so that you
can grow legally I don't want to be
responsible for you breaking the law so
if you plan on Breaking the Law just
change to another
podcast all right uh
sorry I don't want I don't want to go to
I don't want you to go to jail for what
I'm telling you but you're going to do
what you're going to do so uh the next
thing to think about uh understand the
risk you're taking because if you're
growing in a state that's not legal the
consequences can be quite severe it's
not just you you're putting at risk uh
if you're growing in a house everybody
in that house is in trouble uh if you
have a family and you go to jail that's
going to just cause a tidal wave of
[ __ ] in your life so keep that in
mind uh the next thing that I would say
to think about is what are your
realistic needs if you're committed
you're going to grow some cannabis for
yourself what are your realistic needs
do you need to grow for yourself your
family uh maybe a few patients or are
you trying to become the next big
production facility in your area so my
next idea would be set a goal and kind
of stick with that for a few Cycles to
see what you're doing you can't you're
not going to know how good of a grower
or what kind of crop you get on the
first grow stick with that set something
up stick with it for a couple of cycles
and then adjust to your needs after
you've gone a couple rounds like don't
run your first lap and then think my
shoes are too tight my shoes are too
loose run a couple laps see what you're
good at then adjust so my next thing to
consider I would say is does your
location have viable
electricity um this is something Jesse
really stressed on when he got here to
talk about this uh running more than one
or two th000 watt lights in a room may
require some electrical upgrades if you
want to be safe if your Breakers are
flipping and you're scrambling to keep
everything running that's when you're
creating a fire hazard yeah and you
don't want to be on the news for burning
down your house grown weed no
uh in your experience can you usually
just run like a th000 watt light the
blower that it requires and a couple of
fans and if you have like a hydro
bubbler or whatever is that pretty much
what one room can do yeah most most
residential rooms have about 30 30 amps
30 amp breaker yeah so that you're and
if you're putting an air conditioner in
there you're taking up half a breaker
just with that the light takes up about
half a breaker uh if you're flip in the
breaker when you turn on the dishwasher
or whatever uh have an electrician come
and help you out there are a lot of
electric
actually if you're in the PUO area I
have an electrician that I will refer
because he's looking for some work he's
off and he could use your uh your job so
uh don't burn down the house please
please don't burn down the house don't
create that fire hazard with electricity
also if you're in illegal in an illegal
State this is something I just thought
of you're going to have to have an
excuse for all that
electricity yeah if your 1,000 watt
light is going to kick your light bill
up about $100 per month an additional
like the light and the fan and the
blower it takes to run it you're looking
about another $100 every every month uh
if you're just a dude in an apartment or
something like that that may spark some
concerns you might want to get a hot tub
uh we've heard of people using welding
equipment just get something to kind of
make it look like you're doing something
put a bunch of table saws in the garage
if you've got that option you know look
like you have some more for that powder
consumption to go empty empty saltwater
fish
tanks uh but you know all of that stuff
I bet you they can tell that my timers
are on 1212 over at the crow you know
they're like like oh yeah every day at
8:00 this guy kicks on thousands of
watts and then every day at 8:00 they
kick off they're not [ __ ] sorry if
[ __ ] is an offensive or to you uh so
will you be able to ventilate your space
is the next thing I would think about uh
fresh air is super important stale
stagnant humid air is the number one
cause for powdery mildew it'll also slow
your growth it makes your plants look
ugly makes room stink you want to be
able to walk into your grow room and
close your eyes and not smell pot you
want it to smell like a nice clean room
so keep that in mind you have to be able
to ventilate that space number five on
my list of things that you should
consider is your grow space safe and
secure you may need to hide your grow
from the landlord or your nosy in-laws
that come over for dinner are you ready
to live the grow life in your house that
doesn't sound like a huge question but
dude when you've got pot plants in your
house your whole house will stink if you
don't have it under control you might
need some carbon filters you might need
an extra carbon filter or two um I
always have a carbon filter on the air
that is going out the exhaust
but then also I'll hang a carbon filter
with a blower on it just right in the
middle of the room on the ceiling to act
as a scrubber just to clean even more
air and that eliminates more odor uh we
were talking about Ona gel last night
they sell Ona jar Ona gels in like a
plastic jar they say to take the lid off
and just leave it sitting but I actually
poke little pencil size holes with the
drill right in the lid and then just let
it sit and then once it gets down to
about a third of the jar I just add like
a half a cup of water in there and shake
it and it rehydrates all the crystals
and it lasts a little longer uh put
those by your door like your entryway to
your home or entry way to wherever
you're growing and people's nose will
hit that first and now their nose is
already kind of they've been punched so
they're confused and when they smell the
herb they won't know that it's herb
hopefully yeah so you can put them in
inside your ducting too oh yeah that's a
good idea there you go it'll blow that
move that odor around instead of the
Cannabis odor I'm going to add a random
side note this is just a really random
sidebar cuz I just thought about it I
keep hearing a lot of people say the
word marijuana marijuana is a racist
word and it sounds bad people are afraid
of marijuana cannabis is the new word uh
cannabis sounds better it doesn't sound
as racist and I know that's a weird way
to put it but we were taught that
marijuana is the devil and if you smoke
marijuana you're going to get crazy and
rape white [ __ ] cannabis will heal
you cannabis stops cancer so I think we
should just try to abandon the word
marijuana and say cannabis a lot more
that's just my random uh sidebar for the
day marijuana actually literally is a
racist word it was yeah I mean yeah yeah
don't don't doubt that people it was
invented by the government to that's a
huge history lesson uh to discriminate
against Mexicans yeah they didn't like
the Mexicans that were coming to America
and smoking marijuanas yeah and then
bringing it to the Jazz musicians that's
all reer Madness you guys hopefully you
know about that already and hopefully no
hopefully you're not that brainwashed
and you never paid attention to that
hopefully you just call it cannabis all
right uh safe and secure grow space
living the grow life another big thing
to consider is the location of your grow
inside of your house or wherever you're
doing it uh the basement is generally
the coolest spot you're insulated by
dirt and concrete walls and you're
underground you don't get a lot of
climate changes there in the basement
also hopefully you don't get a lot of
traffic down there in the basement you
got like one room in the corner in the
back or something you can just dedicate
uh the attic is going to get hot the
attic is the top of the house it's
getting hit by the sun um you don't have
all this insulation from the dirt and
the concrete walls the attic is going to
be a little more challenging so you're
going to need more cooling power you're
going to have to adjust your snow melts
off the or the snow melts off your roof
in the middle of the winter and it's the
only house in the neighborhood you're
the only house that your roof is clean
because you just melt yeah uh I've had
to make an adjustment because I noticed
that I was melting snow somewhere one
year I was like oh that's obvious as
[ __ ] uh also guys this is something
we'll cover cover a little later but I
want to jump to it you're going to have
to get water there so putting your
plants in the Attic uh once you get all
the grow equipment hung up up there and
everything's up there now you have to
get water up there often so keep that in
mind um and then another go ahead you
got something to add adct just if you
can avoid it's just really not a good
place to grow it's actually a pretty
pretty good uh fire hazard oh yeah so I
mean uh it's uh I mean a significant
fire hazard um
so avoid addict at all cost if you're in
like Wisconsin or something though and
you can't really do it like we can here
in Colorado nobody goes to anybody
else's atcts so that may be someone's
only option for sure guys like we we
were talking about earlier be safe and I
know this sounds cheesy as hell but
safety first bro you don't want to be on
the news for burning down your house
growing pot because when the news comes
you might have been growing legal
medical cannabis but as soon as that
fire starts and the News truck pulls out
you've got a drug lab yeah they're not
going to be polite this this medical
marijuana provider accidentally sparked
fire to his home now the report's going
to say we're here in front of this house
where there's a major drug lab on fire
right now that's what the reports and
you're going to be the [ __ ] that just
went to jail for doing that that was a
nice news voice you like that yeah yeah
sounded really weird in the headphones I
had to bail on it kind of quickly um so
yeah try to go lower in the house is
better um in PUO they're trying to
actually push push an ordinance to where
we have to grow in an out building and I
was reading a book doing research on
this and in Jorge cant book he says
outbuildings are actually the worst
place you could think about growing
because that's where thieves are and the
cops don't consider that trespassing so
they can go into your outb building it's
not part of your home oh nice yeah so
the cops can walk right in that's not
it's a different rule you know it's not
part of your domicile it's a shed so
they can walk right into that they don't
need a warrant that's something we got
to remind all the people that are
opposed to this of Mike did you just
hear that bro your out building that
they're trying to propose that we build
will not be part of your home so it will
not require a warrant is what this book
that Jorge cantes wrote says let me know
how that really works
shout out to Mike he's my legal counsel
um growing in a shed has a lot of
challenges too um so it it's going to be
a lot like growing in an attic as far as
uh trying to insulate it and cool it
okay all that it's going to be very
difficult and I guess I should uh one
more thing The Next Step here is how are
you going to cool the room keep in mind
that you have to use more electricity
for that air conditioner and the air
conditioner has to vent itself somewhere
so you keep in mind how you're going to
cool the room um I had a good point that
I wanted to make and it just left my
head what were you just telling
me what was that with the with the sheds
yeah the sheds okay what our goal is I
guess I should have covered this more in
the beginning but your goal when you're
building a grow room you want as much
control of the lights the air the water
the humidity the temperature that's what
we're trying to do we're trying to build
a room that we can control to set the
ideal climate for these plants uh I
guess it we should instead of just
starting building a room we should know
what we're trying to build right and
that's what you want you want a room
that you can almost automate and let
that happen and just turn everything on
properly get everything set up properly
and let it run and then when the night
time comes you have a nighttime
temperature selected it'll get to that
when the daytime comes again you have a
daytime temp selected the air
conditioner kicks on at the right time
your fans move at the right time your
blowers are all at the right schedule
then you can hit that perfect like 50%
humidity or 40% humidity mark you can
get your 77 degree Mark in there uh you
can get it all perfect you can have just
a little bit of
wind that's what you're trying to do
you're trying to build that super happy
trying to build an aquarium for your
plants or like a cage for plants like
the perfect habitat for these plants a
sub climate inside your house inside
your house yeah that that's your goal I
guess I should have talked more about
that at the beginning um once you
achieve that you know pretty dial in
perfect climate uh growing becomes a lot
easier a lot lot easier the the room is
the room the genetics uh this what
you're feeding and then the grow like
how you grow that's pretty much what
your components are y uh lights air
water soil and love you know cleanliness
cleanliness is Next to Godliness when it
comes to Growing every little piece of
trash or scrap and not just in your grow
room if your grow room is in like your
mom's basement or your Grandma's Attic
or your bedroom closet all of those
clothes all those books all those scraps
of paper all those cigarette butts all
the dust that's all a place for a
spidermite to hide that's all a place
for a thrip to lay a bug also all that
dust and cigarette smoke will end up in
your concentrate and in your flowers if
you're I've kind of stop sweeping my
grow room now after about week six
because I don't want to stir up the dust
and put it in my flowers I will let my
grow room look a little shitty on the
floor for a week to not sweep it up as
often cuz I don't and I'll turn off all
the fans and blowers and air condition
now to sweep up CU I don't want that
sticking to my buds because that ends up
in the hash and we're trying to make the
best hash we can now that's that's seems
to be the point that everybody's headed
to I still try to grow the best flowers
but of course we want the best hash to
go with that yeah all right that was a
long rant uh other than things to
consider there are responsibilities that
I think you should uh practice being a
good
grower um when you're setting up to grow
you don't want to piss off the neighbors
you don't want to attract unwanted
attention by thieves or thugs you don't
want to get cop attention you definitely
this is something people don't think
about there are kids out there that love
to steal pot plants now uh kids are
getting braver the younger kids are
getting dumber and braver they know what
pot is they know how to find a grow and
they want to steal your [ __ ] so keep the
pot and there's also innocent kids that
will just see your pot and want to steal
it just because they're curious so be
careful keep your pot away from the kids
I know I stress that but I'm a father so
I don't want my kid finding your pot
sorry I needed a drink that was a long
rant so some of the responsibilities
that I think and I want to thank my
friends on Facebook for helping me out I
asked for a couple of uh pieces of
advice on this topic and a few people
chimed in I ow owe a huge shout out to
Mr Chris barowitz
uh you guys know Chris barowitz you'll
know why this is funny you can Google
his name if you want uh I asked Chris
barowitz or asked on Facebook what would
be a few things you could do to be a
responsible grower and not get yourself
in trouble Chris's replied was don't do
interviews great answer I love it that's
that's the golden answer right there uh
Chris is finally free after that
interview and welcome home bro you look
good in that iy genetics t-shirt so a
few responsibilities being a grower uh
make sure your lights are not visible
from the outside uh when you set up your
grow room and the sun goes down turn on
all your grow lights walk outside
whatever if you're in the basement attic
bedroom walk outside and see if you can
see your grow lights if you can see your
grow lights fix it you're failing that's
a problem that also means you have a
light leak yeah that means the lights
are getting in during your flowering
cycle which are just going to cause a
bunch of
hermaphrodites also your next
responsibility make sure the blowers and
fans are not heard by neighbors or
people walking past your grow uh if
there's a spot where you don't think
people will ever walk the day you build
a damn grow someone's going to walk
there the meter made the gas guy uh some
kid chasing his dog some cop looking for
someone else going to walk right past
that blower and they're going to go oh
what is this and you're going to think
no one's ever going to walk there but as
soon as you put a blower there dude they
will that's the way life works so just
be careful plan ahead make sure no one
can hear your blowers make sure no one
can see your lights there's ways to
muffle you know even to insulating the
duct insulating the blower uh you can
disguise Outlets as a dryer Outlet yeah
you can try to put it through the roof
or you know just move the blower to the
other end of the chain so it's not so
noisy yeah not right at the window yeah
uh those Mufflers are a great idea
they're actually available at high grow
window or growing supplies yeah and
actually um a cheaper alternative to the
mufflers and uh better for your grow is
a hea filter yes those will you know if
it's sucking in those will help uh you
know over uh all of my ends where I have
I've drilled like 6inch holes or 8 in
holes to have my ends coming in I get
those little square HEPA filters they're
just a sheet I guess they're a rectangle
and I just staple right over it with a
staple gun onto the wall for sure yeah
wherever I do a grow you want yeah that
keeps your bugs out keeps all this stuff
that you don't want in your hat it keeps
all that out of there filter everything
twice twice if you
can people are going oh my God how much
is this going to cost building a good
grow room does cost a little bit of
money people were asking last night
they're like we've got this much budget
should we buy better this or better this
and that's kind of where I I think you
should get the best bulbs and ballast
you can that's your first start and then
moving your air and then like if you
have to buy in chunks I think you buy
the lights and then your air moving
stuff like you're ducting your blowers
and then your air conditioner and then
you buy your pots and soil and nutrients
uh start with the room and just buy
slowly instead of but yeah it's all that
choosing where the weakest link is
always going to be the weakest link yeah
it's hard to decide where to pinch your
budget there get the good bulbs and good
ballasts that's definitely my opinion so
uh here's a big issue that we've been
dealing with here in peblo this caus
cused a lot of most of our new laws here
that are being proposed in PUO are
because of this issue make sure nobody
can smell your grow the smell is the
most offensive and revealing part of
your grow yes I said offensive there are
some people that do not love the smell
of Sweet Sweet Sticky ganja in the
morning there's a guy here in our city
that keeps complaining to city council
that he can smell pot every day when he
wakes up because his neighbors are
growing the Dank not a fan yeah keep
that smell down uh if you build your
grow discreetly and you don't bring
attention to your neighbors will never
know you've got to grow in your home
it's a security issue too being able to
I mean yeah oh yeah you know don't you
know that's just inviting people in man
or people not only thieves but mooches
like you make more friends than you've
ever wanted when people find out you
grow weed can I uh can I get one of
those buds no dude what are you talking
about man what buds there's a dead skunk
in my backyard I don't know what you're
talking about [ __ ] dog got spred
again you know uh several years ago I
lived in another house and I had a grow
in the basement there and the power went
out and I was midflower so it's stinks
dude and the um the power guys had to
come through everybody's backyard
looking for the problem and I wasn't at
the place but my girlfriend was there
and the power guy told my girlfriend
ma'am I'd go in the house it smells like
you got a skunk in the backyard like he
could smell my grow completely and she
just made a cringing face and went in
the house and told me about it later but
yeah so people can smell your even if
you can't smell it people can smell your
grow you're around it you sleep by it
you're in there you wake up you're
smoking it uh you're the you're the last
person that's going to smell it yeah the
church lady down the block can smell it
down the street so don't let anybody
smell your grow here's step number four
to be a good responsible grower when
you're building a grow room do whatever
it takes to make sure no kids get ever
get into your grow space I stuttered
when I said that cuz I mean it make sure
no kids ever get into your grow space
that's important
uh that's like the biggest black eye you
can put on the Cannabis Community right
now is letting kids get caught with your
weed yeah here's something you might not
think about most of the stuff was kind
of uh kind of obvious but here's a good
one you're going to create a lot of
waste growing plants in your house
you're going to have soil you're going
to have plant stems and stocks you're
going to have root balls find a
responsible way to dispose of everything
um some of you guys live out in the
rural areas burn that [ __ ] if you can uh
us compost it compost it if you can
that's yeah but see I in the city and my
girl is in a city facility and so it's
all got to be chopped up into little
tiny pieces and put into secured trash
bags and it's got to be destroyed on
site like so you other guys you're going
to have to find what if the trash guy is
dump in your trash and finds all your
pot leaves in Connecticut when you're
growing pot uh what if he's not cool
what if he is cool then he's going to
want your weed and he's going to rob you
if he is not cool he's calling the cops
so be careful uh they might find your
trash that's they cannot from Jorge's
book that I read they cannot start a
case based on your trash that does not
justify a search warrant but the trash
can be used in court as part of the case
so evidence yep keep an eye on the trash
actually know people I lived in Lawrence
Kansas and now that I think about it I
know people that got busted and had
their trash used as evidence in court
now that I think about it I can't
remember their names but uh couple of
kids I worked at a place with what's up
guys I I've heard that uh for you know
drug drug dealing cases back in the day
and stuff find that tape they wrap
around the packaging yeah I had that
happen to a friend too I worked at a
bowling alley and I found a bunch of
that tape that dark colored tape and you
could tell it was wrapped around like a
I've seen plenty of pounds of weed like
brick pounds of weed I don't know if it
was wrapped around weed or some cocaine
or something but it was that kind of
tape and I know exactly somebody had a
nice bulk of something in my bowling
alley one night wow you found that in
the trash at the bowling alley in the
trash in the bathroom just sitting on
the top so you're telling me that
someone at evidence lockup may have been
crooked
no not the evidence tape that would that
would be a lot cooler you know that like
brown tape they wrapped the kilos with
it was a bunch of that so somebody had a
kilo of Coke or a pound of weed in the
bowling alley which isn't really
surprising now that I'm thinking about
it yeah bowling alleys are kind of
sketchy places that people don't think
about so think about what you guys are
going to do with your trash Guys you got
a bunch of [ __ ] you're going to have to
throw away and not look obvious with it
if you've got more than two lights when
you harvest four lights worth of stuff
three lights worth of stuff that's a lot
of trash to take care of and if you
don't know what to do if you don't know
how to recycle and compost your soil
you've got soil to deal with too uh it's
got perlite in it it's got old nutrients
in it you got to be
careful uh here's another one keep your
yard and house clean and presentable
don't give your neighbors or anyone in
the neighborhood a reason to dislike you
don't stand out if the house is on your
block get the lawn mode once a week go
mow the lawn once a week if they got
flowers growing outside and it's a bunch
of yuppies look like a bunch of yuppies
and grow hour outside dude try to fit in
the best you can don't be just don't be
the neighborhood [ __ ] if you're going
to grow cannabis uh help out you know if
when it snows shovel the extra house in
front or house next door on each side of
you just do what you can to kind of be
friendly a friend of mine Amanda on
Facebook said she actually just moved
into a new house and she's building her
grow in there in a legal state so I can
talk about her she said she walked to
her neighbors on either side and
introduced herself and said hey my
name's Amanda I'm the new neighbor
here's my phone number if you ever have
any problems feel free to call me if you
guys ever want to hang out just let me
know so by making friends and giving
them her number she's done two things uh
if they get pissed off at her they won't
call the cops they'll call her or
they'll come over and be like hey dude
you're Grateful Dead music St Dam loud
can you hippies chill out with the drum
circle in here sorry Amanda I hope
you're listening to that and then uh
she'll stop you know and then also if
something's wrong they don't have to
call 911 they can call her and be like
your house is glowing like there's a
bunch of light coming from the basement
window your curtain fell what's
happening they have to get to the cops
right away so just be a good neighbor
introduce yourself make friends be
social that's my point uh number seven
we've talked about this don't burn the
place down and make us all look like
[ __ ] uh this cannabis Revolution is
new uh there are tons of people who hate
the movement Fox News hates us uh
anytime some dip [ __ ] burns down a house
by blasting indoors or overpowering his
breaker box it makes the entire movement
looks stupid so please guys don't be the
[ __ ] we see on Fox News like I said
earlier they're not going to say this
medical marijuana provider had a snafu
they're going to say this drug lab
erupted in Flames uh and you're going to
be on the news and handcuffs in the back
of a cop car looking like a [ __ ]
please don't be that
guy please and there's there's no reason
to grow equipment is pretty cheap
nowadays don't don't use some sketchy
ass old [ __ ] if you're running a bunch
of Lights get yourself a power box plug
it into the 240 and plug all the lights
into that and you're pretty much legit
you can run like eight lights on that
thing oh N9 or 12 yeah yeah yeah um I've
seen like 16 light ones um but uh yeah
you know an electrical upgrades aren't
really that expensive so if you're going
nuts you know do it the right way don't
run extension cords all over the D no
each extension cord is a fire hazard
each one uh if you need electrical
upgrades guys just call Craigslist is
filled with electricians that advertise
that they are MMJ friendly or 420
friendly get one of those get one of
those guys to come wire up your [ __ ]
because when they do it you'll be so
impressed it looks so cool to have your
stuff the first time you get a
professionally wired up grow room you
got the wire going like the little
conduit going all the way across the
room with a box every like 8 ft or 6
feet for a plugin and then like a big
one big breaker box on the outside of
the room that you could shut everything
off so that you know you can work on
[ __ ] not get any electricity man that is
so sweet looking the first time you get
that so have a pro come do that find him
on Craigslist if you need to if you're
in the Southern Colorado area
I've got a guy I got two guys for you so
if this first guy is busy we can send
his his old boss to come help you
out um yeah don't burn the [ __ ] down
that's that's what we're talking about
there's no need yeah no reason for it
that that should be you know one of the
number one things when you're setting up
a grow room is guys I always add a fire
extinguisher and a smoke alarm uh I put
a smoke detector in The Grow rooms uh
put it near the the exhaust fan like if
you've got a carbon filter sucking air
out put it near there cuz the smoke is
going to get sucked toward that uh and
that way put the smoke alarm there I put
a fire extinguisher outside of the damn
grow room because you don't want to have
to run in there and get the extinguisher
if that room is on fire you want to be
able to kick in the door and just start
spraying that [ __ ] uh at hyro indoor
growing supplies you can pick up an item
called The Flame Defender I haven't used
it I've done a lot of research about it
uh that that I need those those look
like the way to go I think we're going
to get ourselves set up with those yeah
some we'll test them hopefully never to
test them out hopefully we never find
out how good those work all right um so
guys once you figured out how much herb
you need to produce that's when you can
start designing your grow space uh
actually sometimes your space dictates
how you build your grow that's where
that's where the fun kicks in in my
opinion uh building and grow is all
about adapting to the space you're
provided some of you guys are going to
use a small closet some of you might use
a spare bedroom some of you guys are
going to buy a grow Hut and set that up
I will do a lot of talking about a grow
Hut maybe not on this episode we're
already 35 minutes in uh but I will
definitely I'm writing that down grow
Hut they're very versatile yeah um a lot
of people made fun of them at first but
I have done some breeding I've done some
feno selection I've done some great
growing in just a grow Hut they're great
if you have limited space you can put it
in the corner of your bedroom and it's
awesome I've seen a whole bedroom full
of them that was uh quite the little
production area so it's pretty neat so
uh since I'm only allowed a small plant
count here in Pueblo in my house in a
spare bedroom I run two 5x5 Hydro huts
on a flip box uh with a 600 watt light
in each Hut but what happens I run one
ballast the ballast plugs into the wall
on a timer so it goes ballast and then
there's a cord that goes to the flip box
and then the flip box has two cords that
come out and a bulb comes from each one
and every 12 hours side a lights up and
then for 12 hours it stays on on and
then it shuts off and the other side
comes on for 12 hours so instead of
adding electrical upgrades to that
bedroom that I'm just using in the
winter as a grow space for the it keeps
the house warm up here actually so I
just run that uh using the flip box I
can use that room all the time and have
it flowering constantly and not have any
downtime in that room nice yeah so uh
it's like a an 11 it's like a 14 by9
room so those two 5x5 Huts fit perfectly
in there it gives me a little bit of
room to work because I really like the
grow Huts a lot of people talk [ __ ]
about and hate on them they're amazing
that's my friend that was doing it uh um
he didn't have the flip box but um he
had two different ballast so he was you
know one was on for 12 hours the other
was on for 12 hours same same thing just
uh he just had the extra ballast I
didn't want to go buy another one you
know I was like that flip box was the
price of another ballast and everything
so I was like I'll just do it this way
and it was it's kind of a test idea I
wanted to see if I could do that on a
larger scale because I've designed an 18
Lightroom that's two nine room or two
nine light rooms on a flip box M uh and
then I actually did some research and a
guy named Eric bixa kind of beat me to
the punch on this room that I was trying
to build so it's a cool room nice it's a
10 x10 room with a 10x five lung room in
the middle and all of your equipment is
in that middle room uhhuh and you cool
off the all of the air in the middle
room and one side sleeps so you're
producing CO2 in the sleeping plants
guys plants that are asleep kick off CO2
if you can vent that CO2 into your
flower room that's awake you can use
that uh but so yeah you're just you got
you got one air conditioner one set of
ballast one dehumidifier and then you're
just moving the air around to both rooms
yeah for sure killer idea guys we'll
talk about that that's a huge room
that's a lot of money that's like multi
thousand room so some of you guys are
going to grow like in closets and [ __ ]
that's what I saying right some of you
guys are going to grow in grow Huts some
of you guys might even bust out 16
lights in a basement how uh however you
do it there will be some obstacles
presented by your existing environment
that's how it goes unless you're
building a building that's designed to
be a grow space from the beginning
you're going to have to deal with some
type of obstacles that's part of the fun
for me honestly yeah no totally is yeah
I like taking a space like a dirty
basement or a funky attic or the back
part of the dispensary and making it an
amazing sufficient grow with the space
and power that I've got without having
to do any crazy dramatic improvements to
the place it's kind of a fun challenge I
uh I I think I no I I don't think I know
um I do upgrades after every single
run sometimes upgrades to slow me down
quite a bit yeah I've
noticed you've had some downtime for a
minute I've heard you talking about it
all right so let's talk about a few
things that every grow will need uh
there will be more things you're going
to have to add to this depending on your
room and your space but every room is
going to need these things this is
mostly for a just one flowering room if
you want to have plants vegging while
you're crop flowers you're going to need
a small veg room also uh eventually
you're going to want a mother room and a
clone area and a veg area and a breeding
area and a place for your mail plants
and a place to make pollen and
a it gets ridiculous when you start
doing it a whole bunch but eventually
you're going to want to add more rooms
my advice is build slowly and plan ahead
with realistic expectations uh don't
start counting your chickens before they
hatch if you've got a light and you
expect a pound of weed start thinking
you got 3/4 of a pound of weed and
budget for that because you're not going
to grow as great as you plan your first
couple of runs so make your upgrades
Like Jesse said he makes upgrades every
time kind of plan them don't go too
ambitious your first couple of times
like be realistic about it you can fail
crops fail uh things that kill crops
spidermites air conditioner failure if
your air conditioner cuts out in the
middle of a flower cycle and you're at
work and it's 90° outside and you're
going to come home and it's going to be
108 degrees in your grow room and you're
going to have crispy buds they're
already dried and cured
for that [ __ ] happens uh if you're
running a hydro setup if one pump dies
while you're at work or while you're
asleep oh man everything can go crunchy
don't get me started on that yeah it's
happened I know I have we have a mutual
friend that went to Las Vegas for two
days uh he was he was supposed to go to
a wedding and didn't want to go but he
had to go and it was like a 5-day
vacation planned but he went for two
days he flew there and flew back right
away and came home and his pump took a
[ __ ] while he was gone and his whole 4x4
table done yeah yeah we had a uh double
redundancy setup you know two pumps um
and uh on a setup at a dispensary and
both faed on the same weekend while
everyone was at the Cannabis Cup oh man
yeah goodbye two tables worth of weed
two whole tabl
cannabis yeah see thank you good job
yeah no I've been trying that for a
while too cannabis cannabis yeah it just
sounds like a better word you know can
yeah herb I call it herb a lot it's
aasta in me it's a good herb um yeah so
we're talking about things that all
grows need uh yeah every grow is going
to need electricity duh right unless
you're growing outside you need
electricity you're going to need lights
and timers uh you'll need intake and
outtake fans and you're going to need a
water source those are the basics that
every grow will need um and we're at 40
minutes I'm going to try to squeeze as
much of this in as we can but we might
not actually even get to like yeah man I
mean might not get to the build part
until another episode um guys I have
another episode planned that is just
I've had news articles set aside I've
got a couple of things Mike and I wanted
to talk about it's going to kind of go
between these two build episodes I think
but I might put it out as like a midweek
episode so I think after we record here
Mike's going to come over and [ __ ]
with me again and talk about some things
so the next one will be a news heavy
catchup episode and then I'll try to get
Jesse back as soon as possible to talk
more about building because you're going
to send me so many questions I can
already tell nice yeah oh we love the
questions that means we're doing our job
if we spark your thoughts that means
we're doing our job uh hey LB you asked
me questions and I appreciate it I hope
I responded appropriately I don't want
to say your full name because I haven't
gotten your permission but lb I
appreciate you for listening that's
awesome so uh lights everybody needs
lights lights are actually the main
ingredient to your grow space uh lights
dictate the cycles of the gardens uh
they tell you if you're in veg or if
you're in flower uh lights are also the
main fuel and energy provider for your
plants lights create photosynthesis
lights are the main thing it's the
number one nutrient yes uh put as big of
a light as you can in your space is what
I always
say and a lot of them uh so no matter
how big or small your grow space is you
will need some sort of air exchange
system always you got to get rid of that
old stale funky air um I can't stress
how important this is most of the
problems I see from lowbudget grows is a
lack of air flow and air exchange um
moving the air around the room is great
but you need to replace the uh room the
air in the room also uh if you leave a
freshly watered crop locked in a sealed
closet with the light above it you're
creating a very humid environment uh the
plants are trying to transpire but
there's too much moisture in the air and
the plants Can't Sweat like they should
which slows down photosynthesis and
stunts growth that also makes your
plants look angry and sad too uh if the
plants are left in excessive humidity
for long periods they will become very
susceptible to our good friend powdery
mildew Fu powdery mildew uh as your buds
grow your risk of powdery mildew way
increases the insides of your buds if
you're not getting getting some air flow
in there and you got too much moisture
in the room that mold is going to grow
right in the middle of your buds so lock
yourself in your car one day just lock
yourself in the car in the Sun and just
try to sit in there and breathe for the
whole day that's what it feels like for
your plants when you just stifle them
locked up in a tight room that's good
way to put it yeah so we've stressed the
need for air
exchange uh water water should be easily
accessible uh I predict that your thou
each thousand watt light will require
about five gallons of water two to three
times a week
this works uh across the board I like to
put uh 16 three gallon pots under the
light or I like to put nine five gallon
pots or between four and six seven
gallon pots underneath a th000 watt
light and either way I find that that
requires about about five gallons of
water for each watering yeah that's yeah
that's real good estimate actually yeah
yeah I'm glad that works out so keep
that in mind that you guys are going to
have to get water to your grow space at
least twice a week unless you set up a
drip system uh laid in flour and if your
room is a little hotter you may be
watering three or four times a week I'm
hitting my plants is a little cool now
so I'm hitting them Monday I hit them
with nutrients real heavy and then I try
to hit them on Thursday or Friday with
just enough water to keep them through
Monday but since they haven't been
drinking a lot that means that on their
next day when they get just water I'm
going to really water the [ __ ] out of
them to kind of wash out any excess
nutrients that have built up over time
and then we'll start refeeding the soil
again
uh around day 30 I really Pummel them
with a lot of sugars and things yeah and
smaller plants will use uh water a lot
more often too dude that mic stand is
fired after his performance tonight we
have a mic stand that needs Viagra we'll
swap it out for that one over there
sorry about giving you the shitty mic
stand it's all good got to talk to our
sponsors about
this uh if you guys are interested in
sponsoring the igro culture podcast
email me ulture hotmail.com I'd love to
hear what you have to say I'll send you
a one sheet if that's what you're
looking for let you know what my rates
are are uh we've been hitting dude we've
been hitting between 3,000 and 5,000
listeners per episode 5,000 is our Peak
2500 is like our low on an episode now
Jesus that's that's how many people are
here in this show so thank each and
every one of you that are listening that
is awesome yeah thank you guys all right
I feel like we've talked about the very
basics of building a room we talked
about setting a goal for how much
cannabis we need to grow I wrote herb
right here but I corrected myself uh the
next step is figuring out if you're
building your room to fit your
production needs or if you're building
the room to fit the available space
budget and electrical
limitations uh sometimes you can't
always throw 24 lights in your basement
because you can't pull that many amps so
find a happy medium that lets you grow a
few crops and then uh see if this is
something that you can dedicate more
time and space and electricity to and
then after a couple of crops expand your
grows plant them out uh but don't expand
more quickly than you can learn I keep
saying that imagine this imagine getting
ahead of yourself will cause you
headaches in the future future imagine
if you have 24 lights in flour with six
seven gallon pots under each light and
now you have fungus KNN Nats and it's
your first grow and you're like four
weeks into flour and you can't spray
because if you spray you're going to put
[ __ ] in your buds but you got to get rid
of those fungus snats and you got a
whole lot of them you just spend if you
got 24 lights it's like 150
plants wow uh that should be 24 to 30
lbs of weed if you do this right some
guys are going to get 48 lbs of weed out
of these 24 lights yeah if you're run
it's oji cush your girl got cookies
you're hoping for those 25 lbs out of
that yeah and now you may have to cut it
down four weeks in you got to do it what
if you got spiderm in there I'm cringing
so what I'm saying is start small dude
uh fail small before you fail so large
because when you grow you're going to
fail uh I mess up at this rate I still
kill stuff on accident like all the time
but that's the only way I learn I
encourage a little bit of experiment
don't experiment on your mom's don't
experiment on your patient important
crop pick a plant t it see what you can
do to it
but go small like experience a few
problems before you try to battle fungus
Nats in a 24 light flowering room all
right we are 47 minutes in I'm not sure
if we should try to keep going or if we
should save this next part for another
episode because we're uh we kind of got
them on the edge of their seats right
now yeah we'll talk about we'll talk
about this one spot right here and then
uh so we're going to talk a little bit
about room size in relation to how many
and what type of Lights to use we got
about 10 minutes to do this so a small
closet setup uh I would use some small
T5 lights little fluorescent lights I
personally don't like the coiled CFLs I
don't feel like they put out enough
light they work great as supplements if
it's all you got that's going to if it's
all you've got and all you can power
it's going to work but for the amount of
heat that they put off I don't think
they put off enough light I I agree
totally awesome uh for a closet I would
almost recommend it's a t light I think
there are eight bulbs and I think it's
24x 24 is the dimensions of it mhm uh
and I think it's actually made by Hydra
Farm if you've got a small closet that
is the perfect light in my opinion uh if
you can't run a lot of electricity you
can put that in a small fan and leave
the closet cracked a little bit you've
got a grow room dude as long as you're
getting that stale air out of there and
not letting it get too hot keep the
those T lights right above your plants
and then every night you got to close
that closet door at the same time and
turn off your lights to start your
flower cycle and you got to be on the
money 8:00 8:00 every day and night but
so in a small closet I think that little
T5 light I'm talking about as perfect or
maybe a small hid a high-intensity
discharge light uh maybe like a 150 in a
closet I really like a 250 watt high
pressure sodium light I really find
those to be efficient those are cool
lights it's a great Siz light doesn't
take a lot of wattage but it does make a
little bit of heat even um you know if
your closet's a little bigger 400 are
great that's that's exactly what I wrote
down I was going to say a 400 is kind of
the biggest you really want to go in a
closet unless you got like one of those
fancy like belir walk-in
closets uh but everyone's got a small
closet they can dedicate to a grow space
so if you're just trying to supply herb
for you and your girlfriend or something
or your patient just you the closet is
fine especially with the little T5 light
I think you could pull some some stuff
out of a T5 is that where your first
grow was it in a
closet uh technically yes it was in a
closet but inside of that closet I put a
grow Hut in there it was kind of a large
closet it was more of a was a closet
that was actually attached to the hot
water heater area oh the closet had
another door in it and I actually took
the ducting from my hot water heater and
my heater and used some of the CO2 uh to
my grow room yeah that can be a little
dangerous yes that yeah yeah yeah yeah
don't do that if you don't know what
you're doing nice uh so yeah perfect
little closet uh it's a great way to
grow you can grow a little short plants
and then you can supply yourself yeah oh
yeah a small corner of a room works if
you need to like tarp off a room or like
if you have a small room that you can
just take the corner you can put a grow
Hut in the corner grow Huts are awesome
I said I'm going to do a whole talk
about those that will be another episode
guys we're at 50 minutes now I've
noticed you guys don't listen past 45 a
lot of the the listeners click out at 45
minutes you're droning off I mean you're
not droning on that's what I meant it
didn't mean I meant after after a while
we if we listen to the show I can tell
we run out of energy about an hour it's
like oh my throat's done all the
listeners are getting drowsy that's what
I meant to say okay well yeah and I
don't blame you guys uh so you got that
small Corner small space you can put a
T5 all the way up to like a 600 watt
light in like a 6x6 space if you can
vent it uh we'll talk in the next
episode Jesse is actually like a
carpenter Craftsman House Builder manly
man so he's going to talk about framing
up a space and stuff uh in the next
episode we're going to try to get this
part done quickly here grow Huts I will
talk a lot about them uh you can put a
grow Hut in the corner of any room you
can put multiple grow Huts in a basement
um you can put one grow Hut in every
room if you've got limited power find
out where each room is on each breaker
and put one grow Hut on each breaker you
can grow plenty of cannabis in one house
or one location sounds like my kind of
place I think I've been to houses like
this uh then of course there's the whole
dedicated bedroom if you've got a nice
bedroom that nobody needs if you're a
single guy and your roommate sucks kick
him out build a grow room he won't eat
your food he won't bring over ugly
chicks you got a grow room in there now
that's going to produce dank cannabis
and it will pay for itself uh something
I should write down to talk about is the
cost of running the grow room because
that's just on my mind huh I had more
paper here and I don't know where the
note I wrote earlier
went but we'll write that get expensive
uh Big Grow rooms big facilities and
stuff like that pay astronomical
electricity bills but imagine if uh if
imagine if you and I were roommates and
you kicked me out and built a grow room
in my space it would definitely pay for
itself in the long run oh easily and it
wouldn't eat your freaking bener it
would get you high as crap in the end so
a whole room you can put multiple
depending on the size of your room if
you've got so I say like every 6x6 4x4
4x4 to 6x6 space you should put about
1,000 watt light if you can vent it uh
if you've got a room that's like 10 x 10
I think you should put 4,000 watt lights
in there yeah uh if you're getting
bigger and bigger I it kind of depends
on your wattage and stuff but about
every 5x5 Square should be a th000 watt
light if you can vent that I try to
leave people hate walkways a lot of
Growers say that walkways are expensive
and a waste of space I like giving
myself a walkway so I can get to every
single plant and I think the plants like
the space to breathe uh you don't like
being crowded in on the bus with
everybody touching you your plants don't
like that [ __ ] either give them some
room to breath and keeping the leaves
off of each other will prevent powdery
mildew and places for bugs to jump
around so if you've got a whole room put
a 1,000 watt light every 5x5 space up to
the Limit that your electricity will
allow and that you can cool um here's a
random recommendation I think it's about
3,000 BTUs of cooling for every single
thousand watt light is what I think you
want 2500 to 3,000 okay so keep that in
mind when you're and you have to power
that air conditioner also so in your big
room here if you've got
uh and you're 30 amp your two 30 amp
Breakers you're going to be able to run
one maybe two lights and an air
conditioner that's going to be about it
yeah on a 30 amp breaker so you're going
to need an uh an electrician to come
wire up your big room yeah you're not
going to be able to get the air
conditioner on that most likely uh if
you've got a big garage or a basement
you need to have the electrician come
and wire you up with 240 in the whole
basement
and then you need to have a mini split
put in the basement and hang like 24
lights down there in your basement and
you got to have an H fat guy come set
that up yeah and yeah they're fun yeah
that mini split's going to be fun to put
in but man you can keep it so cool once
you get it there and then the next step
up from there uh after you have your
basement or your big garage with
multiple thousands uh anything more than
nine lights I think becomes like kind of
extensive for a hom grow yeah like yeah
if you got like 10 lights in a house
you're of pushing it but then you move
on to like the commercial scale
warehouses where you've got multiple
rooms with multiple thousand watt lights
or one giant room with 100 lights in it
I kind of prefer more separated rooms uh
I like to breed and if something goes
wrong in one room you don't have it
everywhere it's a little more
containable so my main point is plan the
room before you start building uh think
about how many lights you want to run
think about how much cannabis you want
to produce uh think about your
electrical limitations think about your
budget it's going to cost you we said
about 100 bucks a month to run a light
and its accessories so keep that in mind
until Harvest you're not going to have
uh you're going to have to figure out
how to pay for that once Harvest comes
then you obviously have a way to pay for
that uh we're going to be at an hour
real quick here guys this is a good way
to make this a two-part episode the part
we're going to come up with next is
actually the basic steps to building the
room and some guidance on building a
room and things to look for uh I'm going
to cut this episode off right here and
we'll make that part two uh dude thanks
for coming and doing another great
episode we just crushed this one I feel
like yeah um we kind of droned on for a
little bit I feel like I've been talking
for an hour straight so I apologize if
this got boring I hope you guys learned
a whole bunch of stuff this time if
there are any questions make sure you
send them to me you can message Jesse
he's Jesse grow is it Jessie gr OG on
Twitter uh yeah cool Jesse Gros OG on
Twitter follow him on Instagram Jessy
grows uh you can message me ulture
hotmail.com you can find me uh there's
an Agro culture Facebook page there's an
agro culture Instagram we're quite easy
to
find um there's a Twitter Facebook I've
got it all so dude thanks for coming
really uh thanks for that party you
through guys we'll let you know when the
next party is coming uh I'm going to go
ahead and wrap it up he get us some
questions yeah get us questions please
and now that the show is over now that
you've learned how to build a sweet grow
room please go to iTunes or Stitcher uh
find I gr culture find the review
section give us a festar rating type in
a comment let me know what you think of
the show and I will read your comments
on a future episode uh don't forget that
the show is available on iTunes Stitcher
I genetics.com and I am still working on
adding videos to YouTube I took a break
from that for a minute I was kind of
busy this week but they will still come
up there dude I want to give a huge
shout out to the Garden of Weeden huge
shout out to my ninja Spence big shout
out to Jesse thanks again for listening
you guys take a fat dab give your mom a
hug for me
a long long time I'm onj in a dance come
watch me DJ in your dance a long long
time I'm a DJ in a dance come watch me
nice dance long
d