welcome to the show cannabis community
it's time for episode 370 of the growth
from your heart podcast this episode is
brought to you by the hella dank seed
company if you need new seeds for your
garden I highly recommend the hella dank
seed company and you can find them at
www.cdxzipstream.com farms this stuff
smells like skunky strawberries and just
funky fruit and if you dab it at a nice
low temperature
it tastes like strawberries and cream
with a hint of skunky gas enos in the
background it is very delicious it's
almost like eating some strawberry
shortcake at the gas station that's what
it kind of smells like to me the lab
test on the front here says seventy two
point three percent THC with a total
cannabinoid content of 83.9% I really
like this concentrate it tastes
delicious
the high is great and the texture and
consistency are beautiful there is just
enough Terp sauce in here and it's got
some nice chunky crystals I am really
happy with that purchase great
concentrate from our friends and
apothecary farms alright my next order
of business is to give a couple of
people some shout outs I want to give a
huge shout out to Brett Gorman how about
a giant shout out to Riley Hanson a big
shout out to my co Panther a big thank
you shout out to Sam and also a giant
fist bump and a shout-out to Aldridge
thank you guys for the continued patreon
support all right podcast world this is
going to be another grow lesson if
you've been following along you know
I've been doing a long series of grow
lessons that series starts at episode
351 in this series of lessons we started
by setting a goal for our grow then we
decided a good place for our growth then
we acquire the appropriate equipment and
set it up then we either acquired seeds
or clones and we got those growing at
this point in my grow lessons we should
have small plants that are approximately
eight to twelve inches tall and they are
in small pots they are probably in
either beer cups or four inch pots or
maybe six or eight inch net pots but
we've got small plants they should be
nice and healthy at this point they
should have nice branching coming out of
them they should not have any bugs or
any powdery mildew hopefully at this
point we don't have a
burned leaves or any signs of
deficiencies hopefully we have got a
nice developed thriving root system to
work with now if most of those things
are accurate we've got a nice healthy
plant that is growing it's branching it
looks healthy its thriving it's not
struggling and we've got a nice healthy
root system it is time to transplant our
small plants into our larger pot our
finishing pot and start the large veg
phase now these plants will probably
finish out in these pots unless you want
to transplant one more time into an even
larger pot I like to go from the small
pot into my finishing pot I'm generally
going to go into a three gallon or a
five gallon or a seven gallon in an
indoor garden you guys may choose to go
larger you may want to go from the small
six inch net pot maybe to a one gallon
then maybe into your twenty or thirty
gallon if you're gonna do something like
that I talked in a previous episode
about why it's a good idea to use a
smaller container for smaller plants we
don't need to water this giant area when
we've got a tiny plant right in the
middle so if you're gonna go to like a
twenty or thirty gallon pot you may want
to go from the cup to maybe a one gallon
maybe a three gallon then later on
transplant that into your twenty or
thirty but it gets challenging when you
go to transplant larger plants if you're
not experienced with it you can cause
damage you need to lay that larger plant
on its side you need to remove that pot
they need to pop a much larger plant it
does get difficult but I have faith in
you that you can do it if you choose to
transplant twice just be careful in this
lesson we're gonna focus on
transplanting one time we're gonna go
from this small beer cup or our four
inch or our six inch net pot or maybe an
eight inch pot and we're going to pot
into a three or a five or a seven gallon
pot for my example alright let's talk a
little bit about pots and soil I did a
long episode about choosing pots and
soil but let's do a brief recap I like
to use the plastic nursery pots in a
home grow in a commercial facility I
like to use a root pot one of the fabric
pots in most applications I am using a
three gallon pot you can use whatever
kind of pots make you happy as long as
it's going to get you to your goal the
thing I find most important is to make
sure that whatever container you use
that it has plenty of holes for drainage
make sure that when you water this plant
the
says water has some way to escape from
the bottom of that pot the nursery pots
have plenty of holes in them already the
fabric pots will drain naturally just
because they're match those work
perfectly if you're going to use a Home
Depot bucket or something like that
make sure you drill plenty of drainage
holes in your container now let's talk
briefly about soil or soilless mix you
don't have to buy a really expensive
soil if you're going to feed your plants
with bottled nutrients you can buy an
inert medium you don't need a soil or
soilless mix with a lot of nutrients and
a lot of stuff in there you're going to
be on top of fertilizing these plants
with your bottled nutrients so we don't
need to pay extra money for a soil or a
soilless mix it's got a bunch of stuff
in there that will give us the
opportunity to burn our plants because
we're going to add them to a soil that's
got nutrients in it then we're going to
add bottled nutrients on top of that we
do run the risk of over fertilizing the
plants in that situation so we don't
really need an over fertilized soil or
soilless mix we need something more
inert maybe something with some mykos or
some beneficial fungus in there that
would be advantageous but we don't
really need a lot of nutrients whatever
medium you choose to purchase I
recommend you get something with a lot
of aeration in it either a lot of
perlite or a lot of personal light and
if it doesn't come with plenty of
aeration product already in it buy a bag
of perlite and amend it yourself now the
amount of perlite or personal light
you're going to need to add to your soil
or soilless mix will depend on the
fluffiness and the amount of aeration in
that medium when you purchase it I'm not
sure what you're going to purchase so
I'm not sure what to recommend as a
ratio of how much perlite I like it
fluffy when I'm working with Coco I mix
three bags of cocoa and one 5-gallon
bucket of perlite and one 5-gallon
bucket of Percel light now that gives me
about 25 to 33 gallon pots worth of
material to work with you guys can
reduce that recipe as needed for your
garden now if I were working with soil
or a soilless mix I might not use as
much perlite I may reduce that perlite
by about half you don't need in my
opinion I don't need as much aeration in
soil and soilless makes as I do in the
cocoa I feel like the cocoa holds a lot
more water so it also pushes out a lot
more air and it kind of crushes the
plants a little more it gets heavier
because it's got so much water in there
the soil and soilless mix doesn't hold
as much water so it doesn't get as heavy
and it doesn't crush the roots as much
so you don't need as much perlite maybe
go half as much maybe if you're doing
three bags of soil do half of a
five-gallon bucket of personal light and
a half of a five-gallon bucket of
perlite if you guys aren't going to buy
the personal I understand it's more
expensive
it's another product to buy you will get
by with just using perlite perlite is
just fine for this situation if you only
want to buy the one product that will be
fine
so three bags of soil and maybe one bag
of perlite for this application and I
know I work in larger batches than a lot
of people if you want to reduce this
recipe for a smaller garden I think they
sell the bags of soil in 1.75 cubic
yards is what I think most of those bags
of dirt are or at least the bags of
cocoa I was buying her one point seven
seven cubic yards if you buy a one point
seven seven cubic yards of dirt makes
that with a third of a five-gallon
bucket of perlite so just fill the
bucket up about a third maybe half way
if you want to go hard then mix that in
really well with your soil so that it's
nicely even evenly mixed in there with
everything else so that you just see the
little white spots everywhere then you
know you've got plenty of aeration
throughout your entire root zone now
while we're mixing up perlite into our
soil why not mix in some sort of root
inoculant powder in a previous episode I
talked all about Michel Raizel fungi
let's add a mycorrhizae product to our
mix right now and get it distributed all
throughout the soil something like the
great white granulars would work
perfectly you can use great white shark
on its own just sprinkle it in there
right now you can use plus life right
now any sort of powdered myko product
would work wonderfully right now
sprinkle it right into the dirt as
you're mixing it up so I feel like
that's a great way to segue into
actually starting to do the
transplanting process we've got healthy
plants we've got a container we've got a
good soil or soilless mix it's well
aerated we've put a myko product in
there now let's actually get to work
step number one you guys is always fine
to the Bluetooth speaker and put on the
growth from your heart podcast it helps
you grow it makes the plants happy and
it puts you in a good mood to create a
positive garden environment so step
number one find the Bluetooth speaker or
find your earbuds get your earbuds in
get hooked up with the growth from your
heart podcast that is going to make your
garden grow so much more rapidly it's
gonna make you grow more rapidly it's
gonna make everything go better so step
number one find the growth from your
heart podcast get it at an acceptable
volume and get that going in the growth
step number two get some rubber gloves I
often overlook this step we should
always be wearing gloves if we're coming
in contact with mykos if we're coming in
contact with the roots if we're coming
in contact with bottled nutrients we
should be wearing gloves also if you're
gonna be sprinkling those myko products
over your topsoil just all willy-nilly
maybe you might want to consider some
sort of a mask we don't really want to
breathe in microbe products so we've got
the pod cast on we're gloved up we've
got a face mask on you got your
dreadlocks tied up hopefully your nicely
medicated if that's appropriate wherever
you work or whatever you're growing now
let's actually get to business here we
need to fill our container whatever size
container we chose we need to fill it
with our well-mixed medium we've got our
soilless mix we've got our cocoa
hopefully we've got a bunch of perlite
in there hopefully we added a myko
product to there we've got it all mixed
up now it's ready to go into a container
I like to fill my containers by using a
smaller container just a scoop dirt out
of the bag or whatever container it's in
and just dump it right into the pot that
it's going into just fill it up fill it
up most of the way if you're filling up
a three gallon five gallon or seven
gallon pot fill it up most of the way
but leave yourself about an inch and a
half or maybe two inches at the top
where you don't fill it all the way up
all the way to the brim leave yourself
about an inch and a half two inches so
that when we water we've got some room
to put water in the pot you don't want
to pour water on the pot and watch it
run right off the top you don't want to
have to stand there and pour water
really slowly to where you can get that
whole quarter or half or gallon of water
into the pot so you can water it
appropriately I like to be able to just
splash a gallon of water on top of a
seven gallon pot and just watch it
saturate that whole top area and then
you can just walk away and do the
back spot if you fill it up too far you
gotta just stand there and pour it
slowly it's where the water saturates
into the medium and drains down a little
bit then you can pour a little more
leave yourself some space also in the
future we may choose to top dress these
plants we may want to add some worm
castings you may want to add some bat
guano
you may just add some fresh soil with
some charged-up nutrients in it to the
top layer so leave yourself in the room
so that you've got options and you've
got watering space now as you are
filling your container pack your medium
in there slightly tight you don't want
it packed real snug but you don't want
it fluffy and loops we want to make the
roots work to dig down into the dirt and
have some more to grow and kind of do a
little exercise to get in there but we
also don't want to suffocate them and
make it so hard that the roots simply
can't grow into the medium so you have
to pack it a little bit but don't crush
it so so tight to where the roots can't
even grow now if you packed it too
loosely you will notice on the first
couple of waterings you'll just get a
giant hole in the center all the dirt
will just cave in you'll create a hole
in the middle and then you'll have to
repack it put more dirt in there then
reward it that's okay
you didn't mess up you just should have
gone a little harder in the first place
you will learn if you go too hard the
roots just aren't gonna grow if you go
too soft the water is just gonna fall
right through and you will definitely
get indicators so fill your container
pack it slightly tight I usually just
use the palm of my hand and I give it
just a few Pat's I throw in just a few
scoops of dirt just to give myself a few
inches of dirt and then I just Pat it in
and then I throw in some order and then
I just Pat it in you can hear me just
happen on the table here it's not that
hard just patting it down just getting
the dirt nice and even in there then I
just pour more dirt on top of it just
Pat it down I'd rather pour some in and
then pack it down and then pour some in
and pack it down instead of fill it up
and then try to pack all that down I
feel like that's kind of it's not really
as productive as packing each little
layer so pour some dirt in there packing
down pour some dirt packing down get
yourself up to about an inch and a half
or two inches to the top now here's
where it gets fun we have got our three
our five or seven gallon pot filled with
our appropriate mix and it is leveled
off and we've got about an inch and a
half or two inches of space so that we
can add water or top dress later in the
future now in the very center of that
pot we need to create a space for our
transplanted plant we need to create a
little hole in with
to place our small root ball the way I
like to do it is find the middle that
topsoil and just dig out about a
fist-sized worth of dirt just take out
about just a fist I've got a pretty big
fist so just take out about a fist size
worth of dirt right in the center of
that topsoil
then whatever size pot my plant is
already in say I'm in a beer cup or
maybe I'm in a six-inch net pot I will
take a beer cup or a six-inch net pot
and I will dig a hole in my new pot soil
right at the top right in the center and
I will actually plant the cup in that
hole I will dig a hole perfectly to
where that cup will fit then it will
backfill dirt around that cup kind of
snug then I will pull the cup or the
six-inch net pot out of that main hole
now I have got a perfect template that
is the exact shape of the incoming root
ball from my small veg plant
so I basically leveled off the dirt I
dug out a hole I put the previous pot in
that hole I back filled it then I just
pulled that pot right out so I made an
impression a template just a little gap
for the next plant to fit perfectly into
so you've got a top layer of soil with
this little round hole perfectly waiting
just chill and wait for a pot to go in
it now our next step is to pot our small
veg plant into that hole but before we
do that you know what I'm gonna
recommend let's sprinkle a little mica
powder right into that hole our fresh
exposed roots are gonna go right there
let's just sprinkle some mica powder
right there let's just give it some love
give it a boost to give it a head start
that's just like laying out some cookies
for Santa just get it nice and ready put
some mica powder right in the hole now
our next challenge will be to get the
small plant out of that small pot
hopefully it is grown really tight into
your beer cup or really tight into your
six-inch net pot it is nicely rootbound
there's a lot of root mass in that
container so it's gonna take a little
effort to get it out the way I do it as
I make a Spock hand I've got my first
finger and my middle finger together
I've got my ring finger and my pinky
finger together I place the stick of the
plant between in between my middle
finger and my ring finger sticking up
the root ball the soil is in my palm
then I flip it upside
so now the plant is hanging upside down
and I'm holding on to the root ball with
my Spock hand I'll take my I do that in
my left hand cuz it did I don't need as
much coordination it could just stay
there then I take my right hand and I
kind of just squeeze the cup or the beer
or the beer cup or the six-inch net pot
just squeeze it all around just squeeze
it
if you've ever rolled a joint too tight
and you're trying to loosen the joint
it's the same idea we're just trying to
loosen the dirt out of that Cup so just
squeeze all around it just squeeze it
that's all you really got to do and
you'll feel it loosening up maybe
squeeze it and work it to the left and
right just a little bit you'll feel how
to loosen the dirt inside of that pot
once you start doing it all you're
trying to do is loosen the dirt so that
it will fall out give it a little shake
and it's gonna fall out you're gonna
have an exposed root zone in your hand
now it's okay hopefully when it came out
it all stayed together in one big chunk
hopefully you've taken good care of it
you've properly watered it you've given
it proper dry time and the roots have
developed nice and fat in there so it's
all just one chunk if it came out as a
mess that's okay we're just gonna pop
that whole mess into that hole that we
already made and it will be just fine
once you get the root ball out of the
container you already know what I'm
gonna say sprinkle a little mykos on it
why not
we've got exposed roots those roots love
mykos those mykos are activated by
touching roots sprinkle them on there
give it as much mica powder as you can
afford to sprinkle on there at this time
just give it a nice little coating just
infect it with root inoculant powder
then we want to if it came out in a mess
you need to gently place it in that hole
get as much of that original dirt as you
can in there set the root ball down put
some so maybe put the if there are
dangling long roots set the dangling
roots in there put a little dirt on top
of it lower the plant in a little more
put some dirt on top of it lower it in a
little bit more so that you don't bind
those roots up we're trying to give
those roots space we don't want to just
drop them right in there and smother
them with fresh dirt so if they came
apart keep them apart when you're
putting them in there then backfill it
with all the dirt from that container
and you should have enough dirt there to
level everything off if you lost some
dirt during the movement just grab some
more dirt out of your mix and just top
it or you have a nice even layer kind of
pack it in not super tight just tight
enough to keep that plant staying
straight upright now if it came
nice and smooth now we've got another
option if it came out nice and smooth
and you feel like those routes are
perfect and they aren't super bound but
they're growing well you can just set
still sprinkle some Aiko's on it then
you can set that perfect root ball right
into that perfect hole maybe sprinkle a
little bit of dirt on top of it and Pat
it in and you've got a beautifully
transplanted plant that didn't get any
shock or any stress whatsoever during
the transplanting process our other
option when you take it out of the small
container if it is really bound up in
there if you see a lot of white roots
and it is growing in a circle and it's
getting spiraled you do have the option
to kind of break those roots up just a
little bit the way I do it is I hold it
with my left hand and I take my middle
finger and my ring finger on my right
hand and I come straight up from the
bottom of that root ball and I just plow
my fingers through it and just pull it
apart just spread it right in half
you're gonna tear some roots up you're
gonna mess some stuff up if you've got a
nice healthy root system that is only
going to encourage growth you're
spreading it out a little bit then when
you set it in that template hole that
you've got the roots will spread out a
little bit and instead of drawing in a
perfect spiral they're gonna take off a
little bit for you and fill that pot so
either way
sprinkle mykos on the roots on that root
ball that you pull out of the pot
sprinkle mykos on there always sprinkle
some Aiko's into the hole then gently
place that small root ball into that
fresh hole and just cover it with dirt
gently again don't pack it down too
tightly but pack it down tight enough
toward you know it's not gonna cave in
when we water it and that it's tight
enough to give that plant enough support
to stay upright you will know on the
first watering if you did not do it
tightly enough if you didn't do it tight
enough you're just gonna need to add
more medium now that plant is basically
transplanted I recommend you label that
plant at this time before you forget the
next step is to move that plant under
the appropriate light I should also
mention you may need a saucer or some
sort of a catch tray underneath your
plants when we water these plants we
expect to have some runoff so now is a
good time to consider placing your plant
on a saucer or some sort of a catch tray
so we've got the trays down let's talk
about the lighting in which we are going
to place these plants under
you can use T fives for your fresh
transplants you can get the T fives
really close you can get those t5 lights
three maybe four inches away from your
canopy just make sure that you adjust
them every day because the plants are
going to grow rapidly and they will grow
into those lights if you don't pay
attention you can also use ceramic metal
halide for your fresh transplants I like
the 315 s or the 630 s you need to keep
those a little bit further away than the
t5 is probably about a foot maybe 18
inches away LEDs are very brand and
power specific I would follow the
recommendation from the manufacturer on
your LED I don't have enough experience
with your LED to know what it's going to
do to the plants there are so many
vendors so many different makes and
models that it is hard to give advice
for LED lighting but you certainly can
use LEDs through the entire cycle and
you can absolutely use them right now
for your fresh transplants you can also
use metal halide or high pressure sodium
also known as high-intensity discharge
lighting if you are going to use
high-intensity discharge lighting pay
close attention to how the plants are
reacting if you're using a 400 you can
probably get 12 to 18 inches away and
not have any problems if you were using
a 600 you could probably get 18 inches
away and not have any problems if you're
using a thousand watt light you may want
to start off about two feet away from
the canopy maybe even more as you start
introducing these plants to that larger
light as time goes on you can get closer
they will grow closer to the light but
when you were introducing young plants
to large lights pay attention to how
they react we don't want to burn these
lights we don't want to stress them I
said lights we don't want to burn the
plants we don't want to stress the
plants we don't want to put them into
any kind of shock right as we transplant
them this is a critical time we were
trying to put them into turbo mode right
now we don't want to slow them down we
don't want to punish them and put them
on timeout we want to give them
encouragement to take off right now so
we have our plants under the appropriate
light we've got our light the
appropriate distance away from our
canopy let's talk about the amount of
light hours we are going to give these
plants I've talked earlier about
lighting schedules and apparently in a
previous episode
I did make a mistake at some point I
said something about eighteen on and
sixteen off or something like that
somebody said your light cycle will
always add up to 24 hours if my light
cycle I said didn't add up to 24 hours I
was too high to be doing a podcast and I
do apologize honestly when you talk as
much as I do I think you're gonna make a
few mistakes and I encourage you guys to
let me know when I make a mistake so
that I can't correct it and I do
apologize somebody said I did make a
light cycle mistake I apologize for that
allow me to correct myself in this part
there are several cycles that work very
well for our veg plants one common cycle
is 24 hours on and zero hours off I
mainly recommend this if you have mother
plants that tend to auto flower on you
or when you were cutting clones our next
option is 20 hours on and four hours off
I like to give the plants a few hours to
sleep this also gives my equipment four
hours to rest when you're running a
bedroom with 25 lights that is a hundred
hours of lights that you don't have to
run that's a lot of electricity that you
save you're also not paying for as much
cooling and humidity control it makes a
big difference so the 20 on and 4 off is
good for your equipment also the plants
get to take a nap who doesn't want to
take a nap I feel like the roots do a
lot of activity and the dark cycle I
feel like the plants grow a lot in the
dark cycle sugars are processed in the
dark cycle so 20 on 4 off is great that
will make any plants that may want to
Otto flower and a lesser cycle that will
prevent them from auto flowering and it
will also give you maximum growth and
will keep your mother plants really
happy another very common veg 6 off this
is very common because it very closely
mimics the outdoor cycle of the natural
light
another option is 16 on and 8 off this
is very similar to outdoors as well the
reason people will adjust between the 16
and 8 and the 18 and 6 is because some
plants will try to flower on their own
with the 16 hours of daylight once they
get large enough and once they get root
bound also I feel like morale I
is more energy light is the number-one
desired source of energy and nutrient
for our plants so why not maximize the
light input of course some plants will
only take so much light per day and
they'll just shut themselves down but I
don't think you're going to overload
them with light in a small grow room
with a grow light so again our options
are 24 hours on and 0 hours off I
wouldn't really recommend that for these
large batch plants the next option is 20
hours on and four hours off in a
commercial environment that is what I
would do in another environment you can
go 18 on and 6 off that is very
acceptable
another option is 16 on and 8 off that
is very acceptable another thing I found
advantageous of the 20 on and 4 off is
when I do induce that 1212 flowering
cycle those plants really notice a
change in photo period and they really
go into flower really quickly so that's
something that I found has helped quite
a bit
any of those light cycles will work for
your veg plants find what works best for
you you will find pros and cons to each
of those options based on your
environment your location your setup and
your overall grow you're going to have
to find things through trial and error
when it comes to growing try some things
out see what works best for you and your
plants ultimately it's going to come
down to what works best for your plants
they are the boss alright at this point
our small veg plants have been up potted
they are now large veg plants we've got
them in there forever pots we've got
them underneath a good light we have got
that light on a solid schedule we've got
our pots sitting on a saucer or some
sort of a catch tray it is now time to
water our new transplants
I recommend feeding these transplants
with a strong vegetative nutrient if
you've got a bottle that says veg that's
the one you need right now you need
something with a good NPK ratio you need
more n then you do P and K you need a
high end ratio for this time also I
would recommend a myco product if you
haven't put plenty of powdered mykos in
there I recommend a micro Raizel fungal
product that is in liquid form that you
can feed right in your nutrient solution
now mix that in also a small dash of
carbs a little bit of carbohydrates will
help feed those mykos also it will give
the plants a little bit of energy
I also recommend a little bit of cal-mag
at this time the plants are big enough
to take cal-mag give them a little bit
of a boost I would also recommend a
little bit of enzymes at this time that
will speed everything up it'll help keep
the root zone nice and clean the micro
products and the enzymes will work
together they will make a happy
rhizosphere
your plants will thrive you may also
want to add a little bit of potassium
silicates at this time
potassium silicates make for robust
plants and it will also help with any
stress if you have any environmental
stressors that potassium silicon will
make the plants just a little more
resilient and a little tougher for the
mistakes that you may make now I
recommend you adjust the pH of your feed
solution to somewhere between 6 to + 6 4
if we were in cocoa in a commercial
facility I would tell the guys to adjust
the pH to 6 3 if we were in a soilless
mix in a commercial facility I would
tell them to go 6 3 - 6 4 so it makes up
your nutrient solution put your pH meter
in there see what the value is and
adjust up or down as necessary
write that down then water the plants
with that solution since we're talking
about watering plants I highly recommend
you go back and take a listen to episode
337 which is titled one through five
watering tech one through five watering
tech will help all growers if you're a
new grower if you're an experienced
grower if you're a professional grower
you will learn something from the one
through five water tech episode if you
are an experienced grower and you're
trying to teach a new grower how to
water your garden one through five water
tech is a great training exercise so I
recommend everybody listen to episode
337 and learn about one through five
watering tech now before you water your
plants we talked about the pH I did not
talk about the temperature of the water
it's winter time in Colorado and it is
really cold if you're pulling water
right out of the tap it's coming out of
the tap way too cold to apply to the
plants we need the water that we feed
our plants to be right around seven
degrees maybe 65 would be acceptable but
I wouldn't go much lower than 65 imagine
sticking your feet and some 65 degree
water first thing in the morning that's
what it's like when you water the plants
with 65 degree water so I wouldn't go
any lower than 65 I would stay closer to
70 maybe up in the 75 not much warmer
than that right around 70 degrees is
just about ideal for watering the plants
in a home grow you can always just turn
the hot water on as you're filling up
your container in some environments we
don't have the option for hot water if
your water is coming out too cold you
can either get a bucket heater from your
local tractor or farm supply store they
just sell bucket heaters they also saw
them at the farm supply store for
troughs so that you can warm up the pig
and horse water so they don't have to
drink ice water in the morning or if a
bucket heater is not an option for you
you can always fill up containers of
water you can take them into the
flowering rooms or the bedrooms of the
day before and let that light and that
grow room environment warm up the water
for you of course that's only if you
remember to do that the day before so my
point is don't feed the plants water
that is really cold we want that water
to be right around 70 degrees now in
this first watering make sure you really
saturate the medium make sure you have
plenty of water coming out of those
drainage holes we want to make sure to
soak every spot of the container we
don't want a dry spot because roots will
not grow into dry areas nutrients aren't
getting into those dry areas so make
sure you fully saturate the pot I like
to soak it every time I water but it's
mostly important this very first time
water it till you get a lot of water
coming out of those holes also don't
leave the plant ever standing in
stagnant water if that water in the
bottom of your trailer doesn't evaporate
or get sucked up by that plant within a
few hours
get a shot back and suck that out of
there all right so now our plants are
all successfully transplanted they have
now been fed their big-kid nutrients
let's talk a little bit about the
environment in which to keep these
plants we know where to keep the lights
we know what cycled I have the lights on
let's talk about the temperature during
the day I try to keep the temperature
between 70 and 80 degrees then I try to
keep the night around 65 to 75 I really
try to have no
more than a 10 degree swing in my
temperature between day and night
meaning if it's 70 during the day I want
it no lower than 60 during the night I
honestly try to keep about 5 to 7
degrees in that swing I know it's
difficult on a home grow sometimes we
don't have the appropriate equipment to
monitor and/or adjust things all the
time but do your best to keep it within
a 10 degree differential between night
and day now at this point in the large
veg phase I try to keep the humidity
between 40 and 60% right around 50 is
ideal if you want to understand more
about why I keep the humidity and the
temperature the way I do I recommend you
check out episode 314 and it's called
vapor pressure deficit and you can learn
about VPD and why it's important to keep
the temperature and humidity in the
appropriate range for our plants another
thing I like to add to our large veg is
a fan I like to have wall fans or those
fans on stands depending on your setup
but I like to have a fan just
oscillating in the room circulating the
air
the idea is to circulate the air I want
to move the stale air around and move
that fresh air around so the plants have
fresh air constantly you don't need to
beat the [__] out of the plants with a
fan I go in some groves and they're just
terrorizing plants with fans and just
beating them to death and wondering why
the plants look like [__] we just want
to rustle the leaves we just want to
move the air around so I like to put a
fan about one fan every one or two
lights depending on the size of the room
and the environment but make sure that
every area is getting fresh air in that
room at this point I feel like we have
officially entered the large veg phase
our main goals in focus now are to keep
the plants pests and pathogens free we
need to avoid nutrient and pH mistakes
make sure not to over feed our plants at
this time also pay very close attention
to the pH of your feeding solutions we
need to keep these plants healthy and
vigorous we need to work on the top part
of the plants now we focus on the bottom
for the first half now we're gonna focus
more on the top half that means in the
upcoming episodes we're going to work on
shaping and structuring these plants
we're also going to talk about popping
and twisting then we'll talk about
bottoming and topping and lolli popping
our plants but that is all in upcoming
episodes I've got two quick
to cover before we start wrapping up
this episode and then we are out of here
for this week you guys one thing I
should talk about is pest management now
is a good time if you are going to apply
pesticide sprays today is a good day to
start that IPM program those plants are
moving into the bedroom they're in their
big pots let's go ahead and hit them
with a light pesticide spray turn off
the lights douse the plants give them a
couple hours to dry off turn the lights
back on to their regularly scheduled
program and pay attention to those
plants see how they react
hopefully you wrote down exactly what
you sprayed on those plants you wrote
down the product and you wrote how much
per gallon you applied you wrote down
what time you applied it and now you
have a good frame of reference so you
can go in and look you can see how the
plants reacted if they look angry you
need to reduce the application next time
if they look happy about it you can do
the same thing or consider increasing
the application rate if necessary so I
generally start my heavy pest management
application right when I move them into
the large pots
another thing that will be important to
think about is flip time how long are
these plants going to veg in this
environment how much space do you have
depending on your genetics depending on
your lighting depending on your overall
environment these plants could double in
size if you were working within a rise
cross there is a good likelihood that by
the time you finish that plant it will
be twice the size it was when you
started the flowering process so if that
plant is 24 inches tall when you induce
flowering there's a good chance that
plant will end up 48 inches tall before
it is done so as a grower you need to
plan ahead you need to make sure that
plant does not grow up into your lights
and burn itself you need to save
depending on the type of light you're
using you need to save some space
between the bulb and your top Cola so
plan ahead now is the time to start
thinking about how long we're going to
veg if you veg to long the plants will
get too tall you'll have problems we're
also going to do things like topping and
bottoming and Lolly popping and twisting
and cracking and trellising and
manipulating these plants so we're going
to need to give them a little bit of
time to recover from some of these
techniques before we initiate the
flowering process
so if we plan ahead and know how long we
anticipate to veg we can predict when to
do these steps to increase production
and flour at the ideal time and fill our
grow space perfectly we can end up with
our canopy right about eight inches
below that light and it'll be nice and
even and look beautiful you won't have
any wasted space in there once you're an
experienced grower your goal will be to
fill your grow space if you've got a 5
by 5 grow tent you want a 5 by 5 canopy
or at least a four and a half by four
and a half canopy because when it when
the air flows it sucks in a little bit
but you want to fill most of that space
a very experienced grower an older guy
he said one day if you had a cooler and
you could fill it with beer would you
fill it most of the way to the top with
beer
or would you fill that cooler all the
way with beer I'm not even a beer
drinker and that makes sense to me I
want as many beers fit in that cooler
that's just the way you do it so do you
want your grow room to be halfway filled
with buds or do you want to fill that
[__] up with buds the goal will be to
maximize that canopy space so in future
episodes we will talk about trellising
lolli popping will talk about sticks and
cages and cracking stems we will go in
depth and a lot of techniques like that
on ways to fill up your cooler for
maximum production all right podcast
world that is a podcast for this week
ona thank you guys for listening I will
be back in a few days with more fresh
content for you I would appreciate it if
you support the show on patreon you can
support the show by going to
www.petland.com
slash grow from your heart all the
information you need to become a patron
will be right there on the screen once
again I owe a huge thank you to
everybody who has contributed to the
patreon and thank you to everyone who
will contribute in the future I would
also appreciate it if you follow me on
social media you can find me on Facebook
search for the girl from your heart
podcast on Twitter it's at G fyh podcast
if you'd like to follow my personal
Twitter it is at Rasta Jeff 420 I also
recommend you follow my Instagram feed
on Instagram I use Irie underscore
genetics check out the IRA genetics
Instagram feed for fine cannabis
photography also you can join me on
Instagram live drop in Instagram live
videos ask cannabis questions and I will
answer your questions right there in the
live feed if you've got a question or if
you'd like to
sponsored the podcast or if you've got a
product you'd like me to review maybe
just got something you'd like to say and
you're not into the social media you can
reach me through email my email address
is grow from your heart at hotmail.com I
would love to hear from you don't forget
to support our sponsor the hell a dank
seed company you can find them at dank
seed dot store ladies and gentlemen boys
and girls smokers and growers I want to
thank you again for listening to the
girl from your heart podcast I want to
give a huge shout out to the can of
Kratt and until next time take a phat
dab and give your mom a hug for me