welcome to the show cannabis community
it's time for episode 371 of the Grove
from your heart podcast you might be
able to tell by my voice that I've got a
nasty little head cold it's also
Thanksgiving also my website is broken
so I'm unable to post the podcast to
iTunes so I'm not going to do a long
drawn-out grow lesson or an intense
podcast episode for Thanksgiving I just
wanted to drop in and say hello
and maybe mention a few things that I am
thankful or grateful for it's always
good to be reminded and remind others of
things that were grateful for so let's
just get right into it
I am grateful that you folks have been
listening to the podcast almost
religiously
I certainly appreciate all of the
listens all of the clicks all of the
downloads and even more than all of the
listens I appreciate all of the
interaction I appreciate all the emails
all of the Instagram messages all of the
Twitter messages it really means a lot
to me thanks for listening to my show
thanks for hanging out with me and
thanks for trusting me with your garden
and with the cannabis advice that I give
you so I'm really grateful that this
little podcast has developed into a
community and we have got a family based
around this podcast we have developed
the Irie army is what some of the folks
have labeled this little group that
follows the podcast so closely so I want
to give a big thank you and a giant fist
bump to the Irie army I'm thankful for
each and every one of you it wouldn't be
an army without each one of you fill in
your position so thank you guys another
thing I am very grateful for is the
patreon support you guys have been very
generous on patreon thank you I
certainly noticed that and I appreciate
that the kind folks at BestBuy certainly
notice and appreciate your patreon
contributions you guys have covered the
cost of the MacBook that runs this
podcast so thank you you guys have kept
the podcast alive by contributing and I
certainly do notice it and I appreciate
it so thank you and if you're not
contributing on patreon don't feel left
out I still appreciate you just for
listening this for being a part of the
podcast and just for trying to be a part
of moving cannabis forward with me that
is my mission
I want to make cannabis more accepted by
society I want people to grow better
cannabis and I want people to have a
better understanding and a better
attitude toward cannabis in general so
just by listening and opening your mind
you were participating in the way you
can so thank you thank each and every
one of you for all the podcast support
now let's talk about some stuff that's
not podcast related I am grateful that I
am in generally good health I know I
sound like [ __ ] today I've got a little
cold big deal that'll go away I took
some medicine I took a lot of vitamins
I feel the medicine kicking in my palms
are getting super sweaty so this cold
will be knocked out for the most part I
am in good general health mentally and
physically I'm grateful for that I feel
like I'm doing fairly well business-wise
the podcast is part of my business the
podcast is taking off seed sales are
taking off I feel like I read genetics
is going really far we have spread our
wings quite far we've got a far reach
seeds are going everywhere people are
really happy with the products the
merchandise is selling quite well
everybody is happy with the company
myself the customers of the vendors
everybody is satisfied it's growing it's
expanding I'm really grateful for that
that was my little dream one day I was
like I'm gonna make a seed company and
look here it is it's happening you guys
I'm doing it so I'm really grateful for
that I set my mind to something I
thought about steps of how to do it and
I took those steps and it is happening
so I'm grateful that my efforts are
finally paying off it's been a long time
but it is doing something now and I see
it I can actually see the growth I can
see the explosion and I'm really
grateful for that through the expansion
of my company through social media
through all the things I have done in
the past few months I've made a lot of
new friends some really close friends
I'm really grateful for all the friends
I have made locally and through social
media worldwide I talked to a lot of
people that are nowhere near me I've got
friends in other states that I talked to
more than some people that are really
close to me so everybody from the people
in my neighborhood the people in my
house to the people worldwide that I
interact with my little support team my
Friendship Circle I'm [ __ ] super
grateful for each and every one of you
if you've texted me and I've replied if
we've had a conversation that meant
something to me so I'm thankful for you
thank you and I'll talk too much about
my family life on the podcast because
quite frankly that's not what we're here
for we're here to talk about cannabis
but I'm talking about what I'm grateful
for I recently had a health scare with a
family member and I am extremely
grateful he pulled through on that he
still got a long ways to go but it was
scary as [ __ ] for a couple of
days there and I'm extremely grateful
that he is okay I'm also super thankful
and grateful that my mom is still in
good health
she's probably my she's certainly my
closest family member my mom's probably
my best friend you guys so I'm really
grateful that my mom can be my best
friend and that she is still in good
health because she's not a spring
chicken she's getting up there an age so
I'm really thankful that she's still in
fairly good health also I'm glad my
daughter's doing well I don't talk about
my kid on the show a lot but if I'm
talking about [ __ ] I'm grateful for I'm
really grateful for that kid everything
about her I'm grateful for I feel like
those are most of the big major obvious
points I should be grateful for my
friends my family my loved ones my
business my general health I'm really
grateful for all of that stuff but also
they're random things that make me happy
every day just the fact that I can drive
just about any direction I can go ten
minutes that way I can go ten minutes
that way and I will arrive at a
dispensary that allows me to buy some of
the best cannabis flowers and cannabis
concentrates on the planet I am really
grateful for that ability I spent too
many years of my life having to hunt
down some good herb I spent too many
years of my life having to grow good
herb just to have it around I spent too
many years of my life having to watch
over my shoulder because I consume
cannabis so I'm really grateful for the
situation that we are in with cannabis
now of course things could be different
there are some things I would adjust
with the rules I would raise plant
counts I would make a lot of things a
little bit different but I am grateful
that I am able to acquire the stuff that
I enjoy and not have to feel like a
criminal something random that I'm
suddenly grateful for I can feel this
medicine I took starting to work my
sinuses are loosening up I'm starting to
feel a lot better so I'm definitely
grateful that I have access to medicine
that when I am not feeling well I know
I'm stubborn I don't take medicine so
I'm about to die but I really needed
some I finally took it and I feel much
better already so I'm grateful for that
stuff working another random thing that
I'm really thankful and grateful for is
my ability to play the drums I'm very
musical on the drums I'm very gifted on
the drums I'm not trying to brag I am
more grateful than bragging about it
right now that is something that I am
really proud of and I feel like I am
blessed to be able to play the drums the
way that I do so I'm absolutely grateful
on that that really feels like a humble
brag but
I'm so grateful because a lot of my wife
I made a living playing the drums I
travelled around the country playing the
drums I got paid playing the drums I
learned how I guess I kind of learned a
lot about business being sort of the
band manager I'm the obnoxious guy in
the group most of the time I'm the big
guy in the group a lot of the times so I
would be the guy that was sent to tell
the club owner [ __ ] you pay me when
things didn't go right so I learned a
lot about business by being in a band
and being the drummer so I'm grateful
that I had the skills to be a drummer
that took me places and I'm also
grateful that I learned some business
throughout that process and of course I
am super super grateful and thankful for
the skills I have acquired and developed
within the cannabis industry this plant
has taken me far and I owe a great
respect to the cannabis plant so I'm
grateful for the plant I'm grateful for
the industry like I said earlier there
are several things I would change about
legalization there are so many things I
would change about the cannabis industry
but overall I'm grateful that the
cannabis industry even exists and I'm
grateful to be involved in it on any
level and I'm grateful to have been
accepted by so many people as a teacher
as an advocate and somebody that people
look up to and respect in the cannabis
industry I'm really thankful and
grateful for all of that and one last
thing just to wrap this up because my
voice sounds like [ __ ] and I think this
is getting long enough
I am super grateful to live in this age
of information and technology you should
never say I wonder because there's no
need to wonder there's a device in most
of our pockets we can pull it out and we
can find the answer to almost anything
you wonder of course there's some
existential [ __ ] you should always
wonder the most facts most info it's in
your phone go find out I love it I love
being a part of this generation this
time period I love being right here I'm
very grateful that I'm a part of this
whatever we're gonna call it this
revolution this timeframe this era
I am excited thankful and grateful to be
right here in this time today right now
all right podcast world thank you for
letting me share things I am thankful
and grateful for I hope I reminded you
of a few things that you are thankful
and grateful for once again thank you
for listening to this podcast I know
that the episode 370 has not made it to
iTunes at the time of this recording
there is a technical issue with my
website
got the web guy working on it of course
it is the Thanksgiving holiday weekend
he has got some time with his family
which I totally understand
so we are putting all of that sort of
stuff on the back burner we're just
gonna chill out we're gonna enjoy time
with our family I'm gonna get over this
head cold we're gonna take care of this
stuff after the holiday everything
should be back to business really soon
sometimes when you're working with the
internet and computers and coding
shitness goes wonky and this is one of
those times we're trying not to stress
over it we're just gonna enjoy the
holiday season do you guys enjoy the
holiday season also thanks for being
patient with me as soon as we get the
website fixed we will put the episodes
up I will keep recording episodes I'm
not going to stop I'm sure some of you
have found the episodes on YouTube
YouTube is still letting me post that's
really easy it's a different method of
posting so that's not stopped at all
YouTube will continue once I get things
back together we'll get it all up on
iTunes and stitcher just like normal hey
guys thanks for letting me ramble at you
for a good ten minutes I hope everybody
had a great safe holiday even if you're
not celebrating Thanksgiving or ever you
are or whatever you're doing I hope
you're hanging out with some loved ones
I hope you're eating something delicious
and I hope you got to smoke some great
cannabis products with your friends and
family all right podcast world it is
time for me to wrap up this episode I
want to thank you for hanging out I will
be back Monday hopefully my voice sounds
a little bit better for you no
advertising no shout outs just a big
THANK YOU and until next time take a
phat dab and give your mom a hug for me