welcome to the show podcast world it's
time for episode 372 of the girl from
your heart podcast this episode is
brought to you by the holiday exceed
company if you need new seeds for your
garden I highly recommend the holiday
exceed company and you can find them at
www.sedar.com by letting you know what
I'm smoking on today I've been taking
dad's of banana OG ambrosia from
apothecary farms on the label it says it
is 83.2% THC and a total of 97 percent
total cannabinoids I've really enjoyed
the banana OG and it's kind of a change
from what I usually buy I usually like a
concentrate that makes my head spin
makes my eyes vibrate makes it hard to
think the banana OG is kind of more of a
mellow thing it's got me kind of chilled
out it's kind of slow motion it's got my
eyes nice and heavy
it's got my shoulders nice and chilled
out and I really dig the flavor of the
banana og so that's what I'm dabbing on
today I hope you guys are taking dabs of
something delicious I'm not sure if you
can tell but I still have a little bit
of that head cold hanging around I'm
trying to get rid of that I'm not gonna
let it slow me down I am going to
deliver a quality podcast and this
episode I plan to bring you another grow
lesson before we get to the grow lesson
I've got a couple of quick things to
cover I am working on the website of
course I am I read genetics Colorado
my website is I read genetics Colorado
comm we are currently doing some updates
during the process of updating the
website something went completely
freakin wrong and the podcast does not
work from the website anymore all of the
episodes that were up before the update
are still accessible none of the new
things I add to the website are posting
to the RSS feed my web guy is working on
it it is the holiday weekend so he has
taken a few days off but I'm sure he
will get back on it as soon as the
weekend is over my point is I know the
website is messed up and I apologize for
not having the episodes out on iTunes
and stitcher as regularly scheduled I
was just recently bragging about not
missing a Monday in five years and now
here I am I've missed the least one
Monday it looks like I may potentially
miss two mondays in a row I do apologize
however the episodes are recorded and
the shows are posted on YouTube so I
have not
recording I haven't stopped doing the
shows I'm just unable to post them to
iTunes and stitcher because of a glitch
with my website so please be patient
with me and please keep listening to the
show and please find the show on YouTube
if that is your only option of listening
for the next couple of weeks and also
real quick I'm gonna give a shout-out to
the guy who works on the website for me
I don't know if he listens to the show
regularly or at all but hey if you're
listening man big thanks for keeping the
website updated big thanks for all the
updates lately and also big thanks for
getting it fixed when you do get the RSS
feed back in action alright since I'm
givin shout outs let's give some shout
outs to a few of our patreon supporters
I owe a big shout-out to Jade how about
a big patreon shout out to Grimble the
druid and also a patreon shout out to
Tanner Martin oeq and of course another
shout-out to my friend Mel thank you for
all the patreon support I truly do
appreciate it and if you want to learn
how to become a patron you can do so by
going to www.hp.com slash grow from your
heart all the information you need will
be right there on the screen and again
thank you for all of the patreon support
all right podcast world I said earlier
this was going to be another grow lesson
so far in my series of grow lessons we
should have plants that are probably 12
to 14 maybe 16 or 18 inches tall they
are probably in three or five or maybe
seven gallon pots hopefully they are
nice and healthy they have got a fat
root system hopefully they're pest free
at this time hopefully you have it over
or under fertilize them we've talked a
lot about the proper environment and
conditions and feeding for these plants
so I think we know how to take care of
them by now let's talk about a few ways
to improve our productivity and the
vigor of our large veg plants now none
of this stuff is required none of this
stuff is mandatory these are the little
tips and tricks and bonus things that I
do to boost productivity and boost vigor
to kind of turbocharged the overall
performance of my garden one really easy
thing I like to do to all of my plants
to increase performance is just clean
off the crap on the bottoms of the
plants you've got a stalk coming out of
the dirt
and then you've got a few crappy
branches coming off the bottom and then
the next couple of branches will be more
substantial and then you'll have some
solid branches if those very bottom
branches are crappy don't be afraid to
remove them if you feel like they are a
waste of growth on the plant feel free
to take them off we are going to
lollipop heavily once we go into flower
so don't be afraid to move some of the
crappy bottom branches if it's a long
healthy branch that has the potential to
reach the canopy level you can leave it
but if it's ugly if it's droopy if it's
sucking up energy and not going to
produce anything that would be
worthwhile feel free to take it off then
that plant can focus its energy moving
up toward the top of the plant where we
want to build that lush canopy so feel
free to take crap off of the bottom so
now we've removed the crappy bottom
branches there are kind of a waste of
energy here is another thing we can do
to the bottom section of our plant to
improve the performance and move the
energy up toward the top
we've still got bottom branches because
we left some of those bottom branches on
the plant the inside bottom branching is
not going to receive much light so what
I like to do is find that branch and
just follow it up and remove any shoots
that I feel like are a waste of space so
you'll having a thick arm coming off and
then off of that you'll have like a
little tiny sub arm coming off those are
the shoots those are on the bottom of
the plant those are a waste of space
those are gonna turn into buds we do not
want to trim that is gonna be fluffy lar
fee useless little crap it is a trimmers
nightmare by removing that crap from the
bottom we direct the energy up toward
the top we can make bigger top chunky
buds those are better for trimmers those
are better for the market those are
better for the consumer
everybody wants those big fat buds so
let's clean off that crap off the bottom
so you've got the main stock coming out
then you've got your bottom to your
bottom four branches follow those
branches up and where you don't see any
light touching those little shoots feel
free to just pinch them or cut them
right off while you're cutting or
pinching or cleaning stuff off of plants
always keep this in mind you can go back
later and take more off but you cannot
glue the leaves and the shoots back onto
the plant so pay attention to what
you're doing but on that bottom section
just pull that crap in the inside right
off of there I go fairly hard on the
parts of the plants I plan on lolly
popping heavily early in flower anyway
so why not pull off a lot of that crap
now and send the energy up toward the
top of the plant
now while you're cleaning the bottoms of
the plants keep in mind that it may be
wise to take some clones before we put
these plants into flower what are you
going to grow next are you growing from
seed that you spent a lot of money on if
you paid a lot of money for those seeds
I definitely recommend you take a clone
off of each seedling and market we're
gonna talk about this in depth in a
future episode but if you've got a plant
from seed I recommend you take a clone
from it mark that plant plant a mark
your clone clone a go on down the line
with every seedling plant that you've
got then grow them out either grow out
the clone or grow out the original plant
and if you've got something amazing now
you have got a keeper clone of that to
keep around we're gonna talk about Fino
hunting we'll talk about mother plants
we're gonna talk about that sort of
stuff in a future episode but this is
something to think about while we are
cleaning the bottoms of our plants do
you want to use those two bottom
branches may make excellent clones some
of those chutes may have grown big
enough to turn into a clone keep that in
mind while you're cleaning up the
bottoms of your plants now let's talk
about another way to improve the
productivity of our plant and also a
great way to score a great clone from a
healthy plant and of course I'm talking
about topping topping our plant can
greatly improve the performance of our
plant if it is done at the appropriate
time and at the appropriate place in the
plant
now when I say appropriate time we can
do this at just about any point in veg
once the plant is large enough the
plants we are talking about are
certainly large enough if we are in
large veg this is prime time for topping
we have to top approximately 10 to 14
days before we enter the flowering phase
when we top a cannabis plant our mission
is to remove that top node out of the
plant that giant one that's sticking out
of the top making it look like a
Christmas tree we want to remove that
and our goal is to make the next set of
branches become two tops and that will
create competition within the branches
of the plant that will make all of the
branches try to reach up
become the next top basically somebody
killed the king and now all of those
next soldiers are trying to be the next
king the hormones in the plant will
indicate we're missing a top somebody
needs to take over cannabis has a trait
that is called apical dominance it
really wants one dominant top when you
remove that dominant top the rest of the
tops know there's an opportunity for
them to become that main top so you can
top the plants at various ages and at
various stages let's talk about the
process of doing it let me back up and
talk about doing it find that top branch
where it's too tall trace it down the
way I like to do it I kind of find a
spot where I'm thinking about cutting it
and I bend it over and I look at the
plant I say what would the plant look
like without that section is that too
much to cut off is that going to be
beneficial what is my goal in topping
right now mainly my goal instead of
having one giant top I want to create
sort of a bush so that I can grow space
and not have one giant bud hitting the
light but instead I can have a four by
four section of a bunch of buds growing
in the light instead of just one by
taking out that main top you create that
whole section into a bush so see which
one is gonna cut out and make the others
look like a nice even canopy you will
see it you'll get good at it it'll take
a little bit of trial and error it'll
take some confidence it is also very
strain specific topping an OG Kush or
something like that can be a real [ __ ]
because the nodes are so far apart that
you just make it look like a Charlie
Brown Christmas tree but once it grows
out of that it is going to be amazing
the more sativa dominant stuff if you
top scarlet begonias if you top storm
shadow it makes a beautiful bush and
they go crazy so kind of grab the top
and follow work your way down with your
hand and just kind of look and see what
it would it look like if I took this off
and you'll come to a point you'll take
off one and you'll see two branches that
stick up evenly toward the top and the
two branches and underneath that almost
come right up to that top section as
well you'll have four nice new tops and
you'll say that's what Rasta Jeff is
talking about I want to make these four
tops the tops then just cut that one out
and you'll see exactly what I've got
you're probably gonna screw up a couple
of plants that's how you learn stuff
musicians have to [ __ ] up songs to learn
BMX racers have to fall on their face to
learn skateboarders get stitches and
break bones to learn luckily we mess up
plants we can grow more plants
it doesn't hurt us that bad when we cut
up a plant the wrong way hopefully
you've got a couple more and you're
gonna learn the cost of cutting that one
plant from what you learn from it is
invaluable so get in there and just play
around with the scissors top some of
them bottom some of them up see what
they do finish them that way you have
some data now keep in mind that data is
very strain specific like I said earlier
if you're topping an OG Kush plant
you're gonna have totally different
results than if you're topping something
like a haze or a more sativa dominant
like a golden goat kind of a thing the
growth structure is just naturally
different in those plants now when
you're topping your plant do it at the
intersection where it's going to
encourage that plant the most expansive
growth so if you've got two branches cut
you've got the main stock coming up
you've got a branch coming out and then
maybe an inch up you've got a branch
coming out cut right above that top
branch you don't need to leave anything
hanging off or anything extra cut it
right at the intersection where you want
to encourage the spread you basically
want to take an upside down peace sign
and you want to turn it into a Wye and
those new tops of the Y are going to be
the new two tops of the plant and then
the next two branches hopefully they'll
catch up now that puts me back to why I
said we want to do this at least 10 to
14 days before we go into flower or much
sooner than that if it's an opportunity
when we make that cut we've just cut out
the king like I said earlier we need
time for those hormones to move around
into the plant and that helps us when we
go into flower we get much larger bud
sets if you if you flower too soon after
topping your plants just create little
popcorn buds the hormones haven't moved
around they're not exactly sure what to
do they're not sure where the top should
go so you just get a bunch of little
popcorns so give the plant plenty of
time to recover plenty of time to move
the hormones and plenty of time for it
to decide where the tops are going to be
after topping and before moving your
plants into flower earlier I mentioned
that this would be a good opportunity
for a clone that top you just cut off
should be the most robust Hardy
part of your plan that will make a great
candidate for a clone so why not snag
that up now you've got a big fat healthy
clone for the next crop while you're
increasing the productivity of the
current crop alright so we've covered
two great ways to increase the vigor and
productivity of our plants we've figured
out how to properly move the energy to
the part of the plant we want to grow
you can move it up to the top by taking
stuff off the bottom you can spread it
out by completely eliminating the top
and that process we've also created the
opportunity to create clones now let's
talk about another great technique that
I use in a personal garden I use this in
a breeding program I use this in a large
commercial grow this is something I
implement in almost any grow I get to
play in I call it the pop and twist
technique you may also know it as super
cropping it has got a lot of names it is
the same thing no matter what we call it
I like to pop the stems of the plant I
like to kind of pop their knuckles I
don't know if you could hear that on the
microphone I tried to get it in there
that's basically the sound I'm looking
for once the plants are a little bit
thicker than a pen or a pencil maybe a
sharpie I like to grab them right where
they come out of the dirt I grab the
stock kind of firmly with one hand then
I grab it with another hand right above
it and I twist my top hand I don't twist
that hand that's coming out of the dirt
I don't want to twist that dirt I twist
the top hand to her I break the
cellulose of the plant break that outer
structure toward you hear it pop a
little bit it'll go crunch just like my
knuckle did and it'll make a little pop
sound and you'll feel it and you'll be
freaked out the first time it's okay
don't freak out you're doing exactly
what I recommend this will increase
vigor and productivity in a couple of
ways this will be beneficial in a couple
of ways let's talk about that real quick
and we'll talk more about how to do this
throughout the entire plant the first
thing you'll notice when you're popping
the knuckles on these plants is they
will start to make little knuckles on
the branches I feel like these make the
plants more stout more robust so that
when they start to grow buds those
branches can hold up bigger buds bigger
branches bigger buds right that makes
sense you want more support bigger legs
you can lift more right you're stronger
if that mad sad I'm not kind of a
weightlifter guy but if you got more you
can lift more right so you want
something able to support bigger buds
also those bigger stems can probably
feed those bigger flowers better so
you've got more movement another way
this is beneficial is it will slow down
the vertical growth of the plants they
won't get so tall so quickly because
they will be spending a little bit of
their energy on getting fatter and more
robust they'll be short and stocky which
is way beneficial to almost any grower
where most of us are limited by height
in a home grow in a commercial grow in a
giant warehouse grow most of us are
still limited by height so having this
one tip to control the height of our
plants just a little bit can be very
advantageous later on we're gonna talk
about trellising if you can use cracking
and trellising together you can really
control the height of your plants and
you can really maximize productivity so
those are a few reasons why I like to
crack the stems now let's talk a little
bit more about actually doing it now
that I've given you a good reason why to
do this like I said I grab the stick
with one hand I grabbed the stick with
another and I just twist opposite
directions and you'll hear it it will go
pop and crunch then just move up I start
with the main stalk of the plant and I
work my way almost almost 90 percent up
the way of the plant as long as I can
feel it's still crunching as long as I'm
not feeling like I'm about to rip the
top off the plant when I give it a twist
I'll work my way right up then I go to
the bottom branch and work my way right
up the bottom branch then the next
branch and give it a crack
I'll give it a crack I'm looking at the
microphone stand here trying to think
about the distance of cracks I go one
and then it's only four to six inches
apart depending on the size of the plant
I will crack it maybe if it's a tiny
plant if they're short and squat I would
go every three inches if I feel like
that plant could take it most of them
will take it about every four to six
inches without any problems give it a
little crack move up give it a little
crack move up give it a little crack
just do that to every plant in the
garden it will slow down their growth
it'll make them more robust they'll be
more vigorous and you can continue to do
this all the way into about week three
of flower so if you start it early and
veg you can get a good cracking in there
give them about seven maybe ten days
you'll up go back give them another good
crack throw them into flour as they get
bigger they will recover more quickly
from being busted on so go in there and
give them a good crack on day one a
flower right at the start of the
flowering cycle slow down that stretch a
little bit and then think about it this
way if you crack spot one and then spot
two
there's a spot in the middle of that
that you can crack next time so you can
go back in a week and even if they
haven't healed up from all of their
cracking you can crack those middle
spots and make even another little
knuckle another little knurled spot on
your plants don't be afraid to get in
there and do some work on them and bust
them up a little bit they will recover
and they will really show progress from
this I know I probably sound like I'm
crazy because for the past ten minutes
I've been telling you to cut stuff off
of your plants and break them and bend
them and that's going to increase
productivity but how do you get stronger
through stress through proper training
and that's what we're gonna do to these
plants we're gonna tell them what we
want from them and we're gonna show them
what we expect and they're gonna give it
to us with the proper guidance
speaking of guidance let's work our way
into talking about canopy control
earlier I mentioned that our plants are
apical dominant meaning they want to
grow straight up unfortunately for us as
growers it does not benefit us for the
plants to grow straight up
we need to fill horizontal space we need
to spread them out a little bit we have
several options for encouraging our
plants to spread out our earlier work of
topping them was a great start but we
can go much further than that
a very easy affordable and effective way
to spread out our plants a little bit is
by using sticks you can get bamboo
sticks at the local gross store for very
cheap I like to put about four sticks
per pot and I like to put them toward
the outer edge of the pot don't go too
far in because you've got a lot of root
development there you don't want to go
shoving a bamboo stick right through a
bunch of roots so go out toward the edge
of the pot put the stick in there if
your plants are gonna grow six feet tall
get a six-foot stick if your plants are
only gonna grow three feet tall get a
three-foot stick you don't want a stick
too big to where you can't lower the
light close enough to the canopy so get
the appropriate size stick put three or
four five or six of them in the pot
depending on how many giant floppy
branches branches you've got
then you can just pull those big
branches down just a little bit and
attach them to the sticks now instead of
just having them going straight up
you've kind of pulled them down a little
bit now they're probably one or two
maybe three inches shorter depending on
how far you pull them down pull them
down and a fix him to those sticks now
you're doing a couple of things you're
making the plant overall shorter and
you're also widening the plant up to let
some light get into that inner part of
the plant so where you don't have to
clean off as much of that crap in the
inside more of the light can penetrate
in there and you will get more
production from the inside part of the
plant
now these sticks will also work for
another purpose when those buds start to
develop and get fat and big those sticks
will support your buds you're going to
need something to hold up the big buds
so now is the time to think about it
let's work that into our canopy control
and also our plan for supporting our
buds so sticks is the easiest most
affordable option if you've got a small
grow if you've got a home grow sticks
are probably the most economical if
you've got several plants a bunch of
sticks can become a pain in the ass in a
commercial environment I wouldn't even
mess with sticks in a commercial
environment you may want to start
working with tomato cages you need to
get the tomato cages on the plants
before they get too big I usually like a
tomato cage with about a 16 inch top
sometimes I will cut the very bottom
ring off of the tomato cage right flip
it upside down right where that bottom
ring is cut it off you've just made her
a little bit shorter but it's also a
little bit wider you can customize them
for your situation so slide the tomato
cage over the plant spread the plant out
nice and wide let it spread as wide as
it will go encourage it to spread out if
you need to pull some of the branches
out of the cage
pull it out of the cage and as it grows
it'll work itself up and when it gets
real tall put the branch back into the
cage or use those runners up the side
the side supports and you can always a
fix the branches to those side supports
by using a bread tie or a twisty tie or
some sort of garden supply twist tie
there are thousands of options for that
get creative I've used a bunch of
different things we don't need to be too
specific I use zip ties in most cases
but don't go too tight so if you got
your tomato cage on your plant the
branches are falling out and gaining
support from the outer perimeter of the
tomato cage
maybe you've worked some of the branches
up the side
that tomato cage maybe you pulled some
of the branches down and spread them out
by using those outer rings of the tomato
cage the tomato cage gives us a lot of
creative options for controlling the
canopy of our plant while at the same
time providing support for our tall
heavy buds now if you're using a tomato
cage and you did not top your plant
which is just fine that is always an
option you do not have to top the plants
a lot of people like that one big glory
but at the top if you're going for that
glory bud and you were using a tomato
cage you still may need a stick to
support that giant bud if you grow a big
fat top so don't be afraid to make them
work together you can have a tomato cage
with a stick
holding up that giant bud in the middle
again if you're gonna put a stick in a
giant pot I would kind of recommend
putting it toward the outer edge and
then angling it toward the center if you
need support in the center I don't like
to Ram a bamboo stake right into the
root zone that just feels rude to me if
you want it to be right in the middle
because you've got some kind of OCD or
that's where you need to do it you can
do it but just you'll feel it when you
go through those roots and it won't feel
right so those are two very effective
methods of controlling your canopy and
also supporting the large branches and
being prepared for having large buds I
know I kind of glazed over those two
methods those are things you're going to
have to perfect and work on it's going
to be things you have to put your hands
on to learn how to do it it's kind of an
art there will be things that you learn
when you're doing it it will work
perfectly for your situation it would
not work for the next guy the sticks are
really easy because you can just stick
as many sticks into a pot as you need I
mean I've seen people go completely
excessive try not to be too crazy but
you can stick as many sticks into a pot
of soil as you need to support as many
branches branches as you need and you
can use fuzzy sticks or bread ties or
zip ties whatever you need to fix those
branches to those sticks however you
need it's a little harder to lower the
canopy that way but you can get big
branch support that way really easily
the tomato cages you can use the zip
ties or the twisty ties and you have got
round circles to work with you can use
those to keep the plants down you can
bend the branches underneath the rings
of the tomato cage or you can use those
to support the big buds you've got a lot
of options there to work with but you're
gonna have to
play with it to figure it out I can walk
you so far through it but it's going to
be strain dependent situational
dependent but those are very versatile
tools to work with and I'm sure you'll
find some use now let me quit rambling
and talk about one of my favorite
methods of canopy control which is using
trellis netting also known as scrog
netting and of course scrog SC ROG just
means screen of green we're using a
screen to create a nice green canopy
let's talk about creating a screen of
green the number one most common mistake
I see people make when they are setting
up their screen or their trellis netting
for their screen of green or for their
canopy control as they put the netting
way too loose it needs to be tighter you
want that stuff really tight you want it
almost scary tight you want a lotta
tension on there you don't want those
squares you don't want the net to move
at all you want those squares to stay
right in place because that is what is
going to control the shape of your plant
if those things move the plant moves I
like them tight nice and firm like a
guitar string so let's talk more about
the netting now that I've already
pointed out the number one mistake let's
say we're setting up a net in a five by
five 10 it's really easy to set them up
in a tent they've already got the poles
if you don't have poles or something to
fix it to you're going to need to design
some sort of system you can attach it to
the wall a lot of people will get a
five-gallon bucket from Lowe's or Home
Depot they will fill it up with quikrete
and then they will stick a six-foot tall
PVC pole into their sticking straight up
now you've got a nice vertical pole that
you can work with to attach your net to
and that will hold a lot of weight you
can probably get it tight enough with
that five-gallon bucket filled with
cement that'll be enough weight to be
able to pull those screens super tight
so get yourself four buckets fill them
up with the quikrete put a six-foot pole
in each one now you make a little square
now you can make just about any type of
length or width of shape you need to put
your trellis netting
I think they sell it in five by five
squares five by ten squares if you want
to go commercial grade you can get it in
much larger segments sections whatever
the word you want to use right there
you can get it in a commercial
environment I recommend the six-foot
wide commercial greenhouse table
I have found a six-foot wide roll of
plastic trellis netting that works
beautifully for that application at a
six feet wide and it is I think 75 or
120 feet long and it is one roll so you
just put it up on top of the trellis you
got one guy on one side one guy on the
other and it's on a roll so you just
walk and it you zip tie one end of it
down one end of it down and you walk the
length you need to be the zip tie the
other end zip tie the other end and he
cut it off and now the trellis net is up
you of course you got to go back through
and tighten it by using more zip ties
but that's almost kind of fun once
you've got it put up that easily
so the long rolls are amazing they get a
little bit heavy but if you've got two
big dudes I'm 6-5 my buddy Brian he was
6 foot something we just grabbed it lift
it just above plant height walk right
down the rows stretch out a long enough
piece to cover that whole row zip tie it
at the end and cut our section off we'd
have another guy following behind us and
he would put the zip ties in place to
keep it real tight and it would take us
just a few minutes to get each row done
so you've got to start by spreading out
your trellis netting
that's always fun if it comes folded up
in that little baggie it is such a [ __ ]
to get that undone good luck you look
like Spiderman attacked you in [ __ ]
one you're gonna be there for a few
minutes getting that unfolded the bigger
the net the longer it takes don't get
frustrated go smoke a dab and then oh
you know what don't smoke it dad because
when you get all stone and you're trying
to look at that netting that [ __ ]
doesn't work for your face so just
unfold that and then once we get it put
up we'll go take some tabs so unfold the
trellis netting the best you can it's
gonna take you a few minutes get it put
up on whatever poles you've got
available I said we're gonna work in a
5x5 ten hopefully you bought a 5x5
section of netting it may be too big you
may need to go in a square you may not
need to use that outer square you may
need to go one or two squares into that
grid to make it fit tight enough you
don't have to necessarily use every
square of that netting we want it tight
more than we want the amount of squares
so get that net up there tight use a
bunch of zip ties go excessive if you
need it too we want that thing fairly
tight then lower it down onto the plant
canopy you'll watch the plants kind of
Bend you want to just keep going just
kind of bend them down just a little bit
not too far maybe like three or four
inches they'll Bend they'll be okay if
you see something that's about to crack
of course grab it and give it a hand the
idea here is to
actually lower the height of all of the
plants and we were going to use that net
to control the height of the plants
don't worry because we're gonna go back
and manually adjust each branch by hand
and work it into this net correctly but
right now we just kind of want to lower
it down and watch that canopy just
become even now you can see how this
works we have instead of one giant bud
here one long branch here one giant but
on a long branch over here now we've got
a nice even space to work with we want
to fill all that five by five net with a
bunch of small bud sites that will
actually turn into more productivity
than one giant bud here
one giant bud here that are trying to
touch the light we're fighting those
from getting too hot getting burnt
getting crispy and then we've got a
bunch of buds down here that aren't
getting enough light instead we've got a
nice five by five screen of green of
just beautiful even buds so let's talk
about how to work these branches into
this net to create this desired canopy
working a section of plants into a
trellis net is a bit of an art and it
will take some experience to perfect it
think of it sort of like weaving we want
to weave these plants that want to go
vertical we want to weave them into the
net to encourage them to go horizontally
now almost no matter what we do to these
plants other than kill them they're
going to try to grow up because earlier
we spoke of that hormone that gives them
apical dominance so we are going to need
to stay on top of canopy control in this
trellis system the idea is to fill each
square of that trellis net with a branch
that will develop into a substantial bud
site the way to start that process is to
train these plants to spread wide
instead of tall so we use this first
layer of netting to actually spread the
plants out now what we have to do as the
plants grow is they will try to pop up
out of the net we need to go in there
everyday and grab those branches that
tried to get away I just push them back
under that next piece of net so as soon
as they're long enough to go under net
underneath the next section just weave
them right underneath there and what
will happen is you will develop long
arms that fill up the entire space and
when we flip it to flower all of those
branches will develop bud sites that
will fill up each square of that trellis
netting now instead of having
plants that just grow big giant buds and
grow up into the light and are really
good for pictures we are actually
producing a large crop by utilizing the
entire 5x5 canopy space now this will
take some practice to figure out exactly
what I'm saying
some of you are going to try to force
those plants down too much somebody that
taught me a lot of tips on trellis work
will tell you give it a [ __ ] chance
you've got to give it somewhere to grow
up and win the tips of the branches like
to go up give them a chance to win but
don't be scared to get in there and bend
them down now something that is hard to
convey through just audio without any
sort of visual is you may think that to
get this branch the tip of this branch
under this net that you may need to bend
it at wrist height I'm showing myself
I'm comparing the microphone stand to my
wrist the microphone stand is horizontal
my wrist is growing up like a plant
I want to tuck this my wrist underneath
this piece of trellising instead of
grabbing at my wrist and bending there
and tucking that part under I would
actually go down to elbow height to my
elbow joint and pop it down there
and bend it underneath the trellis at
that height that gives me a lot more
room for when that plant starts growing
vertically it's gonna grow out
horizontally because of gravity for a
little while the tip will start growing
up and it's gonna take it a little bit
longer to grow up out of that net again
don't be afraid to crack it lower than
you think you need to is what I'm trying
to say hopefully that gave you enough
different explanations to try to catch
on to what I'm saying but if you think
you need to crack it here to get it
underneath the net that's right here go
a little lower so you've got more
bending room to work with and you've
also got more room for future growth you
guys trellising and canopy work is an
art but when you get good at it it will
drastically improve productivity and
will also make the garden much easier to
work in because it's much more organized
and you don't have that one giant bud
that's trying to grow into the light
which is so photogenic and it's so
beautiful to have but it's also such a
pain in the ass because that's the one
bud you are working your whole garden
setup around so you will learn how to
weave your plants into the snap
perfectly you will adapt your own style
yo I'm sure you're going to the internet
to look at pictures of how to do it
already you'll see a lot of great stuff
on there you will also see a lot of
trellis
nets that were not filled sufficiently
before the plants were flipped into
flour fill that [ __ ] out it takes a
little bit of time it takes more work
but it is much more rewarding than just
growing that one glory bud so if you're
going to use the screen to spread them
out make sure you fill up that canopy
before you flip now I also recommend a
second layer of trellis netting I
probably would put that one depending on
the power of your light depending on
your genetics I would probably put my
second net somewhere between six and
twelve inches above that first net now
the bottom net will fill up you'll leave
it all in and it will get full now you
want to let those branches start growing
up into that second net you want to fill
it up to where you've got one branch
coming out of each of those bottom
squares and those will grow up into the
top squares as soon as they hit the top
squares you want a flower now you've got
a nice six to twelve inch section of
just rows of buds just rows of branches
sticking straight up I would almost
lollipop and bottom and D foliate almost
everything underneath that first net
that all gets cleaned off all that lar
fees stuff the canopy is the lights not
gonna penetrate the canopy far enough to
make that worth anything
I generally clean all that off so that
bottom net is there to spread them out
and give them control you want to spread
the plant that would be growing five
feet tall straight up we've got it three
feet tall but it's also spread five by
five feet wide so we're trying to fill
in all that net space then we're gonna
let it grow a little bit vertically out
of that until it kind of gets close to
that next net then we're gonna flower
all those branches that are sticking
straight up are going to turn into big
fat buds that will grow into that second
net that second net at that point is
going to work as a support it's only
going to be there to hold up all of your
giant buds quite often in a commercial
environment I've had to use a triple
trellis and sometimes we have considered
a fourth that's all going to pinned on
your genetics and what kind of lights
you're using of course we're using
things like a rise underneath Gavita
lighting in a commercial environment we
were getting serious growth if you're in
a tent
you're only going to need the spread net
and then the one net up top for support
now if you want to use the trellis
netting and you don't want to work it
into the net is far if you just want to
use it more for a spread and not kind of
create the scrog you can do that you
don't have to work them as far you can
just put the net on and spread them out
try to get one stick per branch if you
can try not to overcrowd anything the
idea is just to spread it out you kind
of want to spread them make them shorter
than they were tall you want to use more
of that vertical space somebody taught
us a long time ago if you've got a
cooler do you just want to put one layer
of beer in that cooler or do you want to
fill that whole cooler up with beer
that's kind of what we're trying to do
with our canopy we don't just want a
couple of beers touching the Wyatt we
don't want to make a beer tower we want
to knock all those beers down and put
them in one nice a case just like they
were sold in because that's how they
stack the best that's how you can fill
it the best I'm not even a beer drinker
and I still want to fit as many beers as
we can in a cooler also I should
recommend an article I read a long time
ago by an author named Eric vixa the
article was called growing on the grid
and it was exactly on this subject it
talked about maximizing your growth
potential by utilizing the horizontal
space not just the vertical space that
our plants try to create so one thing I
should mention is that you will not be
able to move these plants once you put
the trellis net on so you've got to do
this in whatever room these plants will
be flowering in I started the example by
using a five by five grow tent so in
most cases we would veg in that five by
five put up the scrog and then flowered
in that five by five not a big deal if
you are vegging and flowering in a
different environment you will have to
veg them drag them to the flowering room
try to put that trellis up on day one
spread them out nice and wide you're not
going to be able to work them in too
much but you can kind of bend and
manipulate the plants a little bit
without causing any problems use the
cracking technique I talked about
earlier grab the branch give it a little
bit of a twist and bend it over just a
little bit you'll be able to create a
little knuckle there also create a nice
smooth bed you can control the plant aim
in any direction you want move it over
to the section of the trellis you need
it just be very gentle with them give
them several days to recover before you
go back in and crack them again this is
pretty much how we're forced to do it in
a commercial environment because we
don't veg and flower in the same room we
usually have one large veg area and
multiple
flowering rooms so that we can keep our
petrol cycles going in a commercial
environment one of my major goals is to
harvest and refill a room in the same
day I know that doesn't sound like a big
challenge but imagine if you've got 300
plants in one room you've got a bunch of
trellis netting it takes half of the day
to get it cut down then you got to clean
the room spotless then try to refill it
that's always fun
then we throw the net on then we spend
the rest of the day just spreading those
plants out and adjusting that net tore
those plants aren't too angry with us so
that is my long sidetrack rambley talk
on sticks cages and trellis netting and
canopy control I've got a couple more
quick things to cover on this list of
ways to improve our productivity while
in veg the next thing on my list is
integrated pest management and scouting
we should probably be applying a
preventative pesticide regimen to our
plants at this time if you're going to
use a spray application now is the time
to get started if you're going to use
predator bugs now is the time to order
them and get them prepared so that we
have a nice colony before we go into
flower one thing a lot of growers
overlook at this stage of the game is
manually scouting for pests one of your
best tools and finding bugs in your grow
is your own eyes spend a little time
walking through the garden and just
looking for pests or signs of pests
nature really likes to give us hints
that there are problems in our garden
every pest that comes in gives us some
kind of a warning if you were on top of
your game you've got some yellow sticky
traps hanging up and you were checking
those on a daily basis they will give
you a fair warning that you've got bugs
coming in you know how they'll tell you
there will be bugs stuck to the yellow
card how much more obvious can it get so
check the yellow sticky traps then walk
every row every few feet reach into the
canopy and grab a leaf pull it right off
flip it upside down look at it do you
see any bugs on the underside of the
leaf do you see any eggs on the
underside of the leaf look at the top
side of the leaf do you see any
stippling that is spider mite damaged do
you see any honeydew that is three
damage do you see anything that just
doesn't look right that could be a sign
of overfeeding underfeeding or pH
problems pay attention to the plants and
they will tell you when something is
starting to go wrong and you won't need
to panic
so scout on a daily basis walk through
the grow look at the plants look for
might damage look for thrip damage go
smack the pots just give a couple pots
of good smack
does anything fly out if so you've got
fungus gnats those are really easy to
treat if you find them early scout for
bugs teach all of your helpers to scout
for bugs look for spider mite webbing
also look for powdery mildew look for
anything that just doesn't look right if
you are a crew leader teach people how
to properly report the things that they
see so they know when to come to you
some people say how doesn't look like a
big deal teach them what is a big deal
and what is not a big deal so always be
on the lookout for bugs always be
scouting and know what you're looking
for you're looking for mites and mite
damage which is webbing stippling now
you're looking forthe rip [ __ ] you're
looking forthe rip honeydew that glazy
stuff on the lower leaves that's from
your thrips when you tap the pots those
little black things that fly up those
are fungus gnats when you shake the
leaves those little white bugs that fly
out those are white flies be aware of
what you're looking for and constantly
be looking for them healthy plants will
be much more vigorous and much more
productive than plants that are fighting
off insects also scouting is free it
doesn't cost you anything to walk
through your grow and look for bugs you
should enjoy it put on a podcast put on
the grill from your heart podcast there
on the dude grows put on some Joe Rogan
and just stroll through the garden and
go see what you can find add a go find
the problem chances are there's
something wrong you just need to go find
it alright I'll quit ranting about IPM
hopefully I have inspired you to go look
for bugs in your garden you know what
else is free it will really improve the
quality of your garden overall is
note-taking write down everything you do
that way when something goes wrong you
know what to blame it on and you know
what not to do next time I've done an
entire episode on journaling I'm not
gonna rant too much on that right now
I've got one more thing to talk about
and then we're gonna wrap up this
podcast because my throat is starting to
burn
another way we can increase productivity
and vigor of our veg plants is to
augment the co2 levels in our grow room
the ambient co2 level in your
environment is probably hovering
somewhere between 300 and 400 particles
per million that is just about the
standard on earth and my last research
depends on where you are your elevation
what kind of city you're in but it's
somewhere between 300 and 400 particles
per million our plants would prefer
somewhere around a thousand particles
per million they can take up to 1200
maybe 1500 I've even seen people push
them closer to 2000 particles per
million of co2 and the plants just
explode with vigorous growth now there
are several ways that you can increase
the co2 in your room one thing I need to
mention once you start increasing the
amount of co2 in your grow room
environment it is very unhealthy for the
plants to let the co2 levels decline
past what you have now increased it too
so if you start boosting it to a
thousand you either need to keep it at a
thousand or increase through flower your
plant is expecting this co2 as a new
food source it is now feeding itself
like it's got another food source you
have now put your plant into another
level of high performance it's expecting
to get that high performance fuel it's
adjusted its diet accordingly if you cut
off that co2 that extra co2 it will not
be feeding itself properly you will
start seeing nutrient burn so make sure
you keep up on your co2 habit if you
start that habit and also if you run out
and the plants start acting a little
funny that is probably what is causing
it as they're still craving that co2
they're still trying to readjust their
metabolism because they're still on that
high performance mode and they're not
sure what to do yet so that was my last
tip for increasing performance and
productivity and vigor of our veg plants
I shared a lot of my dirty secrets a lot
of the things that I use in my personal
grows a lot of things that I use in the
commercial grows I hope you learned
something from my talk today I want to
thank you guys again for listening if
you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
and you would like to make a financial
contribution to the show I would
appreciate your support and you can do
so by going to page
on Comm slash growth from your heart all
the information you need to become a
patron will be right there on the screen
and again I do appreciate all of the
patreon support I would also appreciate
it if you follow me on social media you
can find me on Facebook simply search
for the girl from your heart podcast on
Twitter it's @gf wih podcast if you'd
like to follow my personal twitter feed
it's at Rasta Jeff 420 if you've got
something to say and you're not into
social media you can reach me through
email my email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com and I would love to
hear from you don't forget that the
podcast is available on YouTube I will
get the iTunes and stitcher feed
corrected very soon don't forget to
visit our sponsor that held a dank seed
company at dank seed dot store I'll be
back in just a few days with the fresh
new episode I want to thank you guys
again for listening I want to give a
huge shout out to my buddy Jesse James
and until next time take a phat dab and
give your mom a hug for me