welcome to the show everybody it's time
for episode 377 of the Grove from your
heart podcast this episode is brought to
you by the hella dank seed company if
you need new seeds for your garden I
highly recommend the hella dank seed
company and you can find them at dank
seed dot store I like to start the
podcast off by letting you know what I'm
dabbing on today I've got a nice little
buffet of viola labs concentrates in
front of me let's start off with this
sfv og chem daily camp I really like
this because of the diesel II dirty
funky fuel II smell I'm giving it a
smell right now it's got a hint of
diesel feel to it and then that sfv og
in there gives it that kind of fuel II
Feeny kind of thing and I really like
that aroma a lot the next on the list is
the TK la this one smells great I'm
cracking it open right now to give it a
smell it's got that earthiness to it
it's got a little bit of a gas eNOS to
it not as extreme on the diesel Terp as
the sfv but it certainly does have a few
li earthy sort of aroma to it and the TK
la packs quite a punch this one kind of
put me to sleep last night so I'm loving
the TK la and then if we're gonna go by
flavor this next one would be my
favorite in terms of flavor
this is the Tropicana cookies this one
as soon as you crack it open I get a
hint of grapefruits followed by a little
bit of maybe bubbly champagne or maybe a
hint of pineapples now that I'm smelling
it up real close there's a hint of
pineapples and grapefruits in here and
as it lingers on my nose I smell sort of
a sweet candy maybe a sweet tart sort of
a thing so I've got a nice variety of
concentrates from our friends at viola
labs today it's hard to pick a favorite
out of all three of these I like that
sfv o G chem de Lechem blend because of
that gassy decently sort of aroma and
that aftertaste that it leaves I really
love the Tropicana cookies because of
that sweet grapefruit pineapple kind of
flavor and then it just leaves a
candy-coated layer on your tongue but
that tea KLA it lacked in flavor but it
really punched me with the potency so
there are all three winners in my book
big shout out to veal the labs they've
been doing a great job lately and I'm
staring at this package on my table and
I just realized it no matter which way I
turn this this says viola upside down
or right side up so great job at the
creative logo there I'm honestly not
sure if it's viola or viola I was
recently told that it was named after
the one of the people's grandmother I
would like to get your name correctly
but everywhere I go if I say viola in a
dispensary they correct me and say it's
viola if I start by saying viola they
correct me and say it's viola
so I'm always wrong so I don't know the
proper way to say it but big shout out
to your company you're doing a great job
at the concentrates I do approve I will
be back for more while I'm talking about
this great concentrate I should mention
where I picked it up I grabbed this at
the Colorado cannabis exchange at the
south end of Pueblo big shout out to my
friends at the Colorado cannabis
exchange for always taking super good
care of me you guys they do not pay me
to say that they do not sponsor me they
do not endorse me they're just super
great to me every time I go in there
they treat me with kindness
they're super patient and they always
know what to recommend for me so I
appreciate that thank you guys big shout
out in a big fist bump to the whole crew
and the one that got me super talkative
out of that mess was the Tropicana
cookies the other two were kind of more
on the mellow side that Tropicana
cookies lifted my head up and made me
super talkative again so let's get into
a podcast you guys this will not be a
long episode this is going to be a
Thursday episode I have been spoiling
you guys with two episodes every week I
don't want to cut back on episodes but
I'm going to do a couple of short
Thursday episodes for a couple of weeks
while I get a few things handled I am
just busy I'm overwhelmed I don't want
to stop doing podcasting at all but the
Thursday shows make it a little shorter
the Mondays shows will stay long intense
there'll be in-depth grow lessons but
for Thursday's we make goof-off for a
couple of weeks let's have some fun in
this episode let's read some current
iTunes customer ratings and reviews if
you'd like to leave an iTunes customer
review I would appreciate your review
and I will read it on a future episode
to leave a review it's really easy if
you're listening on your iPhone go to
the Grove from your heart podcast go to
the most current episodes and scroll up
as you scroll up the opportunity to
write a review will pop up just click on
there write a review when you click on
write a review the first thing it does
is give you the opportunity to click an
amount of stars click on the amount of
stars you feel I deserve be honest so
far most folks have left five star
reviews I've gotten one one star review
we read that on the show earlier and two
we've got a three-star review we will
get into that one but please leave the
amount of stars you feel I deserve and
type in an honest review and I will read
your review on a future episode if
you're listening to the podcast on a
computer and you were using iTunes and
you'd like to leave a customer review go
to the podcast tab in iTunes it says
music and movies and TV shows and
podcasts click on where it says podcasts
then once you get to the podcast screen
you need to click on the store that's
where you search for the drove from your
heart podcast the search bar is on the
right then you click on the podcasts tab
once you were on the podcast page the
ratings and reviews tab will be very
easy to find it is right next to the
show logo click right there
ratings and reviews will pop up that's
where you are able to leave the amount
of stars you feel are appropriate and
you will be able to type in your review
now let's get into some of the most
recent iTunes customer reviews
our first iTunes customer review is left
by people that call themselves stone
blue the headline says informative and
fun they left us a five-star rating it
says thank you Russ to Jeff for your
informative and fun podcast my wife and
I have made it sort of a ritual to
listen to your podcast while we're
tending our garden time in the garden
together has strengthened our
relationship and were happy to have you
as a part of it she usually doesn't like
to listen to podcasts but after a few
episodes she warmed up to it quickly as
growers ourselves we encourage our
friends to start their own garden and we
recently turned them on to your grow
lessons if you have taken our suggestion
and it's easier than going to their
house and walking them through
everything so thank you Timothy green
thumbs and dread head Martha hey Timothy
green thumbs and red head Martha it is
an honor to be in your grow with you
it's an honor to be contributing to your
relationship and helping you to build a
bond together while building a bond with
your plants
that's an awesome iTunes review I truly
appreciate that I also appreciate that
you are sharing the show with other
people that means a lot to me a great
way for the show to grow is by word of
mouth so you were doing a great job
thank you thanks for the great review
thanks for the great support and thank
you for sharing the show and it's kind
of funny that you say it's easier than
going to their house because that's part
of what started me
boarding a show I got tired of telling
the same speech over and over on how to
do stuff so I just started recording it
and posting it and when people ask me
the same question I can say hey just go
listen to episode 315 and you can learn
about mother plants so I'm glad that you
got the same idea and you were sharing
the show so that people can learn hey
Timothy green thumbs and redhead Martha
I look forward to catching you at a show
this summer thanks again for the great
itunes customer review our next customer
review comes from somebody we have heard
from before this person calls themselves
Yolo grower they left us a three star
review the title of their review is
white Mike and their iTunes customer
review goes like this I think 99% of
your listeners are here for grow
information it would be great if you
stopped bringing white Mike on the show
so we don't have to listen to politics
cannabis-related or not it's still
politics I don't think you have to
convince your listeners to be Pro
cannabis we obviously all are Pro
cannabis well first off let me thank you
for the customer review and thank you
for listening you're obviously listening
to quite a few episodes if you are
catching the mike episodes so I'm
grateful that you're here I'm grateful
that you're a part of the crew I'm
grateful that you were enjoying most of
the show as for not liking the episodes
with Mike the podcast is free and you
can always skip the episode I can
recommend the dude grow show baddam done
show or you can always try to listen to
cannabis cultivation and science with
tad huh see if you need more grow
knowledge while I'm not doing a grow
lesson also let me point out that the
point of the show is cannabis news
education and conversation and just
because we're not talking about growing
cannabis doesn't mean that you're not
going to learn something that there's
not something valuable also just because
there's not something valuable for you
in that lesson doesn't mean that a lot
of people are enjoying it so however
much I do appreciate your review I'm not
gonna change anything Mike is one of my
best friends Mike is a valuable resource
and to be quite honest with you several
people request more episodes with Mike
so look forward to hearing from Mike on
the show this is an out loud invitation
hey Mike whenever you want to come on my
show brother you were always [ __ ]
welcome that seat across from me that is
yours bro come be on the podcast Mike
number two is for you whenever you are
free so Yolo grower
unfortunately this isn't gonna work out
for you I'm going to have Mike on the
podcast more I feel like he is a
valuable resource I feel like educating
and informing our community is an
important thing I feel like I've got a
large audience and part of my
responsibility is to educate and invoke
people I want people to vote I want
people to support cannabis you say that
obviously all of us are Pro cannabis
maybe not I encourage people to listen
to my show with people who are not
cannabis friendly so that we can
possibly sway them to be cannabis
friendly so I'm sorry you don't like you
know what I'm not even sorry it's too
bad you don't like some of the episodes
I wish you would have more of an open
mind and you would learn to enjoy those
episodes with Mike because honestly
there is some gold hidden in those
episodes if you were skipping them
you're missing some good [ __ ] sorry you
couldn't hang out with us for the good
times
Yolo grower I hope everything goes well
for you I hope you still listen to the
episodes without Mike I look forward to
your next review I'm sure I'm gonna hear
from you sometime soon keep doing what
you're doing you will never slow me down
alright let's move on to the next iTunes
customer review this next review comes
from somebody who calls themselves supa
Shah they left us a five-star rating the
headline says this podcast is for you
and the review goes a lot like this if
you were anything like myself and have a
desire to learn how to grow this show is
one of the best ways period from the
basics all the way to his latest grow
lessons Geoff's knowledge and passion
resonate through the podcast hey super
Shaw thank you for the great review I'm
glad you're listening to the grow
lessons and I'm glad that they're
helping you out and I'm glad that you
see my passion I've got a lot of love
for the cannabis plant I've got a lot of
love for people and I want people to
grow the best cannabis they possibly can
I think a podcast is one of the best
ways to effectively teach people how to
grow because knowledge changes everyday
in the cannabis world so I can do
updates I can teach you what I've
learned I can share my knowledge without
having to write a book I feel like by
the time you finish writing a book you
run it through all the processes the
publishers the editors by the time that
book comes out it's pretty much outdated
and all of your knowledge needs to be
rewritten with a podcast I can record an
episode the day I learn something I can
get it out and get all that fresh
content right to you so thank you for
enjoying the podcast and thank you for
learning with me I never enjoyed
but I always enjoyed learning new things
so having a different way of learning
things was always great to me and
finding podcasts and different avenues
of absorbing knowledge without sitting
in a classroom and listening to some
teacher drone on about crap I didn't
care about I feel like learning through
podcasts and things like that were a
great option and an opportunity for a
person with a brain like mine who is
always inquisitive but doesn't have any
desire to sit in a classroom and be
still and listen to a lecture and I
think that also makes me understand how
to teach people in a different way I
don't teach in a traditional way because
I don't learn in a traditional way so
since I've got some weird a DD or
boredom or whatever I feel like I can
keep people's attention who also suffer
from the ad D or the boredom I can get
you learning I can suck you in and you
don't get bored listening to the girl
essence and then you're able to absorb
the knowledge you'll laugh a few times
and at the end it doesn't feel like you
were just beat up by some lecturer so
super Shaw after a long ramble thank you
for a great iTunes review and also thank
you for noticing my passion for cannabis
and also my passion for teaching I feel
like it's partly my duty to teach people
about cannabis I was blessed to absorb a
lot of knowledge about the cannabis
plant very quickly at a young age I was
also very blessed to be involved in the
cannabis industry as it bloomed around
me I feel like it is my job and part of
my karma to go and teach as much as I
can about this plant and to shine as
much positive light on this plant as I
can so it does mean a lot to me when
people notice my passion and my desire
to teach and might drive behind this
plant so extra thanks for noticing that
dude that means a lot to me alright
let's move on to our final iTunes
customer review for this episode this
last review comes from a person who
calls themselves seven eight nine four
five four eight seven nine eight two
three one two three that's a very
specific name they left this review on
December 10th they left me a five-star
review and the title of their review is
full melt six star podcast and that is a
hash joke and I do approve they are
saying that this podcast is full melt we
will leave no funky residuals on the
nail and everything will burn clear and
it will taste great this is
six star full melt podcasting right here
d that's a great review I appreciate
that
that's just the headline the review goes
on to say I loved ABS very irrelevant to
the show but since you said fool melt
six star podcast I can't be mad at you
about anything
I loved ABS and you approve of the show
we are friends big shout out and thanks
for the 5-star customer review from our
new friend seven eight nine four five
four eight seven nine eight two three
one two three bro how did you come up
with that name that's creative thank you
for the great review everybody thank you
for the great iTunes customer reviews I
do appreciate all the support all of the
ratings even if you're not a big fan of
parts of the show I still thank you for
listening when you do listen and once
again I would appreciate it if you leave
a customer review on iTunes
all right podcast rolled I told you at
the top of the show that this was going
to be a short episode it is time for me
to start wrapping up the podcast I want
to give a couple of quick patreon
shoutouts I need to give a huge shout
out to Keith Kay and also a big giant
shout out to bacillus G thank you for
all the patreon support if you would
like to learn how to support the show on
patreon you can do so by going to
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
all of the information you need to
become a patron will be right there on
the screen once again I want to give a
giant shout out to everybody who is
contributed to the patreon campaign it
means the world to me
ladies and gentlemen I would appreciate
it if you find me on social media you
can find me on Facebook simply search
for the growth from your heart podcast
you can find me on Twitter it's at G fyh
podcast you can also follow my personal
Twitter account
it's Rasta Jeff 420 if you were in the
cannabis photography I suggest you
follow my instagram my instagram is Irie
underscore genetics iri e underscore
genetics on instagram give it a follow
check out my fine cannabis photography
also join me in my live feeds I go on
Instagram live and I ramble for a solid
hour we answer Gro questions we hang out
with my friends we take some dad's you
never know what could happen to my live
feeds and it has been a lot of fun
lately if you've got something you'd
like to say and you're not into the
social media you can contact me through
email my email addresses grow from your
heart at hotmail.com and I would love to
hear from you don't forget to visit our
sponsor the hell a dank seed company and
you can find them at
dank seed dot store ladies and gentlemen
I'll be back Monday with another grow
lesson we are going to flip our plants
into flour on the next lesson so make
sure you join me for that I want to give
a huge shout out to my buddy Kelvin
Medina and until next time take a phat
dab and give your mom a hug for me