welcome to the show podcast world it's
time for episode 378 of the girl from
your heart podcast this episode is
brought to you by the hel a dank seed
company if you need new seeds in your
garden I highly recommend the Hellenic
seed company and you can find them at
www.sedar.com off by letting you know
what I'm smoking honestly today I feel
like total [ __ ] and I haven't been dead
and I'm giving my body a little bit of a
rest I've got a head cold I've got a
chest cold I've got this sinus thing
going on that is driving me completely
crazy so I'm not gonna take any dabs
before the show gonna try to keep my
[ __ ] together and deliver you guys a
decent podcast in the last episode I
promised another grow lesson if you've
been following along you know I've been
doing a long series of grow lessons the
grow series started at episode 351 if
you haven't caught up I suggest you head
back to episode 351 an episode 351 we
set a goal for our garden and then we
move on to selecting a space for our
garden we also select the proper
equipment then we build the grow room
then we talk about seeds and clones then
we veg our plants then we talk about a
few tricks and tips to get our plants up
to speed for quality production and at
this point in my grow lessons it is day
one of flower it is time to flip our
crop from the vegetative phase into the
flowering phase of our grow so I'm gonna
press pause for a moment I'm going to
listen back to this intro and see how I
sound and when I come back we are going
to talk about flowering our new cannabis
garden
all right podcast rolled I apologize
that I do sound kind of crappy but the
show must go on I've been promising this
episode I may make this one kind of
quick and then recap next week and move
forward my original idea was to do a
three week chunk of flowering episodes
we would do week one through three and
then four through six and seven through
nine but we are going to focus on day
one of week one today and then we will
adjust from there in the following
episodes so let's get started on
flowering our cannabis garden what do I
mean by flowering we want to initiate
the budding phase the flowering phase
for regular cannabis plants is triggered
by reducing the light cycle if you were
working with Otto flower plants you are
in a total different ballgame those
plants will flower when they are ready
for this discussion we're going to focus
on regular photo
period plants and photo period seeds so
let's talk about flowering our photo
period garden initiating flower is very
easy all we do is reduce the timer to 12
hours on and 12 hours off we need 12
hours of uninterrupted darkness every
day to trigger these plants to flower
I've set up several times but I'm going
to repeat myself
we need total uninterrupted darkness
during the night phase for our flowering
plants a little bit of light is too much
if you can see a pinprick of light
coming in that room it is too much light
if you can see your hand in front of
your face during the dark phase in that
room it is too much light those plants
know that that light is there they will
not go to sleep properly they will not
flower properly if they do try to flower
properly you give them the chance of
hermaphroditic on you in mid flower
which will produce seeds in your garden
which will ruin your whole goal so we
need 100% total darkness in our
flowering room during the night phase so
switch the timer to 1212 be sure that
you have got total dark in that dark
phase you need to go in there and look
you probably need to hang out in the
grow room for about 15 to 20 minutes for
your eyes to adjust properly to identify
the most minimal light leaks you could
possibly have so go in there and check
for light leaks on day 1 of flower if
you have any light coming in you need to
correct that that will ruin your garden
so we've set the timer to 1212 now it is
on for 12 hours a day and it is off for
12 hours a day put a lot of thought into
the hours which your lights run do you
want those lights to come on in the
morning when you wake up so you can
water the plants before you go to work
and then the plants are on all day while
you're gone at work hopefully you get to
come home and check them out before the
lights turn off or do you want those
lights to come on in the evening right
when you get home from work and the
lights can run all night while your home
and you can check on everything maybe
you can get up before work and they're
still on you can check on them again
before you go to work and make sure
everything's cool I would put a lot of
thought into scheduling my flowering
cycle another thing to consider while
you're planning your schedule is
electricity is cheaper during off-peak
hours that means that during the
evenings when everybody goes home and
they're chilling electricity gets
cheaper during the daytime business
hours when everybody's using all the
electricity The Electric Company does
charge you more
those peak hours what many folks will
choose to do is run those lights during
off-peak hours and save money on
electricity this is also advantageous
because it is cooler during the evening
so you don't have the Sun up keeping
your grow room extra hot you're not
heating the outside with the Sun and the
inside with the grow lights the Sun Goes
Down and gets a little cooler outside
you can use that cool outside air to
your advantage and keep the grow room
cool so think about your scheduling when
do you want that 1212 on cycle to be
when do you want that 1212 off cycle to
be if you do decide to run your lights
at night and have your dark cycle during
the natural light cycle be sure that no
sunshine is creeping into your grow room
during that night cycle again we need
total darkness a very common mistake is
that people flower their plants at night
which means they are in the sleep cycle
during the day which means there's the
opportunity for the sunshine to sneak
into your grow room if you've got a
window if you've got a doorway if you've
got some kind of insecure structure you
can get light in there very easily and
it will destroy your crop so you've
thought about scheduling and you know
how it's going to work around your work
schedule you know how it's gonna work
around your life and you know when
you're going to flower these plants you
know when you'll have time to give them
maintenance and work on them and water
them so plan your scheduling around that
so we have set the timer to twelve
twelve that is day one of flower that
first short day is day one right that
day down to many people forget to write
that down and they don't know how long
their plants have been in flower
write down your flowering start date
another thing I want to make clear is
this is day one of flower if you've got
a package of seeds and it says takes 70
to 80 days to flower this is the first
day of that 70 to 80 days of that
finishing time a lot of folks like to
start the flowering phase when they see
bud set starting when they see pre
flowers you are 12 days into flower by
then and you were ripping yourself off
flowering starts the day we change the
timer to twelve twelve that is day one
of flower
so we've now switched the timer to
twelve twelve the plants will be on for
twelve hours a day and off for 12 hours
they are going to start flowering let's
talk about the environmental conditions
we need to provide for our flowering
plants here at the beginning of flower
this will change
as the plants progress right now we
don't have any buds to worry about
they're much less opportunities for
mildew and molds to take hold because
when you get those chunky buds the
mildew likes to start in the middle of
those buds that's not really a worry
right now so we can have the humidity a
little higher at this point we can have
the temps a little higher at this point
but as we progress we are going to lower
the humidity and the temperature in our
flowering room to accommodate those big
chunky buds and to prevent problems so
at this phase of the game it would be
ideal to have your grow room between 70
and 80 degrees Fahrenheit I do not
recommend higher than 80 I do not
recommend to lower than 70 I understand
that you're struggling to keep your room
cool a lot of new growers have issues
keeping the grow room cool 84 is the max
you ever want to hit when you hit 85
degrees in higher your plants will stop
producing they will just go into a
stagnant dead slowdown mode how
productive do you want to be when it's
110 degrees outside
you just feel like [ __ ] you don't want
to do anything you don't want to move
the plants feel the same way the plants
can't move themselves to some shade the
plants can't grab some water and take a
drink those plants are stuck there so
give them the proper environment don't
go too hot don't go too cold at this
phase of the flowering cycle I would
recommend 70 to 80 degrees Fahrenheit
during your lights on cycle now let's
talk a little bit about the humidity of
this grow room during the start of the
flowering phase I like to have about 40
to 50 percent humidity earlier I said we
don't have those big buds to worry about
so we've just got a bunch of lush happy
plants they're just in there sucking up
all that humidity and growing like crazy
so 40 to 50 percent relative humidity
and 70 to 80 degrees during your daytime
cycle if you really want to dial that in
I recommend you check out my episode
about vapor pressure deficit and that
was episode number 314 if you're
interested in learning more about the
vapor pressure deficit which I find to
be very important when it comes to
dialing in the grow room perfectly
VPD will really improve the productivity
of your plants if you understand it and
dial it in correctly so that is the
daytime condition we want 70 to 80
degrees during the day 40 to 50 percent
relative humidity let's talk about the
nighttime temperatures when we turn off
the light things are going to change in
that grow
I try to keep the humidity right around
the same levels at nighttime at this
stage of flowering I want that forty to
fifty percent humidity during the night
cycle now during the night cycle I like
it to get a little bit cooler it
naturally cools off at night so I feel
like the plants probably enjoy a little
bit cooler of a temperature at night I
try not to go any more than 10 degrees
difference on a day and night
temperature that is called your diurnal
temperature variation and you don't want
that to sway more than 10 degrees so if
during your day cycle here at 75 you do
not want your night cycle to get any
lower than 65 degrees I would generally
try to keep it about 5 degrees
difference but I understand we're
building new grow rooms we are learning
our setups we're learning to dial these
rooms in 5 to 10 degrees is acceptable
for a diurnal temperature variation but
if you go any more than 5 to 10 degrees
differential in your day and night
temperature you will cause problems
within the plants the plants will be
confused the plants will begin to grow
slowly and this is also a great way to
invite powdery mildew so try to keep
your temperature swings within 10
degrees from your day and nighttime
temperature now when you're walking
through the grow sometimes just reach
out and grab a plant and feel the
temperature of the plant as the plant
warm is the plant cold how does the
plant feel to your hands if the plants
feel really really cold they're probably
really cold and you could probably
increase the temperature of your room if
the plants feel like they're warm
they're probably warm you can probably
lower the temperature of your room in
the future I do plan to do a discussion
on leaf surface temperature versus
ambient room temperature but we are not
there yet so let's stay focused here now
one thing I may have overlooked when I
talked about equipment is a hygrometer
and a thermometer or some sort of a
monitoring device to know what is
happening in our grow room at all times
most of us growers can probably afford
the hygrometer thermometer combo that
sits in the grow room and it marks the
humidity and temperature of the room but
it will also mark the highest and lowest
points of your humidity and temperatures
so you can find your peaks and your
valleys and identify the temperature and
humidity fluctuations in your room it's
always nice to know where the peaks and
valleys are but I like to have more data
I like to have something in the room
they can tell me what's going on at all
times
for a reliable monitor that can keep you
up-to-date on what's happening in your
grow room at all times
I would suggest something like APO grow
systems minder unit or perhaps a smart B
unit you can use both of those units to
monitor your grow room at all times you
can pull up the data on your phone you
can see what's happening in the room in
real time
some of these types of units allow you
to actually plug in other devices and
trigger them from your smart phone so if
you were away you open up your
application you see that it's too warm
in that room you can say hey let's just
easily turn on the air-conditioner you
can click a button on a tab on your
phone and it will fire up the
air-conditioner in your grow room and
you can rescue your garden while you're
at lunch hanging out with your friends
and you don't even have to leave the
table so my point is have some way to
monitor the temperature and humidity in
your grow room at all times I like to
have a report of what happens when those
lights go off
you've been running that grow light for
12 hours in that room you have created a
lot of heat you have created a lot of
energy all of that heat all of that
light energy has created humidity
there's water rising up in the air now
when we kill that light everything
changes all of that humidity in the air
is no longer being heated it's got the
opportunity to start falling it becomes
kind of thick in the grow room that
short time period while the room
stabilizes itself out from that change
is quite often the cause of many of our
powdery mildew and botrytis issues and
many growers don't even know that that
is happening in the room at that time
they look at their hygrometer they look
at their thermometer they say oh it was
72 degrees in here that's acceptable oh
it was 45% humidity in here that's
acceptable
you don't realize that there was a point
where it was 78 degrees and about 82%
humidity in the room and that's because
we turned off that light all that
moisture that was in the air is now
falling now the plants don't have light
anymore so they are starting to
respirate a little bit they're letting
out a little more moisture and all of
that chaos can really cause problems for
our plants in that type of environment
so my point is try to know what's
happening environmentally in your rooms
at all times all right it feels like we
know what our environment should be like
let's talk a little bit about feeding
our transitioning cannabis plants if you
are working in a no-till bed or you're
working with super soil there's no need
to adjust anything at this time just
keep doing what you're doing you
basically need to water the plants
throughout the flowering cycle if you
plan on adding
a cover crop or a top dress or maybe
feeding some tees you will need to
adjust your tees at this time I would
take the nitrogen products out and focus
more on the phosphorus and potassium at
this time if you're running tees or top
dress or a cover crop now if you are
working with bottled nutrients you can
probably just swap out that veg bottle
and replace it with the flowering
nutrients most of the bottle nutrient
companies make it very easy to follow
their nutrient schedule so simply swap
out that veg bottle put in the bloom
bottle and everything should be good to
go
the main difference in our feeding
schedule at this time is that we are
going to reduce the amount of nitrogen
and we are going to slowly start
increasing the amount of phosphorous and
potassium
our plants take up approximately 80 to
90 percent of their nitrogen during the
veg phase once we switch them into
flower they're done sucking up nitrogen
and they want more phosphorous and
potassium
so they can build robust branches and
big fat buds so let's reduce the
nitrogen and start increasing the
phosphorus and potassium that part
should mostly be covered by your base
nutrients if you're running a one bottle
based nutrient a 2-part or a 3-part you
should be getting the proper nitrogen
phosphorus and potassium from your base
nutrients now there are a few more
things that these plants can use at this
phase I like to add silica when I am
mixing up my nutrient solution I always
put potassium silicates in the water
first
the potassium silicates go first then I
mix in my base nutrients these plants
can probably use cal-mag at this point
in time I also like to give the plants
some sort of a root inoculants in flower
don't cut back the microbes keep them
going keep those roots growing strong
keep them healthy the plants will
continue to flourish in flower I also
like some enzymes those enzymes serve
several purposes the enzymes will
basically help to keep the root zone
clean and they will also break down any
decaying root matter and turn that into
usable energy for my plants I also like
to add some carbohydrates the
carbohydrates serve a couple of purposes
those carbs will feed my microbes those
carbs will also give my plants energy
between the carbs the enzymes and the
mykos
my root zone is really healthy and
really active which will show up top at
the top of our plants so we are focusing
on knife
phosphorus and potassium at this stage
we are shifting away from the nitrogen
more toward the phosphorus and potassium
it's always good to add cal-mag a little
bit of a root inoculant I like some
enzymes always some carbs and to make
everything pop I would add a little bit
of fulvic acid now if you've chosen to
work with a specific bottled nutrient
company most of those companies have a
nutrient calculator on their website so
you can go to whatever nutrient
company.com you can find their nutrient
calculator you can type in how many
weeks are going to flower you can click
on which products of theirs you have
purchased and it will tell you week by
week how much of each product to use
most of those charts are reliable but
keep in mind they want you to continue
buying products so they may recommend
you use a little more than necessary for
an ideal crop situation I generally
reduce the recommended dosage by about
25 percent if it says to feed 100
milliliters of your base product I would
start off with 75 milliliters and see
what happens we can always feed the
plants a little more later but we can
never take out the feeding once we've
put it in so don't burn the plants wait
for them to show you that they are happy
or that they're angry and adjust from
there
most of these nutrient companies offer a
fairly balanced diet within their own
product line you shouldn't have to reach
out to another brand or another company
and fill in anything that they are
missing if you do choose to mix nutrient
lines be very careful that you don't
double up on anything when nutrient
company a made their product lines they
made five bottles and they put the base
notes in one they put the cal mag in the
other they put the humic acid in another
and a bloom booster and another they
know what is in each bottle and they can
recommend your feeding because they know
they're not going to overdose anything
with their design when you introduce a
product from another company you run the
risk of doubling up on specific
nutrients nutrient company a and
nutrient company B did not talk to each
other about their designs so you may be
running a base product from nutrient
company a then you may have a bloom
booster from nutrient company B those
companies didn't talk company a was
putting cal-mag inside their base
nutrient to help you out and save you
with the bottle company B was putting
the cal-mag inside the bloom booster to
help you out save a bottle and you
didn't know that
so now you just spent two doses of Cal
mag because you combined nutrient
companies and didn't read the bottles so
if you choose to use products from two
different companies be sure not to
overlap with any nutrients if you know
what's in each product and you
understand how the plants use each of
those products and you're not going to
cause any problems there is nothing
wrong with combining nutrient companies
if you feel like the brand you were
using is lacking something
feel free to purchase another product
from another company and add that into
your mix as long as you don't double up
any specific elements a good example of
what I'm talking about is in a
commercial environment I like to run veg
bloom powder nutrients in my opinion veg
bloom could use a little bit of fulvic
acid added to the mix in my opinion veg
bloom can use a little bit of
carbohydrates added to the mix later in
flower so I am comfortable adding those
products and I've done my research I
know how much carbs I know how much
fulvic acid is in my starting product so
I know that I'm not going to overdose my
plants
alright I'm confident that we understand
the environment I'm confident that we
understand what to feed the plants let's
talk about some more techniques to do at
the very start of flower if you are
using sprayed pesticide applications now
is a great time to apply a pesticide
application we are running out of time
for sprays we were going to start
developing bud sites very soon so we
need to treat these plants today let's
apply a preventive product to our plants
to ensure we do not get any pests in our
veg cycle if you are not going to use
spray pesticide applications now is a
good time to release your beneficial
insects we want to get them colonized
and built up in the grow before other
insects have an opportunity to take hold
in our flowering garden once the plants
are flowering we don't have a lot of
options for pest control so let's do
everything we can now to prevent a pest
infestation while we have big chunky
buds so I would treat for pests at this
time spray pesticides if that is your
approach another thing I like to do on
day one a flower is trellis my plants in
a commercial environment I am NOT able
to move my veg plants into a room and
trellis them I have a veg room and I
have flowering rooms the flowering rooms
are constantly flowering so I can't veg
in that room so I moved the plants into
the flowering area and I put the trellis
up on
day one and I bend and pop and work
those plants into the net on day one
this gives them plenty of time to
recover from the stress of getting beat
up while they transition to the
flowering phase we've got about 7 to 10
days where they're just transitioning
there won't be anybody won't be any
major activity so if we beat them up on
day one we've got plenty of time to
recover so I like to get in there and
get them under the trellis I also do
popping and twisting which is also known
as super cropping I've talked about this
in depth in other episodes but I'll give
you a quick rundown I start at the very
bottom stalk of the plant where it comes
out of the dirt
I grab the base of the stalk with my
left hand I put my right hand above that
and I grab the stock and I twist my
right hand counterclockwise you'll hear
a pop sounds kind of like a knuckle
popping I pop my knuckle into the
microphone I don't know if it picked up
you'll hear a little pop sound that is
the sound you're looking for you just
want to break the cellulose structure of
that plant so I'll break it once then
I'll move my left hand from the bottom
right up above my right hand and I'll
give it another break then I'll move up
and give it another break I work my way
up the main stem all the way until it
gets real thin and I feel like I could
cause problems by snapping it up there
once I've done the main stalk I go back
down to the bottom of the plant and I
find the lowest branch and I work that
branch all the way up then I work every
single branch on every single plant this
takes hours in a commercial environment
your hands will be sore but the plants
will thank you for it in the future
right now they look like they got
twisted they got a little bit beat up
but in a few days all of those twists
will create what looks like a knuckle it
will make the plant more robust it will
make it stronger it will give it more
strength I feel like those thicker
stalks can move more nutrients which
makes a more productive plant I feel
like a bigger stock can hold up a bigger
bud so we are working those plants to be
more robust by cracking them they heal
themselves and they become stronger so I
like to do popping and twisting at this
time I also like to do a nice
defoliation on day one of flower take
out all that excess leaf we don't need
it while I'm there I like to clean up
the bottoms quite a bit take off some of
the crappy bottom branches take off some
of those sucker branches take off all
the bottom leaves we don't need a lot of
that crap on the bottom of our plan
it's some people like to wait a little
bit later closer to week 2 to do the
bottoming and the wall-e popping I like
to do it early in a commercial
environment
things will get ahead of you so if you
don't start it right away it gets really
easy to fall behind very quickly and in
a commercial environment that only
compounds so on day 1 I move the plants
into the flower room I set up the
trellis I give the plants a nice pop and
twist and work them into the trellis
I'll do some defoliating I like to do a
bunch of bottoming and lolli popping and
then right before we leave for the night
we give the plants a nice pesticide
spray another important thing to think
about at this transitional time is bulbs
what kind of bulbs are you going to use
for flowering I usually recommend a
metal halide for vegging and a
high-pressure sodium for flowering
lighting technology has advanced so far
in recent years that you may be using
LEDs you may be using ceramic metal
halides there are tons of options but
consider changing your spectrum early in
the flowering phase one useful trick I
have learned to help reduce the early
flower stretch is to leave the metal
halide bulbs in for the first two weeks
of flowering a lot of people will swap
out the metal halides for the high
pressure sodium Zonday one of flowering
I have learned that if you leave those
howards in there for two weeks your
plants will not stretch as ridiculously
when you initiate flower that is natural
for plants to stretch they just want to
take off but cracking them popping them
twisting them and keeping in that metal
halide will drastically slow down that
stretch all right podcast rolled I feel
like we have a good solid foundation on
transitioning our plants from veg to
flower at this point if you are growing
from seeds you will need to keep a close
eye on the plants and look out for males
you will need to look out for
hermaphrodites and you will need to pay
attention for mutants if you've got a
plant in there doing some weird [ __ ] you
need to decide if you want to keep it or
let it finish sometimes those mutant
plants put off amazing products they are
also a pain in the ass to grow and they
are problematic so sometimes it's not
even worth it so if you've got a mutant
it is up to you to decide what to do
another thing we need to stay on top of
is scouting for insects yes we did just
apply some pesticides we may have
released some predator bugs but that
does not mean that we are bulletproof
always be scouting for pass
every day as you walk through the grow
just to go from one end to the other to
go get the scissors you forgot down
there or to go find the broom just
glance at the plants as you walk by that
is when I make the most random
discoveries I'm not even looking for
something I was just walking by and I
said what the hell is that out of the
corner of my eye now I know there's a
problem now we can solve it always be
paying attention always be scouting for
bugs and problems in the grow keep your
eyes open
we need to look for hermaphrodites we
need to look for males we need to look
for mutants and we need to pay close
attention for signs of pests all right
podcast world I can feel the cold
medicine that I took starting to kick in
my face is going numb my nose is
starting to run kind of weird I need to
wrap up this podcast before I get too
lit to be on a microphone I want to
thank everybody for listening to the
grow lessons if you feel like this show
is educational informative or
entertaining and you would like to make
a financial contribution to the show you
can do so by going to patreon.com slash
grow from your heart all the information
you need to become a patron will be
right there on the screen and I would
appreciate your support I would also
appreciate it if you follow me on all of
the social media you can find me on
Facebook simply search for the girl from
your heart podcast you can follow the
show on Twitter it's at G fyh podcast
and if you want to follow my personal
Twitter account it's at Rasta Jeff 420
if you've got something you'd like to
say and you're not into all the social
media you can reach me through email my
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I would love to hear from
you if you'd like to advertise on the
show or if you've got a product you'd
like me to review simply reach out I
would love to connect with you and get
your product on the show don't forget
the shows available on iTunes stitcher
Google Play and on YouTube I would
appreciate it if you subscribe to the
show on YouTube and leave some comments
on the videos I'll be back Thursday with
a fresh new episode I want to give you a
huge shout out to my friend hash masta
and until next time take a phat dab and
give your mom a hug for me