welcome to the show podcast world it's
time for episode 379 of the girl from
the heart podcast white Mike is here
thanks for joining me bro what's up man
thanks for uh making this time out of
the day from the little ones and making
it on the podcast yeah thanks for having
me
sounds like one guy hates you but a lot
of people requested you back so thanks
for coming I've got way more than just
one finally expressed it out loud as
always this episode is brought to you by
our friends at the Hell a dank seed
company if you need new genetics in your
garden make sure you check out the hella
dank seed company at www.sedar.com
tradition that we start the podcast off
by letting our friends know what we are
dabbing on let's tell them what we just
took dabs of I think we just hit the
stars on Fambrough jaw one of my
favorites what do you think it was
fantastic delicious right very and it
it's got a good chatty energy which
that's what we need for the show I've
learned lately that almost all of the
dads give me chatty energy I've been
playing with some stuff lately that is
just like an off switch for people at
least for people like me
I watched dab and Granny hit some nine
pound hammer today she was giddy she was
chatty she's talking about all the [ __ ]
she's got to do and she's like let's
take a dab Jeff and she hits the 9 pound
hammer and it was like somebody [ __ ]
hit the slow-motion button for about 30
seconds she was like bradbury bad boy I
was like damn I just watched you that
she said you never see granny sit back
in the chair and she just like sat back
in the chair and took a moment she goes
you know I got really high shaded like
really check herself readjust it happens
so she had to recalibrate so you guys we
are hitting the star dog fan bro show
from our friends at apothecary farms
dude how excited are you that apothecary
is 4.5 miles from my house probably a
similar distance from your place love it
it's uh it's wonderful it saves me so
much time the damn car one of my
favorite things just random [ __ ] that
happened is I walked out of apothecary a
few days ago and Mike was walking in as
I came around the claros I think that's
Jeff's car and before I had time to
really think about that thought anymore
he came walking out the door with this
purchase as I was going in to make my
ego smile on my face made a
recommendation as a hey bro make sure
you getting this
yeah so Charlotte or friends at
apothecary they honestly nobody pays me
to talk about the concentrates I smoke
nobody gives me concentrates or helps me
out like that I just talk about what I
enjoy and today we are enjoying the star
dog Fambrough Jie from apothecary great
spot over there
I'm so glad they're here in Pueblo my
wallet on the other hand may not be as
excited yeah that 35 40 minute drive was
a nice deterrent yes is I don't want to
go do that I don't feel like driving up
and back now that it's just across town
I love it 4.5 miles away now everybody
knows where I live they're drawn he's
here he's in this goddamn circle let's
find him now my precious alright guys
we're gonna get real this is going to be
a fun podcast Mike is here if you're a
regular listener in a previous episode I
think it was 2 episodes back I read some
iTunes customer reviews within those
reviews somebody stated that they did
not enjoy Mike's presence on the podcast
I politely told them how good of a
friend Mike is and how important I feel
Mike is to the cannabis community not
only to the show but to the entire
community
he's well-spoken he's an intelligent
dude I'm not just kissing his ass
because he's here but I wanted to say I
said it on a show I wanted to say it to
his face Mike I appreciate you on the
show if somebody doesn't like you bro
skip the [ __ ] episode cuz Mikey's
gonna be here
Mike's my bro Mike has been around
medical K he's not as outspoken as I am
in the same way but he has been an
activist and advocate a spokesperson a
role model since I've known him which
was around 2007 or 2008 he was doing it
before that I helped someone sign up for
the first time on the medical marijuana
registry back in 2006
there we go it's we spent like eight
months working to get a friend of mine
on the registry and we finally succeeded
you know six so I mean I've been doing
this a long time in my opinion Mike has
earned his spot not only on the show but
in the community and he should be
accepted and involved in this as much as
myself so I really appreciate that man
yeah yeah it's not just growers it's not
just breeders it's not just people with
a big mouth like me you make this [ __ ]
possible I don't go to the City Council
meetings as much as I should because I'm
pre judged by my appearance and it's a
big reason why more
one of the community is involved and
you're there you're speaking on behalf
of us and you come check with me you're
like hey they're gonna make new rules
what should we kind of work for and you
kind of get my opinion as a grower as a
heavy consumer where we're both heavy
consumers I'm gonna call you heavy
consumer
compared to most people but in our
circle you're one of the lighter
consumers but on a different way you're
much more involved in the medical
consumption side I'm more on the I don't
even the the hip trendy [ __ ] side of
cannabis I guess one of the things that
I mean cuz this is this is a free-form
show if y'all haven't picked up on that
yet if you were looking for the second
part of our the flowering series Jeff is
doing this is not gonna be that episode
that'll be Monday you guys stick in
months dice it stick in stick around
into him that's the same thing it sounds
gross when you say stick in I've
actually sent Sanjay Gupta a couple of
like really impassioned emails and
social media messages about this we need
a weed for focused on THC side of the
story somewhere over the last five six
years seven years we stopped thinking of
THC is highly medically active and
started thinking of it more as the fun
side while CBDs the medical side and
that's not at all true you use THC for a
number of medical components and now I
consider you both a medical and erech
user absolutely but yeah we THC has
medical applications millions and
millions of Americans and even more tens
of millions of people around the globe
use THC medically you're definitely one
of those people bro I don't take and
you're also a [ __ ] stoner like don't
let me take that away from you
guaranteed I say that my first two dads
those are medicinal that third and
fourth one those are purely recreational
dabs that that fifth and sixth one that
is just party time I know that there is
a limit
I do have I've got a traumatic brain
injury I've also got some other medical
things I don't even talk about because
honestly I don't think anybody cares
it's not what I'm here for
we got a stomach condition that really
[ __ ] me up sometimes it'll talk about
it but high limonene and high THC
strains work very well for my brain
injury sometimes it just feels like my
skips a little bit like my CD like
remember only had CDs that's a [ __ ]
old I am when your CDs get like just
every once in a while you just you just
know that on that one song that on come
as you are by Nirvana you're doing that
one course no I don't have a gun just
that one time there's jump my brain will
do that occasional I can't predict when
and where did I get those if I keep
enough limonene and THC in my brain it
doesn't do that it stops it and it
sounds crazy because you're like you're
putting THC in your brain to fix a skip
no it really puts the puzzle pieces back
together it lubricates my record player
I don't know how to describe it but that
makes the well what we've learned about
the endocannabinoids system over the
last several years is that it maintains
homeostasis in your body that's what
that particular system does like your
skeletal system makes it so you're not a
[ __ ] blob of flesh on the floor your
vascular system moves blood around your
endocannabinoid system make sure that
all the other body systems are working
the way they're supposed to kind of
balance themselves out and that's why
cannabis has so many different medical
applications it's because it's it's not
affecting one one system or one part of
your body it's affecting the system that
governs everything except breathing in
our rate for the first time I wish this
shows a video show because when Mike
said skeletal system I started doing the
robot
yep I'm not sure why I can't help it
folks I talk with my hands and so I'll
start making shapes and [ __ ] to
elaborate my points and Jeff just looks
at me like dude no camera you can keep
going it'll come out though your mouth
will we'll make those shapes happen if
you keep doing it with your hands I get
it but yes the endocannabinoids system
is some I really think it does balance
things out it can I don't want to sound
like I know what I'm talking about
medically but I know it messes with
blood sugar it messes with hormones it
can balance and throw things out of
whack if things are already a little out
of whack it can make it worse it can
also dial things in it can exacerbate
and fix a lot of things but I'm sure
that it's like a little like a little
bondo for my dent bro
it just little divot in my brain and I
think that limonene and the THC just
smooths it over it just makes it not
skip so that my thoughts can complete
and you can you can see sometimes like
I'll be like [ __ ] water what are the
three words that are blank in my brain
let's let's take a couple dabs and
- dabs later just smooth as can be I can
do a little podcast and what cucumber
boat wire could do is it boat or bird
boat but you convert the wire points
away from my score if you guys know what
we're talking about you are a champ big
shot it's my buddy DB because I am DB
[Music]
[ __ ] us all spoiled yes I keep looking
down at the table and smiling big
because there's enough hash on this
table to keep us just roasted for like
most 12 hours I've been doing some
things in New Mexico business and
pleasure and when I'm down there I get
to go hang out at my friend's house I've
got friends in New Mexico right and I
get to see the New Mexico available
product and I'm not trying to mash
they're not I was gonna politely say I'm
not gonna bash New Mexico but they're
behind they're not quite up to us not
quite caught up to us on concentrate
tech so when I'm in New Mexico I've got
a I don't think I'm allowed to consume
in New Mexico because I'm not a patient
if I were to consume in New Mexico it
probably I wouldn't be a spoiled as I am
here so when I get back I look at the
table and I'm like oh I'm so spoiled
when I'm here dude and a couple of very
real ways we've been living in the
future for a while now that's the truth
when it comes to cannabis products that
are available the quality of those
products the glass that's available I'm
going to shout out Albuquerque and stand
up for Albuquerque when you say I'm not
you didn't bash them when you say the
glass that is available dude Albuquerque
is keeping up on the glass scene are a
couple of artists down there that have
hot glass and I saw some good work in
Albuquerque shout out to those folks
unfortunately I didn't write down any
names they knew who they are there are a
couple of folks that I saw their work
they do a really good job nice yeah they
know who they is if you're an
Albuquerque glass blower and you're
doing it you know who you are I get I
get stuff on social media I'll post
something or I'll share something then I
always get a message from somebody
that's removed from legalization what
the [ __ ] yeah what are you doing yeah
what are you smoking dude I had a it's
an aunt of mine actually sent me a
message a little while ago and someone
she knows ended up in an anti pot
conference and then she was giving
literature
she sent me messages trying to convey
fact check it and I was laughing really
hard she was laughing hard right
I'm afraid to get pulled over with my
diamonds I'm not in a diamond container
of course this says internally flawless
series apothecary extracts it's got the
place on it and then when I bought this
it comes with a receipt they've thrown
receipt there's a video on YouTube you
can pull up where they throw some dude
in jail over a crispy cream frosting
flake like donut glaze it looks like
some liver and that's not like a
euphemism for a drug I'm talking about
the donut sugar frosting he had a couple
of flakes on his his format and they
racked him for crystal meth and he was
in jail for like four days yeah the
tests came the preliminaries came back
from the lab that was like no [ __ ]
that's frosting Wow yes so diamonds and
hashes [ __ ] I've been worried about that
since the beginning yeah how do I
explain to a cop but this is a refill
syringe for my vaporizer exactly well we
weren't at least a shatter we know a guy
who has a YouTube channel he goes by the
name I don't know if it's red banner or
red been because there's Brian Redman
who is a producer and a comedian who
used to work with Joe Rogan and then
there's Dan red ban is who I'm talking
about
he's a cannabis activist he had a
YouTube channel that was shut down I
don't know if it's back I fear of Dan
red band supporter big shout out to Dan
and red Ben but he was taken to jail
because he had a CBD syringe in his
vehicle and they thought it was heroin
and the amount of CBD that was in that
syringe looked like a [ __ ] lot of
heroin I guess I don't know how much
heroin is a serving I'm kind of glad I
don't know that I know about a lot of
things I'm right 99% ignorant to heroin
other than that's like illegal and bad
and you shoot it up I don't really know
a lot comes out of that good job yeah
that's a good thing that's a know all
the [ __ ] I learned on the street I don't
know much about a heroin which is kind
of cool with me but they took him to
jail thinking that that was heroin and
they went and test it and finally they
came back and they're like dude you
can't even have the remaining part that
we didn't test back they gave him back
his scent of his syringe and [ __ ] but
dude I love you Dan he's a [ __ ]
scrawny little white boy he has no
business in a jail you know what I mean
he's not a criminal he didn't he
wouldn't and doesn't do anything to go
to jail he moved here from another state
to avoid going to jail he wanted to
follow the rules I bet he was scared
[ __ ] [ __ ] lesbian in jail that's not
his environment
you're a criminal and you're breaking
the rules and you're a thug you expect
maybe I'll go to jail but Dan is not a
great he's not equipped for that you
didn't see that in life bro so yeah it
got him I've had that little more than
once that like when I come over here I
bring some hash and there's that drive
where I'm like yeah this might be
slightly difficult to explain it I'm
glad I still have it in the original
packaging with labels yeah yeah this
this diamond actually says diamonds and
it says the carat weight of the diamond
10 carat internally flawless diamond and
it's got the cannabinoid and stuff
written on it and it had a sticker that
had all the stuff right here but I took
that off cuz you can't open the damn jar
without it but and I had the original
packaging but yeah I don't want to go
any Bart this Giants looks like a big
old [ __ ] crack rock dude it seriously
does look at this thing like it's the
that's the one thing the anti-pop folks
have been harping on that I actually
kind of agree with is yeah some of the
new hash looks a little cracky it told
this is this freebase massive that's a
tube it looks like a diamond it's the
size you your top thumb joint and it
looks like a quartz crystal in a hippie
shop
it's bigger than it's almost the size of
a junior mint I would say it's it's a
little bigger than it's almost - Junior
Mints crushed together the two that got
squished together yeah yeah the two -
Seth gummy bear it's a full gummy bear I
mean that's that's a hell of a rock and
you're gonna be sitting in jail for a
few a few days while the cops test that
and confirm that it's THC and they're
gonna steal my badass crystal while
they're at it I want to have a rock
anymore
not all at once trust me but that's
that's several several bunch is a good
dad you know but yeah that if I got dude
yeah I'm just so afraid I Drive to New
Mexico every few days now I gotta go
down there and do some work and do some
pleasure and I refuse to take anything
with me I won't even drive down there
with anything it's so I don't see any
police down there in New Mexico
apparently doesn't have a speed limit
from what I've learned but I still I
know as soon as I put something in the
car they have a speed limit but dude I'm
not gonna talk about how fast I was
going when I passed three state troopers
and they didn't budge they
laughed at me they didn't give up well
I'll get how fast I was going but I know
the minute that they were cornhole in a
drum the white guy with dreadlocks and
Colorado plates going the speed I go as
soon as I put one [ __ ] flake of
concentrating the car they're gonna pull
me over I know it and it is not worth
then then I can't work in the Colorado
marijuana Enforcement Division regulated
industry at all nope so that is not
worth it I'm just writing down a note
because I have a question for ya I've
got a an out of country trip planned for
around my birthday next year and one of
my family members was like I can take
your wheat don't like I'm not [ __ ]
not in there like what what do you mean
and I'm like well I'm just not gonna
take anything yeah and they're like you
rich you're really not going to take
anything and it's like no like I don't
it's a it's not that long a trip be it's
not nearly that important to me and see
it's not an addiction right a pleasure
at a medicine and on top of that there's
a magic that happens with pot heads you
look like me I've mentioned earlier I'm
65 I got dreadlocks down to my [ __ ]
knees I'm wearing a grass roots hat
backwards and crooked
I got a Apothecary Farms t-shirt on my
pants are a little baggy I'm more in
Merrell running like mountain running
shoes I look like I smoked a pound of
[ __ ] weed everyday like it's obvious
when I and you can you can tell when you
talked to me that I'm definitely a
cannabis consumer Mike doesn't look like
that as much you've got a couple hints
you got the earrings that may give you a
hint that this guy may break some rules
when I'm on vacation depending on the
country like when I'm in Mexico vender
shouted me like yo come here do you want
some factly exactly where I'm headed
with this cannabis consumers find each
other and cannabis sellers can find in
Kansas buyers it like a [ __ ]
we know I used to be one we have spot
you out of the crowd it doesn't matter
what country you're in
there's someone whose job it is to sell
one gram in three and a half gram bags
over that person is trained to spot all
of the tell-tale signs for cannabis
consumers from all the different little
varieties that pass through their area
yeah I've never been somewhere or it was
hard for me to get hurt and this is
going back to like 98 you can remember
going to New York one time to visit
family and thinking like I mean is we're
going for graduations I'm
there'll be a bunch of beer but yeah I'm
gonna miss my weed a little and I shut
up and two cousins were like so beer we
see yes I've literally never landed a
place matter yeah yeah and you don't
even have to be the white guy with
dreadlocks and it's just it's
serendipitous herb knows that you're
there herb is supposed to be found
herb is supposed to be smoked yep yeah
it's it's there and people live if it's
meant to be and if you don't find it
that's cool something else is gonna be
going on that night I could be turned
down maybe 30 different sale offers in
New Orleans in the ten days I was there
just let me know I was the same [ __ ] you
guys were smoking a minute ago down that
alley no not interested bro thanks
though I don't know how much plastic was
in it with a smell like a tire fire oh
man no oh man no I'm not worried about
it at all and it's like if you're a
longtime listener the show you know I'm
a tobacco consumer and caffeine consumer
and I'm heavily addicted to those two
things if I was facing a prospect of a
trip for 10 or 15 days where I couldn't
consume caffeine or I couldn't consume
nicotine I wouldn't be considering
taking that trip now I'm a hundred
percent comfortable with a 10 or 15 day
trip where there's just like there's
probably not gonna be any lead it's fine
it's a very different thing I'm worried
about my body pain that I'm treating
with THC and CBD not my head or being
able to sleep right there aren't
withdrawal symptoms when you don't have
now you might not be able to sleep I
find myself with extra energy because
cannabis obviously when you consume like
I do it's gonna wear you out a little
bit you're gonna be a little tired from
it by the end of the day so I don't
sleep as well if I don't consume as much
but I'm sure after 3 or 4 days that
would just wear right off but my palm
sweat like I have I have sticky palms
for like three days and it's just gone
it's like I'm nervous for three days
yeah just my palms though I just feel
nervous Alex just that balance is out of
balance and you're missing one of the
ingredients so if we were gonna take you
on a trip and I told you that you had to
go 14 day and 14 days you were gonna be
gone for 14 days you got two weeks to
prepare then you're gonna be gone for
two more weeks how many days before we
left on that trip would you need to
taper you can't smoke cigarettes
you can't consume cannabis and you
cannot drink
caffeine on this trip how many days
before we leave do you need to start
tapering off your use of those three
substances alright so just it's a it's
mandatory this is definitely happening
oh yeah and I'm gonna be gone for 14
days without you you've got to come on
this trip like your life is on the line
yeah head to the kids in the mix to
notice and both so there's like
nicotine's a hell of a drug like I can
quit caffeine in a couple of days and
I'm just a prick for like I'm
short-tempered and my I've got a
headache
I was gonna ask if you get the cafe
anything bad about 36 hours into a
caffeine purge what's the word I fast I
tried sometimes I'll just try to make it
a point about 36 hours and I'll feel it
I'd like oh there it is right behind the
eyes five hours after I'm awake oh well
I haven't consumed at least one
caffeinated beverage iced are you okay
when I was in Mexico the last time I was
just drinking the local coffee and it
wasn't keeping up with what I do with
Mountain Dew most days and there's not
all the other ingredients of Mountain
Dew in that coffee the us the caffeine
and there's not even as much caffeine so
I was having to pound the coffee but I
was able to stay ahead of it alright but
if we're talking about a trip where
there's none of that like either I'm
gonna kill everyone else on the trip on
day two or this is gonna take like major
like work prep support yeah chemicals
think about how many cigarettes you
smoke in a day and then that often I
can't taper if I'm smoking I smoke like
I smoked okay so we just gotta take your
cigarettes away yep so we got to do that
about five days before so you can get
over the [ __ ] phase you get about 14
hours before I break and that's a little
longer if like I smoke normally for the
day and then I go to bed and then sleep
for like a really long time like maybe
stay to bed for 10 hours I could
probably get up and go four or five
hours alright so you're getting to 15 16
hours tops before I'm like in a
homicidal I will [ __ ] kill you or you
get to nicotine rage I feel like we just
brought chad shank on the show and if
you know who chad shank is you're a cool
[ __ ] i don't know if you even
know whose but you just morphed into
chad shank and that's really it's it's a
real addiction like I remember being
much much younger a teenager and when I
just started smoking and I wasn't
addicted I remember that you you can
it's like consuming anything now like
everybody loves tacos
if you're forced to go two weeks without
tacos it's like not even something you
remember a month later you don't
remember that happening yeah that's is
so much different with nicotine dude
it's not even [ __ ] funny I've been in
three car accidents in my life two of
them are directly related to on the way
to acquire nicotine that I didn't have
like my focus was all about that next
dose of nicotine not on the car driving
behind me god damn it Mike so as your
friend you know that those are two
problems right you know that that's not
like no this is what's gonna kill me if
I'm the [ __ ] stop okay as long as
you're we're getting old and I'm
continuing I consume like how the [ __ ]
do you stop kidneys yeah I agree
quite often guys I said bottle bottle
bottles of water that's the hardest word
for my brain bottles of water on the
table and I offer them to Mike and
honestly he brawls his eyes I feel like
I'm [ __ ] [ __ ] for that plenty of
water is just it's I'm over here talking
to on the show I need something yeah
dude we saw Jay and Silent Bob do their
podcast and Jason used to blend like
[ __ ] for Red Bulls in 45 minutes yep
guy I don't know how you even this dude
that guy's brain is so primed for it it
needs constant feedback
he's just destroyed his dopamine loop oh
yes I've met more than one addict that's
like that that when they're they're out
in the world talking in chat and it's
they pound Red Bull like its water and
they chain smoke yeah and he couldn't
smoke in there so he just pound that and
you guys we're not spilling any beans
that Jason Mewes was a heroin addict
he's recovering addict that's part of
why he was very open about it so we're
not spilling anybody's beans that he's a
week in recovery still but the man just
pounds [ __ ] Red Bulls when he's
talking if you go see Jason Mewes and
Jay [ __ ] Duke
what's his real name Kevin Smith Smith
I'm gonna call him Bob I couldn't
[ __ ] Kevin Smith suddenly but if you
go see them pay attention to how many
[ __ ] Red Bulls Jason Mewes pounds so
we have set a good precedent we
understand how the caffeine and the
nicotine are a staple if we take those
away from you you said homicidal you're
gonna turn into Chad shank which is
really funny if you understand that now
let's shift our focus we have removed
your caffeine from you we have removed
the nicotine from you you're a raging
[ __ ] we know that you've got to get
on this flight now how far ahead of that
trip time do we have to start
eliminating cannabis from your diet so
to speak for it not to totally throw
your body into shock if we cut it off no
no time no time so hypothetically if you
weren't white Mike and you were down to
break some [ __ ] rules you could take
some dabs with me in the car as I drop
you off at the hypothetical trip that
I'm sending you on and it wouldn't
affect you move your body wouldn't start
having withdrawal symptoms or [ __ ] like
that all right so I think I mean that I
took the really long especially on this
trip that we're planning because we're
traveling to Europe so but the flights
[ __ ] up my sleep patterns as they're
substantially more than the lack of
cannabis oh yeah so I'm not even gonna
notice one of the only two symptoms I
feel at all because I'm gonna wood
tribute most of that symptom to the
jetlag all right and like it's gonna be
the end of March early April in Paris
like having sweaty palms ain't gonna be
a problem I'm wearing a hoodie anyway
how long of a flight is that dude it's
like 10 or 12 14 hours damn think when I
went in mm it was like four or five
hours to DC and then 10 or 12 to Paris
in that last that second flight you
[ __ ] brutal yeah just brutal you just
fine that long yeah I got lucky I was in
the bulkhead so you get a little bit
extra you're the first row of seats
behind first-class okay like an extra
four inches of legroom
hell yeah hi dude every [ __ ] yatch
matters I'm six five and Mike's what 6-3
6-4
yep yeah and Mike's probably got a good
40 or 50 pounds on me
it hurts he says it's a seriously from
the my back hip bone like at the top of
my ass to my kneecap is exactly the same
length from the back of my seat that I'm
sitting in the airplane to the back of
the [ __ ] in front of my niece it's
flush against your armrest and my leg is
locked in their heart I was trying to
get on a ride at Six Flags and the girl
said put your legs down and I was like
[ __ ] what we're like what do you want
me to do with them at more than once
I've I've gone to to ride an amusement
ride like a roller coaster or some and
the carnies just like yeah you don't
you're too big like yep like I get this
you're only 17 but you don't fit too
tall the cage doesn't come down over
your shoulders anymore
uh-huh in its like weight you can build
it for 450 500 pound people but you
can't build it for people who are taller
than 6 foot what the [ __ ] alright so I
think I made my point if mike has to
eliminate the caffeine and the nicotine
from his diet he will become a homicidal
maniac which I think were his own words
so caffeine's not so bad but nicotine's
a different class of drug but if we took
away your cannabis you'd be just fine
just fine no withdrawals no craziness
just fine just fine me too
me too I wouldn't sleep for a day or two
I bet you just because I give a lot of
my energy to the end of the day energy
it calms me down that's how I just
mellow myself out but after a couple
days it's partly the ritual is what I
would miss the most just hanging out
with you you want to take a couple dabs
bro let's try this Clementine let's try
this whatever we got this Citroen Delic
sunset just try them all and sue a guy
you know it's just part of the fun but
think after a few days I'd be completely
okay with it alright now we'll be okay
and then if I'm on vacation
like you said you're going to Europe if
I was on vacation or something it
wouldn't give a [ __ ] I can look at all
the vacation I've got to see you don't
even need to be stoned for this you
could enjoy that when when I was in New
Orleans I didn't miss cannabis at all
and I kept running into it when I was in
Mexico I ran in a bad weed right away
and it wasn't worth trying to look to
find more but it was a kind of a
stressful trip and it was nice to be
able to go step away from everything for
15 minutes and just break up a little
[ __ ] piece of brick we'd empty out a
cigarette [ __ ] repackage couldn't
even get rolling paper stuff oh man
it was weird everywhere I'd go and try
to get papers they looked at me funny to
try to sell me switchers and I was like
no I don't want I want to I want to play
yeah but you said break up some brick
weed makes you humble right takes you
back to those days the people that gave
it to me were so like they were so
excited they knew I was coming in and in
the next day they wanted to have some
weed ready for me they found some dude
that was gonna sell them weed they sold
them but way more weed than they were
expecting like they gave them enough
money for a decent amount of like
regular American but oh yeah and they
got its equivalent in maxi break yeah
know what to do with this take an ounce
and a half and I'm like days but
whatever yeah and it was nice to be able
to step away and just have that rich
will break it up clean it up roll it up
but it was more get away from everybody
and just let my own thoughts simmer for
15 minutes rather than consuming THC an
actual vacation all right Mike I feel
like we've been rambling for quite a
while you want to start wrapping up this
podcast yeah I get myself in any more
trouble yeah let's see what else you can
say into a microphone hey we should tell
everybody how they can find you on the
social media you can find me at Pueblo
for sensible cannabis laws on Facebook
or at Nemo Punk 15 on Twitter give the
kid a follow also you can follow me know
follow the show on Twitter don't follow
me follow the show it's at G fyh podcast
on Twitter if you'd like to follow me
you for sure can it's a trois to Jeff
420 on Facebook simply search for the
girl from your art podcast you guys i
really suggest you follow my instagram i
use the other company as ireon Durst or
genetics on instagram give us a follow
we're just about at 20,000 Instagram
followers I do a lot of Instagram live
videos I hang out I take dads I talk
with my friends if you ask a grown in
the live feed I try to answer it right
there on the spot so jump in hang out
have a good time with mother always a
good time it's such a good time a bunch
of my friends come ask questions we get
really chatty we have a good time
sometimes I bring other people in the
live feed and we talk and hang out
sometimes Mike is there typing in
comments and questions it's it's a whole
lot of fun we have a bunch of good
friends there a nice loyal following
being shout out to the whole Irie army
over the scalp a lot of fun and kind of
tighten it I like it yes yes they don't
allow if somebody comes in and tries to
troll people the army just get something
like nah bro you can't be here and they
just run them off I don't have to block
people the Irie army will get you it's a
lot of fun um if you'd like to reach out
to the podcast and you're not into all
the social media stuff you can always
send me an email my email address is
grow from your heart at hotmail.com I
would love to hear from you maybe I can
answer your questions that way or maybe
you'd like to sponsor the show or
perhaps you've got a product you would
like Mike and I to review send me an
email
I'd love to hear what's on your mind
also don't forget the show is available
on iTunes stitcher Google Play and every
episode is available on YouTube all
right Michael R at the end of the show
you got anything to say well you got a
bunch of people listening keep leaving
comments on iTunes and YouTube and hit
me up on social media every time I'm on
the podcast I get four or five new
Instagram followers I almost never post
an Instagram but you can follow me there
too there you go
follow Mike you get he'll get four or
five more followers it's funny I was on
dab in granny's live feed this afternoon
and I must have gotten 50 new followers
just from hanging out with granny for
about 15 minutes so funny I was in her
live feed one day and I commented she
saw my comment and shattered me out and
my Instagram just [ __ ] got lit yep
feels like a stop sign in the forest
it's all it takes it's all it takes is
for having granny to say hello and your
social media will go crazy big shadows
my friend Devin granny I love you every
day Gale I hope you're listening to this
I hope you and Kevin are having a
wonderful day
hope everything is going your way I love
you every single [ __ ] Bay alright
Mike I think that was your chance to say
what you had to say hug a hater [ __ ]
control that should have been driven all
you said this whole podcast dude that's
that covered all of your plans happen
[ __ ] it just like I'll go smoke another
cigarette we'll just start this fresh
we'll record a whole different episode
here in 10 minutes I don't know if this
was this place a lot of place we're in a
lot of places there's gonna be some
editing in this show there will be some
editing there are some stuff there's
just folks not usual anyway thanks for
hanging out you guys we're gonna wrap
this up before Mike and criminate
himself any further he's in a mood
tonight
he needs a cigarette he's already got
his [ __ ] headphones off you guys you
should see this kid I'm just gonna turn
off his mic so we can dip and go smoke
Mike thanks for hanging out on the
podcast everybody thanks for being here
I had a great time with you Mike had a
good time with you he's given you a
sergeant salute and a big wave as he
runs out the door the door to go get
that cancer stick into his lungs it's
cold out there he's still gonna go smoke
[ __ ] Savage
all right podcaster old I'll be back
Monday with a fresh new episode we will
continue to grow lessons I'm gonna give
you a huge shout out to my buddy reefer
madness and until next time take a phat
dab and give your mom a hug for me