hey everybody its Rasta Jeff and it's
time for the new year's episode of the
girl from your heart podcast welcome to
episode number 381 thank you for joining
me as always this episode is brought to
you by the hella DANC seed company
that's right if you need new seeds you
get them from the hell a dank seed
company and you can find them at
www.cdxzipstream.com from Green Dot labs
a beautiful combination both of them
have that gassy fuel e tastes that I
love been spoiling myself for the
holidays I hope you're smoking on
something delicious also I hope you've
been spending time with great friends
and good family and I also hope you got
to smoke with somebody new this holiday
season maybe you got to sneak off with
that cool cousin maybe you finally got
one of your brothers or sisters who's
always been uptight to finally burn one
with you maybe just maybe you even got
grandma to hit the vape pen you never
know I hope you got to do something cool
with your family over this holiday
season I hope you have or had a great
safe new year whenever you listen to
this I hope everything went well for you
I hope you had a great evening I hope
you got a great New Year's kiss or took
a fat New Year's dabbe and I hope you
made it home safely in one piece
obviously this is the Happy New Year
show I hope everybody had a happy winter
holiday whatever holiday you celebrate I
hope it was beautiful and perfect for
you
I also hope you have a great safe New
Year let's talk about some things we can
do with this fresh new calendar year I
like to set goals at the beginning of a
year I feel like setting goals and
writing them down really keeps us
focused you can say some goals out loud
you can say hey Ross to Jeff in 2019 I
think I want to do this then I'm gonna
give you a fat ass dab and we're gonna
start talking and in four hours you'll
forget you even talked about a goal or
having any sort of goals for the new
year
so when you're going to set goals it is
my advice to write those goals down get
a pen get some paper and write down one
goal if you're really ambitious write
down three goals if you're a
goal-oriented person who likes to crush
a to-do list make a list for 12 things
and try to get one big thing done every
month
you're a person that's intimidated by
goals get one thing done this year as
long as you write down a goal and you
accomplish it you will feel good about
yourself once you accomplish a goal
what's the next step create a bigger
goal then what happens you crush that
goal and it continues then you start
adding to the to-do list you start
getting more confidence you start
getting more things done you start
learning more you start expanding as a
person life gets bigger and better and
it just expands as things go it goes
exponentially in that pattern so create
a goal small or large that is up to you
as long as we've got a goal and we write
it down you can write it down on paper
you can write it down on a Google Drive
you can write it down on a note in your
phone as long as you go and write down
that goal and review it occasionally and
look at it and think about what you have
done to get yourself to that goal now if
you want to be really detailed write
down three steps that it would take to
get yourself to that goal so let's say
your goal is to walk to the front door
what are the first three steps got to
stand up you gotta aim myself toward the
door then I got to take a bunch of steps
that may sound like a small goal but
once you get there you've accomplished
the goal you've made a clear path you've
gotten there you've accomplished the
goal now what's your next goal it feels
good you've gotten some [ __ ] done so
let's set some goals for the new year
let's start talking about garden goals
we can set a lot of the people listening
to this show keep saying to me in emails
or to their girlfriends in conversation
or to their Bros while they're in their
car smoking that they want to start a
grow why not make this year the year
that you start to grow write it down
make it a goal and make it happen I have
given you plenty of advice on how to get
it going it is time to get your [ __ ]
together and start that grow do it dude
what's stopping you I know there are a
few things that may be stopping several
of you but you keep saying you're gonna
do it you're starting to sound silly
hang up some lights put some seeds in
some dirt and finally get growing make
that your goal now if you're already
growing there are plenty of things we
can set as garden goals how about higher
potency
how about better yields how about better
scheduling how about setting a better
routine and a better cycle for the grow
how about the day you cut down plants
you've got plants prepared to go
into that room so that you never miss a
day how about improving your cleanliness
there are plenty of things we can
improve and plenty of goals we can set
in the grow room I don't know what
you're doing in your grow I don't know
what you're missing you do think about
where you're lacking in the grill
what is your weak point are you not a
good clone cutter are you not good at
transplanting do you not know how to
defoliate are you not good at popping
and twisting do you not know how to work
the canopy are you not really
comfortable mixing up nutrients and
getting the pH adjusted find your
weakness and master that this year make
that a goal maybe find a couple of
weaknesses and cover three or four of
them we've got 12 full months why not
make a goal if you've got a small goal
for every month and then a good goal for
every three months and then a huge goal
for the year you're really on pace to
increase your garden experience and your
potential and your learning base and
also if you just live your life like
that
with so many goals in so many different
areas your life will just be fulfilled
and you will be nourished and you'll be
enriched and you'll be a better person
inside and out because of it so pay
attention while you're in the grow
figure out where you're lacking what is
your weak spot make a note of that and
make it a conscious effort to improve on
that over the next 365 days and when we
meet next year to talk about this when
you say man I really did improve on that
you will have so much pride at how far
you have come in one short year now I'm
always talking about journaling and
keeping notes this is a good time to
take some notes start the brand new year
with the brand new grow journal and on
page one write some goals on page one
maybe one major goal maybe three small
goals whatever you want to do make sure
you write that down say hey Rasta Jeff
said to create a goal here's my goal
it's on paper it's written down now it's
a thing you wrote it down you've got
some accountability use that notebook
through the rest of the year to take
your notes in one year open that up to
page one and look at your goals and
think about it have I accomplished those
goals what have I done to get myself
closer to those goals how can I get to
that goal if I haven't already gotten
there now I mentioned earlier it's
always helpful when you're writing goals
to list steps of how you can achieve
that goal when your brain is thinking
about the goal you get inspired the
brain just starts firing and then you
can see the path if you think about it
hard enough you can actually visualize
how to
there so think about what your goal is
and then maybe write down three steps to
help you get there and check once in a
while am i doing these three steps or am
I still stuck am i at zero or have I
done step one have I done step two or if
I [ __ ] up and jumped on to step three
and miss steps one and two all together
and set myself up for failure in the
future just pay attention to what your
goals are pay attention to the steps to
get there and don't lose sight of your
goal now it is fair to change your goal
if you've learned something different if
you get a better idea you're always
learning you're always expanding don't
feel stuck to a goal if you learn more
and get a better idea a better thought
process just make sure it's well thought
out sometimes we don't know everything
we make a plan we set a goal and then we
realize oh that's not exactly what I
thought I was gonna do need to rethink
everything don't be afraid to abandon
ship and rethink it if that's the
appropriate move don't puss out and give
up just cuz you get scared but if you
realize you're aiming at the wrong
target you got to adjust aim for this
target over here always do that in the
grow and in life that's my advice so
what are your goals this year what are
your goals in life what are your goals
in your garden always have goals always
be moving forward and then you won't get
stuck once you get stuck in life once
you get stuck in the garden it is really
hard to get unstuck so it's best just to
keep moving forward never slow now never
stop never get stuck then you never have
to pull yourself out of it and the best
way to stay motivated is to set a goal
keep crushing those goals then you feel
that rewarding experience then you set a
higher goal then you stay motivated you
keep reaching those goals and it is a
positive cycle it keeps you set up for
success set yourself up for success you
guys in the garden and in your life this
is a grow podcast let's focus more on
growing cannabis what are a few goals we
can set in our garden I mentioned
earlier that we can increase yields
there are several ways to increase your
yield that starts in the veg phase you
can improve your pH I bet you can
probably improve the quality of your
feeding you can probably dial in the
amount of each nutrient a little more
closely per strain nutrient feedings are
very strange specific maybe you want to
learn your individual cultivars more
specifically and build a closer
relationship with each plant in your
grow those are a couple of ways to
increase yield during the veg phase
you can also work on cracking and
twisting the sticks you can work on
canopy control you can work on canopy
management those are a couple of other
ways throughout the veg phase you can
increase yields so learn a few things
like that set goals and learn things to
increase the yield also we want to
increase potency not everybody has
access to lab testing but I bet you and
your friends and/or customers can tell
the difference in the quality of the
product you started growing in the
product you're growing now they can tell
there's a difference in potency and
quality maybe you can set a goal to make
that even better and take a few steps to
get it there the number one thing I bet
would improve most of your potency
flavor and aroma across the board for
most growers is learning a better dry
and cure technique and I've put out in a
full episode of drying and curing if you
would like to listen to the drying and
curing episode it is episode 326
now another goal that I know almost
every grower could set and always reach
is keeping the grow room just a little
bit cleaner than we did last year just
focus a little bit more on cleanliness
spend a little bit more time on cleaning
up after yourself it may add 10 minutes
to each day that's about an hour a week
we can all afford one more hour a week
to clean up after ourselves because in
the long run imagine how much time
you'll save if you don't have to go look
for stupid [ __ ] all the time
in a large grow walking from flower room
a to the bedroom number one could take
several minutes just to walk from one
room to the other because in a large
grill we've got a lot of space to cover
then you got to go find whatever you
lost then on the way back you're gonna
get distracted and have to do something
else then the task you were doing just
got abandoned then you got to remember
oh yeah I was over there doing that
that's why I've got scissors in my hand
and I'm standing in the wrong place then
you gotta go get your brain back on
track to what you were doing if you just
clean up and put the scissors where they
go put the measuring devices where they
go put the hoses where they go put the
goggles and gloves and spray equipment
where it goes and have it cleaned and
prepared for the next use you will save
yourself so much time in the garden
so maybe set a goal of being a little
more organized and working on
cleanliness in your garden this year
these are just a couple of practical
ideas I can think of
off the top of my head you guys
everybody wants more potency everybody
wants more overall product and I've been
to a lot of grows and I know that most
of us could work on a cleaner grow room
environment like I said earlier I don't
know where you're lacking in your garden
I don't know what your weak point is I'm
sure you do so identify that weakness
let your ego go accept that you've got a
weakness in the grow we all do there's
something that every one of us could
improve on I can improve on everything
we can all improve on everything in the
grow it's when you stop thinking you can
improve is when you start becoming a
shitty grower so accept your weakness
embrace your weakness then let's find
ways to improve on that weakness and
make you a rockstar grower in all
aspects all right you guys I think I've
ranted on long enough about goals and
setting goals and reaching goals and
trying to motivate everybody to have a
good positive start to the year since it
is the start of a new year there are
also some things we could do in the grow
to make the grow run more smoothly
throughout the rest of the year like I
mentioned earlier a little bit of
cleanliness and also a little bit of
maintenance will make our day-to-day
tasks go much more smoothly it will also
make some of our equipment last longer
we pay a lot of money for high quality
equipment in our grows it would be in
our best interest to take care of that
equipment if you have to keep buying a
brand new pH meter every couple of
months in your grow and you work for a
commercial grow that could have been
your Christmas bonus possibly think
about things like that and you'll start
taking better care of all of your
equipment I bet if you had to buy all of
the tools in your commercial grow you
would probably take a little better care
of it you probably wouldn't wonder where
you left those scissors you probably
wouldn't wonder where that pH pen is if
you had to buy it in a commercial grow I
bet you would know where it is now let's
talk about a few things we can do at the
start of the year and probably should do
at the start of every month that will
help the grow run smoothly something I
really recommend is that at the start of
every month we clean and calibrate the
pH meters you use that pH meter every
time you water the plants that things
should be cleaned and calibrated very
often you're dipping it into solutions
with a bunch of salty junk in there it's
gonna get build-up then it's getting
left somewhere who knows where the grow
techs are putting it hopefully they're
putting it
back in the solution that keeps it safe
maybe not maybe they're just setting it
on the counter maybe they're setting it
in dirty water we need to clean that
occasionally and make sure that it's
clean and calibrated why not the first
of every month
clean and calibrate your pH meter also
if you're using a TDS or an EC meter
clean that at the same time now is also
a good time to clean and replace your
air conditioning filters does your air
conditioner have a replaceable filter
does your HVAC system have filtration
that needs to be replaced now is a very
good time to replace all of those things
and write it down make yourself a note
hey I changed all of the air conditioner
filters or I cleaned all of the air
conditioner filters on January 1st now
you've got to know now when the HVAC
tech comes and says man this filters
dirty when is the last time you change
this you can just hang your head and say
bro I haven't changed that since January
first but right now you probably don't
know when the last time it was changed I
would rather have a date than a question
mark so write it down and change that
[ __ ] get it cleaned up also it may be a
good time to check on your carbon filter
is that carbon filter still working or
is it just a decoration at this point
you may want to bring somebody that
doesn't consume and smell a lot of
cannabis and have them walk out side
wherever that filter is being blown and
just give it a little sniff test can
they smell your grow I can't smell my
own garden I can't smell a lot of
commercial grows unless it is stanky and
pungent I don't even notice I'll Drive
up to places with other people in my car
and we'll be a half a block away from
some groves and my friends will start
going smells real good here and I'll say
what are you talking about is there a
restaurant or something they look like
dude you can't smell that grow no I'm
immune to it I've been around so much
cannabis that I've got to put my face in
it or it's got to be super dank from my
nose to even notice so if you're around
your girl all the time you might not
even notice some people don't even
notice they stink because they stink all
day when someone else comes around and
they go bro you smell like armpits and
onions they go oh [ __ ] I didn't even
know somebody had to tell him that's how
I feel about it grow you may not even
know that your grow is stinking up the
whole block until somebody comes and
tells you maybe have one of your friends
be the one to tell you instead of the
neighbors or a law enforcement so is
that carbon filter working
or has it become a decoration that is
just slowing down air flow at this point
check on that it may be time to replace
it again when you replace it get a piece
of duct tape write the date on that duct
tape and slap it somewhere on that
carbon filter so that you know January
1st I got a new carbon filter now if
you're running an RO machine or some
sort of water filter again it's a really
good time to check and clean and replace
those filters you may think you're
filtering your water you may just be
running your water through a bunch of
dirty [ __ ] and feeding your plants the
water you started with and wasting a lot
of water the RO machine spits out a lot
of waste water if your filters are dirty
it's shooting out a lot of extra waste
water water is kind of precious water
sparkin expensive people are gonna say
water is not expensive run a commercial
grow run a hundred gallons of water down
the drain and tell me it's not expensive
at that point it makes a difference when
you see it in large quantities it almost
hurts your feelings to have to waste
that much water so water is precious
water is expensive water is life the
plants need water we need water
everything needs water so when you waste
a lot of water you're kind of wasting a
lot of life source so clean up all of
your water filtration that way we don't
waste a lot of water that is my point
it's gonna reduce your bills it's going
to reduce waste and it also may increase
the health of your plants you set those
filters up for a reason you're trying to
get something out and if the filters are
too dirty even work you're just putting
in that crap back into the water and
running it through the filter wasting
time wasting water wasting energy so
clean up your filtration if you were
using water filtration another thing
that probably needs to be cleaned is
your reservoir if you've got a small res
that you store your water in if you've
got a gigantic resin which you store
your water it probably needs a scrub in
I would dry it out drain it dry it let
it dry completely then I would get some
sort of a cleaning product I like to use
five-and-twenty I would mix about 15 to
20 milliliters of five-and-twenty in a
gallon of water and I would use that
like a cleaning solution I'd dip it into
a rag and just scrub the inside of my
reservoir wear gloves when you were
using the fisa and 20 please wear gloves
when you're using the Faiz and maybe
even use goggles I don't know the
recommended PPE for Faiz an but I would
certainly wear gloves and I would
probably put on goggles just to be safe
so clean the reservoir
then rinse it out you don't want any
fives n left in there you'll know if
it's left because it makes a lot of
bubbles and it has a very distinct smell
so get rid of the bubbles get rid of the
Phi's and rinse that out real good now
your reservoir is nice and clean and
disinfected now you can go back to
business here we go again get a piece of
duct tape write down the date right I
cleaned this reservoir on January 1st
2019 and stick that on there then every
time you see that if it's been a couple
of months it will start to bug you
you'll go man I haven't cleaned that in
a long time it's probably getting pretty
grody and you're right it's getting
grody in there there's funk building up
in there that will start affecting the
health of your plants so now that we
were cleaning the tank if you've got any
sort of hydro lines if you're in a
commercial environment and you were
running a feed system a drip system and
auto water system also known as a
fertigation system you guys that's
another word for the glossary it may be
a good time to clean out all of those
lines also a good time to clean the
pumps you can use that same thysen and
water solution run that through your
pumps you can soak the pumps right in it
I don't think it's too corrosive to
where it's going to damage your pump but
it will take off all the algae and all
the funk take that pump apart as far as
you can submerge that in the Faiz and
solution take it out give it a good
scrub and you may need to hit it with a
scrub brush and a toothbrush that's just
fine clean up your pump rinse it out
real well so there's no fives end
solution back left in there clean it out
set it aside let it dry clean out the
rest of the lines run that Faiz and
water through your hydro lines if you
can clean it out really well it is
always a good idea when you're building
a drip system to put a ball valve at the
end of it so that you can run water
right through there and is clean out
that whole system so if you haven't done
that that may be a good addition in the
future that may be a good idea for your
next Auto watering or assisted watering
project we want to clean out those lines
we don't want to let a bunch a funk
build up in there I've seen a lot of
nasty [ __ ] build up in the fertigation
lines in the long PVC tubes and the
black poly tubes and the skinny poly
tubes I've seen slimy moldy stinky [ __ ]
come out of there that you do not want
to feed your plants so clean that up a
little bit of Faiz and a little bit of
warm water will go a long way and
cleaning your hydro setup now one more
thing I want to talk about specifically
is our Bowl
how long have you been running your
bulbs in your veg and your flower area
is it time to swap out your bulbs
depending on the quality of the bulbs
you purchased depending on the white
cycle you chose to run depending on your
ballast there are so many different
factors that determine it but over time
your bulbs have slowly stopped putting
out as much light but they are still
consuming as much electricity so it is
always a good idea to consider a bulb
change every couple of harvests
depending again on your bulb strength
are you running a thousand a six or a
four hundred watt bulb did you buy cheap
bulbs or did you buy good expensive
bulbs if you bought those lesser
expensive bulbs you may want to swap
them every grow if you bought good
expensive bulbs you may want to run
those two or three grows before you swap
them out I understand that bulbs are
expensive you're gonna want to push
those bulbs as many grows as you can
just so that you can maximize your
output with the equipment you've got but
keep in mind you may be shooting a
hundred percent of the electricity into
that bulb and only getting 50% of the
lumens that you're expecting so you're
paying for a hundred percent of that
light to come out and only 50 percent of
it is coming out it probably costs
around $100 a month to run a
high-pressure sodium bulb for that $100
a month for the next two months which is
gonna be $200 worth of electricity
you're only going to put $100 worth of
electricity onto those plants so there's
already $100 worth of electricity that
you basically didn't do anything with it
got lost somewhere down the line it went
through the electrical wires and went
down through the red through the white
through the black and then it hit your
bulb and it just stopped it didn't come
out of the bulb you paid for it you
didn't get it
eventually you'll need to make a
business decision do you want to keep
paying for electricity to come down the
wires and just not happen it doesn't go
anywhere or do you want to replace that
bulb it may cost you 50 to 100 maybe 120
bucks for a really high-end high
pressure sodium bulb swap out the bulb
and actually get all the electricity
you're paying for you're paying for that
electricity I do know that that other
bulb cost you more money but you're
gonna spend the money on electricity
either way so if you think about the
math once that bulb diminishes to
approximately 70 60 definitely 50%
you're paying for a hundred percent of
the electricity
and you were getting 50% of the outcome
so you're spending 200 bucks and you're
getting a hundred bucks worth of light
you could go buy another bulb which will
probably cost you a hundred so now
you're spending 300 you've got 200 on
electricity and another hundred on the
bulb and you were getting 100% probably
a hundred and ten percent compared to
what you were getting 110 percent of the
output and your plants are really going
to show you a difference and if you can
wait till harvest time it will be worth
it if you do the mathematical equation
so it's a good time to check on your
bulbs it's a good time to consider
swapping your bulbs and here we go again
when you swap that bulb get some sort of
sticky note get some sort of duct tape
write down I changed this bulb on
January 1st 2019 that way you know when
the bulbs are fresh then when they start
flickering or when they don't look as
bright as they used to be you could say
oh yeah that thing's been in there for
two months things been in there for
three months it's probably time to
invest some of my grow money back into
itself and replace that bulb often I
talked about using a string and a lumen
meter to determine when to replace your
bulbs I will try to go over that really
quickly get something that is a
consistent length you can use a tape
measure if you have one you can use a
piece of string if that is more handy
then you can purchase or borrow a lumen
meter they are quite expensive a lot of
the growth stores will loan you a lumen
meter if you've got a local friendly
shop they like to loan them to you that
way they know that you're gonna come buy
a bulb when it gets too low so get a
lumen meter get a brand new bulb fire
that bulb up give it a little bit to get
to its maximum shine it takes these grow
lights a few minutes to warm up to get
to their full potential give it maybe 30
or 40 minutes to get warm get it shining
measure a distance from that bulb maybe
12 16 18 inches away then set up your
lumen meter and measure the amount of
lumens that you were receiving on the
meter right there
write it down on day one I was receiving
this mini meter or this mini lumens at
this distance away on this meter from
this bulb try to remember where you were
like right in the center of the bulb 18
inches away write that down but try to
remember kind of where you were visually
like you're gonna have to line that up
and do it again or make a mental note of
where you were physically in the room
and how you were doing it because we're
gonna do that again about every 30 days
we're gonna do it again in 30 days and
make a note
how many lumens are coming out then
we're gonna do it at 45
then we'll do it at 60 then let's do it
at 75 then let's do it at ninety days
and see how that bulb reduces an output
when it gets to like I said earlier 70
60 absolutely by 50% you want to swap it
out that is a really good way to
determine when to swap out your bulbs
and that is also a really good way to
see how much electricity you are
actually wasting that bulb says a
thousand watts but over time you know
it's only putting out 700 now so you're
getting 300 watts that are just going
out to nowhere and you're paying for it
if you don't have a bulb that can
actually put out the electricity you're
pumping into it to be quite honest with
you in a commercial grow environment the
bulbs and the flowering rooms are the
number one hardest thing for me to
convince an owner we need to spend money
on to replace I will tell an owner those
bulbs have been in there for six months
it is probably time to change them keep
in mind there's probably 50 1000 watt
double-ended bulbs in this room so it's
going to be quite an investment but I
say we need 50 new bulbs they usually
walk into the room they put their hand
over their eyes like it's a visor
they look up into the lights and they
say it still looks really bright to me
and they don't believe me that those
lights are only putting out 50% of the
electricity they are receiving then when
harvest time comes they complain that
the yields are not what they were two
months ago you know why because those
bulbs are not putting out the lumens we
think they're putting out and they
refuse to change the bulbs usually it
only takes one or two harvests of low
productivity before they realize this
guy is right we need to spend the money
on brand-new bulbs and that grow also
think about this light is the number one
source of energy for our plants yes they
do want water yes they do want air yes
they do need some nutrients but the
light they receive is their number one
source of life that is what makes them
thrive so why wouldn't we do our best to
give them the most light we can afford
to give them in the environment we've
put them in and I don't mean go try to
stick a thousand watt bulb in a closet
I just mean why not maximize our
potential if you've got a closet put the
biggest bulb you can get in that closet
put a 315 in there if you think you can
handle it
but when that 315 bulb starts to dim out
starts reducing its output make sure you
replace it that way you can maximize the
potential of your gross space and your
grow light no matter the size of your
space
all right podcast ruled that is my New
Year's rant I do have one more thing I
would like to say I would like to thank
you I'd like to thank everybody for
listening to the podcast I would like to
thank you for all of the support I'd
like to thank you for all of the
interaction if you were listening to the
podcast if you were supporting the
podcast in any way thank you if you're
listening on itunes stitcher google play
wherever you're listening thank you if
you were a Youtube subscriber thank you
if you have ever left a comment or words
of encouragement thank you also if
you've contributed to the show on
patreon I owe you a huge high-five maybe
even a bro hug and a huge thank you for
all the support thank you for listening
to the show thank you for all of the
feedback and thank you for trusting me
with your garden I understand that those
plants are your babies I understand you
have invested a lot of money and time
and personal energy and you've got a lot
of hopes and dreams for that garden and
I understand that a lot of you rely on
me to keep that garden going so thank
you for the trust and thank you for
believing in me and knowing but I would
never steer you wrong and that all I
want to do is make you the best grower
that you can be so that we can all grow
the best cannabis we can grow that we've
got all the medicine we need for sick
people we've got all the recreational
cannabis we need for people that just
want to write create and have a good
time I want everybody to be a rock star
in the grow room
I want everybody who wants to learn
about cannabis to be able to learn about
cannabis from a person who has
experience and passion with cannabis you
can learn a lot from books but to be
quite honest with you a lot of the stuff
I learned in books really looks good on
paper it doesn't really pan out in a
large-scale grown environment so I'm
here to teach you in a way that actually
works I'm here to teach you ways that I
have tested and put to use in small
grows large grows commercial grows
private grows I just want to share all
of my knowledge with you guys and again
I really appreciate you for following
along for supporting me for trusting in
me and believing in me and also thanks
for listening to me rant you guys I know
I get long-winded but sometimes you got
to explain [ __ ] at multiple
Engels for different people to
understand so thanks for joining in
thanks for listening thanks for being so
supportive and thanks for being a big
part of what has become the IRA army I
appreciate each and every one of you all
right you guys here's where I start
wrapping up the show if you feel like
this podcast was educational informative
or entertaining and you would like to
make a financial contribution to the
show you can do so by going to
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
that is PA t ar e yo and dot-com slash
grow from your heart all of the
information you need to sign up and
become a patron will be right there on
the screen again I do appreciate all of
the patreon support what I do with those
patreon contributions is I pay for the
website I host the podcast on my website
I region etics Colorado com it does cost
a little bit of money to host the
podcast there I pay for that website
with those patreon contributions also I
did use the patreon contributions to
replace the MacBook on which I record
the podcast the old MacBook kind of took
a crap on me I bought a new one with the
help of my patreon supporters so again
big thank you to everyone who supports
the show on patreon that is where your
funding is going it also goes to replace
these microphone covers so that when
Mike comes over and dab and granny come
over and Jesse comes over they're not
all spitting into the same microphone
cover so it doesn't smell like Jesse
when granny's here and it doesn't smell
like granny when Jesse's here those are
the types of things that you're covering
also I put water bottles on the table
for each of the guests small things like
that are covered by patreon
contributions so that is hugely
appreciated not only by myself but by
the people who don't have to smell other
folks breath on their microphone covers
so big thank you to everybody who has
and will contribute to the patreon
campaign I would also appreciate it if
you stock me on all of the social media
you can find the podcast on Facebook
search for the Grove from your heart
podcast you can also find us on Twitter
the podcast is at g f YH podcast if
you'd like to follow my personal Twitter
it's at Rasta Jeff 420
give me a follow also check out the
Instagram I post a lot of great cannabis
photography I also go on Instagram live
and I talk about growing I hang out with
my friends I take dabs and I get chatty
come join me on Instagram live my
Instagram handle is Irie underscore
genetics iri e underscore
ge and et ICS Irie underscore genetics
on the Instagram if you'd like to
communicate with me and you're not into
the social media maybe you've got a
product you'd like me to review maybe
you'd simply like to sponsor the podcast
you can send me an email my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com you know I would love to
hear from you
I do have grow from your heart hoodies
and t-shirts available on my website
I've also got I read genetics t-shirts
and hoodies and there are also a very
small number of Irie army t-shirts left
on the website if you'd like to check it
out the website is Irie genetics
Colorado dot-com then go check out the I
restore grab yourself an IRA hoodie get
yourself some stickers while you're
there get it all styled out with the new
Irie and grow from your heart gear and I
would appreciate your support again I
want to wave goodbye to 2018 you were
all right but 2019 is going to be
amazing you guys I hope you have the
best year ever I can't wait to see all
of the progress that we make together
you guys I will not put out a Thursday
episode but I will be back Monday we
will continue to grow less uns I look
forward to joining you then I want to
give a huge shout-out to my friend
Aldridge and until next time take a phat
dab and give your mom a hug for me