[Music]
welcome to the show podcast world it's
time for episode 382 of the girl from
your heart podcast once again Mike is
back Happy New Year bro
Happy New Year buddy thanks for coming
and hanging out with me yeah man back
due to popular demand the people have
spoken they want more white Mike on the
show they have spoken we will have more
of the white Mike as always this podcast
is brought to you by our good friends at
the hell a dank seed company that's
right it's the new year it's time to add
some fresh genetics to your garden get
rid of that old stale [ __ ] grow some new
[ __ ] you can get that at the hell a dank
seed company at www.streetevents.com
and the lung there from that last day we
took not to brag not to talk about how
good our dabs are but we took a little a
apothecary farms internally flawless
series diamond broke a few little pieces
off of that they're heated up the banger
dropped the diamond into there and then
dropped a fat glob of lemon Geoffrey
full terpene hive terpene full spectrum
extract damn I forgot the words now
basically lemon Jeffrey Terps right on
top of that dab then capped it up Mike
took a little tiny micro dab it took a
pretty big fat dab of it we both sat
here and coughed and changed colors
played a fun game with Mike ride as he
blew out the damn I said real quick name
this new cross I made and he tried to
spit out stray names and it was funny to
watch him scramble
making words was hard enough then trying
to put them together to make this train
name was pretty funny to watch so words
were hard good words were not possible
we were smoking on I was the internally
flawless diamonds with the elimin
Jeffery Terps on top of that before that
we may have had a few other random dabs
we may have hit the star dog we probably
hit the guerrilla glue oh wait wait the
GG for you can't say gorilla glue
anymore and the goat power
we took a dope power it smells
straight-up like golden goat I don't
know what else that could be I think
it's just gold and goat but anyway we've
had plenty of dabs I think Mike is well
lit I am heavily medicated there may be
a dab break here in the middle of the
show but welcome to the show everybody
welcome folks yeah right over there Mike
I'm good your eyes are we had a slight
technical glitch at the beginning and
Jeff pointed out something on the screen
and I'm having trouble not watching the
audio for you record itself it's still
it's still doing the thing we're cool
I'm confident that that works it's got a
lava lamp like appeal oh yeah bro you
just want to stare at it and watch that
thing move up the drive really hard not
to see to watch my words make lines
I put the computer in a different spot
so that I wouldn't do what mike is doing
right now I catch myself staring at the
little graph that you know when you talk
into audio software that makes a little
graph it shows how high it looks like a
lie-detector test on the screen if you
think about it that way it looks like
the ones it's doing that with my voice
that's jumping up and down I see Aaron's
staring do it while I talk and that's
why I use the headphone so I can stare
into the screen and I can hear you
clearly and I have to look and look
around the table to hear people and I
stay with my voice onto the mic and I
can look into the thing but now you're
mesmerized they may have to move it in
the future so then right I'm trying to
focus on your notepad and notes right
now and it's not working because it's
upside-down to you and you've got
terrible eyesight if you haven't picked
up on it yet work blazed
we might have smoked a lot of dabs
before this show Happy New Year you guys
have the new year I do believe it's the
first episode with Mike Happy New Year
brother thanks for hanging out yeah man
29 to be more white Mike as my
resolution normally Mike on the show
does more white Mike is it cool new
year's resolution for yourself or white
Mike bro that's it alright because there
is going to be content in this podcast
we're not just gonna sit here and get
rambly hi there yes we did write down
some notes on a piece of paper we're
gonna talk about some stuff we just
wanted to have fun at the start of the
show settle in get a vibe going who
needs a business right at the top of the
show it's always fun to have a good time
um Mike do you want to jump into this
farm bill stuff are you ready for all of
that and we most certainly can okay I am
going to admit I said I'm gonna read
this farm bill thing it might ghost bro
it's like a hundred and something pages
and I was like well maybe I'll let you
just tell me about it and it's it's not
just like a hundred pages it's like the
first hundred pages of Harry Potter it's
a hundred pages of some of the most dull
language you could ever come across
lawyers are evil they literally lawyer
means [ __ ] up language no enough
understands that we arguing like I'm
married to one I was asked to have an
expert yes yes but for those of you who
took a look
it didn't feel like reading it we're
gonna do kind of a light gloss over of
what the farm bill is what all is jammed
into it why this year's was special hint
it has to do with hemp legalization and
what that means for hemp market CBD all
that good stuff I'm so glad this is a
Thursday episode and not a Monday
episode I think I'm spoiling of him I
think I said I was not going to put out
a Thursday so to say I feel a little
extra off leash because for two reasons
one you straight-up told people on
Monday you weren't gonna do with
Thursday show and I respected that as a
listener because it's [ __ ] New Year's
go have some fun buddy but we had a
chance to get together so why not do it
there's a [ __ ] yeah that's reason one
reason to I'm just in a really good mood
and we've been having fun good fun
showed up in a good mood and then I got
you extra high so well we got extra
height together I'm not gonna blame it
on me right it wasn't like you tricked
me try some of this one bro you want
some of this blue candy dude if you want
another dab you dig in that pile that
this pile is inviting too but it's the
same [ __ ] that's in that pile just last
week my brain wants to go outside for a
different chemical oh yeah I'm gonna
skip that in not dab and knock you Baker
that igner word it's just fun to say
take the higher stoned err yep stoned
then people are just [ __ ] tunings how
gone on this episode so the farm bill
farm bill dive right into it
we will we are gonna miss if we dive too
hard so let's just wait and then gently
head will gently lay floor alright so
kick your flip-flops off and slowly wade
into this is getting weird the farm bill
is a major piece of federal legislation
that we do every four years I think it
is might be every five pretty sure it's
every four years and it covers a huge
range of topics everything from how and
where different agricultural crops get
grown to food safety testing that's
required to food stamps and nutrition
programs at schools
I mean it's a massive bill that covers
all sorts of different things that are
very very loosely related to agriculture
and food and some of it gets very
scientific and you wouldn't think about
it when you think like farming or the
farm bill it has to do with like lab
testing equipment and FDA rules and
regulations also it also has things like
crop insurance for farmers so if a
tornado shows up and [ __ ] up their
soybean harvest they're not just broke
and destitute now that there's a form of
federal insurance that they can apply
for and things like that so the farm
bill is massive and because it's huge
and politics is kind of weird and quirky
a bunch of different things get attached
to it every time they do it and
politicians use it as a way to get
leverage on other people sometimes or
you're not willing to jeopardize
something you care about in it so if
they slip in a pet project of theirs
you're not going to torpedo their pet
project because it's part of this thing
you care about in one of those little
attachments this year was legalizing
hemp Republican senator from Kentucky
attached it to this year's farm bill and
it passed without any fanfare outside of
our small community which is kind of
surprising the hemp has been illegal to
grow in the US for like 60 or 70 years
it was banned after World War two it was
rebuilt after World War two it was
banned before World War two also but it
was rebound
you could hide marijuana in hemp fields
which if you know anything about the
cannabis plant isn't really a thing they
both kind of ruin each other and if
you're growing the hemp for a reason and
you grill marijuana and cross pollinate
you're gonna [ __ ] up your hemp harvest
and if you're having harvest cross
pollinate your cannabis harvest you're
gonna ruin your cannabis harvest also
not immediately but especially 40 50 60
years ago when they were having this
argument it was exceptionally illogical
because unfamiliar wasn't a thing crops
operation like we know now is the thing
it would have been a major issue but
they managed to attach it to cannabis
prohibition in general and fighting
marijuana and has been illegal to grow
across the u.s. for decades and every
time somebody brings up how moronic this
is and how many different products that
hemp could be and currently is being
used in across the US but we can't grow
it usually the DEA brings up their
original objections it can be used to
hide marijuana or high THC crops
it'll be confusing for law enforcement
spend another one that I've always loved
they they were real vocal in the 90s and
early thousands about how we can't
legalize him because cops could never be
trained to tell the difference and they
were open and honest about how they were
sure that was a thing well if you look
at the two plants side-by-side if I took
you to a hemp farm and I was like bro
show me the cannabis and show me the
hemp you couldn't tell the difference
like if we went out to the big hemp farm
out here on the highway on ninety six
there's a giant one on the right side of
the road there you see it when you drive
out there
those look like cannabis plants if you
get close and rub them they've got
trichomes if you smell your fingers it
smells like arm that Tora Bora that we
used to grow it's got that Afghani
cherry smell to it they're growing a
real Afghan cherries they're grown of
our sincerity right yeah yeah it's a
specific type a hemp that they're using
that grows similar to the plants we're
talking about a lot of the hemp for
textiles is like 11 feet tall okay it
looks like more like sugar cane or reeds
in the river all right then it does like
a bushy Chris yeah very skinny single
stock that goes way up and then you get
a little kind of looks like a bud at the
very top but the field looks very
different you can pull up him for
victory and look at the two plants and
they look fairly dissimilar okay but how
the main issue with hemp being an
illegal is hundreds and hundreds of US
companies have to import it and it's
been this weird rule where you can't
grow it but you can buy all of it that
you'd like and if these objections are
for the growing plant they had their
similarly true or equally true for the
harvested plant but we can import all we
want you've been able to buy
I mean hamsas the brand that I always
think of because it's the one my mom's
used for 20 years but like the lotions
you should have one of her friends
turned her on to the lotion back in like
nine I call it candle shop hemp lotion
yeah what that makes me think it's just
hemp seed oil is one of the ingredients
in them in the lotion product but they
have to import all of that from another
country to use in their products here
and so what this year's farm bill did is
it finally opened up the market to US
farmers so now we can produce our own
hemp which is huge in the fact that
nobody spoke up with any of the dumbass
objections in the past is I think
another big symbol that legalization
moving forward through education is
definitely happening absolutely now we
don't have to import a large import
product from Canada I feel like that's
what it was coming from I mean all over
the planet China grows have Canada grows
have Japan grows hemp
I'm Japan have bright now to clean up
Fukushima yeah it's a incredibly
versatile plant that's being used all
over the world for I mean literally
thousands of different uses and we
couldn't grow it here I remember when I
was in college and a couple years after
so early 2000s there was this Indian
Reservation that I want to say in Texas
and just by fate their location
coincides with an old hemp farm or
whatever and so there's just feral hemp
all over this Indian Reservation and
every five or ten years the cops would
show up be like you [ __ ] know you're
growing weed get down right and they'd
spend ten days being like it's [ __ ]
feral hemp like come look around no
one's growing it no one's harvesting it
[ __ ] off in the local population got so
fed up with these like every five six
years as soon as the cop in charge of
the last raid isn't in charge of the
raids anymore someone sees the field
from the air and freaks out again and so
they started coming up with different
uses for it and I think these are the
people that really found it like hemp
Cree in the US
and a couple of other things and then
we're building whole houses where
everything except the glass and the
doorknobs and stuff out of the hemp
plant from the concrete to the the
insulation to the the roofing panels
were pressed out of something else like
it was intense
yeah I've seen the hempcrete blocks and
they try to light them on fire and
they're really fire resistant it's
impressive how much heat they take but
uh even after they started all that the
feds showed up a handful of times so
we're like what's with this big weed
field like that's just we can't do
anything about it
it's feral right we keep cutting it down
it comes back sir but all of that is
over the weird little tidbit of this
that I'm looking forward to is the feds
have been including feral hemp seizures
in their average potency numbers for the
entire length of have marijuana
prohibition oh because I did not know
that they just don't think anybody knows
that they just don't care it's it's as
far as they're concerned it's all
cannabis and it's all the same illegal
because under the lie was and so they'd
seize it
they test it and they throw it away and
by their process of doing it is they
just grab all of the plant material and
stuff in a trash bag and then someone
takes a handful of material out of that
trash bag and they test it is their
average potency numbers eaves sticks
dirt dirt bird nests oh my okay so
they've been hard there just when they
went in and really just tried to take
the plant they're still taking from the
root the the top or the base of the
stock right where it meets the root ball
up all of that's just a handful that's
going into their testing mix and that's
gonna be high THC one of the big
anti-pot talking points for a long time
is like modern marijuana is so much
stronger than before and now that helps
not part of those numbers I'm gonna I'm
gonna laugh when the average gets really
hinky over the next couple of years when
the data comes out okay
that'll be neat to watch yeah I'm gonna
laugh if there's a huge spike because
the number seems low to me right now
they're they're still reporting it
around twelve
is that a nationwide number yep we keep
in mind not everybody is in Colorado and
not everybody's got the labs that the
legalized states have so if you're in
pick a state that's got some legal
cannabis where I can get caught with
some weed and be [ __ ]
Arkansas okay let's say Arkansas imagine
the left
sorry Arkansas imagine the backasswards
live equipment in Arkansas to test for
THC content they're using the same
equipment that they use for the rape
kits and stuff so it's decent equipment
it's just how they're testing and what
they're testing and also who's been a
part of that for for who's growing in
Arkansas who's the lead grower in Little
Rock units they do all the busts they
got to do their [ __ ] on the down-low
they got a sneek again they got to drive
one dudes car to the gross store and buy
[ __ ] then drive that car to the house
and pull in the garage and load up the
other car and drive that and sneak it
all into the dark they're back in that
era so one feral hemp bust serve all
over the country you see we get at least
one or two good ones a year where the
rear initial report is like massive
marijuana fields found in middle of
nowhere and then you know the next day
is cops tear down 10,000 plants 15,000
plants called a sophisticated operation
a week later
turns out it's a feral hemp spend there
for 30 years it was just particularly
wet this spring and so the it got out of
hand more seeds germinate someone
noticed and yeah
it happens I mean it's happened in the
same spot access like 10 times since
I've been an adult it was a pretty
common occurrence
ooh that'll be fun watching all this
change and it'll be fun seeing the the
first hemp fields go up and then seeing
the high school kids get busted thinking
that the signs that everywhere is saying
this is HAP you can't get stone from it
please don't break in and kill our
plants people are still gonna hop that
fence come in cut a plant down and run
away get pulled over you know a mile
later feel stupid have a big ol stinky
stinky plant in their car that's not
worth a [ __ ] yep unless you're trying to
make a necklace yep but I'm really glad
this past there's been a lot of
foolishness kind of in our community
about this piece of the farm bill
there's a lot of I didn't read it and
I'm assuming and I had bad information
before this happened and now I'm angry
that put too fine a point on it if that
sounded like I was talking about you mm
Jake your social media I'm staying
silent over there it's uh a lot of
people were hoping that this would mean
all CBD products were a hundred percent
legal for all uses and all marketing
ploys and that's just an insane idea
that's not how this works that's how any
of this work is they said hemp not CBD
um this is a huge move for textiles for
seed production for paper production I
mean you can make anything that we make
currently from trees oil or cotton you
can make with the hemp plant and that's
thousands of thousands and thousands of
things like most of the equipment we're
using to make this show comes from some
of those like all our clothes everything
for a table we're sitting at yeah
drywall behind us
the gasoline and the cars where I used
strawberry or like all of it we can make
with him and so all of that's on the
table for production now but CBD and THC
especially if they're marketed with any
sort of health effect at all is covered
by the FDA just like they would be if
they were any sort of other plant
compound if you market something in the
US with any sort of health claim
whatsoever whether it's a mood
stabilizer helps with anxiety depression
doesn't matter what it's helping with if
it's supposed to help with anything but
[ __ ] I'm hungry it's got to go through a
special set FDA approvals so is
basically the difference on that um say
this is the pad let's grab a product I'm
just grabbing a thing that's on my table
so that I have an example this label
right here is not a food product so what
was I trying to say if I put aa sooths
hand pain suddenly I have to have an FDA
thing but if I'm the back I just put the
word CBD in my ingredients if it just
has CBD in the ingredients I don't have
to have an FDA stamp but as soon as I
make a claim is that what I have to add
that stamp the F at FDA is food and so
they also oversee [ __ ] like cucumber
lettuce tomatoes popsicles and so if you
have a CBD food item that you would like
to make in Colorado and sell in
Washington and say was a gummy that had
CBD in it and as long as you weren't
like hyper marketing it you would
probably just have to go through the
food approvals okay
um because at that point it's just an
ingredient like sugar or high fructose
corn syrup and red dye 907 yeah however
as soon as you slap it on the front of
the package and call it like these are
CBD gummies the FDA is probably gonna be
want to know like is that a flavor it's
not a flavor all right what is it it as
soon as that person being asked that
question starts talking they're gonna
end up like or let they're gonna likely
end up in a place where that would have
to go through the drug approvals as well
right and if you go to a health food
store all of those herbal supplements
have been through most of this or all of
it depending on what they're claimed
they get the little purple star and they
say FDA approved yep talking about a
very specific brand because I worked at
a health food store for quite a while
FDA approved doesn't mean it's a good
effective treatment for whatever it just
means they there's enough evidence to
say that that claim is probably true and
that it's also not bad for you like it's
not gonna kill you not indicated yeah
like you if it's got sesame seeds in it
and you're allergic to sesame seeds
that's not what we're talking about here
but in our nation's history we had a
huge problem with fake medicines being
marketed and this is an answer to that
and there are a lot of people in our
community that were outraged when the
farm bill passed almost immediately
after like the FDA knew this was coming
they know that these issues are a cop a
hot topic of conversation so they
released a memo or I don't remember what
they called it I'm missive to the public
right after the farm bill with signs
saying this is awesome but calm down
this doesn't apply to THC and CBD
anything marketed
with those two specifically because
they've been marked as FDA compounds and
further anything that claims to be a
health food item that gets marketed in
the US has to go through our approval
process and that still applies to all
these CBD stuff that's hitting the
market right now and the FDA's been
working for a couple of years now to
rein in the CBD health market because a
lot of it's just random nonsense claims
that have no support I did an episode
called something fishy
it's about funky CBD products they've
found products on the market that claim
to have one thing that and they can't
find it or they find it in different
amounts right it says 100 milligrams of
CBD they find not a hundred milligrams
sometimes they find none at all
sometimes they find compounds that
aren't on the label I was reading this
it was a crazy report that came out with
the farm bill we're right around the
same time about a CBD bust where they
went and bought up a whole bunch of the
vape cartridges and they ordered some
online and they bought some from local
vendors and one of the products that
kept turning up is one of the same ones
that they put in spice and k2
oh [ __ ] and that herbal crap you buy
that's fake marijuana yeah that won't
hit pop or pop hot on a drug test but
it's a synthesized compound that's
coming out of find some secret lab in
China or somewhere that's very similar
to Delta 9 THC but won't come up in a
standard drug strain and they're finding
it in CB pure CBD vape pen cartridges
and [ __ ] in places like Alabama Wow
because the market is really
unscrupulous like that's what the FDA is
there for like when you buy something
with that stamp that says FDA approved
that company's been inspected they're
regulated they follow rules surprise
inspections product testing like
rigorous [ __ ] product testing all of
it so that it they know that when
millions of these go out on the public
there's not gonna be a crazy scare it's
like it's not I don't know there's so
many
want to cut our community that freaked
out about this like oh my god look what
you did now that the FDA is gonna take
away CBD now the cannabis industry is
the biggest conspiracy theorist like as
soon as one thing happens they start
projecting seven thoughts into the
future that mean to just you you
remember the old hippie cliche to sit
around and smoke a joint freaked out
about the government man that's what
they [ __ ] do for real in our industry
a lot a little bit too much yeah it's
it's not necessarily our fault it it
comes from an honest place I think for a
long time in our history if you stood up
and were Pro cannabis you were risking a
lot and so the only people that stood up
had nothing to lose and the people with
nothing to lose usually like they never
had anything to lose and that's why they
have nothing to lose now and that's not
necessarily the best spokesman and that
didn't help us at all and in our fringe
in black market
like conspiracy theories have always
been part of the community make sense
the good old days it's something about
that type of person the black market
grower the recluse we're all like super
extra paranoid you got a stand and peek
out the windows and then your only
friend is the internet YouTube starts
telling you that everyone's watching you
and then the Illuminati wants to steal
your bacon right it starts getting weird
[Laughter]
so that's the farm bill everybody if you
have questions about the farm bill other
provisions if you want me to elaborate
more about what it means for textile
production or what other stuff you can
make them have like you can google most
of that [ __ ] but if you want a tweeted
me it's at nema 1-15 Nemo Punk 15 on the
tweeter or also what about pueblos for
sensible cannabis laws if you do that
you have lawful assent I find me on
Facebook at pueblos for sensible
cannabis laws as well there you go
email me might have to search for that
one a little harder if you're not
already familiar with the Facebook page
are they blocking the cannabis pages the
Facebook's been doing that for months
now okay go search for you haha maybe
six eight months ago Facebook decided to
make it much harder to find anything
cannabis related which made me laugh my
ass off because both sides of the
conversation tend to use the words
cannabis or marijuana Oh
names and so all of the anti-pot in
cannabis pages vanished just as
thoroughly as all of the pro hahaha it
makes me laugh yeah
well it's got a play fair got a play
fair so with this um farm bill do you
see in the future that hemp will be
tested in the same manner as cannabis
not just for cannabinoid content to
ensure that it is not hot as the word we
use for th see if it's got too much THC
we call it hot it's got to be destroyed
or reallocated for different purposes or
it can be constant ran into a
concentrate and in that concentrate can
be separated I'm gonna be separated yeah
something I learned recently um do you
feel that they will be doing pesticide
testing um
they're gonna do so it depends with the
crops being produced for right Wow it's
gonna go through very separate testing
so when you buy hold hemp seed at the
health food store which you've been able
to do for decades it goes through the
same food testing as the sunflower seeds
at the gas station okay alright so
there's no Michael butanol in those
[ __ ] shouldn't be the same things with
the textiles like if you buy a hem
t-shirt at the mall or it online or
whatever it should have got all the
material that went into that should have
gone through the same testing is the
cotton shirt or the polyester shirt that
you bought to so that will in the future
all of the hemp will have to be tested
for pesticides it's currently not to my
best understanding like if we went out
to one of the local hemp farms they
don't have to they do have to adhere to
Department of Agriculture pesticide
rules and laws but after that there's no
testing for pesticide presence or mold
and mildew 'he's like we also test for
in the industry they don't test for any
of that stuff so i I look forward to
when they have to test for that sorry
you guys worse multiple product well
we're gonna be eating a lot of stuff we
we mentioned earlier goes into gummy
bears but if it goes into a salve or I I
have family members I don't to call
anybody I don't get anybody in any
trouble I have a family member who has
very bad arthritis and they use a lotion
quite frequently I don't want them
rubbing [ __ ] floral my lotion for
skin they're getting all underneath that
that should go through all the same
testing that that everything else goes
through one of the the big upsides to
federal legalization um that we just got
with HAMP is we already solved all these
[ __ ] problems for ninety percent of
what we deal with every day like you
don't have these worries when you buy a
shirt or a hat or shoes online
you never think was are these socks
treated with pesticides nope like I make
a point to wash new clothes when they
come into my house but that's more like
a paranoia thing because there's like
three episodes of shows I watched as a
kid where the plotline was like kid gets
sick from genes that didn't get washed
we've already solved all these protect
her food safety for clothing and textile
safety all these rules are already in
place for a thousand other products we
just weren't allowed to use that
infrastructure for him right
because hemp was federally illegal it
was a Schedule one substance just like
cannabis the the farm bill actually
removed him from Schedule one and
changed the official wording of our
federal drug statutes and I mean that's
what I mean when I say that it's weird
that the DEA
and the drug czars office and all of
that federal machinery didn't have
fuck-all to say about this when they
were quiet about it is this was leading
up to is it gonna get put in the farm
bill oh it's in is it gonna get passed
by the Senate is gonna get passed by the
house okay well is the president gonna
sign it all of that they were quiet and
people like me they've been following us
for 20 years we're like well where's the
normal course at [ __ ]
yeah and they just weren't there it was
just really kind of big news did once
again I'm going back to the devil's
advocate was that the right hand going
like this over the left hand he come
over here and pull some [ __ ] while we
were going look at the farm bill thing
look at the farm bill thing and they're
over here just [ __ ] not really hasn't
merchandise out the back door it wasn't
like when they're doing something for a
distraction they shout about it and they
just Marshall there's some waving
there's some blood
something yeah and with this there was
just like hey you know we've got
bipartisan support for a farm bill isn't
that nice
and everybody was like yeah but what
about they were like no that's cool
we're just doing this real quick it's
done and at the end of the day we Pro
cannabis news outlets and a couple
others like yay how's legal and the FDA
was like yeah but CBD and THC are under
the same rules that are applied as
always and that was pretty much it
outside of the cannabis community like
even the people like dr. Bronner's
weren't like and I was gonna bring up
dr. Bronner's I wanted to make a joke
really is anybody heard from dr. Bronner
yeah the stinky past so it's company I
kind of expected someone from his
company or from a similar industry to be
like you know we're really thrilled
about this you know more tonight at nine
yeah but there was none of that dr.
Bronner's soap every single day I own a
number of have clothing items that I've
had free years because they they just
last longer you pay a little more but it
never wears out ever yeah that is the
truth yeah good him quality I'm looking
to see what I'm wearing now there's no
hemp on me oh my socks maybe him I'm not
sure though I've known countless people
that were to that dr. Bronner's so
that's one of the things that made me
laugh is shadow I said the dreadlock
crew the anti pop crowd kind of freaked
out with this now like you know I'm sure
this is just backdoor legalization again
and you know the farm bills bad and look
at this hemp product I found at Target
the other day and it was it was actually
the house brand and I just laughed so
hard and I'm like wait you're half the
age of my mom she's been using that
lotion all time you've been alive and
you think this has something to do with
the farm bill that goes into effect in
January for his name and Jenny refers to
a lady like they're just so [ __ ]
stupid yeah well once you're against
something you're against it much you're
programmed you're programmed and unless
you get reprogrammed or unprogrammed you
might be stuck that's true for most
topics but like at this point anyone who
cares enough to have an opinion either
way is checked on it a little bit in the
only people left in the hardcore anti
camp are either a long time ago they
committed to a life of talking bad about
pie and getting paid for it
and that's their thing
if they go outside of that at all they
have to come up with a whole new
everything a lot of those people have
that story of how I sound like an
[ __ ] right now how one of their
friends drank 17 beers at a party and
smoked a joint and then left and got in
a wreck and killed themselves and they
blame cannabis yeah that's a bunch of
them the big one Kevin Sabet just he
figured out when he was in college that
he could get people to give him money
for being the guy that wears a suit it
is like I'm kind of likable in
marijuana's terrible I mean he's he's
made her up this is a good life it's a
basic good description of that guy - I
wear a suit and kind of likeable he's
worked for three presidents two or three
presidents I think he might have worked
two administration's for Bush and then
one for Obama I think this is his claim
to fame but he might have been Clinton
Bush Obama I'm not sure but he worked
for the drug czars office for a while
and now he's got a company where people
just give him money that they worked
hard for so that he can continue to go
around the country in bash legal weed
it's kind of nuts in here about five
years ago made a point to stop taking
donations from these peoples companies
that like drug test or run rehabs and
stuff and he only takes checks from the
person themselves and so like if Jeff
you were to send me a check in this
manner you wouldn't send it from Ira
genetics Colorado you would send it from
Jeff really and so that way I could be
like I only take donations from private
citizens I don't take corporate money
that's wack but it's a cute little place
yeah I don't know where this change came
from but enjoy that tidbit folks there
you go that's a great way to start
segwaying since I'm getting my cadaver
Eddie anyway guys thank you for enduring
38 I don't know how much of that got
edited approximately 38 minutes of a
podcast that's that's I you shouldn't
finish my report in the farm bill guy
thank you so much really
know I get why a lot of people can't
wait through this [ __ ] on their own and
make sense of it like it's designed to
be really complicated and kind of hard
to understand yeah I just tried to kill
Mike what the day I was gonna give him
had to rethink yeah I said all that
I would just like just like most of this
off but that bring give me the part that
sticks so I'm gonna put this back on
track that was hilarious that was a good
part here I appreciate your presence on
the show you know we stood up for it
before that [ __ ] is valuable people
there are people some people got bored
as [ __ ] but some people are really
interested in that - that was for if you
got bored then that'll be a Monday show
that would be about growing Ken this is
will be back on track I've probably seen
300 people online in our community
arguing about what the farm bill did and
didn't do and 299 of them had no [ __ ]
idea what they were talking about I'm so
I'm glad to help clear up the air for
anyone who wanted to listen that's what
we brought you here for alright I'm
gonna give you a DAB you're gonna take a
dad all right podcast world at that
point in the show I gave Mike and dad he
is probably still coughing we had to
wrap up the show you can find Mike on
social media make sure you find him on
Facebook at Pueblo for sensible cannabis
laws you can also find him on Twitter
he's an emo Punk 15 on Twitter give him
a follow I would appreciate it if you
also follow the show on Twitter you can
find the show at G f YH podcast on
Twitter if you'd like to follow my
personal Twitter account it's a trois -
Jeff 420 give me a follow I would
appreciate the support I would also
appreciate it if you support the show on
patreon
simply go to patreon.com
you need we'll be right there on the
screen ladies and gentlemen I want to
thank you for listening to this episode
I want to thank Mike again for coming
and hanging out taking time away from
his family to come record a podcast I
will be back Monday with a fresh new Gro
lesson I hope you guys join me for that
I want to give a huge shout out to my
friend slaughterhouse cannabis and until
next time take a phat dad and give your
mom a hug for me