welcome to the show everybody it's time
for episode 383 of the girl from your
heart podcast this episode is brought to
you by our friends at the hella dank
seed company if you need new seeds in
your garden I highly recommend the hella
dank seed company and you can find them
at www.steveadubato.org if smells
delicious if you have ever smelled or
smoked a golden goat this is exactly
what golden goat smells like to me I'm
giving it a fresh smell so I can give
you a fair description it's got a hint
of citrus not overpowering citrus but it
does have a citrus base to it with a
tropical pineapple and a juicy fruit gum
sort of aroma on top of it
- that stickiness that a juicy fruit
piece of gum would have I know it's
weird to say something smells sticky I
think that stickiness is part of the
flavor and aroma of the gum it doesn't
have that it's got that tropical
sweetness it's got some citrus it's got
a hint of pineapple mostly a citrus and
tropical fruit sort of a thing going on
I would really describe it as a orange
pineapple tropical fruit Jolly Rancher
would probably be the most accurate
description that I could nail it down -
so that's the aroma and flavor it has
got a beautiful golden color to it it's
got just the right amount of diamonds
just the right amount of sauce in there
beautiful beautiful goat power from our
friends at apothecary farms and
obviously it has got me amped up and
ready to talk my face off so this should
be a great podcast if you've been
following along you know I've been doing
a long series of in-depth grow lessons
in episode 351 we talked about setting a
goal for the garden then we talked about
picking a space for the garden then we
talked about the appropriate equipment
and setting up the grow safely and
effectively then we work our way through
getting clones and starting a grow at
this point we are all the way to week
four of the grow in this episode we're
going to talk about weeks 4 5 &amp; 6 if
you're a new grower or if you're new to
the podcast
I suggest you head back to episode 351
and start with the droll essence there
if you are an experienced grower or if
you feel like you were up to speed or if
you've been following along let's jump
right into a grow lesson in this lesson
we are going to focus on episodes four
five and six of the flowering phase at
this point of flowering it should be
obvious where the bud sites are going to
be you should have little buds popping
up they should look like little
dandelions they're starting to actually
form into buds by now it should be
clearly obvious where the buds are it
should also be more than obvious which
plants are males and females all of the
males better be gone by now or you have
pollinated everything and you're going
to have a seeded crop so all of the
males are gone at this point at this
point your buds are starting to form
you're seeing little pistol hairy
covered buds you're starting to get
minimal bud mass at this point we are
also coming out of that rapid stretch
phase for the first three weeks of
flowering our plants really like to
stretch and take off that is pretty much
over our plants are still going to get
taller hopefully that top bud grows
gigantic but that rapid stretch phase is
over we don't have to worry so much
about the plants just taking off on us
anymore they're going to stop stretching
and they're going to start focusing
their energy more on developing the fat
chunky buds we want now at this point if
you don't have a carbon filter it is
really time to get a carbon filter in
your grow room if you've got any air
exiting the grow going outside that the
neighbors may smell you need a carbon
filter by now things are going to start
getting really aromatic from here on out
it is only going to get worse so keep
your odor under control I've said it
before a very common way for your garden
to be discovered is for the aroma to be
noticed by a neighbor the neighbors call
the police the police drive around the
block they narrow it down they knock on
your door by the time they hit the front
porch they can smell it they know it's
you they come knock on the door if you
were in a legal state they want to count
your plants it's still a pain in the ass
you've got law enforcement in the house
in the Gros it's stressful if you are in
a non legal area if whoever shows up at
your front door feels that they have got
probable cause to come into your house
they can come they can discover your
grow you may be handy with the laws you
may speak well you may know how to keep
them out of the house for now
but if the aroma was strong enough if
their suspicion was strong enough
they're going to contact the judge they
will have a warrant and in several days
they will be back they'll pull off the
front door it will come in armed it will
be scary as [ __ ] it will destroy your
entire garden and ask questions later so
now is the time to have a carbon filter
always be thinking about safety and
security if you were growing an illegal
or non legal state you probably don't
even notice how pungent your garden is
because you're there every day but the
first time the mailman walks in front of
the house and catches a little whiff
he's going to know exactly what that is
the first time a little bit of aroma
wafting a and hits your neighbor right
in her nose she's going to know exactly
what that aroma is immediately in this
scenario we are only four weeks into
flower and our plants are beginning to
stink it is only going to get worse by
week seven eight and nine it is going to
be pungent as soon as we start
harvesting these plants and trimming the
plants that aroma is going to increase
exponentially don't add that extra
stress to yourself by stinking up the
entire neighborhood with your grow I
understand that buying a carbon filter
and an extraction fan sound like just
another expense to a new grower but I
would much rather invest that money in a
filter and a blower than my lawyer and
bail alright I feel like I've made my
point it is time for a carbon filter if
you don't have one now it is time to
start taking the steps to get a carbon
filter in your garden all right I feel
like that's a good overview of what's
going on in the garden buds are showing
the stretch phase is over and it is
starting to stink now let's talk about
the environment in our grow four weeks
four five and six let's start with
temperature for a daytime temperature
four weeks four five and six I would
suggest a range of 70 to 80 degrees
Fahrenheit now if you can dial it in a
little tighter I would like to be
between 74 and 77 degrees now during the
night I would suggest a temperature in
the range of 60 to 70 degrees if you can
dial it in nice and tight I would
recommend 65 to 68 degrees again I'm
going to suggest no more than a 10
degree difference in your day and night
temperature
what that means is if your day
temperature is 77 degrees you don't want
your night temperature any lower than 67
degrees we don't want to see any more
than a 10 degree diurnal temperature
variation if we allow drastic
temperature drops in the night cycle we
will slow down the plant growth and we
will also encourage powdery mildew
development so again during the day we
want to be between 70 and 80 degrees at
night we want to be between 60 and 70
degrees now as time goes on we are going
to want to reduce the temperature of the
grow room later in Flour
we want to make the room a little bit
cooler so if you are struggling to get
the room to 74 at this point maybe just
keep it up there at 78 79 degrees so
that when weeks 8 &amp; 9 come around we can
reduce that temperature down to as low
as you can get it if the lowest you can
get it is 74 let's wait until weeks 8 &amp;
9 to get it there and leave it around 77
now now I know a lot of people are going
to say why do we want to make it cooler
there are several reasons think about a
plant outside as the seasons change it
gets colder it knows oh [ __ ] the end of
the season is coming I need to ripen up
I need to finish so that will encourage
the plants have finish it will also
encourage beautiful colors it will also
encourage more terpene production heat
and light break down terpenes so why not
make it a little bit cooler where we can
preserve a little bit more Terps I also
feel that that little bit of cold toward
the end will increase in density you
will get tighter more dense buds it also
will help reduce humidity and late in
flower we need a little bit less
humidity because we've got those big
chunky buds and we don't want to develop
bud rot in the middle of our flowers so
reducing the temperature later in flower
has many advantages I understand that
not all rooms are set up to be able to
reduce the temperature late in flower
you may be running a perpetual cycle you
just simply may not have the equipment
to get it that cool and flower it is not
a requirement it is just a little bonus
it's a little tip and trick that may
help increase aroma and color and
density and also help you avoid powdery
mildew and botrytis toward the end of
your flowering phase so that is why I
suggest reducing the temperature late in
flower we will
talk more about that as we move through
these grow lessons now let's talk about
humidity for weeks 4 5 &amp; 6
I suggest 40 percent relative humidity
we have reduced the humidity by 10
percent from last week
we don't need as much moisture in the
air we're starting to develop buds those
buds act like sponges they will gather
all of that moisture in the air which
will lead to Boyte Rytas which is our
worst nightmare when we get giant buds
in a commercial facility so let's reduce
the humidity let's get it down to about
40 percent now let's talk a little bit
about nutrients for weeks 4 5 &amp; 6 I know
I don't give detailed information when I
talk about nutrients in these grow
lessons that's because I don't know what
brand of nutrients you were using I
don't know if you're using bottles I
don't know if you're using powdered
nutrients I don't know if you're running
organics I have no idea what you have
chosen to do I can't be too specific
with the nutrient suggestions what I can
do is make sure we cover the bases and I
give you a solid foundation so here are
the things I would make sure to have in
my nutrient mix 4 weeks 4 5 &amp; 6 if you
were running bottles you need a basic
bloom nutrient you may have a bottle
that says bloom you may have a bottle
that says bloom a-and a bottle that says
bloom B those bottles are what we need
for this stage of flowering you'll
notice that those bottles have three
numbers printed on them that is an NPK
value at this stage of flowering we do
not need a lot of nitrogen we just need
a lot of nitrogen to provide energy to
the plants at this stage of flowering we
need more phosphorus and potassium than
we have previously needed in the grow so
you will see a low n number and higher P
and K value numbers on your bloom
nutrient bottles so if you're growing
with bottles hopefully your bloom base
has covered your nitrogen phosphorus and
potassium you will also need cal-mag at
this phase of the game I also recommend
enzymes and microbes I would also
introduce a kelp product to my feeding
regimen
I think kelp has a lot of great benefits
that we will talk about in a future
episode this is also a great time to
start introducing a bloom booster again
I don't know what products you're using
I don't know what brand you have
most bottled nutrients offer a very
obvious bloom booster now is the time to
start implementing that into your
feeding schedule if you really want to
provide energy to your plants you can
feed them a carbohydrate product at this
stage of flowering the carbohydrates
will give the plants energy and the
carbohydrates will also feed your
microbes if you are growing with veg
bloom powdered nutrients I would have
added shine by now I definitely would
put shine in there by week three now is
basically the time I start tapering off
the microbe products and start adding in
the bloom booster products the roots
should be big and fat and healthy by the
time the plant is done
I want that plant to be nearly root
bound so we are well on our way to
filling that pot with roots now I want
to start focusing on moving that energy
up top and making big giant buds so
through weeks four five and six I start
tapering off the microbes and I start
increasing the bloom booster product now
be careful with your bloom boosters a
lot of people want to overfeed the bloom
booster most bottled nutrient companies
have a very clear suggested dose printed
on the bottle most of the time that is
too much they want you to feed your
plants too much so that you have to buy
more of their product more frequently I
would suggest that a new grower starts
off with 50% of the recommended bloom
booster dosage the first time you add
that bloom booster to your plant feed
only put 50% of the recommended dosage
and see how the plants respond if the
plants don't show any sign of burn or
stunted growth maybe increase the
feeding just a little bit next time and
increase it until you see the leaf tips
just barely burn I like to call it
getting their nails done because it
starts to look like the end of the
fingers are just getting their
fingernails on there when you see them
starting to get their nails done that's
when you know you're pushing them to
their limit and they're just starting to
get burned you can either give them that
much again and just keep burning them
just a little bit or you can reduce it a
little bit but do not go any harder with
the bloom booster once you see the
fingernails start happening now it
sounds natural and feels natural to want
to add more bloom booster that's going
to give you bigger fatter buds that's
what everybody wants but there is a
point of diminishing returns if you add
too much it will burn the plant once the
plants begin to burn it will start to
lock
nutrients once they lock out nutrients
it will not take any of your bloom
booster then it all becomes a waste of
money and you have a shitty harvest so
don't be that guy don't over bloom boost
your plants five or six weeks into
flower and completely burn them and make
them look like [ __ ] and ruin your crop
when you've only got three weeks to go
now those are just the basic nutrients I
would recommend if you were growing from
bottled nutrients every company is going
to have other products to offer some
companies may offer a silicate product
some companies may offer a terpene
enhancer
some companies may recommend a bud
hardener I'm not sure what company you
have chosen but be careful when adding
your additives and just pay attention
when mixing make sure that your pH is
correct and tried to make note of your
EC or your PPM's if possible now if you
were growing with organics if you're
growing with super soil you have
probably mixed up your soil at the
beginning and there's not a lot you can
do to it at this point other than adding
teas or maybe adding a cover crop or
possibly a top dress to be quite honest
with you that is not my area of
expertise if you are growing organically
and you want to boost up your plants a
little bit I would probably suggest a
compost tea that included worm castings
and it would probably include some sort
of guano but again I am NOT the organic
expert I am NOT the no-till guy I am NOT
a super soil guy I honestly grow in a
commercial environment and I grow from
bottle and powdered nutrients most of
the advice and guidance that I give you
on this show will be based on bottled or
powdered nutrients so I feel like that
covers the basics of nutrients for weeks
4 5 &amp; 6 basically we want to give them a
solid NPK a little bit of cal-mag some
enzymes some microbes some carbs I would
introduce kelp I would introduce a bloom
booster and basically at this point I
would start reducing the microbe
products and I would start replacing the
microbes with a bloom booster product
over the next couple of weeks all right
now I feel like we know what type of
environment to keep these plants in I
feel like we know how to feed them we
know what's going on in the grow now
what can we do to these plants to
increase production what can we do to
make sure they stay healthy and pest
free all the way up to the end of the
flowering cycle one thing we need to
keep in mind is that we need to be very
soul
effective on sprays this late in Flour I
would prefer not to spray anything at
all on these plants but if we do run
into issues there are very limited
options of products we can use to spray
on these plants so let's do our best at
this point to keep bugs out of the grow
room we should already be implementing
an integrated pest management system
which includes a spray rotation and
possible release of predator bugs
I would also avoid going to other
gardens if you have friends that grow I
would stay away from their grow
I would also never take anybody else
into my grow especially other friends
that grow you are inviting their spider
mites right into your garden also change
clothes if you go to another grow if you
work in a commercial grow and have a
private grow at home change clothes
between those grows I would also
recommend changing clothes between stops
at the gross store and going to your
garden don't go straight from the hydro
shop to your garden you are picking [ __ ]
up at the gross store all day long all
of the dirty growers are going there all
the soil is being shipped there that is
a hotbed for pests don't take your pests
from the gross store right to your
garden I would also recommend a
dedicated pair of shoes for the garden
or for the grow room if you work in
multiple facilities I would have a pair
of shoes for the grow at work I would
have a pair of shoes that I wore after
work then I would have a different pair
of shoes that I put on to go in my
personal garden also if you have an
outdoor grow and an indoor grow change
clothes and shoes between those Gardens
it sounds really tedious and it sounds
like overkill but we do not want to
spread spider mites from one Garden to
another the most obvious and easy way
for mites to spread is for them to
travel on a grower so let's do our best
as responsible growers as responsible
farmers to not spread spider mites to
our other grows and to our friends grows
it's pretty easy to get rid of spider
mites early in flower and veg but it is
a pain in the ass to get rid of spider
mites late in bloom so let's not drag
them into the bloom room if you do have
multiple rooms or multiple facilities
and you do find a pest issue in one area
treat that area as a contaminated space
notify everybody that works there hey
there are spider mites in here don't go
in here unless it is required then if
you do have to go in that area make sure
you change clothes before entering
another grow area and carrying those
spider mites throughout the facility
with you if you have one room that is
not infested with mites and you have
another room that is infested with mites
work on the cleanroom first when you get
to work do all the work that needs to be
done in there close that room up and be
done then go to that spider mite room do
your work in there and then when you're
done leave the grow facility remove your
clothes clean them put them in the
laundry and don't take those dirty
clothes back into that cleanroom work on
the cleanroom first then work on the
dirty rooms last so that we don't drag
those spider mites into the room that is
clean and if you know that one room is
contaminated and you have to go in there
I would almost suggest a lab coat or a
Tyvek suit that you can swap between
rooms if you've got to go into the
meited room throw on the lab coat throw
on the Tyvek suit go into the spider
matted room do what you need to do come
out of that room remove the lab coat or
Tyvek suit replace it with a fresh lab
coat or Tyvek suit and then go into the
room that you need to work in next again
I know this sounds tedious I know this
sounds like overkill but imagine if
you've got 500 plants in one room and
you're expecting to harvest over a
hundred pounds and we distract spider
mites into their from the other room now
we've got one room that is almost ready
to harvest and we've been fighting
spider mites it's almost gone we're
almost through that battle but guess
what you just walked into the other room
and we're five weeks into flower and you
just dropped a spider mite bomb in there
because you were lazy and didn't bother
to change your lab coat small problems
are small problems when there are small
problems but when we go to a large scale
cultivation facility a very small
problem will multiply overnight those
spider mites are going to have a party
when we turn off the lights and
everybody goes home you will come in the
next morning and now it is spider mite
world so let's do our best to not
introduce spider mites to the grow
because we are very limited on plans of
attack to get rid of those mites in this
point of the game there are very limited
sprays we can apply one thing we can do
we can release predator bugs now if you
are planning ahead
part of your integrated pest management
system did include ordering creditor
bugs to be released early in Flour
hopefully around week three you released
an army of predator bugs so now if any
spider mites do show up those predators
are already colonized they're already
there claiming their turf and no spider
mites will start infesting your grow now
if you didn't get those predator bugs in
there early it is not too late to order
predators to come attack your spider
mite infestation but you need to act
quickly don't say I'll order them Monday
when you see spider mites in the grow
order those predator mites today when
that box of predator mites comes you
need to stop what you were doing and
release those bugs into the garden
immediately we need to win the war we
need to release our troops to get in
there and destroy those spider mites
that are sucking the juices out of our
plants they are destroying our potency
and they are diminishing our yields we
need to get rid of them immediately so
if it's too late to spray I highly
suggest you order predator bugs order
more than you think you need we want a
large army to get in there and wipe out
the infestation as quickly as possible
now earlier I did say we are very
limited on the products we can spray to
our plants this late in Flour there are
a few beneficial fungus based products
that can be applied to the plants this
late in flower that will not affect the
taste if you understand the products you
were using you can apply a sprayed
pesticide and you can release predators
and they will work together the proper
pesticide at this stage of the game will
not harm your flowers and it will not
kill your predators again I do not
suggest spraying plants with bulky
flowers but sometimes something has to
be done we do have a few spray
application options do not spray
anything oil-based this late in flower
it will ruin the flavor and aroma of
your plants the only things I would
recommend to spray this late in flower
would be beneficial fungus type products
I would never apply an oil this late in
flower and I don't even want to spray
them unless it is absolutely necessary
I would rather release the Predators
and let them do their thing but I
understand sometimes you're going to go
into panic mode sometimes it's more than
what the Predators can handle sometimes
you may have already purchased the
pesticide and you don't have funding to
order insects I do understand that
things come up in a garden and life does
happen and we can't always control
things one thing we can do from this
situation is take note we can try to
understand how did we get spider mites
and how can we prevent this from
happening next time so it is time to
stop spraying the plants it is also time
to stop running the sulfur burner if
you've got a sulfur burner in your grow
turn that [ __ ] off it is making your
plants taste terrible it is making your
concentrates taste terrible let's stop
using sulfur burners in the grow and
let's start correcting the true issue
what is causing the powdery mildew
people use sulfur to prevent and cure
powdery mildew how about we find the
cause instead of burning sulfur in the
room and making the room smell like [ __ ]
making your bud smell like [ __ ] making
your concentrates smell like [ __ ] making
the final product completely taste like
[ __ ]
let's find out what's causing that
powdery mildew and cure that instead of
just burning sulfur in the room now I
know a lot of people have a sulphur
burner and that is their method that's
how they learn that's what they're going
to do they're not going to stop doing it
because I said so let's compromise if
you insist on using a sulfur burner in
your garden perhaps you can stop using
it around week three or around week four
when those buds start popping up earlier
in the episode I suggested reducing
humidity perhaps reducing that humidity
a little bit will help prevent that
powdery mildew since we're getting the
fat buds we need to reduce humidity
anyway let's get it a little cooler
reduce humidity and stop burning that
sulfur and I'm sure the product will
taste better if you've ever smoked to
concentrate the taste of like fish or
fish oil a lot of the times that is
because there was a sulphur burner being
used in the room during the flowering
phase so no more sprays and no more
sulfur burners after week three please
so now that we are approaching week four
it is time to reduce some of the
physical stress we have been performing
to the plants I still want to do some
popping and twisting and I still want to
work them into the Nets
but I don't want to go as hard and as
Extreme as I was before I want to allow
these plants to use their energy on
producing buds now and not recovering
from all the popping and breaking and
not being stressed out I want them to
just focus on making fat chunky buds and
sweet trichomes for me so I'm going to
reduce the stress a little bit that
doesn't mean I'm gonna stop beating them
up but I am going to mellow out just a
little bit on these girls so we're gonna
reduce the stress we're gonna do a
little less popping and twisting but we
are still going to pop and twist the
stems we're also going to continue
working these plants into the trellis if
you've got a trellis net and you've got
a plant that's taken off getting too
tall don't be afraid to grab that one
crack the stem and work it right back
under the net the star of week 4 is also
a good time to do our final bottoming
we've got those little bud sets showing
we know where the buds are gonna be if
you've got a stick with a bunch of
little tiny shitty buds on it just clean
those little popcorn balls right on off
and leave that stuff at the end of the
branch to develop into a nice chunky bud
in a previous episode I talked about
taking off all those little tiny sucker
buds you can leave the thick branches
but those little buds that grow off the
base of that branch toward the bottom
those can get cut off if they're just a
waste of space and energy and they're
not going to produce anything except
their pain in the ass
you can cut those right off of the plant
some growers like to say that's what I
was going to make concentrate out of
that's what I was going to make my
edibles out of that's fine if you want
to leave that there I feel like if you
cut that stuff off that doesn't get a
lot of light you take that energy and
you move it right up to the top of the
plant instead of the plant feeding those
twelve little tiny [ __ ] buds at the
bottom it can just put that energy right
up at the top where it's getting light I
can use that energy to make that top
Cola that much beefier that much fatter
and it also sucks to trim that bottom
stuff nobody wants to trim those little
popcorn buds nobody wants to waste time
cutting that off and if you can cut
something off to make something better
why wouldn't you do it so now is a good
time to go do a final bottoming just
clean up that messy crap on the bottom
that's not going to turn into any usable
bud now I also like to do a light
defoliation at this point any leaf with
a purple petiole will get taken off at
this point in time so if you've got a
big leaf it's got a purple stem you can
see that long purple stem just go ahead
and break that off break that
I'm off as close to the branch as close
to the butt as you can so you don't
leave that little stand there with
moisture hanging out just break that
stem right off get those leaves out of
the room we don't need all the excessive
leaves so anything with the purple stem
I'll go kind of light I'll do one layer
I'll look at the room I'll say yeah I
can do more and then I'll go back and
take off more leaves and then I'll stand
back and look into the room and I just
try to make sure that I've gotten all
the giant leaves that are blocking the
light from hitting the buds if there if
I can see light coming down and it's
hitting a leaf and I can clearly see
that that leaf is hanging over a bud
site I will remove that leave so that
bud site can get the light now a lot of
old-school growers are going to tell you
don't remove the leaves because that's
where the nutrients and sugars are
stored but I'm pretty sure earlier in
this episode we talked about feeding
these plants a whole bunch of nutrients
there's not really a reason for these
plants to store nutrients we are feeding
the [ __ ] out of them these are high
performance plants that are going to get
a high performance meal every day they
don't need that stored stuff we can pull
those leaves off those leaves will give
us opportunity for powdery mildew those
leaves are places for pests to hide
those leaves have to come off when we
trim anyway why not take those leaves
off now and save us the trouble
now don't go extreme and make the plants
naked take off the leaves with the giant
pea Deol's
and the leaves that are in the way this
is kind of intimidating for new growers
and honestly this is an art and a skill
that you will have to develop over time
a good way to practice defoliating and
seeing what happens to the plants is to
get four plants of the same thing so
you've got four clones of let's say
golden go you got four golden goat
plants they're all in the same room
they're all in the same environment why
not defoliate one really hard defoliate
one kind of hard be fully eight one a
little bit and then don't be fully eight
the other one at all then take pictures
if you can and take as many notes as you
can and then keep an eye on those notes
and pictures and see which plant came
out the best did the plant that you left
alone come out the best did the plant
that we beat to [ __ ] and almost made it
naked come out the best or was it the
one that's right in the middle it's
going to be strange specific on how hard
you want to go with defoliation but most
strains will benefit from a medium
defoliation and they will definitely
benefit from
removing all those super large leaves
that are blocking your bud sites now if
you go too hard your plants will look
naked and the growth will stop you'll
just slow them down so don't go
extremely hard on your first defoliation
kind of practice going there and pull
off some leaves I like to say this in
the podcast all the time you can take
more off but you can never glue those
leaves back on so pull a few off take a
step back look at it see what you think
if you want to take off more get in
there and take them off if you're
intimidated by it leave the leaves there
one thing I will suggest is that if a
leaf is yellow or funky you remove it
don't hesitate and don't be shy
to take down the ugly leaves those need
to go those yellow leaves are
invitations for pests a spider mite will
see a yellow leaf and they will head
right to that leaf because it is weak
the outer layer isn't as thick and
crunchy so that spider mite can get its
shitty little fangs right through that
skin and it can get right in there and
start sucking the juice it doesn't have
to deal with that thick healthy plant
flesh so get rid of those yellow leaves
and remove them from the garden as soon
as possible something else I would
suggest at this point in flowering is to
increase air flow it may be a good time
to add some fans to the room if you
don't have an oscillating fan in the
room now is the time we want those
leaves rustling we don't want those buds
sitting still and letting stagnant air
build up in those buds now we don't want
the plants being bent over and getting
[ __ ] whipped by the fan all day we just
want every leaf to rustle occasionally
you just want that fan to pass by and
just give those leaves just a little
rustle just move the air around just
stir the air just so that nothing can
get still just move that air I just keep
doing this motion with my hand like you
guys can see me just move in that air
but like I said earlier our buds are
going to start developing they're going
to start getting fat and chunky those
buds work like sponges if there's too
much moisture in the air that moisture
will get trapped inside those buds then
we'll start getting bud mold inside the
bud if you've got a fan moving that air
and moisture around that will reduce the
opportunities for bud mold now that
you're adding fans you may need to add
some sticks or some sort of cages for
supports if you're not using a trellis
net your buds are going to start
toppling over
let's not wait till weeks five and six
when those buds are big and chunky and
sticky and they're falling over trying
to break the sticks let's get some
steaks let's get some tomato cages let's
start supporting these plants early if
you've got a big long branch and you can
tell that it's going to turn into a
giant bud go ahead and stick a long
steak into the pot stick it into the
soil try not to cut up too many of the
roots it's going to happen
I understand but shove that steak
straight into the soil get that stick
straight up sticking where you need it
then use a twisty tie or a zip tie or
something gentle to just gently attach
that top elyse stick to that branch you
don't want to squeeze that branch at all
it needs to be loose so that you don't
pinch that branch you want some freedom
in there but you don't want it flopping
around too much don't pinch or crush or
squeeze the branch at all be very gentle
so use a few steaks and stick them in
the dirt and have them sticking straight
up and attach those floppy branches to
those steaks as needed don't be shy I've
seen people use a [ __ ] ton of steaks in
each pot if that's what you've got to do
that's what you've got to do to keep
that plant upright so get some sticks or
get some tomato cages and be prepared to
start supporting your plants I hope your
buds get so chunky that those plants
just want to fall right over that's what
I hope for you but I also hope you've
got some sticks or a tomato cage on hand
so that those plants don't die when that
[ __ ] starts happening so we've got some
airflow we've got some sticks on our
plants another thing we need to focus on
is to continue scouting for pests and
p.m. just because we're this late and
flower doesn't mean that problems can't
arise
keep your eyes open for pests and
powdery mildew and boy try this now
while we're scouting for pass and boy
Titus we also need to pay attention to
plant problems do you see any nutrient
burn do you see any pH issues pay
attention to the leaves a few crunchy
leaves here and there that's acceptable
a few shitty leaves low in the canopy
that's acceptable if you start getting
large clusters of shitty looking leaves
you've got a problem that needs to be
addressed hopefully you were taking
notes of what you've been feeding the
plant
hopefully you've got some kind of record
of what the pH was that was going into
the plants and maybe you've even been
taking notes of what is coming out of
the plants have you been measuring the
EC and pH of your runoff
if so that will help you diagnose
problems if a problem should arise now
while you're scouting for pests and
while you're looking for nutrient issues
also don't forget about all of the
equipment in the grow room just do some
visual inspections while you're walking
through the room listen look you may
notice things always be paying attention
to the plants and the equipment while
you're in the grow now while you're
looking around for equipment problems
you're looking around for pests and
we're also looking around for yellow
leaves we still need to keep our eyes
out for hermaphrodites if you are
growing from seed it is still an
opportunity to reveal hermaphroditic
traits this far into flower so keep your
eyes out for her flowers and I think
we've talked a little bit in a previous
episode about what to do if you do
discover a hermaphroditic plant this
late into flower you've got several
options you can pull out the flowers you
can cut off the main bud that's got the
male flowers on it you can cut down the
whole plant or you can choose to ignore
the immediate threat and you can keep an
eye on that male flower and see if it
opens and drops pollen just keep in mind
that if you do see male flowers you do
run the risk of having pollen in that
grow room and at this point of flowering
those female plants are really eager to
receive that pollen and create seeds so
keep your eye open because it is not too
late to find hermaphrodites in fact that
is always the case keep your eyes open
through the entire grow on your first or
second run with the new cultivar or if
you're growing from seed all right
podcast world this episode is starting
to get long so let's start recapping and
start wrapping up the episode let's
recap week 4 and week 4 we are going to
continue working the plants into the
Nets we're going to continue popping and
twisting we're going to bottom the
plants a little more and now is the time
to put on sticks or tomato cages we need
to reduce the stress of the plants and
start letting the buds develop but we
still need to work the plants and pop
the stems and be foliate a little bit
then we'll work into week five that is
what we're going to do our final
bottoming we need to finish bottling the
plants by the end of week five we will
do our final popping and twisting then
we're going to let the plants just
settle in and develop buds we will do
our final major defoliation we will
continue to lightly be fully through
harvest
but this is the last big defoliation we
will do we will also pull all of the
shitty leaves we'll take off all the
small popcorn buds any branches that
don't look like they're worth the [ __ ]
will get taken out at this time now is
the last chance to get supports on these
buds if you don't have some sticks or
some tomato cages in there now by week
five you are going to see problems in
week six or plants are going to start
toppling over so now is the time to get
in there and make sure you've got sticks
and some sort of twisty tie or something
like that holding your buds up it is
also time to increase air flow we are
going to start gettin chunky buds so if
you don't have the air flow moving now
is the time to do it we also need a
carbon filter in week four I forgot to
recap that we need that carbon filter I
feel like I covered that very well now
in week six we are going to need that
air flow you better have those sticks
and supports done we are done bottoming
we are done working we are done cracking
popping and twisting these plants it is
time to let them grow and let the buds
get fat staying on top of scouting for
problems we need to look for bugs we
need to look for powdery mildew we need
to look for hermaphrodites we also need
to pay attention to environmental
nutrient or pH stresses and if we see
anything caused by those things we need
to adjust accordingly now my favorite
part about weeks five and six this is
when the good photos happen those buds
are starting to get chunky the buds are
nice and fluffy all of the pistols are
still nice and white all the leaves are
still lush and green now is a great time
to start taking photos so that is my
favorite part of week six
so when week four you got little nugs
you've got those little popcorn balls
developing then in week five you're
starting to get actual buds you can see
the buds growing up the stick they're
starting to get chunky then in week six
you actually start developing photogenic
colas it's time to get in there and
start taking pictures you're seeing some
beef you're starting to get some good
colors the trichomes are coming in week
six is when it really starts getting
exciting now the thing to think about is
keeping these plants healthy pest free
problem free all the way till the end
keep yourself out of trouble don't brag
don't start posting photos just yet if
you do take a sweet-ass photo in week
six I suggest you save it until harvest
then start flooding the pictures out
after Harv
that way nobody knows when you're
cutting down your crop that's just kind
of a wheat grower trick from back in the
day another thing to start thinking
about is is the next run ready we're
going to harvest these plants in two to
four weeks depending on your strain do
you have plants lined up for the next
run do you have clones that are getting
rooted have you ordered seeds are you
prepared for the next run we don't want
to miss any time so let's get on top of
the next run that feels like a great
opportunity to pitch my seed vendor if
you need some seeds I highly recommend
the he'll a dank seed company and you
can find them at www.pedestrians.org
we'll be right there on the screen
again that's patreon.com/lenguin
campaign it will explain exactly what I
intend to do with the funding that I
received from my contributors there is
also a list of rewards or services which
I will provide for my patreon
contributors so check it out see if
anything gets your attention and I would
appreciate your support also big thank
you in a giant shout out to everybody
who's contributed to the patreon
campaign in the past I truly do
appreciate all of the love and support I
would also appreciate it if you find me
on social media you can find the podcast
on Twitter simply search for @gf wih
podcast if you'd like to follow my
personal Twitter account it's at Rasta
Jeff 420
give me a follow I also think you would
enjoy my Instagram feed on Instagram I
use my seed company name it's Irie
underscore genetics iri e underscore
genetics check out my fine cannabis
photography and come join me in my
Instagram live feeds I hang out on
Instagram live I answer grow questions I
take dad's sometimes it gets silly it's
always a lot of fun I encourage you to
join us that's ireon Durst or genetics
on Instagram don't forget about the
webstore if you're interested in an IRA
genetics
grow from your heart t-shirt or hoodie
or an Irie army t-shirt or perhaps you
want a Rasta Jeff sticker those are
available on my website the website is
Irie genetics Colorado calm just click
on the high restore you'll be taken
right to the store where you can grab a
t-shirt you can grab a hoodie or you can
get some fresh new stickers don't forget
that the podcast is available on iTunes
stitcher Google Play and every episode
is now available on the YouTube channel
just search for the drove from your
heart podcast find the show on YouTube
click Subscribe and leave some comments
on the videos I do love the interaction
ladies and gentlemen that is all I've
got for you this week I'll be back
Thursday with another mic episode then
I'll be back Monday with another grow
lesson we will focus on week 7 through 9
of flowering our plants I want to thank
you guys again for listening to the
podcast I want to give you huge shout
out to my friend James but ursin and
until next time take a phat dab and give
your mom a hug for me