welcome back everybody it's time for
episode 384 of the growth from your
heart podcast this episode is brought to
you by the hella dank seed company if
you need new seeds for your garden I
highly recommend the hella dank seed
company and you can find them at
www.sedar.com i letting you know what
i'm smoking today I've been taking dad's
of Wi-Fi and Broza from apothecary farms
I picked this up at the Pueblo location
the label says it is eighty two point
five percent THC with the total of
ninety five point seven percent total
cannabinoids I really enjoy this
concentrate I generally like to buy a
concentrate they lifts me up it makes my
head kind of spin it makes me super high
this Wi-Fi is the exact opposite this
was like a punch in the face and made me
sit back in the chair made my eyes super
heavy it made my body nice and heavy
this is some chilling out medicine this
is some nighttime medicines is probably
if you've got some super heavy pain this
would probably knock your pain out if
you're just trying to get nice and
stoned and nice and mellow this would be
a perfect get stoned and sink into the
couch kind of concentrate so big up to
the Wi-Fi ambrosia and a big shout-out
to our friends at apothecary farms in
Pueblo all right podcast world last
Thursday I had Mike on the show and we
talked about the farm bill Mike was
super fired up and wanted to talk all
night so I left the microphones on we
kept talking for a really long time I
only posted the first 36 minutes of the
conversation that Mike and I had last
week so this episode will be the
remainder of that conversation before we
get into the rest of the podcast make
sure you follow mike on twitter it's at
Nemo Punk 15 also make sure you support
Mike on Facebook find his Facebook page
it is pueblo for sensible cannabis laws
ladies and gentlemen boys and girls
smokers and growers
let's welcome white Mike back to the
show we've got a very good friend who
checks on my Instagram live feeds he
sends me some emails he's a really good
supporter of the girl from her podcast
he's on the Huayra army he asked us what
is a good way that he can support
cannabis legalization in his area he's
kind of a business he person he needs to
maintain anonymity to say that work for
me anonymity anonymity say thank you
I've never tried to say that I did not I
didn't snap a picture of the comment
because it was an Instagram live but it
was something the effect of how do I
keep the corporate suit and tie job in a
prohibition state and still fight to
legalize cannabis yes and the answer is
very carefully
I I've been where you are now
and I remember being in it started
oddly enough I pulled the [ __ ] topic
out of the Hat in seventh grade debate
we did this the class project where you
write down the top I can throw it in the
Hat and then you pull out the topic and
you pull you have to [ __ ] debate
whatever side of the argument you pull
all that I'm Devon he's gonna take a
damp I was just about that so you had
debate class in school and was cannabis
you're not cannabis was the subject that
you had to debate worse ok worse I had
to I had to be the the pro used
marijuana while you're pregnant
that was that was my argument that's a
whole nother podcast I tried to get some
ladies to come on the show and talk
about that and nobody wanted to come on
the show so hey ladies if you're out
there and you'd like to be on a podcast
talk about using cannabis during
pregnancy pros and cons I like to find
one lady who was Pro while lady was con
then maybe with some medical profession
they could come on to talk about that
well maybe uh that OBGYN is that who I
need to talk about that the pregnancy
doctor you wanted them to come on tell
me what you think they're gonna say no
but still want their presence just for
their voice you'll CNN then every time
they get John I'll just turn them their
[ __ ] mind but like I do when Mike's
coffin just like that just shut off his
mic there we go like I'm trying to
ramble on cuz you're purple and your
sweaty and you're coughing but
eventually the listeners are gonna catch
on that I'm just [ __ ] talking out of
my ass so that you can cost a couple
seconds ago oh how do for our friend how
do so brought this story up is because
I've been forced to debate this topic
since long before I was comfortable with
it so take your time bro take your time
I'm just trolling
like it wasn't a totally high story the
dab came at a bad time he's really
purple he's really as purple that was a
little bad - I'm sorry it was a I was
worried about it being too cold because
I've kind of gunked-up the nee of the
night doing too cold went a little hot
but that first experience with debating
cannabis taught me a couple of really
useful things one the real trick to
debating any topic is doing your
research
- if you take a controversial topic and
decide to stand up and talk about it be
prepared to get a lot of people laughing
at you
and that's just something that you have
to take from the first like there's a
famous quote I don't I think it's gone -
you're something that's like first they
laugh at you like first they ignore you
then they laugh at you then they fight
you then you win
but like the laughing is a long time
usually and if you go back to like and
there will always be lappers well for
sure but if you go back to like 96 98
2000 and look at how cannabis advocates
even advocates from like the National
Organization for the Reform of Marijuana
Laws normal when they're heavy-hitting
lawyers would go give press releases or
put out statements or talk to the press
the anchor would be laughing in their
face and it's like this is a lawyer they
have a degree from a good university
they have 20 years experience in our
field this is an educated informed
opinion you're just laughing at them but
we've passed that point in history now
so even if like as long as you're in the
US this is true depending on which
country you're listening from this might
not be very true for you hopefully it's
truer than it was ten years ago
but as far as the u.s. goes if you start
talking about pro-legalization topics in
an informed manner you're not going to
get met with laughter and
more you'll still get ignored and people
will fight you but the laughter is
pretty much gone and that's because a
lot of what's not funny
has been made abundantly clear over time
the disparities and arrest rates what
the black market is capable of doing
with 30 or 40 billion a year it's an
amount of money that's almost
inconceivable there's a good meme going
around that's like the difference
between a million seconds in a billion
seconds like one's like 11 hours and the
other ones like 30 days like I got all
of those numbers wrong but if you look
it up the disparity is huge
and it's it's so big that most people
don't understand how big it is and that
amount of money in the black market like
the cosmetics industry all make ups only
35 billion it's huge and all of that's
underground and the amount of people
that employ is the amount of disputes
that creates the amount of taxes that
could get paid on all that like all of
those are things that people kind of
understand at least a little bit now and
I started doing this none of that should
exist it we do not have the seem to sail
model we didn't have any nothing you
have examples yeah when we were talking
about legalizing marijuana five six
years ago here in Colorado people were
like what does that look like blank
stares were all anyone had I mean anyone
in the room the Moses model we had was
the medical marijuana dispensary models
that were starting here and in
California well one of the biggest
problems Kali's had this year is they
ignored their medical market from 96 to
late 2015 and in all that time the
market didn't ignore it itself
it grew evolved changed fell apart got
raided rebuilt itself countless times
and now that they finally has tried to
settle down and regulate and license
this whole kind of giant monster that
they've ignored for twenty years it's
nearly impossible with all the
grandfathering in and you know how can
this place not meet the new rules
they've been open for twenty years
the Mayor was there ribbon cutting we
love these people how can they be
illegal now right there's a lot of that
right now and it all has to do is get
just ignoring it and so the upside for
people still living in prohibition land
is by now even in places like Arkansas
Texas Tennessee Virginia there are
already legislature members of the
legislature the state Senate governors
City Council people actively talking
about marijuana legalization even the
ones that are against it are currently
thinking about if it happens anyway how
do we mitigate [ __ ] like duis and tina
access and advertising and stuff like
that and so they're already willing to
have a conversation that they weren't
willing to even think about five seven
years ago well they know it's coming it
was it's gonna happen around them one
day if they're ready for it or not yep
the other big upside to this is you're
no longer the squeaky wheel like all of
the wheels are squeaking 60 to 70%
statistically so for someone who has a
job that they want to protect or a life
they want to protect to send an email to
an elected representative to say hi I'm
a voter and I would like you to support
the legalization of cannabis and one way
or another medical access whatever the
topic is in your area to send that email
is not opening yourself up to any sort
of blowback these people receive a
million emails a month I think that the
amount of Correspondence they get from
constituents and people around the
country is just bananas make them
another email address if you don't want
to use it's a hundred percent simply not
to create your own
yep and it's real easy to make you look
like a legitimate human being when
you're not because there's not an
investigative portion to sending your
governor and email that says vote for
legal cannabis now if you send an email
that's like I'm gonna eat you and you
know tomorrow or I'm gonna have to set
your house on fire or oh you better look
out different [ __ ] story yeah don't
do this a bunch of investigative people
that will look into your [ __ ] but if you
send an email that says my state's not
currently looking at legalization anyway
I would love for you to be the elected
representative in our area to lead on
this issue or I'd like you to vote for
something that somebody else is
proposing you can do all of that without
any sort of fear of reprisal at this
point and people from all over the
country do it like I email people that
aren't my elected representative at
least twice a month 2019 is going to be
huge for cannabis all sorts of states
that don't have any sort of good
cannabis laws right now they're talking
about doing it by the by legislature
because they're scared the public's
gonna do it without them and they want
to get ahead and get out in front of it
so there's like already 100 or 200
cannabis bills up for debate in the
coming year that we know about already
nice I'm so odds are that the person
that asked this question and thousands
like him are in a place where cannabis
is already being debated and so joining
that conversation through email or a
phone call to your elected
representative s your company has
business before the City Council or your
County Commission or whatever governs
the area you live in
that they don't follow that news so
unless you go and make a bunch of noise
the odds that anyone outside of that
room hears your message is pretty slim
those are televised those are not public
TV I wouldn't do that I had a couple of
fun instances where old family friends
might
ads that live in the next city up the
highway would watch our City Council
meetings for some reason in Sami and
called him and we're like your kids on
TV and some old people don't have
anything to do
yeah it's cable access so it is one of
the free channels but the odds that your
boss is watching that and that's gonna
blow back on you are slimmer the other
option there is there's even if you go
talk publicly there isn't in my
experience anyone confirming that you're
really Jeff and so you can go sign up is
Jeff you can go sign up it's Paul as
long as you're not like Elvis Presley
pitch like they're not gonna check it
they're not even gonna care um the guy
that had to type in the names that would
pop up on the TV screen while you spoke
always used to give me [ __ ] because just
out of nervousness I would give another
version of my name every time I went up
and so he never knew if I was gonna say
my first in my last my first my middle
my last my middle in my last if I was
gonna add the junior it's gonna that's
why people are like how many [ __ ]
names does Mike Evitts cuz he's a junior
so sometimes throw out the first name
and the last sometimes he skips it and
goes with the middle and the last say
both confuse me the first time you said
first the real name I was like wait
you're Oulu it made me laugh there's a
couple of the people that were trying to
fight our local cannabis rate rags
really thought I was three people like
they thought there was yeah all of my
different names that I had happened to
use on camera were different people they
were like their brothers they all looked
very similar like I think only one of
those got earrings and a different one
wears glasses
oh you [ __ ] are just bad could I only
know two of the names so I'm [ __ ]
lost on the third one and it's [ __ ]
awesome yeah I was like Mike Michael
okay there's a lot of variation the
other guy you had to type in the names
would always kind of give him you look
like like I had it when you walked up I
typed it in though the one you use and
now it's different I had two on a fly
strike on you mr. pink yeah ba you don't
have to to even really give your legal
name there another
and that I've actually had people do in
different campaigns is the official
campaign will write a number of op eds
or letters to the editor so like
Charlotte's gonna vote on marijuana and
we think you should for these reasons
proud of myself I wrote letters to the
editor instead of releasing that letter
to the editor is like from the weed
corporation they have it go out as like
from some random person yeah and it
appears in the paper is like from Bob
Huxtable and that's just how it prints
up in the paper I see this all the time
on all sorts of different topics like
I'll I'll know the person that submitted
it or know of them in the language in
the article is something that they're
not capable of clearly you're submitting
this on behalf of someone else yeah but
that's another thing to feel free to
write in a letter to the editor and you
can submit it under whatever name you
want make sure your whatever submitting
it on doesn't include your tagline at
the bottom on all your emails because
that would be awkward sent from roster
Jeff's iPhone right but I mean there's a
bunch of different ways you can stay
anonymous you can contribute financially
to different campaigns dude are you
reading my [ __ ] notes no this is my
thunder bro good ways to help the cause
anonymously you can have one-to-one
conversations or huge like people would
get really offended a couple years back
when the comparison between the the
cannabis legalization movement and the
gay rights movements were being made but
the part of that argument that I always
that always really rang true to me was
its the one-to-one conversations with
people they really end a lot of the
nonsense stigma that society's thrown at
the topic and I know personally that
sitting down with my anti cannabis
family members and being like hey why do
you care
do you see me right you heard like it
clearly hasn't ruined my brain it hasn't
[ __ ] up my future it hasn't made me
anti-social none of the [ __ ] they taught
you in school was true it was all alive
you can see the lie in motion right now
it's just the the stigma just melts away
and so family members that were
staunchly anti-cannibalism those
one-to-one conversations if you're not
really up for those you can always just
submit letters to the editor in their
favorite newspaper and newspapers are
dying for content and they hate having
to pay people for it and so we send them
letters for free that take up ad space
as long as you follow whatever one or
two rules they have and your letter it's
not insane they'll print it so if you're
talking about I think we should legalize
weed a hundred percent that letter is
gonna get printed as long as you don't
use curse words and you stick to their
word limit that's all you got to do
there you go maybe even pass them if
they have a word let me go read some of
the articles that do get pretty super
easy gonna use that as a template okay
so go to any go to any newspaper on
their website click on the opinion
section there will be letters to the
editor tab and there will be an easy tab
that tells you would you like to submit
a letter to the editor and if you click
on it tells you everything you need to
know some of them even bring up a little
pop-up box for you to write it and
passion to there I'll show you that
actors remaining yep or they'll give you
an email email address that you can
submit it to if you do that little box
where it lets you submit it copy it and
paste it to a note file and save it and
if they don't publish it send it back in
a week stay on [ __ ] I always recommend
writing those in a different different
program oh yeah word or Google Docs
wherever you're using
cuz they'd so that you can spell check
and grammar check and all that thing
disappears occasionally your web browser
will refresh and your damn writing is
gone but almost all of them have an
email address where you can email their
opinion letter editor
and they just yep this this guy didn't
say any bad words he's not advocating
genocide he's under 250 words goes in
the print file print print every week
they go how much Phil do we need alright
that's one two three four five six
letters to the editor this week there
you go top six off the stack and print
them um it might take a couple of weeks
but they print a lot of those I've had
twenty letters to the editor printed
over my life yeah and I know when
they're you I know when I see them click
it and now almost all of those were
printed under my name but it's it's
really not as difficult or scary as you
think it is and there's a lot options I
see the one you've underlined repeatedly
do you want to go ahead and do that one
well vote that's the most obvious way
you can do your part to help legalize
chemistry oh and vote yeah vote that's
I've learned over the past few years I
think you and our other friend Wade you
encouraged me very strongly to become a
voter and it feels good to [ __ ] you
know they made it super easy now a
little piece of paper comes to your
house you unfold it you ask him to help
you and then he explains [ __ ] and you go
google it to make sure your friends not
full of [ __ ] and you realize that Mike
pretty much knows what he's talking
about you could just believe in him I
like you when people chat fact-check me
oh yeah well I mean because some of the
wording I'm like wait wait wait like
that a lot of times it's designed to be
tricky yeah so I'd call you I'm like he
explained these three words in a row
does that mean that I am or again I am
NOT up to I don't know if I like this or
hate it but dude voting's huge in I've
said it before and I've said it again if
even half of the people that consume
cannabis every year took a minute to
come out publicly and say we're Pro
cannabis so we vote we would be the most
powerful voting bloc in the United
States we outnumber everybody everybody
but people like our friend who sent us
the message they maybe they kids a huge
a huge majority of them to risk and
voting booth is private and that little
ballot that comes in the mail is private
I dropped mine off in a little box and
there were like 10 cars in front of me
and 10 cars behind me bro that they have
no idea which one was mine unless they
could tell that I was the heavy-handed
mother [ __ ] grim one than that but
there's no they don't know who sent that
in
I used to have a weird like my life has
always been kind of segmented in like
weird chunks and for a while one of
those chunks involved fancy dinners with
governors Supreme Court justices in
Colorado Senate members house
representative members the [ __ ]
governor and I would be the table was
like the district attorney and our two
state senators from from Pueblo and
there'd be eight of us at the table we
don't be chit-chatting and these were
great opportunities for me to just
randomly mention pro cannabis things and
I was always delighted because
especially with our two senators they
always had cannabis questions for me
they were they knew I would be there
they knew I was gonna be at their table
and they had to that they wanted answers
to and they knew I was a person comes to
you and that was after several of these
dinners but you might not have that kind
of peace in your life but you everyone
has a peace in their life where you can
take good informed supported cannabis
knowledge and disseminated to people
that need it find those opportunities
and take advantage of them I know people
in the medical field
that have transformed how the department
they work with or the doctor's office
they work in views cannabis views
cannabis consumers views medical
marijuana all because they had a very
uncomfortable conversation with their
boss at one point and slowly started
bringing in information and watch their
workplace convert from anti cannabis to
pro cannabis this certainly isn't
possible for everybody and then honestly
if you're making real money I wouldn't
[ __ ] with my paychecks just to be pro
we'd use a piece of that paycheck to
fight for the cost for you that leads to
another thing I don't know if you can
see the little sloppily written dollar
sign that I've got written down here my
my methods of helping be an activist
behind the scenes but contribute
financially to activism um if it is not
this person actually contributes to the
podcast through patreon
so do things like that also contribute
to your local cannabis legalization
efforts or also the National
legalization if it's local if it's
statewide if occasionally you've got a
normal chapter in your state I was gonna
say anybody was specific but go with
normal they're always reliable do the
biggest the best the first the original
yep yep since the early 70s you see
Tommy Chong and Cheech wearing normal
shirts in their movies back in the day
there's a reason yeah so contribute some
money to some activism vote with your
dollars is what our friend Scotty real
taught us so get in there and send some
money where you can and this person does
they contribute to this podcast I would
assume they contribute to the dude grows
I bet you they contribute to several
others because they're a great person
but that is always a great way to
contribute send money to normal send
money to your local activism group so
the next thing that that leads me to is
if you're gonna send money to somebody
and it's your local group why not get
involved with your local group even if
you can't attend the meetings and show
your face it's the digital era you can
get a digital newsletter to that fake
email address you made so that you can
send those emails to your local reps and
to the newspaper so get some newsletters
your local news letters sent to you and
provide feedback provide information if
you're getting knowledge from Mike and
myself or other sources include that in
your feedback to that newsletter or
create the newsletter now that may be
your role and you can do that
anonymously you can do that from your
computer and your underwear while you're
listening to the show you can jot down
ideas you can get it going and that can
be your service to the community behind
the scenes with nobody ever seeing your
face when honestly Pueblo for sensible
cannabis laws exists for two reasons one
we had an idiot pop group daddy this
sort of so exists that was putting out a
lot of bad information and that
information needed to be counted and the
other part of that and this is like 75%
of it is one of my nieces was like who
was ragging on my facebook page because
it's everything was cannabis related at
least so it wasn't explicitly pro
cannabis it was a cannabis related news
story or something and she just like it
was just one dinner where she had like
three good burns that we're all focused
on my my personal Facebook page being
overly cannabis related
so I wanted another outlet for that and
there's literally nothing stopping you
from starting a Facebook group in your
area or a Facebook page or a Twitter
page under a separate account that's not
overtly related to you where you can do
all sorts of digital activism that's not
overtly under your name or is gonna come
up in a simple background search can
always start a podcast you can you most
certainly can't thank although to be
honest I you get used to the microphone
and you you admit things that you might
not want to admit to the world sometimes
and so having someone like you that's
really good with GarageBand they can
take out some of the insanity is kind of
necessary there if you're looking to get
involved I'm thinking you're not
currently involved and so honestly like
research and emailing and letter-writing
I think is a great place to start
and honestly campaign donations of
voting they're super easy they're not
time-consuming and they're incredibly
effective I'm proud of myself for
writing down campaign donations and
boning them I'm pretty confident I loved
the donate $4.20 to two different
candidates campaign that was run during
the last election cycle because one
thing that all politicians see is their
donations and they may not see every
donation explicitly and like who it's
from but they're gonna thumb through the
pages and see how they did that week at
some point and if they're flipping
through the behind or just fanning
through the pages and they've received a
hundred donations or thirty donations or
whatever it is for the same amount it's
gonna stand out yeah they say why am i
adding for twenty the number explicitly
tells you why you got that donation yeah
it's super simple it was incredibly
effective messaging and
I got to watch in real time politicians
change their tone on the topic as these
this donation platform rolled out people
went from not discussing it to having a
campaign challenger or a primary
challenger bring it up once or twice to
having it be centerpiece of that
campaign - they've already pledged to
get it done within the first year
whatever their time and often because
they see all those 420 donations coming
in they saw the support also and they
saw how far the tides turned on this
issue from just a few years ago yeah
it's come quickly yeah it can happen
really quickly
there were a lot of unanswered questions
five years ago I mean we didn't know if
like the UN was gonna lose their [ __ ]
because we've signed international
treaties that say we won't realize this
there's more than one there's all sorts
of state and federal rules I mean
there's nothing stopping the DEA from
showing up and trying to shut us down
right there's there's absolutely nothing
stopping them nothing at all every grow
every dispensary what's stopping them is
logistics in the reality of it in public
opinion and if public opinion were
really against us they'd be trying to
knock us down three a day and they'd be
trying real hard yeah and it'd be all
over the news and they know that if they
hit three on Monday on Tuesday they're
gonna have 200 and 300 people outside
everyone they try to hit on Tuesday and
by Wednesday we're gonna be stopping
highways and [ __ ] he just gave me like I
was as you were building up to that I
was building the most insane visual in
my head of like well [ __ ] they took down
three dispensaries yesterday there were
this many cops
let's all go surround our favorite
dispensaries and fight back and it's
battle in my head that's [ __ ] so
funny in my mind history loves to repeat
itself but we did this in California
already a couple of times I mean there's
great footage and a couple of the good
cannabis documentaries I'm like waiting
to inhale and stuff where the feds show
up to raid a very popular farm with a
huge number of patients that was growing
in the best way they could and giving
away as much as they could yeah and the
feds are raiding these people and the
feds have to do negotiations
that involves letting the people they
arrested that morning call the crowd
that has formed while they were -
cutting all the plants down to beg the
crowd to disperse - please not do
anything - please let these officers
pass peaceably and they roll up their
windows they tuck tail and they [ __ ]
ran and they did not come back yeah what
would happen if we threatened no we're
just gonna burn down all the bars and
breweries no more alcohol for everybody
we wouldn't even have to do we wouldn't
even have to damage stuff the there's
this one of the things that nobody
understands about politics and numbers
is once you reach a certain size of the
crowd you can achieve anything and if
you look at history wonderful things
have been achieved horrible atrocities
have been achieved they've both been
achieved the same way you get a whole
crowd hyped up about one thing or the
other he's wrong with it and I honestly
think that if the DEA showed up and just
for an example they started one into the
state they try to work their way to the
other they can only bus there's only so
many DEA agents even if they had every
d-- age and on the planet show up in
southern colorado they couldn't do
trinidad in a day and so literally by
the end of day one there's enough news
footage there's enough press footage of
this happening and this being the plan
to disseminate across the globe news
goes out instantly now and there's
enough of this just in colorado that if
we all hopped on our cars and took the
three-hour drive we could end it all in
a minute just by showing up and being
like hey now go away we don't want you
here yeah that's all we'd have to do we
wouldn't have to shout we wouldn't have
to yell we just have to show up at once
and Satan unison and we used to do it
once a year on 4/20 down a Civic Center
before medical before legalization in 98
2004 a hundred thousand people would
just walk in the Civic Center Park and
the cops if this was any other day would
ruin a month or more of your life if you
lit up cannabis
and a hundred thousand of us just did it
together and there was not thing they
could do about it because they knew that
if they started grabbing one of us
they'd have to deal with a hundred
thousand of us and we weren't hurting
nobody we weren't arguing with nobody
nothing
it just peacefully came together had a
good laugh peacefully left and there was
nothing they could do about and just
that happening so many years in a row
push the conversation of Colorado so
much faster and we saw the same thing
Seattle had a big smoke out California
and a number of big smoke outs there's
something that I mean the five or the
six years down the road after the first
smoke out when the news anchor is still
making the same jokes but you're like
wait a second on st. Patty's Day st.
Patty's was Monday by Wednesday the DUI
reports are out [ __ ] 4:20 was months
ago I never read a report say on a bunch
of traffic actions ever it's not a thing
that stuff starts to sink in little side
effects of just the visual start to sink
in there was one year where the worst
thing that could have happened happened
happened in Denver and somebody brought
a gun and fired off three rounds minor
injuries I think I don't think anybody
was severely injured a couple of people
got hurt when people were running away
right but I remember the next day when
everyone was like wait a hundred
thousand people got really high and then
ran away really fast got in their cars
and sped out of here in no fender
benders no flipped over cars no run over
pedestrians nothing there's just a
hundred thousand people just evacuated
the area immediately without any sort of
major traffic yeah in watching the news
media try to wrestle with that blatantly
obvious fact that they were trying not
to specifically address was funny
I mean it was a tragic incident and I
hated to see it happen but at the same
time it was one of those real-world
tests that teaches us a lot
stuff we didn't know we needed to learn
in I mean in Colorado we learned a lot
of those lessons over the last five
years and the rest of the world stood up
and took notice between these
conversations go down this year in
Virginia in New Jersey the debate about
whether the UN's gonna send peacekeepers
to shut down the weed store like I had
to have that [ __ ] debate more than
once and like convincing people that the
UN wasn't good at you know impose major
sanctions against Colorado like it was
nuts yeah I'm almost conversations are
Contin you can look it year after year
after year of teen youth debt and now
it's all online you just need to know
how to ask Google you just ask nice and
it'll tell you he uses FAQ on up um the
one thing that has changed in a big way
is the perception of harm innocent all
of the [ __ ] we were spoon feeding
them in the 90s is no longer being spoon
fed actual information is being spoon
fed their opinions on cannabis or more
in line with reality and that
statistically visual or seeable in the
graphs you can see that their attitudes
towards how dangerous it is as
drastically changed over the last five
or ten years but their use rates have it
like and people are starting to see
videos like the brave mykayla videos and
the video of the I don't know the
person's name and I would rather know
his name because I feel disrespectful
but there's a man on Facebook I see the
video all the time in marijuana groups
cannabis groups excuse me they'll start
having a seizure and they scored a
little CBD oil on his mouth and within
seconds the dude stops having a major
seizure people are seeing videos like
that I think that's making if you show
videos like that to my mom she cries
back in the day she didn't believe it
when I called cannabis medicine she's
like you guys are just using that as an
excuse to smoke weed I know when she
sees things like that [ __ ] she gets a
little tear in her eye she's like oh you
guys are right I remember Sam one night
it wasn't Thanksgiving dinner but it was
a similar family that was like 15 or 20
people there most of whom were older
adults that I respected in my life and I
remember telling one of them that
cannabis was the most beneficial plant
known to man and this was a statement
largely based on the different products
we can make with hemp and a couple of
the the minor medical uses we've known
about for a long time with THC like
lowering in her eye
sure helping with nausea especially for
chemotherapy patients and alike who
really have trouble swallowing [ __ ]
other medications that kind of thing and
we've known that hard science since the
late 70s and I remember most of the
people at the table laughing at me now
when you say things like that it's just
part of the press about the farm bill
yeah
like people start telling you about
their CBB company yeah their CBD I mean
if you really think about it I mean
cotton oil and trees think about all the
stuff and all of the damage we're doing
to the environment the planet ourselves
each other over some of these things and
imagine if we could change all of that
with fields that are currently growing
nothing yeah fill them up with him yeah
I mean we can stop clear-cutting forests
Oh Mike we gotta start wrapping up this
podcast I apologize yeah we went it's
almost 2 o'clock so we got super late
that won't be a problem edit that part
out just imagine what we're gonna see
over the next five or six years and this
really happens we're gonna see this
market take off for sure absolutely
I want to recap on what this person has
to ask for what got us into this is
asked for ways that they can be active
without exposing themselves we got way
off the track I gotta start wrapping up
this show so ah send emails create an
anonymous email account send emails
doesn't even need to be anonymous so if
you do if you don't want it to if you
want your statement to have impact at
least attach a fake name right yeah yeah
a fake name a suit up in name that's
what I'm looking for so put a pen name
on there write some emails send those to
your local the politicians the what's
the guy the mayor who makes who helps us
make those rules so it depends on who
you want to reach if you're looking in
local level it's probably a mayor or a
president of city council or the current
president of your County Commission this
is all stuff you'll be able to find just
google the name of the place you're
talking about and then add the word
government to the end of it and bring up
the cast of characters if it's the state
you're looking at the governor
nation president senator email all of
them like once a week and tell them that
you support the legalization of cannabis
most of them make them crazy easy the
bigger the politician easier they make
it if you want to email Trump Google the
words email and Trump together and it
will basically bring you up a link where
you can email a dummy box it's some
intern at the president's office the
answer you may have more luck if you
just hit them up on Twitter
yes but senators like your state senator
it's just as easy google email Elizabeth
Warren you may email the roy garcia
email bob bennett i come in boom it
brings up their direct email address
that goes to a staffer in their office
usually and then they're assigned to
send you the blanket reply for that
topic thank you for your interest in
this topic we will be back with a reply
but one of the important things that
those people do is they rank them and so
at a certain point this politician gets
a little report that says hey you had 47
people this week reach out about gun
control all right okay that's cool
cannabis 10 were pro 40 were against and
they get those numbers and they get a
gauge of what their constituents are
willing to reach out about them about um
if you live in the area that votes for
this person mention that explicitly you
don't have to be like i live at one two
three four but hey i live in your
district and i vote
here's my issue that I care about that's
a more effective message than just hey
vote for this because I send those to
people who I don't vote for all the time
and a lot of other people do too the
anti cannabis groups are getting better
at the emailing fit i watch them try to
teach people how to do this and it's
funny but our community is much better
with technology i don't we're gonna have
those issues but this super easy to do
to reach out your representatives
all right then once you've reached out
to all of them use that same email
address to send some letters to the
editor of your local newspapers not just
the local go the other cities are
surrounding you also before you submit
read it aloud yeah make sure it makes
sense make sure you yeah mom please
please please please
edit
also you can create a Facebook group or
you can do a join other forums or you
can create a podcast if you're that kind
of person that people may learn your
voice eventually you may need to be
little key about that you can also
contribute financially to activism
causes you can send $4.20 you can send
seven dollars in 10 cents your favorite
podcast on patreon every month I'm not
saying just me I'm saying myself the
dude grows Shango loaves out there could
use some support who else do we support
tad husky at kiss organics he can help
out so many people financially there's
also normal you've got local cannabis or
local cannabis activism that you can
support financially um there's a lot of
other national groups than normal like I
don't want to stress one above the other
but like they're students for a sensible
drug policy there's the national there's
normal there's the Marijuana Policy
Project I mean those are just the ones
that I'm randomly thinking at the end
there's a bunch and there's gonna be
state specific groups no matter what's
guaranteed so join those maybe create a
newsletter or just be a part of the
newsletter and add contribute to it
reply say hey I think this get some
conversations going with people open
their minds share the truth if you're
listening you're learning a lot of good
stuff that you can share so go share a
lot of that stuff and the final one that
I've got on the list of Mike the most
obvious that Mike likes to talk about
that I'm proud of myself for having
written down without some sort of
guidance is vote vote when it comes time
to vote on cannabis just show up and
vote like I said earlier they send a
little paper to your house it's really
hard to miss it it's a really do they
because here it's like a different color
than all the other mail and it's got a
big flag on it that says ballot it
they've made it remarkably easy in
Colorado but there are so many places
around the country that make it pretty
hard like some places you have to go to
a physical location other places you
have to register monster pants so it can
be a little tricky but once you do it
once you know how it goes and it's super
easy to do again it's also insanely
important here's a trick this is kind of
a magic trick if you were a cannabis
consumer and you are listening you're
gonna vote
encourage your pothead friends to vote
also and then you're tricking you're not
realistically going and advocating
cannabis but you're actually getting a
vote for our side and
your pothead friends to vote and a piece
for the people that still listen because
obviously you care about this topic you
were to turn this off right now those
personal conversations I was talking
about aren't just with anti cannabis
people also pro cannabis people there's
a lot of misinformation and bad
information in the cannabis world and
when we disseminate that publicly it
hurts our cause and so having the
courage to sit down with your pro
cannabis friends and be like bro when
you're out there talking about pro
cannabis stuff could you pretty please
not talk about chemtrails stuff - that
kind of stuff could you maybe not open
your speech with your beliefs about it's
cancer curative properties and and maybe
talk about some of the other benefits of
legalization that you also believe in
that we can support with hard data
because it's making those arguments in a
way that can be quickly fact-check
that's the most effective and reducing
our bad information that our community's
putting out is just as helpful is
converting other people to our cause
don't bro science people I think that's
what Mike is saying alright Mike we've
been going for a long time this is one
of the longest podcast we've done in a
while there will be a very little touch
of editing in this thank you has Judy
you've got a lot of stuff to say today I
wish I could to let you keep recording
because you're fired up I'm going to but
we need to stop it's really late folks
yeah it's late so we're gonna wrap up
this podcast don't thank you guys for
listening hey Mike thanks for coming and
hanging out if this ends up being two
shows I was kind of thinking that so it
may be two shows you never know we're
gonna have to add some of the stuff out
but it should be out right now so who
knows
alright podcast we're gonna wrap up this
podcast don't think Mikey once again for
hanging out I want to thank you guys for
listening to this episode of the girl
from your heart podcast make sure you
follow Mikey's an emo Punk 15 on the
tweeter you can find Pueblos for
sensible cannabis laws on the facebook
if you give it a quick search Mike says
they are harder to find the cannabis
pages that maybe that's why I read
genetics isn't getting any new follows
on the hints on the Facebook Mike thanks
for coming bro thanks for having me man
oh you guys if you feel like to listen
in this long I very much appreciated
hey guys it was a fun show if you feel
like this podcast was educational
informative or entertaining and you
would like to make a financial
contribution to this show you can do so
by going to patreon.com slash grow from
your heart all the information you need
to become a patron will be right there
on the screen once again big shout out
to everybody who has helped out on
patreon
big up Happy New Year much love I'd also
appreciate it if you follow the show on
the social media you can find me on
tweeter on the Twitter it's at G fyh
podcast if you'd like to follow my
personal Twitter account it is at Rasta
Jeff 420 again white Mike is over there
at Nemo Punk 15 also find the show on
Facebook simply search for the girl from
your heart podcast I think you would
enjoy it if you follow the show on
Instagram search for I read genetics I
RIE
underscore genetics on Instagram give
the show a follow check out my fine
cannabis photography check out my
breeding order also I go on Instagram
live and I just do Instagram rants for a
hangout take dads we get lit up answer
grow questions it is a good time so join
me on the Instagram if you've got
something you'd like to say and you're
not into all that social media stuff you
can reach me through email my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com you know I would love to
hear from you if you've got a product
you'd like me to review or you'd like to
sponsor the podcast simply send me an
email we will get you all set up don't
forget the show is available on iTunes
stitcher Google Play and of course you
can follow us on YouTube just search for
the girl from your heart podcast ladies
and gentlemen thank you for listening to
the podcast my throat is dry I am out of
breath I want to give a huge shout-out
to my friend Grimble the druid and until
next time take a phat dab and give your
mom a hug for me