it what's up everybody it's time for
episode 385 of The Grove from your heart
podcast this episode is brought to you
by the hella dank seed company if you
need new seeds in your garden I highly
recommend the hella dank seed company
and you can find them at www.sedar.com
by letting you know what I'm smoking
today I've been taking dabs of goat
power ambrosia from our friends at
apothecary farms this smells just like
golden goat it tastes just like golden
goat and it has got that sativa punch
that golden goat brings and I love it
I've always been a big fan of golden
goat so this is a delicious concentrate
the label says it is 74.8% THC with a
total of 86 point four percent total
cannabinoids I really like smoking the
goat power and gets my brain fired up
and it tastes amazing
so that is a quality concentrate ladies
and gentlemen this is going to be
another grow lesson if you've been
following along you know I've been doing
a long series of grow lessons in this
lesson we are going to do week seven
through nine we are wrapping up the grow
it's almost time to harvest so we're
gonna talk about the final weeks of
flowering we'll work our way into
Flushing and a little bit of defoliation
if you haven't been following along I
recommend you go back to episode 351 and
start listening to the grow lessons if
you are an experienced grower or if
you've been following along or if you
feel like you were up to speed let's
jump right into this grow lesson at this
stage of the flowering cycle we are
entering what I call the third trimester
most of our plants are going to take
between eight and ten weeks to flower I
think nine weeks is a good template to
setup these grow lessons if your plants
are going to take more than nine weeks
I suggest you extend my advice for week
seven one more week just repeat the week
seven feeding the temperature the
humidity just repeat week seven one more
time if you've got a longer flowering
cultivar now I understand if you're
growing from seed you may not know how
long your plants are going to take to
flower you're going to have to pay
attention to the trichomes you're going
to have to be prepared to flush about 10
or 14 days before harvest this is going
to take a close eye you need to pay
attention to your trichomes often times
when I'm running seeds that are
brand-new and I don't know what to
expect I already decided they're going
70 days
I want to let them flower 70 days and
see what they give me if I decide 70
days was too long I can run them less
time next time but I like to give them
the opportunity to show me what could
happen if I go a little bit too long
some plants really like to bulk up that
last week some plants really put on some
extra trichomes that final week some
plants really don't do [ __ ] for that
last week except over ripen you're going
to have to learn your specific cultivar
in most cases you will discover that 9
weeks is just about right for most
plants some will take 10 weeks if you
want to get them perfect so I'm already
in 8 weeks which is really advantageous
because that puts us a week ahead we can
produce another crop in a commercial
environment that really helps out but
for these lessons we're going to focus
on a 9 week cultivar so we are now at
the start of week seven in our flowering
phase at this point the buds are
starting to get really fat they should
be getting really sticky they should be
putting off some very nice aromas by now
they may be starting to make some very
nice colors if you are growing from seed
different phenotypes will start becoming
very obvious at this point in the
flowering stage you may have one
phenotype that has gotten way taller you
may have a phenotype that has stayed
shorter you may have one that is way
branch ear you will really start seeing
the different traits
now that we are later in flower so week
7 is what I call the fill week the buds
will really start filling in the
trichomes will really start getting
dense this is when the photos really
start getting hot I think weeks six
through nine are great for photos it
only gets better as we go on until it is
time for harvest so get out your camera
and take some great photos you're gonna
get good beefy buds you're gonna get
good trichome development and soon
you're going to start getting those
sweet fall colors now let's focus in on
the environmental conditions for our
grow room in week seven of flower our
buds are getting big and beefy so we
need to reduce the humidity if we have
too much humidity in the room we do run
the risk of bud rot we run the risk of
powdery mildew so let's reduce the
humidity let's bring it down to around
thirty or forty percent relative
humidity in the room this will help us
reduce the risk of bud rot so the first
change is that we should reduce the
humidity by five to ten percent if
possible the next thing I would wreck
is to reduce the temperature by just a
few degrees if possible we have been
running our flowering room somewhere
between 70 and 80 degrees during the day
I would like to knock that down just
three to five degrees if possible let's
try to get it
77 to 75 degrees in there and as the
week's go on
I would like to reduce it about three to
five degrees every week until harvest so
this week let's drop it down by three
degrees if you're already at 80 degrees
let's get it down to 77 if you're down
at 77 let's crank it down about 75 let's
make these plants think that winter is
coming that colder environment will
bring out more colors that colder
environment will bring out more terpenes
that colder environment will make your
buds more dense and I feel like it also
speeds up the finishing time of our
plants so let's make it just a little
bit colder during week seven now let's
talk about our nutrients for week seven
this is going to be our last opportunity
for feeding our plants we can start
reducing our base nutrients we don't
need as much nitrogen phosphorus and
potassium as we have in the past
you can almost eliminate the nitrogen at
this phase of flowering we don't want to
overfeed them but we do want to make
sure that they get a nice boost for
their last feeding so make sure you
include some phosphorus and potassium to
make those buds swell I would also
include some cal-mag don't go too hard
on the calmac at this point because it
is really hard to flush it out and you
may taste it if you go too hard with
cal-mag at this point I would always
encourage a kelp product this late in
flower that will add to your flavors and
aromas I do like an enzymatic product
this late in flower because it keeps my
root zone healthy I also use a microbe
product this late in flower I have
mentioned that we should taper off the
microbes and start increasing the bloom
boosters but if your budget will allow I
would include microbe products this late
in flower now the thing to focus on on
this feeding is one final bloom booster
feeding I don't know what product you're
using as a bloom booster but this is
probably your last opportunity to add
that bloom booster to your nutrient
regimen so make sure you get that in
there at this speeding time this is the
last week to fertilize our plants next
week we are going to begin the flushing
phase so if you want to boost those
plants up one last time if you've been
saving one bottle of
something or one little scoop of
something this is the last time to
fertilize those plants because at the
start of week 8 we are going to begin
the flush phase now at this point in the
game we've got big fat chunky buds I
shouldn't have to say this but I want to
remind everybody it is too late to spray
any pesticides on these plants they are
coming down in 21 days we don't want the
plants to taste like anything we apply
it as a pesticide so please do not spray
your plants also do not use a sulfur
burner I've mentioned that in previous
episodes using a sulfur burner at this
point and flower will make your plants
taste like total [ __ ] it will taste like
smoking a pack of matches or it will
taste like smoking a can of fish so
please turn off the sulfur burner and
flower I wish everybody would just get
rid of the sulfur burner and find out
what is actually causing the problem and
cure the problem so no pesticides no
sulfur burners this latent flower what
is acceptable is predator bugs if you
have got a pest issue release an
excessive amount of predator bugs
hopefully you've been on top of that
hopefully you don't have a problem but I
understand [ __ ] happens in cultivation
so predator bugs are the way to go at
this stage of the game the little
sachets that you hang the little teabag
looking things it's too late for those
you need the live predators that are
ready to release that are hungry that
are ready to get in there and destroy
your spider mites or whatever pests you
may have acquired you need the live
active bugs they're a little more
expensive but they are the only thing
that are effective at this stage of
flower so again do not spray anything do
not use a sulfur burner and if you do
see any insects any pests get in there
with some predator bugs and hopefully
those predators will eradicate your
infestation another thing you can do is
defoliate if you do see any signs of
pests remove any infested leaves mark
the plant so that you know where that
infestation was and come check
frequently do what you can to minimize
the problem in that area at this point
in the game I also suggest you defoliate
any yellow or funky leaves any leaves
that look unhealthy are pests
attractants so get those dead funky
leaves out of the grow defoliate
anything that is obvious that needs to
come off if you've got some nice fall
looking colors and you want to leave
those pretty leaves on there for photo
you can do that but the minute it starts
getting crunchy and it is dead decaying
matter it needs to come off of the plant
it is okay to have a few dead leaves at
this point in the game we've got a full
grow we've got a full canopy we've got a
lot of space there will be some dead
funky leaves in the garden
sometimes a leaf just doesn't get enough
light sometimes a branch gets bumped
things will happen you will have some
funky leaves don't freak out if it is
excessive you may have a problem that
needs to be diagnosed but a few funky
leaves at this stage are not a problem
now another thing we should keep our
eyes open for at this stage of the game
are late flower hermaphrodites you
should be scouting daily for pests you
should be scouting daily for powdery
mildew and botrytis during that visual
inspection you should also be looking
for hermaphrodites look at the top buds
of the plants look at the middle buds of
the plants and definitely look at the
lower part of the plant where you were
not getting a lot of light do you see
any male flowers do you know what a male
flower looks like could you identify a
hermaphrodite flower if it walked up and
bit you on the nose if not I recommend
you do a little bit of google research
and know what a hermaphrodite flower
looks like so you do not allow them to
happen in your garden so at this point
of the game we still need to keep our
eyes open for pests and mold problems
and we also need to keep an eye out for
hermaphrodites now I've spoken in a
previous episode about how to handle the
Herms if you should get one don't freak
out don't go crazy spray it with some
water and think of your options do you
want to remove the male flower do you
want to remove the bud do you want to
remove the branch or do you want to get
rid of that whole plant it is up to you
it is your garden you're going to have
to make decisions like that if there is
just one little hermaphrodite flower I
would spray it with water pick it out
with tweezers if you've got two or three
that are on one bud maybe cut that bud
or that branch off if you've got several
hermaphrodite flowers popping up in
different spots on a plant it may be
time to get rid of that plant you have a
lot of things to think about because
this lay in flower will those male
flowers do anything to the rest of your
crop if you're just running one
flowering cycle you're probably too late
into the grow to seed anything if you've
got a perpetual cycle going on those
plants that are earlier in flower may be
ready to receive that pollen should
hermaphrodite released pollen so you've
got things to think about now if you do
have hermaphroditic plant in your grow
room don't give clones of that to
anybody please don't pass out
hermaphrodite clones to your friends if
you want to continue to grow it that is
fine but don't give a her amount to
anybody you're setting them up for
failure we don't want to do that to our
friends and fellow growers now the last
things I have written down for week 7 is
plenty of airflow we need a lot of
airflow in the grow room as these buds
start getting chunkier we may need more
fans I want to see every leaf move
I don't need every plant and every leaf
getting beat down by the wind but I want
every leaf just to get a little rustle
occasionally as the fans oscillate I
want every fan to just feel that fresh
air just change that air around my
leaves that way I know the environment
is getting shuffled we don't have a
bunch of co2 in one area we don't have a
bunch of humidity packed up over here I
want to mix that air all day long and
keep that air fresh for my plants so
have plenty of airflow in your grow as
we get late into flower now the next
thing I want to talk about is kind of
preparing us for the future we plan to
cut this crop down in approximately 21
days do you have seeds or clones
prepared for your next run if you have
another grow space now is the time to
get your seeds or clones prepared for
your next run that way we don't have a
bunch of downtime that way as soon as
these plants are harvested you can move
fresh plants right into that grow room
and never miss a day in the future I do
plan on updating my perpetual grow
lesson I did write a very long perpetual
grow podcast I think it is episode 73 so
if you're interested in scheduling a
perpetual grow go check out episode 73
but I will update that because in
Colorado we have made quite a few
changes to our laws I want to write a
perpetual grow episode based around our
Colorado plant count limits so that is
coming in the future
but let's focus on today you need to get
plants prepared for your next run if you
have got an available veg space so now
is the time to buy clones or acquire
clones from either your fellow growers
or a dispensary or however you get them
or now is the time to start germinating
seeds and getting them started so that
when that grow room is empty we can
clean it up and we can refill it and you
never miss a day in there so that is the
basic
of week seven of the flowering cycle
let's move right into week eight in week
eight we want to continue to reduce the
temperature and humidity
let's get that humidity down between 25
and 35 percent relative humidity this
will make it a little bit dry in the
room for the last two weeks but it will
also help us prevent powdery mildew and
boy Titus we don't want to get mold
right at the center of our big giant
buds so let's start by reducing the
humidity the next thing we can do is we
can reduce the temperature by three to
five degrees at this point of the phase
I would like to be somewhere between 70
and 74 degrees Fahrenheit during the
lights on cycle now week eight is what I
call the final swell week you will see
your buds take off they will get huge
they will get chunky they will start
becoming covered in trichomes it is time
to really start paying attention to your
trichomes with a sixty or 100x powered
microscope you need to get in there and
look at those trichome heads see what
color they are
are they clear are they getting that
milky whitish blue color have they
started becoming amber that is how you
determine the ripeness of your cannabis
plants so it's time to get in there and
start paying close attention to the
trichomes on our cannabis plants now
these plants are also going to be super
sticky and super stinky but they should
also be putting off some amazing colors
so now is another great opportunity to
take more photography as we enter the
flush phase we will start seeing more
colors come from the plants we're going
to start removing nutrients from the
plants we're gonna push some of the
color out some of the green is going to
disappear which will allow room for reds
and golds and a lot of great colors that
you didn't know we're coming from these
plants this is going to be an exciting
two weeks so we've reduced the humidity
we have reduced the temperature now
let's start flushing our plants flushing
is free I have done an entire episode on
flushing our cannabis plants it is
episode three twenty into great detail
quickly here I will explain how and why
we flush for the past at least nine
weeks we have been shoving nutrients
into these plants they are filled with a
lot of nutrients we do not want to smoke
all of those nutrients they are stored
in the buds they are stored within that
plant by flushing the plant we are
starving it of nutrients we will make
that plant use up all of the nutrients
store
within its systems we will also remove
all of the nutrients from the soil so we
basically want to wash out the medium to
make no nutrients available to allow
that plant to starve itself so that it
will use up all of the nutrients that is
stored over its flowering cycle by
removing the nutrients from all of the
buds it will make the buds burn and
smoke and taste much better if they are
properly dried and cured we still need
to get all the way through a harvest and
drying cure phase but at this point
flushing is the first step to getting a
tasty final product so let's start
flushing flushing is very easy when you
water the plants don't add any nutrients
you can adjust the pH somewhere between
six two and six five and just water the
plants until you get twenty percent
runoff if you pour in a gallon of water
in a pot you want twenty percent of that
gallon to run right out of the bottom of
that pot so give them a few heavy
waterings and you will wash out all of
those nutrients then just continue to
water until harvest time that is
flushing it is simple and it is free and
it will make your plants taste so much
better if you do it correctly have you
ever smoked flowers that taste like you
just stuck your tongue in a white socket
chances are those buds were not flushed
properly that person did not allow a 10
to 14 day flush phase before he
harvested his plants and now they taste
like complete [ __ ] flush your plants
I've centered a couple times already it
is free why don't you want to do free
[ __ ] to your plants you don't have to
use nutrients and it saves time all you
got to do is fill the container with
water
adjust the pH pour it on the damn plants
let's flush the plants that is what we
were going to focus on in weeks eight
through nine is flushing the plants for
harvest so that they taste good once we
dry and cure them now before I harvest I
like to do a pre harvest defoliation I
generally like to do this seven to ten
days before harvest so that may happen
in the middle of week eight or at the
beginning of week nine any leaf that has
a pea deal that I can grab I just go in
there and peel it right off I don't need
a bunch of leaves at this point of the
flowering phase those leaves have done
their job it is almost time to cut down
these plants I want to make the harvest
crews job just a little bit easier so I
like to go through and pull off all of
the big leaves seven to ten days before
harvest
now that is a good way to segue us right
into week number nine at the beginning
of week nine if you haven't done it
already feel free to go in there and
pull off all of the big leaves those
leaves have done their jobs we don't
need them anymore
let's take them off of there and get
them out of the room now let's talk
about the environmental conditions in
our grow room for week nine this is the
final week of our flowering phase I like
to reduce the humidity to approximately
twenty-five to thirty percent humidity
at the end of the flowering phase my
buds are huge my buds are chunky I do
not want to risk bud rot in the middle
of those buds so I reduced that humidity
down to about twenty five percent
relative humidity in my flowering room I
also like to get it nice and cool if I
can get it about 70 to 74 degrees for
the last week of flower that really will
make the colors pop out of the plants it
will make them more dense and it will
give you more trichomes and I really
think the plant to pack on a little beef
once it gets colder and it will also
speed them up I feel like making it nice
and cold at the end of the season tricks
our plants into believing it is fall
winter is coming they say oh I don't
have a lot of time left to live so you
really start doing everything they can
do to ripen up and reach the end of
their life cycle so that's why I try to
make it a little colder in the grow room
at the end of the grow cycle another
thing that a lot of growers like to do
at the end of a flowering cycle is
reduce the lights currently you're
probably running 12 on and 12 off toward
the end of the flowering cycle you can
always reduce it to 10 on and 14 off
reducing your light cycle will also make
the plants think that the end is near
they will speed up a little bit and they
will finish more quickly I think that
having it a little bit cooler and having
a little less light in the room makes
the plants finish a little sooner it
also makes them pack on a little more
trichomes it makes the buds a little
more dense and also I think it gives us
a little more terpene presence terpenes
are destroyed by light terpenes are
destroyed by warmth why not give them a
little cool and a little dark and we can
have a little more Terps and we're also
saving a little bit of money we're not
using nutrients because we're flushing
and now we're running the lights for two
hours less per day so we're saving
electricity we're saving the electricity
on running the bulbs
plus we're probably saving a little bit
of electricity on cooling since we don't
have to cool to fight those lights so we
were saving electricity and we're also
saving time on our gear so why not
reduce the lights just a couple of hours
at the last week of flower now here's a
little secret that I haven't shared with
a lot of people if you've got a plant
that takes way too long to flower and
you need to speed it up just a little
bit you can reduce those lights by 4
hours at the end of flowering and those
plants will finish approximately a week
earlier if you've got a 10 week strain
or an 11 week strain and at the end of
week 9 you crank those lights down to
eight hours on at 16 hours off that
plant will finish one solid week early
now you may not get the harvest weight
you would get if you let it go for that
full 11 or 12 week period but sometimes
we just need the plants to be done we
need that space we need that room so
that is always a trick you can use to
speed up some plants so we have reduced
humidity we have reduced our
temperatures now we have reduced our
light cycle we are on the final
homestretch here in week 9 keep flushing
don't add any nutrients obviously please
do not apply any pesticides or any
foliar feeds to your plants this late
and flower you will taste it you will
notice it it will ruin the entire crop
this week is our final bulking and
ripening week you will see that final
bulk
come on they'll start getting fat and
chunky all of your leaves are gonna
start getting yellow and starting to
droop down and get a little crinkly
because we've been flushing and
hopefully you're paying attention to
those trichomes because this is when the
trichomes are really going to start
turning amber and showing their progress
so week 9 is the bulk and ripen week it
is almost time to chop down the plants
so keep a close eye on the trichomes we
have been flushing if you decide the
plants are not done and you want to let
them go a little bit longer you can let
them flower for an extra week and you
don't have to give them any more
nutrients don't mess your whole cycle up
by adding nutrients in and then trying
to cut it down seven days later
you've already been flushing you're
already doing it perfectly don't mess it
up now if it needs to go longer
let it go longer if you are early in
Flour
and you anticipate you may need an extra
week or two again repeat my advice from
week seven week seven is where you
extend your schedule if you're going to
go longer than three weeks so let's act
like we are right on
we're ending up week nine we have d
foliated the plants we haven't ran into
any problems
the next thing to think about is do you
have your harvest and drying and curing
area prepared are you ready for a sticky
stinky time consuming and space
consuming harvest when you cut down the
plants where are you going to hang them
they're going to be there for at least a
week maybe 7 to 14 days depending on
your environment do you have space for
that is it secure is it safe will people
be showing up when people show up are
they going to smell your hanging plants
do you need to plan ahead to keep that
aroma away from visitors do you need to
do something to keep intruders and
thieves away from that harvested product
now is the time to start thinking about
that you don't want to say hey it's the
time to cut down these plants and walk
in there with scissors and cut them down
and then you're stuck you don't know
what to do start thinking about that now
ladies and gentlemen the next step in my
grow lessons is harvest our next step is
to harvest these plants that is only
followed by drying and curing and the
next step after that is to clean and
reset our grow rooms so if you've made
it this far you are 1 episode from
cutting down your plants then after that
all we've got to do is dry it and cure
it and the step after that is finally
sampling our finished product
ladies and gentlemen I'm proud of you I
hope you've made it all the way through
9 weeks of flowering without any issues
if you did run into issues I hope you
were able to solve those problems
without messing up your crop if you've
got any questions about anything I've
said in this 9 week flowering episode or
throughout this entire grow series
please send me an email and ask me those
questions my email address is grow from
your heart at hotmail.com
I would love to answer all of your
questions about growing cannabis about
the cannabis industry just about
anything cannabis in general please
reach out with any questions
all right podcast world that is all I've
got for you for this episode thanks
again for hanging out if you feel like
this episode was educational informative
or entertaining and you would like to
make a financial contribution to the
podcast you can do so by going to
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
all the information you need to become a
patron will be right there on the screen
I'd also appreciate it if you finally on
social media you can find the show on
Facebook's
we search for the girl from your heart
podcast on Twitter the show is at G f YH
podcast my personal Twitter account is a
trois to Jeff for 20 also I would
appreciate it if you find my Instagram
account on Instagram I use Irie
underscore genetics make sure you find
me on Instagram
check out my fine cannabis photography
you can also join me in my Instagram
live feeds if you've got something you'd
like to say if you'd like to reach out
and you're not into all the social media
again you can email me and grow from
your heart at hotmail.com don't forget
the podcast is available on iTunes
stitcher Google Play and every episode
is archived on YouTube just search for
the Grove from your heart podcast you
guys I do have a few more I read
genetics t-shirts and hoodies and also
some grow from your heart podcast
t-shirts and hoodies available on my
website if you are interested in some
new gear the website is Irie genetics
Colorado calm just click on the I
restore you'll be able to grab yourself
some new gear there are some shirts
there are some hoodies and there are
some sweet new stickers make sure you
check that out I want to thank everybody
one more time for hanging out for a grow
lesson I want to give you a huge shout
out to my buddy wand Zilla and until
next time take a phat dab and give your
mom a hug for me