welcome back we've world it's time for
episode 388 of the growth from your
heart podcast this episode is brought to
you by the hello tank seed company if
you need new seeds for your garden I
highly recommend the hello tank seed
company and you can find them at
www.ge.com a tradition that I start to
show off by letting you know what I'm
smoking today I'm taking dabs a fatso OG
from Green Dot labs this is the fatso og
full spectrum extract it's nice and
chunky it's got just the right amount of
chunky crystals and just the right
amount of Terp sauce in there I really
do approve of that ratio the cross on
this or the blend actually is GMO and
legend OG the flavor is described as
dark roast coffee garlic and fuel and I
feel like that is absolutely accurate it
has given me some ridiculous cottonmouth
I feel like you can almost hear it on
the microphone ladies and gentlemen I've
been having a really busy couple of
weeks I've been out of town twice I'm
going back out of town Thursday I have a
comedy show in Denver then I will be
attending the endo Expo in Denver on
Saturday and Sunday so I am doing
another repost for this episode the last
episode was determining ripeness now
that we know when the plants are ripe it
is time to begin flushing our plants I
feel that many new growers and many
experienced growers overlook the
importance of flushing our plants and it
is not happening properly I'm gonna say
this in the episode over and over again
but flushing is free and it can improve
the overall quality of your finished
product so why wouldn't we focus heavily
on flushing at the end of the growth
cycle I'm sure I'm gonna say that plenty
of times through this episode so with no
further ado let's jump right into an
episode about flushing our ripe
cannabis plants before harvest welcome
back cannabis community it's time for
episode 320 of the girl from your our
podcast this episode is brought to you
by our friends at the hell a dank seed
company if you need new seeds for your
garden I highly recommend the hella dank
seed company and you can find them at
dank seed dot store also make sure you
check out our friends at pol grow
systems you can find them at pol grow
dot systems ladies and gentlemen first
off let me apologize for my terrible
sounding voice our friend Brett also
known as Mary's motivation had a
going-away party I went to that
away party and I smoked way too much
flour and way too much concentrate and
my voice sounds like crap I got a little
bit of a chest cold
I got a throat thing going on I got a
sinus thing happening and before we get
too far I just want to apologize and I
want to thank you for listening to this
episode while I sound like poop all
right I'd like to start the episode off
by letting you know what I'm smoking on
today I'm taking little baby dabs of a
gorilla glue for ambrosia and also I've
got some of the New York City bezel
ambrosia batter both from apothecary
it's been a nice mix fiscal and light
today just trying to stay lightly
medicated and not mess up my lungs and
throat again I'm on the path to recovery
and I want to keep moving forward so a
minute ago I mentioned that I went to my
friend Brett also known as Mary's
motivation I went to Brett's going-away
party Brett is leaving the country
Brett's a little scared and nervous
about his trip but honestly I don't
think anybody deserves this more Brett
needs to make this adventure happen I
think it's going to be a great
experience for him so I'm super proud
and super excited for him his party was
awesome at the party we were joined by
of course the always awesome Brett was
there dabbing granny and and Kevin
showed up also Lucy
mama bear dabs is there always good to
see Lucy I got to bump into my friend
twisty seeds who I don't see very often
I got to have a conversation a long
conversation with Chandler dabbing that
was pretty cool
Earle tycoon was there the dude from
hits on hand was there
LJ fresh was there and several other new
and old friends were there hanging out
it was a great party there were a couple
of folks there who brought Canon gars
which are basically blunts rolled with
cannabis leaves as the wrapper that
really [ __ ] up my lungs you guys my
lungs did not like that at all they were
delicious to smoke and we got really lit
but that is why I think I sound like
crap today so shout out to Bret for the
great party the party was a private
party so not a lot of people were
invited the event was at cultivated
synergy I owe a huge shout out to
everybody at cultivated synergy every
time we do an event there every time we
do a large or small party there it goes
very well the place is very inviting the
staff is very accommodating and I always
have a great time so big shout out to
everybody who came to the party
extra huge shout out to Brett for
inviting me who's only able to invite 30
people I was honored to be amongst those
30 it was a great party you guys we
smoked that place out for how few people
there were in there there's a pretty big
building and we smoked that [ __ ] out
pretty good you can hear to my voice
still alright while I've still got some
good voice left let's do a quick podcast
about flushing your plants before
harvest before we talk about flushing I
should do a quick recap in the last
episode I talked about determining
ripeness Mike and I went fairly fast
when we got kinda rambly so I hope I
made it clear the determining ripeness
is usually done by using some sort of a
loop so that you can see the trichomes I
mentioned using a 60 or 100x loop one of
our friends from Instagram what's up
dank Sinatra our friend Dane Sinatra I
shear photo and seeds sent me a message
and he says now I can't see try comes
with my naked eye but I can tell
ripeness of a try comb with a 16x
jeweler's loupe they said of course in
my mind I'm in my mid 20s so my eyes may
work a little better yes dude you are a
little bit younger than me you got those
fresh new eyes but he corrected me he
says he can see the trichomes with the
16x jeweler's loupe so you may not need
that bigger loop that 60 that 100 he
says the 60 is working or the 16 is
working for him so I stand corrected you
may not need that big loop 16 may get
you through all so let's recap a little
bit about what I said about harvest
times I said that if you have a plant
that is said to go 60 days let it go the
full 60 days and start flushing at day
50 if you've got a plant that's supposed
to go 70 days let it go the full 70 days
and start flushing around day 60 now you
may say Rasta Jeff I want to dial it in
and cut these plants down at the perfect
ripeness yes you're going to have to
dial that in something I wanted to
stress is this is not your last grow
with this strain hopefully this is your
first run with this cultivar with this
cut so now you've got a new girlfriend
that you've got to learn a little bit
you've got to take her out a couple of
times you got to see if she wants to
come down at day 60 day 63 maybe day 67
maybe day 72 you've got to dial it in
exactly to the right day now you're
gonna see differences if you use
different nutrients you may get
different ripening dates if you have a
little bit of temperature difference you
may get a different ripening day so
you're gonna have to find the window and
dial that in hopefully this is not your
last girl with this cut hopefully this
is the first of many grows with a good
cut so if it's your first run with the
60-day cut start flushing around day 50
if this is your first time with a cut
that you think may go 70 days start
flushing it around day 60 now when you
get to day 60 or day 70 on whichever
plant you're running you don't have to
cut it down just because you've been
flushing for 10 days start paying more
attention to the trichomes if they are
not amber don't cut it down keep
flushing for a few more days it's better
to over flush then under flush the only
thing you're doing is not giving it
nutrients it may have gotten a little
bigger it may have gotten a little
beefier but we're just trying to figure
out the plant for the first time so that
is how to determine when to begin flush
if you don't know the cultivar that
you're using maybe it's a brand new seed
maybe it's a new clone maybe you're just
new at growing and you don't know when
to cut it allowing the plant 60 to 70
days to grow and then giving yourself
extra time at the end is always your
best bet with a new cut alright so I
feel like I have established how to tell
if the plant is ripe and ready to cut
down and I feel like we have a good idea
of when to start flushing let's actually
talk about flushing our cannabis plants
I think flushing is super simple and
it's something people could easily
improve and they are really skipping
that step and I'm not sure why because
it's free it's a really easy step to
improve your cannabis and it is free
maybe people simply don't understand the
importance of flushing and why it's
important so let me tell you quickly why
flushing matters just imagine you've
been pouring salty nutrients into this
plant for nine weeks of flower plus
another three or four weeks of veg
you've just been filling it up with
nutrients
you've been pouring whatever nutrient
Brandi are using you've been pouring
nitrogen you've been pouring phosphorus
you've been pouring potassium and you've
been pouring carbohydrates into these
plants for the past 12 weeks now all of
that stuff is
built up inside of that plant the plant
is not using all of it it's letting some
of it go it's turning some of it into a
gas and transpiring some of it out but
some of it is still in the plant
if those nutrients are left in the plant
when we harvest try and cure that plant
we're going to taste it the plants are
going to taste like crap if you feed too
much cal-mag too late and flower you're
going to taste it if you feed your
plants too much potassium silicon light
and flower you're going to taste it also
the plants are not going to burn
properly when you dry and cure these
buds they're not gonna smoke you're
gonna grind it up in a grinder you're
gonna roll a joint and it's just gonna
burn black and make a funky weird
charcoal that's because they're leftover
nutrients that you did not flush out we
can get that stuff out of there by
properly flushing the plants you were
mostly flushing the soil you want to
clean out the soil so there's nothing
left in your media but whether it's soil
soilless mix if you got peat whatever
you're working in you're gonna want to
flush that if it's rock wool if it's
cocoa you need to clean it out each
thing is going to take a different
amount of time to clean out but you want
to clean that out so the roots don't
have anything to eat then the plant will
start starving itself and it will start
showing as harvest fall colors and it
will taste proper when you dry it cure
it and smoke it so that's why flushing
is important you want to get all those
excess nutrients out of there all those
excess salts when you roll a joint and
smoke it you don't want it to turn into
a little briquette you want it to turn
into a nice white fluffy ash and just
flake away so that comes from a properly
flushed plant then that also comes from
a properly dried cured and trimmed plant
but that comes in the future today we're
focusing on flushing so that's why
flushing is important you guys you want
your herb to taste good you want it to
burn well and you want it to leave a
nice white clean soft - with no weird
chunk so let's actually talk about
flushing the plants flushing the plants
is really easy about 10 to 14 days
before you plan on harvesting the plants
prepare the amount of water that you
would normally water the garden with if
you've got 1,000 watt light maybe you've
got a five-gallon bucket full of water
right so get that amount of water ready
when you would normally put
nutrients into the water don't do that
just don't put nutrients in there maybe
if you're gonna add anything put some
enzymes in there if you're using an
enzyme that will help break down all the
the decaying roots and all the matter
inside of the root zone and it will
speed up the process of the flush it
will help speed everything up but
enzymes are pretty much the only thing I
would put in there other than maybe a
little bit of shine maybe one to two
grams of shine from veg bloom but you
really don't need it
mostly all you would need is some
enzymes for the last couple of days if
you're gonna flush for 14 days maybe go
for like 4 to 7 days add 2 grams of
shine and add some enzymes but then cut
out the shine and just keep the enzymes
going until the end of the process so
the only thing you'd put in there are
enzymes and possibly some shine but you
would be probably just fine with nothing
at all so clean water add the enzymes if
you're gonna do so for four to seven
days add the shine if you'd like to do
so then adjust the pH to somewhere
between 63 and 65 you'll be just fine 63
and 65 that's a good window to adjust it
to then simply water the plants with
that minimal solution all you've got to
do is pour that right into the plants
just like you normally do when you water
soak the plants and let it run through
now what you're doing pouring the
enzymes in there is going to help the
natural decaying process happen inside
that root zone there's dead things in
there the roots that are dying are dying
in there the enzymes are gonna eat that
and they're gonna speed up that process
also that shine is going to keep adding
density and trichomes and essential oils
to your plants if you choose to add the
shine you still need to flush for the
last week without the shine you guys so
make sure you cut that out you can leave
the enzymes in there if you'd like to at
the end but cut out that shine for the
last week
now you're probably at day 50 right if
we're gonna cut down at day 60 we're at
day 50 we just mixed up a bunch of water
and we just soaked that root zone so now
you've got a pH D water with enzymes and
possibly some shine running through
there
those plants are gonna start looking for
phosphorus and potassium it molybdenum
and all the other things that they want
there are 16 minerals that the plants
really want you guys start thinking
about that learn all 16 of them it will
really help you think about what you're
feeding your plant maybe we'll talk
about that in the future
but the plants gonna start looking for
that stuff and all its gonna find our
enzymes and shine it's gonna be like
well I've got essential oils
I'm gonna go beef up my trichomes and
it's got stuff to build trichomes but it
doesn't have the building blocks to grow
more plant material it doesn't have all
the nutrition that it needs to keep
building bigger buds and fatter stems
and going so it's gonna start showing
you its fall colors it's gonna start
turning into these yellow golden colors
you may get some reds you may get some
Purple's you'll get some unique oranges
I really like taking pictures of my
plants right right at the flush phase
because they really start showing great
colors the buds are nice and fat the
trichomes are all greasy and shiny and
then the leaves start getting these cool
golden tones to them but that's when you
know that the flush is working there are
no nutrients left in that soil for the
plant to eat and it is getting hungry
which is a good thing because now you
know that bud is gonna burn smoothly
it's not gonna have nitrogen phosphorus
potassium believed in them iron calcium
magnesium it's not gonna have all this
other funky [ __ ] in it that we don't
want to smoke it's just gonna be nice
and clean it'll burn nice and smoothly
and it will taste really good so you're
gonna start seeing these fall colors
come on that timing is going to depend
on your medium how much nutrients you
have been putting into the plant it's
gonna be very strained specific and also
temperatures are going to have a huge
effect on this if it's a little cooler
in the room your plants are gonna turn a
little more fall colors if you have a
lower nighttime temperature you'll see a
little more purple from the buds you'll
get a little more fall activity from the
plants like what happened in nature so
you're gonna mix up the solution you're
gonna pH it you're gonna water in the
plants it's gonna run out of the bottom
then depending on your container size
and the vapor pressure deficit in the
room you were going to have to water
again repeat the process you guys makes
up your container put the enzymes in
there put the shine in there pH adjust
it to 6.3 to 6.5 and water it right
through the plants repeat this process
right up to a week before harvest and
then do the same thing but simply take
out the shine add the enzymes adjust the
pH and then feed it right through the
plants
enzymes are totally not necessary the
shine is totally not necessary you can
do all of this with plain water if
you're adding the enzymes and shine you
were going to have connoisseur quality
cannabis that's what I would do I would
do the shine up to the last week then
after that I would just do the enzymes
and then I'd probably do just two or
three days of plain water just to give
him time to finish up there if I was
going at sixty days I would end up going
sixty three in that last three days
would just be playing water and my grow
is what would happen there so just keep
repeating the process you want to rinse
these plants out do you want to rinse
the soil out as many times as you can
between the start of flush and harvest
so if you can get it to dry up and re
water it every other day that's great if
it takes three or four days that's fine
you're still going to get oh if you do
it twelve days we get three waterings in
there if you go every four days but if
you're taking that much time to water
that means you've got a large container
or that much time between waterings
means you've got a large container which
means you're using quite a bit of water
to flush that out which means you need
to make sure to get at least by ten to
thirty percent runoff water so if you
got like a ten gallon pot you're gonna
want to get at least one to two gallons
of runoff coming out of that that's how
you know you're flushing well so get
plenty of water coming out and then
flush the [ __ ] out of those plants I do
it as many times as you can but be
careful not to drown the plant don't try
to sneak in another flush time just to
get more water in there because that may
do more harm than good that may you may
kill the [ __ ] plant right there you
may just drown it you may suffocate it
that may be Bab maybe cutting down early
so don't ruin it right at the end be
careful to stay on your normal watering
schedule just make sure you soak the
[ __ ] out of it let it dry out water it
again do that as many times as you can
in the last ten to fourteen days and if
you want to add the enzymes do that if
you want to use shine do that those are
the only things I would really add at
the end so we have determined how to
tell if the plants are ripe we have
determined a good time to start flushing
we know what to put in the water to
flush the plants we know why we're
flushing we know how to flush you
basically don't mix anything up and you
run that through the plants this will
clean out the soil that is our main goal
as that's happening we're gonna see
colors changing we're
gonna see trichomes ripening we're gonna
see plants finishing up now you're gonna
get a bunch of funky you may I'm not
promising it depends on your genetics
your environment it depends on a lot of
things you're going to get funky yellow
leaves you're gonna get dead foliage
pull that stuff off there's no problem
with just yanking that dead stuff off
make sure you throw it away get it out
of the grow room but just pull all that
dead stuff off and throw it away now
about a week maybe five or three days
before you harvest go in the grow room
and to start stripping off all the big
leaves this is going to save you a lot
of time when it does come time to
harvest there won't be all these big
giant leaves in your way
just cut them off while the plant is
standing up while they're still stiff
while they're still alive you can just
snap them right off pop pop pop pop pop
you can go really fast you don't even
need scissors for it once you get the
thumb technique to just pop in a leaf
off you can just go in there and
defoliate a whole section really quickly
so a few days before harvest go in there
and pull off all those big leaves and
that will save you a big headache and a
bunch of time when it comes time to
harvest the plants you hang them upside
down dry and cured when it comes time to
trim half the leaves are already gone it
will save you a lot of [ __ ] and a
lot of trouble so what do you see them
starting to get funky take off the dead
ones then just a few days before harvest
probably when you cut out the shine
maybe then go in there and start pulling
off the leaves now another thing you
might want to do is you might want to
reduce the temperature just a few
degrees do not create a large swing and
temps between your day and night do not
go too cold at night do not try to
create something drastic if you can
bring it down two or three degrees
during the day and two or three degrees
during the night do that but don't go
crazy you guys don't shock the plants
right at the end don't give yourself
powdery mildew right at the end just try
to mimic nature and get a little bit
colder right at the end because what
happens right at the end of the season
it gets cold that's how things know oh
[ __ ] it's wintertime and those plants
will hurry up and finish so you'll see
more color you may get a little more
density and cool temps are good for
terpenes so lower the temperatures a
little bit right at the end now one
thing I'm sure people are going to send
me messages about and ask is do I use
any flushing agents no I do not use
flushing agent I think all of the
flushing agents are kind of a sales
tactic they are not necessary and I
think they make your herb taste like
whatever they taste like it's the very
end why would I want to put in a new
ingredient I want to get everything out
so I do not use a flushing agent if I
were to use anything I would just use
the the solution I told you the enzymes
in the shine and then I would add
powdered coconut water would be the only
flushing solution that I would use and a
lot of people are saying what yeah
coconut water would be ideal but that
would get very expensive to buy it have
that much coconut water imagine trying
to get a five-gallon bucket of coconut
water shipped to your house every three
days for 14 days that's gonna add up
that's gonna get real expensive but you
can buy powdered coconut water it is
readily available from a lot of gross
stores bill the soil can take good care
of you they do not sponsor the show or
anything but I know that that's a
reliable source for powdered coconut
water also something I should mention a
lot of people are growing no-till a lot
of people are growing in living soil or
super soil or some sort of live soil you
guys if that is what you're working with
you probably do not need to flush
because you have created the perfect
environment inside your plants rise of
the Spirit or it's taking up what it
needs you're not feeding it bottled
nutrients it's not being force-fed [ __ ]
so it doesn't need to be flushed
anything our buddies sub cool when he
would mix up a batch of super soil and
put a plant in there he would just beat
it water for the whole flowering phase
and he would say I've been flushing the
entire time so before people started
sending me emails yes there are some
situations where you may not need to
flush if you were going no-till if
you're going all organic flushing is not
a thing now if you're running that
you're already up to speed and you know
that we don't need to teach you about
flushing you were in the advanced
blackbelt class already now I've got one
more thing I should mention before I
wrap up this so called quickie episode
that's gone on for 20 minutes you guys
are very welcome thank you for listening
um a good thing to do is to measure the
EC or the ppm of your runoff water you
are pouring a bunch of water into your
plants right collect it collect the
water that comes out of the bottom of
your plant into some sort of a vessel
your pH pen in there put your EC or ppm
pen in there and see what the EC is now
if you're in a soil or a soilless mix
you're only gonna get down so low if
you're in cocoa you can get those PP
ends down really really low see how low
you can get it maybe before you start
flushing that day the first day you
flush measure what comes out then
measure each time and see how low you
can get it and then just keep
experimenting see how low it goes every
day and see how low you can get the ppm
s I don't want to give any
recommendations on how low to try and
get it because it's going to vary based
on your medium and I don't want to [ __ ]
up your Gro you're going to have to
learn this based on your grow cocoa
you'll get it really low because cocoa
is inert cocoa is not gonna hold [ __ ]
same thing with rockwool you'll be able
to get the PPM's of your Rockwall and
your cocoa down to amazingly low levels
soil soilless mixes those are still
gonna have some high PPM's because they
are soil and soilless mixes there's just
a lot of [ __ ] in there but play with
your runoff pay attention to that see
how low you can get it and it'll be a
lot of fun it'll be a fun experiment and
then you'll actually see what's going in
and what's coming out of your plants
maybe we should just talk about
measuring runoff anyway in a full
episode we'll talk about checking the EC
or the PPM's of a solution before you
pour it into your plants and then we'll
remesh that same solution the EC or the
P P PMS when it comes out of the bottom
of your plants and we'll compare that to
the pH going in and the pH coming out
and we'll see what's happening in your
rhizosphere anyway that's a future
episode I'm just getting excited you
guys measure the electrical conductivity
or the particles per million of what's
coming out of your plant and you will
know if you need to flush more or not
and then when you cut it down write down
the PM's and then pay attention and then
if you are satisfied hit that number
next time and if you're not satisfied
maybe flush a little longer and try to
go lower but they'll be discouraged
because it's not all about the flush you
still have dry and cure to [ __ ] this up
you could ruin your whole crop after you
cut it down so ladies and gentlemen I
want to thank you for listening to my
flushing episode so so far we have done
determining ripeness determining when to
flush we've talked about flushing I
think the next episode in line is
harvesting and then after that we're
going to do the dry and pure episode
there will be some interruptions to that
schedule because I've got an episode
with some friends and things always pop
up but those are on the chart to come up
in order ladies and gentlemen I
appreciate you for listening to my
podcast thanks for letting me ramble for
so long if you felt like this podcast
was educational and you learned
something and he would like to
contribute to the podcast financially I
would truly appreciate the support and
you can do so by going to patreon.com
slash grow from your heart and all of
the information that you need to sign up
will be right there
it is really simple and I would
appreciate the support I'm not begging
for payments or contributions or
anything I will do this podcast forever
for free I'm really not trying to get
rich off of podcasting but there are a
few people who said they would like to
contribute to the podcast I'd like to
make sure there is an opportunity for
that it is patreon.com slash grow from
your heart what I will do with those
funds is I will pay for my website you
guys I host this podcast on my website
it costs a little bit of money to do
that every year
also I purchased a better MacBook so
that I can record more efficiently my
old computer was not efficient as the
polite way to say it but the
contributions will help to go pay for
the MacBook that I bought and also cover
the cost of the website also you may
have heard Mike mentioned that the
little microphone cover needed a
replacement I use the funding for things
like that so if you'd like to contribute
I would appreciate it I will quit
begging because that got uncomfortable
quite quickly ladies and gentlemen I
would love it if you would stalk me on
all of the social media that is free all
you got to do is click around find me on
Facebook simply search for the girl from
our podcast you can find me on twitter
it's at g f YH podcast you can find my
personal account if you're interested in
trolling me I'm a Rasta Jeff 420 on
Twitter also you should check me out on
Instagram Irie underscore genetics on
Instagram I like to do live feeds where
I go on Instagram live and I hang out
take a couple of dads and then I take
questions from the Instagram live feed
and I will rant about your question and
teach you how to grow cannabis right
there on the spot I think it's fun
because there's no notes there's no
preparation today's somebody asked me a
fairly in-depth question and I had to
stare into the sky and roll my eyes for
about two minutes and try to bored out
the reply I was trying to give them
because I wasn't prepared and it's
really a lot of fun for me it's kind of
like it's like a game of stuff the
grower or stop the breeder or something
like that and I really find it
good for my brain it keeps my brain
going it keeps my growth knowledge on
the tip of my tongue and it keeps my
brain active you guys know that I had a
brain injury a few years ago so I like
to do things to keep my brain going the
right direction anyway I'm [ __ ]
ranting today you guys who needs a quick
episode right find me on Instagram I
think you would enjoy my Instagram live
videos also why wouldn't you want to
check out some dope-ass cannabis
photography go check it out also you
guys one more thing youtube I have got
all of the videos up on YouTube you can
find every episode of the growing our
podcast on YouTube now hopefully we're
able to get a larger audience we can
reach more people we can teach more
people how to grow better cannabis we
can dispel more myths we can educate
more people by having another platform
so make sure you support the YouTube
channel oh click subscribe go like some
videos to leave some silly comments I
would appreciate the support you guys I
think that's all I've got for you today
this was a super rambley episode I want
to thank you guys for hanging out with
me I want to thank you again for
tolerating my raspy crappy voice I feel
like I talked it right out by the end of
episode I finally sound pretty decent
now that the show is over so thanks for
tolerating that at the start of the show
you guys I'll be back Monday with a
fresh new episode I want to give a huge
shout out to my friend Texan toker
and until next time take a phat dad and
give your mom a hug for me