welcome to the show cannabis community
it is time for episode 389 of the Grove
from your heart podcast if you've been
following along you know I've been doing
a long series of grow lessons also you
may know that I've been out of town and
I've been reposting old episodes that
fall right in line with those grow
lessons this episode is going to be a
repost but it is a good lesson on
harvesting our ripe cannabis plants I
cut out a long intro and I cut out all
of the advertising so let's jump right
into a lesson on harvesting our ripe
cannabis plants all right guys let's do
a podcast all about harvesting your
cannabis we've done an episode about
determining when your plants are ripe
we've done an episode about flushing
your plants before harvest now it is
harvest time in the garden there are a
couple of things we need to think about
before we go in and cut down the plants
first of all I should mention if this is
your first time cutting down cannabis
plants you thought they smelled strongly
when they were growing as soon as you
cut those [ __ ] down it's gonna double
and smell I know that sounds like I may
be making it up it sounds like I'm
joking
no it is going to stink it's going to be
ridiculous if I grow one plant in a
small house we'll say in the attic or
the basement and then I chopped that
plant down and hang it up in that attic
or basement the stink of that plant so
normally you can smell it to the living
room right to the to the living room of
the house as soon as you harvest you can
smell that [ __ ] to the driveway I don't
know the science behind that I don't
know if it's paranoia I don't know if
it's because we're moving in and out of
the grow room or I don't know exactly
what it is but as soon as you cut down
that crop it's gonna stink more than you
were expecting so try to be prepared for
that some things you can do to be
prepared are maybe getting some ona gels
if you know what ona gels are ona gels
are jars filled with this gelatinous
substance that just eats up odor it
doesn't put out an odor but it eats up
the odors in the room so you open the
jar I used to just set a jar of it
behind a house plant or behind a picture
you know you got a picture your daughter
up on the coffee table or up on the end
table you just stick one of these ona
jars opened right behind it and that
just starts sucking up all the odor out
of the room so put those by the doors in
the entryways of your house where people
may come in
and that way there you're sucking up
that odor and then also if you can't do
the ona gels maybe do something stronger
to cover the smell it's gonna be hard
like if you're you're spraying lilac air
freshener you're gonna smell while ACK
and weed the onna gels are gonna be your
best bet something to neutralize the
owner odor would be your best bet
another good idea if you can afford it
would be a carbon scrubber most of us
have a carbon filter that blows air out
of the grow room keep that running
because that's gonna keep filtering the
air and make it smell good but also get
a carbon filter with a blower on top of
it and just plug it in and let that air
run through the carbon filter and now
you're just sucking stink out of the air
cleaning up that environment so be
prepared it's gonna stink that is
something we need to start with it will
be stinky now before we even start
chopping down there's a few more things
to talk about where are all of these
plants going to go once you cut them
down let's plan this before we even get
to harvest time are you going to use
those circular racks that they sell at
the Gro store the multi-tiered circle
racks are you gonna be able to make a
line some more with string and hang them
that's what I prefer do you have a space
that you're going to be able to control
the temperature and the humidity and
hopefully keep the aroma under control
and hopefully keep light out and also
keep people away start thinking about
that around week six or seven guys let's
not wait until week nine to start
figuring out where these plants are
going start thinking about that early so
you need a place for them to hang that
you can control the temperature a place
you can control the humidity and a place
you can keep people out of there and
also you're gonna have to control that
aroma so have a place prepared and keep
in mind that if you're gonna dry your
buds
if these buds hang in your dingy funky
basement they're going to taste like
funky dingy basement you've tasted that
smell on buds before and you probably
didn't realize why does this taste like
the damn basement you know why because
it was dried and cured and hung for
seven days and somebody's funky damp
dirty [ __ ] basement that's exactly
why so have some air exchange have some
temperature control and have a good
environment you guys create a good
environment for your plants you've
gotten them this far let's not ruin them
if you're growing in a grow hunt
and you don't have another crop coming
up right behind it why not just use that
grow Hut as you're drying space that
would not be a bad idea you're
controlling that environment already
anyway
so that is always an option create a
good environment you guys will talk more
about the space in a minute you can just
use the grow room if you need to if you
don't have another crop coming up just
use your flower room or remove the
plants into flower use the veg room
that's always an option but we'll get
back to that don't worry you guys let's
talk more about the things we need to
prepare for before harvest time comes
you're going to need a few tools I
highly recommend gloves the black or the
blue and nitrile gloves they don't have
to be super thick you're just trying to
not get sticky you guys when you're
trimming weed and when you're harvesting
and handling this amount of weed you're
gonna get sticky you might want to wear
long sleeves you might want to wear just
a long sleeve over shirt that you could
take off when you're done you're going
to get sticky you are going to stink
some people have an allergy to cannabis
I've got a friend if she rubs up against
a blue dream plant she's gonna break out
into a giant rash so maybe cover
yourself up certainly wear gloves also
if your eye itches do never rub your eye
with a trichome Laden finger if your eye
itches and you're trim and weed take off
your gloves and then it's your eye with
a clean hand or if you've been trimming
and not wearing gloves go wash your
hands before you hit your eye or scratch
your eye because if you get resin in
your eye it is one of the most painful
experiences you will ever endure it
hurts and it won't stop I don't know
what makes it stop it just burns and
burns and burns and it's sticky and when
you blink you expect it to feel better
but it's just stickier it's so [ __ ]
miserable
so gloves a long-sleeve shirt you're
also gonna need some scissors
I recommend quality scissors you can buy
some cheap shitty scissors but they're
gonna break I also recommend using a
different pair of scissors for cutting
down the plants than you use for
trimming the plants when you're trimming
you're getting in there and getting the
fine details when you're cutting them
down you're using brute force and
cutting down tough plants you may need
some some thicker pruners you may need
some choppers to cut down a big plant I
don't know how big your stocking
but you want to be able to get in there
and cut it down easily without hurting
your wrist without breaking your
scissors so I like something that has
got a metal solid piece to it for
cutting them down not the plastic
scissors for cutting them down metal to
solid pieces of metal from the handle to
the blade then also for trimming that's
when I like the little Fiskars the
diamond tips or something similar to
that so something to cut down the plants
with scissors shears whatever you're
gonna use be prepared and if you're
gonna have more than one person doing
the chopping down get more than one
[ __ ] pair of shears there's nothing
more frustrating than watching people
stand around and not able to do work
because you don't have enough scissors
or you don't have the right tools if
you're gonna have a group of people
doing it get a group of shears I know
most you guys probably have a small
garden it's probably one or two of you
and you don't need giant bolt cutter
style shears or giant Fisker shears or
anything but I've been in that situation
before where I'm watching five guys wait
for work because it's just me with a set
of shears chopping down every plant so
have enough shears have enough gloves
maybe get a few different sizes of
gloves if you're gonna go buy a box of
gloves buy two maybe three get small
medium and large 'iz or maybe small
large and extra-large it depends on
who's coming over to help you out but if
you're gonna have people helping if
they're gonna be harvesting and trimming
with you maybe you want a few different
size gloves and here's something I
should mention if you have applied any
pesticides to your cannabis plants and
you're gonna cut them down and have
other people work with them maybe you
should politely let those people know
what pesticides were applied to your
plants so that they can wear long
sleeves they can wear a mask they can
dress appropriately based on their
decisions based on what pesticides you
have applied some things don't bother me
some things I would want to put on some
long sleeves for I'd not get that on my
arms just personal preferences safety
it's always polite anyway so the next
thing we should talk about is how are we
gonna hang these plants because the next
thing you gotta buy is something to hang
them on are you going to use so the
gross store sells this really nice
hanger it's about three feet around and
it hangs in the middle and then it's got
four or five shelves on it that you can
just fill with buds that's acceptable if
you want to cut your buds into small
pieces or your branches into small
pieces and hang it on there that's just
fine but that's not the way I would
prefer to do it
I prefer to hang the branches so that
the buds aren't touching anything so
that they don't get a flat spot so that
there's not a spot where air can't flow
around it I just prefer to hang them so
in Colorado were allowed to grow six
plants let's say we've got a six plant
harvest I would get six coat hangers or
clothes hangers and then I would get
some fishing line or some thick hemp
twine and I would anchor that to two
opposite ends of the room so I've just
got a nice piece of string hanging
across the room
now you can hitting the plants on that
string if you want to but if you're
using multiple strains maybe you've got
six different plants maybe you've got
giant plants that's when you can cut the
plant into smaller pieces and put it on
the coat hanger and you can label the
coat hanger this is all sour tangi this
one is all black cherry now we don't
have one long line of buds that get
confused also it makes more space
another thing you're gonna need is some
sort of labels you might want to get
just some white duct tape you can always
just peel off a piece of duct tape right
on that stick it wherever you want it or
you can get some real labels or you can
improvise however you need to but you're
going to want labels if you've got more
than one strain there's nothing worse
than getting [ __ ] confused right at the
end that's really frustrating so you've
got some way to control the odor you've
got a place thought of and prepared
where you can control the temperature
the humidity the lights the air flow the
aroma and the security you've got that
all prepared and you've got the proper
tools you've got gloves you've got
something to cut it down with you've got
something to hang it on now let's talk
about the room just a little bit you're
going to need I would recommend a
humidifier and a dehumidifier and also
some sort of exhaust fan to get the
stale air out of the room if it's a
small space you probably just crack the
door open but if you've got a lot of
plants and then you're gonna need to
exchange some air gonna need to get that
humid air out of there or the plants
will never dry they'll just get stagnant
and funky also I may recommend a small
fan you don't want air blowing directly
on to the buds but you want to move that
air around you just don't want it
stagnant and funky in there you really
want to be able to control the climate
also you're gonna need something to tell
you what's going on in there a
thermometer a hygrometer
perhaps a PL gros unit you want
something in there so you know what the
temperature is what the humidity is so
you can adjust accordingly now it feels
like we've talked a lot about what to
buy and how to prepare so let's talk a
little bit about the settings in the
room since we're talking about all this
equipment I like to put a humidifier and
a dehumidifier in the room and I set
them both at 50% that way I know that
that room is staying right around 50% if
you can set them up to something like a
PL bro unit or if you can set them up to
something that'll trigger them to go off
and on based on certain parameters put
them both at 50% have the dehumidifier
work to 50% have that humidifier work to
50% and keep that room at 50% humidity
as consistently as possible now it may
be a good idea to have some sort of
exhaust fan in the room nothing major
just maybe a little 4-inch exhauster if
you can do it if you can just suck the
air out of that room occasionally that
would help you out that would get that
old stagnant funky air out of there if
that is not an option
open the door put a fan by the door just
make sure that air exchanges
occasionally so you don't get old air in
there now inside this room where you've
got your dehumidifier your humidifier
and some air exhaust try to keep it
somewhere around 70 degrees in that room
65 to 75 degrees will be ideal any
hotter you're gonna speed up the drying
it's also gonna get funky it's gonna
increase humidity any cooler the room
will start getting too dry and your buds
will get crispy too quickly so you've
got your temperature you've got your
humidity under control you've got some
air exchange let's put a small fan in
the room perhaps on the floor just to
keep the air moving around or up high in
the room you don't want it right in the
middle blowing on the plants too much
that's gonna create a dry spot and just
dry out some of those buds too quickly
we just want to move the air around so
it doesn't get stale I usually get one
of those fans that would sit on your
computer desk just a desk fan it's a
little tiny like a 12 or 14 inch fan put
that in the corner on the floor if
you've got a small room that is plenty
just move the air around alright so that
sounds like we've got a pretty good idea
of a dry and cure space basically a
small room or a grow tent that you can
control the environment in and
you can hang those plants in safely
securely and in the dark if you need to
use a small closet you can do that just
make sure that door gets opened and
those buds don't get stale in there also
like I mentioned earlier if you don't
have sufficient drying space go ahead
and use the flowering room that you
flowered the bugs in or maybe move your
next round of plants from the bedroom
into that flower and use your bedroom
grow tents always make nice dry and cure
areas if you're growing in a five by
five tent
you could easily dry your whole harvest
and maybe a three by three tent that
wouldn't be a problem at all you don't
need that much room to dry your harvest
well hopefully you do [ __ ] hopefully you
need a ten-by-ten but that's not gonna
be logical alright now we know what to
buy we know what supplies we're gonna
need we've got a safe space set up for
our plants hopefully you've been
flushing your plants for ten to fourteen
days there's one more thing we should do
before we get to chopping these plants
while they are still standing up we
should go and take off all of the big
leaves any leaf that you can break off
with your hand now just go ahead and
take it off the plants don't need leaves
you're about to harvest them you can do
this seven five three days before
harvest you could do it right up before
the moment you harvest just start taking
off all those big leaves those leaves
are unnecessary I like to just go in and
throw them right on the floor to start
tearing leaves off thrown right on the
floor and sweep up when you're done
because there's gonna be a lot of them
just tear off all of the leaves you can
get you don't need those this is gonna
save you time when it comes harvest time
we're gonna cut these plants down and
let them dry all those long leaves are
just gonna dry on there and be in the
way and smell funky and there are stinky
[ __ ] to work through once they dry
they're much easier to get off now so
just snap them right off of there do you
leaf this [ __ ] out of the entire room
before you cut down any of the plants
once they are all Preedy foliated that's
what I call the pre harvest defoliation
then it is time to start chopping down
these plants I don't know how big your
plants are but this is basically how I
chop down a plant
I kneel down or if it's on a table
whatever I walk to it I usually kneel
down to one knee and I grab the plant
right above where I'm gonna cut so I've
got the stalk just a couple inches above
the dirt I get my loppers or whatever
you want to call them your pruners your
shears and get in there and cut right up
the dirt right below my hand chopped and
now it's gonna fall over it's gonna
timber on me if I got a little plant no
problem if I'm in a 3 or 5 gallon pot I
got this by myself if I've got a bigger
plant
I will ask somebody to help me Hey Dude
hold the top of this because when I cut
it it's gonna [ __ ] timber down on us
so I would get in there and cut it right
at the base if you have got maybe a
tomato cage or some trellising or
something like that maybe figure out how
to get the plant out of there by cutting
from the top down I like to cut the
whole plan out in one piece and hang the
whole thing upside down and let it all
dry in one piece that's the way I like
to do it if you put the plant in a
screen of green or a tomato cage you may
have to start at the top and cut out
individual branches that is just fine
make sure you get you keep each branch
of each strain together so that you
don't mix anything up I mentioned
earlier how frustrating that [ __ ] is
don't make stuff up so separate your
plant free your plant from its tomato
cage free the plant from the trellis
however you need to then chop it down
now if you've got the whole plant
chopped down in one piece just get a I
get a fuzzy stick is what they're called
they saw them at Hobby Lobby or you can
use the twisty ties that come with your
trash bags because I never use the
twisty ties on the trash bags anyway
they always end up for this purpose wrap
the twisty tie around the base of the
plant do it kind of do it securely put
another put a branch in there because it
may slide off and then tie that to
either your coat hanger or the line that
you're gonna hang it from if you've got
the line hanging across the room attach
it to that securely hang it on there in
a way that you know it's not gonna fall
if you've got to cut it down into
branches try to cut to where you create
little v-shape intersections and if you
hang the plant upside down you'll see
the little wishbone shape intersections
that you can use perfectly to hang your
branches on your coat hanger or on your
line so cut the plant flip it upside
down and just hang it in the size of
sections that you need to here's some
advice if you have to cut your plant
down into smaller sections to make it
fit make the sections similar sizes that
way they dry at similar speeds if you've
got one big piece and one little piece
that big piece is going to take longer
to dry than the little piece it's gonna
cause unevenness and you're going to be
confused on what to do
so chop everything if you're gonna chop
it let it all hang in one big piece if
you're gonna let it hang in one big
piece so cut the plant at the base or
pull out the branches hang them on the
coat hanger either by using the twisty
ties and securing it to the coat hanger
there or just by using the v-shaped
intersections and hanging it like a
little hook on the v-shaped intersection
and just get everything hanging safely
in your drying cure room chop everything
down and just go hang it all up you're
gonna be super excited now you're gonna
want to go post all your social media
about how you just took down your first
harvest but do not do that here is some
old-school advice don't post any
pictures or talk about your harvest
until it's gone
if it's going out for retail if it's
going into your jar and you're safe
that's when you talk about it don't talk
about it while that [ __ ] is hanging in a
room don't talk about it while you're
trimming it don't talk about it yet just
wait okay just wait because right now
it's hanging in a room and when you go
to Walmart and you post it back to
facebook also someone's going on your
back [ __ ] door and getting all your
weed and they're gonna trim it for you
and you're never gonna see any of it so
don't post yet
hold off just wait now if you're
chopping down multiple strains carefully
carefully carefully label these plants
you're gonna so I'll go back recap a
little bit cuz I feel like it went fast
grab it right above the dirt chop it
down it's gonna flip upside down and
hold it upside down either put one
branch over your line that you're gonna
hang it on and let it hang right there
put a label on it or put it on a coat
hanger just slide the one branch through
the coat hangers where it's got one arm
through and then it's just hanging put
it on the coat hanger or cut it into
smaller pieces and do it that way
label the coat hanger what strain you've
got so cut it down hang it up
label it it's gonna hang there for
somewhere between five and 14 maybe a
couple more days I haven't seen them
gone go more than 14 days in Colorado
but if you're on the coast where you've
got humidity you may get some more time
so you've chopped him down they're
hanging upside down you've got them
labeled you've got the lights
temperature humidity and air flow all
controlled in your room now you're just
gonna have to wait somewhere between
five and 14 days for those sticks to
start snapping
when you bend him you just want him to
go crunch you don't want him to explode
you don't want him to just crumble up
like an old bag of Doritos you just want
him to snap you don't want a bunch of
moisture in there and check a few of
them before you get excited but when
they start snapping consistently that is
when the dry phases ended and it is time
to work yourself into the cure phase all
right now I did skip the part about
putting them onto dry racks that I
talked about you could get from the
gross store the gross store sells these
dry racks they look like a 22 inch kick
drum head I think they're about 24
inches around they're messy and they're
kind of cheap but they work really well
you just hang it up and for this I would
probably take the buds off of the sticks
and just put just the buds into those
racks
I wouldn't put the sticks in there I
feel like the sticks are gonna take up a
lot of space in there and they also get
stuck in the [ __ ] netting a whole lot
and they're a pain in the ass I would
cut every single bud off of the stick if
it were me and I would lay the buds in
there and I would spread them out kind
of far and then every morning when I
wake up I would go in there and just
move those buds around and kind of
shuffle them around a little bit that's
not the ideal way to do it but I
understand that some of us are limited
on space if that's what you've got to do
that's what you have got to do I would
rather see you hang them until they dry
and get a little drier and as soon as
the stick snaps then get it off the
stick but I understand that sometimes
you've got to improvise that's part of
being a good grower being able to adjust
adapt and improvise with what you've got
when you've got it
people are so [ __ ] spoiled now we've
got these giant facilities with parking
lots and security cameras and loading
bays and friends when I first started
doing this you couldn't talk about it
you couldn't have your friends help you
carry your groceries into the house
because now they know you're growing and
they're gonna want something or they're
gonna [ __ ] steal it if you need more
space you just call a contractor and you
get a building permit and you just build
out another room and you've got a dry
and cure area back in the day we
couldn't do that you would catch people
drying their [ __ ] weed in the
bathroom hey man I got a piss well at
your house no bro you can't pee here
what man I just got a Pete no bro you
can't pee then you catch on later that
he was drying and curing his [ __ ]
weed in the bathroom anyway I got
rambley there those dry racks are cool
if that's what you got to do
I would prefer to hang it I'd prefer to
hang it whole plant I'd prefer to hang
it until it starts snapping like I said
that's when we enter the cure phase now
if you didn't have time or the
forethought to start defoliating your
plants before you harvested don't be
afraid to go in there and take off all
the excess leaves while they're hanging
upside down it is never too late to do
that all right you guys I feel like I
can reek rap wreak rap let's recap what
I said probably a recap would be better
for a podcast let's recap a little bit
you need the appropriate tools you need
the appropriate equipment you need a
good room you need to be able to control
the temperature and humidity you don't
want people getting in there you need to
control the aroma you're gonna need some
gloves you're gonna need something to
hang your plants on and you're going to
need some sort of labels if you're
drawing more than one strain it's a good
idea to start pre D foliated get in
there and take off the leaves before the
chopped down process is fairly simple
grab it chop it hanging that
[ __ ] upside down and let it
start drying we know what temperature
and humidity we need to keep the dry and
cure room we want about 50% about 70
degrees let those plants hang for four
or five days and start snapping the
stems and see if they pop it'll be 5 7
10 maybe 14 days before they're ready to
go into containers that's when we're
gonna jar them up that's where we're
gonna put them into containers that's
when the cure process is gonna start so
I think we've got a good grasp on how to
harvest our plants the next step in
harvesting you guys is to get in there
and clean and reset the grow room that's
right it may be time to buy new bulbs it
may be time to change your air
conditioner filters it is certainly time
to clean the cover on your carbon filter
also maybe get in there and scrub the
lenses if you've got glass lenses on
your ducted hoods it's a good time to
get in there and scrub that [ __ ] out
make sure that everything is nice and
clean clean the room with a cleaning
product maybe some bleach maybe some
flies in whatever you've got get in
there and clean the [ __ ] out of the grow
room but get in the corners get in all
the spots you've been missing if you
plan on using your grow room or your
grow Hut as your drawing space that's a
good excuse but you're gonna have to
clean it as soon as you're done with
that as soon as those plants come out of
there and you're trimming you should
take a break and go clean the [ __ ] out
of your grow space before you put more
plan
there that is the completion of your
harvest that is also the completion of
your harvest lesson ladies and gentlemen
thanks for hanging out with me I think
the next episode I have a guest
scheduled so there will be another
episode before the dry and cure episode
but there is an in-depth dry and cure
episode coming up I will also talk about
trimming a little bit and then I think
we're gonna continue with grow lessons
and we're gonna start over we're gonna
go right into germinating seeds and
cutting clones and getting a grouse
started all over again
I've got a lot of fun things planned out
for the podcast please stick around you
guys I think you will enjoy what I have
planned for everybody you guys I wanna
give some shout out so let's give a huge
shot it's my friend Melanie Alexander
and also a gigantic shout out to Erin
Johnson I also want to give you a huge
shout out to everybody who contributed
to the patreon campaign thank you I
appreciate it
and also a shout out to everybody who
messaged me and let me know that
stitcher was not working properly
that's huge help if nobody tells me I
don't know it's broken I can't fix it so
thanks for reaching out ladies and
gentlemen I want to thank you guys for
listening to the podcast I would
appreciate it if you find me on all of
the social media outlets you can find me
on Facebook search for the girl from
your heart podcast you can find me on
Twitter it's at G fyh podcast you can
also search for my personal profile on
Twitter it's at Rasta Jeff 420 you can
find me on Instagram
it's ireon der score genetics I RIE
underscore GE and ET ICS I read genetics
on instagram join me I do a lot of
Instagram live videos where I talk to my
friends and hang out and we just do on
the fly Gro talks and I take a bunch of
dads and it's a really good time so
check me out on Instagram I read
genetics if you like to interact with me
if you've got a product you'd like me to
review if you'd like to sponsor the show
if you just like to say what's up and
you're not into the social media you can
send me an email my email address is
grow from your heart at hotmail.com I
would love to hear from you also all of
the episodes are caught up on YouTube
you can hear all 322 episodes on my
youtube channel grow from your heart on
YouTube I keep mentioning my patreon
campaign let me tell you guys about that
if you feel like this podcast was worth
a couple of bucks and you'd like to
contribute to the show financially you
can do so by going to patreon
calm / grow from your heart all the
information that you need to contribute
will be right there I would appreciate
your support
all right podcast world I'm going to
jump in and cut off this old episode I
want to thank you again for listening I
want to give a huge shout out to my
friends at Oregon elite seeds and until
next time take a phat dab and give your
mom a hug for me