all right what's up ladies and gentlemen
you have no idea what just happened at
this table right now but I wish I would
have hit record about 5 minutes ago cuz
some of that [ __ ] was priceless guys
welcome to episode number 39 of the igro
culture podcast I'm your host rosta Jeff
guess who I got back at the table guys
Jesse's here how you doing brother hey
what's up Podcast land dude you sound
great on that microphone we made a
couple Tech adjustments sounds like I
poured some super Thrive into the mixing
gear here we got it going on adjusted
the timing a little yes we got a new uh
Muffler bearing in there everything
quite smooth so uh a couple episodes we
talked about building a grow room and I
got Jesse to come back and kind of wrap
that up a little more for us which
ironically he might have been working in
a grow space yeah did you learn anything
um 150 year old houses are 150 year old
houses oh is it brick or is it like uh
drywall and [ __ ] it's brick Oh that's no
fun yeah everything's brick guys that's
going to definitely come in handy in the
talk later cuz I wrote some [ __ ] and uh
it's all about building a roof inside of
a room and we're going to need to do
that in Jesse space it sounds like but
before we get to that part let's pay
some bills this podcast is brought to
you by our good friends at cannabis
Grand crew cannabis Grand crew Aspen
will take place at the Sky Hotel in
Downtown Aspen Colorado Friday November
14th through Sunday November 16th
2014 what is cannabis Grand crew I'm
glad you asked that sounds so cheesy
every time I say it but it's perfect uh
cannabis Grand crew represents cannabis
culture lifestyle business and community
community in a premier event setting the
event includes lectures seminars
experiential learning and entertainment
centered around the Cannabis business in
the US and around the world industry
professionals and consumers alike are
invited to network and enjoy this year's
beautiful event in Aspen
Colorado while you're there check out
the grand crew Village an area exclusive
to ticket holders that will host
Colorado's best dispensaries including
Wellspring Collective from Denver and
Silver Peak Apothecary in
Aspen Loc at the sky hotel at their
legendary pool deck The Village will
showcase the latest products from the
top manufacturers and companies in this
very intimate setting there is a
disclaimer this is a members only event
due to the current nature of laws in the
state of Colorado attendance at cannabis
events must be By Invitation Only in
order to protect the event and our
guests please complete the information
request at the bottom of the website for
your free membership members will be
sent information directly on how to
purchase tickets guys hurry up because
the Hotels May uh be sold out by the
time this episode goes up but there are
still tickets available for the event
located at the Majestic Aspen no not the
Majestic in Majestic Aspen and nestled
in the Rocky Mountains the event will
take advantage of the amazing community
and provide networking and fun for folks
in the illegal cannabis
industry new speakers are being
announced every day confirmed speakers
include Mason tvert my good buddy John
Hunt and Meg Collins check out cannabis
grand crew.com for full details big huge
shout out to the grimy Gatsby
all right this podcast is also brought
to you by Highly Educated titanium I
said educated that's from cotton mouth
and dabs Highly Educated titanium if
you're using a high-grade concentrate
you deserve a high quality titanium nail
don't trust a chinese nail or an
American knockoff made of crappy metal
trust the industry leader trust Highly
Educated titanium big old shout out to
task Rock if you guys want to grab a
highly educated nail check out aqualab
technologies.com if you want to learn
how to season care for and take care of
your highly educated nail and how to
clean it check out Highly Educated
ti.com got one more big ad two more
sorry this podcast is brought to you by
our friends at H gr indoor growing
supplies H gr indoor growing supplies
has two locations to serve Colorado
visit the Denver store 6271 Beach Street
or come say hello in peblo 618 East 4th
Street in Pueblo Colorado check out hyro
for competitive pricing and a great
selection of indoor grow supplies dude I
use Botanicare and they just stocked up
on Botanicare it looks sweet in there I
use ogt they just got some ogt in there
they're killing it you guys have
hygrozyme on the Shelf yet yeah see I
ordered that once and now they've got it
on the shelf for me all the time heck
yeah loving it we also have a big old
bag of root 707 for $25 this month
that's a steel and I might need to go
stock up on that that space right there
along that wall that's empty we could
just fill that right up with soil and
also this month if you mention I gr
culture you get commercial pricing on
everything think that's the month of
November yeah you hear that guys all the
month of November go to hyro indoor
growing supplies in Pueblo when you're
paying tell them I listen to the
agriculture podcast you will get
commercial pricing you're going to pay
what Rasta Jeff pays you can uh you can
get that in Denver too um they may have
to make a phone call tell them to call
tell them to call Jesse or burn and P
and they'll get you straight they'll
explain it all yeah yeah right on guys
thank you I didn't even know that was
going to happen so I just learned about
that at the same time the listeners did
that is really cool if uh if we have a
good response we'll just probably keep
it that way there we go guys go in there
and use that coupon code or that
discount code so that we can keep it
going the more of you that use it
they'll see the response they'll keep
doing it awesome thank you guys for
listening going there uh we got one more
ad big love to tree thug.com of course
the show is brought to you by our
friends at tree Thugger dcom live music
lifestyle magazine check out tree
Thugger dcom for concert and Festival
news and reviews
www.re Thugger
I think I actually uh just confirmed
that I'm going to check out The String
Cheese Incident in Denver on New Year's
Eve that's going to be kind of cool kind
of random for me I haven't seen the
cheese in years got a friend who needs a
a cheese buddy for New Years and I think
I'm going to be the cheese buddy quite a
Cheesy buddy I think that's enough ads
for the show I think that covered
everybody also check out Nature's green
remedies.com I didn't do a big ad for
them they are sold out of ir gentics
products right now but you can get Gage
green genetics the plot of labs in Sin
City I do not have a coupon code for
them this month once I give them a
refill they'll get a sweet coupon code
you guys will get hooked up uh So
currently what's been going on we had an
election last night Colorado did not
have much cannabis initiative on the
ballots but we did have number 105
regarding non-GMO food this was the
labeling of GMO Foods Colorado dude you
failed bro what the hell this was
supposed to pass this was uh what this
was we're not going to get too much into
it because it's already happened
this was we wanted them to have to mark
genetically modified food products with
some sort of indication that it is
genetically
modified enriched with GMOs we did not
pass this what the hell is going on
Colorado all right yeah and it failed by
Landslide that's the really
disappointing part I liked your uh Jesse
BR a really good Facebook post he said
something to the effect of that's okay
Colorado I didn't want to share my
organic produce with you anyway uh
Jesse's tomatoes are delicious I am
addicted there's only one other place
I've eaten recently that's got Tomatoes
nearly as tasty as Jesse's I know where
that place is dud they get so many shout
outs on this podcast I'm addicted to
that place I eat there a lot uh we went
up there with uh burn and uh Burn's
cousin and uh they made customers yeah
yeah they made friends they treat you
like your family when you're there They
Know My Name by now they start writing
down my order when they see me in line
they like you want the same thing dude
and I'm like yep yeah it's a it's a um
I've never seen that many uh M uh
different drinks yeah so like I was a
little overwhelmed at first it is it's a
little strange the first time you walk
it well the the vibe there is very
unique so when you walk in you're almost
in a new world turn your cell phone up
when you go in there please I agree but
there are so many people in there I go
I've gone late at night and midday and
if you go during the day it's like uh
it's 20 something with their MacBooks
and their iPhones all over the place but
you're right around around 11 or 12 I
wish we could get put their phones away
and chill out cuz it's really chill in
there there were some people playing
chess and uh a couple people looked like
they were on a date or something it's
just real chill in metal the guys
playing chess in there look like robots
they're so good at chess dude the one
guy I I swear he was playing chess with
the guy in front of him and then he was
also playing it on his
iPad he's predicting what could happen
or something yeah I was like man so I've
got a funny joke that only a few
listeners are going to get we were at
it's we're talking about a place called
the mate factor and they make yurba mate
it's a Brazilian energizing tea um they
have two different kinds they have the
dark yurba mate which is what I prefer
and then they have got the green yurba
mate which I prefer the green iced and I
like the dark hot that's just my
preference so if I need a cool drink
I'll get the green one the guy was
describing the differences to a customer
who it's in a really touristy area so
you get a lot of touristy kind of people
they're describing this drink to a
tourist and he said that the dark roast
is the dried leaves that have been set
out and they've dried and they crumble
it and then they brew it or they grind
it and then they brew it together and he
said the green is more the fresh leaf
that hasn't been dried and set out for
as long and I heard him say that and I
looked at the girl that was with me and
I said he's talking about that live
res nice only a few listeners are going
to laugh at that but that's exactly the
description that worked perfectly it's
all about that live resin the dark roast
is the dried and cured and then the
fresh green is the live res and you can
taste the difference it's such a huge
bold the difference um I had only ever
had the green uh before I went up there
and I got the dark and was like yeah
this is the [ __ ] all right they don't
know that this is going to happen but if
anybody that listens to this podcast
goes to the m factor in manatou Springs
say something about you heard about say
I heard about this place from the igro
culture podcast and they told me to say
hi and then maybe they'll catch on cuz
they know who I am I've said that I'm
the host of a show nice yeah so nice
maybe maybe one day they'll maybe I just
want a free veggie wrap out of the deal
I got a free muffin from them the other
night they were really kind they gave me
a fresh warm free muffin all right
that's a lot of talk about the mate
Factor the place is so good bro uh if
you go up there go hike on Rainbow Falls
I never said nothing about the secret
Rainbow Falls that place is awesome if
you can find it go hike it it's cool
graffiti Falls so we're talking about
the uh the votes that happened last
night um Oregon Alaska and Washington DC
have legalized recreational Cannabis
welcome to the cool kid Club yeah
Florida on the other
hand you're just old people in Disney
World still how many people in
Florida do you think could actually
reduce their like their their pain
medication
consumption uh drastically every day do
you think that maybe some of those pain
companies the pain clinics kind of
lobbied against all of this medical
cannabis or cannabis no surely not I
mean I I would think a a big major
corporation would have a lot more
Integrity than that good honest company
that we need to do something like that
because that would be kind of cheating
and
dishonest just poisoning their citizens
no come on big Pharma yeah yeah so if
you uh if you did not go out and vote
you can't [ __ ] about what happened in
Florida but if you voted in Florida and
I'm sorry you did not get your cannabis
rights there Oregon Alaska and
Washington DC however congratulations
like that's awesome yeah you going to
say I kind of cut off oh I was going to
say unless for some reason they're
listening to this and they voted against
it then go [ __ ]
yourself I will second that but I will
not pay the
fine nobody's tallied up how many times
I uh said the f word on so many episodes
so whoever was paying attention uh you
got to go math that up for me and we're
going to discontinue that actually we're
going to stop doing it because I haven't
said that in quite a long time on the
show so it's kind of cool somebody let
me know what I owe and I'll pay it I H
you on two for one episode yeah yeah but
I don't remember which one or when or
where or anything so Dreadful Jay where
are you girl you always listen to the
show and remind me of funny stuff that I
said so count up those FWS uh what else
was I going to say Washington DC our
nation's capital now has legalized
cannabis why doesn't the rest of the
nation just follow suit with what the
capital has done yeah I guess it there
are intelligent people in DC contrary to
popular belief hopefully change some of
the uh their Habits Like while they're
up there doing what they do instead of
just droning on and be like yo bro I
think that these GMOs were Croc of [ __ ]
and we need to knock this [ __ ] out bro
can I get a ey and then everyone will be
like yeah o this just made uh getting a
uh uh smoking a joint in front of the
White House photo op a lot easier
o well that's uh there was actually I
was at Garden of the Gods and I think I
saw a sign that reminded you reminded
you that that's a state park and you
cannot bring your cannabis there oh yeah
because it's still federal land so I'm
pretty sure that that White House land
is federal land and you can't have your
cannabis
there good point yeah if you uh if you
go to a state park right now in Colorado
people that are not from Colorado this
is a random we did not prepare this part
at all if you're not uh if you were in a
state park in Colorado like Red Rocks is
a state park uh most uh the reservoirs
like the PUO Reservoir all the big
reservoirs where you'd want to go hang
out most of the cool [ __ ] is a state
park you cannot take you you can I mean
you can they're not stopping everybody
in check you it for years yeah we do but
we're not going to say we do but you can
take we're not encouraging it's illegal
to actually have cannabis at a state
park so yeah even if it's legal in DC
smoking a joint at the White House is
still going to be a little sketchy
although shout out to Snoop Dog Snoop
claims that he smoked that weed at the
the White House there and also big shout
out to Willie we know Willie smoked at
the at the White House so all right so
Bill Clinton smoked something there
Monica Lewinsky smoked something
there they just turned 50 recently and
there were pictures of her online I'm
not going to comment on the pictures but
that did happen oh man doesn't that kind
of make you feel old I wasn't going to
go there I that did come to AC cross my
mind but all right we've been talking
about uh Jesse and I were talking about
building a room a couple episodes back
and we're talking about planning your
grow room we talked about selecting your
space uh being a responsible grower um
this episode we're going to talk more
about building and setting up your grow
we're going to discuss grow tents a
little bit or those Hydro Huts or
whatever you want to call them and maybe
if we have enough time we're already 15
minutes in if we have enough time I will
try to uh tackle that $500 grow room
question that's going to be a challenge
but um basically do everything that
we're doing and go much smaller dude we
don't even get to pots and soil and
stuff on the stuff that I've got written
and we've got five pages of stuff typed
out so this is going to be a
lot um we wrapped up the last gr up
episode with to talk about deciding how
much light to use in your space and we
kind of talked about uh where you're
going to hang the lights and where
you're going to my phone is making noise
that's a poor podcast move right there
oh it's
already no yeah it was on silent I don't
know what that was all right um yeah
talking about we're going to hang the
lights how you're going to vent the
humidity we talked a little bit about
bringing fresh air into the room uh so
now let's kind of talk about building a
room which is kind of helpful cuz Jesse
has a lot of experience in this uh you
need to make a clean grow space that
allows you to control the light cycles
the temperature during the day the
temperature during the night and you
need to control the humidity and it's
also ideal to have a lot of control over
the air going in and out of the grow
space uh if you're using an extra
bedroom or a closet you'll have all the
walls already built but you'll need to
work around the existing room Jesse was
talking about working in a brick
building or a brick facility I don't
know where it is I didn't ask I don't
want to know but he was talking about
it's 150 years old and it's brick and
that's got to suck because you don't
have anything to screw [ __ ] into uh
bricks crumble if you hit them with a
hammer and try to put nails into them sh
can go really wrong if you move one
brick now you've got an unstable wall
all right so I'm ranting about a brick
Oh yeah if you've got an open area like
a garage or a basement or maybe Jesse's
brick area you're going to need to build
a room you can't you could just hang
lights up in your garage or in that
basement but it's going to be a lot
easier if you build a room or set up a
free pre-fabricated grow Hut uh because
that just gives you actually control
over your environment and an environment
simple reflection and trapping the light
and having it reflect around makes the
light up to 30% more efficient is what I
read in a couple of books one said 20
one said 30 how about we'll settle on
25% more efficient and if you're running
a th000 watt light that's 250 Watts
basically of efficiency that you're
going to not lose by having more
reflection so just putting it in a good
designed room is already saving you
money and increasing buds because like
we talked about on another show the
light is the main nutrient for your
plants it's not what you pour in it's
not what you feed it it's actually the
light
so uh where are we Let's uh let's
actually get into building a room I was
looking at all kinds of stuff and trying
to figure out how to do this I just
decided let's kind of build a four light
room um we're going to act like we're
building it either in a garage that's
got plenty of room or the basement
that's got plenty of room or maybe in a
warehouse sorry about the cops guys
we've been taking dabs so let's build a
room we need four 1,000 watt lights and
a conditioner a way to remove the
humidity and a way to draw in fresh air
so let's choose like I said we're going
to do the basement or a garage or
something like that that we want to
build a four light room I want to build
a room that's go ahead how big is this
room that's what I was just going to say
8 by8 because 2x4s come in 8 foot
sections right or a 2x3 or whatever we
decide to use a 2x4 well you can get
them in tin too but okay yeah but most
of us aren going to have a 10ft ceiling
in our basement our garage so I was
going to just stick with the you can buy
a bunch of 8 by eights a bunch of eight
foot 2x4s and I think you could set up
this room in a day that'd be nice yeah
you you and I could do it in probably 5
hours cuz we've done this enough times
uh so if you're going to use a grow Hut
or something or a pre-made grow lab what
do you guys do you guys sell grow Huts
at the over at Hydro indor growing
supplies um we have grow Hut we have a
generic brand is it the grow lab um and
we have the grow Labs yeah okay um the
generic brand is different than the um
uh grow laabs I've never seen one but uh
we can get a really good price on them
all right and they're just basic you
know I use the grow laabs uh that's what
I think they're grow laab 120s or
something like that or the 5x5 those are
sweet same thing throw 1,000 watt light
in there and those are awesome they also
make a 10x10 one which would work
perfectly uh for what we're going to
talk about here it would be we're going
to basically build an 8 by8 version of
that 10 by it's 10 by 10 ft x 10 ft by 6
high I think or seven High we're just
going to make an 8 by 8 by 8 room and
one of the best ways to build a room um
you know even like a big huge Warehouse
what they do is essentially they build a
gigantic grow Hut out of 2x4s and you
know drywall and everything uh they'll
build a room inside of a room even in
like the vertical uh uh commercial
lettuce farms and stuff like that that's
they they start with these cells so you
know
um you need to you know sometimes
looking at had a 10x10 uh grow Hut
they're kind of expensive but so was
building a 10 x10 room right and if
you're not uh and like if you can build
a 10x10 you can build this 8 by8 room
you've got the tools and everything I'll
build us a house man I don't have I me I
I've got basic skills but for me buying
the 10x10 Hut and snapping those pieces
together is so much easier for me and if
something were to go wrong in your grow
the thing comes down in an hour you
could have everything down concealed in
one hour uh move it to another spot and
put it back up hopefully in another hour
with those grow huts and if you're like
working in a a garage or a big open
basement I mean you know it's
just if you want to expand and stuff
like that there there's a lot of good
reasons to have multiple rooms uh when
it comes to Pest Control uh uh equipment
failure and all kinds of stuff like that
you know it's it's good to double up uh
I agree completely uh if you get bugs
over in this room or if you have an
equipment like you said if the air
conditioner fails in this room it didn't
fail in every room only failed in one
light or four lights worth of stuff you
only murdered 30 plants instead of a 100
all right so I'm glad Jesse said that
part about building a room within a room
uh he comes in handy sometimes CU most
of what I wrote was about building a
room inside of a room I was going to say
frame out of 8 by8 room that's nice and
tall I was going to say try to leave as
much head room as you can but most of us
are going to be in a basement or garage
so we'll be limited on space and then I
said if you can use the full uh 8 foot
2x4s you're in good luck so frame out
your 8 by 8 by eight room wherever
you're working and then here's where I
kind of start getting into detail since
Jesse kind of I'm so glad you said build
a room inside of a room most of what I
wrote is build a room inside of a room
even like
uh big like restaurants and old
buildings and stuff like that that's how
they you know make it sanitary yeah make
it look all nice just build a shell it's
called over
framing all right so overframe yourself
a nice room all right you got an 8 by8
room just framed you don't need to frame
it like super rigidly secure you just
need a couple of cross beams yeah 24 in
studs every 24 inches so have Jesse or I
stand every 24 inches is what he's
saying you need to stud every 24 inches
plan for a door sometimes you guys
forget doors uh the hydro Shop sell I
don't know if you guys have this yet but
I've seen this at plent okay they it's
like a sticker you stick it right on
your on the myar we're going to talk or
not the myar the poly we're going to
talk about later and then you use a
razor and you unzip the zipper and as
you unzip it you just follow your razor
right along with it and cut a hole in
the poly and now you have a zipper door
do not unzip it before you stick it
on has that
happened okay we're just going to move
on because we don't want to make fun of
your customer that did that uh you're
going to need to put some beams across
the top to hang your equipment so now
you've got this 8 by8 building just just
a frame um studs every 24 in maybe a
couple across because you're going to
hang some equipment uh the uh roof beams
well it depending on if you go all the
way to the to the ceiling um if you
don't go all the way to the ceiling um
just stand your don't lay them down
stand your 2x4s up on the skinny Edge um
get you some metal clamps and screw them
to the the top of two walls and it'll
help support the brace everything and
you can hang lights from it all kinds of
neat [ __ ] that's why we brought Jesse
that's why he's here it's why you pay
him the big bucks all right so once
everything's framed up uh you can
insulate the room with the blue
insulation boards if you want to make it
more soundproof and more uh have more
stable Temps I don't find that to be too
necessary if you're in a basement if
you're in the garage maybe because it's
going to get colder yeah in the winter
and hotter in the summer but the
basement like we talked about stays
fairly cool most of the time uh some
people choose to use plywood or some
type of board on the walls whatever you
want is cool build it how you like at
that point but once you've decided on
the walls and insulation that's when we
hang uh we call it poly or Panda
film uh PO is basically plastic sheeting
that's white on one side and black on
the other now you hang the white side on
the inside of the room and the black
side on the outside of the room uh it'll
the white will keep the reflection of
your light in there and give you more
efficiency uh you need to cover up the
whole room the walls the floor and the
ceiling and seal it up with tape seal up
any spots where bugs can get in uh any
spots where light can get out you want
it to be a little Fortress that's its
own private little room you want to seal
that [ __ ] up and the the more time you
take and the tighter you get all the
plastic and everything there's less of a
spot for
um bugs to get and stuff like that like
yes take your time with this stuff take
your time with it uh if you can if you
have a little bit of overlap everywhere
there's some kind of Gap that's a good
idea when you're putting your Staples in
put down a little square of duct tape
yep and then the staple yeah yeah
because that'll help from the poly
tearing it'll also keep the Staple in a
little bit better you can also go back
and take a uh little bit of silicone
cocking um and uh um stick that right
over the staple had to make sure I got
that l in there yeah yeah you don't want
to have your [ __ ] out in the grow room
yeah all right so now you've basically
built a little grow Hut like we were
talking about um most of what we're
going to talk about now works in the
grow huts and it translates it kind of
translates to if you're just working
with a bedroom also if you'd haven't
built a room the main difference is you
won't have the buffer zone around the
grow area if you're in a bedroom you'll
need to vent out of the room or the
house without anybody noticing uh the
room that we've built inside of the
rooms gives you more privacy and I feel
like a little bit more control should we
uh go over a bedroom uh how to vent out
a window real seat uh schnazzy like real
quick I think I talk a little bit about
it
um yeah we can talk about it and if when
I get to it later on we'll just skip it
later okay so crack your window open um
half inch inch kind of depends on how
much air flow you need through it uh and
then screw it shut
um or at least screw it to where it
can't be opened any further and you do
that by
uh real gently running a nice 3-in screw
through the uh most people have vinyl
windows um through the the inside uh
track of where the window goes up and
down that'll hold the window shut keep
someone from ripping it open then you
take your your W window blinds get you a
nice new set of mini blinds cheap ones
um throw that down close them so that
you know no light can go through um
maybe leave them open a qu inch at
bottom uh air will still suck through it
pretty pretty good um and then take
Panda film put the white side to the
outside of the window staple it over
that and then take you a piece of
plywood screw it up over the wall and
you can cut holes and mount uh Mount
fans on there and all your ducting and
everything there you go yeah so you can
use one window as an intake and one
windows and exhaust have you ever done
the thing where you uh put the blinds up
just like you said
uh I would close the window or leave it
open just a little bit okay we got to
leave it open for what we're doing on
this one sorry too many ideas in my head
uh you leave the half inch Gap and then
you build basically a box around the
window so you take some plywood and you
make like three inch deep little square
around the the like an inch around the
window and then you put a piece of
plywood over that and then you can put
all your ducting in that Plywood And it
almost looks like you could put like a
Christmas light or a candle light or
something in there and it looks like
somebody's home all the time and it just
makes it look like you got a light you
know just like it's the room and you can
actually use that as ducting and [ __ ]
too now because it's open I did one I I
actually stuck a Christmas light in
there a yellow one and it reflected off
all the plastic and everything enough to
you know you could just flip it on is on
a little timer and everything and then
now you've got a a window open and it
looks like somebody's home you got a
light on in there and it looks like it's
just part of the normal yeah so if
you're I have no idea why we would need
to be that
secretive you know it's mostly uh I'm
not worried as worried about the police
as I am about the thieves I actually
heard a story about some thieves getting
into somebody's air they went in through
their house through the air conditioning
duct and were taking their plants while
the people were home oh wow they found
out and I shouldn't even be talking
about this cuz now whatever but uh the
people found out their plants were being
stolen because of the cops knocked on
the door and found kids running out
their backyard with pot plants oh God
yeah right I don't know how that story
ended I bailed on that conversation
yeah scary [ __ ] all right so I hope my
story about building the Box around the
window makes sense it's I kind of had a
vague idea of how to do that in my head
I was thinking too many thoughts so you
take a just shape the the size of the
window you add an inch square so now if
your window is 24x 24 you make it 25 by
25 square piece of plywood and then you
make a freaking box out of it you know
what I mean like a half box so it's only
you only need it 3 inches deep make a
little tray and then put that up against
the window and then you can put a
curtain and just make it look like it's
a real window yeah it works you guys can
math that out in your brain I hope sorry
I wrote a bunch of [ __ ] and that's not
on all my notes you're just messing with
my brain
man let's see where was I on all these
papers I hate uh I hate sloppy uh
Windows um I've actually seen a few
houses around town drive around you're
like oh yeah there's one I know what
that is come on man there there's
actually two I can drive to right now
and be like grow house yeah right there
you can always see the metal highlight
in the
Attic all right
so hang that poly real carefully Like
Jesse said take your time with the poly
this is the building of the room these
are your walls you wouldn't build your
house wall is all shitty you want your
plant room nice um cover the whole room
seal it up seal any spots where [ __ ] can
get in now we basically you got that
little grut uh we're talking about a
bedroom I think I already did most of
with the part I'm talking about uh more
privacy so now you got the room built
and sealed up if you're going to use a
bedroom make sure to clean and dust the
bedroom first get onliner oh yeah yeah
that's definitely on my list [ __ ] uh
cover the windows where the light can
get in or get out cover any cracks if
you got cracks in the walls cover those
uh cover all your walls in the bedroom
with reflective material the panda film
Works in a bedroom also pull up the
carpet if you have that option cover the
floor if possible and right here I wrote
I like a pond liner for my floor um I
like to get the pond liner about 3 to 4
in up the wall all the way around the
room so if you do accidentally flood
your res in that room or you spill a
bucket or something that's cool you just
got a pond liner there to catch it all
and in the doorway there uh to help keep
the doorway all sealed up just cut you a
door a
2x4 um is wide as your doorway stand it
up on the outside and screw it in place
and then that's a place to staple your
pond liner too yeah so it turns the
whole little bedroom into a pond you
know you're going to have to step up
when you go in and out but you know big
deal I like the way you did that because
I did it kind of a shitty way in my my
newest build it works but I didn't do it
that smooth
this
guy a nice little air seal if you put it
real tight and everything put a piece of
foam in there and that's something we're
going to talk a little bit about because
some of us are going to have to use that
crevice underneath the door to let air
in yeah true that's actually a pretty
good spot if for some of us and that's
guys everything I'm talking about is uh
under ideal conditions yeah this I mean
there's I'm just trying to throw out
ideals out there cuz there's so many
ways you could use I mean and so much
that different
if you walked
into okay this is a four bedroom house
if we walked into all four bedrooms and
tried to build a grow room in it we'd
have to deal with different obstacles in
every single room each room would have
different [ __ ] to deal with yeah that
room's only got a window on that side
that room you can't mess with the window
because it's right up against the
neighbor's house if you exhaust out
there you're going to be blowing heat
into the neighbor's window basically so
there'd be some obstacles yeah all right
so wherever you are you're going to have
to deal with some [ __ ] everything we're
saying is just kind of kind of hopefully
going to work for what we're doing so
now we've got this clean room basically
we've got a Hut that's sealed up uh
we're going to add so you got your 8 by8
by8 room it's all Panda filmed or you've
got a 10 x10 grow Hut or whatever
something similar uh now this is where
you want to add an intake and an outtake
uh I talked in that last episode a lot
about how important it is to vent you
the air in your grow I like those inline
style fans or blowers I like the vortex
Vortex has always been reliable the can
fan is great they're a little more
expensive but they're adjustable speed
and dude those are reliable uh those
green h Hydrofarm blowers those are
reliable they work but they're loud yeah
they're really loud and they're the
green hydrarm inline boosters are
junk all right yeah don't waste your
money on them Jesse works at a hydro
shop and I was not going to bash any
brand but since he works there and has
to order from them we'll let him go
ahead and talk
[ __ ] yeah well I mean it is what it is
they there's a reason they sell uh um so
many refurbished ones of those that's a
lot of grow stores who get the uh Hydro
Farm no I just better shut up yeah all
of what he says is allegedly and I am
not responsible for that I like uh for
for the room we're going to build we
need an 8 in blower um I'm going to say
get a can fan or a Vortex and don't buy
one of the green hydrarm ones get a um
get if you can afford the can fan get
that the vortex is ideal next so yeah
the hydrarm blowers are great it's the
the booster you know the ones that the
one that go in the ducting yeah yeah
those those are all crap no matter who
makes them those are all crap I think
can fans isn't bad but okay it's that's
not a primary fan you know it says
booster on the box so okay all right
yeah if you got the right blower you
don't need the
booster so add that uh let's see where
were we 8 inch blower attach the blower
uh to the framing and get it fairly high
in the room depending on where you are
some of you guys might need to do this
in the dead center of the room some of
you may need to do it off to a corner
just try to get High uh I think it's
better to get the heat high it's better
to dump it out of the room High I like
to do everything
High all right so now this is when you
need to decide if you're going to use
vented hoods or open hoods uh vented
hoods are the ones uh just for the
people that are new with this your light
reflectors and hoods vented ones mean
they have glass on the bottom and
they're sealed and your ducting will
attach to it and the light will be moved
away from the grow and not dropping down
on your plants if you have open hoods
you're going to have to have more air
conditioning but you don't have to have
as much ducting so that's when you need
to think about what you got to do you
get more value for your for your light
that way but air conditioning is
expensive right I like the vented style
yeah that's pretty much industry
standard I'd say yeah unless you're in
I've actually seen a couple of huge
rooms that just dump AC at ridiculous
levels and it's in a couple yeah when if
if you're supplementing CO2 and stuff
you can't be exhausting a lot yeah takes
a little bit more
work um and if you're really cool kids
you got the gavitas or the nanolas or
something like that oh yeah those
gavitas you can't duct those so then
you're going to okay so if you're using
gavitas you're going to have to use more
air conditioning a lot more a lot more
all right so if you're using open hoods
and you're trying for the ducting
situation we're doing you can just
attach a carbon filter to your 8 in
blower and now you've pretty much
finished the extraction but if you're
using uh make sure you use the carbon
filter also that's what I want to add
make sure you're using the carbon filter
on the extraction fan cuz your crop is
going to stink like about week six
you're going to be able to smell
everything I just hit week five in the
middle of week five in a room and that
uh that Gorilla Glue number four is a
stinky little [ __ ] oh my God so if you
do use vented hoods you got to run
ducting we're running four lights in
this design so I would do it kind of
like this but I'm going to take a little
drink of this drink first right now
taking a drink
and that was well deserved all right so
if we're building this room with four
lights I would put a large carbon filter
I like the 39 by8 carbon filter they
have those available right now at hyro
indoor growing
supplies then I would take that 38 by 8
in carb uh 39 by 8 in carbon filter I
would use an 8 in y duct that goes into
two 6in ducks so now my eight just went
to two sixes and I would use the Y to
run the ducting to two two lights on
each side so I would have light 1 a
light 2 a and then light 1B Light 2 B on
opposite sides and then use another y
duct more ducting and then a y duct to
bring them back together and then attach
that y duct and the 8 in
blower uh I wrote something weird
they're attached that Y and the 8 inch
blower and the blower send the air out
of the room something I wrote doesn't
make sense but attach that y duct to the
blower and then send the air see I
already have something wrong here
because you should have carbon filter
blower is the way it should go yeah so
it should be carbon filter blower
ducting or carbon filter blower y
ducting light light Y and then out of
the house yeah is where it should go I
type something different but I must have
just been high at that
time that'd be a good spot for a booster
fan that right at the end there would be
the perfect spot uh so in this case
we're running it out of the grow Hut or
out of this 8 by8 room that we built or
if you're in the bedroom that's when you
got to build that little wall and
running out of that duct or that little
box that we made
there that was a good burp I'm glad I
got that one off the microphone um in
some cases you're going to need to run
the ducting out of the house or to
another room uh booster fans come in
handy there try to keep the uh the
ducting as short and straight as
possible you don't want a lot of bends
in your ducting and you don't want
excessive long ducting also if you can
hang your carbon filter from the ceiling
yeah because all of your heat and stale
air is going to go up hopefully air
moves just like water so you know if you
got to um pump it all the way to the
ceiling from the floor you know that's
just uh stealing energy there you go and
heat rises so you put that thing up
there and you're yeah and then it won't
suck stinks more too so yes that's very
true stick it on the ceiling yeah uh and
your carbon filter will work better if
you keep the humidity at a more
acceptable level get it closer to 50 get
away from that 70% like I've seen a
couple of guys in their flower rooms at
70% humidity cuz they say it makes the
bud sticky it'll make your bud moldy as
what you're going to get bro I've seen
flower rooms with 0% humidity so much
good old Southern Colorado fres just
going to say it's Colorado bro don't
look at me like that and then your
carbon filter pretty much quits working
at that point too yeah yeah you need
some some moisture to keep that charcoal
active dear God all right so we've got
an exhaust set up now you need air in
uh depending on the situation I might
make uh a 4in hole 6 in from the corners
and 6 in off the ground uh so imagine
there's the corner of the room I would
go 6 in in and 6 in up and make a 4in
hole and then on the opposite side of
that corner do the same thing and
that'll give you eight 4in holes for
fresh air uh then I go and get those
HEPA filters from Lowe's they're just
little square sheets and I staple those
over the holes to keep any dirt bugs uh
freaking dog hair hippie hair keep all
that [ __ ] out of the grow room with
those Hippa filters they work pretty
well uh I use dryer vents to cover and
prevent light leaks um right on the
outside I put those on the outside uh to
where or you can put them on the inside
too if you need to but I like them on
the outside they just look smoother but
you know the inside may work cuz now the
lights coming this way it's not going to
get in there if you're using them for an
intake don't forget to take the little
flapper out yeah I've actually heard one
going and I like what what is that no oh
[ __ ] I forgot to take that out yeah um
you could replace the small holes with
one big hole and you can have a blower
in there if you do have something
bringing air in make sure that it is
smaller than the exhaust fan you want to
suck out more than what you're bringing
in you want to create negative pressure
in a grow room you want it to feel if
you have a real door if it's in a
bedroom when you open the door you want
the you want to turn the knob and you
want the door to fly open on its own
that's how you know you got enough
pressure in a grow room positive
pressure is that that's negative sucking
oh yeah yeah never mind yeah I I was
actually thinking of a room I was just
in so the door would have been yeah
never
mind we'll catch up we'll get you on the
same show well I'm doing episode 39 I
don't know what number you're on 42
man all right so now
we've guys I wonder what's going to
happen on episode 42 because Jesse just
jumped to the Future on me it clicked in
my brain a second late I was like wait
man we got to catch up all right so you
can replace all those holes with a big
blower uh you've got fresh air being
pulled in when the exhaust van pulls out
Stella air and humidity out of the room
room and out of the house what does that
even mean you can tell I was lit when I
wrote some of these notes and it got
late uh so we got fresh air coming in uh
when the exhaust fan pulls the stale air
and humidity out of the room so you can
add an air conditioner to bring in fresh
air also uh you might be able to bring
in enough air under the bedroom door if
you're doing this in a bedroom um I had
a perfect little girl when I first
started off it was in a bedroom and I
had the blower going over one light I
had a 6-in blower I was going over two
lights and sucking straight out of the
room and I hung a carbon filter in the
ceiling and I just let the fresh air
come right under the door and I feel
like it was enough air nice yeah yeah I
feel like it was sufficient in there it
didn't get stifled or anything in there
so that space under the door guys that
could be useful you need fresh air
coming in so if you're building this big
8 by8 room cut some holes in there or
add a blower if you're using an 8 in
blower out you can use a four or a 6in
blower in I think and you'll be just
fine and even if you're running a sealed
room I hate seeing this this is a a
little more advanced stuff but um even
sealed rooms need to have the ability to
inject fresh air
um you know even if you don't use it but
once a week or something like that it's
you still need to recycle your air every
now and then pumping CO2 into air it's I
don't know I I know uh do you know what
I mean I know what you mean uh he's
talking about a uh control a closed
environment agriculture room where
everything is sealed up the only air
that goes in the room is CO2 that's
supplemented with the CO2 tank we'll
talk a little bit about that in the
future um because plants actually breed
CO2 and let out oxygen but I think just
pumping all that CO2 in there they are
going to need some oxygen your roots
need oxygen your micro it gets stale in
there yeah yeah so I agree you have to
put some oxygen in that closed room
somehow and just use those Hippa filters
and filter your air they also sell those
shroom things the shroom covers I'm a
big fan of those okay
I've always thought they were a little
overpriced so I've just stuck with the
hip of filters I can't argue with that
yeah so yeah um we sell a much bigger
intake filter that's uh similar to a
carbon filter and uh um you know it's
not applicable in all situations but um
it's very reasonably priced for what it
is the lifespan it's just touch over 100
and it does some serious filtering so
you can bring air from outside into your
grow essentially if you filter it with
that okay [ __ ] that's worth a ton of
money it looks like a gigantic uh k&amp; air
K&amp;N air filter for like a freaking F22
Raptor or some
[ __ ] oh I wonder God imagine when you're
done with that thing you go dump it in
the [ __ ] oops $5 you go dump it in
the [ __ ] landfill I'm not doing that
anymore I just called it was over I'm
glad you go dump in the landfill and you
set it down I'm just picturing like some
sort of Breaking Bad desert is where I
was watching somebody in my mind dump it
like throws it down in the desert and
all these bugs and like imagine all the
crazy [ __ ] that's going to come out cuz
you got a blower attached to it sucking
every bug that flies by is going to go
and just get sucked into that and get
stuck in your trap now we'll go Huck it
over the fence at the Monsanto facility
there we go we're coming for you
biological warfare we're coming for you
all right I'm going to try to I've got
like three more pages of stuff typed out
and I'm going to have to edit out the FW
so we're going to have to finish the
show pretty soon you should leave just
that part in though I'll leave the f-
word in I'm done with paying $5 for it I
already declared that earlier in the
show we're
cool I was just so daydreaming and
thinking about like where would this
thing because you can't like I wasn't
picturing me and you doing it I'm
picturing like some shady grower with
this big gigantic vent cleaner and he's
just rolling it out of the back of his
truck in the desert somewhere and I'm
just like oh imagine what comes out of
that dude hair bugs it's going to not
going to be anything
pretty all kinds of weird molds and
danders and pollins oh man yeah oh so
gross all right let me that's what I was
that was one thing when I was actually
uh researching it before we got it I was
like oh uh this will be great for uh out
protection from outdoor uh yeah uh
amateurs outdoor amateur pollen yeah or
hemp man I've got a male that might blow
soon you just reminded me that I did not
move it earlier oh [ __ ] he's in a shitty
spot if he goes I don't want that to
happen premature uh yeah he's in yeah I
don't need him to go he's in a bad spot
all right so guys uh we've been ranting
here we're going to try to get back on
track for a little bit we got 15 more
minutes or so before everyone's going to
get ad kind of already happened to us uh
since we've got ducting in place let's
hang up some lights guys in this room we
have an 8 by8 footprint and four lights
that means means we can use a 4x4 area
for each light it's going to be bright
in here that's what we want divide the
room into perfect quarters find the
center for each quarter hang your lights
so they're centered in the corners or
the quarters not Corners you want them
centered in the
quarters uh so basically you got a 4x4
section with the light perfectly above
it and every 4x4 space has a light right
above it Jesse's doing math on how many
lumens and how many watts per square
foot that is yes it's impressive you
could do 600 watt lights in the setup if
you wanted thousands are the way go in
here I
think that's my professional opinion if
you've got the electricity and you're
building this room put thousands in
there oh yeah no I uh totally agree all
right I use those little uh so 64 square
feet obviously that's simple
math
um I'm all stoned work a
calculator wrong way always divide
things the wrong way that's uh 62 uh uh
watch per square foot and what would be
your recommendation Mr Hydro shop expert
um that's a really healthy W uh per
square foot all right yeah this is going
to be a healthy room hey Ryan you've got
a room kind of like this dude so good
job you might have taken some advice
from me that's no tiarra Rojo uh 120
watts per square foot but yeah that
indoor acre we were talking about a spot
called the indoor acre is what is that
place is amazing there's like a mile and
a half of Plum in there just for the
hydro kit all right so we're hanging our
lights they're in the corner the the the
center of the quarters of the room right
there might be a lot of editing on this
show guys we're dabbed out so I like to
use those little ey hooks I sell at
Lowe's they're just uh screws with a
little circle at the end of it basically
screw that into the ceiling uh screw it
directly into the ceiling beams make
sure you hit a stud yes well there'll
only be studs there I mean have myar or
a St or plastic or a stud so make sure
you get it in there yeah if you're in a
bedroom though yeah yeah okay there you
go right on I forgot about the bedroom
actually got a quick trick for that and
it helps you Center your lights take two
8ot uh 2x4s screw them to the ceiling
then you put your lights anywhere you
want you always know you hit a stud yeah
I need to do that in one one
area yeah I worked at a place where the
lights were um I I worked for two
companies in the same building
ironically um and at the first company I
didn't help set anything up um and all
the lights were hung from a floating
grid ceiling big old Raptor hoods uh
with little tiny plastic hooks is
absolutely like just super dangerous
dumbass move um but uh when I went to
work for the other company I got paid to
do a 2x4 structure all through the that
uh could support a couple gorillas so
yeah guys be safe when you're building
stuff we've talked about not being that
[ __ ] that burns down the house also
don't be the guy that takes down the
bedroom on accident if you're renting
you're going to have to pay for whatever
you mess up all right um I like those
little light hangers to hang my lights
the ratchet style ones those are perfect
I love them uh hang all four lights
screw in your bulbs and wipe off the
bulbs when you're done uh wipe them off
I like to use like a uh it's a thing
that you should be cleaning your drums
with it's a little soft uh it's like a
microfiber Yeah clean it off with that
sunglass stuff yeah sunglass stuff
exactly you don't want any scratches in
there uh in in the bulb or any dust or
dirt on there or any oil from your
finger on there any little thing that
close to the bulb is going to definitely
kill lumens make sure your bulb is
screwed in completely yeah that and all
of your connections are all pushed and
tight on your ballast as well so screw
in your bulbs wipe it off make sure it's
tight uh run the ducting from the blower
to the Y duct to each light back to the
other y out of your grow room and then
secure all of those ductings with tape
there's going to be a lot of pressure on
the the duct uh an 8 in blower puts out
a lot of pressure it may be a good idea
also to grab a fan speed controller U
you plug that in and then you plug your
fan into that and you can actually your
blower your 8 in Vortex blower you can
adjust how much by percentage of from it
only works about 50% is as low as I
think it goes but then you can go from
50 all the way to 100 uh if you're
wanting to keep a little humidity in the
room turn it down you can get it down to
you know 50% % humidity turn it down to
70% it'll help you out that's actually
how I run it in one space at about 70%
all the time and so many of the can fans
come with the little three-speed switch
on the cord already adjusted to it yeah
so that may be beneficial and the hyper
fan the best fan on the market in my
opinion it comes with one built-in ah
see that's a new product for me when I
upgrade it's time for some of those all
right so now we've got ducting you got
lights hung it's kind of starting to
look like a grow room uh you got to hang
a couple fans on the walls
I would put fans uh right above the
expected height of your plants like if
you think your plants are going to get
5T tall put a fan at 5 and a half ft uh
right between the fan can or the light
canop the damn lot of words right
between the plant canopy and the lights
is kind of where I like a fan yeah keep
the air moving uh you don't want the air
to get stale plants suck up the CO2 in
the room quickly they can use the CO2
around them super quickly and you just
got to move the air so there's more CO2
for them to use up yeah we're 51 minutes
in go ahead what are we going to say
would you throw uh maybe a box fan on
the floor I do like a box fan on the
floor super low speed um if you're on a
budget the box fan is awesome if you
have more of a budget I would recommend
a carbon filter with like a 6 in blower
on top of it just dead sitting in the
center of the room put some ducting off
the blower up to the ceiling and just
move that air from the floor back up to
the ceiling and you're picking up CO2
off the ground and putting it back up to
fall back down onto your plants nice
yeah yeah and that's just differences in
budgets if you've got a low if you got
30 bucks buy a fan if you got 160 buy a
blower and a filter yeah just kind of or
I guess it's going to be closer to 260 I
guess that blower is going to be 120 130
your filters are going to be got
expensive you know uh I've watched
everything escalate in price uh since
I've been expanding my grows and since
Colorado has been getting more popular
everything has just gone up in price and
it's not even a competitive raise it's a
gouging raise and we I can see it they
know what we're doing I uh man remember
buying a light in like
2002 and keeping your head down at the
store trying not to be noticed man I
swear I paid like five 600 bucks for my
first light setup and it's just a
magnetic uh 400 watt like nothing
special whatsoever so but everything
else I feel like has got more expensive
yeah um lighting is the only only thing
and actually I guess it's just because
there's so many newer options but basic
lighting I feel like's gotten
cheaper yeah and more reliable I
remember you would you'd buy [ __ ] and it
would just die on you and now stuff
seems to last at least a year or two and
if if it doesn't you can take it back
all right we've gone 52 minutes my next
part is all about hanging up the ballast
and electronics and making the board
that I like to hang my stuff on I think
I'm going to leave everybody hanging and
we're going to do that part of the next
episode and I got a trick to help you
take better pictures when you're doing
that oo oh Jesse's going to help us out
with some tricks um when can you come
back and do another episode bro probably
next week all right yeah um we'll try to
get him back for part three of our
growing our building our grow room
episode I'm going to give a huge huge
super huge shout out to high gr indoor
growing supplies I know jessee's here so
I'm kissing his ass a little bit but
seriously uh they helped me out a lot
they sponsored this show and without
them I couldn't do some of the things
that I do do you have any idea when the
next Growers meeting is going to be yeah
um I'm really bad with dates but I know
when it is he's one of those guys that
can build you a freaking Farm in 10
minutes but if you give him math or a
calendar he just gets all this like look
on his face of like can I hit it great
with math I just can't ever do my work
but um where the hell I just got a new
phone so he stepped up into the future
yeah so he's looking through his phone
to find out when the next next Growers
meeting is at high gr indoor growing
supplies We Gather at the back of the
shop can we talk about growing it's
going to be Friday the 21st Friday the
21st of October yeah November November
November because we can't go back in
time no yeah
well it's my favorite movie ever Back to
the Future Trilogy all right guys I'm
going to have to get free that day no
matter what happens because you guys are
all going to come say the date again uh
November 21st November 21st it's a
Friday at H gr indoor growing supplies
about 6
6:15 uh yeah yeah uh we did it 4: to 8
last time and kind of decided the 2
hours when we were open was kind of lame
so okay that's a little hint there but
I'm not saying anything but um we're GNA
have
uh I don't know it's awful yeah no we're
going to have barbecue pork we were
thinking about doing turkey but
everyone's going to have plenty of
turkey I don't want to be that [ __ ]
oh that's true yeah that's true but uh
we're going have some good smoked pork
um from probably my dad will do it uh
he's been smoking meat for many years
Jesse's dad is a cool son of a [ __ ] and
I am going to get a veeg awesome
vegetarian option too so nice that's
much appreciated and just for people who
need to eat their damn veggies so
everyone eats your veggies eat your
vegetables guys I've been a vegetarian
for oh my God over 10 years I can't
remember exactly when I know I was a
vegetarian in 2002 for sure um I can't
remember before that when and I started
but there was an event that happened and
one of my friends I hadn't seen in a
while made fun of me for being a
vegetarian at bonaroo and I remember the
first bonaroo was 2002 so I've been a
vegetarian since then and ni since I
started eating better I eat I try to eat
a little better and better and better
all the time but the more I take care of
my body the better I feel it's so great
so eat your vegetables guys that's a
that's a not don't eat as much meat you
know even if you do eat meat yeah
America eats way way too much of it and
try to eat food quit eating like food
product
like processed [ __ ] that kind of
resembles food you don't want that you
want food if it's got like 17
ingredients in it that's not food
anymore yeah look for the fewer
ingredients and the easier they are to
pronounce yeah yeah all those osis and
exosis and udam matens none of that [ __ ]
is good for you all right we're kind of
rambling now how about we uh wrap up a
podcast and we'll look forward to
talking to you guys in about seven days
where's the end I've got that thing I
read at the end of the show and I can't
find it guys what am I going to do going
to have to add lib I think I saw it
there's the paper I need all right guys
don't forget to follow Jesse on
Instagram and Twitter it's Jesse gr OG
on Twitter it's Jesse grow on Instagram
make sure you follow iy genetics on
Instagram make sure you follow I gr
culture on Twitter Instagram and
Facebook that's a lot of demand just
check us out if you can I'll quit
begging do it and do it now yes open up
your we need to get some like really
cool tone open up your your phone and
follow us on
Instagram hey I want to give a shout out
to uh Yeti OG that's just an awesome
strain so I got some yeti in middle of
week five and it is fire yeah it looks
great that's my favorite new strain it
that I uh got my hands on this
year we'll see well I haven't ran the
glue yet I'm getting close to I've got
them next to each other in a room
there's cookies Yeti Sour Diesel
Grateful Dog two gorilla glues and then
two Platinum ogs all in a row so that's
like my stellar row yeah I'm like let's
see what these girls do next to each
other they're all getting fed the same
thing they're all under the same two
lights we'll see what they do they're in
seven gallon pots I'm getting excited uh
just recently I got to Chuck pollen uh
took a Grateful Dog mail and threw his
pollen all over a bunch of sexy ladies
so in about January Nature's green
remedies will be stocked up nice nice
yeah all right now that the show's over
go to it Tunes Andor Stitcher search for
IG gr culture find the review section
give me a festar rating after that type
in a comment and let me know what you
think of the podcast and I will read
your comments on a future episode big
thanks to all the guys that have left
comments I appreciate that the guys and
gals that have left comments I do
appreciate that uh don't forget that the
show is available on iTunes Stitcher and
every episode is available on IR
genetics.com yes I have been slacking
off on putting videos on YouTube but I
will catch up pretty soon I've been
having too much fun lately went to
Garden of the Gods with my friend and
had a great time just enjoyed life for a
couple of days I'm sorry I'll get back
on track don't worry I want to give a
huge shout out to my ninja Spence I want
to send an extra special thanks to Jesse
for coming to all these episodes it's
really cool thanks a lot bro no problem
I enjoy it having fun he's getting good
at it isn't he guys you can tell he's so
much more comfortable now I'll sit in
here like Larry King with a pin in my
hand get you some suspenders bro that'
be dope hijack my Dad's closet there we
go all right guys thanks again for
listening take a fat dab and give your
mom a hug for me hey
baby e