welcome to the show podcast world it is
time for episode 390 of The Grove from
your heart podcast this episode of the
show is brought to you by Oregon elite
seeds that's right Oregon elite seeds
North America's largest online seed
retailer if you need new seeds for your
garden I highly recommend Oregon elite
seeds and you can find them at
www.cdxzipstream.com a be curious what
is that Buckeye banana the Buckeye
banana is the Ohio Buckeye from Melvin
etics cross - the banana og from Texas
kid I've got some pollen from that plant
and I applied that to the blueberry
cookies and the strawberry fields I
think those will make some very
interesting crosses I don't plan to
release those seeds at least not the F
ones maybe further generations my
initial goal here with this original
pollination is to create a few seeds for
myself to play with I'm really excited
to find a male from the blueberry
cookies Buckeye banana cross I'm hoping
to find a male that stays kind of short
kind of squat kind of branchy I want
tight internode spacing I'm hoping to
have big fat indica dominant leaves I'm
hoping to find a male it doesn't take a
really long time to start producing
pollen I want sort of a shorter
flowering plant at this time I'm also
hoping that that plant carries the
aroma from the blueberry cookies but
then I want the colors from the Buckeye
purple then I want the trichome content
from the banana og so I know what I'm
looking for on this mail I just have to
find it in the amount of seeds that I
create I anticipate I've created about
thirty to fifty seeds in my experience
with the size plant that I pollinated I
didn't have as much pollen as I wish I
would have had but I feel like I did a
pretty good job pollinating those little
tiny plants so in several weeks those
seeds will be done I'll harvest the
plants I'll dry the plants I'll crack up
the buds I'll get the seeds out I'll
pick a few seeds
I'll germinate them I will grow them
hopefully I find a super stud of a male
in that first batch of seeds hopefully I
find a couple of sexy females in that
first batch of seeds based on what I see
from that first batch of seeds I will
make my decisions on which plants I
choose to pollinate with that new male
plant and I will also decide if I choose
to make f2s
or further generations of this seed line
I can't really make any commitments or
get too big of an idea at this point in
time because I don't know what I am
creating I like to have confidence I
like to believe in myself I like to feel
like I have a good intuition but these
plants may not breed well together that
is always an option I may have made just
a bunch of crap so I need to grow them
myself I need to see what I've created
before I get too excited I don't need to
put the cart in front of my horse and
start thinking about where I'm going to
sprinkle the pollen from a plant that
hasn't been selected yet so I can't make
any decisions I can't make any future
plans with this project until the
pollination creates seeds the seeds are
grown and I take a lot of notes and then
I know what I've got to work with all
right podcast world I've got one more
thing I'd like to mention before we get
to the main topic of the show which of
course is going to be the endo Expo I
would like to announce that I read
genetics is now a proud member of the
organ elite seeds team that's right
organ elite seeds North America's
largest online seed retailer now carries
Ayari genetic seeds make sure you check
them out at Oregon elite seeds dot-com
all right let's jump into the main topic
of this show which is the endo Expo the
endo Expo is the world
largest indoor cannabis and hemp expo
and it landed in denver on january 26th
and 27th and i was lucky enough to be
invited to be a vendor with oregon elite
seeds this year the past couple of years
I have attended the endo Expo as a
visitor I got to walk around and check
out the expo see all of the booths see
all of the vending see what was going on
in the entire place I walked a hundred
miles each weekend but this year
I got to share a booth with my friends
Oregon elite seeds our friends from
Oregon elite seeds hosted a booth and we
brought several breeders to the booth
with us we had always be flowering
hanging out we had Med tree seeds
hanging out with us and over the weekend
we had docs tank passed through we had
shoreline seeds pass through we had a
whole group of breeders at the booth all
weekend long it was a great time it was
my first time finding in a booth and I
honestly thought that it was going to be
really stressful but parking was the
hardest part and once he got parked all
you had to do is carry your [ __ ] in and
it all happened on its own the endo Expo
moves all around the country and does
shows every few months and this was
their tenth show so they've gotten
really good at organizing the event
everyone knows where to go everybody
knows where to be so it's not super
confusing like some of the cannabis
events tend to be so that was great so
loading in was super easy I started
meeting people and making friends at 8
a.m. Saturday morning we didn't get
loaded into the building before people
started coming up and asking questions
and introducing themselves I didn't
waste any time I got right to business
and right in action started shaking
hands I saw a lot of wonderful people
this weekend at the endo Expo let's get
into that part I saw a lot of old
friends there are some folks I only get
to see it endo Expos there are some
folks I only get to see it industry
events I miss a lot of those folks and
it is a great time seeing all of your
smiling faces so I really enjoyed that
part of the endo Expo being stuck at a
booth I didn't get to travel around
Saturday I left my booth one time to go
hit the men's room and it honestly took
me way too long to get away from my
booth to the men's room and back because
being a member of the Colorado cannabis
community at a cannabis event I was
quite popular I'm not trying to say I'm
popular but I know a lot of people at
that venue and it took me a really long
time
to get from my booth to the men's room
and back I didn't want to be away from
my booth for that long I felt like an
abandoned ship my logo my I read
genetics flag is hanging up on the wall
and I'm not there I don't like that
feeling so Saturday I was away for maybe
20 minutes to go use the restroom and
get right back then Sunday I didn't even
leave my booth I had no reason to take
off from the booth I didn't have an
opportunity to eat or drink anything
because the booth was so busy so
honestly there was no need to use the
restroom so what I'm getting at is I was
at my booth the entire time the entire
weekend and the good part about that is
everybody knew where to find me I posted
up to social media hey I am at booth
four one four come say what's up
so a lot of people stopped by and said
hello I got to see so many friends I got
to see of course I got to see all of my
Expo friends all my friends that I only
see at industry events I got to see
people that I have not seen in a long
time I got to meet new people that I
have never met before I get to meet
people I've been interacting with on
social media either Facebook or
Instagram or whatever it is for years
and I've never met them in person I got
to do some handshakes some high-five
some hugs that was really great got to
see what people smiles actually look
like because you could post whatever you
want on social media I got to meet a lot
of folks who listened to the podcast a
couple of the breeders next to me were
like man a lot of people are just
walking up and saying thank you what the
hell do you do and I was like ah bro
I've got a podcast they teach people how
to grow like man that is really cool a
lot of people stood in line to come
shake my hand and say thank you for
doing this podcast that meant a lot to
me that meant as much as all of the seed
business meant to me all weekend long so
thank you if you stopped and said hello
if you shook my hand and said thank you
for the podcast if you stopped by and
said hi at all that means the world to
me thank you for all of the support you
guys I also met a lot of other great
breeders there a lot of great breeders
stopped and said hi breeders I've been
like I said talking to interacting with
I finally got to meet all of those
breeders that I've been talking to
online and wondered what they look like
something I really enjoyed and something
that my friends at my booth were making
fun of me for is every dreadlock person
at the Indo Expo stopped at my booth and
said what's up they either came straight
to my booth or they'd be walking by and
they would see either me with dreads or
the
see my I read genetics flag which is the
Colorado flag been turned red yellow and
green they would see their me or that
flag and something in them would just
bring them right to my booth and they
would want to come talk to me and I
really love that all the deadheads all
the Rastas all the dreadlocks all the
freaks all the weirdos they all wanted
to come say what's up to me and that
really means a lot that I've kind of got
my own little niche community there in
the cannabis industry that really meant
a lot to me so big shout out big fist
bump to all the dreads all the Rastas
all the deadheads all the freaks and
weirdos all the freaky people that came
to see me this weekend big fist bump
that means a lot to me you guys thanks
for all the support also talking about
support I want to give a huge shout out
to a few of my fellow podcasters I
haven't known the boys from the dude
grows show for a little while I've met
Scottie and the dude a few times but I
don't remember ever meeting guru and I
finally got to meet guru from the dude
grows podcast at the Indo Expo what's up
guru thanks for taking some great
pictures of the dude and I thanks for
hanging out you're really cool dude I
hope we have more conversations in the
future also is good to see the dude the
dude has moved to Canada so it was
really great to see the dude back here
in Colorado
I met the dude at a dude grows cup a few
years ago in Denver in my mind he will
always be a part of the Colorado
cannabis seam so it was great to see my
buddy back in Colorado
it was great to take a few pictures and
get a few selfies and get a high-five
from one of my podcasting buddies so big
shout out to the dude hey scotty real i
didn't see you at the endo expo bro
where were you hope to catch up with you
next time scotty and if you guys aren't
listening to the dude Grows podcast make
sure you go give them a subscription
great cannabis podcast i think you will
enjoy the show if you like my show you
should definitely like the dude grows
podcast also i want to give a huge shout
out to Shango Lohse from the shaping
fire podcast several episodes back
I gave Django Louis and his podcast a
huge shout out Shango was gracious
enough to find me at the Indo Expo and
approached my booth and shake my hand
and personally thanked me for shouting
out his podcast on my show he told me
that he saw a measurable amount of new
subscribers because of my shout out and
I think it was really respectful that he
walked up and shook my hand and thanked
me personally
so if you're not listening to the
shaping fire podcast yet I recommend
that show also I think you can learn a
lot and I think you will really enjoy
the show so once again big shout out to
the boys from the dude grow show and
also a big shout-out to Shango lows from
the shaping fire podcast now I'm trying
not to get too specific with shout outs
because I met and interacted with so
many people this weekend that I know I
will end up leaving somebody out if I
tried to list everybody so I'm just
going to get to a few people since I'm
talking about fellow podcasters let's
talk about our friends from P and L grow
systems that's right my friends P and
Lee have been supporting the podcast for
a long time I have been supporting piano
grow systems for a very long time their
business is based out of London UK and
they made it all the way to Denver for
the Indo Expo to come be a part of the
Denver cannabis community it was a great
honor to finally say cans with my
friends Peter and Lee from PNL grow
systems it's been an honor to work with
them we've done a lot of great
promotions I've worked with their
equipment they've given me some
equipment in fact in a future episode
I've got a minder unit to give away to a
podcast listener so stay tuned for
details on that but it was great to
finally meet my friends that we have
supported each other for a long time and
they actually told me that they would
not have made it this far in their
company they certainly would not have
made it to the Indo Expo if it were not
for the support of myself and the Grove
from your heart podcast which means the
support from you folks that listen to
the show so it was great to finally
shake hands and get a hug and take a
picture with my friends P and Lee from p
NL grow systems what's up guys I hope
you're listening to this big shout out I
hope you make it back over here soon
I hope we get to hang out I hope we get
to spend more time together you guys
that is a great way to segue into my
next part of this podcast I want to talk
about the endo Expo I didn't get to see
much of the endo Expo because I was at
my booth the entire time I've mentioned
that before I spent the entire day at my
booth interacting with consumers it was
a great time I got to teach a lot about
cannabis I got to teach everybody about
I read genetics
I had a great debate about feminized
seeds I got to meet a lot of great
breeders I shared a booth with always be
flowering with med tree seeds
there were several other experienced and
great breeders that pass through our
booth and came and said hi so that led
to a lot of great conversation and a lot
of great introductions so that was a
great time however I wish I would have
gotten to see a little bit of the expo I
did see a little bit and from what I saw
there were a lot of seed vendors and
seed breeders from what I was told there
were over 20 I think we counted at least
23 seed sellers at the expo I know that
exotic genetics was there I know Kappa
later was there our booth was right down
the row from Brothers Grimm who is mr.
soll ethos genetics had a giant booth
there were a lot of seed sellers and
vendors there another thing that was
really popular at the endo Expo was LED
lighting another thing I saw a whole
bunch of was Auto trimming machines
which I'm not a fan of but they were
there I'm just telling you what I saw a
lot of Auto trimming machines also a lot
of extraction equipment something that
was really huge this year at endo Expo
was heme seed and CBD many of the people
that approached my booth on the first
day were from out of state and they were
looking for bulk hemp seed that they
could take home and start farming hemp
the other thing that was huge was CBD
last year there was an area known as the
hemp hallway and that hallway had all of
the hemp vendors this year there was the
hemp and CBD pavilion a large portion of
the Indo Expo Center was dedicated just
to hemp and CBD products you could find
anything with CBD in this area there
were dog treats with CBD in it I tasted
some amazing maple syrup that had CBD in
it there was CBD icecream there Reseda
SAVs and rubs there were CBD
concentrates available in that area
anything you could imagine to put CBD
into was available in that hip and CBD
Pavilion at the endo Expo this year so
even though I didn't get to see a large
portion of the endo Expo I still had the
time of my life this was my favorite
endo Expo I honestly thought it was
going to be stressful I thought that
running the booth may give me a little
bit of anxiety but honestly it went
super smoothly it went without a hitch I
couldn't have asked for a better time
and I honestly had the time of my life
so I want to give a huge shout out
again to everybody that came and said
hello everybody that high-fived me even
if you just kind of walked by the booth
and you just gave me that little head
nod that people do or the big eyes or
maybe you threw up a peace sign or maybe
you did a little fist bump across the
way if you said what's up to me at endo
expo what's up thanks for the love and
support if you came to the booth and
shook my hand if you walked away with
some gifts or if you walked away with a
shirt big up thanks for all the support
I appreciate it if you came and said
hello if you came and said thank you I
appreciate all that it meant the world
to me I still have a big silly smile on
my face from all of the fun I had at the
endo Expo and I can't wait for next year
all right you guys that is my Indo Expo
wrap-up I know this was a short sweet
podcast this was a Thursday episode I
hope you had fun hearing about the endo
Expo I'll be back Monday with another
episode most likely I am going to repost
the trimming episode as the next grow
lesson which will be followed by the
drying and curing episode which will
most likely be followed by the cleanup
and restart episode which will conclude
my long series of grow lessons at that
point I will start putting out brand new
content so if you've got questions if
you've got some emails now is a good
time to start sending those in I will
start getting them lined up for the new
episodes I want to thank you guys for
listening to the long series of grow
lessons I also want to thank you for
listening to this episode I look forward
to joining you on Monday don't forget to
find me on social media on Facebook
search for the girl from your heart
podcast on Twitter it's @gf wih podcast
on Instagram I use my seed company name
it's Irie underscore genetics I read
genetics on Instagram if you've got
something you'd like to say if you'd
like to sponsor the podcast or maybe
you've got a product you'd like me to
review you can send me an email the
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com that's all I've got for you
today I want to give a huge shout out to
closed-loop Lucy and until next time
take a phat dab and give your mom a hug
for me