hey welcome to the show podcast world it
is time for episode 391 of the growth
from your heart podcast this episode is
brought to you by Oregon elite seats if
you need new seeds in your garden I
highly recommend Oregon elite seeds and
you can find them at www.ge.com it has
become a tradition that we start the
podcast off by talking about what I'm
dabbing on today I'm taking dabs of
Starr dog ambrosia from our friends at
apothecary farms you guys know that I
love the star dog I love the aroma I
love the flavor and I love the head buzz
that it gives me if you've been
following along with the podcast you
know that I've been doing a long series
of grow lessons at this point in the
grow lessons it is time to dry and cure
our freshly harvested cannabis crop for
this lesson I'm going to repost episode
number 326 my original dry and cure
episode so ladies and gentlemen let's
time travel back to episode 326 and
let's recap drying and curing our
freshly harvested cannabis welcome back
cannabis community it's time for another
episode of the grow from your heart
podcast your source for cannabis news
education and conversation I try to hear
who grower if you're a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
dedicated Davor
if you're a cannabis activists or even
someone who is just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me this episode of the podcast
is brought to you by my friends at the
hell a dank seed company if you need new
genetics for your garden I highly
recommend the hella dank seed company
you can find them at dank seed dot store
ladies and gentlemen roll up a fat joint
pack up the bong or start heating up
that daybreak because it's time for
another episode of to grow from your
heart podcast
[Music]
welcome to the show internet world it is
time for episode 326 of the girl from
our podcast thanks again for joining me
I have got a very detailed episode
planned out for you this is going to be
the long awaited long anticipated dry
and cure episode we have done an episode
on determining ripeness we did an
episode on harvesting your plants now it
is time to dry and cure our cannabis
plants before we get there let's cover a
little bit of business this episode of
the girl from your heart podcast is
brought to you by my friends at the hell
a dank seed company if you need new
regular or feminized seeds for your
garden I highly recommend the hell a
dank seed company you can find them at
dank seed dot store ladies and gentlemen
please support my friends at the hella
dank seed company also this podcast is
brought to you by our friends at pol
grow systems you should know what's
going on in your grow room at all times
and you can pay close attention with a
Pio grow minder unit so check out my
friends at pol grow systems at pl grow
dot systems one more order of business a
lot of people let me know that the
episode with Deb and granny and giddyup
and Max had an audio issue
ladies and gentlemen that audio issue
has been corrected if you were
frustrated listening to that show I
encourage you to go back and check out
the corrected audio version of that
podcast thanks for being patient with me
and big thanks to everybody who let me
know there was a technical issue
and speaking of technical issues I am
still working with stitcher to resolve
the technical issues that happen
randomly some episodes will play for
some people some episodes randomly will
not play for people the only people
experiencing the technical issues are
people who are listening to the podcast
through the stitcher application on an
Android device sometimes it works for
you sometimes it doesn't I'm not sure
what's causing it we thought we had it
narrowed down we corrected a couple of
things it has done it again I will keep
working at getting that resolved if you
can't listen to the episodes through
stitcher through the application you can
always go to the stitcher website you
can find the show there also you can
find the show on YouTube I'm trying to
keep all the episodes updated on YouTube
so I apologize if stitcher is fighting
you I am working on it the tech team and
the customer support team
stitcher are helping me and we cannot
find the problem all right I feel like
I've gotten most of the technical
business out of the way let's get into a
podcast ladies and gentlemen you know I
like to start the episodes off by
letting you know what I am smoking on
today I've got the honor of dabbing some
sauce made by a friend this was locally
grown and locally extract that my buddy
doesn't want to be mentioned on the show
so I'm not gonna say his name but dude
thanks for the great work my friend
gruesome cream of course I bread the
cream the cream is cookies and cream to
arise I passed along some seeds he grew
it he harvested it he extracted and made
sauce out of it then he was kind enough
to bring me a couple of sample jars and
you guys this stuff is tremendous it's
almost gone because it is so delicious
he brought me a little sample of
straight isolated crystals he brought me
a little sample of straight isolated
Terps and he also brought me a sample of
the two combined so I've got the Terps
I've got the crystals and then I've got
the saucy mixture put together at a
beautiful ratio you guys the mixture
smells like cupcake frosting and cookie
dough and then we need to take a dab of
it it tastes like you just took a big
bite of cookie dough with cupcake
frosting on it and then when you blow it
out it smells like somebody's baking
fresh cookies in the room it smells like
warm chocolate chip and cinnamon cookies
filling the room this concentrate is
excellent it is super smooth I took a
couple of gigantic dabs there was no
throat tingle
there was no heaviness on the exhale
super smooth super clean super delicious
concentrates dude I know you don't want
me to say your name on the air but great
product great work you did a hell of a
job with this this stuff tastes amazing
the only problem is that it is almost
gone I've probably got one or two dabs
before this stuff is extinct so bro come
back with a bigger jar and let's uh
let's make a deal all right you guys I
am obviously loving these cream dabs
grown and extracted by a local farmer
hey bro great work I truly do appreciate
it in fact this episode is gonna be
really long so I've got all the opening
business covered I'm gonna press pause
I'm gonna take a DAB probably the last
two dads of this cream and when I get
back I will give a long lesson on drying
and curing your freshly harvested
cannabis plants all right podcast rolled
I am back
I am well medicated I am well hydrated
and I am ready to talk about drying and
curing your freshly harvested cannabis
plants now let me do a quick update from
the last episode in the last episode we
talked about harvesting your plants we
talked about cutting them down we talked
about hanging them in a room upside down
in a climate-controlled room one thing I
failed to mention you should only hang
one crop in a space at a time to prevent
remoisturize
the first crop don't cut down one crop
and then let it hang for four or five
days five or seven days and then bring
in a fresh crop and lock that in the
same room because what you're doing is
just introducing a whole bunch of
moisture into that room and it's just
gonna go into the other plants you're
going to re moisten the other plants and
make them take longer and now you've got
to kind of restart you're dry and cure
process so one one crop at a time is
ideal hanging in the room that's
something I should have mentioned on the
episode before and I didn't remember to
mention that so now we are up to speed
now let's actually get into drying and
curing our freshly harvested cannabis
plants now after spending four weeks and
veg eight to ten weeks and flower you
really don't want to mess these plants
up at the very end here curing is a very
critical process curing you can make the
most delicious buds taste like total
[ __ ] from drying and curing them
improperly you can ruin the entire crop
at this point don't get too scared
because I'm gonna guide you through not
ruining it but keep in mind that this is
one of the most critical parts in the
growing process this is a huge process
and a lot of things can go wrong if you
don't pay attention so take your time
and pay attention and don't rush to
smoke your new crop you've waited what
what do we say about 14 weeks probably
is what we did the math on 120 days
you've grown these plants for 120 days
is about how long it takes why not wait
a couple of days longer until they are
perfect before you start smoking it so
let's get it actually drying and curing
these plants now the last grow episode
was a harvest episode and it left us
with our plants hanging upside down in a
room with proper temps proper humidity
and minimal light now we've been waiting
for the sticks for our plants to snap
we've got plants hanging upside down
they've been delete or just way
for the right humidity within the plants
for the sticks to pop the sticks should
snap we're waiting for him to snap but
not explode when you grab a branch of
the plant and you just bend it you want
it to sound kind of like that you don't
want it to go Shh
you don't want it to explode with
dryness you don't want it to fall apart
and you don't want it to be gummy or
rubbery or bendy you don't want it to to
bend you want it to snap and pop so the
stick should snap the bigger sticks and
larger plants are going to take a little
bit longer the skinnier sticks and
smaller plants are obviously going to
dry more quickly because they don't hold
as much moisture also if you took off
Leslie for more relief they're going to
dry more quickly without the leaf and
they're going to take a little longer
with that extra leaf on there because
it's going to hold more moisture
there'll be more moisture in the room
just more moisture overall to deal with
so we're waiting for is those sticks to
snap when the sticks snap that's when
the container curing process begins I
use two different methods for this based
on crop size don't forget that I run
commercial grows in a commercial setting
we do things a little differently than
we would do in a home setting I'm used
to pulling down 50 or more pounds in a
commercial environment you don't want a
bunch of jars you don't really have the
space for a bunch of jars you don't have
the manpower to open a bunch of jars all
day so we do things a little differently
in a home grow it's not as many pounds
it's less jars so I use jar technique in
a home grow but let's talk about the way
I would do it in a commercial grow in a
commercial grow I'll chop the large
stalk and naked stems out of the plants
and place the buds still on sticks into
large Rubbermaid containers so you've
got a big plant
you've lollipop tup probably 12 to 18
inches of it so you've got some naked
sticks right that's what I mean by naked
sticks the the shaved legs and that main
big stalk I'll cut all of that out and
that goes to waste and a commercial grow
that's actually got to be weighed and
documented as removed waste so now I've
got two piles one pile is naked sticks
that need to be documented as waste
they'll be chipped up and thrown away
then there's another pile that's the
usable product of the sticks with buds
up it they need to be trimmed those buds
still on the sticks get put into the
Rubbermaid containers on
prynt there's something to keep in mind
carefully label your Rubbermaid
containers do not label the lids never
label lids in a facility in a home grow
don't label the lids lids are
interchangeable label the container so
chop the sticks out put the good usable
buds into the Rubbermaid container don't
squish them in there too tight fill it
up pretty well but don't cram anything
in there you need some air space in
there and you don't want to smash
anything and if it's too tightly pressed
together it'll get funky it'll start to
smell bad Moisture will get trapped in
there and you'll start to get that stale
ammonia smell and that's what we were
trying to avoid with proper drying and
curing so I would go through and remove
all of the sticks get all the good buds
into the containers and then once they
are all completed I would go through and
put the lids on every container at that
point I would have everything labeled it
all be sitting open and then when we're
done with every plant that's gonna get
been that day that's when I start
putting the lids on and sealing up the
containers now I feel like I haven't
described these containers properly
these Rubbermaid containers are like the
size of maybe a laundry basket they're
about three feet wide I guess and then
maybe a foot or so wide I know I said
wide but three feet long and a foot or
so wide and then probably about eighteen
maybe twenty inches deep they're the one
that you uh use for packing or you just
put a bunch of clothes in there just a
bunch of [ __ ] or it's the one when
the kids come to the front door they're
trying to sell candy for church like I
got some candy for church sir would you
like to raise some money I think if the
big Rubbermaid container that's the
container I'm talking about it's just
like a moving box or something is what
it looks like a storage container we can
fit three or four large plants in those
containers from the commercial grow so I
guess I should have mentioned that a
little earlier but it just dawned on me
that I did not describe these containers
in any way so now let's talk more about
what happens to these plants once they
are put into this container and the lid
is put on them they need to be opened
and rotated every day until they're dry
enough to seal up without risking any
mold development the first day is always
scary when you seal them up and then
leave overnight that is always a scary
feeling until you get there the next day
don't be afraid to leave them open if
you feel like they're a little too moist
if you cut them down and get them in the
bin and realize aw [ __ ]
a couple of these are too wet
don't be afraid to leave those open open
overnight you would rather leave them
open and get them a little too dry then
close them up and get them a little
funky a little funky doesn't go away a
little too dry we can work with so you
seal them up you put the lids on them
and then you might want to check on them
before you leave for the day make sure
that nothing needs to be rotated nothing
needs to be flipped around nothing needs
to be left open like I said if it needs
to be left open leave it open don't be
afraid then you're gonna leave you're
gonna come back the next day you're
gonna have a bunch of sealed containers
they need to be popped open immediately
I would pop them open for four maybe six
maybe seven hours and check on him while
they were sealed a lot of the moisture
that was inside those sticks
reconstituted throughout those buds and
a lot of moisture built up in that
container you're gonna find a lot of
spongy and wet buds when you come in in
the morning that's expected don't worry
it'll be okay you're gonna leave it open
and get some of that [ __ ] out of there
that's the idea you want to open it up
every day and let that stuff out of
there when they start getting dry again
some of the sticks might not even snap
again some of them may have remoisten
where they don't snap that that means
you may have gone just a little bit too
early but it's not bad because we can
get that moisture out you don't want it
to get too dry so you're gonna pop them
open you're gonna see how what they are
leave them open you may just want to
leave them open for an hour if they're
real dry an hour is fine
four to six hours is not uncommon on the
first day if you chop those plants down
or if you bend those plants a little bit
too early they may be really wet and you
may have to leave them open for four to
six maybe the whole shift of 8 to 10
hours they may have to stay open that's
not uncommon try not to cut them down
and put them into the bins so early next
time but you'll be okay this is
something you're gonna have to dial in
with your facility and with your
technique so the duration of burp time
is going to decrease as slowly as the
buds dry these bins are going to sit in
a room ideally that is at 50% humidity
and 70 degrees until you have time to
trim them I run a humidifier and a
dehumidifier at the same time and
they're both set at 50% humidity so if
that room gets to 55% humidity that
dehumidifier kicks on immediately if it
gets to 45% the humidifier comes on
immediately I don't get out of that
degree range and it stays pretty close
with both of those machines and they're
fighting each other they pretty much
just stay on all the time so I've got
these buds they are in containers they
have not been trimmed yet and they still
need to be burped on a daily basis the
first thing the dry and cure manager or
the trim team manager should do when
they get to the grow is pop open these
bins and see what type of situation
you've got they should be getting drier
and more smokeable and they should start
smelling more like dank cannabis every
day that fresh green wet smell should be
going away but you're going to have to
pop them everyday and pay attention to
how long they need to be open like I
said that first day you're gonna get
four to six hours maybe the second day
four to six hours maybe the third day
four hours maybe the fourth day three
hours then maybe you're gonna have to
pop them open for an hour every day and
see what's going on and check it out
eventually you won't have to open them
anymore once you've gotten them to about
65% humidity inside the container
consistently you don't have to burp it
that is cured where you want it and it's
also in that room with 50% humidity so
it's gonna stay about 50% humidity and
it won't get less than that and they can
the containers hold moisture in there so
it's gonna stay above 50% trust me so
while you're drying and curing inside
those bins be sure to burp the bins
every day and rotate the buds to prevent
mold and funky aromas until they get dry
enough to leave alone don't be afraid to
take the buds and pick them up right
outside of the container and flip them
over and set it back in so all the buds
that were on the bottom are now on the
top and do that you can do that once or
twice a day if you feel like you need to
if they are really wet now something I
want to keep stressing is if they are
too moist don't be afraid to leave the
lid off the containers and tell the buds
are nice and dry and you feel
comfortable closing them up and you're
sure there's not going to get any mold
in there because if you leave it closed
for too long or you bend these buds too
early you're going to create an ammonia
type funky terrible smell inside your
butts they're not going to burn well
they're gonna taste terrible they're
gonna smell funky and it's not gonna be
desirable and you're not gonna be able
to sell it at your dispensary or however
you plan on selling it so one problem
you may run into if you leave it closed
too long
is funky aromas the only thing you can
do to fix that is try to air it out just
leave it open let it dry try to let that
smell go away and it's probably not
going to you've probably gone too long
so make sure not to seal it up for too
long and make sure not to seal it up
when it's too moist another problem you
could run into during the drying and
curing process is the buds could get too
dry if your buds get too dry in those
containers a trick you can do is to go
pull a few leaves from your growing
plants if you've got a flower room you
probably need to be foliate a little bit
and pull some plant pull some leaves off
those flowering plants anyway so go get
I would say four to six large leaves per
Rubbermaid container is more than enough
to rehydrate some semi-dry buds in one
of those containers we tried to put too
much in there and it made it really wet
really quickly so four to six leaves is
more than enough to remoisten an entire
Rubbermaid container if you left it open
just a little bit too long if you got it
down into that Colorado crunch zone then
you've done [ __ ] up and you might not
be able to fix it but we'll talk about
that a little bit later in the episode
but if you didn't go too far just grab
four or five maybe six leaves throw them
in in the container and seal it up for
just a few hours then go check on it
that moisture will reconstitute the buds
and give you a second chance I would not
recommend using anything other than
cannabis leaves maybe Boveda packs
Boveda packs however you like to say it
the Boveda packs come in sixty two
percent humidity you can use those if
you'd like although I do not prefer them
myself I think they make a weird flavor
in my cannabis buds I think that using
the leaves of the same plant is the best
idea all right so that is basically the
commercial grow version of drying and
curing your cannabis plants on a large
scale now I'm going to take a giant dab
and when we get back we will talk about
drying and curing your cannabis on a
smaller scale for the home grower
[Music]
all right podcast well let's get back
into this dry and cure episode the home
bro or the connoisseur version of drying
and curing your final product is a
little bit different than the commercial
grow version but it's basically the same
idea we want to slow down the drying
process we want to get those buds to
feel nice and sticky you want them to
smell nice and sweet we wanted to burn
nice and smooth so this is how I would
dry and cure my product in a small
connoisseur batch in a smaller grow a
home grow or a boutique grow or maybe
something I was going to enter into a
competition if this was going into a cup
this is how I would cure my product the
main difference is that I would not be
using the gigantic Rubbermaid containers
I would use court size widemouth glass
jars I don't want to use bigger jars I
feel like maybe too much moisture gets
stuck in there you have the same
conditions that you create in those
Rubbermaid containers I like the smaller
more focused jars another note before we
get too far make sure you label each jar
if you're working with more than one
strain label the jars not the lids lids
are interchangeable be careful with this
please if you're working with different
phenotypes label the jar whatever arise
phenotype to arise phenotype three if
you're running a pack of seeds or
whatever label the jars so that you know
what you're working with basically
everything up to the point of the sticks
snapping is the same we're waiting for
the sticks to snap once the sticks snap
that's when we can start the jar curing
process for jar tech I would take the
snappy sticks and chop off every bud
into a bucket just get all those buds
off the sticks into the bucket throw
those sticks away get rid of them do
whatever you do with them compost them
shred them up toss them those are done
then I hand trim the buds I'll do
another episode all about hand trimming
the buds I don't like trim machines and
I don't like wet trim but I'll talk
about that in the trimming episode that
is coming up so I trim the buds
they should be dry enough by now to
knock off most of the leaves with your
thumbs and thumbnails so trim them up
pretty closely with your thumb then put
the trimmed buds into the glass jars
that we talked about the wide mouth
quart-size mason jars fill those jars
about 75 to 90% fool if your buds are
fluffier if your buds are bigger you're
only gonna be able to get 75% in there
because of all the air space I get it it
makes sense if you've got smaller buds
you can put up to 90% in there but do
not press them down into the jar and
don't over pack them and don't squish
them in you just want them lightly
sitting in there
now once the jar is full I add the lid
and I set a timer I like to check my
buds about 4 hours after being sealed up
for the first time this first check lets
me see how much moisture is trapped in
my butts if the inside of the jar is
extremely humid I'll just leave that lid
off for an hour or more and the
commercial grow we were talking about
four to six maybe eight hours maybe even
10 hours those are much larger plants
much larger batches and much larger
containers there is much more moisture
in there so for these smaller jars I
only want to leave it off for a little
bit at a time these smaller batches can
get away from you quite quickly so pay
more attention so open it up see how
humid it is if it's really humid and
really squishy you're gonna want to
leave it open for an hour maybe a little
bit more just keep checking on it and do
not forget about it set another timer if
the humidity has not made the buds
squishy again I'll leave the jar open
for only like 15 to 30 minutes to let
the moisture out and that old funky air
out of the jar and then it'll kind of
refresh with fresh air in there then
I'll reseal the jar and let it sit for
another four to six hours I set a timer
for this then in four to six hours I pop
that jar and I gently stir the buds
around and check the aroma that comes
out of there what I'm looking for when I
smell is an aroma of ammonia or funk or
just you'll notice it your nose will
crinkle up and your eyes will make a
weird squint you'll go [ __ ] I [ __ ] up
looking for that aroma I'm hoping that's
not present it shouldn't be also I'm
looking to see if it smells
less wet has it gone from that wet juicy
hey smell two more of that cured chronic
smell that I'm looking for because it'll
start doing it quickly and then it will
improve over time so I'm cracking the
jar open I'm looking to see how much
humidity is in there um I stir him
around if the buds seem damp or extra
spongy at this point I'll dump them out
of the jar and let them sit for a few
minutes until that excess moisture
evaporates you don't want the buds super
soggy and sealed in a jar you don't want
the buds super wet and pressed together
in a jar if they still feel wet and
spongy on the outside I'll dump them out
and let them sit out for a few minutes
until they feel dry on the outside but
when you squeeze them they're mushy
still a little bit you just want them
dry on the outside wet on the inside is
what you're going for at this point if
the buds are sticking together then I
dump them out completely and let them
dry more before putting them back in now
we want a little bit of moisture in
these buds the little bit of moisture is
going to make the drying and curing
process happen but we don't want enough
moisture to cause mold and funk so we
burp the jar about every four hours to
make sure we don't seal too much water
in the jar for too long we let some of
the curing process happen by opening the
jar letting that old gas out that
contains the chlorophyll that contains
the sugars that gas evaporates out of
the jar we replace it with fresh air we
seal it back up then when we seal it
it's allowed to restart the curing
process it'll start deteriorating and
eating up more of that chlorophyll more
of those excess minerals and sugars
inside of there and they will start
evaporating out of your buds you'll get
them out so let's get back on track here
after the first couple of days you can
slowly increase your burp intervals as
the buds get drier you may only need to
open these jars up every six to eight
hours after a little bit and the time
that you leave them open will also
decrease so maybe after a few days you
pop it open every eight hours maybe you
pop it open right before you go to work
you leave it open while you're brushing
your teeth and getting your shoes on and
then you close it up and you leave you
come back from work and then you pop it
open it's probably been 10 hours by now
pop it open again stir the buds around
make sure nothing's gone funky if
nothing's gone funky just leave it open
for five minutes let that air exchange
in there seal it right back up then you
can go ten hours and you know you're
safe it
hours see what happens at 11:00 hour see
what happens at 12 hours just start
stretching it every day by the end of
two weeks you'll just be popping these
jars open once a day you'll check it out
you'll give it a good smell and you'll
say that is so close and then you can
close it back up by the end of two weeks
these buds will be beautifully
beautifully cured so the blood should be
sticky on the outside and spongy but not
dry and crumbly they should almost have
a little bit of squeeze a little bit of
give to them and then stick to your
fingers
they shouldn't fall apart and just
crumble up like a lot of the Colorado
dispensary bud does unfortunately and
the reason for that you guys is because
it's sitting on the Shelf out there all
day they're opening up those jars and
showing it to you all day this stuff is
just getting dry so that's the problem
with the Colorado crunch I apologize for
that the growers work hard to get it
proper and then it's sent to the
dispensary and left in those jars and
the bud tenders don't do us justice so I
apologize so on day one I chopped the
buds off the sticks and I trim them up
then I filled the jars
about 90% full then I seal the jar I
checked the jar in about four hours I
opened it long enough for the excess
moisture to come out of the jar that
could be a little while that could be a
short amount of time it kind of depends
on how wet the buds were when you jarred
them up then I check it again in about
four hours I shuffled the buds if I feel
that's necessary it's likely necessary
then I check again in four to six hours
and leave open as necessary if they're
getting too sticky again I'll dump them
out you'll want to check as soon as you
wake up the next day the burr process
will slow down over the next few days
you want it to take as long as possible
without allowing mildew to develop you
want to slow it down the longer it takes
the better the more time that it takes
for that moisture to come out the more
opportunity you have for chlorophyll to
be removed the only thing to worry about
very similarly to the rubbermaid
technique is trapping too much moisture
in your containers for too long and
causing yourself mildew or funky flavors
if you locked your buds up in these jars
long enough to where you got like white
MOLLE webbing growing on there and it
looks like some cotton coming out you
[ __ ] up and didn't pay any attention
throw that away if your jar is starting
to get an ammonia smell you've sealed it
up too long you've got
open it more frequently and longer next
time you may be able to save it but it's
unlikely the only thing you can do is
leave it open and let it dry out and
hopefully that smell will go away so
don't leave it closed too long
don't let mildew happen don't let that
funky smell happen once you're past the
first few days you'll kind of be out of
the mildew danger zone but still be
careful also keep your jars in a cool
dark place while you're curing your buds
but also don't leave them somewhere
where you're going to forget about them
also here in Colorado I'm running a
swamp cooler in the main portion the
living area of my house don't go dump
your buds on the table near the swamp
cooler this is not going to do you any
good this is going to reconstitute them
and make them wetter think about wetter
is that a word anyway think about the
environment where you were drying and
curing your products if you're gonna
dump them out on the table and an
attempt to get them more dry make sure
that the room is drier than the butt or
it's not going to work just keep that
kind of stuff in mind you guys think
about your environment think about your
products so I feel like we've got a
basic understanding of how to cure our
buds now let's get into the technical
talk about why we do it and what's
technically happening securing your buds
properly makes your buds burn and smoke
smoothly and it also brings out the best
flavors and aromas proper drying and
curing will also increase your potency
now why why does that happen because
your buds contain chlorophyll
chlorophyll is what gives your buds that
harsh smoke and hay like flavor that
burn your throat kind of funky flavor
that's from too much chlorophyll that's
from excess minerals in the plant that
could also be from an improper flush but
it's usually from an improper cure so
curing the buds will remove chlorophyll
and increase your potency at the same
time the only way to remove chlorophyll
is by turning it into a gas sealing our
moist buds in a jar creates an
environment that will break down the
chlorophyll and turn it into a gas
darkness moisture and oxygen will create
a bacteria within the jar that bacteria
will break down the sugars and leftover
minerals created by the decomposition of
the chlorophyll and it will turn into a
vapor the
escape the jar when you pop it open that
was what I was talking about earlier
when I said we pop open the jar and let
the chemical reaction happen now this
process is going to make your bud burn
smoother it's going to tape make it
taste better it's gonna bring out the
proper aromas the proper terpene profile
that you're looking for and it's also
going to increase the overall potency of
your finished product now if you really
want to nerd out and dial this in and
create a connoisseur product find
yourself a hygrometer that fits inside
of your mason jar there are a couple
available that fit right inside the
mason jar you can press it up to the
front of the jar where you can read the
display without opening the jar find
yourself hygrometers that will fit in
the jar and here are some suggestions on
when to open and close your jars and how
to dial them in perfectly if your buds
feel wet or if they are above 70%
humidity if the little display on that
hydrometer inside of your jar reads
above 70% humidity you need to dump
those buds out of the jar and let them
dry until they get to 65 to 70% humidity
now when you dump them out and you leave
them somewhere that's not by the fan
that's not by the swamp cooler that's
not by the air-conditioner that's not by
something that's going to drastically
affect the rate of their drying
don't forget about them set a timer and
go find them some of you are a little
obsessive you're definitely not gonna
forget some of you are gonna take a
couple of dabs and go play fort night
and your buds are gonna dry up to [ __ ]
don't let that happen to you guys
so if they are too humid dump them out
let them dry out a little bit get them
down to 65 to 70% humidity now if your
buds feel moist to the touch if they're
sticky and wet to the outside of the
buds and the display reads 65 to 70%
humidity pop the lid off of that jar for
fifteen to thirty minutes and let a
little moisture evaporate out if you
think they need longer than fifteen to
thirty minutes
let them go longer but like I said don't
start playing fortnight and start
building [ __ ] and shooting people and
forget about them because you don't want
them to get too crunchy so fifteen to
thirty maybe 45 minutes maybe an hour
seal them back up set yourself a timer
to remember to check on them in a little
bit and now you can go play fort night
and relax
now your goal is 60 to 65% humidity you
want that hydrometer to read between 60
and 65 percent humidity and you want
them dry but not crunchy they're gonna
feel squishy and sticky hopefully but
they're not wet you just want them dry
but not crunchy you might need to let
your buds sit out for a little bit
before you roll a joint if it's cured
perfectly the display will say 60 to 65%
you may need to take a couple of buds
out of there and set them I just set
them right here on the front of my
computer if I'm gonna roll when it's a
little warmer right there to suddam
chill they're not like in the path of
the fan or anything just let them chill
right here that's what I'm gonna roll
the joint with in a few minutes and just
let them sit there you know just just
for a little bit just maybe if I'm gonna
go to lunch and come back and smoke a
joint I'll set them out right before I
go to lunch and then you go to lunch and
then you come back and then they grind
up nice and fine and they're still
sticky oh they're still juicy and then
your joint burns super smoothly and if
your joints not burning super smooth
then you probably have too much moisture
in there and you gotta let it dry and
cure just a little bit longer now if you
hit that 55 percent or lower mark you're
entering what I call the Colorado crunch
area and your buds are gonna burn too
fast and you're also losing weight if
you're working with more than a quarter
pound there and you're drying it up do
you risk losing you know a quarter of an
ounce or whatever depends on how much
you let it dry so if your buds get too
dry don't add anything funky to
rehydrate them the only thing I would
use are fresh
cannabis leaves and a little bit goes a
long way so take them out when the
moisture comes back and don't let those
leaves mold up in there and [ __ ] up your
crop check on them frequently if you put
wet leaves inside of either your curing
jars or your packs or your [ __ ]
turkey bags however you do it make sure
you take them out and don't leave them
for too long check on them after an hour
one hour is more than enough go check on
it set yourself a timer don't get stuck
doing an Instagram live video and forget
to check on your buds all right so it's
gonna take a little bit for your
hydrometer to measure the humidity in
the jar but it's gonna get you a pretty
good idea of when to open and close
those jars and it's gonna give you some
actual data to go by you'll be able to
squeeze those buds and feel how wet they
are and you'll be able to compare
that number or that moisture to the
number on the hygrometer and you'll go
oh that's what 65% feels like that's
what's Jeffs trying to get me to so that
gives you something to work with it's a
little bit of a cheater but if you're
using one hygrometer you're gonna have
to seal it into the jar for a few
minutes and wait for it to get to where
it needs to be now if it's jumping real
fast go ahead and pull it out leave that
jar open that means it's really humid in
there and that you're just gonna seal it
up and cause problems all right so we've
got a little tiny hydrometer in our jars
we're watching the numbers we're trying
to get ourselves to 60 to 65% humidity
inside of those jars make sure you don't
forget about your buds make sure you
don't get that funky aroma in there make
sure it doesn't smell like ammonia and
mildew make sure you don't ruin it you
should be paying attention to the number
on the hygrometer and then pulling some
buds out and seeing what they feel like
so that you know what 50 what 60 what 70
what 80% humidity if you get to 80 you
[ __ ] up but so that you know what the
percentage of humidity feels like inside
these jars what the bud feels like this
will give you a really good idea start
paying attention to that stuff and you
will get ahead of the drying and curing
game now once you've gotten your buds
dried and cured to 55 to 65 percent
humidity and you don't see any
fluctuation inside that jar on the
hydrometer
you only need to crack them open to
check on them or pull out some buds to
smoke you don't need to keep popping
those jars open they're gonna get too
dry if you do that so you can trap the
moisture in there leave it right at that
point and your blood will be perfectly
cured for whenever you need it now I've
said before that I don't like the Boveda
packs but they work if you do [ __ ] up
the Boveda packs I would buy are the
sixty-two percent and you can just drop
them right inside your jar it'll help
reconstitute that package or that jar
and then sometimes I feel like they
leave kind of a watery flavor on the
buds but I guess I'd rather have a
properly cured bud that has that aroma
within some Colorado crunch it's just
gonna burn up when I light my joint at
the show so ladies and gentlemen that is
my dry and cure episode I want to thank
you guys for listening if you have
questions please send them to me my
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
I would love to continue the
conversation and clear up anything I
left out for you just let me know also
this is a good time for me to recommend
my patreon campaign patreon is a website
that gives you as a podcast
Center the opportunity to contribute
financially to my podcasting efforts if
you feel like this podcast was worth a
couple of bucks if you feel like you had
some fun if you feel like you learned
something I would encourage you to go to
patreon.com/scishow on campaign I know
that not everybody is able to
financially contribute to the show I
will always keep this show free for
everybody I want everybody to be able to
hear my message I want everybody to be
able to improve their garden I want
everybody to have better medicine I want
better cannabis worldwide and I'm gonna
do my part for free but there are people
who would like to contribute there are
people that feel like they can help out
I would appreciate that help what I do
with that funding is I pay for my
website I actually bought a MacBook so I
need to pay for the MacBook I actually
buy these little microphone covers so
that when granny and giddy are on they
don't have to spit into these same
microphone covers over and over again so
there are things like that that do need
to be covered and I do appreciate the
support you guys I'm not begging if you
don't know that it's an option you don't
know how you can help out so I do
appreciate everybody that has helped out
with the patreon campaign it blows my
mind every month to see that come in
thank you also you guys thanks for
listening to the podcast just thanks for
putting your trust in me thanks for
believing in me
you guys are risking your gardens on my
advice and that means a lot to me so
thank you you guys I'm gonna start
wrapping up this podcast ona thank you
again for listening to the show thanks
for hanging out for the drain cure
episode I hope you learned a lot I will
have a trimming episode coming up and
then we're gonna talk about restarting
the garden I've got a bunch of great
plans for the podcast thanks for hanging
out thanks for all the great emails
thanks for all the great messages I've
been getting it is really encouraging
you guys I would appreciate it if you
stalk me on all the social media you can
find me on Facebook simply search for
the girl from your heart podcast on
Twitter it's at g f YH podcast on
instagram i use i re underscore genetics
I RIE underscore GE and ET ICS I re
underscore genetics on instagram check
out my cannabis photography also join in
on my live videos i drop in to instagram
live and i hang out with my friends i
take a few too many dads and we talk
about growing cannabis who knows what we
may talk about on the live feed so pop
in check it out say what
hang out maybe I'll answer your
questions in the live feed also if
you've got something you'd like to say
and you're not into the social media or
if you'd like to sponsor the show or if
you've got a product you'd like me to
review you can send me an email my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com you know I would love to
hear from you ladies and gentlemen don't
forget that the show is available on
iTunes and stitcher and every single
episode is available on YouTube simply
search for the girl from your heart
podcast on youtube you guys I want to
thank you for listening thank you for
all the love and support I cannot wait
for the comments from this episode you
guys I'll be back in just a few days
thanks again for hanging out with me I
usually in these episodes by giving a
shout out to one specific person but on
this episode I want to give a shout out
to everybody who is listening if you
hear this big shout out high-five
fist bump however you do it thank you
shout out to you ladies and gentlemen
until next time take a phat dad and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]