hey welcome to the show podcast world it
is time for episode 393 of the girl from
your heart podcast this episode is
brought to you by Oregon elite seeds if
you're looking for new seeds for your
garden I highly recommend Oregon elite
seeds and you can find them at
www.irs.gov mandarin sunset from
contraband extracts available at a cut
above in Colorado Springs this
concentrate has a great aroma and flavor
it is sweet orange and candy with a hint
of pepper and spice at the backend and
the high is tremendous it goes straight
to my head it goes straight behind my
eyes it kind of makes it hard to think
it makes it hard to pay attention but
that is exactly what I'm looking for in
a concentrate so shout out to our
friends at contraband extracts and a big
shout out to everyone at a cut above if
you have been following along with the
podcast you know I've been doing a long
series of grow lessons this is going to
be another grow lesson however this is
going to be a reposted episode a while
back I did an episode about trimming our
freshly harvested cannabis it was
originally posted as episode 327 it
falls right in line with our grow
lessons so I'm going to repost it as
episode 393 I hope everybody enjoys this
repost ladies and gentlemen let's jump
right in to trimming our freshly
harvested cannabis
welcome back cannabis community it's
time for another episode of the grow
from your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
I try to hear a new grower if you're a
professional grower if you're a new
smoker or a dedicated Davor
if you're a cannabis activists or even
someone who is just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host my friends call me Rasta Jeff I
want to thank you guys again for joining
me this episode of the podcast is
brought to you by my friends at the hell
a dank seed company if you need new
genetics for your gardening I highly
recommend the hella dank seed company
you can find them at dank seed dot store
ladies and gentlemen roll up a fat joint
pack up the bong or start eating up that
average
because it's time for another episode of
the grill from your heart podcast
[Music]
welcome back podcast world it's time for
episode 327 of the girl from your heart
podcast thanks again for joining me you
know I like to start the episode off by
letting you know what I'm smoking on
today I'm taking dabs of this New York
City diesel and Broza batter from
apothecary farms I'm giving it a nice
smell right now this stuff smells like
like diesel fuel with a little bit of
lemons make a hit of oranges and then
there's kind of a sweet tart sort of
smell on top of it that I really enjoy a
one thing about the New York City diesel
and Broza batter here that I'm smoking
on my eyes really don't get red when I
smoke I can smoke and I don't get red
eyed but when I take one dab of this New
York City diesel my eyes go fully
bloodshot red I'm not sure what does it
but I get super red I get super head
hide from it and I really enjoy it and
if that weren't enough I've been adding
this sour amnesia high cannabinoid
full-spectrum extract into the mix and
it just adds a really a nice it's like
turbo charging my dad it is really nice
I like the lung expansion and the flavor
from the New York City diesel then you
put the high cannabinoid full-spectrum
extract on top and it really makes it
like a turbocharged dad so I'm in the
mood for a podcast you guys I feel super
rambley I feel like I got a lot of
energy let's get into a podcast this
episode is going to be all about
trimming your cannabis plants that's
right we've learned how to tell when the
plants are ripe we've learned how to cut
them down we've learned how to harvest
them we learned how to hang them until
they're ready to snap we know pretty
well how to dry and cure now let's talk
about trimming our plants now there are
two different ways you can trim there's
wet trim and there is dry trim I
definitely prefer dry trim they're gonna
say why is dry trim better
I think dry trim is better because it's
less sticky and it's much easier to work
with it's also less work the leaves are
dry those leaves are gonna fall off all
you have to do is just brush them with
your thumb maybe touch them with the
scissors and those brittle leaves will
come right off of there the buds have
dried and tightened up and then it's a
little more obvious for a new trimmer
what to take off you just want to take
off that fluffy outside [ __ ] so it's a
little less work it's less sticky and
there's also less chance to ruin your
buds
improperly storing them a lot of people
once the buds are trimmed if they wet
trim they like to just shove them into a
container or a package and then those
wet buds go into a container and that's
when they get ruined so we're not even
gonna let that happen we're gonna let
the buds dry then we're gonna trim them
then we'll put them in a container now a
lot of people have listened to the dry
and curing episode you may be trimming
these buds before they go into the jar
for cure you may be trimming these buds
after they've been in the cure jar for a
little while it's all the same process
the leaves should be similar in dryness
they should just be popping right off of
there you might not even need scissors
for this sometimes when I'm dry trimming
the only thing I use my scissors for is
for cutting the plant into smaller
pieces and cutting the sticks out and
cutting the bigger buds down to smaller
buds now let's talk about a few
preparations we can make in a few items
we can have to create a comfortable and
successful trim environment for
ourselves
trimming sucks it's going to take a long
time you're sitting in a chair with your
elbows up high staring straight into
something for a long time your neck your
elbows your eyes your back that stuff
all gets sore and tired so let's try to
make it as comfortable as possible
I like to have a nice clean space I've
got this table where I like to do my
work I clean the whole table off there's
nothing on the table except my dr.
pepper and some trim supplies maybe my
phone for some entertainment but it's
just there for music I'm not gonna be
touching it don't have your phone out if
you're trimming you guys it's so [ __ ]
distracting and it'll slow you down
it'll take twice as long put on a
podcast hit play start [ __ ] trim it
anyway I like to have the table nice and
clean I don't need [ __ ] in my way I need
maybe my scissors for cutting my buds
into smaller pieces and then just a few
basic essentials and we'll talk about
those a nice clean space I also like a
nice comfortable chair you're gonna be
sitting there for a while get a cozy
chair so a nice clean workspace in a
cozy chair are super important for me
for trimming but then you need some sort
of entertainment hopefully you got
somebody there to talk to
usually I got Mike or somebody around to
[ __ ] with some sort of conversation
makes trimming go much more smoothly but
if you don't have that option put on a
podcast you guys I like to put on a
podcast of course I recommend old
episodes of the girl from your heart
podcast put on some Joe Rogan something
like that maybe a YouTube video
something to entertain yourself to
listen to but nothing to look at back in
the day we used to trim all around the
TV and we would watch youtube videos and
trim
I found that that is super distracting
don't watch videos people will put their
[ __ ] scissors down and you'll catch
them just watching TV if you're paying
people to trim don't have a TV in the
room podcasts maybe some stand-up comedy
it's hard to get everybody on the same
page when it comes to music but maybe
play some good music just some sort of
stuff to make it comfortable and help
the time pass without your brain going
crazy is what I'm getting at you guys so
you got a clean space you got a chair to
sit in you got a good YouTube video on
you got a podcast going so now your cozy
your mind is entertained now you need
some gloves put some rubber gloves on
you want to wear gloves and you're
trimming you're going to get extremely
sticky you don't want to have to itch
your face and have to go wash your hands
just to scratch your face you're gonna
be your hands are gonna be covered in
trichomes and resin you guys wear gloves
also you need some good scissors I like
the little tiny Fiskars diamond tip
scissors that you get you can they're
expensive at the gross store they're
cheaper at Hobby Lobby they saw them in
the craft section right the craft
section of Hobby Lobby that's all of
Hobby Lobby there's some in the fabric
section over there by the fabric there
are Fiskars diamond tip titanium
scissors I really like those they work
really well for trimming they're super
light get something with the spring in
it that opens on its own because you
don't want to have to be opening and
closing scissors you don't want the kind
of scissors that have loops that go
around your fingers because you're gonna
be cutting for so long those little
loops around your fingers are gonna dig
into you you just want lightweight super
fast trimming shears they're easy to
find and they're affordable maybe get
yourselves two pair so that you can set
one in the rubbing alcohol to clean off
you can dirty up another pair swap them
out real quick not have to spend a lot
of time cleaning your scissors so you
need some good gloves some good scissors
then you need some containers you need a
container for untrimmed buds I recommend
a five gallon bucket for the untrimmed
buds maybe you don't have that much herb
maybe something smaller will work then
you need another container for trimmed
buds then you need another container for
savable trim and then we need another
container for waste so you need trimmed
buds untrimmed buds usable trim and
waste a couple other things I'm gonna
recommend and you're gonna say why the
hell would he recommend this for a grow
I would recommend either some coconut
oil or some baby oil for your trim
session you're gonna say why do we need
that here is why when your fingers and
hands and arms get all sticky you can
use the coconut oil or the baby oil to
remove the trike
that's right if your hands are all
covered in resin my thing is that my
arms get covered in Resident cuz I'm the
one cutting down the plants I'm reaching
in there and playing with them and
carrying them around my arm hair and
[ __ ] gets all coated in trichomes and
and plant resin so I use a coconut oil
or baby oil to just rub up on my arms
and rub that [ __ ] right off and all the
resin comes right off and then you're
not all sticky all right so that's the
basic breakdown of things that you're
going to need for your trim session you
need a nice clean space in which to work
you need a nice cozy chair in which to
sit you need a good podcast to listen to
probably the girl from your our podcast
then you need some gloves you need
scissors then you need your containers
then you've got your cleanup supplies
now let's talk about doing the manual
work hopefully a few days before harvest
you went in and did a pre harvest
defoliation now what I mean by that is
while the plants are still alive while
you're flushing anywhere between I don't
know seven days before harvest up to the
day of harvest you can go in there and
just start pulling off all of the big
leaves the plants are done growing
they're just flushing out they're just
finishing up the trichomes are ripening
up you don't need all that excess leaf
in there so just go ahead and tear all
that leaf out of the room having a pre
harvest defoliation session will save
you a lot of time when it comes time to
trim because all of that long straggly
leaf is already gone it's not even there
to deal with it's already been removed
and it will also help your drying and
curing time so go in and pull off all
the big leaves before you harvest then
it's harvest time I've done a highly
detailed harvest episode if you haven't
listened to that go listen to that then
come catch up at the end of the harvest
episode we're left with our plants
hanging upside down in a controlled
environment now we want those plants to
get to where the sticks snap once the
sticks get snappy you can start trimming
you can also start trimming them after
they've been in their cured containers
for a little while I like dry trim I'm
just waiting for the buds to be dry
enough toward the leaves kind of just
flake right off there's still gonna be
moisture inside those buds there's
moisture in the middle but the outside
is dry enough to where you can just kind
of knock the the buds off the leaves off
the buds with your thumb I'm making a
little motion with my hands that sort of
looks like I'm playing a video game like
I've got a game controller in my hand
but my hands are really close together
in my mind I'm just holding that little
bud with my four fingers or maybe with
my left hand and I'm just knocking the
leaves off with my right hand
just like I'm
it looks like I'm playing a video game
I'm just holding the bud and just
rubbing the leaves right off if you hold
it with the bud facing up if you rub
down those leaves will just rub right
off you'll see what I'm talking about
when you figure out the technique you go
man that is so easy so my point is that
I want it to where the buds are dry I
want to be able to just knock those
leaves right off so here is how I
actually do my trimming whenever I'm
working with the plants I like to wear
gloves so step one of trimming is put on
some rubber gloves I like the six
millimeter nitrile gloves I don't care
if they're black I don't care if they're
blue I just care that they fit and that
they're comfortable so glove up I don't
want to get all sticky and also I don't
want to get my skin all over the buds so
step one is glove up step two of
trimming is to knock all of the buds off
of the sticks into a five-gallon bucket
this makes it so much easier just go and
get everybody off the sticks into a
bucket and then discard all the sticks
now you've compressed your work into a
much smaller space it looks way less
overwhelming and you can see what you've
got ahead of you you've got a five
gallon bucket filled with buds that you
need to trim it doesn't look like this
big sprawl of branches and leaves and
[ __ ] everywhere just the bucket it's way
less intimidating and you can get
through it
so knock all the buds into a bucket
maybe you can use just a small bowl
maybe you can use something smaller I'm
not sure how much you grew maybe you
need five buckets I hope you need ten or
twenty five gallon buckets but find the
container that's the right size for what
you need a five gallon bucket from Home
Depot or Lowe's is really affordable and
they're disposable so I like to use the
buckets so I knock every bud into a
bucket now I've got a five gallon bucket
full of buds my next step is just to
reach in grab the bud off the top and
start trimming now I'll actually start
talking about trimming a little bit and
the actual trimming of the bud process
the idea is to knock or cut off all of
the excessive leaves and stems and give
yourself a nice pretty presentable but
you guys know what a good trimmed bud
looks like when they start off they're
covered in leaves it's our job to knock
those leaves off we don't want to smoke
leaves leaves contain chlorophyll leaves
don't taste good
leaves don't get you high what we want
is a nice frosty green nugget so once
you guys get started trim and you'll see
what's leaf material and what is a
usable but once you start digging in
there and just start not
and off some of the leaf you'll find
that but in the middle and it will start
to become very obvious what you do and
do not trim if your buds are kind of
airy and fluffy don't trim too deeply
just knock off the leaves I like to grab
the bud by the base by that little stick
at the bottom of the bud and just use my
thumb to push the leaves off I just kind
of spin the bud in a circle with my left
hand I will turn it I'm looking that's
counterclockwise no that is clockwise
I'll turn the bud clockwise and as it
comes toward me I'll use my right thumb
I'm using my left hand to spin the bud
toward me and is that one side come
towards me comes toward me my thumb just
knocks the leaves off right there I'm
just wiping them off like I'm just just
scraping the leaves off they're so dry
that they knock off on their own and
don't press so hard that you're [ __ ]
up the shape of the bud and knocking off
trichomes you can do this really gently
you'll find the technique after you do
it a few times it'll be really
comfortable and you'll get really fast
at it a lot of people like to do this
with scissors they'll hold it in the
left hand and they'll take their
scissors and just turn it and trim it
the leaves are sticking off horizontally
just keep your scissors horizontal you
can get adjust your angle as you need
and just spin that bud and keep cutting
just like you're giving it a haircut you
just want to take off those leaves and
leave that bud there so just knock off
the leaves don't carve too deeply into
the buds and don't squish the buds while
you're trimming them don't squeeze them
super hard and try not to handle them
too much a little tiny bud doesn't need
a lot of handling you don't want to get
all those trichomes on your gloves you
want to leave the trichomes on the bud
so you can use scissors if you want I
like my thumbs for most trimming you
guys the little edge of my thumb and my
thumbnail is a perfect little trimmer
for me I've mastered that technique I
knock off the little leaves and cut the
big buds into smaller sizes if you guys
can see a stick in there and it's like
one bud and then a little stick and
another bud take that [ __ ] out nobody
wants to buy a stick connoisseur quality
bud is taken down to the small part if
you want to leave your buds in big buds
that's fine it's up to you I like them
smaller a lot of people don't want to
buy a big stick you'll see people I
don't know you'll have some customers
that want big buds I used to have people
that just wanted big buds and then some
people know better they're like man I
don't want to buy that quarter that one
one bud that weighs a quarter because I
know right up the middle of it as a gram
of stick and I'm getting ripped off so
some people want it some people don't
that's up to you so once you've got it
trimmed up to the size you want it and
the
of trim you want I cut off all the
little leaves at the bottom also there's
like a lot of people leave little
cabbagey looking leaves at the bottom I
cut that [ __ ] off
I call it cabbage and I also take out
the handlebar sticks on the bottom
you're gonna have the branch that the
bud was actually stuck to the branch to
and then there's two little sticks that
come out that those first leaves were
attached to and they're all dry and
shitty look and cut those off of there
if you've got a pound of weed and you've
got all those little tiny sticks in
there those little sticks make your
pound look like [ __ ] just take it out
and your pound is gonna look so much
better it's gonna be so much more
desirable it's gonna get you more money
alright so that's the bottom line here
trim it and it's worth more money so
take off all the leaves take off that
little stick at the bottom knock off all
the crow's feet if you've got a little
tiny pointy leaf sticking out of
somewhere cut that out or knock it off
with your thumb
those little triangle leaves make you
look lazy if you did a whole good job on
most of the bud and you just left one or
two little triangles at the tip you look
lazy take that stuff out of there so
while I'm doing this all the trimming
work I trim over a tray or a container
to catch what I trim off all that little
stuff that gets clipped off is going to
be used to make concentrates or edibles
in the future so gather all that stuff
up take care of it don't just don't trim
into the floor and then sweep it up
don't trim onto the table and then scoop
it up trim onto a tray trim into a
container so that it is kept clean so
it's treated with respect because it may
go into edibles and things that you're
gonna eat need to be treated with
respect things you're gonna smoke need
to be treated with respect this is our
medicine so gather this stuff up and
vacuum seal it I like to keep the trim
in a vacuum sealed bag in the dark until
I'm able to use it get that to your
extractor as soon as you can
now the sticks those are thrown away I
throw all the sticks away in a
commercial grow they're thrown away in a
home grow those should go to the compost
pile or they could be burned or
something but the sticks are trash don't
try to extract sticks you guys that's a
waste of time it's a waste of energy
you're not gonna get anything out of it
and also if you're adding the sticks to
the trim you're just making the hash
worse you're not making it better what
goes in comes out and if you just put
[ __ ] in to make more you're gonna get
more but it's gonna be [ __ ] so gather up
all your trim vacuum seal the trim keep
the trim in a dark place and get that to
some
they can turn that into concentrates for
you also if you've got like yellow or
brown or funky leaves that are falling
off as you're trimming separate those
pull those out of the trim don't send
that to the extractor that's gonna make
your hash and dark that's gonna make
your hash taste like [ __ ] it's gonna
make it less potent and it's gonna make
it less desirable so do a little work
clean it up get it out of there and you
will have a better product so use your
thumbs or some scissors to gently remove
the excess leaves and the little stems
from the buds get rid of the handlebars
get rid of the crow's feet
now once the buds are trimmed to your
satisfaction you can place them into a
container for finished products now when
I say to your satisfaction how you want
to trim your buds is up to you if you
want to leave it a little fluffy go for
it if you want to trim it nice and tight
go for it that is up to you if your
product is for you personally then you
can leave it as leafy as you want you
can knock those leaves off right before
you smoke it you can clean it up
yourself if you plan on getting top
dollar for your product you'll need to
have a tight clean trim job one thing I
should mention that will help us speed
up the process of trimming is the rule
of thumb if the bud you were trimming is
not bigger than the tip of your thumb
it's probably better to let that bud go
to your hash pile and trim something
more substantial put those little
popcorn buds in the hash pile put it in
your trim pile and you can make better
hash that will improve the quality of
your concentrates so if it's a little
tiny bud don't waste time trimming it
just throw it in the hash pile and don't
waste your time trimming little tiny
buds if you feel like that little tiny
bud is worth less money than the time it
is taking you to trim it set it aside
and put it in the hash pile you don't
have to trim that if herb costs ten
dollars a gram and it takes you like a
minute to trim that little nug it's not
cost-effective so toss that little nugge
to the trim bin we'll add that to the
concentrates grab something that we can
trim and get on the shelf and make it
purchasable for the consumer so if it's
real tiny if it's ugly
don't bother trimming it you can put
that in your hash pile you can add that
to the to be extracted pile and that
will just improve your concentrates it
will also speed you up of course if you
need every little half gram every piece
of gravel out of that crop to make your
goal to make your wait go ahead and trim
that up add that that'll be weight in
the bottom of the bag but if
not necessary if it's just for you put
that in the concentrate pile and speed
yourself up in the commercial grow the
growers are expected to kick out a pound
minimum per person per shift some people
turn in two pounds every day and if they
spend time trim in that little gravel
[ __ ] they would never get there we have
a way of separating all those little
tiny buds all that little stuff gets
filtered out it gets pushed to the side
and then all of that those little buds
and the trim they're combined and it
gets turned in to concentrates so do a
nice tight trim if you want to sell it
but don't go overboard don't trim it too
tight and also don't try trimming all
those little buds or you're gonna put
yourself in debt you've got to pay your
trimmers you're spending your time make
it cost-effective
now something I want to mention trimming
will be very strain dependent some buds
are tight some buds are real fluffy some
buds are a little compacted little rocks
you can just kind of rub your fingers
over those and those are gonna trim some
buds our area and have a lot of texture
to them those are gonna be a little
harder to trim because you don't want to
knock off all those calyxes you're going
to have to adjust also if you're working
for somebody else you're going to have
to adjust to how they want it trimmed
when you go to a grow and you're working
for someone else they get to dictate how
tight your trim is don't over trim don't
under trim you trim to their expectation
if you're not sure what they want
have them trim up a bud and show you
have them trim up two or three buds and
set those at your workstation so you
have something to refer to as the day
goes on so that you don't forget and
also if they come by and say hey why you
doing it like that you got a couple
little buds to show them you could say
these are what you showed me this is
what I did show me the difference show
me where I'm going wrong then they can
say [ __ ] you're doing it just like I
showed you I'm sorry so we got a nice
tight trim we're setting the trim in one
pile we're setting our little tiny buds
in another pile we're mixing that up so
we can make good concentrates out of it
we're getting rid of all the sticks you
guys I think we have covered most of
trimming one great thing about trimming
is scissor and glove hatch all that
sticky [ __ ] that builds up on your
gloves and scissors is smokeable you can
smoke that right away Mike love scissor
hatch what I like to do if I've got if
I've been trimming so see even trim and
you've got this weird layer of like
sticky gooey looking [ __ ] all over your
gloves that's resin that's trichomes
that is potency rub your hands together
and you'll start figuring out how to rub
your hands in a circle to make that
stuff stick to
a little bit of heat goes a long way so
if your hands get warm it'll start
taking that resin right off of your
hands I don't want to smoke it off your
skin back in the day we used to call it
finger hash but please wear gloves now
and we're gonna call it glove hatch you
can scrape it off your scissors you can
smoke it off your gloves then put it in
a bowl you can put it on top of some pot
or just put it in an empty bowl and just
put a flame to it and melt it just
slowly melt that [ __ ] until it starts
smoking and you can smoke that sizzurp
hash that glove hash you can smoke it
right away but please don't pass that
[ __ ] to me if you did that off your skin
and weren't wearing gloves I don't want
to smoke your skin so that's one good
thing about trimming is you get scissor
hash right away I think that anything
that sticks to your gloves
that's yours you get to smoke that if
you come trim for me and that [ __ ] stick
to your gloves I have no problem with
you rolling that right off your glove
put that in a pipe and smoke it right in
front of me you earned that that is your
scissor hash that means you're trimming
your ass off if it's on your scissors
scrape your scissors off smoke that [ __ ]
what a lot of people will do all the
trimmers in the room will just gather
all their scissor hash into one pile and
put it into a big ball and then at the
end of the day you guys all smoke that
together like a little celebration but
it's smokeable that's my point you can
make edibles out of it if you want to
but I would recommend smoking it Mike
loves smoking it's not my favorite to
smoke it's a little odd it's heavy on
the lungs and it tastes kind of wet but
it is potent and it will give you a big
fat hit another great thing about dry
trimming that I didn't mention is that
when you are done trimming you can now
weigh your product you've been cutting
off the extra crap and throwing that in
one pile then you've been thrown those
finished buds into one pile all you got
to do is set that container on the scale
and weigh it now one thing I would
recommend it's a good idea whatever
container you're going to throw your
buds in to your finished buds if it's
gonna be a bucket if it's gonna be a
Tupperware container wave that and write
the weight of that on your container so
that when you're done trimming into that
container you know how much that weighs
so just subtract the weight of your
container and now you know how much
product is on the scale so it's always
rewarding knowing how much product
you've got right at the end of the trim
process when you wet trim you don't know
is you've gotta wait for it to dry still
so when people say how much did you trim
today and they said I trimmed a black
pound how do you know bro it was wet
it's got a dry we'll find out in a few
days so if you're paying people to trim
by the pound dry trim is the way to go
because now you've got dry
away you don't have a wet pound to guess
on the weight so here's one more thing I
should definitely mention to all of my
friends who have never trimmed before
everybody who is new with cannabis
here's something that I have to tell you
when you were trimming or working with
plants in general do not touch your eyes
with sticky trim fingers don't rub your
eye with the back of your hand go wash
your hands before you touch your eyes if
you rub your eyes with trichomes or
plant resin on your finger it is going
to burn for the next hour and it is
sticky every time you blink most of the
time you think you can blink and it will
fix your sticky eye or whatever's in
your eye not when you have resin in your
hai every time you blink it gets [ __ ]
stickier and it feels like your eyelid
is sticking to your eyeball and it just
burns so wear gloves and if you need to
itch your eye take your [ __ ] glove
off your hand
VIN it your eye I would almost consider
washing my hands before the itch take
the glove off go wash the hand VIN
scratch the eye but I understand
sometimes you just got to stick your
finger in your eye cause shit's going
weird take that glove off you guys don't
put plant resin or trichomes in your eye
it will [ __ ] suck that's the
technical term for it it [ __ ] sucks
there's no other way to describe it it
[ __ ] sucks you guys alright so I feel
like I've given you a pretty good lesson
on trimming I know I didn't teach you
exactly how to trim the act of holding
the bud and putting the scissors to it
is something you're going to have to
experience you will develop your
technique in your style I feel like I've
given you a pretty good outline you know
what to do with the product you know how
to get it there you just need some
practice doing it get some buds and put
some scissors to him that's the only way
you're gonna get good at it it's the
only way you're gonna get faster at it
when we hire new trimmers at the grow we
don't always hire the people that claim
to be the fastest trimmers we hire the
people that interview well and seem like
they're gonna fit in with the crew if
they say they can only trim a half a
pound of weed when they start that is
fine if that is real if they say they
can trim a half a pound and they only do
a quarter pound then I've got issues but
they say I can trim a half a pound in a
day I'm fine with that we will train
them we will teach them our system we'll
teach them some tricks they'll get in
they'll get a rhythm they'll get a
routine and eventually they'll be
trimming a pound and a half a day so
it's all about just finding the rhythm
it's all about finding the groove and it
takes you a little bit of time and
experience to get in there and do it all
so you
our buds these are precious to people
I've been in this industry for a long
time I can grab a flowering plant that's
a few days in and just cut that [ __ ]
down and feel no remorse or anything if
that's what needed to happen in a
commercial grow I kill the plant a lot
of people treat little buds like they're
the most precious thing they've ever
seen which I respect you don't get to
grow a bunch of plants I have produced
over a ton of cannabis in my life I am
responsible for a ton of cannabis but
having been produced a lot of people
don't have that under their belt so
every bud is precious to them they don't
want to [ __ ] up one single but I get
that so when they're new at it they go
really slow especially a higher trimmer
that is not their product that is your
bud that they're playing with respect
them for taking their time and going
slow with it but also encourage them to
go faster you have to learn and go
faster but people like to go slow in the
beginning because they're playing with
gold they don't they're playing with a
little pieces of gold they got little
babies in their hand and they're new so
they're kind of intimidated so keep that
in mind you'll get faster as time goes
on is what I'm trying to say you guys
you just need some practice you'll
become a good trimmer if you want to
become a good trimmer and if you want to
get your foot in the door in the
commercial marijuana industry being a
trimmer is probably the number one way
to get in the door trimmers and bud
tenders are how you get started so
trimming can be really time-consuming
and tedious but it is the last step
before you claim victory in your garden
if your garden is for sale you're one
step away from money if your garden is
for medicinal uses you're one step away
from feeling better so trimming sucks
but you're almost there it's it's the
hardest most time-consuming tedious part
in my opinion it is my least favorite
part but it is one step away from sweet
success all right podcast ruled I hope
this trimming lesson made sense again
the only way to get good at trimming is
to get sticky and get some practice get
in there get your gloves dirty get your
scissors all sticky and start trimming
up some weed if you want to learn and
you've got friends that are harvesting
volunteer to trim for free everybody
could use a free trimmer and we know
we're gonna have to teach you that's
fine but we hope that in a few harvests
you're gonna show up and you're gonna
trim your ass off like a savage so there
are people that will help you learn by
letting you trim for free if you get
those opportunities please do take them
ladies and gentlemen I'm sure I left
something out I'm sure I miss something
if I sparked any questions with
episode I invite you to email me all of
your questions my email address is grow
from your heart at hotmail.com I would
love to hear what i skiped I'd love to
hear what I left out or if you've got
some other random questions I will
answer those also once again it's grow
from your heart at hotmail.com ladies
and gentlemen thanks for listening to
the trimming episode here is the part
where I pitch my patreon campaign I
would truly appreciate your support on
patreon if you feel like this podcast
was worth a couple of bucks and you were
able to contribute financially you can
do so by going to patreon.com slash grow
from your heart that's p80
r0 n patreon.com slash grow from your
heart if you'd like to contribute to the
podcast all the information that you
need will be right there if you
contribute to the podcast I will use
those contributions to pay for the
website that keeps the podcast free for
everybody and I will also use those
contributions to pay for the upgraded
MacBook I bought so that I can keep the
podcast coming and keep the videos
coming to everybody for free you guys I
will never charge you for this podcast
as long as I am able to put this podcast
out for free it will be free for you as
well I may in the future release some
paid content which will be bonus content
but this version of the podcast in this
format always will be free iTunes
stitcher and the YouTube channel as it
is will always be free I do this because
I love cannabis and I love you and I
want you to be able to medicate and
wreck create the best ways possible with
the highest quality cleanest safest
products available and I think the only
way you can do that is by growing it
yourself so I've got to teach you how to
do that so that you don't have to rely
on anybody else so my point is that the
podcast will be free but I know there
are people out there who would like to
contribute because they emailed me and
they said hey Jeff how can we help you
out so patreon is the best way to do
that patreon.com slash grow from your
heart also I would appreciate it if you
stalk me on the social media you can
find me on Facebook simply search for
the girl from your heart podcast on
Twitter it's at g f YH podcast and on
instagram i use my other company name
it's I read genetics i RIE
underscore genetics on Instagram make
sure you follow me there you guys don't
forget that the podcast is available on
iTunes stitcher and every single episode
is arc
on the YouTube channel simply search for
the girl from your heart podcast you
guys don't forget to check out our
friends at the Hell a dank seed company
you can find them at dank seed dot store
thanks again for listening to this
episode everybody I'll be back Monday
with a brand new episode I want to give
you a huge shout out to my friend grim
bolt the druid and until next time take
a phat dab and give your mom a hug for
me
[Music]