welcome back podcast world it's time for
episode 394 if they grow from your heart
podcast this episode is brought to you
by Oregon elite seeds if you need fresh
seeds for your garden I highly recommend
Oregon elite seeds and you can find them
at Oregon elite seeds dot-com it's
become a tradition that we start the
podcast off by talking about what I'm
dabbing today I'm taking dabs of vanilla
cookies batter from Apothecary farms and
it tastes delicious if you let the nail
cool nice and cool you get the real nice
vanilla cream kind of a flavor out of it
if you're a savage and you hit it while
the nails a little bit hot you get that
spicy Durbin poison part of the Girl
Scout cookies flavor and I really love
both flavors and it really gives me a
great buzz so I really enjoy the vanilla
cookies from apothecary farms big shout
out to everybody at a Pathak airy big
shout out to all three locations they've
got a Pueblo location they've got a
Colorado Springs location and by the
time this comes out they will have
opened a Denver location so big up and
congratulations to all of my friends at
apothecary ladies and gentlemen this is
going to be another repost episode if
you've been following along you know
I've been doing a long series of grow
lessons in the time line of those grow
lessons and has become time to clean up
and reset our garden for the next run I
originally did this episode as number
327 i'm reposting it now as 392 so
ladies and gentleman with no further ado
let's clean up and reset our garden for
the next run welcome back cannabis
community it's time for another episode
of the grow from your heart podcast your
source for cannabis news education and
conversation I try to here at new grower
if you're a professional grower if
you're a new smoker or a dedicated
dabber
if you're a cannabis activists or even
someone who is just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host my friends call me Roscoe Jeff I
want to thank you guys again for joining
me this episode of the podcast is
brought to you by my friends at the hell
a dank seed company if you need new
genetics for your garden I highly
recommend the hella dank seed company
you can find them at Bank seed dot store
ladies and gentlemen
a fat joint pack up the bong or start
heating up that dab rig because it's
time for another episode of to grow from
your heart a podcast
[Music]
welcome back podcast world it's time for
episode 328 of the girl from your heart
podcast thanks again for joining me you
know I like to start the show off by
letting you know what I'm dabbing today
I'm smoking star dog ambrosia batter
from our friends at apothecary farms if
you know me you know I love the star dog
I love the aroma I love the flavor I
love the high I love the way it grows
and of course I love taking pictures of
star dogs she's a very photogenic stream
so today I'm taking dabs of star dog and
Broz your batter from our friends at
apothecary now if you've been following
the show lately you've probably caught
the episodes about determining ripeness
of your cannabis plants then we did an
episode about flushing your plants then
we did an episode about harvesting then
we did an episode about drying and
curing your canvas plants then we did an
episode about trimming now it is time to
clean up the grow room and get restarted
for the next cycle let's talk a little
bit about after harvest cleaning it
sounds pretty basic but there are a few
things you may overlook now if you had
bugs or powdery mildew you may want to
step up your cleaning product you may
want to step up your cleaning regimen
but if you didn't have any bugs or any
issues I think a white bleach and water
solution should work or maybe you might
want to get yourself some flies in and
use 15 to 20 mils of 5n per gallon of
water use that to clean up your whole
grow either way whatever product do you
use let's clean everything let's clean
the walls wipe down every inch of every
wall start at one section at the top and
just work your way down and to the right
and then just keep going until you've
covered every inch of that grow room
also if you can reach scrub the ceiling
if you can't reach find me I can
probably reach if not get a ladder scrub
the ceiling let's clean it with either
bleach and hot water or flies in and hot
water and just get anything off of there
that may be hiding that we don't want in
that grow room maybe you've got a spider
light up there chilling out maybe you've
got a little bit of powdery mildew Spore
that you don't know about maybe there's
a piece of pollen up there that you
don't know about let's clean everything
to be sure so clean the walls clean the
ceiling clean your light reflectors
clean the lights the top of the lights
they're probably dusty up on top the
reflectors they're dusty on the inside
clean those things take this opportunity
while the rooms empty and clean
everything you guys so take the light
reflectors down if you think they need
some cleaning clean them hang them back
up clean your fans take the fans off of
the wall take the little grate off the
front unscrew the little thing that
holds the blades on take the blades off
clean the blades I know they're dirty
fans get disgusting the grate on the
back is filled with muck and hair and
just weird random gunk that I can't even
tell you what it is clean that [ __ ] out
of there you're probably gonna be
disgusted that you've been blowing that
[ __ ] around in your grow clean your fans
while you're cleaning the fans look at
anything that moves air or blows air
look at the air return on your
dehumidifier that thing's pulling in a
bunch of water and a bunch of air and
then it's blowing air back out does that
filter need to be changed does that
dehumidifier need to be cleaned off is
the water line it's draining water out
of your dehumidifier is it gunky does it
need to be cleaned is the reservoir that
you're draining your dehumidifier water
into starting to develop slime and algae
if so you need to clean that stay on top
of those sort of things so clean the
walls clean the whites clean the fans
clean your dehumidifier dust everything
the top of everything is dusty the top
of everything is funky you've been
spraying pesticides in there imagine you
sprayed some stinky pesticide like a
Xamax in there then it got dusty let's
just stick into the eyes of X it's funky
it's gross clean everything wipe it and
dust the tops of everything clean your
hydro tables if you've got tables in the
room clean them if you've got trays and
you can take them outside take them
outside spray them down with the hose
you've got a power washer they don't
look the power washer if those tables
are real dirty scrub them down with some
Faiz and scrub them down with some
bleach make sure you rinse them out real
good and just get them real clean you
guys the fayette is gonna foam up be
prepared for that you're gonna make foam
with baizen and make sure you clean
everything out when you're done using
cleaning products clean out your tables
and reservoirs really well if you use a
cleaning product
rinse the [ __ ] out of those hydro tables
rinse the [ __ ] out of all your tubing
and all of your lines clean that stuff
so that it's not clogged and so there's
no algae in there here's something
people don't pay enough attention to
clean the floor yes I know we just walk
on the floor all day right
sweep it mop it clean it up if you've
got some sort of poly film or panda film
on the floor some sort of subfloor does
it need to be replaced are there holes
in it has your poly or your Panda film
started stretching and getting holes
from the staples you need to duct tape
some spots check that kind of stuff out
clean your floors everything lands on
the floor the floor is gross
clean it up also here's something I
should mention if you've got light
reflectors with glass on them so that
they're air-cooled clean that glass take
that glass out wipe that [ __ ] down with
some Windex let it dry and put it back
clean the reflector glass also clean all
of your air conditioner filters check
them make sure they are clean if you've
got ducting anywhere check your ducting
make sure the ducting isn't bent in any
weird places make sure there are no
clogs make sure all of your duct is
secured make sure it's duct taped or
clamp somewhere so that the air you're
trying to move away from the grow
doesn't accidentally end up being blown
right where you don't need it if you've
got a leak that air is just gonna come
flying out of there you may just be
moving the heat from the light right
back into the grill room then your air
conditioner has to work harder and you
can't figure out why the room isn't
cooling down and it gets frustrating so
check all of your ducting check your
carbon filter is that carbon filter
still filtering can you smell the herb
outside when you grow did anybody
mention that your harvest stunk really
badly how long have you had that carbon
filter did you write it down you should
know when that carbon filter needs to be
replaced a lot of the brands say they
will last two years I never believe in
that I've never had a carbon filter last
two years also that carbon filter cover
maybe you're gonna leave that filter
there for two years and it's got that
little dust cover on it take that ugly
thing off throw it in the washer with
some oxy clean and clean that thing
nobody wants to see your pictures of
your black and gray carbon filter dust
cover that is gross also you guys get in
there and clean out the reservoir if
you've got a reservoir that you make
sure
nutrients in or that you use as part of
your hydro system that you're pumping
your nutrients from right to your plants
clean that reservoir why wouldn't you
want a clean fresh start you don't want
biofilm and funk in there because that's
going directly to your plants also clean
all of the tubing I've already said that
once but clean it all because all that
gunk will end up into your plants
another thing we should remember to
clean is the emitters if you've got a
hydro system with some sprayers or
emitters or sprinklers at the end of a
line make sure you pop those emitters
off and clean them they like to get
filled with some gunky funk now is the
perfect opportunity to take all those
off and clean them up real well another
really important thing we can do while
we've got the room taken down we can
decide if we need to replace any bulbs
how long have your bulbs been in the
grow depending on what type of lighting
you're using it may be time to swap out
some bulbs when bulbs get old they still
draw the same amount of electricity but
they do not put out the same amount of
light so you're paying for that
electricity and it is not making it to
your plants so check your bulbs and see
if they need to be replaced a good way
to find out if they need to be replaced
is to get a lumen meter a lumen meter
will measure how much light is coming
from your bulb if your bulb is putting
out less than 75 or 80 percent of its
maximum output it is time to replace it
now how do you know what the maximum
output of that bulb is the way to find
that out is to buy a brand new bulb put
the bulb in your reflector and turn it
on then you've got to wait a few minutes
and let that bulb get to its maximum
brightness it takes a little while for
the bulbs to heat up and get to the
right spectrum and get all the way
bright once it's bright and all the way
heated up go about 12 to 18 inches from
that bulb and measure what the lumens
are right there and write it down write
down the date and the amount of lumens
then check it now when you're cleaning
the room go the same distance away with
that lumen meter and see how many lumens
are popping up if you're not satisfied
with the amount of power you're getting
out of that bulb it is time to replace
it if you feel like you're paying for
electricity that it's not making it to
your plants it is time to replace your
bowl lumen meters may be expensive but a
lot of times the grow shop will let you
borrow one because they know that if you
bulbs are bad you're probably just gonna
come buy more bulbs when you return the
lumen meter so ask him at the gross
store they may have one available that
you can borrow all right guys
most of the cleaning stuff should be
fairly obvious clean the [ __ ] out of
everything scrub everything if you're
gonna put plants in anything that had a
cleaner in it make sure you get that
cleaner out replace the bulbs replace
the filters some other things we may not
remember to think about our check and
reset your timers and all of your
programs if you've got your lights on a
certain schedule fix that schedule if
you've got your co2 or your auto
watering on a schedule
make sure you correct that schedule
before you put new plants in here did
daylight savings time happen check that
is the timer on the right time is your
timer on the right day a lot of the
controllers have a day that you can set
is it Monday Tuesday or Wednesday is
that the proper day do you have AM and
PM set properly make sure you check out
all of your controllers before you put
plants in there and you accidentally
flour them way too early
also check out all of your co2 controls
another thing I like to do at this point
in time is calibrate all of my pens and
meters I like to calibrate my pH pen I
like to make sure that my EC meter is
working properly these are all things
that you should check on between
harvests I like to calibrate my meters
about once every two weeks to tell you
the truth probably every 10 days I just
like to check on them and make sure that
those things are accurate another thing
you should have a fire extinguisher near
your grow check on that look at the
little gauge on there make sure it's in
the green if your fire extinguisher
gauge is not in the green either buy a
new one or take it to the fire
department and have it refilled
correctly I really hope you don't have
to use that fire extinguisher but if you
need it I really want it to work for you
also check the batteries in your smoke
alarm yes I said smoke alarm your grow
should have a smoke alarm you don't want
to burn down the house because something
went wrong in the grow room and you did
not have a smoke detector and a fire
extinguisher so be a responsible grower
make sure that the safety precautions
are in place now since we're checking on
the fire extinguisher and the smoke
alarm it is a good time to
check on your respirator are you using a
respirator to apply pesticides
I really hope you're using something to
keep yourself safe if you're using a
respirator now is the time to check
those cartridges how long have they been
on there is it time to replace them is
that respirator clean maybe it's time to
watch a google video and learn how to
properly clean and take care of your
respirator that thing is going to save
your life over time take care of that
also it's a good time to replace your
gloves do you need more nitrile gloves
do you need more time X suits now is a
really good time to make a list and go
to the gross store and stock up on those
types of items all right so we've got
the grill room nice and clean we have
checked all of our safety precautions
we've refilled all the necessary
supplies now is a good time to do a
quick inventory of your pesticides and
nutrients and any accessories you think
you may need if you're gonna need
pesticides or nutrients start ordering
that stuff now so that when you move
your plants back into the room you have
got all the nutrients and all the
supplies you need so that you don't miss
a day of the growth cycle so we've got
everything cleaned up we've checked out
all of our safety equipment we've
restocked of our personal protective
equipment we have reordered all of our
nutrients now if we didn't have any
problems with pests or powdery mildew it
is time to start running that room and
get it prepared for the next cycle now
if you did have pests or problems there
are a couple of more steps that we need
to take we need to clean this room
thoroughly we need to spray it with some
products we might want to go a little
harder with the bleach water we might
want to go a little harder with some
thysen you might want to get a product
called procure if you had powdery mildew
you're gonna want to spray something to
get rid of the spores in that room if
you had bugs I would recommend spraying
some sort of pesticide through the
entire room just mix up your pesticide
sprayer your pump sprayer if you don't
have one go get one from Lowe's get a
good one
get a deck sprayer that can handle
bleach because you're gonna be putting
some chemicals in here they're not that
expensive you just need one that holds
about a gallon maybe two gallons of
water fill it up with water put your
cleaning product in there whether it's
Faiz an whether it's procure whether
it's a bunch of bleach maybe you want to
use granulated sulfur if you had a PM
shoo mix that up spray the [ __ ] out of
the entire room this is your best
opportunity to spray everything and
eliminate your problem there are no
plants in there so you can use products
that you wouldn't spray when you've got
plants in there so get in there and
clean the [ __ ] out of the room I would
start with the normal cleaning I
recommend it take everything down and
clean it then put it back up then set up
the room and before you put the plants
in there go in there with this
extra-hard commando cleaning spray and
go really hard you guys you got to get
all of the bugs out of there
or you're just gonna bring plants in
there and they're gonna get bugs or
they're gonna get p.m. and you're gonna
have another struggling harvest and
nobody likes to struggle through a
harvest so now we've taken everything
apart we've cleaned the [ __ ] out of the
room we've replaced the bulbs we've
replaced all of our filters we have
calibrated all of our equipment we've
got new protective equipment we have
tested our safety equipment we've put
the room back together we've gone in
there and done another final spray maybe
we hit it with fyz and maybe we sprayed
procure on everything to try to get rid
of our problems
maybe we just spray bleach water real
hot bleach water in there maybe we went
in there with some h2o - that would work
really well also but if you use any type
of products like that you guys make sure
you wear personal protective equipment
some goggles and a respirator you don't
want to spray bleach you don't want to
spray h2o - you don't want to spray
flies in without some sort of protective
equipment that should all be terrible
for your eyes terrible for your skin
please take care of yourself and if
you're using a sprayer to spray anything
please use some sort of respiratory
protection please now once the room is
put back together here is something I
suggest I would turn on the lights I
would turn on your blowers I would turn
on the fans I would turn on the air
conditioner and I would let everything
run for a few minutes and I would stand
in the room and pay attention is there
anything wrong is there anything you
could dial in is there anything you
could adjust do it while you're in there
then go outside and walk around your
grow space if your grove is at your
house just go walk around the house just
go pick up trash around the house or
whatever and see if you can identify any
light leaks do you see light coming out
of your grow room if you see light
coming out there is light going in
we do not want and cannot have light
leaks in our grow room so walk around
the house walk around the perimeter
identify any possible light leaks also
listen do you hear the blowers do you
hear the fans do you hear your air
conditioner is anything outside making
it obvious that you're running aggro in
that house this is a good time to
discover that we've got light leaks or
that we've got noisy equipment so that
we don't get ourselves in trouble you do
not want to attract law enforcement it
may be legal where you grow it is legal
where I grow I am still stealth because
you know who's worse than law
enforcement [ __ ] thieves you don't
want people to know you've got to grow
in your house because somebody may come
and take your crop from you that is a
real thing keep that in mind you have to
be careful even in a legal state keep
your grow stealth so walk around outside
look listen smell
pay attention see if anything is going
wrong outside once you're sure that
everything is fine outside that's when
you can go back in the grow room turn
off the lights in the grow room and
stand in there for about ten minutes let
your eyes adjust now is the time to find
out if any light is leaking into the
grow now is the time to find out if the
sunshine from outside is coming through
your ducts for your vanity
right into your light reflectors into
your grow room and shining light on your
plants during a dark period now is the
time to find that out now the catch to
these last two things you're only gonna
be able to tell if you have a light leak
outside if you go walk around the house
and it's dark outside the only way you
can tell if you have a light leak inside
is if it's light outside and you go in
the grow room and you turn off the
lights on the inside of the grow room so
you're gonna have to find the time of
day to do that you're gonna have to do
some investigating and some inspecting
but these are very important details to
not overlooked make sure your grow room
is light proof make sure there's not a
lot of noise coming out of there and
also find out if you've got too much
aroma and correct it if you do you don't
want to attract attention that you don't
need once you've been growing for a
while or if you're somebody who is
looking for
so say myself I've been grown for a long
time when I used to go walk my dog in my
neighborhood I would always discover a
new grow I would go a different route
I'd go two blocks that way three blocks
that way I blocked that way and then I'd
come back and then the next day I'd just
do a different pattern I would always
find a new grow about once a week
because I know what I'm looking for
listening for and smelling for I know
the details I know the clues if I hear
you're weird blower at 3:00 in the
morning going from your basement window
chances are you got to grow in there if
you've got an air conditioner in your
basement window in the middle of winter
chances are there's a grow in there if
you've got one window by the basement it
has no snow and the rest of the backyard
is snowy there's a grow in there if
there's one spot on your roof above one
bedroom that there's no snow on it
there's a grow in there there are really
easy signs that give it away so pay
attention you guys because if I can see
it
law enforcement can see it and so can
the thieves so be careful with your grow
try to stay stealth even in legal states
there's no reason to brag there's no
reason to set bait
all right podcast world I feel like that
is a pretty good clean and reset episode
hopefully I mentioned some details that
you would have overlooked hopefully I
rescued you through a couple of pitfalls
now you don't have to make those
mistakes hopefully everything was well
in your grow and you don't have any
problems hopefully you don't have
anything funky to deal with also now
that the grow is nice and clean let's
[ __ ] keep it clean let's get in there
with a mop and a broom everyday if we
need to and mop and sweep that [ __ ]
let's get in there with a shop vac and
suck out you know that [ __ ] in the
corner you've been looking at get the
[ __ ] shop back and back that out it's
not gonna shop back itself that's a
great place for a spider mite to hang
out it's a great place for some aphids
to hang out and breed that's a great
place for some powdery mildew to start
that is just a vector for problems so
now that you've got it nice and clean
don't be lazy get in there and clean it
as often as you can
they say that cleanliness is godliness
and I think that most applies in
kitchens and grow rooms you guys so
clean up that grow room give yourself a
nice clean environment give your plants
a nice healthy start I think your plants
will be more comfortable and I think you
will also notice working in a cleaner
more organized environment will
you happier it'll make you faster and
more productive and [ __ ] now that you're
done cleaning up the grow room why don't
you clean up all your supplies go
organize your nutrients go organize the
pesticides the measuring devices your
cleaning supplies go write down a list
of anything that you can need anything
that you're low on go get yourself
organized also get a notebook and start
making detailed notes start documenting
when you changed your bulb start
documenting when you change your carbon
filter start documenting the last time
you change your air conditioner filters
it calibrated your meters start writing
that stuff down so that when something
comes up you can look in there and go oh
that's why my pH meter isn't working I
have it calibrated the [ __ ] thing in
two months you may find some things you
were slipping on if you start taking
more notes
all right podcast ruled I feel like that
pretty much wraps up my clean and reset
the grow room episode I want to thank
you guys for listening thanks for
hanging out with me for another episode
this is the part of the podcast where I
remind you about patreon if you feel
like this podcast was worth a couple of
bucks
you can contribute by going to
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
and all the information that you need
will be right there
you guys don't forget to check out my
friends at the Hell a dank seed company
you can find them at dank seed dot store
also I would appreciate it if you stalk
me on all the social media you can find
me on Facebook simply search for the
girl from your heart podcast you can
find me on Twitter it's at G fyh podcast
and on Instagram I use my other company
name I use I Ari underscore genetics
make sure you check me out on Instagram
if you'd like to reach out to me if
you've got something you'd like to say
you're not into the social media if
you've got a product you'd like me to
review or you'd like to sponsor the
podcast or maybe you've just got a
question you'd like me to read on the
show you can send me an email my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I would love to hear from
you ladies and gentlemen don't forget
that the show is available on iTunes
stitcher and every single episode is
archived on youtube go to youtube and
search for the girl from your heart
podcast and you can listen to every
single episode of the podcast right
there on the YouTube channel
big thanks to everybody who has
subscribed and left comments on the
YouTube channel I appreciate your love
and support I want to thank everybody
once again for listening to a rambly
podcast I will be back in a few days
with a fresh new episode I want to give
a huge shout out to my
and mama bear dabs and until next time
take a phat dab and give your mom a hug
for me
all right podcast rule that concludes a
long series of grow lessons I want to
thank everybody for listening to the
grow lessons I want to thank you again
for listening to the repost episodes I
really hope you learned a lot from this
grow series I hope you gained some
confidence and I also hope you're going
to have more fun in your grow with the
knowledge and confidence you have gained
if you feel like this episode or this
grow series was educational informative
or entertaining and you would like to
make a financial contribution to the
podcast I would greatly appreciate your
support you can support the show by
going to patreon.com slash grow from
your heart and all the information you
need to become a patron we'll be right
there on the screen once again that's
patreon.com/lenguin
[Music]
all right you guys I'll be back in just
a couple of days with fresh new content
I'm going to get back into the emails
I've got some great content put together
if you've got a question if you've got a
grow question a cannabis industry
question a cannabis culture question I
would love to get that question on the
podcast and answer that for you right
here on the show you can get that
question to me by sending it to me via
email my email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com and I do look
forward to hearing from you
ladies and gentlemen that's all I've got
for this episode I want to say thank you
once again for listening to the long
series of grow lessons I'll catch up
with you guys in just a few days I want
to give you a huge shot it's my friend
love for the plant and until next time
take a phat dad and give your mom a hug
for me