this is Doug Benson and you're listening
to the grow from your heart podcast
[Music]
welcome back cannabis world it is time
for episode 395 of the girl from your
heart podcast this episode is brought to
you by Oregon elite seeds that's right
Oregon elite seeds if you need new seeds
for your garden I highly recommend
Oregon elite seeds and you can find them
at www.opm.gov/openseason is 62.2% THC
and seventy three point four total
cannabinoids this stuff tastes delicious
it has a really unique funky aroma I
can't find the right words to describe
it it is gross it is funky and it is
sweet spicy and sour and delicious all
at the same time I really can't get
enough of the gelato cake batter the
aroma is remarkable the flavor is
incredible and the buzz is beautiful
it's got me nice and high and it's got
my eyes kind of droopy and I've got the
best cottonmouth right now it is
delicious so big shout out to all my
friends at apothecary farms thank you
for the great gelato cake batter all
right podcast world if you've been
following along you know that I've been
doing a long series of grow lessons in a
previous episode I mentioned that those
lessons were over well I was wrong since
that time I realized I left out a very
crucial part of our grow experience we
started off by making a solid plan for
our grow we thought out our equipment we
thought out our space very well we
thought out our genetics hopefully we
successfully ran a full garden cycle we
have harvested we have dried and cured
that product we've got some beautifully
trimmed up buds you know the one thing I
left out we never smoked this product so
this episode is going to be the smoke
that [ __ ] episode we've ran a full
garden let's reward ourselves and enjoy
our finished product there's really
nothing like smoking your own product
any flowers that you've grown harvested
trimmed you spent a bunch of time with
it you've really got some attachment to
it
there's really a rewarding feeling that
comes with smoke
a crop that you grew I've been drawing
for quite a while I've grown many many
small personal crops I have grown many
large commercial crops I've done a lot
of Fino hunts of plants that I have bred
I have grown a lot of plants and it is
still very exciting to me to get to try
the first little batch of smoke from
each crop that I grow there's something
very rewarding and very satisfying and
very fun it feels like a kid inside like
a kid on Christmas morning I get to try
my new thing you know let's see what
it's like I spent all this time with it
and I finally get to enjoy it every time
I do it especially something that I've
just bred and it's his first run with it
so I bred something I made some seeds
that grew those seeds out I Fino hunted
those seeds and now I finally have a
finished product that is real
satisfaction to me there's nothing like
that feeling so this may be your first
time getting to enjoy this experience I
want this to be a great experience for
you I want every harvest to be a
wonderful experience for you there's one
thing they can really ruin your
experience when it comes to testing your
cannabis for the first time the one
thing that can really [ __ ] it up is by
being impatient if you cut down your
plants too early they aren't going to be
the quality you deserve if you dried and
cured your plants in a rushing manner
you are not going to get the quality
that you deserve so make sure those
plants got to finish
make sure your plants were flushed make
sure they were harvested dried and cured
and trimmed correctly let's not try to
smoke our first crop too early and put a
bad taste in our mouth literally about
our new crop you're gonna take a bud
you're gonna dry it fast you're gonna
try to smoke it it's gonna taste like
[ __ ] and you're gonna feel like [ __ ]
about your whole crop you're gonna have
just a bad feeling about it you spent
all this time be patient let each bud be
ready before you smoke them so the first
thing we need to test before we get down
to smoking this product is is it ready
is it dry enough have you dried and
cured this product properly before we go
putting it in a grinder and try to roll
it up or put it in a pipe it is
acceptable for a cured herb to be kind
of sticky and a little bit moist that is
the way a lot of people like it you
don't get a lot of that in the Colorado
area because we have what is known as
the Colorado crunch here and I do plan
to do a
Podcast all about the Colorado crunch in
the future but let's stay focused let's
talk about your dried and cured herb
before we smoke it it may be a little
spongy it may be a little sticky if you
have cured it properly that is okay you
may need to take a couple of nugs out of
the jar and set them on the table for
three four maybe five or six hours
before you decide to smoke it is not
uncommon to see a connoisseur smoker
pull out his jar of nugs crack the lid
take out three or four nuggets set him
on the table
seal the jar up put it back in his
little stash spot and then leave those
Nuggets on the table throughout the day
and that's what we smoke on as the day
goes by they may be a little bit damp as
soon as we pull them out of the jar but
as the day goes on they're gonna dry out
perfectly
to roll a fat joint and pack a couple of
bowls so make sure your herb is cured
and dry enough to burn properly so you
don't disappoint yourself with your
first experience now if you're confident
that your buds are dried and cured and
ready for consumption let's talk about
taking that first taste test of our new
crop for me testing a new product is
sort of a combination between a science
experiment and a ritual I like to be in
my environment I like to use my
equipment I like to know what to expect
I like to take away variables that way I
can see what the actual product is
telling me now I know that may sound
weird to some people but a lot of
stoners are very ritualistic and by
ritualistic I don't mean some fancy
ceremony I just mean I like to be in a
certain place I like to be right here
this is my comfortable smoking place if
you gave me a new concentrate if you
gave me some flour and you said hey I
want you to judge this or rate this this
would be the best place for me to
conduct that experiment so that I could
give you a proper review this is where
I'm comfortable I know that the door is
locked i know i can consume safely here
i know that nobody can bother me here i
can control the environment here i can
control the music here this is a great
place for myself to consume any type of
cannabis product I'm comfortable here
nothing could go wrong there's a couch
over there there's a bed about 50 feet
away there's snacks in the fridge I'm
set up here I'm really comfortable also
I've got my little chair this is my zone
I got my drinks right here in front of
me I got the computer so I could browse
the Internet I've got my my next step in
this talk is my equipment I've got all
my favorite smoking equipment just to
the right of me
my favorite pipe is here my favorite dad
rig is here all my tools to keep those
things in proper smoking condition are
all right here so part of the ritual is
being in the right place
you've probably got that little place
it's your little chair it's that little
spot on your bed everybody's got that
one little cozy spot where they want to
chill and smoke so get in your little
cozy place get comfy
put on the music that you like get the
air the way you like it be in your right
place also get your favourite piece
maybe you've got that favorite bong
maybe you've got that favourite daybreak
maybe you've got that favourite pipe
find your favourite piece be in your
comfort zone also maybe there are
certain people you do or don't like to
smoke around do you want to smoke your
crop for the first time by yourself or
do you want to make it fun and bring
your friends along and be like bro check
out what I smoked let's try it together
for the first time it's always fun to
have your friends around also that puts
you on the spot
maybe you smoked it and it tastes like
you just stuck your tongue in a light
socket and everyone's gonna get to smoke
that with you and experience it that's a
learning experience just be honest
go ahead and share it with your friends
see what everybody thinks we're gonna
talk more about that reaction in just a
minute another thing that is really fun
to involve your friends in is if you do
a Fino hunt so if you grew five seeds
you've probably got five different
phenotypes or maybe two or three
different phenotypes to select from
out of those five it's always fun to
load up five balls or roll five joints
and label them somehow right on the end
of the filter right number one number
two or just remember and then smoke them
with your friends and see if you guys
like plant number one plant number two
plant number three better see if
different people in the room like number
one or number three better maybe
everybody in the room says bro number
five was amazing that's always fun to
bring your friends around to consume
with you to see what you have just done
so do you want your first try your
ritual do you want that to happen with
friends around or do you want that to be
a little isolated situation I could go
both ways in my little comfort zone
right here there are two chairs right in
front of me where Mike is always invited
Kevin likes to take this spot right here
there are several other folks that come
over and smoke they're always invited
that's always fun to me I've got a
couple other chairs we can pull out if
it gets crowded
I like to smoke with friends I don't
know if you want to smoke your first
crop with friends you may be timid you
may be shy that may not be your thing
but think about that do you want some
friends around another thing I recommend
when you come to sampling your new
product is make it your first smoke of
the day don't smoke anything before that
don't eat any edibles before that go in
totally sober go in fresh so that you
know exactly what your product has done
to you so let me back up a couple of
steps I've gotten ahead of myself let's
start off by grinding up our product
once you are in your comfortable spot
with your people with your music plan
with a drink on hand you're ready to
rock the first couple of things to
consuming your new flowers are a visual
inspection let's take a look at it let's
look and see what we've done let's enjoy
the beauty of this product what colors
do you see did you trim it well could
you trim it better next time by looking
at it how did the trichomes look is that
plant real frosty is it just kind of
frosty give it a nice look enjoy it
smell it hold it up to your face give it
a nice smell enjoy that it is yours you
put a lot of work into it I think the
next step is to give it a little bit of
a squeeze yeah you may break it up a
little bit that's fine we're about to
put this in a grinder and smoke it we
can destroy this but it is yours enjoy
it so I'd give it a little squeeze how
moist is it do you think it's ready to
smoke is that ready are you gonna
embarrass yourself by trying to put that
in the pipe do you really need just
another day or two of curing that or
does it need to sit on the table for a
couple hours
is it ready this is your last chance
before you grind it up in front of your
friends so make sure how does it feel in
your hands is it real sticky now that
you've played with it a little bit smell
the inside of the bud smell your fingers
how does that smell try to absorb and
enjoy all of this stuff especially if
it's your first crop and if this is like
your thousandth crop slow down for a
minute stop and smell the flowers this
is one of the most rewarding parts of
the entire process we've done a lot of
work let's enjoy this stuff let's not
think too much about how much did we
harvest what is it weigh what is it
worth let's enjoy the actual flowers
that we have grown let's enjoy the
effort we made that turned into a
consumable product that is beautiful
that has a great aroma to it that is a
of art and nature and science all put
together that you did take a moment
enjoy that [ __ ]
so smell it break it up smell your
fingers now it is time to put it in a
grinder when you put it in the grinder
and give it a couple of turns if that
grinder is really hard to spin your buds
may be too wet when you open up that
grinder if it's a little moist in there
you'll be able to tell at this point if
that one bud is a little bit too wet
you still need to let the rest of the
buds dry and cure just a little bit
longer don't worry you can dry them a
little bit more and you will be just
fine
now if you feel like the bud that you
have ground up is ready to consume let's
talk about consuming it how do you want
to smoke it what is your favorite way I
spoke earlier about your favorite piece
are you gonna roll a joint
are you a joint kind of a person are you
a bond kind of a person are you a pipe
kind of a person are you gonna throw out
the vaporizer how do you want to do it
that is up to you please please you can
do it however you want it's your herb
but please for me don't wrap it up in a
blunt wrap you just spent so much time
drawing the most delicious herb you
dried it and cured it why are you gonna
wrap it up in a paper bag I am all about
smoking a fat joint but I do not
appreciate smoking a blunt if you're
gonna roll it up get yourself some good
papers get something like some roz some
elements something quality but please
for this first test
please don't roll it up in a blunt and
since we're on this subject if you're
gonna pack a bowl clean your pipe you've
got some fresh herb you've got your
friends over you want to impress
yourself and your friends the best you
can with this new herb so clean your
pipe and if you're smoking through the
bong dude
clean the bong and change the bong water
you wouldn't believe how many places I
go to smoke a bong load and the water
looks like muck and I will not smoke a
bowl so just change the bong water clean
your piece and everybody will enjoy it
much more and it will make your product
taste much better we're trying to
impress everybody you guys so let's do
the best we can to make your product
taste the best that it can all right so
you ground up your herb you've got a fat
joint rolled you've got a bong load
packed you've got a pipe loaded maybe
you filled up the vaporizer maybe you've
got a volcano bag going on however you
decided to do it now it is time to take
our first puff of our freshly dried and
cured cannabis crop like I said earlier
I recommend this being your first
puff of the day that way you know
exactly what your herb does to you we
have now come to my favorite part of the
entire process it is now time to smoke
the first sample of our newly harvested
crop so if you rolled up a joint now's
the time to spark it up if you packed up
a bowl now is the time to start taking a
couple of puffs if you've got the
vaporizer going now's the time to start
taking a couple of pools take a couple
of pools a couple of draws a couple of
totes off your new product and sit back
for a couple of seconds and let it sit
in and see what it does to you I don't
know how much you consume but depending
on your consumption level you should
probably be able to take two three maybe
four good draws or whatever you're
smoking on if you're smoking a joint
maybe two or three good draws if you're
smoking a bowl maybe two or three maybe
three or four good puffs off of that if
you're hitting the bong hopefully you
only need one or two good bong rips
before you start feeling it
I find vaporizers to be unpredictable I
never know if I'm gonna need 1 or 6
pools off the vaporizer but take as many
as you're comfortable with get a little
buzz on and sit back for a couple of
seconds and just see what happens
are you stoned did you get mallow did
you get low are you high did you get
giggly and goofy are you paranoid do you
have the munchies how do you feel give
it a couple of seconds if you've got
other friends in the room start
conversation you guys will start talking
about the product you start talking
about the herb somebody will mention the
taste
somebody will mention the aroma
conversation will start pay attention to
how your friends react to your herb make
a mental note of what you think of the
herb do you like it do you like the
aroma do you like the flavor
do you like the buzz that you've gotten
from the way you've consumed it now it
may be time to take a couple of more
puffs and go to the next level
now what do you think now that you've
pushed it a little bit how do you feel
now are you super stoned or you stuck to
the couch or eve flying off the couch
and just hanging on for dear life
how's it making you feel how's it acting
to your friends are they lit are they
bored see how they're enjoying it pay
attention to the words that they're
saying and try to make a mental note of
their review of your product now let's
talk about a few things to look for
while you are smoking your first sample
let's look for some things about the
product to pay attention to how does
your product burn does it burn smoothly
did it burn like a charcoal briquette or
did it burn a nice why
ash if the ash that you knocked off the
end of your joint or that chunk that you
dumped out of your bowl at the end if
that was chunky and black you may not
have flushed your product long enough
you may want a longer flush time also
you may not have dried it properly it
may still be a little bit wet if it's
not burning properly it could still be a
little moist and it needs more dry time
so pay attention to how it burns also
how does it smoke is the smoke nice and
smooth is that smoke thick and harsh
does it hurt your throat does it make
you cough or can you just toke on it all
day and blow clouds and it doesn't
bother your lungs and throat at all pay
attention to that you can make
improvements in your next grow based on
the quality of this product how is the
flavor how is the aroma are those things
on point because if the flavor and aroma
and burn factor are not on point you can
absolutely correct those in your next
grow I was talking about paying
attention to what your friends say
because they are going to be honest with
you
you're going to be very proud of your
crop you spend a lot of time on this
you're going to think it is the best
herb you've ever smoked that is a very
natural thing for new growers
to experience listen to your friends
they smoke a lot of herb also they're
going to have very influential feedback
don't let their criticism hurt your
feelings you're going to take their
compliments when one of your friends
says brother this [ __ ] smells so good I
can't believe you grew this you're gonna
glow when the other guy says bro this
kind of burns my throat you have to take
that compliment just as strongly as you
did or that criticism as strongly as you
did that compliment they both matter
equally so use the compliment as a
driving force to move you forward use
the criticism as a way to improve your
crop next time don't be hurt when one of
your friend says bro that we burns my
throat that's cuz you did something
wrong and you need to improve and he was
honest with you because he's a good
friend I mentioned earlier that some of
the things that you may need to improve
that you'll notice right away are your
flush how is that product burning again
is it a dark chunk or is it a nice white
clean ash does it burn all the way
through the joint or do you need to keep
relighting it if it's burning a real
black and chunky and you need to keep
relighting it you probably needed to
flush longer if
just keeps going out but it's not
burning real black it may just be too
wet and you need to dry and cure it a
little bit longer how was your cure
process does the herb taste good
does it smell good is it crunchy is it
dry is it moist did you dry and cure it
to your liking do your friends think you
dried and cured it properly what do you
think as long as you're happy that's
what matters as long as you were
consuming it if it's going to market
it's got to satisfy the market so pay
attention to what the market says also
how did you trim it are you satisfied
with the trim are your clients satisfied
with the trim maybe you can improve on
the trim a lot of new growers don't trim
enough in my opinion you could go a
little bit harder on your trim job now
that you were consuming the product and
you can actually tell what type of buzz
it gives you do you think you should
have flowered a little bit longer or do
you think you should have flowered a
little bit shorter if you pay attention
to the finished product and how things
came out this time if you took plenty of
notes throughout the grow you can look
at your notes you can look at your
finished product and you can see things
that you can improve for the next run
which will make you a better grower so
take all of those compliments and take
all of that criticism and ball it all up
into one big learning lesson and think
of ways to improve your crop next time
now the overall deciding factor on the
quality of this product is how do you
feel do you like it were you going for a
low couch lock kind of a buzz or were
you going for a big psychedelic head
spinning hi and did you get what you
were after do you think if you would
have let that plant flower a little bit
longer that you would have gotten better
quality do you think maybe you would
have gotten a fatter yield do you think
maybe if you have chopped it a little
later that it may have started to
diminish the flavor do you think if you
were to cut it a little bit earlier that
it would have been a little more head
buzzy and a little bit racier there are
things to think about as you were
testing the final product are you
satisfied with your finished product is
the bottom line if you're satisfied
don't change a thing if there are things
that you're not satisfied with look at
your notes and think of ways that you
can improve those things for your next
run now I started off our little science
experiment slash ritual of testing our
first crop by sitting in our little
comfortable environment cannabis
consumers stoners
heads whatever you want to call us I'm
okay with all of the above we have this
tendency to smoke and get trapped in our
little spot we don't want to go anywhere
we're nice and comfortable here like I
said earlier the music is just right the
air-conditioner is just right the fridge
is full of snacks my bros are right here
at the table why would I want to go
anywhere why because when you step out
of this little comfort zone you may be
twice as stoned as you even noticed it's
really easy to smoke a whole bunch of
product and sit here and be blazed out
of your mind to be comfortable because
this is the zone you know where
everything is I know there's a drink
right here I know the dad rig is right
here I know the pen is right here I know
where everything is there's no chaos
right here maybe go somewhere go for a
walk
maybe call an uber and have them take
you to the mall or to the park just go
somewhere just get out of the house
maybe just go get some food some more
with your bros and just get out of the
house while your freshly buzzed on that
fresh new product and see what kind of
brand new experiences the world brings
to you out there there's this thing
about stoners that once you smoke you've
got about 10 minutes if you don't get up
and leave in 10 minutes
you're [ __ ] stuck wherever you just
smoke so smoke a little bit if you're
comfortable just hanging out at the
house do that see what you experience
but next time take a few puffs of that
new product call an uber and go some
more exciting and see what life brings
you you may get into some cool new
adventures
all right podcast rolled that is my talk
about sampling and trying our freshly
harvested cannabis crop I hope you had
as much fun as I did I hope you learned
something if you found this episode
educational informative or entertaining
and you would like to make a financial
contribution to the show I would
appreciate your support and you can help
out by going to patreon.com slash grow
from your heart all the information you
need to become a patron will be right
there on the screen just so you know I
use the funding from patreon for things
like keeping the website alive I do host
a website I read genetics Colorado calm
is my website that is where the podcast
is hosted that's how I'm able to keep
the podcast coming to you for free it
does cost me a little bit of money to
host the website every year so I do pay
for that out of the patreon
contributions I also use last year's
patreon contributions to fund the
MacBook that I am using to record the
show on right now I also use some of the
patreon funding for a little microphone
covers and for equipment that breaks
occasionally
had to replace this headphone amp a
couple of times I buy memory cards and
things like that with the funding from
patreon so it mainly pays to the podcast
and the equipment and the little
microphone covers so I want to thank you
guys for contributing to patreon and I
look forward to all of the future
support I would also appreciate it if
you find me on all of these social media
on Facebook simply search for the girl
from your heart podcast on Twitter it's
@gf wih podcast if you want to follow my
personal Twitter account it's at Rasta
Jeff 420 also I encourage you to check
out my Instagram on Instagram I go by
Irie underscore genetics I read genetics
on Instagram that's my seed company I
post a lot of pictures of cannabis
photography I think you would enjoy it I
also go on Instagram live and I do live
videos where I hang out with my friends
I talk about growing and I answer grow
questions so follow me on Instagram and
catch my Instagram live videos and maybe
I will answer your question in the live
feed there if you've got something to
say and you're not into the social media
maybe you've got a question maybe you've
got a product you'd like me to review
perhaps you'd like to sponsor the show
you can reach out to me through email my
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com and I would love to hear
from you don't forget that the show is
available on Apple podcasts stitcher
radio google play tune in radio and of
course you can find every episode on
youtube I want to thank you once again
for listening to this podcast zona thank
you again for listening to the long
series of grow lessons I hope you had as
much fun as I did
ladies and gentlemen I'll be back in
just a few days with fresh new content I
want to give a huge shout out to my
friend Kelvin Medina and until next time
take a phat dab and give your mom a hug
for me