this episode of the girl from your heart
podcast is dedicated to my friend Brody
Stevens
welcome to the show podcast world it's
time for episode 398 of the girl from
your heart podcast this episode of the
show is brought to you by Oregon elite
seeds if you need new seeds in your
garden I highly recommend Oregon elite
seeds and you can find them at
www.ctvn.org forms the label says it is
seventy four point nine percent THC with
eighty nine point six percent total
cannabinoids I really like this
concentrate it's got a nice stony effect
to it it's more stony than high seems to
put me in a nice little bubble puts me
in my own little space in my head here
and I really enjoy that so today we're
taking dabs of the banana wafer cush
from our friends at apothecary farms all
right podcast world in this episode I'm
going to read a few listen or emails and
answer a few questions but before I get
there I want to read a comment that came
in on the YouTube channel on the last
episode I talked about the Colorado
crunch now what's the Colorado crunch
that is when the herb gets super dry
from being left in the jars all day in
the dispensary in Colorado we had a
comic they came from a listener named ER
on YouTube and Dr says I just want to
add that Bovina packs save my ass I wish
I would see more dispensaries out there
using them that don't prepackaged their
product now I do appreciate the input
but I do also despise the Veda packs or
Boveda packs however you say it I do not
like them in the jars with the product
at the dispensary on the shelf in my
opinion those packs leave a funky aroma
and flavor on the buds now with that
being said if you like the packs and you
like the results that you or your local
dispensary are getting by using those
packs don't change anything because of
what I say do your thing let it work for
you but let me make a suggestion for
your personal grow this method wouldn't
be practical in a dispensary environment
but it does work in a commercial grow
and it would work in your personal grow
environment if your buds get too crunchy
something I suggest is
grabbing a leaf from a fresh plant if
you've got a mason jar one leaf will be
enough stick one fresh leaf inside your
mason jar just set it in there seal the
lid leave it in there for like 3045
minutes
crack it open and see how much it has
moistened up the rest of those buds that
moisture from that one leaf will move
around in those buds very quickly and
you're using the same plant with the
same breaks level the same aroma the
same flavor you're not adding anything
different into that jar to make a funky
flavor you are putting the exact same
plant in there with the same aroma the
same flavor you're not gonna mess things
up so if you'd like to get away from the
Boveda packs also save yourself a few
bucks that is another option for you
maybe experiment if you're interested
again if you're happy with what you've
got going on don't change anything on my
account keep doing what you're doing the
only way you're doing it wrong is if you
kill the plants or if you're not happy
with the final outcome if you're happy
with your final outcome and you're
satisfied with your product keep doing
exactly what you're doing but also keep
looking for ways to improve all right
again that came from Dr on the YouTube
channel big thanks to our friend dr
thanks for listening to the show and
also thanks for the great feedback and
thanks for the great show material I
would appreciate it if everybody finds
me on YouTube simply go to youtube and
search for the girl from your heart
podcast click Subscribe leave some
comments on the videos and who knows
maybe I will read your comments on a
future episode alright now it is time to
start working through the mountain of
emails that I've been saving up for the
show
I love and appreciate all of the emails
and questions that you guys have sent me
but I was tied up in that long series of
grow lessons so I wasn't really paying
much attention to the emails now that
that series is done it is time to start
working through these emails so let's
get right to it on the top of the stack
here this one goes just like this
what's up Rasta Jeff I've been looking
forward to growing for a long time now
over the past year I've loved listening
through your podcasts I'm finally ready
to get started as all of my equipment
was just delivered this week dude first
of all thanks for listening to the show
and second congratulations on all of the
new equipment I bet that is super
exciting the message goes on to say I'm
going to be working in door
and a four-by-four vibe Oh Sun tint I'm
hoping to put four plants in five gallon
buckets under a 1200 watt LED grow light
I'd like to order seeds from your online
store but the selection is so vast that
it's a little intimidating now let me
jump in and say that I don't have a
website that sells seeds I am a breeder
but my seeds are available on other
vendor websites you are probably
referring to the Halliday seed company
at dang seed store or possibly your
shopping on Oregon Elite seeds at Oregon
elite seeds dot-com there are a couple
of other great vendors they carry my
products but those are the two who I
have talked about most on here so that
is probably where you were shopping and
yes I do agree that it can be quite
intimidating
I myself offer over 20 different seed
lines so there are 20 lines available
from just myself there are probably 20
or 30 different vendors available on the
hella dank seed company organ Elite
seeds has got at least a hundred
breeders available on their website so
it does get very confusing it can get
very intimidating it can be overwhelming
very quickly sometimes when I go to a
restaurant or even a dispensary I
complain that there are too many options
I say you should just give me one or two
options and say that's what you're
eating and take it and shut up and be
happy because right now it's gonna take
me 30 minutes to sift through all these
options just to figure out what I want
so I get it it can be overwhelming it
can be a lot to think about it can be a
lot to look at also some seed strain
descriptions can be very deceptive and
very misleading also it can be very
confusing to a new grower what all the
X's and parentheses mean when the
genetics are listed so I totally agree
that it can be overwhelming so let's get
ourselves back on track here the message
continues it goes like this I was hoping
you could provide some suggestions and
maybe even some pro tips on growing
whichever strain I decide on please let
me know if I can provide any more
information about my situation and help
narrow down what would work best it's
going to be my first growth so I'm not
expecting perfect results but I figure
some expert advice could go a long way
looking forward to hearing from you and
then they signed it with their name
which I do not have permission to say on
the show so I'm gonna hold that back but
hey do do you know who you are thank you
for the great email let's start
answering a couple of your
questions I really think you've got the
right idea with four five gallon pots in
this environment that should be just
enough space
don't let the plants get too tall I
don't know how much ceiling height
you've got in your tent but make sure
you flower soon enough to where those
plants don't reach up into your light
also make sure that you've got plenty of
airflow in that tent you need some way
to pull that moist hot stale air out of
the top of that tent and let fresh new
cool air come in into the bottom of the
tent so that you can keep those plants
in a healthy environment many new
growers overlook the importance of
airflow when they are building a grow in
a tent so please make sure to have some
way to remove that humidity out of the
tent it won't go out by itself you need
an extraction fan coming out of the tent
to suck that humidity out of there and
honestly I don't know much about that
brand of tent and I don't know much
about LEDs but it sounds like you're off
to a good start with your grow so let's
focus more on the seed aspect of your
question selecting new seeds for your
very first grow can be a lot of fun I
would recommend finding a strain that
does not take a really long time to
finish something around eight weeks
would be ideal for a new grower that is
less time to screw up the product for a
new grower that extra week or two is a
lot more opportunity for things to go
wrong so try to find something that
finishes around eight or nine weeks
would be my first suggestion so as
you're scrolling through and you're
looking at flower times if you see that
it says it's going to take nine to ten
or ten to eleven weeks I've kind of
steer away from that and find something
a little quicker in the flower area
something else to think about do you
want to grow regular or feminized seeds
you've only got room for four those are
the folks that I recommend feminized
seeds to folks with very limited space
and not a lot of experience those
feminized seeds will help you out in
several different ways first you don't
have to look for the male's second you
don't plant a plant and then grow it and
then flour it and realize you've got to
throw it away if you were Fino hunting
if you were that type of a grower that's
when I suggest you get regular seeds but
someone in your situation I may suggest
feminized seeds now I know you said you
were looking for IRA genetics seeds
let's talk about some iris genetics
suggestions they may work well in that
Roah something that I would recommend
that is not feminized would be prana
prana is flow cross to arise that flow
keeps it kind of short and stocky it
smells really nice
it grows nice and bushy it would work
well in your environment my next
recommendation would be sun kiss Sun
kiss is not feminized
it is a regular seed but it stays nice
and short and squat and it grows real
wide and branchy and I think it would
work great in your environment now for
feminized options I would recommend the
Michelangelo again we have got the
Platinum tangi in there that is cross to
my blueberry cookies that one won't get
super tall on you it's really easy to
grow it produces well it makes a lot of
resin and it smells and tastes like
oranges and funky candies and it is
delicious another one I would recommend
is the Raphael Raphael does take a
little bit longer to finish but it is
very quality product and it is very
simple to grow she won't give you any
problems except she'll get very large
buds which for a new grower will feel
very rewarding you'll have to learn how
to keep those buds from toppling over
you'll have to learn how to use steaks
or tomato cages or a trellis or
something but it will be a very
rewarding experience and of course the
Raphael is available only in feminized
seeds another one I would suggest is
Bebop bebop is easy to grow it makes a
lot of trichomes and giant buds again
you're going to have to give it some
sort of support
bebop will make huge buds early and
flower so it needs sticks or tomato
cages or something to keep those big
buds from flopping over again bebop is
only available in feminized seeds my
next and final suggestion my
strain-specific recommendation will be
Rocksteady Rocksteady is another one of
my crosses it is feminized and it does
produce giant buds that are covered in
resin and they smell amazing so there
are six great options I can recommend
just from my own seed line that I feel
would work perfectly in your environment
now it does not hurt my feelings at all
if you choose to work with another
breeder there are so many breeders out
there because we all offer something
different my friend mr. soll said it's
kind of like bands and music listeners
one guy's out there playing one kind of
music one guy's out there playing
another kind of music people are
naturally going to walk to the kind of
music that draw
them I don't take it personally if you
prefer another seed company over me
they're doing something different I'm
doing something different that's how the
world is supposed to work but if you're
going to buy seeds from another breeder
I highly suggest you get something from
a reputable breeder somebody that you
have heard of somebody who has been
around for a little while somebody who
has a positive online presence maybe you
go check out their online their social
media presence and see how they interact
with people go check out their customer
service I definitely suggest you do
research on the breeder before you
purchase seeds from them also buy from a
reputable vendor there are so many seed
vendors available online right now who
knows what they're going to send you who
knows when they're going to send it do
your best to do your research on the
seed company and the seed vendor you are
going to spend your money with don't get
yourself ripped off the internet is a
black hole of scam artists and there are
plenty of people out there just trying
to take your money so do your research
before you give anybody your credit card
information
there are several reputable reliable
honest seed vendors out there I'm going
to list a few that I work with
personally I work with the hella dank
seed company I work with organize eats I
work with Southern Oregon seeds I work
with the seed Bazaar and I work with
Gringo's beans I can give all of them a
five-star rating and a thumbs up so
again real quick Oregon elite seeds
hella dank seed company Southern Oregon
seeds the seed Bazaar and Gringo's beans
those are five reliable seed vendors
that I can confidently recommend to my
listeners so now I have made a few
suggestions on seeds from my lines that
would work perfectly for you I have
recommended that you buy from a
reputable breeder and I've also
suggested that you buy from a reputable
vendor but let's talk about the most
important part the most important part
is the consumer and what that consumer
enjoys I'm going to assume that you are
the person that is going to be smoking
most of this finished product so what do
you like to smoke what are you into do
you like gassy smells
do you like fruity smells do you like
oranges do you like strawberries
do you like just weird funkiness think
about what type of aromas and flavors
you enjoy
when you smoke cannabis maybe you smoke
something in the past that really stood
out to you what type of flavours did
that have
do you remember what strain that was
maybe you can find that strain maybe you
can find a phenotype that really
represents what you had in the past and
then you can have that around for your
own personal grow it's really all about
what you enjoy and at this point in the
cannabis evolution or revolution you can
probably find something to fit your
palate exactly if you were into garlic
mashed potatoes and onions there is a
strain that smells like that if you were
into oranges covered in sugar with a
little bit of cherry juice dusted on it
there is a strain that smells and tastes
like that you've just got to check the
menu you've got to kind of find what
works for you now the next thing I would
think about what type of effect are you
looking for do you want that Racing head
buzz do you need a big sativa high or do
you need that chilled out indica put you
in the couch watch some cartoons sort of
a thing what do you desire are you
consuming for a medicinal effect are you
consuming just because you're a pothead
and I'm not judging you either way that
just makes a difference in your
selection and what you're going to grow
also what are you going to do with the
final product are you going to smoke it
in flower form are you going to press it
into rosin are you going to make bubble
hash are you going to make some type of
BHO or hydrocarbon extraction that is
another thing to keep in mind when you
are planning your seed selection so
that's my guidance on selecting seeds
for your very first grow I want to
continue with the email there's a lot
more to cover you also say I was hoping
you could provide some suggestions and
maybe even some pro tips on growing
which ever strain I decide on yeah man
when you make your selection let me know
what you decide and I will send you all
of the tips and tricks I can think of
I'll send you some cheat codes and we
can get your garden boom in on your very
first run you also go on to say please
let me know if I can provide any more
information about my situation man it
sounds like you did a pretty good job
explaining what you've got going on you
made it clear the size of your
environment and the amount and size of
pots you're gonna put in there and the
amount of light as long as you've got
some airflow in there I think you'll be
doing just fine I would also recommend
some carbon filtration but other than
that it sounds like you were off to a
good start the last line of your message
says that it's going to be your first
Rosi are not expecting perfect results
but you know that some expert advice
will go a long way
hey expect perfect results man strive
for perfection in your first grow now I
do have some expert advice for you that
will help your first grow be perfect if
you do pay close attention to details my
first piece of advice is to buy a grow
book from a reputable grow author a
cannabis expert somebody who has done
this repeatedly for years and has the
knowledge to put it into a book buy one
or two books then read those books the
books are no good if you buy them and
send them by the toilet and it looks
like you're cool because you have those
books you look cool cuz you have them
but they don't do [ __ ] for you you don't
have the knowledge that is in that book
it looks like you've got the knowledge
that's in that book but if I ask you a
question and you haven't read the book
you don't get the knowledge just by
sitting it there
I do hope that in the future we can by
USB thumb drives and you can just pop
them into little USB port right behind
your ear in your neck and then you can
upload all of the information from that
book into your brain but we are not
there yet so you do have to buy the book
you have to open it and you have to read
it so read a couple of reputable grow
books my next piece of expert advice
would be to go back to episode 351 and
start listening to the grow series from
episode 351 and catch all of the grow
lessons that take you from the very
beginning of the grow all the way
through harvest all the way through
cleaning up all the way through smoking
your finished product so go back and
listen to all of the grow lessons and I
feel like you will have a good head
start on your first grow and if you're
not the type of person that will go back
and pick out the grow lesson episodes
that's okay because I plan to do
compilations of all of the lessons
uninterrupted consecutively so what I
mean by that is I'm going to find the
first grow lesson
the second grow lesson the third grow
lesson and I will put just the lessons
in order in a long episode in about
three hours so however many episodes
will fit in a three-hour chunk that's
how many will go in episode 401 and then
the next group of lessons will go in 402
and I'm going to do that until we get
through that entire grow series that way
all the lessons are out there
uninterrupted without those
random episodes me and Mike talking and
me talking about random [ __ ] in the
middle of the gross series so I plan to
put it all out in a consecutive chunk
without interruptions in the very near
future alright I want to thank you once
again for that email and I do look
forward to hearing from you when you
make your IRA genetics selection and you
get that garden started all right I'm
gonna jump right into the next email and
it goes like this
Rasta Jeff I've been growing at home for
a little over two years and have grown
approximately 15 plants with the results
varying from average to probably below
average results hey Pema first of all
proud of you for being able to admit
that you had below average or average
results most growers think that their
first product is the most amazing [ __ ]
that they have ever grown and they've
got an ego problem so you were already
doing better than a lot of growers the
email goes on to say all of my plants
have been healthy-looking and grow well
in the vegetative stage I have used a
variety of nutrients with none of them
appearing to be some kind of magic
bullet yes that is absolutely accurate
that is correct there is no magic bullet
when it comes to plant nutrients there
are a lot of things that go into keeping
a plant happy nutrients are a very small
part of that pie and no nutrient bottle
or nutrient company is a magic solution
or a magic bullet like you've said the
email goes on to say I am currently
experimenting with the cns 17 line from
botanic hair in deep water culture and
of course that CNS stands for a
commercial nutrient system that should
work great in the deep water culture
there he also says I use recharge
cal-mag and a bloom booster in flower I
feel like I can read plants relatively
well but I find myself unsure as to the
quantity of nutrients to provide through
plants different stages typically I find
myself doing a sort of ramp up at a rate
of about 200 PPM's per week from week
one after seed sprout until I hit 1200
ish PPM's and that is typically where I
usually plateau I am a little nervous to
go too high too fast can you give me any
tips on how to do a better job of
pushing my plants or how you go about
determining how much is
strike any advice would be greatly
appreciated on another note you have
hands down the best podcast for cannabis
information out there
the sound quality information and care
you take is definitely noticed also not
a man-crush thing but you have a great
radio voice I could fall asleep to that
[ __ ]
can't wait to run a batch of a rise when
helideck has them backed in so on the
other note about the best podcast dude I
appreciate that there is no competition
but when you were told you're the best
honestly it will always put a smile on
your face so thank you I appreciate that
the sound quality is truly important to
me I am a sound nerd I've got a lot of
great sound equipment so I appreciate
you noticing that thanks for noticing
the information and care I take are
definitely important to me I try to put
out accurate information that is useful
and gives you some sort of quality and
improves your life some way give you
some sort of value I make sure I put
that in each show and the care it comes
from my heart everything I do grow from
my heart drum from my heart podcast from
my heart that is from my heart so thank
you for noticing the radio voice dude I
hear that a lot so it is not weird I
can't stand my own voice in these
headphones when I listen back to edit
the show I'm like who is that [ __ ]
rambling I can't take it so thank you
for the compliment on the voice you
could fall asleep to that [ __ ] that's
kind of weird
I probably give people weird dreams if
you fell asleep to me I can only imagine
what kind of dreams you would have then
you wrap up with can't wait to run a
batch of a rise when they're back in
stock will guess what bro they are back
in stock so go check them out before
they run out they should have five packs
and ten packs available at this time now
let's focus on the nutrient part of your
question it sounds like you've got all
the right tools in your arsenal you've
got the the botanic air commercial
nutrients system lineup you've got some
recharge in there to give yourself a
root boost you've got cal-mag because of
course high performance plants will get
a cow mag deficiency and a bloom booster
later and flower it sounds like you've
got all of the right tools you've got
the right idea for the ramp up however
you could go a little bit higher later
and flower with that botanic hairline up
and those additives you could probably
push to the fifteen or sixteen hundred
ppm
and not cause any problems honestly you
could probably go a little bit higher if
you do not double up on any elements so
if you were if you know how much
nitrogen is in each product and you know
how much phosphorus is in each product
and you can balance it out to where you
don't overdose anything you can probably
go pretty high there are some variables
I would like to know before I give too
much advice about this grow such as is
their co2 running what type of lighting
are you using I just want to know about
your environment and your overall setup
because that would tell me where we can
improve and if you have co2 you can
probably run a little higher ppm s if
you've got stronger lighting the plants
can handle higher PPM's because they
have enough light energy to metabolize
those nutrients if you've got low
quality lighting you can't feed it
strongly because they're not
metabolizing it if you've got powerful
lights and co2 you can feed the [ __ ] out
of them and you may not see any burn if
you feed that same feed regimen to a
plant that you're not authentic co2 and
you're running it under a fluorescent
it's going to burn so with so many
variables I have to be careful with my
advice in my suggestions here you do
have the right idea starting low and
working your way up have you thought
about working your way up until you burn
the [ __ ] out of one of them honestly
that is how I find my plants limits I
increase the PPM's
until I see I call it getting their
nails done think about the plant leaf
looking like a hand when you see the
tips starting to get yellow or starting
to get funky colors or getting their
nails done as soon as you see one of the
ladies starting to get our nails done
you know you have pushed it right to the
limit you can either continue to go that
hard and they'll just keep burning just
a little bit and you probably won't see
it in the final product because you're
gonna trim off all of that leaf honestly
and you're going to flush it also you
won't even notice so you can push it a
little bit if you know what you're doing
with each nutrient and you say that
you've got a good eye on the plants so I
think this may be where you're headed
push them see what it does now when you
start pushing you've got to decide do I
want to keep pushing it and see how this
burn progresses or do I want to stop
right where I am and keep giving it that
or do I want to dial back and prevent
more burn
that's where you have to think about it
as a grower that's where you have to
make the decision I think the move at
this time is to increase the PPM's later
in Flour and see how much they can take
push it until you burn them and see if
you come out with a better harvest
you're already not satisfied so what
could go wrong are you gonna be less
satisfied if you do some experimentation
you may do an experiment and you may
improve your garden dramatically another
thing we need to keep in mind is could
this be a genetic issue do you simply
have weak genetics I'm not making fun of
you I'm not calling you out I'm just
saying that this is an option genetic
potential maybe you're a limiting factor
at this time you've got deep water
culture you've got good nutrients I said
earlier I don't know about your
environment I don't know about your
lights your air your water your soil I
don't know about your personal attention
to the plants I don't know about that
but one thing that could be limiting you
is the genetics your email starts off by
saying that you've grown approximately
15 plants but I really don't know if
that was the same plant 15 times or if
you've grown 15 different seeds or 15
different cuts I really don't know but
maybe genetics are what are holding you
back so it sounds like you've got the
right nutrients I would start pushing
them push them a little bit harder and
watch for nutrient burn once you do see
a noodle a little bit of nutrient burn
that's when you need to decide do I want
to dial it back you will want to keep
going or do I want to go a little bit
stronger you're in deep water culture I
don't know if your plants are in
individual buckets I don't know if
you've got one main reservoir feeding
each plant but if they're in individual
buckets why not
test each plant differently I don't know
how many plants are growing maybe you've
only got one so you've only got one
option but if you've got multiple plants
why not try one with your 1,200 max
PPM's that you're used to and Mark that
plant the one getting fed low ppm s then
mark the other plant the one getting fed
medium PPM's and go to 14 with that one
then take another one and hit it at 16
then get another one and feed it all the
way up to 18 and feed another one all
the way up to 20 and see what happens
some of them will burn some of them will
definitely show you
nitrogen toxicity or some sort of a
phosphorus overdose you will see some
sort of a problem that's how you know
what those
it's can take honestly that's how I
became an advanced skill level grower I
[ __ ] a lot of things up just by
experimenting and trying and I
understand that your plants are precious
to you and that every plant counts and
that you need that harvest but if you
want to take your grow to the next level
you may have to take some risks it may
cost you one or two plants but that
experience is invaluable if you can take
your crop from what did you say average
to probably below average to
above-average and [ __ ] stellar it may
be worth killing two or three maybe four
or five plants just to see what they can
take now another thing I want to talk
about is you said you were using the
botanic air C&amp;S 17 product line I am
going to open the botanic air website
and I'm going to open the nutrient
calculator they have a nutrient
calculator right here on the website and
this allows me to punch in what type of
base nutrients we're going to use we're
going to use the cns 17 bloom based
nutrient we're going to measure our
product and milliliters I'm going to
type in that we have a one gallon
reservoir just to keep this simple
it wants grow time we're gonna say we're
gonna grow for four weeks we will bloom
for nine weeks this is just a
hypothetical for the case of this
podcast so I can give you some advice
here now on the botanic air website on
their official nutrient calculator on
the bloom phase for week one of flower
it is recommending that I use 13
milliliters of the cns 17 bloom nutrient
that is going to put my PPM's at 910 now
the next week they increase that dosage
to 17 milliliters per gallon and that
continues all the way through week 8 now
if I correctly add 17 milliliters of CNS
17 bloom base nutrients to my water
according to this speed chart that is
going to bring my PPM's to 1190 which is
very close to the 1200 number that you
said you were ramping up to now Botanica
is recommending you start week 2 at 10
ppm below where you are maxing out so
this chart on this website is telling us
that your PP ends of your
nutrients are way low and you need to
increase your nutrient feedings of your
plants earlier in the flowering phase
now I do preach that these nutrient
companies suggest you use more product
than necessary so that they can sell you
more but they wouldn't suggest enough to
blatantly burn your plants so let's push
it according to their chart and see how
the plants react on their suggestion now
I don't doubt your skills I don't know
who you are I want to make this really
simple for everybody the way to achieve
that specific ppm test in your nutrients
is to start with clean water water with
0 ppm s that is RO water if you've got
City tap water there's going to be
something in there already measure that
write down your baseline see where
you're starting then you have your
amount of water probably five gallons
maybe more depending on your situation
put your ppm meter in there pour in that
base nutrient give it a stir see what
the meter says if it doesn't say 1190
pour in a little more your goal is to
get that ppm to eleven ninety once
you've got your base nutrient at the
correct PPM's then add your additives at
the recommended dosage I would suggest
you check the PPM's
after you add each additive so you've
got your base nutrient in there what are
you gonna add next maybe your cal-mag so
measure out your two milliliters per
gallon of cal-mag and pour it in there
then put your ppm pen back in there give
it a swirl and write down what the ppm s
are at this point now you know how many
ppm of cal-mag are in your solution take
the number that appears on your ppm
meter and subtract eleven ninety because
that is how much base nutrient we added
the remaining math is how much cal-mag
is in your solution continue this with
all of your additives write it all down
feed your plants pay attention over the
next few days and see how they react if
the plants look angry we [ __ ] up we
need to reduce the nutrients but now we
know what they can take if the plants
explode with vigorous growth we know
we're on the right path to fixing your
dissatisfaction so if you haven't
already
I suggest you head over to the botanic
air website and check out their nutrient
calculator and play around with it a
little bit put in the cns 17 base and
then
and see what it suggests you feed at
each week then add a few things to the
chart and if you can afford a new
product I would recommend the liquid
karma as the next thing you add to that
lineup add that to your feed chart see
how much of it to mix in and add that
right to your lineup that will improve
the quality of your finished product and
you guys if you're not using botanic air
most of the major nutrient companies
will have a nutrient calculator on their
website again these companies do want us
to buy more than necessary so they may
tell us to use a little bit extra so
follow the same advice that I gave our
friend here start low start with maybe
50 or 75 percent of the recommended
dosage off the website and then work
your way up to a hundred percent if you
feel like the plants can take it the
reason I like those nutrient calculators
is because it shows you the breakdown of
what you can be feeding your garden and
it shows you correct ratios you may not
want to use every product on that chart
but it kind of gives you a ratio and
shows you if you use this much of the
base let's just say if you use two parts
of the base you may want to use one part
of this bloom booster and then a quarter
part of this root inoculant they just
give you good ideas it may suggest
things you were missing and I feel like
it is a good baseline recipe for a new
grower it was a little bit overwhelmed
and confused by starting a brand new
nutrient regimen now I hope that helps
you improve the quality of your finished
product don't be afraid to burn a couple
of plants for the sake of overall
improvement I want to thank you guys for
the great emails I want to thank
everybody for listening to this podcast
if you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
and you would like to support the show
financially you can make a financial
contribution by going to patreon.com
slash grow from your heart all the
information you need to sign up and
become a patron will be right there on
the screen once again I want to give a
huge thank you to everybody who has
supported the patreon campaign I would
also appreciate it if you find me on
social media on Facebook simply search
for the growth from your heart podcast
on Twitter it's @gf wih podcast on
instagram i use my other company name it
is Irie underscore genetics on instagram
I read genetics on Instagram check out
my fine cannabis photography I think you
would enjoy it
if you've got something you'd like to
say you're not into all of the social
media perhaps you've got a question
you'd like read on the show maybe you've
got a product you'd like me to review or
maybe you just like to sponsor the
podcast you can reach out to me via
email my email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com and I would love to
hear from each and every one of you
don't forget that the podcast is
available on Apple podcasts stitcher
radio google play tune in radio and of
course every episode is available on the
YouTube channel don't forget to visit
our friends Oregon elite seeds I'm gonna
give you a huge shout out to my friend
Cipriani and until next time take a phat
dad and give your mom a hug for me