[Music]
yeah what's up ladies and gentlemen
welcome it's time for episode number 40
of the igro culture podcast I'm your
host Rost Jeff joining me at the table
again is our good buddy Jesse how you
doing bro pretty good how's it going out
there uh podcast land podcast land
internet world uh hopefully you guys are
listening to us while you're driving to
work or playing in the garden or doing
something fun whatever you're doing I
hope you got a dab or a fat joint or a
bowl of something super dank we're
smoking some uh live resin some Bounty
kill or no not Bounty Killer it's oh it
is Bounty Killer live resin no it's not
it's Capleton live resin sorry I just
lied it's Capleton live resin uh stuff
is tasty good uh big shout out to the
dude that grew it what's up Ryan nice
work and an extra special shout out to
the guy that blasted extracted it for us
this stuff is super tasty who who would
imagine that uh uh the iy genetics guy
would have all those iy genetics tab
sitting over there dude it's really nice
to see can't even keep them straight
yeah true uh it's really nice to watch
my friends grow my genetics yeah and
then to have one of our good Brothers
extract it for us and then he gets his
hash back and he calls me dude come over
and get some of this hash I just had
made from your strains I'm like hell
yeah I'm on my way nice I got a nice
gram of Heart of Gold there was grateful
dog and there was Capleton live resin
and dude that was tasty stuff oh yeah it
left a I keep saying citronella candles
sort of scent in the room uh if you're
into that that was a great
smell uh guys I want to take one quick
second and give a huge shout out I
always do this at the end of the show
but we got to do a special shout out
extra special shout out to my ninja
Spence uh Spence has been sick as hell
uh we found out just recently that his
appendix had ruptured inside of him and
he had to have it removed uh dude I'm so
glad you're on the way to recovery we
were super worried about about you I was
stressing out worrying about my brother
I love you more than you ever will
realize so big shout out to Spence dude
everybody send your love and energy to
getting Spence better get better buddy
come on Feller yeah buddy get up you got
to shoot some hoops you got to make some
hash Spence is going to win The Secret
Cup finals in Vegas I'm confident minus
an
[Music]
appendix can he fly cheaper he just lost
some weight huh no [ __ ] yeah yeah isn't
your appendix only like about an inch
long anyway yeah I actually looked it up
today Ked it almost killed him I'm
pretty sure he was pretty bad shape and
it's it's completely worthless somebody
asked me what does your appendix do and
I looked at him and said I don't know
it's full of a poison vial that's what
it does it's an awesome thing to let's
just stick this inside of a human and
wait for it to rupture one day good job
Creator that's the self-destruct switch
he gave us all I guess I guess so also
over since we're sending out L energy to
people that need some help uh I want to
send a big huge healing vibe to my good
friend Angela uh she hasn't been feeling
well the past week she's got some
medical things going on uh that's kind
of private to her so we don't need to
elaborate but uh dude send a lot of
healing Vibes to Angela big shout out to
Angela care a lot about you I want you
better I want to see you smiling again
hey what's up guys I have to jump in and
do a disclaimer I played this shout out
for Angela and when she heard it she
said that I made it sound like there's
something wrong with her vagina I need
to assure you there's absolutely nothing
wrong with Angela's vagina let's get
back to the show uh yeah let's get off
the somber Vibe and get into a show I do
owe another shout out two more shout
outs dude I always shout out to the man
afran I saw P I got to hang out with
this dude afran he sings that song
Because I Got High uh he played a show
in a town near me uh there's a little
VIP party added to spencery called The
Spot shout out to the spot what's up
Robert what's up
Vegas hope you guys are listening to the
show shout out to everyone at the spot
uh they got me to see Afroman got a
couple of photos with Afroman who's
actually Angela's fault she uh works
there she got me the little VIP hookup
so thanks again Angela super shout out
uh I walked in and Afro man was taking
pictures with people and doing a little
quick private meet and greet and he saw
me and he goes oh [ __ ] come here my man
and he took pictures with me uh he
posted my photos up on his Instagram I
thought it was kind of funny awesome
yeah he blew off a lot of people to come
hang out with rosta Jeff for some reason
[ __ ] yeah uh the owners of the spot said
that he could come smoke with me but he
probably would not make it to his show
so he opted to not smoke with me he was
like you look like you might murder me
with some smoke so yeah he didn't want
to do that yeah well then you're also
yeah at a dispensary and unfortunately
not allowed to smoke at a dispensary
they totally knew I was going to drive
him off in my car we yeah we were going
to do that had you just been able to
hand him a joint would have been a lot
easier you know he did do a show in
Colorado Springs after that so we can't
talk about what
happened um all right I want to talk
about a couple other things too shout
outs are done shout out to everybody
that's listening to the show dude this
is episode 40 we made it 40 episodes bro
this is getting good I promise you guys
the episodes are getting better uh I've
been doing more preparation been doing
more planning I've got the next few
episode topics already listed of what
I'm going to do um coming up in a couple
episodes we're going to do an episode
about nutrients I've had a couple people
ask me tell me about nutrients what is
all this
NPK uh 539 on my bottles what does this
[ __ ] mean what should I be feeding what
do I need so we're going to cover that
um and also um our friend Ross Cola King
Cola Sean is going to come be on the
show uh I haven't called him yet but he
did send me his phone number I've got
his phone number so I could text him and
ask him to be on the show [ __ ] yeah uh
he Hypes a growing system that he has
labeled organic as [ __ ] and I'm kind of
impressed I've been growing for quite a
while and he has uh he has the approach
that I hope to get to I'm not where he
is yet he's got a very environmentally
friendly environmentally sustainable way
of growing and it's kind of impressive
I'm impressed and it takes a little bit
to impress me yeah that's he does these
uh fermentations that look uh delicious
you know I would almost if I didn't know
what was in there some of that stuff
would look tasty yeah yeah no they
really do and it smells good because of
the Molasses all right we'll let Sean
tell you about his stuff when we get him
on the show so shout out to Ros Cola
King Cola and organic as [ __ ] we'll get
him on here pretty soon and guys I'm
saying that for but it doesn't cost
money anymore and I'm actually quoting
this guy's brand so you can't charge me
on that one something you can charge me
for this podcast is brought to you by
Highly Educated titanium if you're using
a high quality concentrate like these
Heart of Gold Live resin dabs you
definitely deserve a highgrade titanium
nail made right here in America don't
trust those Chinese Nails you keep
seeing in head shops that are cheap
they're cheap for a damn reason yep it's
not titanium you want grade 2 Titanium
because it's the most I I can read you
off the website trust me you want type 2
titanium it's what you want for your
dabs and you know who uses them Highly
Educated that's where you get the best
titanium the industry leader Highly
Educated so check out highly educated
ti.com
if you want to buy a nail right now
check out aqualab technologies.com
they've got all kinds of sweet Highly
Educated products on there they have the
new colored stuff it looks sweet uh make
sure you guys check out Nature's green
remedies.com I don't have a coupon code
for them this month I will um probably
in December but make sure you support
Natures green remedies.com
I want to give a big shout out to Jesse
for coming and doing all these episodes
uh this podcast is brought to you by
hyro indoor growing supplies uh hyro
indoor growing supplies has two
locations to serve Colorado check out
the Denver store at 6271 Beach Street or
the peblo location 618 East 4th Street
in peblo Colorado do you have any deals
this month bro uh we still got the roots
707 for 25 bucks nice um mention the
Agro culture podcast for commercial
pricing yep I went there today and she
had no problem typing in commercial
pricing for me I got myself a bag of
soil for my seedlings nice it was nice
and easy dude can I tell them what
they'll pay for that bag of uh what did
I get there's that light Warrior yeah uh
that that bag was less than 18 bucks it
was $17 and some change for that bag
usually that's a $25 bag of dirt so we
saved I saved eight bucks just by using
or by telling them hey I listen to the
igro culture podcast damn yeah so go get
yourself a bag of soil dude it was
really cool it was really easy they
didn't even you know when you get a
discount some places they act like
you're a dick she's like don't I owe you
pricing and I was like yes you do you do
give me a deal y uh so make sure you
tell them that you're listening to the
Agro culture podcast and also check out
their website hyr denver.com pretty sure
I didn't write it down cuz I thought I
remembered and apparently I just forgot
yeah hyro denver.com I think we also
have
hyro uh. us okay so and they also have
hyro peblo has a Facebook if you're in
peblo and you want to team up on their
Facebook check it out because they post
a lot of cool stuff on there we uh we
have an Instagram too um getting around
to using it a little more so it's hard
to keep up with all the social media
isn't it yeah well especially like I
don't know how to Instagram be in a a
shop it feels weird right take pictures
of products for the front of the store
and then this is what's on sale yeah
yeah we're going to start doing some
cool stuff we uh ordered a grow ttin for
the store so sweet so you can set that
up yeah yeah we're going to show how to
work it get some stuff going yeah so and
then we've got the uh um next Growers
meeting uh next Friday I believe got a
horrible Friday the 21st yeah the 21st
it's the day after my mama's birthday so
happy birthday Mama you don't listen to
the podcast but whatever dude it's the
thought counts we got uh some uh a bunch
of Supply or freebies coming um already
have some dude I got hooked up last time
I have a couple little gifts last time
it was nice yeah thank you um so we're
going to go over uh cloning and
seeding uh in person so that'll be
really helpful yeah um beans and house
plants so don't get your hopes up I was
going to say are you able to can we
clone a cannabis plant in
there I think we could but we could just
take a plant that looks just like
cannabis and teach them how to do it
work yeah okay be safe yeah we like that
Hydro shop so let's not risk it that's
where I go to get my my gear for cheap
yeah also guys this podcast has brought
to you by our friends at tree Thugger
dcom tree Thugger dcom everyone ask me
what is that it's a cool name go look at
it right yeah it's uh it's mostly
concert and Festival news and reviews is
what it is uh they talk about all the
concerts that come to Red Rocks if you
listen to stuff like the string cheese
fish uh Galactic The Grateful Dead uh
soundt tribe Sector 9 the Disco Biscuits
even if you're into like boom box and um
bass neor is who I'm trying to think of
that's not my thing sorry I'm more of a
fish Grateful Dead reg kind of a kid but
I check it out because I want to know
when fish is coming what the cheese is
up to so tree Thugger dcom will keep you
up to date with all of your hippie news
I like to say look out at the cookout
with tree Thugger
docomo that dude that's a great band
Richard Cheese if you guys Haven listen
to Richard Cheese he does uh popular
songs in a lounge Style it's pretty
chill Rage Against the Machine all Big B
Style Lounge Against the Machine Lounge
Against the Machine all right usually I
would take this time to read comments on
Facebook or on uh Stitcher and iTunes
but I haven't gotten any new comments
big thanks to the people oh God sorry I
got loud big thanks to the people that
did leave comments if you want to leave
some comments on iTunes and Stitcher I
will read them I'll also uh check out
the comments on Facebook there is an
Instagram page but like Jesse said I
don't Instagram a lot because it's a
podcast I can take pictures of Jesse and
me and I can post them up other than
that um not a lot to post all right so
we're going to talk more about I want to
make sure I covered all the intro stuff
I did it's a good place to leave
questions though I'll say that much I
look at every every now and then make
sure there's no uh you know on the
Instagram yeah yeah oh yeah I try so
hard to answer all of the questions I
get since they shut down Facebook shut
down the iry genetics Facebook page and
took it from an interactive page and
made it to just a business page which I
find boring so I've gotten a lot of
spare time to check in stagram and stuff
like that lately I don't really mess
around that much on those Facebooks I do
check them to answer your questions but
I don't really play there like I used to
they kind of pissed me off taking my
page down like that without even talking
to me yeah
dicks all right so we've been doing grow
lessons teaching you guys or trying to
sort of Stoner style teach you guys how
to set up a grow room for yourself so
that you can be self-sufficient we've
gotten the room built we talked about
the best places to do it uh we gave you
a good guide so far we've got a room
built with lights hanging but we haven't
hung our ballasts yet and our timers so
that's kind of where we are um if you
guys need to catch up I'll take a pause
and you can go listen to the two
episodes before this and you can catch
up to where we are pausing all right
we're back now I hope you listen to
those and learned a whole [ __ ] ton we
didn't really pause that long I should
have pause longer cuz I need a
drink there's another
[Laughter]
chance oh editing is fun I I don't even
edit these shows anymore I just put them
out the way they go I like I like the
it's way better when we're just High
doing our thing all right so we've got
these big uh this big 10x 8 by8 yeah we
built an 8 by8 room you've got your poly
wrapped around everything it's all
sealed up you got your lights hanging um
now what I would like to do is show you
the not show you tell you the way I hang
my ballasts and my electronics and Jesse
and I have a lot of different ideas so
this will get fun uh I use a piece of
plywood to mount all of the electronics
in one area at Lowe's or whatever
hardware store they actually sell a
pre-cut board I think it's 24 it may be
18 in by 36 in uh and you can screw that
right on the wall and you can hang I can
fit four I can fit five ballast and my
power box on that and so all the ball
are plugged in to the power box and it's
also screwed to the board I screwed the
board to the framing on the outside of
the grow room to keep the heat down uh
Jesse was talking about if you put it on
the inside keep it close to the door the
outside is ideal because if something
goes wrong you don't have to go in there
to turn everything off yeah um also keep
a fire extinguisher near that box that's
something that I recommend um you don't
want to have to run into the grow room
if keep a smoke alarm in there if there
is a fire you don't want to have to go
halfway through the room to get to your
fire extinguisher you want to have it
outside kick the door open and start
spraying and put out fire that's your
that's your biggest fear but we you got
to be prepared for that so you got this
board you got four ballasts you've got I
put a power box on there cuz that's how
I plug everything in uh screw to the
wall safest way to do it too yeah I like
those power boxes they're really
reliable uh they don't pay me to say
that i' buy them straight America made
in America yes I was going to ask you
here's a random side note what ballasts
are made in America do you
know I can find out you can Google that
while I read on for a second I can just
yeah it's almost time for me to buy
several more ballasts and I would like
to buy americanmade products because uh
I noticed that the um what the hell
brand is that the quantums that used to
be made in Germany uhhuh now they come
with a made in China or a made in koreaa
sticker on them and they smell funny now
and also I've noticed that the fans
don't last as long they start [ __ ]
out really quickly now so I don't want
to buy those anymore those used to be my
go-tos because they don't fail like a
nextg does a nextg will just [ __ ] out on
you it'll try to start up and fail just
starting yeah yeah you can't start
properly I don't want you actually have
a 400 watt nextg right now I'm using I
have a 400 I need to replace my 400 watt
nextg because it took a [ __ ] on me I'm
running a 600 in that room now just
because I don't want to go buy that
400 um we actually we try they're kind
of hard to find nowadays the 400 yeah
yeah everyone's going bigger yeah that's
um I like to keep my males under a 400
in flower just because you can just keep
them flowering and you don't need to run
all that much light yeah if you're just
doing a feno hunt for boys how many
people feno hunt for males if you're
feno hunting for males you're probably
not listening to this show you're beyond
you're beyond everything we've said so
far you should be hanging out at the
table right here if you're pheno hunting
for males you're invited send me a
message we'll find you AGR culture
hotmail.com we're just strategizing
about that very
subject yeah uh dude can we talk about
that yeah go for it I'm getting really
excited about it so me too I'm I'm IR
genetics of course I'm rosta Jeff from I
genetics I've been running I genetics
for a couple few years now it's been
public seeds have been available uh I
cannot keep up with the demand for my
product I've got I've got enough
breeding space to breed plenty of seeds
but when they go on sale at Nature's
green remedies they sell out in like 48
Hours yeah I've noticed uh so our good
buddy Jesse has stepped up to the plate
and now I think Jesse will I'm going to
run a bunch of his [ __ ] as soon as it's
done and when I see that his stuff does
good we're going to add him to our
lineup he'll be part of Team iy genetics
he'll be another breeder he'll be our
second breeder yeah tripod Farms tripod
Farms I'm excited to get them in there
but pretty soon stuff that Jesse bread
will be available through the iy
genetics catalog yeah it'll be sweet got
some Kim dog stuff coming and some uh
OG uh flavorful stuff coming I like the
teas yeah I like the teas um I just hit
on Halloween I put Grateful Dog pollen
on a platinum OG female and on a sour
diesel female and I've never pollinated
those with the Grateful Dog before so
we'll have Platinum dog and sour dog
nice I got that same sour you have so
nice that's a great I was thinking about
throwing that up or you know dusting him
up a little too so Cu uh that's a great
strain it's stanky it just doesn't grow
with the Vigor that I want I want a
hardier thicker plant top it top the
[ __ ] out that thing that's what you got
to do it's got good yield for a plant
that normally exhibits that trait though
so and flower her early because man that
thing Tak off dude I learned the hard
way it doesn't keep up with Gorilla Glue
my Gorilla Glue has tripled in size
since I started flowering yeah nice did
you find me in americanmade ballast um
no I'm not finding uh I don't suspect uh
the galaxies are um I know some that a
lot of their uh uh products are made in
America but um
yeah I don't know we'll keep going we'll
if you guys have an idea of a good
americanmade ballast let me know CU it's
for me I'm shopping I need a lot of them
oh man you know what actually I think I
know of one it's a really expensive one
they the gavas or the no those would be
made in Holland um yeah that's what I
thought what's the gav's competitor the
eaps eaps I believe those are China
China so are the nanolux D I know those
are made in China are Lush lights made
in America I wonder if Lush lights are
made in America or if they're made in
China um I would suspect they're made I
for I'd really hope they are yeah well
oh uh solist Tech made in California
okay yeah really good stuff something to
check out guys reced by the Cotton Mouth
Kings
[Music]
even I thought that was one of the
weirdest endorsements I ever saw in my
life we recommend these ballasts
shouldn't a breeder or somebody endorse
that [ __ ] um I suspect that maybe the uh
hoarder luux makes ballast I think maybe
they stuff's made in America okay um I
want to buy americanmade ballast guys I
encourage you to also so I take this
board that I bought at Lowe's and I put
the board on the floor and I mount my b
i i don't screw it to the floor I set it
on the floor so I can work let me be
clear about that I set the board on the
floor and then I screw the ballasts to
the to the board and then I screw my
power box to the board and now this
board is movable you can hang your
ballast damn near anywhere you want bolt
that to where is convenient for you if
it's the outside of the room is what I
would prefer cuz then you're keeping
heat out those get yeah do it outside of
the room and then then you can mess with
your timers and stuff and not be in the
room so that it's just easier so bolt
that wherever you need screw that
wherever you need to the framing then
run that wiring through a small hole in
the poly and tape over it to keep the
light from leaking so now you've got air
in air out lights and power you're
probably going to need to cool down the
room um an air conditioner is definitely
what you're going to need you may need a
dehumidifier uh so take another small
board and put um your air conditioner
thermostat on there if you have one that
doesn't attach to the air conditioner um
you can plug your air conditioner into a
temperature sensor and hang that on the
wall mhm and then when the temperature
gets to a certain thing to the certain
temperature during the you can set the
day and night temperature and then that
little meter will tell the air
conditioner when to come on and when to
go off and you can do that with almost
any piece of equipment in your room uh
you can automate your um your
dehumidifier your air conditioner you
can automate your fans um and one room
I've got a emergency shutdown switch if
it hits over 95° in that room everything
turns off everything even the air
conditioners because I don't know what's
causing the problem so everything just
shuts off and the ambient temps are only
going to be 70 something in that area
anyway with there's no when there's no
light so I aam automation put all your
automation stuff on one board and put
that where it's visible uh put a
thermometer a hygrometer on there all
the stuff that you want to be able to
see sometimes that has to be inside the
room so put that in the room if you have
to if you can get the it's if you want
that out side of the room it'll be more
expensive trust me but that one will
probably have to go in the room so just
put all your stuff onto one board and
nail it to one spot up high where you
can see it a random side note uh when
you're building a grow room and you're
thinking about planning a grow room
think of water goes low electrical goes
High uh you want your water low on the
ground if you have a bucket if you got a
reservoir there's no need to lift that
up off the ground too high keep it low
uh because if it does topple over you
don't want it to spill on your
electronics which should be kept above
waist high yeah uh I don't run conduit
along the wall lower than about 36 in
that's my waist I actually believe that
code
um yeah pretty sure okay yeah well that
makes sense but these guys aren't
they're just building a room so we got
to keep water low electricity High
because you don't want to pour water
into your electricity ever uh keep your
cords organized you guys I've seen so
many messes of Grow rooms keep him as
short as possible yeah yeah I'm going
turn this back sorry Co no worries it
kind of tipped it got impotent on us
um and put a smoke alarm and fire
detector where you can get to them the
smoke alarm in the room the fire
detector outside of the room those are
little side notes that I wrote yeah uh
so you're going to need air conditioning
is what I wrote down next uh I follow
the general rule of 3,000 BTUs of air
conditioning per th000 watt light uh if
you want to use those uh traditional ACS
you can put in the window you can cut a
that do go in a window you can cut a
hole in the poly and mount the AC to the
framing but that's going to heat up
whatever room you dumped the AC exhaust
into if you're in a garage or an unused
basement that's cool uh but you can't
heat up like if you're you have to
exhaust that heat up it's got to go
somewhere or it's just going to continue
to heat up yeah you can run it a lot of
people run it straight through the
chimney if you got one I've seen it go
into the attic if you need to if you
guys are in illegal States you're going
to have to plan this a little better cuz
your heat signature is what they're
going to look for to bust you I think um
I've heard they have to have a warrant
for that but I'm no lawyer right well
and it's also uh 2014 almost 15 where
the can do just about whatever the this
is true too we are living in a police
state yeah they'll just fly over with
that camera they'll say oh look all that
bright light and then they'll just send
a car to go sit in front of your house
and then they'll notice some [ __ ] you
know that's the cops are the worst gang
that we have nowadays the worst
criminals on the D streets on the air
conditioners if it's going to outside a
lot of them or if the air conditioner is
in your room and it's in an outside
window um light shines through yes you
can take a uh
uh can of spray paint get you
um I can't remember how I did it but
there's some way you can get a nozzle on
there um that you can stick a little
straw in uh like WD40 I was going to say
the WD40 straw yeah perfectly um and
spray the white foam inside the vents
with black spray paint and it's all
clean and everything stop your refle it
stops the light from coming out good
idea good idea and if you're putting
that in the uh I picked that up from
subcool
actually shout out to subcool uh did you
uh so I didn't brag about this I posted
a really sweet picture to Instagram the
other day and subcool actually sent me a
message that said we should collab so in
the future there could be some uh TGA iy
genetic stuff happening but uh right now
I'm going to focus on what I'm doing
with Jesse because I know that's for
real and I know I can trust Jesse I
don't know anybody else out there um
what else uh that I'm really honored for
that too um oh dude you're like the
first person I thought of for sure yeah
for sure um [ __ ] I had something else I
wanted to say before we got sidetracked
uh the black spray paint on the um air
conditioner um keeping light out yeah
[ __ ] keep going okay uh I like to use
the and they're they take more energy
but I like those air conditioners on
Wheels uh they have a little duct you
can just ducted it right out of a 6-in
duct it works perfect uh those are
glorious they take a little more air a
little more electricity yeah but they're
awesome also you need maybe a fan speed
controller if you're oh yeah for sure
those are always helpful just there's
always a reason to add a fan speed
controller I bought a uh little
thermostat thing to turn off my air cool
fans when it uh gets too cold outside
yeah that's I walked out to the room the
other day and there's 4,000 watt lights
burning um and uh normally you know it's
72 68° in there and uh it was like 55 de
yeah I shut all the fans off everything
and it took most of the light cycle to
heat back up wow yeah so I'm loving this
wi uh it was -6° here the other night
where we live very [ __ ] cold that is
cold yeah uh my my my air conditioners
aren't on in any of my grows right now
and I'm confident that that's okay I've
turned all of the air conditioners off
just let that I'm saving some
electricity right now a lot of
electricity yeah yeah we heat with wood
um in yeah I've I've gone through an
insane amount of firewood in the last
three days wow yeah
that's probably 3 400 lb [ __ ] I don't
even know you build your rooms to where
there you build your grows to where
there are a lot of work I'm that guy
that automates as much as I can so that
I do not I'm just talking about my house
oh just the house holy [ __ ] okay man I I
don't automate any of my waterings I
feel that I need to be in there watering
the plants by hand myself that's when I
touch them I move every pot when water I
touch every plant I look at I'll pull
off a leaf off of almost every plant and
look at the bottom look for a bug like
I'm anal in the room I've got like a
ritual that I go through in there every
day you know like no you can't bug me
until this is done or everything will go
wrong I have to love this room but I
automate almost everything else I can of
course your light cycles your air
conditioning your dehumidifier your CO2
all that stuff and the new rules that
they're trying to propose here in PUO
Colorado they want to ban CO2 augment
what yeah that's one of the stupid
things they wrote in the rules so we'll
talk about that more in the future but
that just came in my head yeah p p right
right clown shoes yeah clown shoes guys
size 55 Triple
E yes um so yeah you got your I hope
that made sense we just mounted the
ballast right to a board then we put the
board right up on the wall and then you
got to run all the cables that's the
part I skipped make sure when you push
the cables together make sure you push
them tight all the way all the way tight
because when that shit's loose that's
electricity that's live right there just
being exposed I want a design I I've
made them myself I just bend them all up
but out of wire but I do a safety wire
too to hold it all together uh when I
was in bands I learned to tie cords that
are connected together in that knot to
where if you pull instead it tightens
the knot instead of them coming apart I
like that move a lot I used to be a roie
and a
musician back in the 70s man um the I
talked about a tip on pictures and since
we're talking about running cords here
it is um the cord that runs from the
ballast to the light is what causes all
the bars in your picture so the shorter
those are and the um neater they're hung
and everything the less bars and [ __ ]
you'll have coming up on your you know
on some cameras yeah cuz it's the
magnetics that causes that yeah okay and
I think I that's a good tip I didn't
know that I can't remember I haven't uh
I didn't really care about it when I set
up my new room but um I think if you
keep all the chords away from each other
too you know individually instead of so
they don't TI together on the ceiling
Yeah well yeah that makes sense because
way more of that signal all at once that
would make
sense I wrote down so much stuff on so
many different papers I'm looking for
them
all too many different things on too
many papers looks way professional I'm
trying dude I'm trying [ __ ] looks like
Howard Stern or no hey now
can I get sued for that that's like his
[ __ ] trademark huh screw that guys
sorry Howard I didn't mean to steal your
trademark that was uh that was flattery
is what that was um all right so we've
got this room mostly figured out uh we
got lights hung we've got all of our
automation set up hopefully uh we got
air going in we got air going out we've
got an air conditioner now that you got
most of everything set up you got your
pond liner on the floor uh I would add
four 4x4 tables um I use and I don't
want to say Brands but I use the hydro
Farm 4x4 White Flood tables cuz they're
perfect yeah those are perfect I like to
raise them up off the ground uh I like
the white Botanicare trays you can find
someone to make you a stand for them or
you can put them on buckets those those
tables that they sell are so damn
expensive don't buy the tables that are
preab unless you're looking to look like
you got a pro room um and just straight
up Hydro Store guy here most of those
tables are
[ __ ] so the big foot table one over
yeah I was going to say the Bigfoot
table is just stuck together with little
plastic pegs it can fall over so easily
they're ridiculous yeah uh the reason I
like the tables and the trays I like to
get the plants up off the ground uh the
floor gets too cold when you lift them
up off the ground that you get a more
regulated temperature I feel like you
can get a little more air flow and I'm
6'5 dude haven't plants done on the
ground I have to get on my knee to get
down to the soil to see what's happening
at the soil level or the bottom foliage
lifting them up off the ground 2 feet
now they're in my face they're right
where I want them and I don't have to
squat all day um I like that better too
um you get to see a lot more what's
going on too it's just I feel you know
you notice way more for sure and this is
that that's kind of it depends on how
much space you have and how big a plant
you want to grow if you're growing seven
gallon pots and you're putting them on a
table now you're going to have a 7 foot
tall plant maybe by the end so you got
to plan ahead uh but the 4x4 tables you
can fit four seven gallon pots or 9 or
12 three gallon pots you can they're
perfect for one light worth of stuff uh
if you're in a legal State and you got
the numbers and you're going to do Hydro
you can do 64 those little 6in rock wool
cubes and just put a clone in there and
veg them for like a week and flow in
there dude I've seen people pull a pound
and a half off of 64 little clones veg
for a week and a half on a table like
that 64 little nugs yep that's all it
was they weighed about that uh seven
grams each or something the the Cali
Connection that's how totally H to
success or whatever he call Fast Track
to success fast TR shout out to Swerve
what up swerve that's my homie well I
haven't heard much from that guy in a
while you know he has been uh social
media social media kind of killed
everybody Facebook went and the Facebook
Nazi police went and made everybody use
our real names now when I scroll through
I don't even know anybody um I except
coma what the hell how how did you pull
that off dude you can uh here's the
trick guys if you are a um a drag queen
and I know that's not the appropriate
word but I don't know the appropriate
word anymore I'm not politically correct
in the drag queen that's my cousin's one
yeah all right well if you're a drag
queen you can email Facebook can say I'm
a drag queen and this is my alter ego
and they will allow you to use your fake
name wow yeah huh my uh that probably
won't work anymore after a couple of
days that this show is out and people
try it but that's worked for that's why
a lot of the people that like in the
Cannabis Community uh handmade they're
still Richard or they're still handmade
instead of Adam
hand uh yeah a lot of people got to keep
their
[ __ ] that's random huh yeah I know a
bunch of drag queens that like to know
that
they all had to put their real names up
oh that sucks yeah well because now
instead of being Simone
Laro y Michael
wit no not wit no sorry I had to try I
had to
try I know who your dad is I should shut
my
mouth what's up Mr wit hope to see you
uh the grover meeting November 21st at
high gr indoor growing supplies it's
going to be awesome I will be there
rosta Jeff will be there also so that
night here's a random plug Joe Rogan's
new comedy special comes out on Comedy
Central the night of the 21st at
midnight so I'm going to leave high grow
indoor growing supplies and I'm going to
come home and I'm going to get super
dabbed out and I'm going to watch The
Joe Rogan special because I was there at
Comedy Works when that [ __ ] was recorded
and I want to see if show my high ass on
that thing [ __ ] I might have to watch it
dude it was weird and this is we're
totally off topic guys but have fun with
us uh they were seating us for The Joe
Rogan Experience or the recording of his
live show and then were cam is all over
Comedy Works and they put me and my crew
there was me and my date and one of our
good friends and we all had dreadlocks
and they put us in about row eight where
no one can see us and so we're like yeah
I get it but then they would bring in
normal looking people and set them in
rows three and four but then if a guy
came in with a good-looking girl like
there was a girl that came in and I'm
not even being a dick she had her
boobies hanging out she was wearing like
a peach colored shirt she was all tan
and had her hair all done and I looked
at my date and I go front row watch and
they got two people out of the front row
they're like you guys have to move and
they put her in her date front row in
the middle yeah it was just funny and
they were just doing it for TV it was
just Prett people up front they put me
under a camera so that there was no
chance of that camera getting me it was
but it was cool because I was the camera
that job was looking directly into the
whole recording there was a camera like
about 20 rows back from the stage they
only did about half the comedy club full
that night it was awesome but yeah I'm
way ranting but I had so much fun seeing
Joe R it was stressful being a taping
the rules they all they ask you for your
phone like Comedy Works wants to take
your phone from you so that it doesn't
ring or go off during the taping oh
Jesus they wanted they wouldn't let you
wear a hat they wanted me to cover up my
iy genetics logo on my shirt but I
didn't do it yeah they did not want
logos they definitely put the three
dreadlocked tippies out of camera sight
I thought that was funnye two and a half
dreadlock no yeah I'll agree with that
uh and we're calling Adam is the half
dread if you're curious Angela you count
as a full dread sweetie I heard Michael
uh make that joke there
dude he's getting there they're
tightening up a little bit what's up
Adam he's going to be listening to this
show uh probably Monday morning when it
comes out at work what's up dude I hope
you get to go to work today snow has
kind of wrecked everybody's Work Week
[ __ ] yeah it has it's been snowing for
days here man God there I'm the only one
with the four-wheel drive vehicle that's
reliable right now so I've been playing
uh I'm not going to say taxi cuz I don't
mind doing it but it's been nice helping
all my friends out they're stuck and I'm
like I got you bro I'll give you a ride
I'll give you a ride I'll give you a
ride it's kind of nice I pulled a a
chick and her little boyfriend out the
other night nice I have a gigantic truck
so you do you do have well no it's not
one of those diesel [ __ ] uh penile
issue Tru things it's very functional uh
it's not classy it's not pretty it's not
a chick getting truck it's a working
man's damn truck you can deliver soil
anywhere in PUO or anywhere in Colorado
in that truck pretty much the top of
Pike Speak oh easily yeah yeah all right
driving around like kin block
it's how it is around here right now
it's just slushy just go slow you guys
will be cool seems like nobody's driven
in the snow before oh yeah no you guys
are in Colorado you've done this was
just a year ago not even that all right
guys we're going to get back on building
a grow room we're kind of ranting here
we've had some dabs I hope you're taking
dabs so uh if you're building a hydro
Hut that's very similar to this setup
I'd run the ducting for the lights uh
there's a couple way to do the lights
but I would run the lights the ducting
straight through the Hut so that the
light Heat never makes it into the Hut
there's a hole on the left side and the
right side of the Huts at the top uh
hang the blower inside the hut on one
side run the ducting from the
outside um over the blower over the
light and out of the other side um yeah
that way the heat that makes sense you
just make a tunnel right through it and
the heat never actually stays inside the
grow Hut yeah uh there's also a little
hole in the roof of the Huts I had a
blower there I said roof just the roof
that's all the top had over there uh to
pull fresh air through the Hut
constantly I put a carbon filter and a
blower inside the hut and F it out of
the top there it makes the air flow pull
air in from the bottom and the heat goes
out the top uh and always remember
always remember that your blower can
pull more air than can push then it can
push I wrote down a lot of shitty half
ass notes right there none of those
notes were full sentences blowers work
better when they're outside of the room
it's the same reason you never see the
fart fan in the bathroom it's always
mounted up in the ceiling it's easier to
pull air out than it is to push it out
definitely easier to pull um um here's a
question for you uh do you run a carbon
filter in ense when you're collect
collecting pollen you know I've I don't
because I don't have a blower at all in
my tent where I'm collecting pollen I
run um when God you're dude this is
crazy secret [ __ ] right there I've got a
male that's in full flour right now get
ready to do it it's a genuine quit so
I've got him in his own 3x3 Hut with one
coily CFL in there to keep him awake and
that's all because I can't create any
heat cuz I don't want to suck the out
gotta yeah so he's just in there with
the CFL you can take a peek when we're
done if you
want maybe you don't want to there's
pollen in there yeah you'll need a
shower um I've always wondered about I'm
I'm flowering one under a th000 well I'm
flowering a couple under a, watt right
now so I think uh I might be changing
that out to a different light if uh
although I want to see their full i h
here's more [ __ ] that I don't tell
people I take a brown paper bag and put
it right over the top Cola and secure it
and then um when I'm sure that I see him
when he's nutting a whole bunch I just
cut that sucker off yeah and then I have
the branch sticking out of the bag and
I'll hold it with my hand around the
branch and pull the branch out of the
bag slowly and as you pull you knock
everything off into the bag and you just
come out with a stick and then you just
clean up the yeah and then I'll clean
out all that get the wet material out of
there pour that onto a I use a drum head
actually an old drum head flip it upside
down and pour all my [ __ ] under there
buch of separate yeah I had a that's how
I got the idea I like I'm going to
repurpose that [ __ ] but nice uh so if
you leave those in the Hut with that bag
over there with the blower on the top it
doesn't steal a lot of your pollen but
it does take some a little bit but
you're going to make enough well see I'm
also fenal hunting too I'm not just
collecting yeah and I already know that
male is who I want so I'm just let him
sit in there and just jizz away and
collect it for sure just circle jken or
[ __ ] in in a bag over
there not just Paul and chucking this
time yeah yeah this male this is his uh
the same male probably his 10th time
pollinating [ __ ] a clone of the same
male not the same guy but a clone of
that one this his 10th time hitting
stuff at least shoot my one male that uh
already have picked out proven himself
and everything um that's I took clones
of them the other day and I took like 25
nice uh just to make sure I will only
keep one but you got to have yeah but
you got to have one yeah so yeah I'm
excited that all the Clones I recently
took uh they all cut or they all rooted
um most of the seeds I've sprouted are
all germinating um man I'm working on
another project I am I don't know if I
even want to tell everybody this I am
starting to F2 black cherry Kim I'm
doing the feno hunt to find the male and
the female to F2 that I plan to start
the flowering cycle right at the start
of the year so by March 1ish I should
have found a good male and a good female
that will be used the Clones of those
will be ran next to be bred to make and
I'll use two females and one male I'll
use a purple female and a non-purple
female and see what the progy make
definitely a solid purple male I just
want to see if I cuz I may uh may make
it recessive if I force too much purple
into it may not come out till the F3 if
I do that with the two purples mhm yeah
I hope you guys are paying attention to
that that's random [ __ ] right there also
another way that I've been setting up
these tents um with just one blower
because it seemed it seems efficient uh
if you're in a small space I put the 5x5
Hut with uh I do the blower on the roof
outside of the Hut it's actually sitting
there's that hole right on top I just
set the blower right on top of there I
run ducting into the Hut and then around
into the light uh fix the light
reflector and then ducting out of the
light reflector to a carbon filter and
the carbon filter is hung really high in
the Hut as high as you can get it so now
you're filtering the air pulling out
humidity and cooling your light all at
one time yep and those work great in the
garage right now in Colorado in the
winter you need a heater more than you
need cool you got to put a heater in
there at night to keep it warm but if
you've got two of those Huts you could
run them side by side and you could vent
that heat into the other Hut from your
light if you thought about how to do it
and CO2 yeah which is soon to be illegal
yeah uh sleeping plants emit CO2 so if
you move your dark the air from your
sleeping room into your awake room you
are moving CO2 to a usable space that's
a that's a definite good hint for people
I wonder if uh mushroom bags are on that
seat O2 ban sorry to keep harping on
that no that uh that's a very they I
think they're talking about using tanks
is what they're afraid of because it's
unsafe because we have to travel with
tanks and we don't have any sort of
Licensing or anything oh Jesus but my
argument because I am going to go to
City Council when this comes up I'm
going to say this is available at the
hydroponic store why can the guy growing
tomatoes or the guy growing orchids or
whatever else he's using why can he have
CO2 and since I'm a cannabis grower I
cannot I don't I drive around with a
bottle of acetylene you want to talk
about something [ __ ] dangerous yeah
um I have no special license I went down
to air gas and they gave it to me I
signed a contract that says I wouldn't
damage their bottle but I'm not that's
all they cared about don't R our
container yeah I could blow up a
freaking building with that not that I'm
going to but accidentally you could on
accident yes yeah the the capability it
lies
there you'd be the last one ever do that
bro don't worry I know you just said
that you got paranoid right after you
said it you're like I can't say that on
the air can I I can't say that [ __ ]
abort yeah I mean Fu there's so many
more dangerous things out there than
yeah anyways let's yeah yeah I agree
with you let's save this for Mike let's
save this for Mike Mike uh we need you
back on the show here in a week or two
because you've been going to those
meetings dude thanks a lot that is not
my thing I'm so glad you're going but we
need you to come update us with what's
going on in our community and what kind
of rules they're trying to enforce on us
I wanted to go the other night but
[ __ ] weather the weather and the
Growers have shitty it's yeah it went
from uh like ooh it's kind of chilly out
to oh my God it snowing instantly yeah I
think I was wearing shorts that day yeah
it was like uh 60° and within an hour it
was uh just [ __ ] damn near freezing -
6 was cold the other night I was driving
home it was nice and cold at - 6 it's
freaking cold right now man it was
coming out and coming down like crazy
out there I'm getting better at it uh
once you're prepared the first few
winter I'm from California dude when I
first moved here winter killed me and
now I don't get I'm to knock on wood I
don't get sick like I used to when I
first moved here I'd get terribly sick
every winter just cuz I didn't know what
to do with minus 6 have to go to school
and I didn't know even what do you do
how do you even dress for this you got
to dress like it's Antarctica to get to
school and then when you get to school
it's 77 in the classroom so now you're
sweating your ass off I had to learn how
to adjust without getting sick it was
weird I'm from Durango so I've been used
to it oh yeah um living in PUO softing
me up so this is like whoa I think these
gener we were talking about this earlier
these Generations are getting softer as
we go yeah uh we were talking about a
doctor our good buddy Spence had his
appendix removed and Jesse was kind
enough to post a meme of a doctor
removing his own damn appendix on
Spencer's Facebook that's pretty cute uh
but this generation I don't know how
many people would just reach down and
remove their own appendix we're too
entitled shouldn't somebody else do this
yeah
it's kind of where we are guys if you
have more questions about a hydro Hut uh
I'm pretty good at them I just don't
know what to say uh if you got a
question I can set up your hydro Hut
like a champ I can give you a lot of
advice on that um bracing sometimes
these hoods and you get a carbon filter
and a blower and everything hung up
there um easy ways to brace it um it's a
good idea go buy some PVC um and just
freaking tape it really tight or tie it
um to the other roof beams that'll help
give you a little yeah structure up
there I've seen someone uh screw a they
had a 4x4 Hut so they took a 4x4 piece
of plywood and screwed it to the roof on
the outside um and that really really
strengthened that thing out man the dude
could have stood on the top of it so
nice they do they are a little rickety
they're a little wobbly if you're
putting like a a heavy if you don't have
the right carbon filter the good carbon
filters are heavy they sell lighter ones
that are more expensive if you don't
have that one putting a lot of weight up
there uh a light is expensive if you're
hanging like a tri XXL Raptor that's
some heavy [ __ ] yeah you probably don't
need one of those in a in a tent just a
little you know T there yeah um what is
the the 8 in uh Sun
H oh uh Sun Sun Stars snow yeah I know
exactly which reflectors I love and the
radiant sixes oh yeah the radi six or
the radiant eight it's about the size of
a shoe box it's nice and white those are
great I think instead of a big big wide
reflector a little reflector is better
because and you can make a sexual joke
out of this if you want but I want it to
go deeper I don't want it so
wide I want my light to penetrate the
canopy I was going to say you get better
penetration that way yeah I want more
penetration I don't need you tearing it
apart so wide go deeper it's still I
mean you got 1,000 watts is 1,000 Watts
so if you're reflector spreading it out
to a 5x5 area or you have a reflector
spreading it out to a 3X3 area which
you know reflector you gonna get a
better value for that thousand Watts
from and in my opinion it's going to be
the 3X3 every time absolutely and in
those Huts uh those Huts are very well
made with that reflective material in
there agreed I feel like I get a lot
more lumens out of those Huts than I do
the open rooms that I run mhm for sure
they take better pictures too yeah they
sure they got that sexy background in
there all right so most of this is the
same if you're working in a bedroom or a
closet just uh on a smaller scale uh if
you can't cut holes uh for ducting try
using a window we kind of talked about
tricking you on the Windows uh once
again use some of that blue uh it's foam
board I don't I think it's for
insulation they got it at Lowe's uh cut
that to size pop that in your window
with some duct tape uh if you need to
cut holes out of that I take actually I
use a pre-made 6 in or 8 in flange
that's used for a blower and I set that
on that blue foam board and I just step
on it that's how I cut holes in my foam
board perfect sizes for my ducks nice
yeah put your shoe on and step on it cuz
that should cut take
off yeah and then you got to you got to
knock that out cuz it gets stuck in
there so you got to use something to
punch it out yep it's kind of fun damn
that's a nice little uh uh life hack is
the popular new on that or grow room
hack instead of trying to cut just be
lazy and stomp it out uh I always use a
dry wall saw and make a gigantic mess
everywhere oh yeah that blue when you
cut that blue foam board it's going to
make a gigantic foamy mess everywhere
and it'll clog up your saws like nothing
other oh yeah yeah and it gets real
hot um yeah disguise your out Ducks um
if you can duct it out of the attic or a
chimney uh that's awesome uh you don't
want your neighbors seeing it's minus 6
outside right now where my heat is
dumping outside I'm pretty sure it's
making
steam yeah yeah no M even if it's even
if it's 20° it'll probably make Steam
dumping into minus 6 so they can see
your air coming out of your grow space
at 80° coming up the lights yeah seen
that before um melting snow off the roof
so yeah there was a guy in another
neighborhood that a friend of mine and I
used to make fun of cuz every morning at
7:00 you could see the blower click in
and the one section would clear from the
snow and about 30 minutes later one side
of the roof would be all clear like
that's where his grow space is you can
see it in the Attic right up there all
right so you got all your automation uh
you've got everything ducted we've got
lights going we've got
timers um man it's almost time to add
plants I would say get everything set up
run the room uh set all of your timers
and everything run a cycle or two make
sure your air conditioner kicks in when
it gets too hot make sure the lights go
off and on as planned uh pay attention
to the temps and humidity without the
plants in the room and this is the time
to make Corrections if you need to also
keep in mind um an empty room runs
hotter than a room full of plants when
plants absorb heat and energy so and it
will also be less humid yeah without
plants so it's going to be hotter yeah
so when I put plants in the plants are
going to cool it yeah yeah um do you
have a guess if I were running this 8
by8 room how many degrees my plants are
going to drop it no okay I I he's
completely right but I thought he may
have done more thought on that I I've
noticed it but I don't know and I also
know that when I'm in there I heat the
room up ridiculously yeah yeah I've
noticed that too so fast um I've really
noticed it mostly on ents um I'd say
actually you know what I've noticed it
on gigantic rooms too um it it varies um
it's at least a couple degrees dirt can
hold a [ __ ] ton of heat the dirt kind of
yeah kind of uh then reservoirs um you
know they'll hold heat too uh water
reservoirs yeah yeah so that's how we
heat greenh houses I was going to say
I've seen you guys put big jugs of water
in the Sun and then haul them into the
greenhouse at night to keep them warm uh
my friend Ryan actually was heating
bricks in his oven he would put a big uh
like a pot of bricks like he was just
making a pot roast full of bricks and
he'd heat those up and then go outside
and cover the plants in a tarp and then
put the hot bricks underneath the tarpu
he just harvested like a week ago in
Colorado nice Outdoors speaking of all
these uh cold weathers um weathers god
let's go down to
Walmarts
um uh my Greenhouse I harvested all the
plants right before it got freezing cold
in it um but uh I had a couple
containers with lettuce and spinach and
radish and onions um and I'm super
stoked that uh with my little tiny
heater and my little Greenhouse uh the
spinach made it through so did some of
the lettuce nice uh everything else is
frozen [ __ ] dead but frozen
vegetables already
yeah all right guys we're getting 50
minutes in here um yeah run your rooms
that's what I'm going to say run the
rooms run that bad [ __ ] run it and then
once everything is cool then you can put
plants in there and then you're going to
have to make a couple of adjustments
once you put plants in there um for sure
if you're just vegging you're fine you
can tweak around with your rooms while
you're vegging you're not going to piss
the plants off too much as soon as you
start flower you have to be really
really careful with your photo periods
that's your light cycle we call that
photo period we're going to start saying
photo period all the time and leave out
the word light cycles because photo
period is appropriate and
proper if you interrupt your photo
period on a flowering plant uh it will
possibly revert back to veg and it will
probably hermaphrodite and you're
running a good chance of making some
seeds out of that on accident that you
don't want so don't don't mess with your
photo period keep that solid yeah leave
the seeds to us no no no just kidding
please do if you got a good breeding
project keep it going um can't props I
used to be really kind of secretive and
I didn't like to share my breeding
information because I feel like I'll
teach you how to grow but breeding you
got to get a good grasp on breed on
growing and once you've got that then
you'll kind of learn how to breed with
that on accident yeah yeah uh but I kind
of been sharing a little bit of my
breeding secret so if you guys have a
specific question I'd rather help you
than just watch you fail is how I feel
about it you're going to do it so why
not help you do it right when I first
got started I won't mention any names
but I hit up a couple guys um you know
it just was some basic questions and I
got told to you know [ __ ] off basically
so um always kind of disheartened me so
yeah but it also encouraged me I was
like screw these guys I can do this
right uh just taking a little time to
research stuff and read it on your own
goes a long way oh yeah the internet is
great but and I've been banned from so
many forums and chat rooms because the
internet is full of [ __ ] and people will
type whatever they want without knowing
what they're talking about and I feel
that that sucks cuz it causes problems
that's part of what inspired this show
was reading [ __ ] on the internet going
dude I hope nobody tried that or
actually seeing somebody ask his friend
a question on a forum that sounds like
troll it up but it's not troll it up
it's very similar I've been banned so I
won't advertise the site but on troll it
up somebody asked a question and the guy
replied with a totally [ __ ] answer
to his friend and he's like awesome man
I'm going to try today and I'm like dude
don't your friend just killed your whole
crop however many plants you have
they're dead if you do that and that's
part of what inspired this I wanted to
get people that know what they're doing
to come and put a good voice out for
cannabis there's a um a thing on the
probiotics Farmers Alliance uh a pin
it's the very first post if you ever
join it um I I can't quote it for
verbatim but by any means but um uh you
know it just says essentially you know
don't make something fact just because
you believe or okay yeah I can't I can't
really uh recreate it but yeah it's just
it you know um there's so much [ __ ] out
there and people just type [ __ ] and they
believe it and they're full of [ __ ]
themselves and you know just what work
for them may not work for you your
situation could be totally different
yeah yeah I don't think I'm a member of
that group anymore so I won't be able to
see it yeah I had to leave that group
cuz they put up too much stuff and I got
way too many yeah I mean it's a great
place but yeah yeah I'm not in the group
so I can't view their stuff but still
good group yeah yeah Allan Atkinson uh
um it's a lot of the Gage green genetics
group too yeah those those guys are man
they're sharing incredible knowledge
that's incredible genetics the stuff
Gage green has been putting out lately
is super impressive I actually breed
with a gage green genetics daybreaker
maale so that's how much I like that
[ __ ] I've made my own F2 daybreaker
maale to use so that I don't have to use
Gage's original workings I have to it to
have my own yeah it's good good strain
Adam was here the other night and I cut
down nine daybreaker plants that were
about 3T tall nice uh just uh Eugenics
basically they weren't for what I needed
for that project and he didn't know what
to think dude he's not he's not an avid
pot Gardener so I was like hold this
trash bag open for me and he's like what
are you GNA do and I chop chop chop chop
chop and he just went he told me I made
him sick he's like my heart's broken man
oh that um I re well last spring I had a
plant that got some mold and uh I didn't
notice it till we were trimming it and
uh I saw it threw the freaking thing
away and the guy that was helping me Tri
uh I'm pretty sure he wanted to go take
through the trash can yeah I just threw
it in dirt I was like dude I'm not no
it's just I had
AET like your situation I had a white
rhino plant that had to be 5 oz it's a s
gallon pot uh the top Cola was as big as
a football it was the size of this
Gatorade bottle oh Jesus and uh it was
this season of the year so there was a
lot of cold in the air and I was like
that plant I know it already and I kept
checking it nothing kept checking it
nothing at Harvest Time the center of
one bud had Milo all up the middle and I
threw the whole plant away because I
didn't want to go fish through every bud
and my my trimmer buddy Mike it was Mike
at the time we were just kind of new
friends at the time nice I just put a
trash bag over it and threw it all the
way and he's like the whole thing bro
and I was like yeah we we can't mess
with that I'm that's the difference
between a pot farmer and a caregiver MH
I'm growing medical weed the person that
would have sold that is just growing
shitty weed for me for money oh and then
also I mean yeah yeah there's just so so
many reasons throw it away uh I don't
like failure so I don't want to keep a
moldy plan around my house to spread
muls even more and just you know just
screw it yeah take some pride in what
you do guys you're working really hard
at growing cannabis do it right don't
make people sicker make people feel
better all right I feel like we went
over a whole bunch of information in
kind of a scattered way um keep your
plants off the ground yeah keep your
plants up off the ground especially in
this cold weather uh keep keep
everything off the concrete floor you
can that's your nutrients your water
reservoir clone trayes most definitely
oh yeah um unless you're running an easy
cloner and you need that cool water true
true that's you know but it if you
figure that out you're you know you're
probably one of those guys that's just
getting entertainment here
so yeah which is cool thank you yeah
thanks for listening guys we're going to
we're going to definitely get more
advanced as we go we're 40 episodes in
you guys are learning stuff now I'm
learning stuff now because I have to
read just to make sure I don't lie to
you because I made a mistake on the show
one time and I felt really stupid I
don't want to go teaching wrong [ __ ] so
definitely had to come back and correct
myself so I've been making sure to read
everything and stay on top I'm reading
more about nutrients because I know
about nutrients but you get so
comfortable that you don't even pay
attention anymore I'm like he I know
when I look at that plant that's a
phosphorus deficiency I need to give it
some phosphorus and I just get in there
I'm going to have to kind of brush up a
little bit more yeah I need to do a
little homework I should be doing that
anyway so honestly with my profession
but um yeah yeah those times when you're
sitting there in the store ready to pull
your beard out just grab a book yeah
you've got the internet there yeah no
I've got a I actually got a couple books
down there nice Hydro Farm sent us of um
a free book for employees and stuff
that's kind of cool um uh one of our
other employees is reading it right now
but I can't wait to go over it it's just
about indoor hydroponic gardening you
know not pot specific or anything so
grow rooms are grow rooms yeah yeah and
hydrarm is afraid of the Cannabis
industry yeah I like how you have to
hold back on that answer oh yeah I have
if if you ever really want to know my
view on that come see me at the
store I've talked to several other Hydro
shop owners and you guys all seem to
agree everybody feels the same about
sunlight and hydrarm our customers built
a I'll say this our customers built him
a hell of a nice [ __ ] living so yeah
yes yeah all right guys I feel like it's
about time to wrap up the show we've
been going for almost an hour here uh
Jesse you got anybody to shout out
anybody to say thanks to anything like
that uh burn and everyone down at the
store um had a good experience in there
today sweet good so um let me think of a
strain no I've been digging on uh on
some sfog lately big time so when do I
get my cut of that sfog Oh I thought you
already had one no no that's all I had
to say huh nice that's the cut I've been
told so yeah yeah yeah I think I know
where yours came from and they don't
want me to have it yeah they wouldn't
give it to me being a breeder dude
people don't want you to have their Cuts
yeah yeah I know that that uh cut of
sf's made a lot of great strains and I
think we're going to make a couple with
it too so I guarantee we'll make a
couple I'll make a couple you'll make a
couple yeah yeah all right guys we're
going to wrap up the show now that the
show is over uh please go to iTunes or
Stitcher go to the iTunes Store or the
stitcher main page search for IG gr
culture find the review section and give
me a fstar rating after that type in a
comment and let me know what you think
of the show and I will really read your
comments on the show don't forget that
the show is available on iTunes Stitcher
and every episode is archived on iry
genetics.com why aren't you checking out
ir gentics colorado.com and joining The
Forum right now if you go ask questions
on the Forum a lot of people will will
answer you I'll answer you um my buddy
Al will answer you there's a lot of
helpful people on The Forum IR gentics
color.com check out the Forum the
podcast is there make sure you follow us
on Twitter Instagram and Facebook just
search for I gr culture follow iire
genetics on Instagram I post a lot of
great cannabis photography on there
follow Jesse on Instagram it's Jesse
grow he posts a lot of great cannabis
photography now if you're interested in
sponsoring the podcast or if you have a
product you'd like to see us review send
me an email at ulture hotmail.com and
I'll get you all the info you need we
still need our own theme song if anybody
wants to help us out with that uh once
again shout out to my ninja Spence big
shout out to Angela shout out to Jesse
for coming to do another episode much
love to you guys for listening until
next time take a fat dab give your mom a
hug for
me
e
e e