[Music]
welcome back podcast world it is time
for episode 400 of the growth from your
heart podcast this episode is brought to
you by our friends at Oregon elite seeds
that's right it's time to get new seeds
for your garden and you can find them at
Oregon elite seeds dot-com ladies and
gentlemen
joining me on episode 400 to my left
it's white Mike welcome back bro thanks
man
what's up everybody also right in front
of me a longtime favorite Clint's back
at the show thanks for joining us bro
hello friends hello friends thanks for
being here dude
thanks man thanks to both you guys for
being here it's episode 400 or ah no I
was gonna do a Ric Flair welcome buddy
we've been dabbing so it is always a
tradition that we start the show off by
talking about what we're smoking hey
Clint
I think the last time you were here were
you an on pot smoker or had you just
started consuming Clint was not a
consumer for the first part of his
podcast in tahrir though and now he is a
cannabis consumer so welcome to the
green team yeah we're doing it what do
you smoking bro do you know what strain
you've got over there
it's a Afghani something I don't I you
know I'm still pretty new to it so we
don't really care as long as you got
some green smelly bud to put in a pipe
and you get stoned you're pretty happy
huh yeah that's pretty easy I like that
about you
it smells good it looks all right he's
smoking flowers over there Mike and I on
the other hand are taking some dabs we
smoked some vanilla cookies batter from
apothecary farms the label said it is 79
percent THC with 94.4% total
cannabinoids also on top of that dab
just to give it a little a little spice
a little turbocharged I took some star
guava HCF se that's the high cannabinoid
full-spectrum extract it looks like
citrine's little chunky THC diamonds
that is labeled at sixty to sixty six
point two five percent THC and seventy
six point five percent total
cannabinoids sprinkled some of that onto
the vanilla cookies I give it a gassy
root beer candy kind of a flavor really
delicious
obviously I'm nice and baked because I
can't shut
I'm glad you approve I'm glad everyone's
happy yes just think about it brought
the coffe back yeah Mike's been just
coughing you gotta get you off those
cigarettes yep some Nicorette or
something going in your life this is a
distinct possibility let's do it bro
let's help Mike get him off the
cigarettes tweet him tell him to quit
everybody harass Mike on the Twitter at
Nemo Punk'd 15 get him off the
cigarettes in the podcast is concerned
look so since we're pitching Mike's uh
Twitter would you like to pitch any of
your social media stuff there Clint so
that the final listeners can follow you
all right there we go
that was a polite way to die do that one
prepare for seven random Instagram
there's just nothing I don't I don't
post anything I don't have a SoundCloud
I got all these new face tattoos and
those mumble wrapped I like your style
just the old graffiti scrawl one yeah so
this is episode 400 you guys this is how
it's gonna go you're not gonna learn a
lot here we're gonna have a good time
we've already been consuming a lot of
dabs a lot of flowers the room is smoky
my head is cloudy my eyes are red Mike's
coughing his lungs out for a good show
Clint's eyes are red her than I've ever
seen he's got a big smile on his face
we're gonna have a good time here my
first bullet point says the podcast
birthday is coming woohoo the birthday
of the first episode there has been some
some debate a couple of times here we've
talked about how long the show is going
the actual first episode somebody
document this so that listeners can
remember so that in the future when we
go in which to show one of you guys it
likes to remember all the stuff uh when
he folks you know who you are the people
that when I say hey somebody help me
find this detail there are a few guys
that can email me that detail
immediately so the birthday of the show
episode number one was March 28th 2014
nice yeah so we've been going for quite
a while haven't missed a Monday since we
got it started Mike how many shows have
you been on enough I'd say you've been
on a good at least a hundred of them
it's one of my favorite parts of episode
100 is some you asked me that on episode
and before I could answer somebody was
like too many oh well we like having a
think we've proven that we've had some
people try to complain about mic through
comments and such you said hey to anyone
15 on Twitter
there's no hatred if they want to start
a podcast they can you know that's kind
of how I feel if you don't like this one
and also there's so many other good
shows to try to ramble better yeah
there's somebody doing it trust me they
listen to this because they like you and
they like the grow lessons so if they
want to listen to us for one episode
they'll be alright they're gonna have a
good time with this this is episode 400
you guys thanks for listening to 399
episodes all the way up to 400 that's a
lot of loyal followers right there are a
lot of loyal listeners I don't know why
I called you followers it's not social
media you were two listeners it's a cult
it is the small it's the Irie army that
exami and I I appreciate each and every
one of the people that listen to the
show
for 400 episodes it's crazy that's crazy
yeah that's so much content how many
hours have we spent around this table
staring at microphones at least 400 I'd
say at least 200 because each show is at
least thirty minutes on when you're on
they get closer to an hour because you
got more to talk about
so the probably probably got 400 hours
of content oh yeah
some of the episodes are well there are
some repeats because we do those long
blocks but speaking of long blocks the
grow lessons I have compiled the grow
lessons into large chunks without
interruption so when we did the grow
series from planning your grow to
selecting your space or a whole bunch of
really specific grow lessons what I did
was sometimes we were doing that series
we got interruptions like Mike came over
for an episode we talked about candy
breaks yeah little breaks to break it up
and make it fresh and fun for me I've
really wanted to put all of those
episodes into one chunk so that people
could really just focus in and learn so
I've made compilations those compilation
posts will start at episode 401 so 401
402 403 and I think 404 will be
compilations of very specific highly
detailed grow lessons nice I made it 401
through whatever so they're really easy
to find
you just 401 it starts at zero ones
where the Guru lessons are so we're
gonna repost those and then we'll get
caught up on regular lessons
gonna be a good time but that way I
think people can really focus in and
learn I think it'll really help them
find all of the lessons so that's just
what I wanted to say after that I don't
know why that was so important right now
the next bullet point I've got written
down is uh music on those shows is
obnoxious the music on 401 and 402 and
403 somebody said make your own theme
music and Jeff went at it I went for it
but what I could what I would like sorry
I'm stumbling hi what I would like is I
need a theme song I've tried to use
music from other artists and other
places and I keep getting flagged on
youtube so if you have the ability to
make a fresh original song that you
haven't posted anywhere else that you're
not stealing rhythms from something else
if you can make a fresh new theme song
for the podcast
I would love new intro music obviously I
like reggae kind of stuff but if you've
got something cool for me probably
hopefully something instrumental without
a lot of voices in it maybe if it's just
got my voice being looped or something
maybe people that have been on the show
if you capture some show stuff if you
make music you know how to make an intro
music you know what I'm talking about
I would appreciate the support I don't
have a lot to offer in return but I will
definitely give you something that will
put a smile on your face so if you can
make some music maybe like a two-minute
intro that'd be pretty cool maybe a
little longer I wouldn't complain maybe
a little shorter can't be mad at you but
an intro track would be super sweet and
start at around episode 405 or something
if we can get it on time once we get
past these grow lessons cool yeah that'd
be rad deicide that would be pretty fun
they'd be crazy no thanks if they sent
me something cool that was like really
hardcore why not let's do it at the end
of an episode yeah so now here's a
hardcore song all right we're back yeah
do you side take me back to eighth grade
bro man I don't want to think about
sorry all right
you brought it up I know I did so if you
do have an intro track even if you are
deicide I'll play it on the show you can
send it to me at grow four
your heart at hotmail.com is the best
way to get it to me I want to hear what
you're doing musically I am honestly not
the best musical producer when it comes
to creating my own intro tracks with the
computer I mean it sounded like you did
pretty good to me but I mean these guys
will see it pretty soon they'll hear it
mic just started to speak about it and
then gave up what I heard was
technically music it was technically
original I mean YouTube might have some
problems with it but I don't think it's
gonna fly oh that's all original that
stuff is gonna fly at some of the reggae
tracks that I've built with GarageBand
YouTube has been like no that's a ripoff
and like but I mean it's already flagged
that one beat dude yeah it knows the
boom chicka chicka I know and it's just
you can't teach YouTube that there are
different yeah I get it Mike I get it
yeah I've been trying not to make that
joke for three minutes I know I saw it
on your face two minutes ago I have to
keep pushing that's why I knew you're
going boom check good headed there all
right new music would be highly
appreciated even if it does go boom
Chicka Boom Chicka I play guar do you
say Barbie goosey Guarin instead of just
throwing like weird [ __ ] at you they
throw like joints it's somewhere out in
the world right now there's an IRA I
remember that's also a big wide by two
worlds no I have no hatred toward the
metal people would be surprised Clint
this is kind of what brought up the
metal to be honest Clinton I were
hanging out a little bit before Mike
came I was dabbing Clint was smoking a
ball and we're just talking about music
Clint brought up on to his favorite
bands from back in the day and I enjoyed
it but it wasn't my thing and I was like
that's like this band with a different
kind of singer so I went and played some
hardcore stuff and Clint was like no no
no no no that's not for me and I was
like so it's like similar music the
background tracks are the same but the
singers were way on different levels
when I was younger I like to delve into
the really aggressive side of music I
just enjoy music altogether I can listen
to some jazz I can listen to a little
bit of death metal but of course I'd
prefer some fish or some reggae but yeah
I appreciate all kinds of good music but
that's where that came from
we're talking about old music back in
the day what was the name of that band
II we're jamming dude I can't think of
the name of the one I liked yeah
Oh protest the hero protest to the hero
so if you guys like them we leave a
comment or something yeah tell us what
you think about protest of the hero that
is one of Clint's favorite bands those
guys are cool from nice guys what what
grade were you in when you fell in love
with that band like senior in high
school okay all right perfect
yeah I don't know somewhere around there
have you have your musical tastes
changed now that you're up I had no I
I'm still listening to like a lot of the
same music I feel like my dad how he
just never stopped listening in to the
who that's kind of how I'm doing things
now is like no I'm just gonna listen to
like Killswitch Engage from like 2010
like that's like my favorite era of
metal music so it's like I'll just stick
with that
I don't need new stuff it ain't broke
don't change it bro yeah that's why my
sound clouds are not working very good
do you still dress like you did from
that era also yeah I think just jeans
and t-shirt that's a guy though guys
that's a guy that's what we tend to do
like around high school graduation year
around 20 that's why we're gonna dress
like that's how you dress from now on I
think that's Mike's kind of staring off
into space trying to do the math on that
no I'm actually I've every time I look
at my closet I feel guilt over this
phenomenon because I'm like I'm familiar
with the concept of man boys I don't
want to personify this but I will not
change my baggy jeans to doctors it's
not gonna happen yeah Mike is wearing
Jen COEs tonight I can't give them up
it's it's part of me from that era it's
a really weird podcast tonight 400 I did
not say that we're gonna talk about any
growing or any weed stuff we're just
gonna have a good time tonight you guys
know you're here you already hit play
you're stuck with us enjoy well that's
not really true is broken
there's mashing on that 32nd forward
button like do they ever get to anything
does this [ __ ] go anywhere mm we'll
see we'll see
let's ride with us please we could take
it somewhere we've gone for a few
minutes now I do have one thing planned
that we can handle real quick does
anybody need a DAB before we get into
some iTunes
customer reviews okay Mike said I'm good
clean you want your first dab on the
podcast no that was hesitated I think
it's way better that I don't I think the
audience could know that I don't do dabs
it's just I feel like this is behavior
we should encourage like not
over-consuming is a good thing I think
all three of us are too old to be
carried home by our friends from a night
out oh geez [ __ ] six four and two
hundred pounds you ain't getting carried
too far I'll make them to that couch and
that's probably where he spends the
night yeah it's weird to explain that
you blacked out at a friend's house
because you over consumed and that's why
you didn't get home till 10:00 the next
day it's really heartbreaking to have to
call your adult friends wives to come
pick them up yeah like it was cool we
were 22 it was like oh so-and-so needs
to get carried home like I'll help but
now it's now it is strange all right I'm
trying not to move the computer too much
because we have all of the technology
plugged in it don't jiggle it don't the
computer too much when you've got the
USB plugged in here and you try not to
break anything and you hope you're still
recording cuz you can't see the screen
anyway we're gonna read some iTunes
customer ratings and reviews I like to
do that on the podcast here this first
review I don't know if I have read this
one it feels like I may have read this
one but it's a good review so we're
gonna do it again anyway
this one comes from a person who calls
themselves ganja goddess they left this
on January 17th the headline says this
has become my favorite podcast thank you
for that I really appreciate it it says
honestly I started with the dude show
and that's how I found this podcast
needless to say it's grown on me it's
grown on them I don't know if they even
meant that grown on me and is now my
favorite show to listen to and then they
give the little thankful hands and they
signed it with their at seas of cheese
that's probably their Instagram handles
so follow seas of cheese for 20 on the
Instagram there it ganja goddess thank
you for the great 5 star review I do
appreciate that one next review is left
by somebody who calls themselves nom nom
juju bug clan is that you busted the
headline says dude they gave us a 5 star
sounds like it's me this will have
January 31st that had the review itself
goes like this Jeff bro you are dope
much love from Florida
hashtag we love it when you ramble Bert
Kreischer you think that's Bert
Kreischer that left that ones there from
Florida yeah alright thanks Bert
Kreischer or whoever nom nom juju bug
might be I doubt that's Kreischer
because that's too many letters for
pressure to spell you just fell asleep
on his keyboard some autocorrect [ __ ]
right there that sounds like a Russian
bot what's his daughter's name
why are we what's not Shirley something
about juju bug reminded me one of his
kids will you said Bert Kreischer I was
like okay so that review was left by
Bert Kreischer thanks Bert Kreischer the
machine for the great review who from
the what expert
whoever everybody gather in Florida
thanks for all the support Alex Florida
that's Florida growers union people big
shout out this next review not from Bert
Kreischer came from a person who called
themselves freedom 35 well they didn't
put two threes and freedom so freedom 35
with threes in there the headline says
real deal lessons they give us a
five-star review this one was left on
February 4th of 2019 and the review goes
a lot like this I looked away I can't
find it here what are the most detailed
and accurate grow podcasts out Rasta
Jeff makes it way easy to grow seed to
harvest the episodes with white Mike and
others are also nice to stay on stay up
on the state of the industry weekly
episodes from a longtime grower and
breeder are not one to miss hey Mike
they like the episodes with you
appreciate it and they like the episode
there's other people so that's you Clint
starts today I'm doing the guys you did
gold star
hey freedom thank you for the great
review I know we're joking around today
but I do appreciate these reviews we're
having fun on episode 420 or 400 oh oh
there's no editing in this show live to
drive baby it's how we're doing it
freedom 35 thank you for the great
review thank you for the 5 stars
I'm glad you appreciate the detailed
grow lessons and I'm glad I'm making it
easy for you that's kind of what I'm
here for is to kind of take the stress
off of a grower it can be really
stressful setting up your first growth
you've got a lot of equipment to think
about you've got a lot of plans to think
about you've got rules to follow and
then you've got these plants I like your
new babies it's like getting a kitten
but it doesn't meowing eat normal food
you got to figure it out you know what I
mean like a kitten just would look at
you and you gotta feed it then it goes
on shits on the come with instructions
either that's right that is very true so
it's a little challenging you become
stressful so I'm glad that I'm easing
the stress for the grower making it fun
instead of stressful and I'm also I feel
like I'm improving the quality of
people's outcome so instead of run mid
grade the first time they're gone kind
of low high grade like the lowest of the
high grade quality and then they have
opportunity for super high grade next
time and it's just more encouragement
instead of starting off almost failing
your first try well it's nice being able
to listen to it for free over and over
if you need for free yeah you can just
hit that rewind and repeat button and
keep listening
well like or you're coming back to
something it's like well what was that I
remember him saying something about that
and I'm sure that I mean leave your
comments below let us know when rasta
Jeff told you something that like helped
you out a whole bunch that's pretty cool
there you go yeah what's your favorite
episode let me know because I am making
a complete compilation of best podcast
episodes also they will be on a playlist
on YouTube so let me know which episode
do you learn the most from and I'll make
sure to include those episodes in my
compilations that way they're easy to
find they'll get a lot of views very
cool hell yeah
Mike you have a really serious look of
concern on your face over there not
concerned at all not concerned nope
alright as long as you're cool with ever
doing it doing everybody still recording
I think we're still recording I haven't
looked at the thing Wow but I'm pretty
sure that since nobody's hit stop as
soon as you mentioned it I became
concerned also isn't it a weird feeling
you're not even the show producer I just
realized that I always see the sound
levels in the background and they're not
there now yeah all of this could be
disappearing into the ether this could
be a one-time thing
but I think it's working this might just
be for us it might be but I have a
feeling that's working so it feels dumb
just doing all this part so yeah thanks
a lot freedom 35 I do appreciate that
even though we are [ __ ] super lit
today I do appreciate the reviews the
next customer review comes from somebody
that calls themselves Seb fan 2200 the
headline says outstanding show of course
they gave us a five-star review this
review was left on February 16th of 2019
and it says I've listened to numerous
grow related podcast and this one is
most definitely on another level my
go-to podcast thank you that is a huge
compliment
hopefully we're taking your grow to
another level and I'm glad that it's
your go to podcast I appreciate that
thanks for listening I always say that
it's no competition I do appreciate that
there are other grow podcasts but it
always does feel good for somebody to
say that you're the best even when
there's no competition but I'm just
gonna participation trophies go on I
think you're uh you're the one that's
doing it the longest trying the hardest
and just to ease everybody's mind it was
I'm glad all the people that are
listening to this recording who were
probably worried about that right it's
like watching a movie when you wonder if
the person lived but you know that they
live because they're in the [ __ ]
documentary doing [ __ ] interviews
like I wonder if he's okay and you're
like oh wait there he is with both legs
he survived
we're like if second movies see the
trailer for it or something he's still
like there's a part two I know he lives
if this was live that would have been a
really interesting moment where the
listeners knew [ __ ] that the
broadcaster's didn't hey you guys are
still straight getting tweets tweet us
now and let us know if we're still on
forever forever I see you on there you
make really great tweets I like your
tweets yeah they're positive they're
cool keep them we'll keep them private
positive energy yeah good [ __ ] good good
[ __ ] so I want to thank everybody for
all of the itunes customer ratings and
review
I do appreciate that that helps out the
podcast that helps us move up in the
rankings more people see the show which
means more people listen to the show
which in turn means more people grow
high quality cannabis which means in
turn we have more people on Team Green
to help us fight the legalization battle
so we're doing our part one click at a
time and thank you for your support and
if you'd like to leave a review it's
really easy
you've probably got an iPhone or an iPad
or some sort of Apple device go to the
podcast where you normally listen to the
podcast just like you're listening and
when it shows the available episodes
scroll up and if you scroll too far it
will give you the option to leave a
rating and review of course I do
appreciate five stars believe what you
really honestly feel I deserve so far
we've gotten all five star reviews
except for that one guy who left a
really terrible review I honestly have
no power to remove reviews iTunes took
that down I didn't do it I can't do it I
have no access to that iTunes has taken
that review down it is gone that's good
yep I mean it's a hundred percent that
means enough people went and reported it
and said that it was a negative comment
and that it didn't wasn't valid who
wasn't yeah just a hater comment so one
of the guys were talking to right now
thanks guys I like that we got the
battery that you got the bad comment cuz
it brought up your overall ranking yes
once you get a negative comment it
believes that your real like if you have
just a bunch of good comments and you
could just be a but like you said a
bunch of Russian BOTS just mean I like
show great show thumbs up yeah instead
we got one like these guys are [ __ ]
wack and they left us two stars and a
thumbs down or something yeah so that
made it real you know I know you have a
complaint you must be real
I bet iTunes remember the realness
though yeah oh yeah for sure yeah
well the internet remembers yeah this is
permanence one of the things that you
gotta remember when you're here this is
permanent here I'm gonna take this sip
of this frosty cold beverage that
doesn't pay us to advertise do you have
a favorite of the 23 Terps oh come on
what are you doing why manin it's not it
is product with it's my favorite turf
then we're gonna take a DAB or at least
take a drink at the same time to make it
awkward somebody's got to talk I'll just
keep doing it I'll see I'm gonna take
one for the team I may regret this
decided I took my drink so I'll talk now
they're your chose boys chose we're
gonna like go out kind
kind of I'm we can edit but I'm curious
what Clint was gonna say oh I was gonna
announce to the audience how excited I
am to be here for episode 400 this is
I'm really proud of Jeff I really am
this is you you put a lot of effort into
this and I hope that this rewards you
the way I think you deserve to be
rewarded I appreciate all that with a
straight face I really do I appreciate
that and it is all coming together being
in the industry which I am in and being
the person I've been trying to be and
putting my energy in the direction I'm
trying to get it it is coming together
I think Indo Expo was one of the first
things that showed me it is really
working many many people walked up
listeners fellow podcasters fellow
breeders growers they walked up and
wanted to shake my hand 70% because of I
read genetics in the breeding and the
cannabis industry work a good solid 30%
was all podcast friends and listeners
and Shengo Louis walked up and wanted to
say hi and thanked me for a great
podcast and he told me that is my shout
out to his show increased his audience
so just knowing that I can increase
somebody else's audience was kind of
cool so thank you man I appreciate it
and I do feel it finally it is but you
said I hope it rewards me the way truth
it is it is all coming together now and
I'm starting to feel it and see it and
although it's almost 10 years in the
making in this industry doing what I've
been trying to do and it is finally
paying off so you guys if you've been
doing something for a long time
you keep doing it it'll come together if
you get your heart and soul into it it's
not killing you doing it you're loving
it keep putting it in there it's gonna
take you about 10 years to get anywhere
with the real business yeah very true
very very true but thank you dude I do
appreciate that uh with that being said
I'm gonna take a DAB I'm gonna I may
have to start another jar here look we
scrape this one clean that's the saddest
concentrated jar every open that up and
it's just hollow it Mike happy Christmas
[Music]
five-0 there's all the Clint dad's a
millionaire that I'm going to take so
I'm taking a little bit of this vanilla
cookies batter and I'm taking the last
HCF se crystal out of this star guava
and I'm just gonna scrape in the jar and
then I'm gonna dab that um which one of
you guys is gonna talk about some cool
[ __ ] while I take this tab here you can
take that dirt to my competing it's
grape a half a ton of those together
cool stuff huh well you know I mean I'm
not let's see I believe dabs look like
drugs so that's a really good that
that's I'm all about this conversation
as I'm gonna call you an outsider yeah
you're not into the cannabis culture you
said earlier I don't even care what
strain I'm smoking as long as it [ __ ]
gets me stoned I only need two hits
anyway so I don't really consider you
you were a cannabis consumer you are
part of T my region edited part of the
Irie army but you're not you're your
cannabis community but you're not part
of the like the hip culture part of it
you know what I mean you don't care to
be you don't care you just don't care to
wear the cool clothes anybody wears you
don't care to be cool to be seen you
gonna take care of your family and be
clean just me so it's kind of I'm gonna
call you an outsider to this culture yes
as an outsider how bad does this look
like drugs there's there's some of like
the the concentrates that as you I mean
you're using a blowtorch so that's
that's something that just seems now my
question I'm gonna compound on that mmm
this torch I'm using is not like the map
gas torch you see the crackheads using
or somebody that you'd see in a shop
welding something or maybe the kind of
torch that attaches a creme brulee torch
community people usually see yeah does
this torch make it does this being like
a cigar torch or a creme brulee torch or
not a crackhead looking torch does this
change the vibe slightly to you at least
I think I think that just the it clicks
it has the flame there's like you're
heating up something just to smoke it it
just looks like I understand
that this is like knots this is the same
thing I'm doing just sit and accelerated
rate it just looks like drugs okay I
like that and it's not I don't have a
problem with it oh yes yeah it just
looks like it okay I just don't know how
much people on the inside of your
culture like deep into it just don't
realize that oh well if when you're
putting up pictures on Instagram and
like your rigs dirty or something like
that like oh I'm doing my dabs now it's
just like man you're just if you're
gonna take a picture of something at
least clean it up I agree with that
I don't know man there's a lot of things
what you just said took my brain a
couple of different places
sure like part of the war on drugs over
the last [ __ ] 80 years is there was a
lot of stigmatization that went with it
and as far as like being a longtime
member of the cannabis community like I
got over the do you think my clothes are
silly you think my music is silly you
think my hair is silly you think my
earrings are silly
like I get that when you look at me you
judge me for lots of stuff adding
something like a blowtorch to my
cannabis consumption didn't bother me
that much on an appearance level but I
am more cognizant like when I'm out in
the world and people are paying
attention when I go to do a DAB non-kin
community members perk way up and become
far more interested than if I pulled out
to joy absolutely I could agree with
that they're like what do you got there
in the anti pot crowd [ __ ] loves to
rail about concentrates and dabbing they
uh they haven't figured out exactly how
and why it's like other drugs yeah
but they know it looks like harder drugs
and it's scary to people that aren't
familiar with it and so they're running
with it pretty hard yeah you know what I
think those people that think that it
looks like harder drugs that are on the
news that are like it looks a lot like
they're doing this kind of drug because
they used to do that kind of drug and
they know or they just seen it in their
town and it scares them because like
there's epidemics on [ __ ]
all sorts of drugs that hit you know the
East Coast got ravaged by heroin yeah I
mean coke came in and took over the
whole country for a while there and then
there's ecstasy and what's what's the
meth is hitting like small [ __ ] it so
so I I have extended family that is
definitely [ __ ] with that [ __ ] and it
[ __ ] them up sorry to drop a couple of
hard f-bombs
it's just [ __ ] it that's it scary so you
start seeing that stuff and you start
seeing the lifestyle that they were in
and it's like damn well it kind of looks
the same as this daybreak and I
completely understand that it's not but
you start seeing some of the stuff that
they were like smoking out of whatever
they were doing like Matt there's no
joke so I just I don't think that this
is a gateway because I'm not even
willing to gateway into daps you know
I'm not gonna go back to drinking either
though so I I don't know I'm a I'm a
different breed you know I'm willing to
smoke because it's the right thing for
me
it keeps me healthy I appreciate that
does it unhealthy you either like
there's that component to a lot of it
too yeah yeah like that's the thing with
me and booze is like the first couple of
days that I'm having a drink or two if
I'm on a trip or something aren't a
problem it's a week later what I'm
having half a bottle at night oh yeah
yeah so I want to continue with the
other dabs look like drugs thing you
were saying earlier that we've got a
mutual friend that smokes with a nectar
collector I'm gonna describe the
difference between the nectar collector
and a normal rig a little bit here so
with my rig it looks like I have got
this is a it's called a hammer head as
the style of pipe so it is a can just
imagine a small cylinder and then coming
off that cylinder is a long mouth piece
that is flared open that fits your mouth
and they're just pretty cleanly so you
don't have to make a little kissy face
then coming off at the top of that is it
looks like a bowl it looks like a pipe
bowl it looks like a thimble on a 90
degree piece of glass you heat the
thimble part and you put the dab in
there then you put
cap on it and you smoke it just like you
would any other pipe or bubbler I like a
small dab rig I've talked about why like
a small dab rig in several episodes so
this one looks like kind of like your
basic like maybe your bubble crack pipe
or just a basic bubbler for smoking bong
or smoking flour yeah so with the the
nectar collector it is just a straight
tube it is straight and it may have
water if it doesn't have water I call
that a dab straw but it's just a
straight tube it's also known as a drill
I'm in instead of putting the dab onto
the nail you leave the dabs in a tray or
a glass dish something that kind of
looks like similar to an ashtray kind of
see a lot of people dabbing straight out
of their silicone container which I
don't know how I feel about yeah but you
heat the tip of that and then you press
that directly into the concentrate and
then you inhale through the opposite end
it works its effective I prefer a rig is
definitely the way I prefer to dab in
your opinion does the nectar collector
versus the daybreak does that look any
different to you that less drugs or just
just as much drugs the the little straw
thing looks pretty
I mean his is yours clean and his not so
that's something to do with it - okay
Mike it's also you're using a creme
brulee he's using like one of those blue
torch like alright you know it's just I
don't know I really think that for me
it's the torch okay as you went through
this thing it's like yeah I'm not mad at
your little bong you know what
essentially that's a little wrong that's
all it is it's a bong for constant for
the curious looking little bowl like
what kind of new bowl is that it's it's
probably just the way it heats up to me
that's just like wow that's that's
excessive with the optics better when it
was electric did you ever see the
electronic I did but that I mean that's
been so long ago I mean I'm you know I
don't even remember who I was back daddy
was brand new at that time when he was
coming over with the email on the table
oh yeah yeah yeah Jesus seems like a
lifetime ago it was we've evolved so far
those two hundred episodes ago probably
Wow
man how the time flies huh
time flies episode 400 it'll be episode
420 I can't believe you're for us double
just at 300 yeah yeah it feels 100
episodes we just did 300 yeah once again
thank you everybody for listening I know
this is a rambley ass episode but I
think the rambley episodes are super fun
Mike's not in his head yep good radio
voice head-butting the mic for
indication to Mary I go back and listen
to the shows and I listen to most of the
episodes listeners even the ones I'm on
my favorite part is the like I'm usually
alone when I listen to the podcast or
like it work with headphones in or
something and it makes me feel like I'm
at the table hanging out with friends
for a little bit which is really nice
especially if you do right go ahead
click go ahead I feel like the people
that listen to the podcast I have
developed a relationship like a
friendship with a lot of people online
with I only know them through the
podcast some of them I get lucky enough
to actually meet them in person like
Aldridge came a little while back and I
got to shake his hand and meet him I
said a lot of people from the Indo Expo
I get to meet a lot of those people but
there's a thing that happens when you
listen to 400 episodes of people they
know us now like they know people
remember [ __ ] that I said that I forgot
I even said and they bring it up and I'm
like how do you know that podcast where
I probably said that and I have I've
since I listened to a lot of podcasts I
see the same thing in other shows like
when people come when comedians come I
feel like I know them like we do know
people but it's even we have tighter
relationships with them just because of
their podcast I feel like I know stuff
about them and when they come it's like
hey how you been how is I know some of
my friends wives names because of their
podcast and other dogs name I know that
one of my friends has to have an eye
surgery because of his podcast when he
comes I talked to him about that and so
the people that listen have that they've
developed that with us too definitely
we're we're friends like we have bros
and lady friends that aren't romantic
what do you call Bros it or females I'm
trying to find a non gender bras that
see that don't like that at all and
chicks is really derogatory
see we have a bunch of friends of
multiple genders it's 2019 so they could
be [ __ ] anything at this point I'm
just saying bro weird bro weird a lot of
bras watching the show right
no but it's great to have developed
friendly relationships with the people
that listen to the show I really like it
some people I know what's going on in
some people's gardens like there are a
couple of people that I'll check on them
if I haven't heard from them in a few
days I'm like hey did you fix that [ __ ]
yet because we've been checking on their
garden for like two weeks trying to
solve a problem and sometimes we'll get
it fixed you know just through a few
emails and so I feel like I know those
people now and I want to check into like
a bro are those mites gum or whatever
you know like that's cool yeah and those
are just people that we have developed
relationships through the podcast on to
social media and you know it's it's
great that we have this platform that
this is a thing that we're allowed to do
this is a great freedom yeah yeah this
used to be pirate radio you know what I
mean it really did it used to be what we
made a fairly decent movie about it
called pump up the volume like way back
in the day
yeah the idea of having an open free
communication platform like this and I
actually made my niece and nephew go
watch it they were both blown away by
the whole concept of that being a movie
now and the internet yes no that [ __ ]
was around before yep I can remember
clips of that movie when he had to hide
the phone so that it could make him look
like he was somewhere else and then the
seven-minute stretch no good part of the
movie got that movie you guys really
really young Christians yeah Christian
Slater meets good in that one when he
looks like he might have you know
finished college a couple years ago and
is still able to play a high school kid
I'm gonna go home and watch Sandra
Bullock in the net I should do the thing
too me too
like oh it's got a symbol in the corner
of the webpage no one will ever click
that it's not just the only thing on the
webpage all right no one will click that
oh [ __ ] I love movies like that where
you get a good taste and flavor for like
the world of the level attack at the
time and even a few years later its yeah
we didn't have yea the pirate radio we
did not have the internet back then we
couldn't do this and then we got
podcasting and then they tried to stop
podcasting with the patent troll thing
and we fought that and got that off and
now we're still going I said got that
off that's kind of gross but we beat
that and now we're still going
podcasting is pretty amazing you're
right and then the ability to just reach
out for anybody to reach out to anybody
nowadays is great there's no limit like
I can access the president which I mean
that's just probably I used to be the
top of the tier when you trying to talk
about important people that you want to
access now you just tweet him and he'll
tweet back at you and tell you to [ __ ]
yourself if he doesn't like you it's
kind of amazing
it's the presidency was removed from
that itself very recently yeah remember
when Twitter was like you could reach
anyone except the highest tiers of
government yeah but now you can anybody
it's crazy it's all Will Smith great job
on that movie I could tell another actor
to go [ __ ] himself I could tell some
other actress that I loved her dress I
could tell Greg Proops hey thanks for
that great show and they'll reply to me
they actually respond and they say Jeff
I'm glad you enjoyed the movie that we
did make sure you check out the next
movie I'm putting out you know like
you're checking around all the time
Greg Proops would be like hey thanks for
coming out to the podcast sorry that all
the volunteers from the audience were
whacked like groups will actually
respond to me and stuff like it's this
era this time period is great it's
really exciting to be part of all that
and then having 400 episodes and you got
a leg up on anybody that's starting
right now - I mean everybody can listen
to this podcast and take this as an
example out of like okay we we want to
do a grow podcast this is this is a real
niche like market you know there isn't
like a whole lot of people that it's
like you know I was thinking about
growing marijuana today where should I
start right so there's a lot more of
that now though than there was when we
started I got you and that that is
happening and I think that things like
this I I really think weeds gonna get to
the place where it's almost like
Tomatoes where we're headed towards
craft brewery for sure you know
everybody grew their own they will
be easy I compare it to like Mike said
craft brewer brewery is probably a
really good comparison I kind of think
of it like music equipment and musicians
there are different levels of musicians
and different level of commitment and
different aspirations when it comes to
music just like there are when it comes
to growing the equipment is overpriced
you have to invest in a lot of it it
takes a lot of time to get good at any
of it I kind of think of it like a
musician and that's kind of how it
evolves and there's all there are always
new young people coming in older people
coming that want to become a musician I
myself I rant this is random rap that
fits right in it's midnight I just
turned 40 years old right now for my
thank you thank you much thank you
listeners that are telling me happy
birthday I do appreciate that for my
birthday I bought myself the expensive
drum set that I've been staring at since
I was a kid so there will be growers
that come along that are youngsters that
want to learn how to grow there will be
people that have a medical need that
their state just comes along that
legalizes that want to grow then they're
gonna be guys that are 40 years old that
just for their birth today they're gonna
say well it's legal now I got a little
bit of money because I'm doing well in
my old age but if I can go buy a grow
set up and start growing and they're
gonna want to find a podcast like this
or like you're saying the other cannabis
podcast so it's gonna be a growing
growing market I hate to call it a
market that sounds like I'm trying to
capitalize too much but it's a growing
there's always going to be a demand for
this even after all 50 states legalized
because eventually we'll have national
legalization that's the goal right is
legalization nationwide so that we can
all possess consume and safely I have
access to our medicine once we get to
that point we're gonna have everybody
from every book every single state is
gonna try to want to grow cannabis and
then once that tapers off we still get
those waves of folks like I was talking
about the young kids that just turn old
enough it's legal to grow when you're
this age whatever the nation makes it 18
21 as soon as a bunch of people turn
that age they're gonna start growing
we're gonna get waves of that then
you're gonna get the midlife crisis guys
as I guess what we're gonna call them
the 40 year old dudes that want to just
do something new instead of buying a
drum kit a bunch of guys are gonna go
buy run down to the hydro store and drop
two grand yeah and just go learn it in
the basement just like a lot of guys are
gonna do with the drums I mean it right
now is like this DIY era of everything
because I I cannot say I don't know how
anymore absolutely there is no no one
can say that at all I it doesn't matter
what you're doing there's a YouTube
video for it yep
it doesn't matter what you're doing
there's gonna be a podcast about it
yeah and somebody's put in 400 episodes
into some niche thing that yes it's
blowing up or coming comparatively to
what it's been for the last 150 years
but I mean it's it's neat that we have
access to this I'm really excited for
what we can make happen like individuals
you know what I mean
like you put in 400 episodes I'd I put
in five you know Mike's helping out with
a hundred but he would have done zero on
here without you here yeah I'd I said
there's no way my podcast yeah I
appreciate that yeah it's just you know
hard work that's all I don't know
getting older I start seeing it and I
start respecting it more well thank you
bro thank you
there's there's some time at this table
end of this podcast dude I burned out a
macbook i drew please the macbook
because mainly all that old macbook did
was a podcast and it's your passion
that's got 400 episodes I mean maybe six
of those were me calling you and being
like I want to do an episode on blank
right and I wouldn't have made those
phone calls had you not already done a
couple hundred episodes on other [ __ ]
there's one time when I was super sick
just so sick I got like six of my
friends here and then you guys did a
podcast without me basically i sat here
and worked the knobs and press record on
the computer and it was just six of my
friends just [ __ ] talking for me so I
was pretty cool I think Mike and Jesse
and Hannibal remember if you were never
missed a money thing is huge like the
amount of effort and dedication that
that takes is kind of nuts well I don't
plan on stopping you guys there's no
reason to stop podcasting the computer
works the table is pretty sturdy I feel
good cannabis is gonna just keep getting
better and more illegal everywhere we go
so there's no need to stop very true
we're definitely gonna make it to 4:20
and then we're gonna make it to 500 from
there the moon then a thousand is the
goal after that right the weird number I
think it should be 701 is the goal
several two is the goals I just every
one of these is special Flint wants to
go one step at a time
I'm that's all I am time I like it
stick with us you guys this is gonna be
a good show there's gonna be a good
future for us
we got really rambley today but it's
been a fun 400th episode holy crap how
long do you think it's still America
legalized this weed
I don't think do you think we got 10
years how many states were left Mike
he's doing the math that is
guessing there's maybe six eight states
that don't have any laws in conflict
with the federal marijuana law so I'm
including CBD only states like Utah
leaving six or eight states that still
have a hundred percent all marijuana is
illegal including hemp so we're like
ninety percent of the way yeah that's
pretty good
we're I mean we're at the traditional
tipping point now there's thirty some
medical states that allow medical access
on one level or another for high THC
content cannabis there's another half
dozen CBD only states there's a couple
of you can't smoke it but she could have
it medically states there's eight or ten
recreational states now usually this is
the point with this many states in
conflict with federal law where the feds
go all [ __ ] alright fine we'll talk
about it and then we spend a couple of
years hashing out what the feds are
gonna end up doing in the House and the
Senate and then eventually something
lands on the President's desk saying the
feds are gonna do this so that the
states can go ahead and do this like
when we do this with alcohol when it
became legal again there were a number
of states that said the Volstead Act is
ridiculous the eighteenth Amendment
gotta go we're repealing prohibition
just here in Colorado and then the feds
were like well it's still illegal
federally there for a couple more years
until enough states had come online and
we've done this both ways like with
highway funding the states were like
well through or the feds were like we'll
throw you a bunch of money for highway
funding but you have to jack your
drinking age up and that's how they got
the drinking age to 21 across the
country I didn't know that
yep yeah yeah it's cool I mean I'm happy
that the drinking age is 21 because I'm
so anti alcohol that that's a good thing
Bryce I do like the idea of it falling
into line like this like the dominoes
are falling towards the end of this
prohibition in honestly there's a ton of
federal action right now there's the
federal cannabis caucus is a group of
senators that are all very Pro cannabis
and they've been around for two or three
years and they've been a pretty
unimportant non powerful group up until
this year and they've got a lot more
clout this year the federal regulator or
the federal legislation that's been
submitted so far this year is already
getting a lot more press and a lot more
attention more co-sponsors and that sort
of thing then we've seen traditionally
we've never had up a president is
uncommitted to a stated set of policies
that's pretty diplomatic way to say it
as we do right now so we don't really
know if Trump's gonna show up tomorrow
and be like make wheat legal if I were
gonna edit this how would you have said
that diplomatic statement how would I
have said that yes diplomatically yes
never had a [ __ ] [ __ ] like this in
office before okay just keep in mind I'm
not going to edit that I was just
curious what you would have said but
honestly there's you have no idea what
what he's gonna do from one day to the
next and he's under a ridiculous amount
of pressure and scrutiny right now
because like everyone involved in his
inauguration team is now in jail or on
their way there has pled guilty to
several felonies he's pretty cool so I
mean wouldn't gangster when you bang
people into a corner like that it's hard
to tell what they're gonna do and he
seems like the type of dude who likes to
say whatever it is to get you to stop
yelling at him and I have a feeling that
one of the crazy things he does when
he's really backed into a corner is just
like all right we're making weed legal
by Proclamation which isn't the thing
the president can do but
it doesn't stop the orange POTUS before
but if he does it we're all just gonna
go yeah well if he did something like
that immediately after then the members
of the House and the Senate that are
committed to marijuana law reform
would immediately dive on that and use
it as pressure to push actual
legislation that would change the law
forward
I still think States should be allowed
to not I mean I get that like I don't
maybe not recreational it should be the
state's choice because once we start
going national then it's like the nation
telling us what we're allowed the only
thing the feds would do with would be to
say the states can pick and choose from
themselves just for the sake of
conversation why do people have to be
sick they enjoy cannabis I guess I don't
think it's so much that I think it's the
state that's that's why we have States
is so that way we can write those things
in yes so if the majority of a state
says no we don't want that then that's
their prerogative I don't think we
should push anything on anybody and if
you want to come to Colorado I mean it's
full no I think most people are deserted
walls are already up so you guys are
[ __ ] out of luck
I'm sorry that's bull if you want to
move here now you have to convince new
people to leave yeah that's the rule but
you can come here but good luck finding
somewhere to [ __ ] Park or just parked
any parking spaces left in Colorado yeah
three years so let's say I want to just
keep that I like this conversation we
really got on a good roll here um so
let's just say that we do legalize
cannabis we create in my mind it'll be a
recreational thing they're not gonna
they're gonna go for if we go medical it
has to get too involved in the medical
system and it's not the way we're doing
medical cannabis is not the way that any
other medical program would work it's
not like that I hate to crush anybody's
idea of what a medical cannabis program
is if you think about the way medicine
works you have to go back and see your
so you go to get a cannabis card a
medical marijuana recommendation you go
see the doctor you give them some money
goes here's your card have a great day
any other medicine if
I went to the doctor and I said on my
back hurts he said cool we'll give you
some of these medicines to make your
back feel better I got to go back in 30
days and tell him how it worked if I've
got any recovery if I feel worse he's
gonna check my liver and kidneys if he's
a good doctor and make sure that
medicines not [ __ ] me up then he's
gonna have a treatment plan a medical
marijuana doctor goes oh you smoke weed
for your problems there's a card
he says crush the dreams it's the look I
mean even if we're just talking about
Colorado's system there are physicians
and patients doing exactly what you're
describing within our current system
it's just it's not mandated most of the
patients I just referenced are under the
age of 18 right it is much more
scrutinized if you're a minor well in
the other side of that coin is patients
aren't getting nearly what they do with
every other class of drug like there's a
number of things in cannabis that help
with countless medical ailments but
we're not refining or targeting or
studying most of these effects and so
we're just guessing and I've had to go
back I mean when I wasn't buying the
level of product i buy now but I
remember going back to the Spencer II
two or three times in a week playing
with different stuff before I had
learned enough about which strains
affect my symptoms the best what I'm
really looking for as far as cannabis
for medical affects I was I was born so
Chivas and wondering what my pain wasn't
any better now I know but like in an
ideal world when I go to my physician
and I say I've got pain and inflammation
the pains being caused by inflammation
in my neck it's pinching nerves what do
you have to help me
the doctor is gonna give me a pill with
what's taken and useful from the
cannabis plant in it that's focus
specifically on my problem same thing
for epilepsy cancer whatever and those
drugs are on the market now for a number
of reasons but to make up for that lack
of availability we've got the current
system and it's just not tenable if this
is legal coast to coast
okay No so in what I was getting at is
if we do go national illegal it's gonna
be recreational for the reason that Mike
and I stated that was a long way to stay
it but I agree yeah so now we've got a
recreational legal cannabis system in
Colorado
it took three to five years to get that
system figured out you know what I mean
it the medical so the medical system was
a train wreck when it started it was the
Wild West you could do whatever you
wanted for seven eight years when the
state refused to even look at it for
seven or eight years and so it just went
totally unregulated that's why Callie's
so [ __ ] now
that's why Oklahoma is awesome right now
also by the way so then we have the
medical market con we already had that
medical experience to build on but when
the recreational markets opened up it
was still a semi [ __ ] it was done
pretty well for who it wasn't what it
was but it was a semi [ __ ] when
the national system does come from the
day they say I'm gonna sign this paper
and then January 1st 2000 and whatever
we're gonna say 2020 just to be hopeful
January 1st 2020 cannabis is legal you
can open up a dispensary or recreational
dispensary for people 21 and over
anywhere in the United States of America
ready set go how long do you think it'll
take for that to actually be in place
because we know that people if he says
it in 2019 we're not gonna be ready in
2020 it takes a long time you got a
build rules area start setting up
regulations how long until we actually
have a system that works is that a three
year process is that five or ten years
it'll vary based state to state in
places like Colorado that I already have
a highly regulated system that's already
fully up and running it'll only take us
six months nine months to get all of our
paperwork changed over in our
accountants familiar with the new rules
and [ __ ] we're just gonna have little
procedural changes right a couple of
compliance things maybe another two
inspections to schedule now that the
feds gonna be real busy for a couple
weeks right but like we've already
figured out most of it okay
places like do you think will kind of be
the guideline do you think we qualify if
you were gonna say already
gold-standard okay well I worked with
another state like it's not unknown that
I do consulting for other states I've
got one state dude that they refused if
Colorado's done it like with him [ __ ]
we don't like it they like want to
reinvent the goddamn legalization wheel
and it is the most frustrating thing
ever there's a bunch of that out in the
world word my god if someone else has
done it you have to do it over it drove
me nuts when we were writing just the
marijuana rules here I called it the
committee to discuss reinventing the
wheel they like to meet every month and
at the end of the meeting they go well
[ __ ] boys round it is I guess yeah
that's exact
we're rolling the wheel in Colorado
we're ten years ahead of you guys and
you just don't want to play with us it's
really weird but uh especially when it
comes to cannabis you run into people
who are like but what about the
boogeyman yeah and it's like well we can
talk about it and we can make a rule
that prevents that but like it's in your
head you know that right we're making a
rule that people have to follow because
of nonsense in your head and they'll go
like yeah but it's important that's a
lot of the cannabis industry that's a
lot of them a lot of politics in general
we're just mainly focused on cannabis
I'm noticing that that is a lot of
politics in general so let's do it back
toward kind of where we were we're
getting this legalization nationally
Colorado is the golden standard we've
kind of set the rules people are gonna
follow our outline our guideline on how
to do the National legalization rollout
I've got a shitty idea on where a lot of
that cannabis is gonna come from that's
I think there would be some sort of a
national program something will come
into place where there's a regulation of
grows that it comes from somewhere
that's government regulated we'll talk
about that in the future so other states
we've got states like Oregon and
Washington they've got a pretty good
head start do you think they'll be
online with this national program within
just a year or so give or take if the if
your state's already gotten up and
running program I can't see too many
problems that it might have while it's
up and running that would cause any
money six months to already running bio
track or metric and I don't mean metric
like the measuring system I mean metric
the computer program system the
marijuana enforcement tracking and other
stuff system we all have to log into and
hate anybody using that I think there'll
be a little bit ahead of the
the only thing I'm thinking that's
really gonna slow people down is the
local rules and zoning [ __ ] can really
bogged down the process I'm in Colorado
took about three years to really hash
out the medical rules and that was after
five years of mumbling about we need to
do this then there was a good three
years of actual debate before the rules
got hammered out and then we had another
year and a half of debate for rec rules
I mean just a couple like a year and a
half after we finished the Med rules we
did recreational in most places decided
they wanted to completely reinvent the
wheel they didn't want to base anything
off of their existing medical rules it
was just a bizarre process but I think
most places now have gone through at
least some of that there's very few
places that are really going to be
starting from scratch the thing that's
gonna take the longest is when the feds
say we don't care anymore let go ahead
and let the states do what they want
there's gonna be a period of time where
each state goes well what do we want and
for the states that haven't moved on
this issue yet if they decide they want
to go with legalization then they're
gonna have to pick well what type of
legalization we want do we want youto
alcohol model where it's from state-run
stores that are staffed by off-duty cops
or we want the Colorado model where when
you show up here with your duffel bag we
give you two ounces a weeded average
like which model do you want to go with
each state maybe another year and a half
while the hammer that [ __ ] out and then
another year while they hammer out
zoning rules so if Trump said let's do
it tomorrow you're looking at three
years before your your Salt Lake City is
driving past the dispensary
all right that Jeb we were trying to
convince people earlier not to drive to
Colorado to move here and you just said
that everybody gets two months a break
please don't encourage them okay that
also costs $8,000 you know unfortunately
there's only only about 300 bucks if you
want to Welch's and the weed and the
Davidge the cheap studio apartment is
or any 1250 a month yeah it's gonna get
expensive that will get expensive beyond
everyone being able to smoke
recreationally I think that it's gonna
people that are in jail for this [ __ ] is
[ __ ] ridiculous
so like that will be the best thing that
like pushing nonviolent cannabis
offenses or this is just expunge those
yeah you just like oh you got hemmed up
for growing a couple of times you know
three strikes and you got screwed and
it's like if you weren't stealing
electricity and working with some sort
of weird crazy distribution system yeah
make sense there's a lot of like when
you look at the people that are only in
jail for specific marijuana rule
violations you can get that number
pretty small because most of the people
that actually end up in real trouble
when the cop busts you for weed they
bust you for weed and right
and so it's while you were on parole or
probation or stealing power or driving
wall whatever and so just when the feds
changed the rule if we decide to go
ahead and let go anyone who's just got
marijuana on their their record it's not
going to do that much good what really
helps is the expunging getting all of
that off you off your record like San
Francisco's talking about doing now
there's a couple of places that are
already doing it I mean that's just huge
for people to get that the scarlet
letter off your back right trying to
apply for jobs and [ __ ] that's where I
was headed a lot of the cannabis
industry jobs if you've been in trouble
for growing cannabis in the past you
cannot be in the industry and that
leaves honestly who's more og than the
people that got caught growing weed in
1985 like they probably know more about
herb than most people right and now they
can't even work in the Grove because
they got caught I don't know about the
rule the statute of limitations but
people that have been caught for drug
offenses and cannabis offenses are
banned from the cannabis industry and
they probably know a lot so we're
blocking people that way so like mike
says cleaning up that record we'll be
able to let those people back into the
industry right now in Colorado those
people are diving on hemp jobs because
it's just outside of the industry but
your record doesn't matter there's no
meed when it comes to him absolutely I
know a guy who actually is in that exact
situation he's a pretty good hemp grower
he's a cannabis grower can't be in the
industry runs a giant hemp farm the
cannabis Facebook page I run the biggest
story I shared last week Mike what's
your cannabis Facebook page called low
for sensible cannabis laws I wasn't
going to take that opportunity but there
you go
the biggest story I shared last week the
one that got the most attention was
about a CBD processing plant it's gonna
be hiring like 150 to 200 people and
half of the interest was like oh [ __ ] I
don't need a badge for this and that's
huge for people that industry is blown
up right now getting a badge is super
easy if you don't have those though so
if you're dragging your feet on that
it's like you print out a 12-page thing
you paid 75 bucks you go to Colorado
Springs you've done and that's it yep
take your finger I'm sorry guys I forgot
this is global marijuana Colorado so
it's pretty easy so look it up if you if
you're interested in this industry it's
blowing up right now yes it is so let us
get in now that's that's how I feel
about it you know you don't have to
smoke but you can work in these places
and you know you probably end up smoking
because you're gonna be around it a lot
but there are plenty of non-consumers in
the cannabis industry I'm sure lots of
them there's money-hungry of people that
don't smoke weed
so people need jobs for sure we'll need
jobs and just there are people that work
at the cereal store that don't eat
cereal you know what I mean there's
people that work at the chip factory
they probably don't like Doritos I'm
gonna be pissed if I find out of vegans
in my state all right with that
vegan sin hate at 15 yeah I've got two
final bullet points that I want to cover
there's no way to segue into these just
random things that I had written down as
we start wrapping up the show here I'm
just making sure that okay cool
one thing I want to talk about is I was
at a dispensary recently and a young man
came it was cold outside and a young man
came running from his vehicle into the
dispensary and he opened the door he
walked any shook his jacket
he sat down and he patiently waited in
line like anybody else should another
person in the dispensary made a comment
to me about how he was cheating the
medical marijuana system because he
looks like he's well bodied and able to
run into the dispensary Mike is shaking
his head he already sees the session so
me - I wanted to politely tell people
you don't have the right to decide who
has a medical problem that validates
them using cannabis to improve the
quality of their life that young man has
a mental condition the cannabis prevents
him from hurting himself on a daily
basis I know that person he's a friend
of mine so it kind of pissed me off that
that person said that about him that
person has come a long way in their life
and cannabis did it without cannabis
that dude would have killed himself to
be quite frank he would have killed
himself a long time ago I've been his
blood tender at multiple dispensaries he
used to come to a dispensary Mike and I
ran in 2008 so when that guy said that
about him I was like yes yes I was like
good I wanted to yell at that guy be
like you're [ __ ] wrong dude just
because you have a cane and you walk
with the limp
doesn't make you any more of a valid
patient than that young man he can run
he can lift weight but his struggle is
internal and you can't see that little
even doctors can't glance at you and
diagnose you right and you see this
outside of the cannabis industry too
like I just saw something on Facebook
about this happening to just a woman
with a disability that's not obviously
obvious when you glance at her walking
across the parking lot but it drives me
nuts in the cannabis space because
there's a million reasons that people
take cannabis medically and like I'm in
physical pain a lot say nine days out of
ten my pains at a fiver better never or
almost never does that affect my walking
people that know you I know you I see
you on a regular basis I can see it yeah
but people don't like know you'll see me
walking in the store I'm just another
giant guy walking store your hips move
differently when you're hurting
you're a terrific guy walk next to you
on a regular basis you know yeah but you
can't see it the first person I ever
helped get their medical marijuana card
of the person
credit with really starting me on my
cannabis advocacy they have MS and some
days you can be like all [ __ ] dude
what's wrong with him like at a distance
you can tell in other days you can't
tell at all he's young he's healthy he's
fit it doesn't make sense at a glance
why he's got my handicap placard in his
windshield the last time me and him went
to a concert at Red Rocks he felt super
guilty when I was like dude you're
driving and he was like what do you mean
and I was like [ __ ] handicapped
placard dude we're going all the way to
the top for parking in a good spot we're
walking 15 feet to our seats like if we
try to do this Red Rocks the other way
you're not gonna make it through the
first act you'll be too tired to keep
your head up and I'll have to call
people to help me get you back to the
car bro and he felt guilty about using
it for himself and then halfway through
the show he was like [ __ ] I'm so glad
you suggested this I'd be dead if we
tried to walk here in the seat but
people that watch this park and watch us
get out of the car and watch us walk to
our seats I'm sure there were a number
of people that were like [ __ ]
cheaters right I don't see that I see
because you're a compassionate person
and not an [ __ ] but there are some
[ __ ] out there that saw that young
man that who's a veteran who's been to
war and [ __ ] is a serviceman and has
MS they [ __ ] watch that dude walk and
couldn't see his lamp or see his
struggle and they judged him so that's
what I'm talking about you can't see it
my claim to fame I've got blown out
knees as part of why I've got a
marijuana card i I hit my knees on the
dash and a car accident also I've got
some stomach problems you don't hear a
lot about my stomach problems I don't
talk about it a lot
nobody cares nobody wants to hear me cry
that my tummy hurts but that is a lot of
my medical marijuana condition it helps
with my stomach you can't see that can
you can you tell right now by looking at
me how does my stomach feel do I need to
fart am i hungry
you have no idea yeah sometimes it hurts
like someone's putting an ice pick in
just to the my right side of my belly
button it feels like they're putting an
ice pick in there and then kind of
pointing it up a little bit and then
after it really starts to hurt it goes
straight down and I've had a camera in
my throat I've had a camera in my butt
there's no reason why but if I consume
enough cannabis
Stilley that doesn't happen that's
awesome yeah yeah it sucks right let's
do that we've got a cure that we found a
patch for it that it doesn't hurt so
yeah pretty easy cure too it's not like
[ __ ] radiation for cancer and the
side effects from niacin is right but my
point is you guys don't and I'm sure
that nobody listening to the show here
is going to judge anybody based on their
appearance based on their cannabis needs
but sure that what the world don't let
people judge people just because that
young man ran into the store edgeless
that dude's got issues that you can't
see he's he deal I don't know if I
should talk about that dudes things he
may hear this but yeah he's got
struggles and we don't need to [ __ ]
judge him and that's probably even worse
if that's why he [ __ ] struggles in
the world because people are judging him
okay we're just gonna right now I saw
something funny in the news this is
sadly funny
this is you were just talking about the
warehouse that was hiring in I visioned
a warehouse and it brought me back to
this news subject there are a few taco
spots in Colorado Springs where I love
to eat dude I love to eat it all these
little crappy taco spots they've got a
burrito supreme and some french fries
with cheese and guacamole I am an dude
it'll be nice and late I'll be coming
home from a show and that's the perfect
spot to stop and get some snacks um a
few weeks ago one of the taco places was
closed I was like well I'm just gonna
ditch her over to the other taco place
of the same name just a few blocks away
and that taco place was closed as well I
was like what's going on with all my
taco shops and I mentioned it to a
friend and like dude you didn't know
that all the taco shops by that name got
shut down by the local law enforcement
because they were all laundering money
for a drug cartel and I was like that's
why they made the best burritos on the
planet for like six bucks do you like I
want a burrito in like six dollars no
tax for just six dollars you're like
that's weird already like six dollars
and you'd get a burrito that was the
size of like a watermelon you'd be like
that's a burrito and I couldn't eat the
whole I'm a big dude and I couldn't
finish that burrito and I get the
burrito with french fries cheese and
guacamole it was like 13 bucks for all
of it you can get a horchata with it for
15 bucks are you set up they were a
straight up front for a drug cartel just
cleaning up all the money today bro too
the news you're smiling so I think you
saw the same article it's so funny there
was a giant warehouse near them that
just recently got raided because they
were not ordering anything that they
were claiming they were ordering they
were writing off tax order saying we
ordered like this many tortillas and
this much food for this many restaurants
they're connected you're talking about
the distribution warehouse for these
restaurants yeah and I just got around a
bus in the warehouse yeah yeah they were
only delivering to these taco shops but
they were acting like they were
supplying all of Colorado Springs with
food for preparation but it was just one
place so they were just so they this
whole bus stems from a dude paying for a
car that cost more than $10,000 in cash
up in Wyoming like three years ago he
you know that if you deposit or spend
more than ten thousand of cash they have
filed paperwork they filed the paperwork
and they looked at the dude they were
like so he's an illegal alien who lives
in the next state over curious why he
drove to Wyoming I mean everyone's
favorite destination they had a blue one
there right Chevy Tahoe but the story
gets funnier funny when they first
busted the taco shops there were a bunch
of poyo sir Manos jokes yeah and now
that they've busted the distribution
chain every psycho [ __ ] dude offense
gilliam now there's rumor that they have
attached it to El Chapo so I was eating
El Chapo veggie burritos ooh yeah yeah
thanks El Chapo
yeah I loved that the El Chapo trial
took place this is a weird edge during
the wall debate because every day in the
press you would hear reasons for and
against building a large physical
barrier on our southern border and then
at night after the trial adjourned for
the day you would read how major drug
cartels shipped drugs and never ever did
these two conversations meet I'll let
listeners will research their various
ideas and things involve wall won't stop
that's [ __ ] there's a catapult
yeah the catapults [ __ ] awesome
there's a drone the wall doesn't stop it
no except your ability to own the land
that's underneath it's like a speed bump
that's all it really is for a cartel
smell
it's not even that it's just a thing
like they're sending [ __ ] cocaine
here by the ton and submarines yeah
they're in the entire train is drugs the
only thing that's not drugs is the
[ __ ] wheels in the engine in no we
think the wall is gonna stop the train
the airplane the submarine no it's the
semis bringing it in to that just not
all of them get checked as well as other
ones like why tape one kilo to a person
when you could tape a million kilos to
one train yeah so it's a pretty scary
proposition there well now that you are
can't make any money off importing
cannabis you got to up your ante do you
think that's what happened do you think
that that's why disciple I should know
things got worse in Mexico or not I
don't know things have gotten stranger
the cannabis farmers are still farming
drugs for the most part they're just not
farming cannabis anymore in the
traffickers are still trafficking drugs
they're just not traffic in cannabis
anymore right and that has had some
weird repercussions all the people that
used to make money on weed that are
making money on weeding now are doing
other various things to make money and
like that was one of the weird negative
consequences that we kind of knew to
expect but didn't like to talk about is
look I bring this up a lot online but
the best guess for what the black market
was coast to coast before legalization
is thirty to sixty billion dollars a
year just us domestic and that's
Americans by thirty to sixty billion
dollars for the cannabis each year you
know all of that underground you got to
imagine just how like if you imagine a
root system how far those [ __ ] roots
go to do thirty five to sixty billion
dollars a year to put that in something
that you can picture cosmetics or thirty
five billion a year so like all shampoo
and eyeliner and [ __ ] is 35 billion what
is Apple worth
I was just Carrie I think somebody in
the room would know that off the top can
you compare that all Google if when you
guys keep talking I'll find a
a company that is worth thirty five
billion dollars Justin that's how I got
the cosmetics is because I looked up
like US domestic sales 35 billion or
whatever kind of imagined cosmetics with
as much [ __ ] is my wife and kids by
well think of all the different stores
that you interact with on a monthly
basis say that sell cosmetics in one
form another from the gas station that
sells just blistex to the Sallie Mae
yeah Sally's that sells all that
specialty hair dye [ __ ] like all
different levels the manufacturing
warehouse is the distribution trucks and
as much as all of that is like almost
it's all underground weighed minimum of
underground wheat and that's the minimum
almost you stepped thirty to sixty yes
so I mean we might not expect sixty but
we could probably say forty five yep
it's forty five billion dollars
stretches way out apples worth a
trillion that's not they're twelve zeros
in that I think I saw I already went
past it cuz it blew my mind I didn't
want to focus too much I'm looking to
see what Netflix is worth now has a lot
of zeros 1200 my bank account too
they're on the wrong end of the ones
though yeah yeah great when when we
moved this market into the legal market
we a lot of places specifically excluded
people that had gotten in trouble or
were overly involved previously and so
all those people got [ __ ] out of a job
and it did some weird [ __ ] guy was
looking at arrest numbers the other day
in Colorado cannabis arrests are down
like 6500 a year but the number of
people we arrest each year has gone up
now some of that's the cop having free
time now but some of that's other [ __ ]
too right I'm not saying weed cause
crime to go up but these are things
so uh this is a ramble cast I've kind of
wondered hoping helmet if no more the
helmet we didn't make it but the the
lack of the black market having the
money of we'd yeah I get you no wait a
step up your game now huh I gotta go I
gotta go make my fifty bucks because my
family's hungry well what do I do
man go and steal something from Sears
and it got weird cuz people
automatically assume like well the weed
dealer just sells coke now and it's like
well okay they could switch which drug
they sell but there are an equal number
of consumers of any other drug compared
to cannabis right look unless this
mythical person opened a liquor store
something attached to this I kind of
want to segue off of that because I've
had this question for a little while do
you think now that herb cannabis is
legal and kind of just out in the open
it's just like drinking a beer in a lot
of places nobody cares anymore if you're
in Colorado and you smell weed you don't
even hesitate anymore
and a lot of places when you smell weed
you gotta go someone smoked and some
reefer playing Colorado it's just what
it [ __ ] smells like now yeah do you
think you smell what like the smells
like do you think that that has made
cannabis less desirable for the rebel
kids and now they're going straight for
something different because back in the
day it was kind of it was no there was
this different feeling of like him
[ __ ] smoking a bowl on Drive and I
totally shouldn't be doing this and now
it's just I still shouldn't be doing
that don't smoke a bowl okay smoking a
joint well I'm walking down the mountain
that's that sounds amazing let's do that
okay with the dog and a pretty lady I'm
just responsible lady it definitely was
a rite of passage when we were younger
yeah there's a thing going around now
that's like in the 80s it was beer in
the 90s and the 2000s it was weed and
now it's getting vaccinated
it definitely wasn't especially when we
were teenagers like the first was did
you steal a beer from your parents yet
then it was you snuck a cigarette from
somebody yet
and then it was have you found weed yet
yep and I don't know about you guys but
like my first weed was literally [ __ ]
thrown at me in seventh grade while I
was at school in the hallway like I was
sitting there and was pelted in the
chest with a bag of weed that literally
[ __ ] happened Mike that's a story we
were gonna have to have in full detail
here on this podcast if not tonight in
the very near future but like I didn't
even have to seek out that rite of
passage it was just sort of like I woke
up in line for the roller coaster yeah
it's like you're just standing somewhere
and your friends are smoking a joint
somewhere like we'd come from like are
you gonna hit this yeah what are you
guys but it it definitely wasn't right
of passage and that's going away slower
and slower that's one of the compare and
contrast with the Netherlands that
people have brought up a lot is they
have far less teenage and young adult
drug use period and cannabis use even
though they have stores that sell
cannabis to 18 year olds and it's
because it's not that interesting how
long do you think till walmart has
cannabis currently at Walmart you can't
buy cannabis cannabis but you can buy a
puff coke peak which is a vaporizer for
smoking cannabis concentrates you can
currently by a volcano vaporizer which
is just the Walmart online though yeah
it's at the Walmart online store but you
can find a puff coke peak and a volcano
vaporizer you can find an oil slick pad
you can get dab tools there in the last
time I saw them they were in the impulse
section at the checkout line did the
funniest thing is they're right next to
the Magic the Gathering cards so it's
gonna go home and play some Magic the
Gathering it takes dad know your
consumer that's the truth I'll play the
magic the gathering but no dabs please
okay I know I'm just asking like is it
gonna be immediately after we legalize
it as like nationally like it may be
like all right these will be on the
shelves in like months there's that
first group of people that has to go
it's vegan that mean ya know what I mean
but like the generation that's just a
year or two younger than that guy they
don't like it's no longer a brass ring
for them to wear at all it's just not
being the dumb that older people do I
feel Walmart maybe a little too
connected they have their roots or too
deep there are there may be a little
religious or a little
turkey or a little to goody-two-shoes to
actually go booth perfect that's my
point
they're not for the can they may be they
may lose more business by selling
cannabis yep but then how many people
are they going to lose if they say we
support cannabis they're one of the
largest they don't need to change
anything
honestly the Walmarts face the just
because we're talking about Walmart this
has come up a million times with Walmart
and they just stare the world down and
go [ __ ] you it's cheaper here like when
do you remember one that everybody was
fired up because Walmart puts all the
mom-and-pop people out of business there
yeah everybody cared for a while and
then it was cheaper Walmart's yeah until
they didn't want to go to Target Best
Buy King Soopers and Barnes &amp; Noble on
one trip they went to Best Buy and
everything there as long as you can
avoid the people out front trying to get
your signature for some random [ __ ]
every week you're just fine I really
don't think we'll see Canada's sold at
Walmart or the gas station or anything
like that for at least the next 15 20
years and who wants to buy that go to a
dispensary go to over to apothecary and
get some good [ __ ] yeah now but I mean
it's coming I mean I it's it's just like
alcohol they didn't have that in the
thirties they didn't have it in stores
and I get that there was already like a
way to get it and we love bars and all
this stuff so when it finally becomes
legal there will be maybe specialty
shops like the smoke shops you know
maybe it'll be like liquor stores you
know the same thing but they do sell
liquor at like Sam's Club has we're
definitely headed to a place in not so
distant future where you can get really
mediocre marijuana products it just a
convenience store we're definitely
headed that direction I think it's
inevitable
you can already buy CBD hemp flour at
very many head shops so yeah and I see
it getting into Walmart because Walmart
cares about their shareholders and as
soon as the shareholders see oh [ __ ]
we're gonna make all sorts of money
that's I mean that's all it is it's just
an organization that size it would just
be a small side line item but like they
carry all kinds of [ __ ] they only make a
few percentage points on and it's all
the search small percentages all those
small percentages add up to a big
do big percentage my last bullet point
that I've got written down here just
part of what we were talking about
earlier I feel like I can see a
difference in this town in our town of
Pueblo just in the few years that
cannabis has been here we've got some of
the world's if not some of the country's
largest if not the world's largest legal
cannabis production indoor and outdoor
here in Pueblo Colorado people like to
do the shits on people back to work that
yes and you can see it in our community
we have I used to complain about the
food I still complain about the food
options we were getting more better
restaurants here we're getting some good
food options here and I think that a lot
of the cannabis money is bringing that
here more people are coming here with a
more open mindset more money is coming
here more educated type of ideal is
coming here this used to be known as
being kind of a steel mill town where
you can come get your ass kicked and
drink a lot of beer absolutely it was it
was still very much a steel town but we
hadn't had a thriving steel industry for
thirty years at that point right
oh the me the steel mill is still where
most of the people a lot of people have
some roots that's why a lot of the
people are here is that steel mill and
that steel mill branches out to several
other companies and I think this guy
right it's probably worked for several
of them yeah I've worked for a couple of
places that worked for the steel mill
itself and then I worked for the place
that they were supplying right so yeah
so that mill does a lot of stuff here
it's still got this town kind of had
that mentality its hard-working let's
get your hands dirty 20 business of them
didn't go to the bar right after work
and get shit-faced and then get in a
fight and then go right back to work
tomorrow like nothing [ __ ] happened
but I see that the cannabis is making
its changing it it's a little gentler or
getting a little more culture we've got
an Art Walk now we're getting a little
where I see a lot of evolution and I
think a lot of the money a lot of the
intellect is coming from this cannabis
evolution it's bringing a great mindset
it's making people want to work together
people that would have never been in the
same industry or working together now
people like everybody wants to work in
the cannabis industry so you got the guy
in the Grateful Dead shirt next WI and
the Tupac shirt next to the guy with the
Juggalo shirt all hanging out in the
trim room I'll listen into the Joe Rogan
podcast I'll listen him to grow from
your heart all having a good time
I just I see a difference in this town
it's more peaceful we've got some money
now we've got some food options the
potholes aren't as bad I know that
sounds crazy but they're filling
potholes in this Pueblo was smart we the
people that were in charge of allocating
that money knew that they couldn't fund
long term repeat [ __ ] with it like you
can't hire cops because you're gonna
need cops this year next year in two
years and five years down the road and
anything that reoccurs like that you
can't count on cannabis because you
never know if the next presence
president is gonna go nuts and enforce a
closure or something which is why I like
teachers aren't getting funded with this
[ __ ] either
but knowing that they decided to fund
improvement projects the people like you
and me would actually care about so like
a couple of schools got sidewalks where
they didn't have [ __ ] sidewalks
leading to the school a couple of kids
got scholarships from kids are a couple
of thousand kids in Pueblo now have
received $2,000 a year from our cannabis
taxes so that they can go to college or
to help pay for that college it's not
like $2,000 is gonna cover all the
tuition but it helps a lot looks it's
there's some weird restrictions on it
but like if you kid and you wanna go to
either the local community college or
CSU P it's two grand no questions asked
no GPA required it's just because you're
a local person this money's available
and I know a several students that have
used that money to stay in school but
these projects actually help beat the
road repairs help the the little
improvements around the community help
if you look at the list of projects like
there were some golf
improved golf area golf course
improvements I don't know why we're
course left my head for a minute cuz you
don't ever go to it but yeah I never use
that and so I was a Gladstone why are we
doing that and then I kind of looked at
the demographics and I wanna coop
Webelos got a pretty heavy older
population and they all love that [ __ ]
the golf course is so always packed when
it's warm yeah like by all means make
that five percent better so that they're
five percent happy
let's go ahead that shit's helping it
all over Colorado
we're getting better entertainment here
as well because of it I think we're
since we have a different demographic
here a little more money brings a little
more different demographic which brings
more options for entertainment we could
spend a couple more bucks on a better
band to come a better comedian to come
and it's happening so I see a difference
I usually hear people that bring up this
specific thing in a negative way but I
really like it like I grew up in
Colorado and whenever we would travel
before legalization when say people
would say hey where're you from if you
said Colorado they'd go oh do you ski
yeah and I don't or do you because it
hurt me a lot when I was little so I was
never a fan and it was always like
annoying that people would ask me if I
did this thing that my state was known
for that I hated and I'm happy when
people like oh the legal we'd place and
I'm like yeah feel free to ask questions
I'll tell y'all about it yeah but I know
a number of people that are annoyed with
that change but I like it it's beautiful
Clayton you look like you got something
you want to say it but you're not sure
if you should know it was what a podcast
is about yeah I've never ridden a horse
but Colorado was known for horses that
was I don't know so as piggy whoreson
piggy whoreson or peterson oh man I've
been piggy horse the name of this
episode hey ladies and gentlemen it has
been a really fun time hanging out with
you guys for episode 400 Mike it's been
a great time thanks for coming yeah
Clint thanks for coming dude it's been a
great time thank you so much dude
congratulations I do thank you I do
appreciate that that's so awesome
yeah we told everybody what time it was
so they know that it's approaching one
o'clock because my birthday was 55
minutes ago so we're gonna start
wrapping up this podcast do you
gentlemen have any things that you would
like to say while you were on microphone
here at the end of the show right before
we say goodbye to everybody
nope be nice to each other
they have be excellent to each other see
there we go party on Wayne party on
Garth thank you buddy I was gonna leave
you hanging I saw you look into my
clique come on dude come on dude I
thought you guys were friends all right
ladies and gentlemen I'll to thank these
gentlemen once again for coming and
hanging out I want to thank you guys for
being
a great audience you are a loyal
audience it really appreciates still
yeah especially since I just turned your
mic down and they barely heard you say
that Mike said you [ __ ] rock if
you're still listening thus far there
will be some editing so this will be a
little bit easier to listen to than
you're assuming make sure you follow
Mike on Facebook it is Pueblo for
sensible cannabis laws you can also find
him at Nemo Punk 15 on the tweeter Clint
would rather remain anonymous he doesn't
post you don't want to see pictures of
his [ __ ] cat anyway you can find the
show on the social media on Facebook
search for the girl from your heart a
podcast on Twitter it's at G fyh podcast
if you'd like to follow me on Twitter
it is a trois to Jeff 420 I encourage
you to follow my Instagram feed it is
Irie underscore genetics on instagram
check out my fine cannabis photography
check out my live videos I think you
will enjoy it if you've got something
you'd like to say and you're not into
all of that social media nonsense you
can reach me through email my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I do love that type of
interaction don't forget there is a
patreon campaign if you feel that this
podcast was educational informative or
entertaining and you would like to make
a financial contribution to the show you
can do so by going to patreon.com slash
grow from your heart all the information
you need to become a patron will be
right there on the screen once again I
want to give you huge thank you to
everybody who is contributed to the
patreon campaign I think you can hear my
voice starting to burn out so we're
gonna wrap up the show make sure you
guys support my friends at organ elite
seeds I wanna give a huge shout out to
my friend Brody Stevens and until next
time take a phat dad and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]