[Music]
welcome back podcast world it's time for
episode 402 of the quote from your heart
podcast this episode of the show is
brought to you by the hella dank seed
company if you need new seeds for your
garden I highly recommend the hella dank
seed company and you can find them at
www.sedar.com I talking about what I'm
smoking today I've been taking dabs of
vanilla cookies batter from our friends
at apothecary farms the label says this
concentrate has 79 percent THC and 94.4%
total cannabinoids this concentrate
tastes delicious and to tell you the
truth I am nicely medicated from this
concentrate it has got a nice really
heavy buzz that's got me nice and mellow
I am just chilling out I really like
this concentrate this episode is going
to be another compilation of grow
lessons this is going to be a repost of
episodes 359 360 360 - 360 360 4 and 365
so ladies and gentlemen with no further
ado let's jump right back in to a long
group of grow lessons
[Music]
welcome to the show podcast world it's
time for episode 359 of the girl from
your heart podcast this episode of the
show is brought to you by the hella dank
seed company if you need new seeds for
your garden I highly recommend the hella
de exede company and you can find them
at dank seed dot store I like to start
the podcast off by letting you know what
I'm smoking today I'm taking dabs of
bubble Jack full-spectrum extract from
fuego extracts I really love the flavor
and aroma of this concentrate it smells
like Jack Herer
bubblegum and when you dab it it leaves
a sweet soft bubblegum flavor on your
mouth that just lingers for a long time
and the high goes straight to the head I
really like this concentrate one thing I
am going to complain about is the
packaging these little plastic jars get
stuck the Fuego jars get stuck every
time I buy them it is a pain in the ass
then they're putting the jar inside of a
black bag with a drawstring kind of like
a little tiny Crown Royal bag the jar
has stickers on it to indicate the brand
and the strain the little black bag has
a bunch of fibers that come off of it so
now I've got a jar that looks like it's
got long black hairs hanging off of it I
don't like that at all it's unappealing
there's no need for that bag it's a
waste of material it's another step in
the packaging process and it is
completely useless then after they've
put the jar in that bag they place that
bag inside of another box which slides
into another box which is all
beautifully decorated and well labeled
it is a lot of packaging I'm sure most
of that packaging is because of the
Colorado compliance laws but I would
like to see less packaging from the
concentrate companies I feel like I
throw away a lot of packaging alright
you guys so let me be completely clear
the concentrate is amazing the bubble
Jack full-spectrum extract tastes great
the highest perfect my only complaint is
with the packaging and that is not just
Wego I just happened to be using fuego
products today when I'm talking about
this a lot of the companies are using
too much packaging and I understand it's
Colorado law we've got to be compliant I
get it I just wish there was a way we
could do this more efficiently and more
environmentally friendly all right guys
let's move forward with the show this is
going to be another grow lesson this is
going to be the seventh lesson in a long
series of grow lessons in this episode I
want to talk about planning your
integrated pest management everybody
likes to think they will not get bugs
everybody likes to say that's not gonna
happen to me but guess what it will and
the only way you can prevent it is by
starting an integrated pest management
system while you're planning your grow
while you're setting up your grow and
having it in place before you ever
introduce plants into your grow
environment now let's talk a little bit
about integrated pest management what is
the goal of our integrated pest
management
system the ultimate goal is to keep our
garden free of pests and bugs a good
spot to start would be knowing how to
identify the bugs we are looking for and
the damage that they will leave now what
insects are we going to find in our
cannabis garden the most common problem
we are going to find is spider mites
spider mites are very small you are very
unlikely to see a spider mite unless you
flip over a leaf and look at it and do
some investigating what you will see is
spider mite damage if you've got a leaf
it looks like somebody has just been
taking a needle and poking little dots
in that leaf or something's been
sticking its fangs in there and sucking
the juice out of those little spots that
is spider mite damage learn how to
identify spider mite damage if you see
damage on a leaf
pull that leaf off flip it upside down
and look at the underside of the leaf
along the main vein of that leaf tucked
right up against that vein you will see
spider mites and spider mite eggs those
little dots you see those are spider
mite eggs those little itty bitty dots
that are moving those are the spider
mites they are there it is time to treat
for them depending on what cycle of
growth you are in treating for spider
mites can be very easy it can also be
kind of a pain in the ass later in Flour
if you learn how to identify spider my
damage and learn how to identify spider
mites finding the problem early and
correcting it should not be a problem
before it gets out of hand another pest
that is very common in the garden and
very easy to identify because of its
damage is a thrip a lot like a spider
mite the thrips like to suck the juice
out of our plants after they do this
they leave a little trail of gooey stuff
called honeydew on the leaves if you see
a little trail of silvery shiny shimmery
stuff left on your lower leaves you
probably have thrips if we become
familiar with what thrift damage looks
like we can identify the problem sooner
and that makes it really easy to
eradicate our problems so my point is
knowing what to look for will be
seriously advantageous when it comes to
treating for a pest problem
another common pest you're going to run
into is the white fly what does a white
fly look like it looks like a little
piece of ash just flying around just a
little white fly it'll start off with
two of them then the next day you'll see
200 of them then the next day you'll see
2,000 of
them white flies multiply rapidly but
once you see them they are easy to get
rid of if you understand how to combat
them so the very first step of an
integrated pest management system is
learning to identify the damage caused
by common garden pests once we know how
to identify the problems then we can
identify the pest then we can decide on
the course of action to treat that
problem also it is very important to
treat for the correct pest some
pesticides will work on a broad spectrum
of pests but if you are using specific
pesticides or if you're using specific
predatory pests you do need to use the
correct method of attack in today's
market we can't afford to spend money on
a product that does not specifically
attack our problem and also we can't
spend time applying a product or
releasing predators that are not going
to get in there and eradicate our
problems so learn how to identify the
signs then identify the actual pests
then we can dial in an attack to
eradicate our problem now let's talk
about a few ways we can prepare our grow
and prevent pests from entering our new
garden cleanliness is a huge factor when
it comes to keeping bugs out of our
garden
everything that goes in that garden is
taken in there by you you travel in and
out of there you take things in and out
it is your responsibility to control
what goes in and out of that grow one
way to prevent contaminating your garden
is to have a dedicated garden clothes
don't come from a hike don't come from
the gross store don't come from work
don't go from wherever you are into your
grow room have specific garden clothes
change your clothes change your shoes
change your hat
don't take your daily clothing into your
grow room who knows what's on you maybe
you've been petting a dog maybe the dog
was outside leaning against the tree
maybe that tree had a fits a dog came in
rubbed up against your leg you and the
dogs spent a minute together scratching
on each other then he went to the grow
you just took those aphids from the tree
to the dog into your garden tried to
prevent that sort of thing be very
careful
I've got dreadlocks down to my knees I
wrap my dreadlocks up in a specific hat
before I go into any grown
if you've got dreadlocks or long hair I
suggest you put it in a hat of some sort
maybe a hairnet whatever it takes my
hair would not fit in a hairnet
I wrap my dreads in a big bun on top of
my head I wrap that in a piece of
material that wraps real tight then I
slide a dreadlock hat over that so I'm
double wrapped nothing will get in
nothing will get out
I won't transfer any problems from grow
to grow or room-to-room so if you've got
dreadlocks or long hair I highly
recommend you keep it wrapped up maybe
in a hairnet or something similar
maybe a dread hat just where it's
contained in there and not exposed that
way you can prevent moving spider mites
around through your hair and some of you
guys with the big beards you may want to
consider a beard net also not just to
prevent the bugs from getting into our
hair but also to prevent our hair from
sticking to the buds nobody wants to buy
a bud with a big hair in it so change
your clothes keep your hair tied up and
then let's get back to that dog I was
talking about I don't recommend having
pets in the grow room I see a lot of
pictures of people with their dog or
their cat in the grow room talking about
it's their their guard dog or their
mascot that's cool if you want to do
that but I don't recommend it like I
said earlier your dog or your cat goes
outside it rolls around in the dirt it
rolls around in the bushes
it just goes everywhere who knows what
it's getting into then you let it walk
right into the garden maybe it walked up
right up against a plant that was
covered in spider mites and you had no
idea
now that dog is in your garden rubbing
up against your plants guess what free
spider mites for everybody I don't
recommend having a pet in the grow if
you insist
do your thing that is your grow but in
my opinion that is a huge risk for
bringing bugs into your garden another
thing I would recommend is that if
you've got an outdoor grow and an indoor
grow don't bring your tools from that
outdoor grow into your indoor grow
environment you may be bringing problems
and sometimes I know I sound like I
might just be paranoid but it's better
to be paranoid than to make stupid
mistakes now as long as you're changing
your clothes you're keeping your hair
clean you're keeping your shoes and your
equipment clean and you're not letting
your dog or your friends in your grow
room there shouldn't be a way for any
pests to get into this grow you may have
some cracks in the walls there may be
gaps in your building that's always
gonna happen but we're not going to drag
them in there on our own if they find a
way in we will deal with that now once
you're certain you've minimized the
opportunity for pest to entry or grow
through your own doing we need to think
about treating the clones that come into
our grow before they are introduced to
population wherever your clones come
from if it's your best friend if it's a
dispensary if it's some guy on Instagram
wherever they came from treat them as if
they are contaminated with some sort of
pest issue never introduce clones into
your general population without some
sort of quarantine period if your room
is brand new you don't have bugs
why take plants in there that have bugs
on them we can treat those plants before
we take them into our main grow room if
you've got a room with plants going why
would you want to introduce a plant with
bugs on it into that room to contaminate
the entire grow if you get clones from
anybody isolate them quarantine them
investigate them get a jeweler's loupe
and go over the leaves and see if you
can see any signs of bugs on the top or
bottoms of those leaves if you see any
pests now you have to decide if you want
to keep that clone or if you're going to
treat it and try to eradicate that
problem before you introduce that clone
to your general population if I got a
clone that had bugs on it I would
probably throw it away unless it were
some super elite cut that I could never
get again why start with problems
I wouldn't even allow that to make it
past quarantine if it looked like it was
clean I would still probably treat it I
would treat it with whatever pest
management system I have decided to work
with if I'm using sprays and oils
I would heavily treat it with multiple
oils several times it would probably
spend a week in quarantine the first day
it would get blasted with something on
day three would get blasted with
something different on day five
something different then we're gonna
look at it if I feel like it's safe and
clean I may enter general population on
day seven or it may get treated one more
time depending on how it looks to me if
I were working in a facility that did
not use spray applications I would put
that plant in an isolated area with
enough light and living conditions to
survive for a few days and then I would
start heavily applying beneficial
insects I would build up a colony of
predators on there hopefully they would
go through and eat anything that was
causing me a problem and by day seven I
would be safe to enter that clone into
general population but honestly if I got
a clone and it was contaminated I
probably would just destroy it it
wouldn't even make it past
inspection stage it wouldn't even get
into micro so as a grower it is your
responsibility to check incoming clones
and check them thoroughly no matter
where they came from if it came from
your best friend if it came from a
dispensary if it came from somebody on
the internet it is your responsibility
you cannot blame anybody for giving you
a clone with bugs that is your fault it
is not their fault so treat any incoming
plants as if they are contaminated
isolate them treat them and continue to
monitor them until you are certain the
problem is not there or has been
eradicated now another very common way
for people to get garden pests is
through store-bought soil or soilless
mix a lot of people try to blame
specific brands for being infested with
specific bugs I find that to be
inaccurate think about it this way brand
a is made in one area in California
brand B is probably made in another area
of California and brand C will just say
that it's manufactured in Colorado so
all three of those brands are made then
they are all shipped to a warehouse
sometimes these warehouses store their
soil in pallets outdoors now if one of
those pallets had a little bit of bugs
in it they started thriving in that one
pallet of soil then they moved over to
the next pallet then they moved over to
the next pallet now they are in brands a
B and C there is no way to blame a
specific soil company for giving you
bugs it was probably the warehouse in
which all of those pallets were stored
is where your bugs came from so let's
try to get away from blaming a specific
brand for having specific bugs in there
that's unfair and probably uh nak urine
but it is a fact that our soil does come
with bugs quite frequently a lot of
times you'll notice this when you're
transplanting you'll stick your hand in
there and a little bug will just fly
right up it's usually a fungus gnat or a
white fly it'll just fly right up out of
the soil you know there there now it's
time to start thinking about how you are
going to treat for those pests other
times you don't see those soil-borne
pests until the first time you water you
just potted all those pots you got a
whole bag worth of soil with uh pots
done you feeling really good about life
you got the grow room all organized you
mix up your nutrients you go to water
and that first batch of water that hits
that soil you see
bugs come flying out those are fresh
bugs they came fresh with the soil
they're not a big deal as long as we
know how to identify the insect and we
know how to properly treat for that
problem treating for soil bound pests is
very easy you can either purchase
predator insects that will get in there
and eat that specific pests or we can
mix up a route drench which is a basic
pesticide and he makes it with water and
then you water that into the plants just
like you would when you normally water
then that pesticide gets down in there
in the root zone and then it will
eradicate any pests that are in there
the things you're most commonly gonna
find in soil are going to be white flies
you'll probably find some fungus gnats
and I quite often have found thrips
in my soil so just know that your soil
may have bugs in it be aware be looking
and be prepared and once you see some
pests identify them then start thinking
about eradication strategies I do plan
on giving you options for eradication
strategies but I'm not going to tell you
what to do
there are countless options and
variables when it comes to deciding your
integrated pest management but I want to
give you guidance to let you decide and
modify your own pest management system
to where it fits with your grouse style
with your grow environment and also it's
got to fit your budget so I'm gonna give
you a good guideline on how to take care
of pests in your garden but it is up to
you to implement and modify these
practices to work for you all right so
we've covered most of the ways that we
are going to introduce pass into it grow
let's talk about the other ways pests
are going to find their way into the
grow they're gonna come in through your
venting and your ducting if you have any
spots that are not sealed up a spider
mite or a little bug to just wiggle its
way right through there it's gonna smell
that sweet ganja plant it's gonna feel
that warmth from the light it's gonna go
man I want to be in there and it's gonna
just go that way and then it's gonna
tell all of its friends hey bro I found
a way in and they're just gonna start
parading in so any cracks or gaps in
your structure need to be sealed if you
can find a gap or a crack or a hole of
some sort put some caulk in there put
some tape over it seal it up super tight
so that the bugs cannot get in there now
it's ideal to have a completely sealed
room but I understand that that is not
always a viable option since we do have
the opportunity to get bugs in there our
next step is to have a way to monitor
and indicate the presence of paths and
the easiest way and most affordable and
cost-effective way to do that is first
by scouting you need to spend time every
day looking through your garden to see
if you see any signs of bugs or bug
damage scouting for bugs is free it just
takes time depending on the size of your
grow this could take anywhere from five
minutes to a full hour but it is
important work put on some good music
get in the zone and scout for pests
train everybody in the grow how to
identify signs of pests and also teach
them how to identify which pests they're
dealing with if you do discover pests
have a way to mark the plant and also
mark on paper where it was in the
facility you probably have row numbers
or room numbers or if it's just a home
grow just plant number three or the
plant in the middle just kind of mark
down roughly where it is and then start
thinking of a strategy if you're not the
one in charge of pest management make
sure you report that to the person above
you so just make a note of it write down
what you found what it looks like
what pests do you think it is and then
start doing research on how do we
[Music]
radicans so scouting for bugs is free
you walk the rows you turn the leaves
upside down you look you look low in the
canopy you look high in the canopy you
look around feel free to pull a few
leaves off if you can't get a good look
reach in there pop off a few leaves look
at those under your scope see if you see
anything you should be scouting for
pests on a regular basis with some sort
of a strategy now while you're out
scouting for pests you should check your
yellow sticky cards every grow should
have yellow sticky cards and they should
be checked frequently and changed
frequently as well yellow sticky cards
are exactly what I'm saying there are
little yellow cards there are about 4
inches by 4 inches or maybe 4 inches by
6 inches and they are bright yellow and
they are sticky they've got a disgusting
glue on them that if you touch it it's
gonna take all day to get that stuff off
of you don't get one stuck to your elbow
and you're working in the grow if you've
done it you know exactly what I'm
talking about when you do it you'll go
oh that's what he meant but you should
have yellow sticky traps all over the
grow I like to put yellow sticky traps
low down by the soil so that if I get
any soil bound pests coming up out of
the dirt I get indicators of that I like
to put yellow sticky traps low in the
canopy so if I get any low flying stuff
get indicators of that i'll put stuff at
the top of the canopy and then I'll also
put stuff up near the light so that if
anything flies into it I get an
indicator of that and that is a really
easy way to find out that you have got
insects bugs love those yellow sticky
traps they say wow look how bright that
is that's a leaf that is weak that's a
leaf that's got a weak surface that I
can get in there and really start
sucking the juice out of without a lot
of effort I want to go to that so the
bugs run to that yellow sticky trap and
they go oh [ __ ] this is yellow sticky
trap I'm stuck here and then we come in
in the morning and we get to find out
what kind of bugs were messing around in
the garden having a party while we were
at home trying to get some rest
yellow sticky traps are really
affordable and they are a really early
indicator of the presence of pests so
hang up your sticky traps check them on
a daily basis if you start seeing things
stuck to them investigate what that pest
is and tree accordingly then hang up
fresh sticky traps and see if that
problem has gone away or if it has
gotten worse or if anything new pops up
but if you're going to use the yellow
sticky traps there has to be some sort
of method to your madness you have to
hang them strategically you have to
check them and you have to replace them
and if you see something you have to
react accordingly so now we have two
methods of finding bugs in our garden we
can use our own vision from scouting and
then we can use yellow sticky traps to
assist us our next step is to learn to
use our integrated pest management
system to continue to prevent
infestations and we also need to learn
what to do if a pest infestation should
occur in a strategic pest management
system it's always wise to have
preventative measures in place why wait
until we've got bugs to start treating
for bugs let's make it uncomfortable and
undesirable for the pests we know may
arrive now before we talk about options
let's talk a little bit about ethics
you can choose predator bugs you can
choose organic sprays you can choose
harsh chemical sprays whatever you
choose to treat your garden is up to you
I encourage you to use something safe is
it safe to you is it safe to the
consumer is it safe to your pets and is
it overall
safe to our environment if you're gonna
smoke it yourself spray whatever you are
come
with spraying on your garden that's
yours you can do whatever you want I
probably don't want to smoke it if you
sprayed it with a few things but if it's
yours and you're sure it's not going
anywhere you can treat it however you
are comfortable if you have other
consumers that are going to consume your
product keep their health and safety in
mind not everybody is a young healthy
person some people may have underlying
health issues that may be exacerbated by
a pesticide or an essential oil or a
botanical oil keep other people in mind
if you are going to share sell or
dispense your product in any sort of way
then of course please make sure that
your pest management system is
environmentally friendly we also need to
keep in mind to be long-term effects of
whatever we choose to use beneficial
mites will have a long-term
environmental effect but it is a much
gentler effect than if we wouldn't
outside and sprayed harsh chemicals so
think about long-term think about
exposure not just to the plants the
environment the soil your neighbours
gardens but also to yourself you've got
to apply those chemicals or pesticides
or botanical oils think about if they're
going to harm you over time also think
about this is something we don't think
about often enough here but I'm trying
to gear myself more toward think about
the ethics of the company that makes the
product you were using does that company
care do they care about the environment
do they care about people do they care
about cannabis are they opposed to
cannabis there are some companies out
there that make products that are
available at the hydro store that are
completely opposed to cannabis and
cannabis legalization why would we buy
those products to support those people
so when it comes to selecting a
pesticide understand the company
understand the product you're buying
understand the active ingredient and
understand the effects of that
ingredient in the long term understand
what it's doing to yourself understand
what it's doing to your consumers and
try to understand what it does to the
environment and then really think about
if that's something you can support if
that is something you would be proud to
see you did if that is something you
would stand behind and if you're proud
of it if you can support it and you'd
put your signature on it go ahead and
use that product do what you're
comfortable with so now let's talk a
little bit more
preventive that's where I was headed
with all of that preventive measures
it's okay to start treating for a pest
problem before you see a pest problem
why wouldn't we go ahead and make an
undesirable environment what are easy
ways to do that an easy way to do that
is to already apply beneficial insects
why not start a colony of beneficial
bugs in our garden before the bad bugs
even have a chance to take hold you can
start getting your personal s your
Swarovski's whatever you decide to use
in there do a little bit of research
make sure that you order the proper bugs
that work for your environment your
temperature and humidity will play a
huge factor in the bugs that you need to
order but get some predators in there
get the army established and get them
started before the bad guys can even get
started so another route you can take is
by spraying pesticide applications you
can use your essential oils your
botanical oils or you can use your light
or heavy chemical sprays whatever you
choose to use you can start applying
them before you see an insect
infestation that way if a bug does try
to creep down the ducting and jumps on
the plant and goes on [ __ ] that I don't
want to be here at all and it just tries
to run it doesn't invite its friends you
can create that undesirable environment
before you even get an infestation I
would start with a schedule and a
strategy decide that you're going to
spray every so often and then decide
that you need to rotate your products
this frequently and then set a schedule
and a routine and then if you see
anything you can step up your game
accordingly we'll talk more about
scheduling and strategy a little later
now let's say we have been scouting and
we've been doing our preventative sprays
and now we have discovered some pests
now how do we treat them what's the
first step the first step is to
correctly identify your pests on a
commercial scale it would save a lot of
time and energy to treat for the correct
pests the first time so the first step
is to correctly identify our pests the
next step is to think about how do we
want to treat this problem do we want to
use predators do we want to use
horticultural oils do we want to use
botanical sprays do we want to get in
there with essential oils or do we want
to step up our game and start using
light pesticides or maybe even stronger
pesticides this is where we have to
think about that a lot of the essential
oils and the hippie products aren't
going to get rid of a
wrong infestation that's where you'll
need to step up to a mild pesticide a
lot of the pesticides are organic a lot
of those will work for you if you've got
a serious infestation and you don't want
to deal with some organic stuff you can
step your way up to more harsh chemicals
but like I said those are toxic and they
become dangerous and you need to think
about the ethics of what you are giving
to other people now if you're trying to
stay more organic if you're doing a TLO
sort of setup you can introduce predator
bugs perimeters are expensive you also
have to have specific insects to battle
specific insects you can't just release
one thing and expect it to go take care
of any bug that you may get
Soper dinners are an option they're also
time consuming you have to get out there
and let them go you have to apply and
they either come in sachets or they come
in a bottle with like a little spout you
got to let them out somehow they have to
be dispersed through the garden so they
are time consuming but they are organic
they are 100% organic you're not
applying anything to the garden that's
going to change the flavor you're not
putting any chemicals on there that may
make anybody else sick and they are
completely safe so you found a pest you
identified the pests you've done some
research on products that will help you
get rid of that pest to either
beneficial bugs or pesticide sprays and
now you've decided to apply that product
now keep in mind if we apply the same
product to a pest too many times those
bugs will develop a resistance so you'll
see a bug you'll treat it it'll look
like it's gone it'll come back you'll
spray for that bug again you'll think
it's gone
couple weeks later it'll come back
you'll spray twice as hard it'll come
back and it won't show up for a long
time when it does come back you won't be
able to spray it down with the product
you've been using before you'll have to
switch it up so to prevent that I
recommend using multiple modes of attack
and don't forget that if the pesticides
work together and don't cause a chemical
problem together and don't disrupt the
plant health you can mix more than one
pesticide and it tank together I've done
an episode about it titled tank mix
don't be afraid to mix multiple products
together so you mix your products you
give it a good shake you apply to your
plants I would say give it two or three
days then apply a different mix then if
you still see the presence of bugs apply
a different mix don't go at it with the
same product
over and over because they will develop
a resistance to it earlier I said we
would talk about scheduling and strategy
so let's talk about a more scheduled and
detailed integrated pest management
strategy here is a quick rundown of my
scheduling and my strategy for pest
management in aggro now everything I
mentioned is approved by the Colorado
marijuana Enforcement Division and also
the Colorado Department of Ag I cannot
apply a pesticide that is on the banned
list or that has not been approved for
use in a commercial grow so everything
I'm using is approved by the state of
Colorado now to start my pest management
system every Monday I apply a specific
pesticide regimen to all of my
vegetative plants my small veg my large
veg my mother plants and the clones that
are rooted and in pots they all get
sprayed with a pesticide depending on
the size of the plant I may spray them
with a little more potent mix I may
spray them with a lighter mix i'm a
spray with just one product i'm a mix up
multiple products at a time but every
Monday those plants are getting treated
I also write down exactly what I sprayed
on each plant that way next week I know
I can switch my pesticide I can spray
something different next week to prevent
a resistance now I know that my plants
have got a protective barrier there's a
little protection going on to prevent
from getting pests in the room if you're
using lighter sprays if you're using
botanical oils or essential oils you may
want to up your spray regimen to twice a
week if those things don't stick around
very long you may want to apply them
more frequently so have a weekly spray
schedule in place and try to switch up
your products so that you can prevent
your pests from building any type of
resistance now when you're in there
applying the sprays spray the undersides
of the leaves you'll notice the spider
mites are on the underside of the leaves
why not spray there so start at the
bottom of the plant and start spraying
the underside of the leaf and work your
way up the plant to the top and you will
saturate the entire grow this way try to
cover all the plants just to the point
of runoff right to when they start
dripping specific products will have
specific guidelines but I recommend you
spray rights where they start running
if you just want to saturate that plant
don't leave any desirable space for a
pest so get in there and spray once
maybe twice a week and you can do this
throughout the vegetative stage now once
we start approaching the flower phase we
need to think about what we are going to
do for pest management during the bloom
phase and a typical commercial grow I
would generally apply approved
pesticides until day fourteen or fifteen
of the flowering phase I may go in there
the first day of the third week and hit
that room one last time if I've had any
problems just to make sure those bugs
aren't coming back if you don't have any
buds building yet if you're just
starting to get bud set you should be
okay with one final spray if you were
selective with your products now if you
haven't seen any bugs you can taper off
your spray applications earlier in Flour
and that's when we can start to
introduce our beneficial and predator
insects
now the beneficial insects work just
like pesticide applications you have to
reapply them at specified intervals most
of the vendors that provide live bugs
are willing to set you up on a scheduled
tour you will receive the same order
every week that way you can rely on it
coming it'll show up at the grow you say
hey look they're here and then you've
got to hang them because they're right
there in your face you can't forget you
can't put it off they're alive so that's
a good way to get yourself on a good
regimen and a good schedule of getting
the live bugs out so when a commercial
grow we basically work with spray
applications until we see bud set that's
when we switch to the predator bugs make
sure to taper off your spray application
tour it doesn't destroy your predator
bugs now if you've been releasing your
predators on your schedule and you start
seeing spider mites you can order fast
release predators that will get in there
and eat those spider mites for you they
come in a bottle with a little spout and
they are hungry you turn the spout you
open that bottle you point that bottle
at a leaf and the spider bite the party
termites that are in there start
marching out they go and destroy the
spider mite colonies so if you start
seeing an infestation during flower and
you're already putting out the bugs you
just need to step up the bugs and try to
ride it out through flower you can D
foliate take any spider mite infested
leaves out of there get them out of the
room don't go into a different room
after that don't drag the bugs
from the dirty room to the clean room on
your clothes trying to start the day
working in the clean room and then work
your way through to the dirtiest rooms
and try to work on the bug infested room
very last if that is an option so if
you've done everything correctly you
won't see spider mites late in Flour but
if you do and you were using beneficial
insects you've got the option to apply
more beneficial insects I don't
recommend spraying flowering plants with
anything once you have bud set
everything you spray on there you will
taste it if not in the flower you will
taste it in the concentrates so if you
do notice a presence of bugs late in
flower in your flowering room and you
were using beneficial insects as your
pest management system or if you are
using sprays as your pest management
system it is time to step your game up
in your vegetative areas we need to
eliminate the pests in veg because if
you've got them in flower they are in
veg and we need to start getting rid of
them and having a clean grow before we
move stuff into the flower room because
like I've mentioned once we get past
week three we can't really spray those
plants we can only treat them with bugs
and that takes time to build up so let's
focus on getting the plants clean and
pest free before we even move them to
that stage a lot of people try to focus
on the flowering plants they want to get
those pest free those are on their way
out let's focus on the moms let's go all
the way to the beginning and get the
mother plants very clean let's get the
source material clean let's work on
keeping the clones clean let's learn how
to get the veg room immaculate so that
way when we move into the flower room we
don't have to battle bugs we don't have
to battle pests we can focus on building
those fat juicy buds and delicious
trichomes that we're all after now one
thing I do recommend is write down all
of your sprays if you were working in a
commercial grow you were required to
write down all of your sprays you have
to write down the date the time you also
have to write down the name of every
product and the EPA number of every
product and the amount of every product
that you applied you have to write down
the REI of each product that you applied
you have to write down the lot number of
plants there's a lot of documenting to
be done in a commercial grow I recommend
you do the same thing in your private
grow just for peace of mind it's always
nice to have records and if you do end
up working in a commercial grow you've
already got experience writing
what you've been using now I'm sure
there are a lot of people that will not
agree with my pesticide spray
application regimen that is just fine
with me I like the people have different
opinions that's just the method that I
use in a commercial environment it's
what has been proven to work for me it
has been proven to be cost effective and
it is something that I can train other
employees to do on a repeatable basis
just like all other aspects of growing
cannabis the options for integrated pest
management are endless and as long as
it's making you happy as long as you
were satisfied with the results keep
doing it
all right podcast world that is my quick
talk on integrated pest management I
know I didn't recommend any products I
didn't recommend any specific vendors I
did not recommend any brands my goal was
to give you an idea of how to start your
own custom tailored integrated pest
management now you know what to expect
and you've got a few options on how to
prevent and how to treat those things
now you can customize that program to
work for your grow your budget and your
style if you've got any questions or
comments about this podcast I would love
to hear from you my email address is
grow from your heart at hotmail.com if
you feel like this podcast was
educational informative or entertaining
and you would like to contribute to the
show financially you can do so by going
to patreon.com slash grow from your
heart all the information you need to
become a patron will be right there
ladies and gentlemen I made it 35
minutes without taking a break my voice
is burning out I want to thank you for
hanging out for this long episode I'll
be back Monday with the fresh new
episode I want to give a huge shout out
to stabby mixed a person and until next
time take a phat dad and give your mom a
hug for me welcome to the show everybody
it's time for episode 360 of the girl
from your heart podcast this episode is
brought to you by the hella dank seed
company if you need new seeds for your
garden I highly recommend the hella dank
seed company and you can find them at
dank seed dot store you guys know I like
to start the show off by letting you
know what I'm smoking today I'm taking
dad's of bubble jack FSC from Fuego
extracts I really love the flavor of
this stuff it tastes like bubblegum the
flavor just lingers on my tongue
really like it there's a little
information printed on the side of the
package here it's got a lab test that
says seventy one point eight three
percent max THC two point eight five
percent C BGA and it's got nine point
nine eight percent terpenes I really
enjoy this concentrate that bubblegum
cotton candy flavor that just lingers on
the tongue is perfect and then that head
hide that goes straight to the brain and
keeps you rambling keeps you motivated
is perfect so a big two thumbs up to the
bubble jack full spectrum extract from
fuego extracts I really do enjoy smoking
this alright you guys let's keep moving
this show forward because I have got a
lot to talk about we're gonna get back
into the grow lessons on this episode
this is going to be the eighth lesson in
a long series of grow lessons so far
we've talked about our goals and ideas
and where to set up our grow we've gone
over the equipment we've talked about
the lights we've talked about our
containers we've talked about soil and
medium we've talked about pest control
and if you're not caught up I recommend
you go back to episode 351 and start
there there are a couple of
interruptions in the lessons I will
sneak in a few episodes that are not
grow lessons while I'm doing this series
sometimes I'll need to read emails
sometimes I'll need to answer questions
coming up we're gonna have some iTunes
customer reviews things like that will
disrupt the lessons but I think it keeps
the show's fresh it keeps me motivated
and it keeps it fun but in this episode
we will continue the grow lessons but
before we get there let's talk about a
couple of things I kind of overlooked
while we were talking about building our
grow it might be a good idea to add a
smoke detector to each grow room
wherever you've got a grow light hanging
have a smoke detector in that room also
I would recommend a fire extinguisher
outside of each grow room now I hope you
don't have to use it but if that smoke
alarm goes off you'd rather have that
fire extinguisher outside of the grow
room so you don't have to open the door
run in there get the fire extinguisher
then start working on the fire if it's
outside of the grow room you can just
grab it you can be a little more
prepared you can get in there you can
start putting out the fire also if
you've never used a fire extinguisher
maybe read the instructions maybe
understand what to do in case of a fire
maybe just read that little book that
comes with it and also make sure it
stays
charged it's got a gauge on it it's got
a red a yellow and a green make sure
your little arrow is in the green at all
times you might want to think about some
sort of automated fire suppression
system they make things that hang in the
middle of the grow room it's got a
little heat sensor in it if it gets too
hot it basically explodes it releases a
powder that rains down into the grow
room that will put out any fire that's
in the room think about some sort of way
to detect and suppress a fire in your
grow room should that situation occur
another thing I overlooked when we were
designing and building our room was an
automated watering or an assisted
watering system an automated watering
system can really speed things up once
you get into a larger grow it also makes
the plants really happy because the
plants love consistency if you're
interested in designing an auto watering
system I did a full episode about auto
watering on episode 335 unfortunately
there were some audio technical
difficulties and parts of the episode
chopped out if you listened to that
episode and you still have specific
questions send me an email I grow from
your heart at hotmail.com
and we will get your auto water system
dialed in all right so at this point we
should have goals and reasonable
expectations for our grow we should have
a good idea of where we want to put the
grow we should have a good idea of the
gear we want to buy the lights the pots
the medium we should also have a good
idea of pest control now we've talked a
little bit about fire suppression I've
also done an in-depth episode on fire
suppression that is episode 260 if you
want to learn a lot about fire safety in
your grow episode number 260 will teach
you a lot there if you decide you want
to add an auto watering system to your
grow episode 335 is the episode all
about Auto watering so that should get
us all caught up the room is ready we've
got the gear planned out we've got a
good idea of pest management we know
what we're gonna feed the plants we know
how to take care of a fire we know how
to set up an auto watering system if we
need one now we're getting to the fun
part of this journey
let's start thinking about plants what
do you want to grow what do you want to
dedicate your time your energy your
space and a bunch of money to over the
next 90 to 120 days what strains have
gotten your attention
what strains do you really enjoy smoke
does something work for you medically
does something work for you
recreationally is there something that
is reliable that every time you smoke it
you get the desired effect this is gonna
fall back to the very first episode of
this bro lesson series are you growing
this for yourself are you growing it for
a medical patient you have a lot of
things to think about when it comes to
deciding what strains to grow in your
new garden in legal medical and
recreational states we have a lot more
options for acquiring genetic material
we can go to a dispensary and buy a
clone off of the shelf we can go to our
friends garden and ask them for clones
and they can give sell or trade those
clones to us we can acquire clones here
very easily in Colorado in fact I went
to a dispensary just a few days ago to
pick up these fuego extracts and they
had two different variety of clones on
the Shelf that looked very healthy it
had purple punch and dos Eidos on the
shelf ready to go at a very reasonable
price so clones are readily available in
Colorado seeds are also available in
some Colorado dispensaries so you can
walk right into the store you can grab a
pack of seeds and you can start your new
garden from seeds you picked up at your
local dispensary clones and seeds are
both viable options for starting a
garden this episode is going to focus on
the great debate on seeds versus clones
before we get into that let's talk a
little bit about how you can decide what
strain you want to grow the best way to
do that is to smoke a bunch of different
strains now if you're in a medical or
recreational state that is a lot easier
than if you were in Prohibition land if
you're in prohibition land who knows if
the strain you were buying is even
really what whoever is selling it to you
is called they're probably growing
something and they're calling everything
cookies because cookies sells anything
with the letters OG at the end of it
sell so you've probably got something
cookies OG anything with the word fire
in their works well so you probably you
guys are probably buying fire cookies OG
in Prohibition land everywhere and it's
probably whatever that person got a
clone of or whatever that person's
buying bulk of and they're just renaming
it because they know that names are hot
so in a prohibition state it's gonna be
a little bit harder maybe you'll get
lucky maybe you'll get a seed in your
bag of weed one day you can always grow
out those bags see
sometimes you find phenotypes very close
to what you started with also sometimes
you find hermaphrodites and problematic
plants so be prepared for that as well
but sometimes it is your only option
it's always an awkward situation asking
a grower for clones if you're a new
grower and you're buying herb from
somebody and you're like bro I really
love this strain do you think I could
get a clone that always presents an
awkward situation first of all now you
both know you're growing if you're in a
prohibition state that makes things
really weird for both of you also the
guy doesn't want to release as genetics
to you because now he's going to lose a
customer so unless you're on a really
friendly basis with your weed guy I
would avoid that conversation now in a
legal state in a recreational or a
medical state it's really easy to go
find out what strains work best for you
you go to the dispensary and you buy as
many grams as you can afford of
different varieties and you go home and
you smoke them you start fresh every day
and you try this strain I haven't smoked
this one yet let's smoke strain a and
you take a few notes and you see how it
works for you first thing in the morning
if you've got a target if you're trying
to make your leg pain go away if you're
trying to make your headache go away for
trying to make your back pain go away if
you're trying to make your anxiety go
away document the level of which that
ailment starts is it a five is that a
ten okay I started off with a level five
leg pain I smoked a bowl of this strain
a I know my leg pain is it it to
document that the next day I woke up leg
pains at a five I smoked strained B now
my leg pain is still at a five I
obviously don't want to buy any more of
this [ __ ] then you want to go then the
next day day number three I woke up my
leg pains at a six I smoked some of this
now I'm at a two this one might work
well for me let's put a little star by
that and remember what this is and then
just keep doing a little test like that
on yourself and with the flowers and
find out what strain works for you if
you find a strain at one dispensary it
works very well for you try to find it
at another dispensary and smoke that
product because they have different
growers they may have different clones
their product is gonna come out very
different in the end even if we start
with the same clone to commercial grows
will produce two very different products
so try them both and see if it's the
strain it might have just been that one
batch it might have just been that one
grow but try different batches if
possible I know it sounds like I'm
completely spoiled but this is a real
thing I can drive to ten dispensaries in
my area and probably five of them have
wedding cake and that wedding cake was
probably grown by three different grows
and I bet you if I try all three of them
they're all gonna have very subtle
nuances one will taste a little
different one's gonna burn a little
different and one's gonna have a better
high but they're all gonna have that
wedding cake droopy I giggle II kind of
think going on so try to check them out
from different grows if you can make
sure that it's the strain and not just
that one grower that did it for you now
one thing I want to loop back on we
talked about trying to get a clone from
your grower if you do try to buy a clone
from your grower friend don't be
offended when he hits you with a really
steep price think about this he's been
selling you herb for how long and now
you're gonna grow your own how much
money are you taking out of his pocket I
know you're gonna save that much money
but that guy's been relying on you as a
customer and now you're gonna try to
grow your own he's gonna go dude this
guy's gone you've got to put a fat chunk
in his pocket as a parting gift when he
gives you that clone that's why he needs
so much for it also
he's the only one growing that in town
that's how he's living that's how he's
making his income
you're gonna bite into that that genetic
is gonna be out there how does he know
you're not gonna run a bunch of it and
flood the town with it so when they hit
you with a really high price for a clone
in a prohibition state that's why it's
because that's how that person is living
that is his income that's his artwork
he's probably Fino hunted that or he
paid a whole lot of money for that clone
himself so he's sharing his revenue
stream with you and kind of opening up
the floodgates to put himself out of
business once you guys do a Fino hunt
and you've found your own keeper you
kind of understand a little bit more
especially in a prohibition state all
right you guys we've talked a little bit
about deciding what you want to grow
what you want to grow is up to you once
you decide what you want to grow if you
pick something that takes ten or twelve
weeks and it grows tall and skinny if
that's really what you think you want to
grow you're gonna have to adapt to that
plant don't try to make that plant adapt
to you that is not how it works all
right I've got a bunch of notes but I
don't have a good segue so let's just
jump right into this let's talk about
the debate on seeds versus clones you've
decided what you wanted
now do you want to grow it from seed or
from clone growing from either seed or
clone both have their advantages and
disadvantages something you'll have to
think about with both of them is
availability are clones available where
you are does somebody in your area grow
that is willing to release clones to you
for your personal production is there a
dispensary in your area that sells
clones if I read correctly
in Canada you can ship clones to each
other through the mail so that's an
option but if nobody has clones near you
they are not available now if somebody
does have clones are they accurately
labeled do they have the variety you're
looking for and are they clean we'll
talk about that in just a minute it's
kind of the same story with seeds do you
know somebody that's got seeds that is
willing to share some with you and if
you get them from somebody are they
accurately labeled and do they have the
variety that you're looking for one of
the advantages of seeds is that there
are shops on the internet that will send
seeds directly to your mailbox if you
were in a prohibition state and you
order seeds from an online vendor it is
your responsibility to keep those seeds
in the packaging and do not allow them
to grow if it is illegal to grow them in
your area save them as souvenirs and
collectibles until legalization happens
in your area or until you move to a
legalized state but there are several
online vendors who will send you seeds
to keep his collectibles if you do
choose to germinate those and grow those
yourself that is your responsibility
anything that happens from that is up to
you but seeds are available online and
seeds don't die in the mail now I want
to do a friendly debate on clone vs.
seed but to keep it fair
we need to act like there is a place
where we can go that has clones and
seeds available and just about any
variety we could imagine think about the
strain that you chose you want to grow
for your first time let's imagine
there's a dispensary where we can go and
they've got flowers of that strain grown
by three different growers so we can
smoke it from three different people and
make sure it's what we like they've also
got extracts there so if you're into
smoking
concentrate they've got full-spectrum
extract they've got shatter they've got
wax
they've got whatever you're into that
way so you can make sure it's the strain
you desire for your concentrates then
also they have got seeds and clones of
your favorite strain ready for you there
now you've got the option do you want to
buy seeds or clones for your grow let's
start a friendly debate right here now
before I get too far into this let me
give a quick explanation on what a clone
is I'm pretty sure most people know what
a seed is that's a little beam that
grows into a big plant it came out of
another plant now let's talk about a
clone a clone is basically a photocopy
of a plant we take a cutting off of a
plant and it roots and now we have a
photocopy of the plant we started with
cannabis plants are annuals which means
they only live for one year or one cycle
so we grow it from seed it produces bud
we harvest it it is over by taking a
clone we can have that plant again and
again then we can have repeatable
reliable outcomes and a reliable product
from each harvest so a clone is
basically a genetic photocopy of a
reliable plant in the form of just a
tiny little plant and we'll talk about
clones and we'll talk about Fino hunting
a lot more as these grow lessons go on
now let's talk about some of the pros
and cons of seeds and clone the pros of
growing from seed one of the best parts
about growing from seed is there are no
bugs and no pathogens you don't get free
powdery mildew with your new clone all
too often people give out clones that
are infested with spider mites with
Russert mites with aphids with thrips or
with powdery mildew that is not an
option with the seed so let's also put
that in the cons category when it comes
to growing from clone one of the
disadvantages of starting from clones is
that they may come with bugs or
pathogens now let's talk about one of my
favorite parts about growing from seed
growing from seed allows me to find
custom tailored phenotypes that work
perfectly for what I'm looking for
medically and perfectly for what I'm
looking for in my grow it grows the
height I want it to grow it grows for as
long as I want it to grow and it gives
me medicine it gives me the effect that
I need so draw
from seed allows me to find something
completely unique for myself that works
perfectly for my garden and my medical
needs the cons that is it does take time
for a selection I have to run the batch
of seeds I have to find the plant that
works for me hopefully there was one in
that batch that was exactly what I
wanted if not I keep searching so that
is the downside to that and we will do
an episode on Fino hunting in the future
that is lined up in this series so one
of the advantages is that I can find
perfectly custom-tailored phenotypes
that work for myself and my grow the con
to that is that it does take time for
selection I have to run the seeds I have
to grow them up I have to cut clones I
have to flour them out I have to dry
them cure them smoke them and see which
ones I enjoyed see which ones I didn't
enjoy usually when I run a ten pack I
find two or three that I want to run
again so I'll repeat the process and
eliminate it to one but that does take
time money and energy to get to that
point also there may be males there may
be hermaphrodites and there may be
undesirable phenotypes in that test run
so depending on the quality of the seeds
and the experience of the breeder and
the stability of the work I may not find
the phenotype I'm looking for in a ten
pack it may take more than ten seeds to
find the desirable phenotype but if I've
got reliable seeds and the breeder did
his work and I've done my job properly I
may find something in there that is
amazing and I may find something in
there that nobody else has which will
set me apart from the market if I'm
growing for a production to put on the
street having a very unique strain would
set me apart from the market if I've got
the frosty estanque a strain on the
market people are gonna want to buy that
first which means I'm gonna make more
sales which means maybe I can charge a
little more so having that perfectly
selected phenotype that grows exactly
the way I want it to
it grows perfectly for my grow and it
works perfect for my area for my market
that is a great advantage of growing
from seed another advantage of growing
from seed is that there is a huge
variety available I know we talked about
this imaginary store where everything is
available but it's not like that in all
places there are seed banks
line that make many varieties of seeds
from very many reputable breeders
available to people all over the world
so seed availability is a huge advantage
not everybody can get their hands on
clean reliable accurately labeled clones
so being able to order seeds from a seed
bank is definitely advantageous now the
downside to that is seeds can be kind of
expensive depending on the vendor and
the breeder seeds can have a huge markup
and if you're working with regular seeds
you may lose 60% of your crop right when
you switch to flour because you're going
to have male plants to deal with so
buying seeds can get expensive and you
also need to have a reliable breeder and
a reputable vendor so that you know you
were getting what you pay for now let's
focus more on growing from clone what
are some of the advantages or pros of
growing from a clone if properly
selected that clone is a female if
properly selected that clone is known to
put out high potency and to grow without
any issues now that being said we have
to rely on a grower so that is one of
the cons of growing from clones
somebody has to grow the seeds and find
the keeper plants out of those seed
packages hopefully they chose the
stellar keeper to pass on as clones to
the consumers in a dispensary what
usually happens is I'll cut a hundred
and twenty clones for my next run I only
need a hundred of them so I actually
send those twenty to the store so that I
don't have to throw them away we put
them on a manifest we send them to the
store and those are made available for
shoppers in the retail store so if
you're buying a clone from a dispensary
and it's accurately labeled you're
probably getting the same exact cut as
they're growing and putting on the Shelf
so you know that those clones have been
properly Fino hunted you know that those
clones are proven females with proven
potency and have proven themselves to be
resistant to bugs and pathogens so
that's the advantage to growing from a
clone the disadvantage to that is who
knows who selected that if you're just
getting it from some dude on Craigslist
who knows how discerning his I was maybe
his idea of amazing bud and your idea of
amazing bud are two completely different
things so keep that in mind when working
with a clone another advantage of
working with
clone is we have an idea of what to
expect like we said before somebody Fino
hunted this clone they've grown it out a
couple of times they know that it's a
female they know that it's gonna have
high potency either high CBD high THC or
a beautiful ratio of both we know what
to expect we also have an idea of what
type of growth patterns to expect is it
gonna get real tall is it gonna get real
bushy is it gonna stretch out real bad
is it gonna need a lot of water we also
have a good idea of how long it will
take to finish because our friends and
partners have probably grown this cut
several times before they gave it to us
so the main advantage to growing from
clone is that you've got a proven female
you don't have to worry about calling
males every plant you put in there is a
female they've been tested for potency
they've been tested for vigor they've
been tested for resistance we know what
to expect we know if we need sticks we
know if we need trellis we know how
often to water it we know if we can over
feed it we know if it likes a high or a
low pH and we already know how many days
to let it flower so that is a huge
advantage from working with a clone also
you can always call the guy and say hey
bro this plant is doing something weird
have you ever seen this strain do this
and you'll say oh yeah man I drew that
like 10 times before I gave it to you
you probably just need more Cal mag so
he's got some sort of history some sort
of experience with it and he can help
you diagnose a problem if one does arise
so that's a huge advantage of working
with a clone let's talk about some of
the disadvantages the number one
disadvantage the number one con to
bringing clones into your garden is most
of the time they are infested with bugs
and pathogens every grower likes to say
my grow is immaculate there is not a
single bug in my garden nine times out
of 10
those guys are wrong the guys that boast
most about having the pest free garden
are the ones that don't know the pests
are they're the guys that say no I've
got a little bit of spider mites they're
the guys that are paying attention that
are actually checking and they know that
those bugs are there they are there so
getting a clone you're probably going to
get some sort of a problem everybody
also likes to say my buddy wouldn't give
me clones with pests on them yeah he
doesn't even know they're there he
didn't check he's not paying enough
attention he's just trying to make five
dollars a clone by selling them to you
he didn't care if you get spider mite
because you're gonna need more clones in
the future either way so the downside to
clones is they come with free bugs quite
often you get spider mites you get free
route a feeds you get free white flies
you get free fungus gnats and if you're
really lucky sometimes you even get free
powdery mildew with your new clones
another disadvantage to growing from
clone is everybody already has it if
you're just growing this strain for
yourself for your medical needs or for a
loved ones medical needs and that strain
works perfectly for you that is great
but if you were growing for a market
reason and everybody has that strain
you're going to have to be a better
grower than everybody else growing it to
make your product stand out otherwise
you're just another guy selling weed on
the black market if you don't have a
standout strain you will blend in just
like everybody else so if you're growing
the same clone that all of your
competition is growing you've really got
to be the best grower so that's one of
the downsides to growing from clone is
everybody's got it and you guys that's
why some growers are tight with their
genetics that's why some guys won't let
clones out because they're the only one
growing that specific strain in that
area if you want that you've got to go
to them they've always got some income
because their product stands out now
another downside to working with clones
is they can get expensive and something
in me says that you get what you pay for
when it comes to clones if you're going
to Craigslist and paying three to five
dollars for a clone you're going to get
a three to five dollar clone it may be
quality genetics it may be what you're
looking for but how healthy is it how
good of a start did it get how many bugs
does it have clones can get expensive
the clones that I saw at the dispensary
recently or in 4x4 cubes of cocoa the
clones were about six or eight inches
tall
they looked super healthy they were 40
dollars if you're trying to buy six of
those that's gonna add up really quickly
can you throw down two hundred and forty
dollars every time you want to start a
fresh grow a package of seeds is way
cheaper than that but you have to do the
work you have to grow them you have to
find the males and you have to find the
keeper the advantage with clone is
somebody has already done all of that
work for you so they can charge you 40
bucks
so one of the disadvantages to growing
from clone as
they are expensive unless you're getting
them from a friend they can add up and
cost quite quickly you guys I've seen
clones go from anywhere from five or ten
bucks
I saw those clones at the dispensary the
other day they had a purple punch and a
doe see does there were $40 each it is
not uncommon for me to see a clone sell
for the 500 to $1,000 range and there
are stories of certain cuts being sold
for ten to twenty five thousand dollars
depending on what strain we're talking
about there are rumors of astronomical
numbers but I don't know how much of
that is true but some of the people in
the Bay have paid ridiculous prices for
some of the og cush a--'s and some of
the more well-known strains that the
rapper's rap about some of the og cush
and cookie crosses went for big money
when they first hit the market and
people have built entire empires and
businesses off of those cuts so clones
can get quite expensive quite quickly
another disadvantage to clones is are
they available does anybody in your area
have clones does anybody you trust have
clones available and if you do get
clones are they accurately labeled ask
your friends what clones they have don't
ask for a specific strain because if you
ask for wedding cake now your friends
suddenly has wedding cake and he needs
big money for it if you ask what strains
he's got available he'll give you a list
select from there don't give them the
option to invent a name or slap a label
on something just because you're willing
to throw some money their direction for
that cut so that is my quick debate on
seed versus clone we'll go over really
quickly again and recap the pros of
growing from seed no bugs no pests no
problems you don't start off with
somebody else's problems in your grow
another advantage is that you can select
perfectly selected phenotypes that work
for you and your grow also nobody else
is going to have your phenotype which
will give you better market value some
of the cons of growing from seed is that
it takes time for selection you have to
grow them and find out what you've got
and select a keeper and then grow from
there you will also need to call males
and undesirable phenotypes they're also
a little bit expensive also is the
strain you want available in seed form
some of the older stuff
may not be available anymore because
breeders are always evolving and
creating new stock another thing you
have to think about is are the seeds
accurately labeled are you being sold
what you're paying for now let's talk
about clones really quickly again the
pros you have got proven potent females
you know what you've got you know what
you're working with you know what to
expect you know what to plan for some of
the downsides to working with clones are
you get those bugs you get those
pathogens you get free problems also
everybody else in the area has everybody
else is already growing it there's
nothing different there's nothing
exciting about it unless it's custom for
you also our clones available can you
even get clones do you trust the people
you have to deal with to get them and
are they accurately labeled when you do
get them that is my quick friendly
unbiased debate on seeds versus clones
of course being a breeder I want you to
buy seeds and I want you to buy them at
dank seed dot store then I want you to
do a Fino hunt and find the one that
works best for you we will talk about
phenyl hunting in the future we will
also talk about cutting our own clones
in the future that way once you've
acquired clones or seeds you can do a
phenol hunt you can select the keeper
then we can cut clones off of that
keeper and we can be self-sustainable
and not have to acquire genetic material
from other sources unless we decide to
add something new to the grow so we'll
talk about phenol hunting we'll talk
about cloning we'll talk about mother
plants I have done a long episode about
what to expect from a seed pack I think
that would make great supplemental
listening to this episode if you are
interested in hearing my episode about
seed packet expectations it is episode
245 I encourage you to go check that one
out if it's not available on iTunes and
stitcher it is still available on
YouTube all of the episodes are always
going to be archived on the youtube
channel just search for the grow from
your heart podcast
ladies and gentlemen I'm sure you can
hear my voice starting to burn out so
I'm gonna wrap up this episode I would
appreciate your support on patreon for
more information go to
patreon.com/crashcourse aport there I
would also appreciate it if you find me
on social media on Facebook simply
search for the girl from
our podcast on Twitter its @g fyh
podcast and if you'd like to follow my
personal Twitter account it is at Rasta
Jeff 420 don't forget to check out my
instagram page it's at Irie underscore
genetics check out my cannabis
photography and come join me in my
Instagram live videos ladies and
gentleman my throat is burned out I want
to thank you again for listening I'll be
back in just a couple of days with
another fresh episode I'm gonna give you
a huge shout out to my friend Jim Murphy
and until next time take a phat dad and
give your mom a hug for me hey what's up
podcast world it's time for episode 362
of the girl from your heart podcast this
episode is brought to you by the hella
dank seed company if you need new seeds
for your garden I highly recommend the
hella de exede company and you can find
them at dank seed dot store I like to
start these shows off by letting you
know what I'm smoking today I've been
taking dad's of orange skittles ambrosia
from apothecary farms I really like this
as my morning smoke I'm recording
earlier in the morning than I usually do
and this orange skittles has that orange
juice orange candy sort of a taste it's
also got my head going pretty quickly so
it's a great way to start the day I'm
smoking the orange skittles Fambrough
juh from apothecary farms the only
difference between the ambrosia and the
fan Broza is the ambrosia is a 1 gram
jar when they put it in the 4 gram jar
that's when they call it the fam
brochure that's for the fam so the
orange skittles fam Broza
the potency says seventy three point
seven percent THC zero CBD total
cannabinoids 84.6% it's a great way to
start the day it's got an uplifting head
high it's got that amazing orange candy
flavor to it and it's got me nice and
talkative and energized so this should
be a good podcast this is going to be
another grow lesson in the last lesson I
talked about clones versus seeds now in
this episode we're gonna talk about
regular seeds feminized seeds and auto
flower seeds before we get into the seed
talk I want to give a few shoutouts to a
couple of our patreon supporters I want
to give a huge shout out to Angel Bertus
how about a big shout out to Miles
Porter a super shout out to Jayde and an
extra Viking shout out to Grimble the
druid thank you ladies and gentlemen for
all the support on patreon if you're not
already a patron and you would like to
learn how to become a patron you can do
so by going to patreon.com slash grow
from your heart that's PA t ar e yo
n.com slash grow from your heart you can
learn how to sign up you can become a
patron and I will give you a shout-out
on the next episode
all right podcast world this episode is
going to be about regular seed feminized
seed and Otto flower seed and deciding
what will be best for you and your new
garden a lot of people out there will
have an opinion about feminized seeds a
lot of people out there will have an
opinion about Otto flower seeds
don't let anybody stop you from growing
what makes you happy there's a reason
why regular seeds exist there's a reason
why feminized seeds exist there is a
reason why Otto flower seeds exists
there are applications for all of those
types of seeds do what you love and
don't let anybody out there stop you
from growing from your heart when we are
shopping for seeds we are thrown a lot
of information some of it is very useful
some of it is just fluff for advertising
somewhere in that information we should
be able to tell if the seeds we are
shopping for our regular feminized or
autoflowering that should be clearly
noted somewhere in the description if I
don't see any sort of notation I
generally assume they are regular seeds
now that's a really good place to start
what do I mean by regular seed by
regular seed I mean they were produced
conventionally they were made with a
male plant and a female plant so in that
package of seeds you will find males and
females they are also not Otto flower
which means they are photo period now
let's talk briefly about photo period
photo period means that a plant is
triggered into its flowering stage by a
light cycle in nature
this light cycle is mostly dictated by
your location in relation to the equator
are you right on the equator are you far
north or are you far south of the
Equator
now as the seasons change as fall rolls
around regions on the equator will start
experiencing longer nights and shorter
days those longer nights and shorter
days tell our plant Hey
winter is coming you need to start
producing
your flowers so that you can reproduce
before the end of the season and that
triggers the plant to go into flowering
that is its photo period indoors most
cannabis plants require about a 12 hour
dark period to induce flower outdoors
can be different because the Sun puts
off different spectrums they trigger the
plants to go to sleep as the Sun sets it
puts off a red spectrum that tells that
plant hey it's nighttime and then it
starts going to sleep as the Sun rises
it puts off a blue spectrum that tells
the plant it's time to wake up so you
don't need the 1212 outdoors you can
work closer to a 14-hour day and more of
a 10 hour night outdoors because the Sun
tells the plants to go to sleep but that
is photo period the plants work off the
light cycle and the light cycle works
with nature outdoors indoors we're
controlling that with a timer so that is
basically photo period if your seeds are
marked regular seeds or if it says photo
on the package that indicates that those
plants will be triggered to flower by
reducing your light schedule to 12 hours
on and 12 hours off now regular seeds
also indicates that there will be males
and females in that package of seeds if
you're trying to grow a seedless crop
you will have to pay attention and keep
the males out of the flowering room
somewhere between 7 and 10 days those
plants will start showing their sex
you'll have to go through and pull out
all of the males if you leave one male
plant in there for too long it will
pollinate and all of the plants around
it will be seated and depending on how
long you let that male go and how much
pollen he released and how much wind
flow and how much movement you have in
that grow you may see the entire crop
with just one male so that is basically
regular seed they are regular seed they
were bred conventionally traditionally
with a male and a female plant they are
photosensitive which means they will
trigger into flower by reducing the
lights to approximately 12 hours on at
12 hours off some plants will work one
hour either direction you could go 13
hours on you could go 13 hours off you
could play with that but we recommend 12
12 is the critical period also you will
find males and females in your regular
seeds if you're not looking to do any
breeding if you want to grow seedless
cannabis you do need to call those males
so that's the only major downfall of
regular seeds when you buy a package of
regular seeds you've got about a 50-50
chance of getting males and females it's
hard to dictate what you get with
regular seeds now a lot of people don't
want to waste the energy the time the
space or the money buying and growing
seeds that could possibly be males and
need to be removed from the garden now
that is where feminized seeds come into
play a lot of people have hatred toward
feminized seeds because they are
misinformed a lot of people have hatred
or a bias against feminized seeds
because there were a few breeders back
in the day that put out a batch of
feminized seeds newer total [ __ ] and a
few people bought those and it put a bad
taste in their mouth and those people
spread that taste throughout the
internet and I understand when you get a
terrible product you want to tell people
people believe you I get that but that
was way back in the day we have come a
long way since then we understand how to
produce feminized seeds on a commercial
scale and there are a lot of breeders
and producers out there putting out
reliable quality feminized seeds when
they are made properly feminized seeds
will produce plants they give you 99.9
percent females this is nature and
science together so there will be
anomalies you will find things that
don't fall into the chart that we drew
because that's how nature works that's
why we say 99.9 percent if I do my job
correctly when I produce feminized seeds
you will get 99.9 percent female plants
I'll give you a brief explanation on how
I make feminized seeds and how a lot of
the leading feminized seed producers
make their products I create a solution
of silver thiosulfate that is really
easy to learn how to do all the
instructions for that are readily
available on the internet you can make a
silver thiosulfate solution from
products that are easily attainable on
the internet for less than $30 get these
products I use product number one and
product number two I mix them into water
then I mix the two things of water
together now I've got my silver
thiosulfate concentration i dilute that
each plant that I'm using requires a
different dilution and application rate
there is a standard that I start with
the basic dilution that I recommend to
start with would be a 1 to 9 ratio
silver thiosulfate to water so you've
got nine parts water one part of the
silver thiosulfate concentrate mixed
into there
shake that up real well and apply that
to the plant on the first day of flower
and then apply it every three days for
21 days so you're going to give the
plant seven full applications and spray
it until it drips and get the stalks
don't just get the leaves get in there
and spray the stalks and be careful when
you're using the silver thiosulfate
spray because it may turn some things
purple if you've got a white wall
depending on which are up against
whatever that hits it could turn it
purple
including your skin so be careful wear
gloves wear a mask when working with the
silver thiosulfate solution that is
always my recommendation so I take the
silver thiosulfate solution that I have
created then I apply it I mix it at a
dilution of nine to one nine parts
distilled water one part silver
thiosulfate concentrate then I apply it
to the plants every three days for 21
days it gets twenty-one applications
then usually around day twenty five to
thirty it starts putting out pollen
that's when I start collecting the pall
and I put something usually a piece of
glass just depends on where I am and
what I'm working with and put a piece of
glass near the plant collects and pollen
as it naturally falls out pick the male
flowers out of there gather that let it
dry then when it really starts getting
dumping that's what I'll move it right
over by the girls and give it a good
shake and now we have just made
feminized seeds I've still got six or
seven weeks of nourishing those seeds
but if I have done everything carefully
and done everything correctly I have
created feminized seeds and there should
be no reason why those should be
problematic unless I completely screw up
the next six or seven weeks which is
very unlikely because all I've got to do
is make sure the equipment functions
make sure everything stays on a 12-2 op
cycle I've got to feed it properly I
know how to feed plants that are
pregnant I know how to produce quality
seeds I've got a defoliant and I've also
got to make sure to keep everything pest
and problem free and I'm quite
experienced at all that so far so there
should be no problem I also make sure to
thoroughly test run every batch of seeds
I make before they make it to market I
grow some out myself
I give up bunch out to my friends I'm
sure you guys see on Instagram people
have the new stuff you're like how did
they get that it's because they grew
something of mine I was impressed by it
I reached out to them and I said hey you
want to
my next batch I need you to take good
notes take good photos send it all back
to me and then I'll know if I want to
release that line or not so I have other
people grow it I grow it myself we test
it before it's put out to market that
way I know that you're receiving a
quality product I'm gonna go off way on
a side right here that's not even
written down when I make a new strain so
let's just say I just pulled some seeds
out of a plant last night that's a brand
new cross nobody's ever seen it I've
never seen it I don't know what it's
gonna do before those seeds go anywhere
I'm going to throw a handful of them in
a paper towel and germinate them and
then in 24 hours I'm gonna pop it open
and I'm gonna see how many have sprouted
tails and I'm gonna make a note and I'm
gonna write down the ratio however out
of a hundred they sprouted tails or they
did not sprout tails then I'll close it
back up and I'll let the other ones keep
going or I'll see in 36 hours how many
made tails and I'll take good notes then
I'll put some of those the ones that did
sprout tails and look good I'm gonna put
those into some cups of dirt and I'm
gonna grow them and I'm gonna pay
attention to them and I'm gonna keep a
lot of notes I'm gonna veg them I'm
gonna flour them I'm gonna grow them I'm
gonna dry them cure them smoke them make
concentrates out of them smoke the
concentrates we're at least 120 days
from even knowing what that product
tastes like probably closer to 150 with
the dry and cure phase in there then
that is my first grow with it if I
approve then I'll pass some seeds on to
grim if grim Bowl grows it and it looks
good in his garden I'll spread it out to
a few more people if they grow it well
that's when I'll let it go to a vendor
or for retail but I test the [ __ ] out of
my feminized seeds and my regular seats
so I stand behind my product and
honestly every feminized seed that I
produce sells
I can't keep feminized seeds in stock
and I don't get any complaints on my
feminized seed products so that's how
things are made that's how I make my fam
the advantage to feminized seeds is
there are no males to remove from the
garden you know that every seed you
plant will result in a harvested crop
you won't have to grow it long enough to
sex it you won't be wasting any time
that's advantageous for people who live
in medical states or anybody who is
limited by a plant count so your
feminized seeds are all going to be
females that you would say why would
people grow photoperiod seeds when they
can grow them and I see
and guarantee that everything they grow
makes it to harvest like I said a lot of
people have a bias against feminized
seeds also a lot of people like myself
like finding the males breeding with
females and reversed females and alpha
females is a great practice but I like
working with a solid male plant I've got
a passion for conventional breeding I do
make feminized seeds but I have more fun
with conventional breeding another thing
you may notice when you're shopping for
seeds is that feminized seeds are about
twice the price of regular seeds so yes
you do get viable females that you can
take to harvest but that pack of seeds
cost exactly twice is what a regular
pack of seeds cost although you didn't
have to waste the time the space the
soil the energy and you didn't have to
have that extra plant count to add to
your numbers in your legal garden so if
the packaging says feminized seeds that
means that 99.9 percent of the plants
that come out of that seed package will
be females now here's something that is
kind of a side rant that I was talking
to somebody on social media about that I
want to include in a podcast I'm just
gonna give it a couple of seconds we
talked about the flip when we flipped a
flower feminized and regular photo
period seeds we flip them to flower by
changing the light cycle either from 24
on and 0 off to 18 on and 6 off or
however you've got your light cycle set
up then you switch to 12 on and 12 off
you are now in flower or if you're gonna
follow the DJ short plan you go 11 on 13
off that's a whole other podcast
anyway we flipped a flower that is day
one of flower your seed package will
give you an estimate of how long they
need to flower nine to 10 weeks 60 to 70
days whatever it says the day you
initiated that flip is day one not the
day you see bud set not the day you
smell something not the day the
butterflies flew in and did their magic
dance the day you change that timer is
day one of flower that's how you keep
track of that that's what we're talking
about when we indicated that on the seed
package just wanted to add that side
note I'm not sure if that was even
relevant but there you go a little bonus
nugget for your brain all right now
let's work into autoflowering seeds
let's talk about otto flowers what do i
mean by an autoflowering seed earlier
I was talking about your location in
relation to the equator most of us live
in an area where we see seasonal changes
and we also see changes in day and night
time but keep in mind there are parts of
Russia and Alaska that will receive
extreme stretches of daylight and night
time without interruption there are some
points in Alaska when they will have
full sunlight for 80 days in a row they
will not get a night for 80 solid days
cannabis is an extraordinary plant and
it has evolved the cannabis that we are
familiar with which is evolved from
these extreme conditions with no dark is
known as ruderalis these ruderalis
plants have evolved to flower without
any dark period after so many
generations they went hey it doesn't get
dark we need to do something about this
so through evolution they started to
flower without a dark period a lot of
those ruderalis plants have no desirable
effect when smoked but they have a lot
of desirable traits when grown some of
them stay short they stay squat they
push out really nicely and you don't
have to change the light cycle to
convince them to flower for you so
cannabis breeders got a hold of
ruderalis plants and they bred them
together they bred our autoflowering
ruderalis to our high potency cannabis
plants and the offspring resulted in
high potency autoflowering cannabis
plants most of the autoflowering seeds
available for most breeders now are
feminized so you'll get autoflowering
seeds that are all girls which is really
advantageous and we'll talk about that
in just a minute
I should warn you that when you're
looking at seeds and you see feminized
seeds on there also look to see if they
say photo period or Auto flower on there
make sure they indicate that if they
don't there are probably photo period
all of the auto flower guys like to let
you know that you're working with Auto
flowers they clearly indicate that on
the package and earlier I mentioned that
feminized seeds cost twice as much as
regular Auto flowers generally cost
twice as much as feminized so you got
your regular then they're doubled then
they're even doubled again so they will
let you know if there are auto flowers
just make sure you read the package when
you're buying your seat that'll either
say regular
feminized or Auto flower just do a
little research before you buy your
seeds make sure you know what you're
getting now let's talk a little bit
about how these auto flower seeds are
useful if you've been listening to the
show for a while
you love my favorite example of these
Auto flowers and use several years ago
there was a very large grow discovered
in a national forest not too far from
here and it was discovered that that
grow was ran by a cartel as the reports
and pictures came out they were saying
that the cartel had three different
stages of growth happening in their
illegal grow area now that really made
me wonder how are they growing different
stages outdoors because the Sun dictates
what our plants do if they put him
outside they all went into flower at the
same time then my brain went dude
they're using Auto flowers so this large
cartel would set a patch of auto flower
plants then they would wait a few weeks
and they would set another large patch
of auto flower plants wait a few weeks
and set another large patch of auto
flower plants tor eventually they had a
perpetual cycle going to where they had
people out there in this national forest
does camouflaged hidden growing a
perpetual grow packaging up and sending
it to who knows where I have no idea
where it was going but they were
producing quite a bit of cannabis out
there by using Auto flowers they had a
perpetual grow under the natural Sun
they didn't have to veg and then flower
they could just throw the seeds out
there they would grow and do their thing
so that's one way where auto flower
seeds were highly effective now let's
scale that down a little bit let's say
you've only got one grow space and you
want to produce a perpetual grow you
don't have a bedroom you don't have a
flower room you can't go buy clones from
a friend you can't have a friend veg for
you the way you could run a small self
sustainable perpetual grow is with Auto
flower plants in one room fill up a
quarter or half of the room with Auto
flowers as soon as they start flowering
plant more Auto flowers and put them in
the same room you'll have veg plants and
flowering plants in the same room you
can't do that with photo period plants
so if you're limited on space if you've
only got one room that's a really useful
method and a really useful application
for auto flowering plants the major
downside that iceice auto flowering
plants is you always have to buy new
seeds you can
clone an auto flowering plant if you're
growing with regular or feminized
photoperiod seeds you're always able to
cut a clone you can keep that clone as a
mother you can keep it perpetually and
then you can always clone off of that
mother and you can keep that plant
sustainable with Auto flowers you're
always going to be buying new seeds and
earlier I mentioned most of the Auto
flower companies are only putting out
feminized so you're not even able to
breed your own Auto flowers with males
and females anymore you're gonna have to
reverse one and I have no experience
doing that all right you guys that is my
breakdown on regular seeds feminized
seeds and autoflowering seeds the
regular seeds are always photo period I
like them because we find males and
females
I like breeding with the regular seeds
that's a lot of fun for me
the feminized seeds can be photo period
or they can be Auto flower they are
probably well marked on the packaging
those are always going to be females if
they were bred properly I've done a
whole nother podcast episode about
marking feminized seeds with s or r1
generations I encourage you to listen to
that one that one is episode 331 and
it's titled selfing and reversals you
learn a lot about why we label the
packages the way we do also I recommend
you listen to an episode called seed
pack expectations and that is number 245
there's a lot of useful information in
that episode for anyone who's
considering purchasing new seeds then
we'll keep it moving we talked about
autoflowering seeds auto flowering
plants are unique to photoperiod plants
because they flower based on their size
or their age we can put them under the
veg lights we can have them in the 1860
and they will still flower and they will
still produce buds a lot of auto
flowering plants boast that they will be
completely done around ten weeks so
that's 70 days of a full cycle with a
photo period plant you've got closer to
a hundred and twenty days if you want
usable product so that is my lesson on
regular feminized and autoflowering
seeds I hope I made your decision easier
when it comes time to go shopping don't
be afraid to try regular seeds don't be
afraid to try feminized seeds and don't
be afraid to try Auto flower seeds you
just may fall in love with something you
never thought you would even like and
don't forget you can find your seeds at
DANC seed dot store we're working on a
Black Friday sale you guys this
get interesting you guys have only been
gone for about 22 minutes but honestly
my recording here has been giving me a
couple of technical issues and my throat
is obviously burning out so I'm gonna
wrap this up while I've still got a
quality podcast on the screen I don't
want to lose any of the stuff I recorded
so please do support me on patreon at
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
stalk me on all the social media on
Facebook it's the girl from your heart
podcast on Twitter it's @gf wih podcast
on twitter i use the other company it's
Irie underscore genetics also you can
email me and grow from your heart at
hotmail.com don't forget about the
YouTube channel simply search for the
girl from your heart podcast on YouTube
click Subscribe watch the videos leave
some comments I would appreciate your
support there you guys know I'll be back
in just a few days with a fresh new
episode I'll get all the equipment fixed
up so I quit getting glitches in the
recording gear and I don't have to wrap
up the end so quickly I want to give you
a huge shout out to my friend Roger and
until next time take a phat dab and give
your mom a hug for me
welcome to the show cannabis community
it's time for episode 363 of the Grove
from your heart podcast this episode is
brought to you by the hella deep seed
company if you need new regular or
feminized seeds for your garden I highly
recommend the hella dank seed company
and you can find them at dank seed dot
store I like to start the episodes off
by letting you know what I'm smoking I
just finished the last dab of the orange
skittles ambrosia that left a nice
orange flavor in my mouth gave me a nice
head buzz I followed that up with the
last dab of the bubble Jack
full-spectrum extract from Fuego
extracts that was delicious
the combo made me super rambley and gave
me a lot of energy so this will be a fun
podcast if you've been following along
you know I'm doing a long series of grow
lessons if you haven't been following
along I suggest you go back to episode
351 and start there and get caught up
that will give you a solid foundation on
planning your grow and getting prepared
for your new grow if you've been
following along you know that we've
selected our space we've selected our
equipment we've done a lot of talk about
genetics and now this episode is going
to be about sprouting our new seeds
let's not waste too much time let's jump
right into it seeds can be expensive
depending on who you ordered them from
how many you BA
what kind you purchased you may have
spent a lot of money on seeds before you
think about germinating your new seeds I
highly recommend you have your veg area
ready to rock before you even think
about starting your seeds
you're gonna think oh I can just driven
ate these seeds and then I'll build up
this veg room in the next couple of days
and then while they veg will work on the
flower room once you get plants going
you start time-traveling things go so
much more quickly than you anticipate
things pop up things get in your way
then you fall behind then those seeds
you just paid a bunch of money for start
growing funky they get out of control
and you've got shitty plants to start
with and you're frustrated from the
beginning
so before you germinate your seeds have
your veg space prepared that is my very
first piece of advice to you that will
save you a lot of frustration now my
second piece of advice is to start with
quality seed try to get your seeds from
a reputable vendor and also from a
reputable breeder don't fall for hype
when you're shopping for seeds don't be
sold try to find somebody with a good
reputation somebody that you have heard
of and also try to buy those seeds from
a vendor with the good reputation
somebody that you have heard of somebody
that has a good relationship with the
breeders and if you're going to buy
seeds online I recommend you buy from a
seed vendor in the United States that
way you don't have to risk customs of
course I recommend the hella DANC seed
company
I also recommend the seed Bazaar and I
can also vouch for Southern Oregon seeds
those are three quality seed vendors
that I trust and respect and I work with
them personally so I know they will take
good care of you I'm not bashing any
other seed company I'm just saying I
rely on these three companies I have
worked with them I've got a relationship
with them and I know they are rock-solid
so I recommend you start with a quality
seed something you know what the parents
of that seed were something you know
where it came from
if you don't have access to fancy label
the expensive seeds grow what you've got
in an ideal world we would all go to the
store and we look at the shelf and we'd
say you've got that strain that was the
best I've ever smoked I want seeds of
that and I get that that's everybody's
fantasy that day is coming unfortunately
we are not there yet for everybody some
people are going to have to be
resourceful you may have bought a bag of
weed ten years ago it's
random place and it had seeds in it then
you're gonna have to grow those seeds
you never know what you're gonna get out
of those seeds you could find duds you
could find hermaphrodites you may find
the next magical strain in there so grow
what you've got no matter where your
seeds come from whether they're regular
whether they're feminized seeds pay
close attention to them pay attention
for males pay attention for
hermaphrodite um pay attention for
problems you will have to keep an eye
out when you're growing from seed now if
you've got a bag of seeds lying around
and you don't know what any of them are
it's just a perhaps a sandwich bag or a
little mason jar just stuffed with
random seeds from bags of cannabis
you've gone through over time and you
can't decide what to grow I go for the
really healthy-looking seeds and by
healthy I mean probably darker probably
bigger a lot of people like the tiger
stripes that's always a good sign some
seeds will not make tiger stripes no
matter how long they grow no matter how
mature no matter how healthy and strong
they are
they just won't stripe up that's just a
genetic thing I prefer the darker
colored seeds the harder seeds I give
them a little press on the table I hope
they don't crack if they don't crack
that's probably a good seed if it cracks
it obviously isn't gonna grow that too
dead seed a lot of people like a larger
cannabis seed but I've noticed that a
lot of strains produce little tiny seeds
so sometimes a little tiny cannabis seed
can produce a seriously potent plant
don't judge it too much by the size
judge it more by the health of the seed
a lot of the grayer white colored seeds
will grow I don't put those in my packs
because people freak out I grow those
myself but those lighter gray the paler
colored seeds those will grow the white
seeds those are more questionable I
don't think the white seeds do as well
the gray kind of silver shiny seeds
those usually have a good take off the
darker ones those take off quite quickly
and then of course you get those bigger
harder tiger-stripe seeds those really
have a lot of figure and they take off
really quickly for you so seed health is
important selecting healthy seeds if
you've got a big bag of seeds try to
select the healthiest looking beans out
of that bag maybe a couple of them just
call you maybe you've got a bag of a
thousand seeds and two of them just go
hey bro I'm the seeds you want to grow
right now listen to that kind of stuff
that is usually accurate alright now
we've got our veg space ready we know
what to look for in quality seeds we've
got some seeds on hand and it is
to germinate our seeds what do I mean by
germinate it's just a fancy word for
starting the seeds we need to give them
the proper conditions to make them start
we want to crack the seed open we don't
want to do it we want it to happen
naturally we want the seed to crack
itself open and we want a little tiny
tap root to come fishing out and that is
the start of life in nature those seeds
would fall out of last year's but winter
would come it would knock those seeds at
those the buds would dry the wind and
the moisture would knock those seeds out
of those buds those buds would fall into
the ground winter would come and
everything would be frozen for a little
while as the spring came and the winter
frost or the winter moisture started
moistening down into the soil those
seeds would begin to receive moisture
and warmth from nature that would
trigger them to Germany than they would
sprout up they would find their way up
dig up out of the soil they'd start
seeing Sun and they'd go Here I am and
then they would live and they would
become little baby cannabis plants now
human involvement will we've done we
have collected the seeds before they
fall out of the but when I breed I let
the plants get done and let the seeds
get finished I cut the plants down I let
them hang they dry then I basically
crumble up the buds and I manually
remove the Caesar several methods of
doing that that's not important right
now but that process happened then those
seeds were passed on to you that you
have to play the role of mother nature
we have to give these seeds the proper
environment to trigger them to start
their life the two main things that are
going to start our seeds are water and
warmth the main thing being water warmth
very secondary to that warmth will speed
up the process and make them much
happier now there are countless ways to
start new seeds I'm going to cover four
or five methods here in this episode and
I'm going to start with the method I use
personally I like the old school paper
towel technique it is very simple I get
a plate out of the cover just a glass
plate like you serve a meal on or make a
sandwich I also get a paper towel just
like you'd use to clean up that meal or
that sandwich I fold the paper towel one
time then I fold it again now you've
just got a little rectangular paper
towel I set that paper towel on to the
glass plate and then I get a bottle of
water
I prefer bottled water for this because
I don't want the chlorine or whatever
else
in my tap water affecting my new
ceilings so I've got the folded paper
towel sitting on the plate I simply soak
that paper towel with water it will only
hold so much I simply saturate it then I
tip the plate to the side to make sure
all that excess water runs out of the
paper towel and off of that plate just
drain it right off into the sink that
water is gone so now you've got a soggy
paper towel in the middle of a plate
I place my seeds in the paper towel and
then I gently fold it one more time if
you want to fold it another time you can
and make a little tiny square that's
fine but I think that first fold will be
just fine
just fold it up toward those seeds or in
the middle and they're getting wet and
they're not getting any light the way
that that wet paper towel works it'll
kind of seal itself up so the seeds
won't move around too much there won't
be any light in there so you've got some
seeds folded up in a wet paper towel and
those are sitting on a plate now at this
point you've got a couple of options if
you are able to pay attention to those
seeds and be around them all the time
and make sure they don't get dry you can
just leave them on that plate and leave
them exposed if it's not too hot or not
too cold in your area they will sprout
just fine just left sitting like that if
you want to slow down the amount of
moisture leaving that paper towel and
try to keep it moist a little bit longer
without having to pay so much attention
just set another plate over it flip the
plate upside down and set it on top of
the first plate just like you do if you
had a sandwich in there and he didn't
want anything to get to the sandwich so
you just got two plates with your little
folded up paper towel in there
you have to keep it moist at all times
do not let it get dry if you feel like
you're going to get forgetful or if you
need to go to work for an extended
period of time and you cannot monitor
the moisture of your new seedlings you
can always set them in a baggie put your
folded paper towel with the moisture in
it in a baggie this will give the
moisture nowhere to go it will be
trapped inside that little environment
just make sure you check on them as soon
as you get home from work if you leave
that wet paper towel folded up in a
baggie in a really warm spot for too
long you can create a mildew situation
so make sure you pop that open get some
fresh air in there and
check on that as soon as you get home
from work so it sounds really easy
because it is you were folding a paper
towel into a square
your moistening it you're letting the
excess moisture run off we set the seeds
onto that moist paper towel and then we
fold it to cover them up and then if you
need to place another plate over it to
slow down the dry time if you're really
forgetful and you're gonna be away for a
while put it in a baggie to retain that
moisture then set it somewhere semi warm
most of the time if you are comfortable
in that area your ceilings are probably
comfortable as well room temperature is
acceptable for seedlings a great spot
for seedlings if you do not forget them
is on top of the refrigerator that
temperature that happens right on top of
the refrigerator is perfect for
seedlings if you don't forget them put
them in a baggie set them right on top
they should be ready in 12 to 24 maybe
36 hours if you've got one of those old
big TVs nobody's got those big old TVs
anymore they used to get warm on the
back that was a great spot to set
seedlings and a baggie was on the back
of the old Sony Trinitron 36 inch TV
where it got warm from playing video
games all day that would be the perfect
temp for seedlings other than those
subtle heat sources like the top of the
fridge or the back of the TV I really
don't recommend a heat map for
germinating new seeds or for your clones
I've seen more clones and seeds
destroyed roasted and barbecued than I
have ever seen assisted by one of those
heat mats but I'm gonna talk about that
more later in the episode I think so
let's skip that for now and try to stay
focused alright so we've got our
seedlings they are folded up in a paper
towel we're keeping them moist we don't
want them soggy we don't want them
dripping all the time we want to keep
them moist and comfortable so you've got
them folded in the paper towel and you
were checking on them every few hours if
you were able they're easy to check on
just set your hand right on that paper
towel don't crush the seeds just set
your hand on there gently and if the
paper towel is kind of cold kind of
chilly
they're probably wet enough if you don't
feel like it's wet enough moisten it up
a little bit get your water bottle and
just pour the water on there gently and
then tip the Tiye that plate over toward
the excess water runs off into the sink
and then you've got a moistened up for
the rest of the day they should only be
in this paper towel for 12 to 24 maybe
36 or 48 hours before
you see them starting to pop open it
will pop open on one side and a little
white tail will start coming out that is
exactly what we are looking for that is
the start of life that is a taproot that
is the beginning of everything that
little root is gonna dig down into the
pot once we pot it and it's gonna dig
down and start finding nutrients and
that's gonna be the legs that's gonna be
the foundation and then it's gonna start
shooting that seedling straight upward
toward the light and then it's gonna
shoot little leaves out of there and
that little seedling will fall off and
then you've got a little plant so that
is the start of everything happening
right there and you get to see it
because you've just got it right there
in that paper towel it's not buried
under anything so you can check on them
check on them about twelve hours if you
don't see anything check on them in 24
hours if you don't see anything go 36
you're gonna get impatient after 24
hours you'll be checking out on every 4
to 6 hours don't worry just keep
checking don't forget about them we only
need maybe an eighth of an inch maybe a
quarter of an inch of that tap root to
pop out before our seedlings are ready
to put into soil but we will get to that
so I think I covered how to germinate
seeds in a paper towel you fold it you
wet it you drain it put the seeds in
there fold it again and then you keep an
eye on it and keep it moist keep it
slightly warm but don't roast it if you
think you might forget about your
seedlings place the paper towel set up
and a baggie and that will keep them
moist until you open it once again don't
forget about them make sure you check on
them then when you unfold that paper
towel and you've got a little tap root
sticking out that's when it's time to
get ready to put them into your potting
mix but we're gonna talk about that a
little bit later the only thing left to
cover in this section is what if those
seeds don't pop open after 48 hours the
only thing you can really do is wait a
little bit longer maybe increase the
heat if you didn't already set them on
the fridge maybe set them up there on
top of the refrigerator where it's a
little warmer
maybe lessen the moisture maybe you've
got them a little too wet maybe just
keep that paper towel just damp maybe
you've still got a little bit of a
chance but if they haven't opened after
48 or 72 hours I would consider starting
a fresh batch of seeds at that point now
if it is really cold in your environment
it will take longer for your seeds to
germinate so expect that if you're
growing in the basement in Colorado
you've got them sitting right
on a concrete floor that's gonna take
longer consider your environment like I
said earlier the warmth will speed
things up but that too can go wrong in
excess so try to stay in the right area
try to be about 70 to 85 degrees ish and
you should be okay with rapid growth for
your seeds now let's talk about our next
method for sprouting our seeds our next
method is using rapid rooters or route
riots or whatever type of plugs are
available in your area
although I am NOT including rock wool
cubes in this section I don't like rock
wool cubes for sprouting seeds they do
not work well for sprouting seeds I
would not recommend that if it's what
you've got do it similarly to what I
recommend here with the rapid rooters
but before you use your rock wool cubes
make sure you clean them out and make
sure you soak them in a pH balanced
solution rinse them very well to get
anything out of them then soak them
either in clean water or a light
nutrient solution that has been pH
around 6 you don't want to use rock wool
cubes without rinsing them and adjusting
the pH so this is all about rapid
rooters or riot plugs when we start with
these plugs we need to soak them so I
get a container based on the amount of
plugs I'm going to use I'm generally
using a five-gallon bucket I think
they're sold in a 50 pack so most of the
time I just do all 50 and I either do 50
clones or 50 ceilings I just use the
whole package you soak as many as you
need what I do is I get a container it
will fit enough water to soak as many
plugs as I'm going to use I adjust the
pH to somewhere between 6 and 6 3 I
usually place the rapid Rooter plugs
back into the rapid Rooter tray if
you're not using the tray that's okay
you don't need it but that's usually
what I do I put it right in the tray
then I take a seed and I insert the seed
into the rapid Rooter plug that seed
goes pointy end down if you look at your
seeds it's got a round end and it's got
a pointy end it will be obvious when you
look at it the pointy end goes down this
is important because of the way that the
seed grows pointy end down when you are
putting it into a rapid Rooter or any
sort of a cube or if you are going
directly into soil pointy end down all
so if you are going into a rapid Rooter
if you're going into a root riot cube if
you're going into soil or if you're
going against my advice and you're going
directly into rock wool it is always
suggested that you plant your seeds
about one knuckle deep just go just the
tip of your finger just push it in until
you press that first knuckle right that
first bend in your finger that's far
enough stop pushing that ceiling is deep
enough into the soil it's deep enough
into that cube it will live there it
doesn't need to be buried way down in
there it stands a much better chance if
it's just about knuckle deep as all you
need to go so after I've got all my
seedlings planted and I've got all my
cubes labeled make sure you label each
cube if you're planning different
strains make sure you've got a way to
label each cube so you know what you've
got also label if you're doing more than
one paper-towel of seeds make sure you
label that paper towel some way most of
you're just doing one pack of seeds or
one strain but if you're doing multiple
please carefully label things so we've
got our seeds they are in our rapid
Rooter cubes they're carefully labeled
they are nice and moist they are about
knuckle deep down into the end of the
cube now I place them under a very white
light you don't need very powerful
lighting for sprouting seeds a really
weak LED or a t5 kind of high up is
plenty of lighting a compact fluorescent
is probably just enough light you don't
need to go extreme for a ceiling just
enough to encourage it to grow once it
gets bigger we do need light but right
now we don't need ridiculous lighting
for a small seedling so place it under a
light that will give you a warmth and
that will encourage it to grow now in
about two or three days maybe four or
five days at the latest you should see a
little sprout pop out of your cube and
you have now got a little seedling now
that seedling can live in that little
rapid Rooter for several days but it's
going to need a forever home it's going
to need to go into either some soil or a
hydro set up fairly soon while it's in
that rapid Rooter we need to keep it
warm we need to keep it somewhere
between 70 and 85 degrees and we need to
keep that root cube moist at all times
once it dries up that plant has no live
source and it will die so keep it moist
and keep it warm and keep it under a
light and then we need to think about
getting it into a good potting mix or
into a hydro system very soon so that it
can thrive
that is the basics of sprouting a seed
in a rapid Rooter or a root riot cube or
against my advice if you choose to use a
rock wool cube you would use a similar
method basically soak it with a proper
pH solution then press the ceiling in
pointy in down and only go about a
knuckle deep set it under a light and
leave it alone for two or three days you
should see a little sprout pop up if you
don't see the sprout pop up look in the
little hole and see what you see
sometimes the seedling simply gets
caught and it's bent over and it can't
pop itself up out of the root cube that
happens you can carefully get a pair of
tweezers or a chopstick and very gently
encourage that plant to grow straight up
don't pull it out of the seed casing
don't pull it out of the cube maybe
spread the whole of the cube open just a
little bit and encourage it to pop out
of there just needs to bend up and come
out
you can probably guide it out if you're
gentle if it's close to doing it on its
own don't touch it just let it struggle
and it will come out if you feel like
it's been long enough and you're getting
impatient just give it a little tug it
may pop out for you keep in mind you're
risking killing this ceiling if you get
too rough you're going to destroy it if
you get too rough but you've got a good
chance just use your thumbs and spread
that Rapid Rooter open just a little
tiny bit and you may open it just enough
for that seed to unbind itself and be
able to pop straight up it may just be
stuck it's trying to move up in the two
leaves on the top they just got stuck
somewhere that happens quite a bit it'll
just have to break itself free so pay
attention to that if it doesn't pop up
in four or five days if the others have
popped up and you've got one that didn't
pop up look in there that could be the
issue with that one seedling now let's
kind of touch on another method that is
very similar to the rapid rooters and
the root riot cubes but it is also very
different this next method you cannot
put this into a hydro kit as simply as
you could a rapid Rooter or as simply as
you could a seed from a paper towel I'm
sure some people have done it I'm sure
some people do it but it's not as easy
it's much more challenging and it's not
as logical so let's talk about using
jiffy cubes jiffy cubes are great if
you're going to go into soil but like I
said you can't really use them going
into a hydro system I'm sure there's
somebody doing it gonna tell me I'm
wrong but it's not common so a jiffy
cube they're very similar to the rapid
rooters but they start off really small
any moisten them and they expand to the
proper size so you moisten them they
puff up you squeeze the excess water out
of them then from there they work just
like the rapid rooters or the root riot
cubes you place your seeding and sealing
in their pointy end down you go about
knuckle deep and then you've got to keep
your jiffy cube moist just like you do
with your other cubes now if you're
using rapid rooters or brute riots or
jiffy cubes or if you're going against
my advice still and using the rock wool
cubes
make sure not to get them too moist for
too long if they are too moist it will
simply rot your ceilings they will turn
green they will turn brown it will fall
over and die or they will not even
germinate at all there's a big
difference between being soaked and
being wet and being moist we want to
soak them in the beginning put the seeds
in there when they are soaked then just
keep it wet from there you can usually
tell by looking at the rapid rooters how
dry or wet they are when they start
getting that brown crusty color they're
too dry when they start getting that
Sheen to them they start showing a
little silver a little light reflection
that's just right when they're really
really black that's when they are soaked
so learn how to identify soaked and
saturated and wet and moist and create a
little scale for yourself I did the 1
through 5 watering technique maybe we
need a similar thing for the rapid
rooters I kind of just did that if
they're totally soaked in black that's a
5 if they're dry and crispy that's a 1
we need to keep them about a 3 at all
times ladies and gentlemen so there we
go 1 through 5 tech on rapid rooters
just like we did on watering normal
plants so now we know how to germinate
seeds in paper towels we know how to
germinate seeds in rapid rooters we kind
of know how to do it in rock wool cubes
we know how to germinate seeds in jiffy
cubes it is just like doing it in the
rapid rooters you guys you moisten them
they expand you squeeze the excess water
out of there then you treat it just like
a rapid Rooter from there our next
option is to plant our seedlings
directly into soil that's the way
happens in nature why wouldn't we do
that in our personal garden so let's
talk a little bit about planting our
seeds directly into soil or the medium
we are going to use if you plan to start
your seedling in soil I highly recommend
you use a very small container I would
recommend a beer cup or something that
size there's no reason to have a tiny
tiny plant in a large container of soil
so my first recommendation is a small
container with plenty of drainage my
second recommendation will be a good
soil for starter plants something with a
lot of aeration and something with not
too much nutrients added to it maybe
something with some mykos or maybe some
beneficial bacteria that's good but we
don't need a lot of boosts for our
little babies so start with a small
container of high quality starter soil
so I've got my container and I've got my
starter soil now i'm oice in that soil
before I put my seedlings into there
just simply water that soil with a pH
adjusted solution you don't need
nutrients just water pH around 6-2 6-3
you should be just fine just water it on
in let it drain out once it's done
draining take your pointer finger and
just make a little tiny hole just
knuckle deep just like I keep saying in
the episode I may name the episode that
just go about one knuckle deep into the
soil
then take your sealing and just set it
right inside that hole then gently press
the dirt right over that sealing just
real gently you don't need to pack it
down just cover up that ceiling and then
just let it rest and then within 24 to
48 for 36 maybe 72 hours you should see
a little baby plant just popping up
right out of there you'll just see two
little green leaves just popping right
up out of that top soil I like to keep
my little baby plants in the beer cups
under a t5 light I try to keep the light
kind of far and when they're little and
then as they get bigger I move the light
a little bit closer I try not to let
those seedlings get too stretchy if they
start getting a little leggy I move the
light closer I like to put a fan on them
while they're a little that gives them a
little strength makes them a little more
robust so there are advantages and
disadvantages to starting them in the
beer cup the advantage they're already
in their soil you don't have to up pot
them you don't have to transplant them
you don't have to do any
damage to a little seedling the
disadvantage is sometimes you just
completely lose a seedling and a beer
cup filled with soil sometimes they just
totally disappear sometimes they don't
sprout at all and sometimes you totally
drown them by trying to water so much
soil so starting them in beer cups in
soil is a little trickier but it may be
the only option for some people not
everybody is able to order rapid rooters
or root riot cubes not everybody has
access to a rock wool cube and some
people may just want to try it because
that's the way it happens in nature so
that is a rundown of my basic methods of
germinating seeds hopefully one of those
methods works for you honestly I use the
folded paper towel method the most in a
commercial environment I may use the
rapid Rooter method next but I honestly
do not start seeds directly in soil
anymore
I found that I can start a lot more in
much less space by using the rapid
rooters imagine the amount of space it
takes to start 100 rapid rooters
compared to 100 beer cups it's a large
difference in the amount of space that
you need I honestly don't have any
experience with the jiffy cubes I've
never had to use those I've always had
access to the rapid rooters and honestly
I've just been sticking with a paper
towel method so that's what I'm doing
the most I encourage you to use the
method that works the best for you I
encourage you also to try different
methods if you think something works
great why not try another method if
you've got some seeds that you can spare
why not try something you may find that
something works better for you all right
so now we've got our seeds germinated
we've either got some seeds folded into
a paper towel or we've got a rapid
Rooter or a root riot or a rock wall
cube with roots hanging out of the
bottom of the root cube our next step is
to pot our new seedling into a pot of
soil or soilless mix in this episode I
will cover how to pot the seeds
germinated from a paper towel into soil
but my next episode is going to be about
cutting clones then shortly after that
we will have to pop the clones into soil
which means I'm going to do a combo
episode of planting our new seedlings in
the rapid route
and planting clones in rapid rooters
into soil at the same time I'm just
gonna knock that out in one episode so
that part will be coming soon but for
now let's talk about planting our
freshly germinated seedlings that are
just sitting in a wet paper towel I like
to catch these seeds when the new tap
roots are very sure I don't like to get
it too long and too out of control
because I feel like that gives me too
much opportunity to cause it too much
stress so as soon as I see my seedlings
crack open a little bit and that little
tap root is sticking out just a little
tiny bit I'm comfortable putting them
into their soil or soilless mix and I do
that with a very similar method as I did
earlier when we talked about planting
seeds into the beer cups I get a beer
cup or a very small pot with plenty of
drainage I fill it with a quality soil
that is good for small plants something
with a lot of aeration and plenty of
drainage then I moisten that soil with
water pH around 6 to 6 3 then I do the
same thing as we've been doing the whole
episode I make a little tiny hole about
knuckle deep in that soil then I simply
place the germinated seed in that little
hole I do my best to point it with that
little white root pointing straight down
if your tap root is nice and short don't
worry about which direction your ceiling
is facing when you place it into soil it
should be just fine if it's really long
you may want to make sure you point that
root down and the seed is going up so
gently place your seedling in the soil
brush dirt over the top of it you don't
need to bury it or pack it down just
cover it and then the tap root will go
down it'll start to spread out and the
little tiny plant will grow up to the
top and it'll push the seedling with a
little set of tiny tiny leaves right
through the topsoil and you'll have a
little starter baby plant the main thing
to worry about when potting your new
seedlings is to not damage that little
white tap root sticking out of the
seedling
do your best not to disrupt stress or
damage that little white tap root
they're very delicate so once I've got
it potted I put it under a t5 light I
keep the light a little distance away so
that I don't shock the plant as the
plant gets bigger I bring the light a
little bit closer once I feel like the
plant is kind of taken off I put
fan on it and then once it gets its
first set of serrated leaves I start
adding very light doses of nutrients so
that is how I pop my ceiling
it was germinated from a paper towel I
basically fill a beer cup with good dirt
poke a hole in the bottom go knuckle
deep in the soil on the top drop my
little germinated seedling in there and
cover it up and then put it under the
light and wait for it to pop up and then
it grows and grows until I see a set of
leaves with serration and that is when I
start feeding it a little bit of light
nutrients now let's talk about a couple
of things that happen quite often when
we are working with seeds sometimes the
seed shell will get stuck to the seed
and hinder the seeds growth and threaten
that seeds life but it's not as scary as
it looks when it happens you'll know
what I'm talking about that seed hole
will just get stuck the the sealing will
come up out of the dirt and you'll see
that seed the leaves are trying to open
up it's trying to live and it's just
trying to open up but it can't because
that seed casing is just stuck to it it
is really easy to solve I get a spray
bottle with water and I moisten that
ceiling really heavily just spray it
with water just keep spraying it more
moisture more moisture more moisture
then see if you can just brush it off
with your finger it may just come right
off if not spray more water if that
still doesn't work get some tweezers and
just do a gentle dissection if it is
really moist you should be able to get
that seed casing off it is supposed to
come off of there that plant opens up
the way the plant opens itself up the
way that that seed casing spreads in
half it should pop right off of there
just give it a little assistance a
little moisture little tweezers maybe a
pair of chopsticks depending on how
skilled you are it shouldn't be too hard
to do don't be afraid to get in there
and pull that casing off earlier I
talked about not using heat mat I have
honestly seen people roast more seeds
with heat mats
than I've ever seen success with the
heat mat from a seedling the only time I
have ever needed a heat mat was when I
was growing in a warehouse in Colorado
and it was really cold during the winter
other times I don't use the heat mat for
cloning or for seedlings and I have
great success if you were comfortable in
the area your seedlings are probably
comfortable in that area also and I'm
not talking about some Colorado mountain
boy who's outside barefoot in the snow
I'm talking about a normal person room
temperature is acceptable for your
seedlings now I've got one more thing I
want to touch on before I start wrapping
up the episode and the note I wrote is
called pre-soak a lot of people like to
pre-soak their seeds before the official
germination if you've got older seeds
that have been sitting around for a
longer I meant may recommend you give
them a pre-soak it's really easy you
simply pre soak them in water before you
germinate them I recommend 12 hours
maybe 24 at the most never go more than
24 hours on a soak because that will
drown your seeds my theory behind the
pre-soak is some seeds just have a hard
outer coating and they don't want to
germinate very easily soaking them in
water for 24 hours will definitely
soften that outer coating and encourage
easier germination so if you've got
older seeds that you've been having a
problem getting to germinate
maybe soak them for 12 hours then give
them the paper towel method if that
doesn't work try soaking some for 24
hours then giving them the paper towel
method if that doesn't work then we're
going to need to try more scientific
approaches there are chemicals we can
add there are tricks we can do but that
is much more advanced science than what
we're prepared for today so if you've
got old seeds or if you feel like you've
got really hard seeds with the really
thick coating don't be afraid to give
them a pre-soak 12 to 24 hours never go
more than 24 hours I don't feel like
that's a good idea
all right you guys I feel like that is a
good lesson on how to germinate your
seeds I will not forget to teach you
guys how to pot those freshly sprouted
seeds that you've got in your rapid
rooters or your rock wool cubes like I
told you not to do or in your jiffy pots
will talk about that in a future episode
that is written down that is on the
schedule you guys want to thank you for
listening to another episode I want to
encourage you guys to support the
patreon campaign if you feel like this
podcast was educational informative or
entertaining and you'd like to make a
financial contribution to the show you
can do so by going to patreon.com slash
grow from your heart all the information
you need to sign up will be right
there and I do appreciate all the
support big thank you to everybody who
has been helping me out I would also
appreciate it if you find me on all of
the social media you can stalk me on
Facebook simply search for the girl from
your heart podcast on Twitter it's at g
f YH podcast if you'd like to follow my
personal Twitter account
it is Rasta Jeff 420 also I encourage
you to follow my Instagram its Irie
underscore genetics iri e underscore g e
and e t ICS Irie underscore genetics on
instagram do me a follow check out my
fine cannabis photography and also check
out my Instagram live videos where my
friends come and ask me cannabis
questions I answer cannabis questions I
take some dabs we hang out sometimes we
get goofy it is always a good time I
encourage you to participate there I
recently just hit 19 thousand followers
on Instagram so a big shout out to
everybody for supporting my Instagram
efforts you guys don't forget that the
podcast is available on iTunes and
stitcher and every episode is available
on the YouTube channel simply search for
the girl from your higher podcast you
guys I'm gonna wrap up this podcast I
think you could tell my throat is
burning out I'll be back in just a few
days with fresh new content thank you
guys for listening I want to give you a
huge shout out to my friend indica Dogg
oh and until next time take a phat dab
and give your mom a hug for me welcome
to the show everybody it's time for
episode 364 of the Grove from your heart
podcast this episode of the show is
brought to you by our friends at the
Hell a dank seed company if you need new
seeds for your garden I highly recommend
the hella dank seed company and you can
find them a dank seed dot store I like
to start the show off by letting you
know what I'm smoking I just took a
gigantic dab of star dog ambrosia from
apothecary farms I always love the
flavor of the star dog I love the effect
of the star dog and the folks at
apothecary always get it right so big
shout out to apothecary farms and the
star dog ambrosia extracts alright you
guys this is going to be another grow
lesson if you've been following along
I've been doing a long series of grow
lessons in this lesson we are going to
talk about cutting clones we're going to
cut clones into rapid rooters we will
cut clones for use and an easy cloning
machine
and we will also talk briefly about
cutting clones directly into cups of
soil I feel like I have a lot of
detailed information written down so
let's not waste a lot of time with the
long intro let's get right into a grow
lesson let's talk about cutting clones I
think a good spot to start talking about
cutting clones is beginning with healthy
mother plants you need a healthy donor
plant to have a healthy clone I suggest
you listen to episode 315 and learn all
about healthy mother plants so if you've
listened to episode 315 or if you feel
like you are up to speed and you have
healthy veggie mother plants let's get
into a lesson on cutting clones let's
talk briefly about why we take clones
why do I want to cut a clone from a
healthy plant that is a really good
question first off I suggest you cut a
clone from every new plant you grow have
a clone if you've got the opportunity to
cut a clone and keep a clone in another
veg space I always recommend that you
may get a pack of seeds you may grow
that pack of seeds and find it the most
amazing plant in that pack of seeds and
if you did not take a clone guess what
it's gone you can't grow that again the
advantage to cutting clones is if you do
find a keeper in a pack of seeds you can
grow that same keeper over and over
again if you have taken a clone you have
reliable tested genetics you know it's a
female
you know it's potent you know it tastes
good and you know it grows the way you
want it to grow so that's the main point
of taking a clone from any type of plant
you are getting a reproduction of the
plant you are familiar with so we take a
clone then you can either grow out that
clone or you can create a mother plant
from that clone and take multiple clones
from that plant and fill your grow room
or rooms with that same cultivar over
and over again and have repeatable
reliable results with that clone seeds
do show variation we try to narrow down
the variation in seeds through breeding
but that does take time if you're
growing from clones you know you are
going to have exact copies if you take a
hundred clones off of one plant and you
put those all in a grow room they are
all going to act exactly the same you
shouldn't see any variation in there so
that is the point and the purpose and
the advantage of growing with clones and
why we want to learn how to take clones
now I know somebody out there listening
is going to bring up the subject of
genetic drift
I suggest you take a listen to episode
343 of the girl from your heart podcast
and you will hear my full opinion of
genetic drift in this episode I'm going
to cover three common methods for
cutting clones in all three of those
methods one of the most important things
we can think about is cleanliness of the
plants and cleanliness of our tools and
cleanliness of our environment
cleanliness is very important when
cutting clones think of it this way
we're taking a plant we're taking
something sharp we are cutting that
plant we are severing a limb from our
plant hopefully the tool used was clean
and sanitized hopefully that plant was
pests and pathogens free hopefully you
were wearing gloves so we have just made
a fresh cut in a plant we've got a plant
with a cut in it we've got a fresh cut
with an open wound at the bottom of it
we have a lot of opportunity for
infection or pathogen to enter this
plant at this point keep your
environment clean now everywhere you set
that clone needs to be clean the product
you dip that clone into needs to be
clean and contaminant free so when
you're pouring out your dipping gel your
clone x gel or whatever you choose to
use don't dip your clones directly into
the container pour out about a shot
glass worth at a time and dip your fresh
cuts into there before you stick them
that is my recommendation to keep some
sanitation going through the grow so
every step of cloning we need to think
about cleanliness cleanliness is very
important clean out your cloning trays
before you use them clean your cloner
before you use it clean your clone plugs
even if you just bought them rinse them
off those neoprene collars give them a
nice rinse if you're using permaculture
and over again with no problems clean
every part of the cloning process think
about it this way we are basically
performing major surgery on our cannabis
plants would you want to be in that
environment with your arm severed would
you trust me in your clone room to say I
got it bro and grab whatever scissors
you use to cut the clone I'm gonna cut
your arm with off with that okay then
I'm gonna set your arm wherever you put
the clones after you chop them you cut a
bunch of clones and then you set them
down somewhere until you get a chance to
do
and stick them because they can't all go
at once wherever you set those clones I
want to set your severed arm how do you
feel about that are you okay with that
is it that clean then I want to dip your
severed arm into some clone gel we're
not gonna clone your arm are gonna stop
there but I want your mind to think
about that level of cleanliness also are
you comfortable running around with that
severed arm in that grow environment is
it clean enough or you looking around
going I'm gonna get some dirty [ __ ] in
this stump think about that in your
cloning environment clean it up it
doesn't take that long get a broom get a
mop clean some [ __ ] up the process of
cutting clones will give your plants a
lot of opportunity to pick up problems
this is where we see people pick up
problems that they later try to identify
as genetic drift so wear gloves clean
your tools clean all of your equipment
use fresh neoprene if you're not using /
mcclellan collars you need to replace
them every time don't try to reuse those
cheapos they have a lot of space in
there where things can build up the
perma clone collars are made out of a
different product you can clean them
don't try to reuse the cheapos please
you will get problems clean everything
that is my point let's move forward from
talking about cleanliness let's talk
about the actual procedure for cutting
clones the two methods I use most
commonly in a commercial grow
environment or in my own personal grows
are cutting into rapid rooters or using
ez cloners or the botanic air turbo
cloner machines when I talk about the EZ
corner or the turbo corner I will
probably say ez cloner all the time I
mean the same thing they're both very
similar machines so let's talk about
cutting clones first into rapid rooters
this is a very common method it's very
cost effective and it does not require
an expensive machine so let's get right
into it cutting clones in rapid rooters
step 1 soak the rapid Rooter plugs in a
week but pH balanced nutrient solution
if you're using bottled nutrients you
can use your veg nutrients at about a
quarter strength for your clones so fill
up a gallon container of water pour in a
quarter strength worth of nutrients and
then adjust the pH between 5/8 and 6.0
no I usually get the tray with the whole
setup that's got the little spots for
those plugs to go so I've got a little
spot
them stood up if you don't want to buy
the whole tray you don't have to do that
many clones but it's a lot easier I find
filling the whole tray keeps the
moisture level easier to control inside
of the dome we'll talk about that in a
little bit so you soak your plugs then
you put all of those plugs in the tray I
put all 50 of them in the tray then once
all 50 of them are in there now it is
time to go and cut our clones I like to
cut clones from a few different parts of
the plant when I'm topping my plants I
quite often make clones from that super
healthy fat top of the plant those make
beautiful clones if I've already cut the
top out I also make clones from when I
lollipop when you go clean off the
bottoms of the plants I usually clean up
the bottom 6 or 8 maybe 10 or 12 inches
depending on the size of the plant those
bottom branches those make beautiful
clones you can take your clone from any
part of the plant as long as it is
healthy and as long as you are happy
with removing that section of the plant
right before I flip my plants into
flower I do a major cleanup anyway so
that's a good opportunity for me to get
clones off the bottom parts of those
plants so try to cut your clones from
the healthiest part of the plant take
about a 5 to 8 inch cut off of your
mother plant and when you cut it try to
cut at a 45 degree angle we're gonna
talk a little bit about that 45 degree
angle here in just a couple of minutes
now always always clean your scissors
you guys clean your scissors with
rubbing alcohol and when you change
mother plants if you cut 20 clones off
of this mother plant and then you decide
to cut clones off of another mother
plant clean your scissors between plants
earlier we talked about this being just
like surgery you wouldn't use the same
scissors on different patients you don't
want to spread disease that's the exact
same reason why we want to clean our
scissors between mother plants now when
I'm cutting clones I try to take a small
cup with a little bit of water with
nutrient solution in it and I take as
many cuttings as I need at one time and
fill that cup and then take that cup
back to my cloning station I don't go
cut a clone then take that back to the
station and then go cut another one and
then take it back
I'll go get as many as I need if I need
50 I'll go find 50 good clones of one
strain then I head back to the clone
station I clean them up I dip them and I
stick them then I can put the dome on
and then I can leave them alone for a
few days that I'll have to keep walking
back and forth between each cut
have to worry about the plants wilting
because the dome isn't on I don't have
to keep taking the dome off and on
trying to rescue plants it's much more
efficient and gentler on the plants to
go take all of our cuts and then head
back to the clone station and work on
all of them at once so I've taken all of
my cuttings and I'm back at the clone
station now I'm gonna take each cutting
it's about five to eight inches long
depending on the genetics and the
stretchiness of that plant on a five to
eight inch cutting you may have one or
two little side nodes sticking off of it
but at the top we've got that fresh new
growth coming right out of the top and
then there are those two main leaves
coming right out of the top of that
branch we basically want to remove
everything from our clone other than
those two top leaves and that new parts
sticking out of the top we don't need
much more than that less is more when it
comes to taking clones in a rapid Rooter
we don't need a lot of material to get
started once you get more experienced at
it once you get better you may be able
to take larger clones but smaller clones
are easier in this type of setup so all
we really need is those top two leaves
and that new fresh part coming right out
of the top there's nothing really there
to sustain life in this clone so we
don't need to give it a lot of stuff to
try to keep alive we don't need to
burden this plant by having a whole
bunch of extra leaves and extra little
side branches so just those top two plus
the new stuff coming out is all we need
clean that all up
I generally cut those two top leaves I
trim them quite a bit so think about it
this way the leaf is oval shape it
starts off real skinny it gets wider it
gets wider and then at some point it
starts to taper back in right where it
tapers in is where I cut that leaf tip
off so right at the widest part of that
leaf I just cut it right off so now I've
got a little stalk with these two leaves
that have been trimmed up and then this
was a little fresh part coming right out
of the top of it there's not a lot there
but that is much easier for us to
sustain than a big plant in a clone dome
so now I've got this little stick with
these trimmed up little leaves with this
fresh growth coming out of the top now
at the very bottom of that when we cut
it off we should have cut at a 45 degree
angle if you didn't make a nice
45-degree angle when you originally cut
it go ahead and make the bottom of that
stem a nice 45 degree angle now the next
thing I do is use a razor blade to
gently scrape the edge of my clone
anything that's going to be submerged
into the rapid root
I gently very gently give it a scrape I
just want to take off that very top
layer just disrupting the very outside
layer of that clone so that it will kind
of break that skin and give it an
opportunity to root a little more so I
give it a very very light scraping all
the clone that is going to be dipped
into the rapid Rooter will get just a
very light scraping don't overdo it if
you see the white part of the plant
you've gone too deep you just want to
kind of disrupt the outer layer of the
plant so I just take a razor blade
sometimes I even use my cloning scissors
and I just rough up that edge just a
little bit you'll see the outer layer is
a little bit of a different color than
the inside layer that's how you know
you're doing it properly again don't go
too far you can kill your clones by
cutting too deep this way just give them
a very little scrape if you want to skip
this step until you learn what you're
doing that is okay but this may speed
you up just a little bit by breaking
that outer layer of the fleshy plant
material so we've got a nice cleaned up
plant we've cut a nice 45 degree angle
we've kind of scraped it up a little bit
to remove that outer skin to give it an
opportunity to root now we need to dip
our fresh cutting into a rooting hormone
I've been doing my best to not recommend
any specific brands or products but what
I have had the best experience with has
been the purple clone X cloning gel that
works great for cutting clones into
rapid rooters it works great for cutting
clones into rock wool cubes it works
perfectly for cutting clones into the ez
clone machines and it also works well
for cutting clones directly into soil
I'll tell you right away that that
product is not organic and many people
will have opinions about that product I
am aware of what I'm using I've done the
reading I've done the research and I
know what is in there and I am okay with
it you may want to do a little bit of
research when you were selecting your
cloning hormones and since I'm on the
subject always wear gloves when using
any type of cloning solution all right
so we've got our clone x gel or whatever
cloning solution you have chosen I
usually pour mine out of the container I
don't like to dip my clone directly into
that container if there is a problem
with my donor plant now I have just
dipped that dirty plant right into my
cloning solution and I plan on using
this cloning solution to make all of my
clones which means I'm going to set
myself up for failure from the very
beginning so pour your cloning solution
out of the
bottle into a smaller container I
usually use a shot glass or something
similar whatever you choose to use don't
pour the leftovers back into the
container that defeats the whole purpose
so pour out some cloning solution then
simply dunk the fresh-cut end of your
new cutting into that cloning gel just
stir it around so that he gathers a
little bit then gently place that end
right into that hole in the rapid Rooter
don't press too hard if it bends or a
kinks over you've broken it and you've
killed that clone you've either got to
cut that end off and start fresh or
start with the fresh cutting so gently
push that cutting into that plug but you
don't want it to penetrate all the way
through the bottom if it pokes out all
the way through the bottom that end of
it is just gonna rot it's gonna turn
black and die if you've buried your
cutting too far under the Rooter it'll
be okay just grab it and pull it right
on out just pull it real gently and back
it out just a little bit and it will be
fine so make sure you go deep enough
into the root plug for the plant to grab
and have some sort of life in there but
don't go so far that it pokes all the
way through when we were planting seeds
I taught you to only go knuckle deep you
may need to go a little deeper than that
when you're sticking your cuttings into
the rapid rooters if you're using a
rapid Rooter or a root riot I recommend
you go about 3/4 of the way into the
root plug so if they're an inch deep go
three-quarters of an inch down into that
plug and now you basically repeat that
process until you've got your desired
amount of clones cut dipped and stuck
into the cubes once I've got my tray
full I spray the inside of the dome I
close the vents of the dome I put that
on the tray and then I set it underneath
a t5 light I like to put my t5 light
about six to ten inches above my clone
dome and I leave those lights on for 24
hours a day you'll find it is much
easier to control the environment around
your clones if they don't have any
changes in light cycle every time the
light goes on and the light goes off the
temperature and the humidity will change
and you will change the environment in
your clone dome your goal is to keep
your clones warm and moist and humid so
by keeping the light on all of the time
we're able to keep a consistent
environment inside of that dome so now
we have got our fresh cuttings cleaned
up we've got them dipped into cloning
solution we've got them stuck into the
rapid rooters we sprayed the inside of
the dome we closed the vents on
dome we put the dome on the tray then we
slid the whole clone set up underneath
the t5 light now here comes the hardest
part the hard part is waiting you don't
even need to check on your clones for
three days if you've got the proper
conditions as long as you see
condensation on the inside of that dome
over the next few days you don't need to
do anything to those clones around day
four or five those clones may need to be
remoisten pop the dome off of the clones
and take a look at the rapid rooters
don't be afraid to pick one up pull it
right out of the tray and feel it is it
heavy is it moist
is it dry visually look at it it's
really easy to tell when rapid rooters
need moisture by looking at them when
they are soaked they are black they look
completely black when they start drying
up a little bit they get a little bit of
a silvery gray when they are too dry
they become Brown try to keep them moist
but not soggy if you give it a little
gentle squeeze you don't want the water
to run down your arms but you need a
little moisture to stay on your fingers
we want them moist but not soggy we need
that rapid Rooter to be able to hold
enough water to sustain life but we also
don't want to have so much water in that
rapid Rooter that there is no room for
oxygen so check your rapid Rooter for
moisture if it is dry we need to
remoisten it I recommend using a spray
bottle and spraying a very light
nutrient mix into the rapid rooters and
just spray it until they are soaked then
pour off the excess water if there's any
water left in that tray simply pour it
off we don't need water sitting in the
bottom of that tray when roots do start
to develop if they're hanging in that
water they will just rot it will defeat
the purpose so give the rapid rooters a
little bit of a spray get them nice and
moist once you've got all the plugs nice
and moist put the dome right back on the
tray and put it back under the light now
on day 5 we're going to open the vents
on the dome if you've got a dome with
the two small vents you can open them
all the way if you've got that dome with
the giant vent in the middle I would say
maybe go a quarter maybe go half way
don't go all the way right away that is
too much airflow I feel like that hole
is too big so on day five we open the
vents and start giving those clones a
little bit of airflow now we're going to
need to pay attention to the moisture
level
a little more frequently because we are
allowing moisture out of that dome by
opening those vents we are letting fresh
air in but we are also letting our
moisture out so start paying attention
to the clones more frequently now
beginning at day six we are going to
start hardening off the clones what that
means is we are simply going to start
removing that dome and introducing them
to the environment slowly every day we
don't want to just take off that dome
and expect the plants to live that's not
gonna work we've got to introduce them
to the environment slowly right now
they're really relying on that dome to
keep the wind down and keep the humidity
and moisture in that environment for
them we need to get them used to being
in population with the rest of the big
plants the way to do this is to take
that dome off and slowly increase the
interval without the dome every day so
starting at day six we're going to take
the dome off for 15 minutes
just take that dome off let the plants
survive for 15 minutes check on them if
you feel like they're too dry moisten
them up put the dome right back on let
the plants hang out for the rest of the
day the second day we're going to crack
that dome for 15 minutes pop off the
dome see how wet those rapid rooters are
if you feel like they're too dry moisten
them up let them sit for 15 minutes
check the moisture level again before
you close them up if you feel like there
are too dry moisten them up it's always
better to moisten them as you open them
so that you don't soak them and then put
the lid on I recommend you take the dome
off moisten them let them get their 15
minutes of hardening time then check
those rapid rooters again if you feel
like they may need moisture go ahead and
add some then put that dome on there we
are going to repeat this process again
on day three they get 15 minutes on day
3 then on day 4 we are going to increase
our interval to 20 minutes then on day 5
we are going to increase to 30 minutes
now you have to pay attention to the
clones as you're doing this if they
start looking weaker if they're getting
angry while the dome is off feel free to
put that dome back on there and rescue
your plants but the goal here is to
harden these plants off so they can
learn to survive without that dome for
protection
so as these clones start getting
stronger we want to leave the dome off
longer and longer as time goes on we
should see little roots pop out of these
clones around 7
ten days that is very strained opinion
but our goal is to have these little
babies into soil around ten or 14 days
into this process so we need to slowly
start getting them used to the outside
environment by hardening them off so
increase your open time every day but
also pay attention to the plants and
don't stress them so maybe on day six
you go thirty five minutes maybe on day
seven you go 40 minutes maybe on day
eight you're going all the way up to
forty five minutes maybe by day ten
you've got them open for a full hour our
goal here is that when we do transplant
these into their 6-inch net pots or
their starter pots that they don't have
to rely on that dome that they are okay
being open all of the time because they
will no longer have a dome for
protection so slowly increase your open
time if you can get your clone domes
open for two solid hours without seeing
any negative effects on your clones
they're certainly ready to go into their
soil or Coco Pops now the most common
mistake I see when people are making
clones is they over moisten the clone
plugs they soak them they try to drown
them pay close attention to the amount
of moisture in your clone plugs you
don't want to drown them if you're new
it cutting clones I suggest you take way
too many clones take way more than what
you're going to need because you're
going to kill a bunch of them in the
learning process and that is acceptable
this is a learning process so now we
basically have to sustain these clones
in this dome until they are rooted
enough to put into our soil or soilless
mix or go into our hydro setup whatever
we choose to do with them and I told you
that I'm going to talk about potting our
seedlings and potting our clones in a
future episode so let's move on to
another cloning method let's talk about
cutting clones directly into soil if I
were going to cut clones directly into
soil I would do it very similarly as the
method I use to cut clones into rock
wool cubes the main difference is that I
would use a beer cup filled with good
soil I try not to recommend brands but
I'm going to say I would probably use
light Warriors soil for my babies I
would buy a bag of white warrior soil
and I would buy some beer cups and I
would poke a bunch of holes in the
bottom of the beer cups for drainage I
would pack up the beer cup with soil
I would moisten the soil then I would
cut the clone exactly the same as I do
for the rapid route or
I would dip it into the routing solution
then I would make a hole in that soil
with my finger in this situation I would
go about two Knuckles deep then you
place that dunked clone into that hole
and gently back fill that hole just push
the soil right around the stem and now
you want that plant to be supported and
it looks like you've got a little baby
plant sticking out of a beer cup filled
with soil it looks like you're basically
done the next step is to take a clear
beer cup and place it upside down on top
of that beer cup to act as a dome then I
use a piece of tape generally a piece of
duct tape and just wrap it right around
there to make sure that that lid stays
on there and you've created a one plant
dome situation you've got a beer cup
filled with soil its moistened you've
got a plant in there and you've put a
dome right on top of it to keep that
moisture in put that underneath the
light and it will act just like the
domed clone acts just like the rapid
Rooter we're gonna need to check on that
soil we need to keep it moist we don't
want it soggy we don't want it soaked
and we don't want it dry but we need it
moist and warm so that our clone stays
healthy and happy now the advantage here
is once that clone roots we don't have
any work to do it's already transplanted
into its first pot the disadvantage is
that it takes as much space as a beer
cup for each clone so you can't fit 50
clones in a small space like you could
in a rapid Rooter tray so the beer cups
work if you're only trying to take a
couple clones and you don't want to go
by rapid rooters and you don't want to
buy a dome setup you can fill up a
couple beer cups with dirt moisten up
the soil put a little hole not with your
finger
clip dip and stick a few clones and you
can create clones just like you would in
a dome setup make sure you harden off
your cupped clones just like you do your
domed clones and you should have healthy
happy little babies in beer cups all
right you guys I've been talking for 25
minutes and my throat is starting to
make a funky noise I'm gonna press pause
I'm gonna take a drink I'm gonna pull a
couple of fat dabs and when I get back
we will continue a lesson on cloning and
we will talk about cutting clones in an
easy cloner or a botanic hare turbo
cloner machine take a couple of fat dabs
you guys I will be right back
all right podcast rolled I am back and
it is time to talk about cutting clones
in a narrow cloner and that will include
an easy cloner or a botanic air turbo
clone
or whatever type of auto cloner you may
have purchased or maybe even bill on
your own let's jump right into it my
first piece of advice is to replace all
of your clone callers each cycle and
start with fresh clean neoprene clone
callers the only brand that I am aware
of that I would approve of reusing are
the perma clone clone callers they are
made from a different material that are
much easier to sanitize and they are the
only brand that I would recommend
recycling that are the only brand I've
had any positive experience trying to
reuse if you're using the cheap neoprene
it's probably safest and most cost
effective to throw them away and buy
freshies every run it is most cost
effective to buy the perma clone clone
callers and follow their instructions on
sanitizing them after each use and they
do not pay me I've just had a lot of
great experience with the product so
always start with fresh clean clone
callers the next step is to make sure
that the cloner is completely cleaned I
like to fill the cloner up with hot
water and bleach and let it run for
about 24 hours then I dump it out hose
it out real well fill it up with clean
water and let it run for just a little
while to make sure I rinse all that
bleach water out then I dump it out and
let it dry once it's fully dry I give it
a smell if I don't smell any bleach I'm
pretty sure that it's clean at this
point I fill it up with clean water
I would suggest RO water if you've got
it but that is not an option for
everybody when I'm filling up the EZ
cloners I generally fill them right
below the halo the spray halo is where
you in where you screw the emitters that
parts called the halo there's the pompe
in the halo and then the emitters I fill
it up right to the base of the halo once
I've got the appropriate amount of water
in the cloner I apply clone x solution
the purple stuff that comes in the tall
bottle not the thick stuff with the
cloning solution not the clone gel it's
called clonic solution I apply that to
the cloner
to get the EC between one point zero and
one point two I want my EC the
electrical conductivity to be between
one and one point two then I adjust the
pH to five point seven to six point two
now the next step is to add clear res
clear res is a product that will prevent
algae from
building up inside of our cloner I
recommend you put 30 milliliters of
clear res for every 5 gallons of water
in your cloner so if you filled it up
with a five-gallon bucket you need 30
milliliters if you filled it up with 10
gallons you need 60 milliliters and so
forth date it get a little sticker and
write the date on that sticker and put
that sticker on the cloner somewhere
that sticker with the date is important
because you will need to add clear rez
again every 5 days that's why I put a
sticker on there that way if you're
working in a facility with more than one
person you don't have people doubling up
and adding too much clear rez
everybody's on the same page there's a
sticker it's as employee number 422
clear rez on day 1
now when day 5 comes around we know
somebody needs to change the clear rez
you get 30 milliliters of clear rez per
five gallons and pour it right on into
the cloner get a sticker right employee
number 420 in here on this date and that
way we know when to add more and we
don't double up so write down how much
clear as you put in there and how often
you do it so that you don't double up
and again I suggest you put 30
milliliters per every 5 gallons every 5
days so now we've added our clone X
solution we've got our EC somewhere
between 1 and 1.2 we've adjusted the pH
to somewhere between 5.7 and 6.2 we've
added the appropriate amount of clear
rez now let's put the lid on the cloner
let's turn on the pumps and make sure
all of the emitters are properly
functioning you're going to need to open
it up and peek in there and make sure
that all those sprayers are spraying
everywhere and that all the inside of
that cloner is getting coverage pop out
a couple random neoprene and put your
finger in there and make sure that your
finger is getting sprayed we want to
make sure that all of the sprayers are
covering all of the cloner spots inside
of that cloner now once you're sure that
cloner is set up and functioning
properly and that all of the emitters
are spraying and covering the entire
inside of that cloner it is time to take
our cuttings to fill the clone machine
we are going to take our cuttings in a
very similar method as we did in the
rapid Rooter technique we're going to
cut about a 5 to 8 inch cutting we're
gonna clean it up we don't need to trim
these leaves as extremely as we did
on the other setup but it is a good idea
to cut the tips off a little bit to
encourage some growth so clean up your
cutting then cut it at a 45 degree angle
stick it in the clone x gel I would go
about one inch into the clone x gel then
those neoprene discs open up like a
pacman open it up to look like pac-man
and then close it around your clone and
you want approximately one inch of
material sticking out of the bottom of
the clone then you take that neoprene
disc and stick it right back into the
machine with that freshly cut part
sticking down into the water and the new
plant sticking straight up now carefully
repeat that process until you fill the
cloner or you run out of healthy
cuttings now I like to hang a t5 light
above the clone machine and I generally
place it about eight to 12 inches above
the canopy of the plants I also like to
leave the light on for 24 hours for
these clones
some people may choose to go 18 on 6 off
that is up to you I have had amazing
results running the lights on for 24
hours and also leaving the pump inside
of the cloner on for 24 hours a day you
can experiment with light cycles and
pump cycles as much as you'd like you
may find that 24 hours of light works
best for you you may find that some dark
cycle works best for you if the water in
your cloner is getting too hot a good
way to cool that water down is by
letting the pump rest for a few seconds
every minute or a few minutes every hour
in one situation I would run the pump
for 45 seconds on in 15 seconds off
every minute those timers are quite
expensive in another environment I was
running the pump on for 45 minutes and
off for 15 minutes every hour and both
of those methods worked well for me but
the 24 hour a day method worked just as
well now we've got our cloner filled up
with fresh cuts it's gonna run overnight
tomorrow we need to check on it
overnight
that purple cloning solution which we
dunked in the cuttings in is going to be
washed off of the plants and it's going
to end up in our reservoir in our water
in our cloner that's going to make the
pH go crazy so we need to check the pH
first thing in the morning and correct
it don't be surprised if the pH has
jumped dramatically it's because all of
that purple stuff
dripped off of the plants and it is now
in your water so just simply adjust the
pH up or down use a few drops of a
reliable pH up or down product don't use
some home remedy or some cheapo product
for your cloner in the cloner we need a
reliable pH up or pH down product also I
recommend a reliable pH pen don't buy a
cheap pH pen you get what you pay for
when it comes to pH testing products
these cuttings are going to live in this
cloner for approximately 14 days we're
going to have to check on them every day
there are a few things we need to check
on the first thing we should check on is
general plant health are they alive are
they standing up are they getting yellow
and crinkly can you see any spider mites
can you see any spider mite damage can
you see any spider mite webbing do you
see any powdery mildew do the plants
show any sign of stress just give a nice
visual inspection of the plants every
single day the next thing I suggest you
check is the pump is the pump plugged in
is the pump working properly the pump is
basically the heart of that machine so
make sure it is working the next thing I
recommend you check is the water level
is the water level just below the halo
while you're in there why not check the
temperature why not check the pH and why
not check the EC of the water in your
cloner you've got it open grab your pins
grab your meters give it a little test
and write it down so once you've made
sure the pump is working you've checked
the water level you've checked the EC
you check the pH and you've checked the
temperature I would put the lid back on
and then I would remove one of the
callers and put my finger in there and
make sure that the water is spraying
everywhere look inside the hole while
that neoprene is gone and see if you can
see that all the plants are getting
sprayed put that neoprene disc back and
if you're brave lift up the edge of the
cloner and look inside and make sure
that sprayer is hitting everything try
to give a visual inspection to each
emitter inside of that machine if you're
using an EZ cloner you've probably got
the red emitters in there make sure none
of those are clogged up if you're using
the botanic air turbo cloner I think
that comes with yellow emitters make
sure none of those are clogged up if you
do find that you've got a clogged
emitter you've got a
find something real tiny to poke down in
the hole and try to unclog it sometimes
you have to take the emitter all the way
out of the halo to poke it and unclog it
be very careful those things get very
brittle and they break very easily if
you plan on unscrewing one I recommend
you have a backup on hand because
there's a good chance it's going to
break in fact while you're thinking
about it right now
just go to Amazon and order a bag of
replacements because those emitters get
broken all the time and it's going to be
really frustrating when you're setting
up your machine and you break two of
them and you can't run your cloner
because you've got two busted emitters
they're very cheap the frustrating part
is you've got a way for them to get
shipped to you so buy some now and then
you've got them for when you do break
them because I promise you you're gonna
break a lot of them so that's our
everyday inspection now remember we
talked about the clear resin earlier
we've got what I like to call the fifth
day check every five days we need to add
more clear res to our cloner we need to
put thirty milliliters of clear res for
every five gallons of water in that
reservoir no earlier I suggested we
check the EC and the pH of our res
everyday but it is not required what is
required is that we check it every fifth
day at least make sure you check the pH
and the EC every five days don't let it
go longer than that without checking
since you're in there adding clearer res
anyway unplug the pump lift up the lid
put your pH meter and your EC meter in
there and just check it and see what it
says then add your clear res in there
put the lid back on plug it in and it's
business as usual
if the EC has gotten too low add a
little bit of the clonic solution if the
pH is out of whack adjusted
appropriately always adjust the pH after
you add the clonic solution if you ever
find that the water level has gotten too
low we need to add water and when we add
water we need to add of course clonic
solution we need to adjust the EC
somewhere between 1.0 and 1.2 when we
add clonic solution if we add water and
clonic solution of course we need to
adjust the pH again always keep the pH
between 5.8 and 6.0 now here's a random
tip I keep calling the top of the cloner
the layer
top I keep changing up the name for it
but the top of the cloner has your
cuttings in it so when we're taking off
that top to work on the water
be very careful keep in mind that the
bottoms of your clothes are sticking out
of the bottom of that cloner they are in
there exposed if you are going to slide
that cloner across the top of the clone
machine diagonally to make it rest
across the cloner don't let it fall
toward the bottoms of those cuttings hit
the edge of the cloner and get broken it
may be safest to lift the top off and
just set it down on the table it's going
to drip water it's gonna drip stuff onto
the table or wherever you set it but you
won't crush the bottoms of the cuttings
because the cloner is tall enough to
protect them if you turn a diagonal
across the base of the clone machine
across the reservoir portion of the
cloner you do run the risk of tipping it
over I've seen it happen quite often you
get that angle going one guy moves the
other guy moves you push it one
direction it'll fall off a corner and
you will break a lot of cuttings
be careful keep in mind that those
cuttings are exposed they're sticking
out of the bottom there when you're
doing work on the cloner itself don't
forget about the clones and also if you
lift it up like it's a hatchback if you
just lift it up to look inside there
keep in mind you're probably pushing
some of those clones directly into the
light you've got that t5 light hanging
right above your cloner and as you lift
it those clones on the edge closest
towards you they're moving right up and
they're getting pushed into the light
above you so pay attention to the root
base part of your cuttings and pay
attention to the parts sticking out of
the top of the cloner when you're
working on the inside of your cone
machine now these cuttings which are
going to turn into clones will live
inside of our clone machine for about 14
days in about four to seven days you'll
see a little wart look and things pop up
on that stem that is inside the clone
machine that is where the roots are
going to start popping out of by day ten
you should have nice roots coming out of
there
then by d14 you should have a start of a
little spaghetti factory just coming out
of the bottom of those plants it should
look like a little set of dreadlocks
hanging off of each of those plants that
is when it is time to take our new
clones and put them into their soil into
their Coco or into their hydro setup so
that feels like a perfect spot to start
wrapping up this lesson I've already
promised that in a very soon to come
episode I would talk about putting our
seedlings and clones into cocoa or soil
so the only part left to talk about now
is cleaning our cloner once you are done
with the cloner we need to clean it I
start by draining all of the water then
I fill it up again with fresh water I
also add 2 or 3 cups of bleach depending
on the size of the cloner then I plug it
in and I let it run overnight the next
day I drain all of that water if I'm not
using permaculture oh the callers away
and by freshies if I've got perma clones
I followed their instructions on how to
sanitize and reuse them then I take the
cloner outside and I spray it down
really well with the hose to get rid of
that bleach I take it apart completely I
take the pump apart and I clean the pump
completely it is really easy to clean if
you take it apart get a little
toothbrush or a little brush and just
scrub it it does not take that long
clean it then I use a paper clip or
something similar to clean out all of
the emitters you guys like I said
earlier have extra emitters on hand
because when you start taking them out
they are going to break they get brittle
and they get especially more brittle
after you run bleach through the machine
so clean everything up then put it all
back together then it is ready for use
the next time you need clones in a
commercial environment are easy cloners
our turbo cloners never got a break by
the time the guys could empty him I had
two more guys carrying them outside they
were hosing them down by the time they
got brought in
I had cuttings cut and ready to go into
those corners they never get a break in
a commercial environment all right you
guys that is my lesson on cutting clones
I hope you enjoyed the podcast I hope
you learned a lot if you have any
questions please reach out my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com if you feel like this
episode was educational informative or
entertaining and you would like to make
a financial contribution to the show you
can do so by visiting patreon.com slash
grow from your heart and all the
information you need to contribute will
be right there and once again thank you
to everybody who has contributed to the
patreon campaign I do appreciate all of
the support I would also appreciate it
if you find me on all of the social
media you can find me on Facebook simply
search for the girl from your heart
podcast
you can find me on twitter it's @g fyh
podcast if you want to follow my
personal twitter page it's a trusted
chef for 20 I highly suggest you follow
my Instagram its Irie underscore
genetics on instagram check out my fine
cannabis photography and join me on my
Instagram live videos if you've got
something you'd like to say and you're
not into the social media or perhaps
you've got a product you'd like me to
review or maybe you want to sponsor the
show I'd love to hear from you reach out
to me it grow from your heart at
hotmail.com don't forget to visit our
sponsor the hell a dank seed company and
you can find them at dank seed dot store
you guys I want to thank you for
listening to a long episode I hope you
had as much fun as I did I will be back
in just a few days with a fresh new
episode I want to give a huge shout out
to my buddy Kelvin Medina and until next
time take a phat dad and give your mom a
hug for me welcome to the show cannabis
community it's time for episode 365 of
the Grove from your heart podcast this
episode is brought to you by the hella
dank seed company if you need new seeds
for your garden I highly recommend the
hell a dank seed company and you can
find them at www.danosongs.com extract
and I love the flavor and aroma of this
stuff it smells like bubblegum and
cotton candy when I dab it it goes
straight to my head it makes my brain
goes super fast it makes my mouth go
super fast so I think this will be a
great concentrate for smoking before a
podcast all right before we get too deep
into this episode I want to give a few
people a shout out I'll a big shout out
to my friend Jake Jordan Iowa shout out
to Jade and also a big shout out to
Grimbold the druid and also a shout out
to Tanner
Martin uuk thanks for supporting the
podcast I really do appreciate all of
the support ladies and gentlemen this is
going to be another grow lesson I have
been doing a long series of grow lessons
I hope you have been following along if
you are interested I recommend you go
back to episode 351 that's where I start
this long series of grow lessons start
there and get caught up if you feel like
you're up to speed
welcome to the grow lessons in the last
two episodes we talked about sprouting
seeds we also talked about cutting
clones
this episode we're going to talk about
putting those seeds and those clones
into containers of soil or soilless mix
so let's start with the seeds we talked
about germinating in paper towels I may
have covered this briefly in the
previous episode but we're going to talk
about it a little bit of a recap right
here just to make sure everybody is up
to speed so we started a few seeds will
be folded a paper towel we soaked it we
put seeds on the paper towel we folded
it again to secure the seeds inside
maybe we put that in a baggie maybe we
put that in a warm place the seeds it
now sprouted hopefully they've got
little tiny tails maybe a quarter of an
inch maybe a half inch hopefully you
didn't go any more than one inch long
here is how I recommend planting those
seedlings I generally try to stay away
from recommending products every time I
recommend a product I get emails from
people saying I did something wrong but
I want to make this easy for everybody
so I recommend light warrior soil from
Fox farms for your new seedlings it is
readily available it is affordable and
it works very well I'm sure other people
will have other ideas and other
suggestions I am okay with that do what
you're comfortable with
I recommend this product because like I
said it's available it's affordable and
I know that it works I'm not gonna send
people on some crazy mission looking for
a product that's hard to find or
overpriced so we've got our medium you
can probably get away with one bag of
white warrior soil now we need
containers to put this soil in to put
our seedlings in I recommend small pots
for small plants there's no reason to
fill up a big three gallon pot and then
plant a little tiny seedling in there
and then you have to water that entire
space of soil you have to put water and
nutrients in all of that space just to
water that plant properly if you've got
your seedling inside of a little tiny
cup you only have to water that much
space you don't have to waste water you
don't have to waste nutrients and you
don't have to waste space a lot of new
growers really like to drown seedlings
in larger pots if they put a sealing in
a larger pot they've got to water all of
that soil so they go and they pour an
entire pitcher of water right on top of
that three gallon pot then that seedling
gets washed away in all that water who
knows where it goes sometimes when
people apply water they do it kind of
heavily the seed gets washed away it
gets lost in there they kill the seeds
they drown they fail with the seeds they
get discouraged so I highly recommend
starting with a
our pot maybe a 4-inch net pot maybe a
6-inch net pot maybe a four inch square
pot maybe a six inch circular pot
something that size
I honestly start my seedlings in a beer
cup I take a few beer cups I stack them
up on top of each other then I put a
drill through the bottom of them I can
go through about 8 cups at a time I poke
one big hole through the bottom and I'll
do a few smaller holes on the side just
to give some proper drainage and I feel
like beer cups are the perfect size for
new baby seedlings the seedlings can
sprout in there they can get a good
start they can develop a good root
system and by the time they get big
enough you can just up pop them into
there 3 or 5 gallon pot and it works
really well so let's talk about actually
putting these seedlings into I'm gonna
go with the beer cup for this method
I've got my beer cup I've got my light
warrior soil mix I'm gonna fill my beer
cup most of the way up with soil I want
to pack it down fairly tight then I'm
gonna fill it up with soil and leave
myself about a quarter of an inch so
that when I water I've got plenty of
room for water and it doesn't just run
off the top of the cup so I fill it up
I've got about quarter inch of space
left on the top then I water that soil
before I even put my clone or my
seedling into it in this case we're
gonna put a sealing in there so I would
water it since I'm going with the
sealing I do not use any nutrients at
this time I'll water it I'll let all
that water soak through the bottom then
I take my pointer finger and I dig a
little hole just right to the first
knuckle on my finger then I put that
little freshly sprouted seedling right
inside that hole if the ceiling has
developed a long tail that taproot if
that tap root has gotten long you need
to make that be facing down and the seed
facing up you want the seed coming up in
the tap root going down so gently place
that seed facing down or the tap root
facing down the seed pointing up place
that right in the dirt dig the hole as
you need as deep as you need to dig it
if you've got a longer tap root just
push your finger in there as long as you
need to go then gently set that tap root
down in there and then you just want to
put the dirt right over a real gently
you don't need to pack it down
just make sure that it's covered up to
where the lights not getting to it and
it is packed in there tight enough when
you water it the next time that water
will probably pack it just tight enough
for you you don't need to press it down
too much at this point you don't want to
risk crushing that seedling so if you've
got a real short tail just go knuckle
deep drop that little sealing right in
there and bury it if you've got kind of
a law
Tail you've got to dig a little deeper
of a whole set that tail down in there
and then just carefully bury that be
really careful not to disturb that white
taproot that is really delicate and it's
important that it is not disrupted now
your new seedlings are basically potted
in their cups of dirt I would place them
under a t5 light with the t5 light about
eight to twelve inches away I would try
to keep them around 75 to 85 degrees and
I would try to keep it quite humid
around these little tiny baby plants now
when it comes time to water these new
seedlings we have to be very careful for
the first few days I recommend using a
sprayer to water new seedlings I got a
tiny 1 gallon pump sprayer from the
local hardware store I mix it with my
whatever nutrient solution I'm gonna use
or just plain water that's been pH
balanced correctly then I pump it real
hard and I just spray the topsoil with
that water instead of pouring a heavy
dose of water in and risking drowning
those seeds or disrupting those seeds I
just spray it from the top I kind of
spray it at a few angles that way get
all the soil saturated and it works just
like the morning dew would so I feel
like spraying them is really gentle and
it works really well for new growers to
not drown these plants and not flood the
soil when they're starting baby
seedlings now let's briefly talk about
when to start feeding our seedlings I
like to start feeding when I see the
first set of truly developed leaves when
you see the first set of 5 or 7 or 9
depending on what variety you're growing
when you see the first set of full
leaves that's what I like to start
adding nutrients depending on your brand
and your product I usually recommend you
start with about 1/4 strength if the
bottle says to use 40 milliliters of a
certain product I would recommend you
start with 10 milliliters of that
product and then as that plant gets
bigger and stronger and more developed
then you can increase your nutrient
feedings to those plants but while
they're small let's feed them lightly so
we don't roast them now let's talk
briefly about what to feed them these
plants need a little bit of nitrogen
they need a very small amount of
phosphorous and a very small amount of
potassium oast of your basic grow
nutrients will be just fine for small
seedlings I would recommend adding a
root inoculant product something like
mammoth pea something like great white
something like recharge something like
plus life any of those products will
work for you
do a little bit of research find what's
available in your area find what fits
your price range and get the product
that will work best for you something is
better than nothing
when it comes to root inoculants and
microbes and beneficial fungus and
bacteria I highly recommend it for small
plants and I highly recommend it
throughout the entire growing process so
when your plants are little they're not
going to need a whole lot of nutrients
just a base nutrient and I highly
recommend some sort of root inoculant
they won't need cal-mag probably until
we transplant them into the next pot if
you want to add a full Vic or a humic
acid that's always good for the plants
at all stages but at this point I mainly
like to focus on healthy plants with
strong roots so I really focus on root
development at this stage of the game
I'll add microbes and beneficial fungus
and then I'll also add carbohydrates but
at this point like I said I am mainly
focusing on root development until I
transplant those plants into their next
pots so we talked a little bit about
what to feed these little babies let's
talk about pH for small seedlings I like
to keep my pH around five point eight to
six point two once they get a little bit
larger I will increase the pH slowly and
I'll move up towards six point three or
six point four but for these small
babies let's stay closer to five point
eight or six point two now really take
your time increasing the amount of
nutrients you give these plants and also
take your time increasing the pH of
these plants they need to grow they need
to get a root system to be able to
process all of this stuff you're giving
them these little tiny plants don't want
a lot and you do run the risk of burning
them if you overfeed them so pay
attention and go slow now after several
days these seedlings will start taking
off they'll start getting full sized
leaves and they will start catching up
to the same size as the clones we cut
once they reach that size I consider
them to be small veg plants and I treat
them just like I do my small veg plants
and we will talk about caring for and
feeding small veg plants here in the
near future next let's talk about
planting our rapid rooters maybe we
planted some seedlings in Rapid Reuters
maybe we cut some clones and rapid
rooters and put them in a dome and now
they are sprouting roots and it is time
to plant them how do we know when it is
time to plant our rapid rooters ceilings
or a clone
I like to plant seedlings as soon as I
see that first tap root coming out of
the rapid Rooter I don't want to let
that tap root get too long too leggy and
too stretchy so I do my best to get
those into soil right away when I cut
clones and rapid rooters I like to make
sure they are sufficiently rooted before
I try to put them into soil make sure
your clones are properly hardened off we
talked about this in a previous episode
we have to expose our domed clones to
fresh air for durations of time and
extend that duration over a period of
time to make sure the clones are ready
to not be in a humidity controlled
environment we need to get them used to
being in our regular veg environment so
we've been hardening off our clones and
they show sufficient roots what do I
mean by sufficient roots I want at least
five maybe ten or twelve white thick
roots popping out of that rapid Rooter I
want them to be just busting out of
there and kind of thick I want them to
look like they're just little worms
coming out looking for somewhere to go
if you've got more than five maybe more
than 12 and they start building up in
there you were really doing well we want
to develop a nice root system before we
pot it but there is a fine line between
just enough and too much if you lift
that little clone up out of that tray
and the roots have begun wrapping around
the Rooter you've gone too far
if those roots are hanging down inside
the root or tray and hanging into the
water we have gone too far we want to
get those into our soilless mix as soon
as possible I want just a little bit of
dreadlocks just hanging out of there not
a lot just maybe a little tiny mop just
a little fuzzball maybe 10 or 20 of them
just hanging out that is prime time to
pot those and I want them about a half
inch to an inch and a half long is
perfect now let's put these rapid
rooters into our beer cup full of light
warrior soil or whatever size pot and
whatever soil makes you choose to use
just make sure it's a quality soil mix
with plenty of aeration and make sure
whatever size or whatever container you
use has plenty of drainage we don't want
our plants to get muddy at the bottom
get stagnant water that will totally
drown and destroy our roots will get
root rot it will be a mess it will be
disgusting so quality soil pots with
good drainage that is a requirement now
just like we did the beer cups for our
small seedlings let's fill them up with
soil and leave ourselves about a quarter
of an inch of space for water now if I'm
putting the seedlings in the rapid
Rooter
into this soil I most likely will not
give them nutrients at this time when i
put the clones into the soil at this
time i do like to give them a small
nutrient feeding i use a light
vegetative mix about 1/4 strength of
whatever brand you're using use about
1/4 strength of whatever they recommend
i also like to use a microbe product
again something like mammoth pee
something like great white shark
something like recharge something like
plus life from veg bloom anything with
beneficial fungus and bacteria that will
encourage root growth will be great for
your small plants so we've got our white
base nutrients we've got our root
inoculant let's talk about pH I like to
keep the pH for these small clones
somewhere between 5.8 and 6.2 so we've
got our base nutrients we've got our
root inoculant we've got our solution pH
now I water that solution through my
cups of soil just pour it right on
through until it drains out a little bit
you want to fully saturate that new soil
now once it's done dripping and that
soil is fully saturated I will take two
fingers and just gently make a little
hole right in the center of that soil
and I go just a little bit deeper than
the height of that rapid Rooter so if
the rapid Rooter is an inch tall I go
maybe an inch and 1/8 or maybe an inch
and a quarter deep then I get the rapid
Rooter out of the little tray and I said
it gently inside of that hole and I do
my best to not disrupt any of those
roots if it's a seedling you've probably
only got one or two roots sticking out
of that rapid Rooter you need to be very
careful gently set that in the soil set
it right inside there then backfill that
hole really carefully over that rapid
Rooter I like to go right over the top
of it so you can never tell the rapid
Rooter was there and just a little plant
is sticking up out of the soil
be really careful if you're working with
the sealing that one tap root is all
it's got to survive through at this
point if you're working with a clone we
still need to be very careful with these
roots by the way we're rubber gloves
when you're doing all this I highly
recommend rubber gloves whenever you're
coming in contact when you're putting
your hands or your skin in contact with
the dirt with the roots with the plant
just try to wear rubber gloves if you
can or latex gloves try to glove up
whenever possible I would still suggest
watering that rapid Rooter sealing with
the spray bottle just like I
recommended before until it gets nice
and large until you were confident that
you're not going to drown it just water
it with that spray bottle make sure you
fully saturate the soil but it's easier
to not go overboard when you're spraying
with the spray bottle because you can
only spray so much at a time if you're a
new grower and you don't have a lot of
experience watering plants in your new
watering the clones don't be afraid to
water them with the spray bottle also
just get in there and saturate that soil
keep spraying until you feel like it's
saturated and then wait until it's
fairly dry to water it again you'll know
when it feels real light when you pick
it up you'll say oh that needs water
then just soak it until it's mostly
saturated again eventually you'll
realize that you're spending too much
time using that spray bottle to water
the clones and you'll start using a more
efficient method but it's a great way to
learn how to not over water so I
basically fill my cup with soil moist in
the soil I make a little hole with my
fingers and I set that rapid Rooter
right inside of that hole really gently
really careful not to damage any of
those new roots then I carefully bury
that wrap and Rooter with the moist soil
then I put that cup underneath a t5
light again I like to keep that light 8
to 12 inches above it when they're brand
new like this I don't want to scorch and
I don't want to burn them then I like to
keep the temperature somewhere between
75 and 85 degrees and I try to keep the
room fairly humid when I have new
seedlings or young plants in the room so
that is really quickly how I put my
rapid Rooter seedlings and clones in two
cups of soil let's talk next about
putting our clones from an easy cloner
machine or a botanic air turbo cloner in
two cups of soil my method for potting
these clones into soil starts the same
as potting our seeds or potting our
rapid rooters I start by filling my cup
or my desired container with a light
warrior or my desired soilless mix about
a quarter inch away from the top
I then saturate that soil the same as I
did with my other cloning method I use
about a quarter strength of my
vegetative new and I like to use plenty
of microbes then I adjust the pH between
5.8 and 6.2 now when we cut these clones
I said to leave about an inch underneath
the neoprene collar into the water
getting hit by that sprayer that entire
inch
should have roots popping out of here we
should have a nice little mop of roots
before we try to pop these so I've got
my cup of moistened soil I've got a well
rooted clone now I usually grab the cup
with my right hand I use the pointer
finger on my left hand and I just poke a
hole about an inch and a half deep right
into that soil now I may widen that hole
up a little bit depending on the root
mass coming off of that clone if there
are a lot of roots I need more room I
don't want to crowd or crush the roots
into that soil I like to lower the clone
down into the soil and let those roots
spread as far as they can get so if
you've got something hanging off try not
to squish them try not to coil them we
want to encourage those roots to spread
out as far as they can go if you've got
a lot of roots maybe make a small cone
of soil in the bottom of the cup a
little triangle so that the roots can
hit that triangle and spread out around
that instead of getting into a ball we
want the roots spread out that is really
important if we tangle them up if we
twist them they'll just suffocate
themselves and they will kill the plant
and the clone will not survive at all
now if your roots have gotten
excessively long I recommend you trim
some off if there are more than six or
seven inches long just go ahead and trim
the bottoms of those roots off your
plants will thank you for it they won't
have so much root mass twist it up in
the bottom of that cup trying to figure
out what to do you'll just have a nice
thick root mass started and it works a
little bit like topping your plants
you've just created more sections for
that root zone to branch out from so
your plants will appreciate it so you
pop that clone up out of the EZ cloner
you've got the neoprene disc you take
the neoprene disc off you put that back
in the hole so the water doesn't go
spraying anywhere you've probably got
the cloner turned on while you're
potting the clones then you take that
clone and you just set it right inside
that hole that you've created in the
soil but as you lower it down into there
try to spread the roots out if they're
just short and stubby they're gonna go
the direction they want to go if they're
getting long enough to where you can
stretch them or move them and encourage
them which direction to go try to make
them spread out like an umbrella we want
to get them nice and far if they're
really long you can put soil in the cup
lower some of the roots down into the
cup then sprinkle more soil on top of
that then lower more roots down into the
cup and then sprinkle more soil on top
of that then no matter how much soil you
use no matter how long the roots are
we need to bury that clone deep enough
into this cup to give it some support to
stand straight up we need to get the
soil tight enough around it and get it
deep enough in there to get the clone to
support itself and stand straight up but
at the same time we need to not bury it
so deep that we cause a root rot on that
short stem that is there so we put one
inch of it underneath the neoprene disc
getting sprayed by the water so we've
got roots about one inch then that
neoprene disc is about a quarter of an
inch deep so I would say probably plant
it somewhere between one and a quarter
and one and a half inches deep into your
medium
now we've already moistened the soil so
the nutrients are in there the next
thing to do is to move our potted clones
underneath a t5 light again for freshly
potted plants I like to keep that t5
about 8 to 12 inches away I will lower
that light as the plants get stronger I
just don't want to move them right under
there right away and scorch them and
burn them and give them the opportunity
to stress out for these new baby clones
I like to keep the temperature between
75 and 85 degrees and I do like high
humidity it depends on how much airflow
I've got in the room it depends on my
environment it depends on the situation
if I've got plenty of airflow if I can
have air exchange I will put higher
humidity in the room if I feel like
there's not a lot of airflow and it will
create problems I will reduce the
humidity accordingly I know I keep
stressing it but the most important
thing to think about when you are
potting these clones from the easy
cloner from the turbo corner is to not
let those dangly roots wrap up on
themselves don't let them by and don't
let them smother themselves don't let
him suffocate themselves these cloning
machines can make roots explode you look
in there on day five and you won't have
any roots you look in there on day six
you'll be getting roots you'll go away
for the weekend you'll come back over
the weekend on Monday the roots are
hanging down into the water they go
crazy very quickly
you will see what I'm talking about when
you get it dialed in don't take those
fat clones with big crazy roots and kill
them by suffocating them by coiling them
up in your soil all right so at this
point we've got a bunch of seedlings or
a bunch of clones in small pots or cups
we've got them underneath t5 lights or
whatever light you've got available
maybe you've got an LED maybe you've got
a small HPS maybe a 250 or a 400 if
you're using something larger that works
just keep it further away just raise it
up real high so he's got it under an
acceptable light we've got it in a
desirable climate which is around 75 to
85 degrees with the appropriate humidity
hopefully you've got somewhere between
50 and 75 percent humidity for your
small plants
I would suggest either 24 hours on or
possibly 20 on and 4 off or a lot of
people like to do 18 hours on and 6
hours off for our new small plants also
I would recommend a white fan on these
plants just a fan to keep the air moving
around them will prevent the plants from
getting leggy and stretchy and I think
it just makes tougher more robust plants
when you put a little breeze on them so
at this point the clones are now in our
small veg phase in a very short time
those seedlings will catch up to what I
consider the small veggies which is when
they are about 6 inches tall and they've
got a couple of nice sets of leaves and
they can start taking small veg
nutrients I plan on doing a complete
episode on small veg here in the very
near future that episode will include
recommended light cycles for your veg
plant that episode will include
recommended nutrient schedules for your
veg plants I'll also talk about optimal
environmental conditions for your small
veg plants then we'll talk about
transplanting our plants into their
finishing pots and we will consider that
large veg and then we will begin to talk
about our large veg phase ladies and
gentlemen I hope you are having as much
fun with these grow lessons as I am I
would love to hear your feedback reach
out to me on Twitter or through email on
Twitter it's @gf wih podcast and of
course the email address is grow from
your heart at hotmail.com and if you
feel like this episode was educational
informative or entertaining and you
would like to make a financial
contribution to the show you can do so
by going to patreon.com slash grow from
your heart and all the information you
need to become a patron will be right
there on the screen and I do appreciate
all of the support from everybody who
has contributed ladies and gentlemen I
want to thank you again for listening to
the podcast I know this was sort of a
short episode but I feel like I did a
good lesson I taught you well how to
transplant your new babies I feel like
there was not a lot of fluff or a lot of
BS to filter through I feel like a lot
of people can learn from this one
and that is the point so short and sweet
right to the point we served our purpose
I think Mike is on his way over so we
will record a long and rambly episode
that will make up for the short episode
I did today you guys I want to thank you
again for listening I would appreciate
it if you find me on all of the social
media you can find me on Facebook simply
search for the grow from your heart
podcast you can find me on Twitter it's
at g f YH podcast if you'd like to
follow my personal twitter feed it's at
Rasta Jeff 420 I also recommend you
follow my Instagram feed on Instagram I
use Irie underscore genetics I post a
lot of fine cannabis photography I like
to go on Instagram live and hangout I
answer questions I talked to my friends
I take dabs if you come on my Instagram
live feed and you ask a question there's
a very good chance I will answer your
question there on the Instagram live
feed so follow me once again it's Irie
underscore genetics on Instagram if
you've got something you'd like to say
perhaps you'd like to sponsor the show
or maybe you've got a product you'd like
me to review maybe you're not into the
social media you just want to say hi you
can reach out through email my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com you know I would love to
hear all of your feedback also don't
forget about the YouTube channel every
episode is now available on YouTube
simply search for the drove from your
heart podcast on YouTube give us a
subscribe leave me some comments I would
love your support on the YouTube channel
don't forget to visit our sponsor the
hell a dank seed company you can find
them at www.stanford.edu mama hug for me