[Music]
welcome back podcast world it's time for
episode 403 to grow from your heart
podcast this episode is brought to you
by our friends at Oregon elite seeds if
you need new seeds in your garden I
highly recommend Oregon elite seeds and
you can find them at www.seannal.com I
like to start the podcast off by letting
you know what I'm smoking today I've
been taking dabs of pineapple Fanta live
batter from Green Dot labs this is a
combination of golden pineapple and jet
fuel gelato on the label it is described
as tasting like citrus cleaner Hayes and
Fruit Chews I would agree with that but
I would also say it tastes just like a
pineapple Fanta it's got that sweet
pineapple citrus flavor and it even has
a fizzy flavor to it it may sound crazy
but when you dab it you will agree with
me so big shout out to our friends at
green dot labs for the delicious
pineapple Fanta ladies and gentlemen
this episode is going to be another
compilation of reposted grow lessons in
this episode I'm going to repost
episodes 368 369 370 370 to 374 and 376
ladies and gentlemen with no further ado
let's jump right in to episode 403 of
The Grove from your heart podcast
welcome to the show everybody it's time
for episode 368 of the girl from your
heart podcast this episode is brought to
you by the hella dank seed company if
you need fresh genetics for your garden
I highly recommend the hella de exede
company and you can find them at
www.sedar.com i'll etting you know what
smoking on today I've been taking dabs
of screaming watermelon from our friends
at viola extracts the stuff has a really
nice flavor if you dab it too hot you
totally kill that sweet watermelon
flavor if you go in nice and cool it has
a sweet watermelon Jolly Ranchers sort
of flavor and I really like it the label
here says it is 94.5% th CA and 0% CBD
or CBG for a total of 82 point eight
eight percent THC that's a pretty
impressive lab test for something with
so much flavor so big shout out to the
screamin watermelon from viola extracts
and also big shout out to my friends at
the Colorado cannabis exchange for
taking good care of me all right before
I take us into the Gro lesson I want to
give you guys an update on my webstore I
have added some new merchandise to my
website there are new Irie army t-shirts
there are I read genetics t-shirts there
are growth from your heart podcast
t-shirts there are I read genetics
hoodies and there are growth from your
podcast hoodies all available on the
website plus a plethora of great
stickers so make sure you check out the
website I read genetics Colorado com
grab yourself some shirts grab yourself
some stickers get a hoodie for the
winter
get yourself all styled out with the
fresh new eye region that excu alright
you guys let's work on a podcast this is
going to be another grow lesson I hope
you have been following along with my
long series of grow lessons we started
off by selecting a goal for our grow we
worked on selecting a proper space we
built a good grow room we decided if we
wanted to grow from seeds or clones we
acquired seeds and clones we have got
them sprouted now they are potted into
their little pots I think by this time
all of our seeds and clones should be
about the same size we've got stuff any
either a four inch pot or a six inch net
pot but we should have clones or
seedlings with just a few sets of leaves
they're probably four maybe six inches
tall by now and that is what I call
small veg so let's do a podcast about
the small vegetative phase of growing
your cannabis garden in my opinion the
vegetative phase of growing cannabis is
often the most overlooked phase of
growing people think they need to invest
all their time energy and money on the
flowering process that is very important
but I like to believe that you can't
build a strong building without a solid
foundation and that foundation starts in
the veg phase by the time we get these
plants to the flowering room we need
them to be healthy we need them to be
robust we need them the shape we want
them we need them the structure we want
them and we need them pests and
pathogens during the small vegetative
stage is to develop a strong root system
for these plants I want to get those
roots thick and busting out of that pot
before I transplant them into their
forever homes my second goal is to keep
these plants past and pathogen free now
if I'm working from seeds I'm also
paying attention for issues mutations
problems whatever a seedling may show
you a seedling has a ton of options that
can occur through the entire grow cycle
you need to pay special attention to
your seedlings if you're growing from
clones you should know what to expect so
my main focus during this small
vegetative phase is developing a strong
root system my second priority is
maintaining clean healthy plants I don't
want any bugs and I don't need any
pathogens then my third priority if I'm
growing from seeds I want to pay close
attention to those seedlings and I want
to keep my eye out for any weird
mutations or weird problems now if
things go right we are only going to
spend two to four weeks in these small
pots in our small veg phase but in my
opinion this phase is equally as
important as the flowering process we
need to treat every step of the grow
process as an important process we all
want to focus on that flowering phase we
all get excited around week four we get
super pumped up at week five by week six
you're just ecstatic week seven and
eight you can't wait to cut it down by
week nine you're in there every single
day taking pictures looking at the
plants hoping you can cut them down
today or tomorrow just trying to be
patient why don't we put that much
energy into the starting phase of our
plants I know they're not as pretty
there's nothing to show for it but it is
just as import now let's get a little
deeper into this small veg phase what
makes this small veg what makes it small
veg as my plants are small they are in
small pots now what makes it veg veges
the light cycle cannabis plants are
triggered by the light cycle if they
have enough light they will not flower
once we reduce the
to approximately 12 hours on in 12 hours
off every day that triggers our plants
to flower they think that the fall is
coming they think it's the end of the
season they start doing their
end-of-season business which is
producing flowers the parts that we call
buds are the cannabis flowers they are
dried flower tops from a cannabis plant
that is induced by changing the light
cycle so until we manipulate that light
cycle we are in veg since we are using
small pots and have small plants once
again we are back to small now let's
talk a little bit about these light
cycles we've got plenty of options for
light cycles in our veg phase from what
I have experienced the most common and
most popular veg light schedule is 18
hours on and 16 hours off in a daily 24
hour cycle there are other options you
can go 24 hours on and 0 hours off I
have seen great success with 2 hours of
darkness so that's 22 hours on and two
hours off every day in a commercial
facility and a mother room and in a veg
room I am known to do 20 hours on and 4
hours off
now I mentioned the 18 6 that is kind of
a classic that's really close to what
nature does also there is the sixteen on
and eight hours off all of these have
their advantages also they all have
their disadvantage what is the advantage
of 24 hours and zero hours of darkness
24 hours of light means your plants are
getting 24 hours of light energy I
usually recommend a 24 hour on cycle
only for clones and tiny plants or if
your rivetting sometimes we have mother
plants that if they get root bound or if
they don't get enough light or if they
don't get the proper energy they will
decide to OTO flower on you over time I
like to keep those plants under 24 hours
of light that does prevent them from
flipping themselves into flower because
of another environmental factor so most
of the time I would not recommend a 24
hour light cycle unless you are cutting
clones or you're trying to revenge or
perhaps you've got a mother plant it
gets temperamental and wants to try to
Otto flower on you
I like the 20 on and 4 off for a
commercial environment I like a little
bit of dark cycle I think every living
thing likes a little bit of dark cycle
I think roots develop in the dark I
think the plants like a little rest also
that is four hours of electricity not
being sucked up if you've got one light
you're saving a little bit of money if
you've got fifty lights you were saving
a lot of money that is two hundred light
hours that you are not running right
there that's two hundred thousand watt
light hours that you don't have to pay
for if you've got a larger facility so
20 hours on four hours off is always
great for a commercial facility you can
keep your mother plants in that room you
can keep your small veg in that room you
can keep your large veg in that room
usually I put the clones in that same
room underneath the t5 light in the
corner so there's just a little bit of
light in the room it doesn't really
bother the rest of the plants they're
able to do their thing that t5 doesn't
do much in a giant bedroom in a
commercial facility now I always like to
mention the downside of what I'm talking
about there's not much of a downside to
a 20 on and 4 off cycle I guess really
the only downside is that you are always
running lights you only get four hours
of darkness
compared to my next method which is an
18 on and 6 hour off everyday cycle a
lot of growers prefer this because it is
closer to the natural cycles of life it
is closer to the natural rhythms of the
Sun outside it's a little closer to the
natural circadian rhythm that our plants
would be subject to in their normal
environment and it just feels a little
more natural in general so the pros to
an 18-6 cycle is it feels pretty natural
to you and the plants it also saves you
quite a bit of electricity having a six
hour night cycle that is six hours that
you don't have your lights on that's six
hours you don't have to cool the room as
much that's and multiply that by however
many lights you've got and you start
saving more and more money and I also
think the plants really enjoy a nice six
hour nap you can see a lot of
productivity from that six hour nap that
the plants get now our next option is a
sixteen and eight cycle that is very
similar to the eighteen six but some
plants will show you some differences
some plants may try to flower under that
sixteen eight cycle if they get root
bound if they become nutrient deficient
if there are any environmental factors
that stress those plants they may decide
to flower on you underneath that 16 and
8 white cycle depending on what part of
the
globe your plants originated from they
may have a different critical period and
let me explain the critical period the
critical period is the amount of dark
hours a plant needs to induce its
flowering cycle some plants will flower
with a 14 hour dark cycle some plants
will flower with a 10 hour dark cycle
the reason we go for that 12 on 12 off
is it's right in the middle and it seems
to work well with most of the plants
that we have bread for our indoor
environment now since some plants come
from north of the Equator and some
plants come from south of the equator we
do have different flowering times in
tropical areas those plants can flower
for much longer because they're not
going to get snowed on also in those
areas we don't get as drastic of a day
and night cycle change there may be as
much as one hour difference between your
summer and your winter day period in
other areas we get winter we get snow we
get dumped on and we get long dark
periods so our plants have evolved and
adapted and climatized themselves to
those regions then we have bred with
those plants that we've created hybrids
and brought them indoors indoors some of
our plants will flower with a tan our
dark period indoors some of our plants
will flower with a 12 hour dark period
we have established that 12 on and 12
off seems to work really well for most
of the plants that we have bred now to
prevent them from flowering early we
like to use an extended light cycle
that's where we put them on 16 hours on
at a minimum that way we know they are
not going to flower I like to go that 18
hours because why not give them two more
full hours of energy every daylight is
the number one desired nutrient from our
plants light is the number one desired
factor for growth from our plants so why
not give it that extra two hours now in
my mind I say why not give it that full
20 hours every day so that we can get
maximum growth and give our plants a
four hour nap every day I think it works
really well now another reason I like
the 20 on and 4 off is I find that when
I move my plants into the flowering room
and I take them from a 20 hour day
to a 12 hour day they induce flowering
very quickly in other facilities where
I'm running shorter vege periods I
noticed they take a little longer for
the plants to start popping up bud
at their little pre flowers the little
pistols don't start popping up as early
as if I were to run those plants on a
long day cycle and then kick that 12:12
right away I feel like the plants go oh
[ __ ] it is time to flower we have really
had a reduction in daylight they know it
so that's why I do 20 on and 4 off in my
veg and mom area of course I'm running
sometimes I've got 50 or 75 different
cultivars in a mom room so I've really
got to keep things happy and I found
that the 20 on and 4 off prevents
anything from auto flowering and again
it really triggers that flowering when I
put them into the 1212 room so those are
the basic veg schedules I would
recommend 24 20 and for 18 + 6 or 16 + 8
I wouldn't go much lower than that you
may notice problems you won't have the
desired robust vegetative growth that
you need and also you may get plants
that decide to flower before you're
ready alright I feel like we know how
long to leave the light on now let's
talk about what kind of light to put
these plants under we don't have to
throw these small plants under the
Gavita lights right away we may crisp
them up we may roast them they may not
be prepared for that so I like to start
my small plants under smaller lights in
most situations I think a t5 would work
for most people in most commercial
environments I use the 3 foot long t5
fixtures they're three feet long they
have eight bulbs I feel like you can fit
quite a few small veg plants under those
in a commercial environment I like to
set up a two-tiered veg system I get a
Uline rack I put plants on the bottom
shelf of that Uline rack I hang a light
underneath the top shelf to light those
plants now I've got that top shelf freed
up I put plants up there and I hang a
light from the ceiling now I've got two
layers of plants and I'm maximizing my
space by using a two-tiered veg system I
like to use a t5 fixture for the plants
on the bottom shelf and then for the
plants on the top shelf I either use a
Gavita or a metal halide either
somewhere between a four and a thousand
watt depending on my space depending on
my environment depending on how far from
those plants I am but those small veg
plants start off on the bottom shelf
under the t5 s then as I transplant I
move them up to the top
shelf and they go underneath the metal
halides sometimes those are kavita's it
just depends again on my environment now
I really find the two fives to be
cost-effective I think they're efficient
and I think they do a great job if you
want to invest a little more money on a
better light I have seen great success
vegging underneath LED lighting small
plants really love LED lights and also
those LEDs don't produce much heat and
they don't use a lot of electricity they
are a little pricey upfront but I think
they are worth the money if you get a
quality LED I personally don't have much
experience with LED lighting but I have
seen great things from LED lights in
small veg in large veg and through
flower the most important thing about an
LED in veg is the spectrum and that's
also important when it comes to t5 let
me back up because I overlooked that
part when I was talking about t5 s I do
not have any notes on this this is all
coming out of the top of my head today
so let me catch myself before I go too
fast
t5 lights are commonly available in two
spectrums most of the time you will find
them in a 3000 Kelvin and a 6400 Kelvin
for your veg phase I recommend the 6400
kelvin they will put off a more blue
light which is what we want for the veg
later on when we move the flower we want
more of that orange spectrum so that's
when he would switch to the 3000 Kelvin
t5 bulbs if you are going to flower
under them which I do not recommend but
they are great for veg so spectrum is
very important and I almost overlooked
that when you were selecting your t5
bulbs make sure that you get the six
thousand four hundred Kelvin bulbs those
are what I would recommend for your veg
phase I also recommended the bluer or
wider spectrum lights when it comes to
LEDs a lot of the new LEDs give you the
option to turn on certain boards and
turn off certain boards when you were
vegging you want more of the blue and
wider spectrums again once we turn to
flower that's when we want those orange
and red spectrums so while we're in veg
whatever kind of light you're using
focus more on the white or blue
spectrums so I've got another option for
lighting that I can recommend but I
would only suggest this for a very small
scale grow environment maybe for one or
two very small plants maybe for a cab
grow or something this would be an
effective grow light in a pinch I have
seen a lot of folks build a small grow
cabinet with a compact fluorescent light
those CFLs they put off barely any heat
and they use barely any electricity so
if you can get enough of them around
your plant to feel like you're giving it
enough light the plant will grow don't
expect huge growth don't expect robust
plants don't expect a large harvest but
you can make a plant grow with a compact
fluorescent light of course the more
light the better but some people are
very limited in space and power and some
people only want a small grow for a
small personal experiment so a compact
fluorescent light may work for you that
would always be my very last option now
let's talk about a big-boy light a lot
of people are familiar with growing
under high-intensity discharge lighting
a lot of people are going to flower
under an HID light if we are careful to
not roast the plants a metal halide
light will be perfect for your small veg
plants maybe a four hundred maybe a six
hundred a thousand maybe overkill unless
you keep it a little distance away you
can get a 400 watt light fairly close to
your small plants if you keep it cool if
you've got a ducted hood and you're
keeping air moving over that lights
where none of that heat is making it to
your canopy you can get that four
hundred watt light fairly close to your
plants just don't let that heat roast
your plants and dehydrate your soil I
would say maybe keep a 400 watt light 18
to 24 inches away from your small plants
the t5 s you can get those t5 s six to
eight inches away from the plants the
bigger the light we need to go a little
further because it's going to be hotter
and more intense and you don't want to
have super hot and tense light right in
your face all day you survive from the
Sun and you're happy with it being real
far away think about the plants and the
light and the Sun and yourself having a
similar kind of a relationship you need
plenty of it you don't want anything in
the way but also you don't want to get
barbecued so you can put a 400 watt
light 18 24 inches away a 600 I would
probably go 2030 inches away a thousand
watt light you're gonna want to be a few
feet away from those small plants it's
going to get hot it's going to be very
intense but if you've got a 400 watt
light and it's ducted which means it's
guy
adduct coming off of each end and you're
sucking air through it to move that heat
away from that bulb and you've got glass
between the bulb and the canopy you
should be able to run a 400 watt light
with very minimal problems if you pay
attention to heat and the distance from
those plants all right I think that
pretty much covers our lighting options
for our small veg plants let's talk a
little bit about the environment let's
talk about the temperature and humidity
for these small plants in my experience
my small plants appear to be happiest
when they are somewhere between 70 and
80 degrees Fahrenheit I really think
they like it
about seventy-five degrees to 77 degrees
is right about the prime spot for small
veg plants that's when I see the most
growth that's when I see the most
production that's when I see the most
root development that's when I see the
happiest plants so somewhere between 70
and 80 degrees or if you can dial it in
perfectly 75 to 77 is that sweet spot
they really seem to like it right there
now for that temperature to work
perfectly you need to dial in your
humidity temperature and humidity work
together there is a math equation I've
done a full Episode on it this creates
what is called a vapor pressure deficit
I encourage you to listen to episode 314
and learn about vapor pressure deficit
but now let's talk about humidity these
small plants would like to be in an
environment with the humidity somewhere
between 50 and 70 percent I have noticed
that when the humidity is too low the
plants do not produce there is no
production for the whole day when the
humidity is too low the leaves start to
droop the plants don't make any progress
they don't look as robust as they should
the roots are not growing
there's no productivity in that plant
and they also start to develop a woody
texture on the outside of the stems so I
encourage proper humidity too much
humidity on the other hand can cause
similar problems it can cause slow
growth it can cause rot it can encourage
powdery mildew try to keep the plants
happy by giving them the proper
conditions how much better do you
perform when you are happy with your
conditions if I made you go do your job
some of you are gonna laugh at me
because you have to do this if I made
you go do your job outside in 30-degree
weather and shorts and a t-shirt how
happy are you gonna be you're not gonna
get [ __ ]
if I put you in shorts and a t-shirt and
put you in a 77 degree room and I dial
that humidity back to about 50% you're
gonna be completely comfortable in that
room and you're gonna get a lot done the
plants feel the same about life if we
keep them comfortable and we keep them
happy they're gonna produce for us and
give us what we want if we don't keep
them happy if we don't treat them
properly they're not gonna give a [ __ ]
it's gonna be a struggle the entire grow
so again for temperature I want
somewhere between 70 and 80 degrees
right around 75 to 77 is that sweet spot
from what I have experienced and then
again with humidity I like to stay
between 50 and 70% too low he started
slowing down growth too high
you start slowing down growth so that is
the temperature and humidity again I
highly recommend you go listen to
episode 314 and learn all about vapor
pressure deficit all right you guys we
have talked about lighting we have
talked about environment I feel like
this is going to turn into a long
podcast I'm 20 minutes in I am going to
press pause for a moment I need to take
a drink of course I'm gonna take a
couple of dabs I encourage you to dab
with me I will be right back and we will
talk about nutrients and feeding our new
small veg plants hey guys well I'm
taking a couple of dabs I thought it
would be a good opportunity to give
thanks to people who have supported the
show on patreon I want to give you huge
thanks to my friend Sam how about a
giant thanks to Aldrich a big giant
shout out to Tanner Martin oeq and also
a big shout out to Todd Keller thank you
for all of the patreon support if you
would like to learn how to support the
show on patreon all you have to do is go
to patreon.com/scishow
I am back I am well hydrated I am very
well medicated and I'm ready to talk
more about our small veg plants I said
we were going to jump into nutrients
I've got one more thing I want to add to
our grow environment before we talk
about what we are feeding let's add a
small fan to our grow environment I want
to ruffle each leaf of our small plants
as they grow I don't need the fan
blasting the plants constantly I don't
need the fan making the plants bend over
I don't need a whole lot of fan activity
if
you've got an oscillating fan that's
perfect put it on low and just let it
breathe across the canopy of those
plants that's gonna make the plants more
robust and it's going to make them
develop stronger roots and I think the
plants do better when we give them a
little bit of a wind but there's wind
outside it would get blown around a
little bit I think that what happens
when I push you if I shove you a little
bit not super hard you know but if I
just give you a little nudge what do you
do natural instinct is to spread your
feet further apart to have better
balance I kind of feel like if we blow
on a plant make it wobble around a
little bit maybe it's gonna spread its
roots a little bit wider to get better
balance which will also result in a more
robust stalk which will result in an
overall more productive plant when we
move that plant into the flowering phase
so let's give the plants a little bit of
wind they would get wind outside let's
introduce a little bit of that to our
indoor environment again don't blast the
plants if some of the leaves closest to
that fan start getting dry or leathery
or crinkly or they start looking like a
potato chip they're getting blasted too
hard by the fan reduce either the fan
speed or the frequency that they're
getting hit by the fan they're getting
too much air movement and you're
disrupting the vapor pressure deficit in
that area so pay attention to the leaves
they will let you know if they're
getting too much wind but give them a
little bit of airflow and your plants
will really be happy for it you like a
nice little breeze don't choose a nice
warm day a nice sunshine on your face
what's the next best thing that could
come along it's just a nice little
breeze
I think the plants kind of feel the same
way so give them a nice little breeze
and I think they'll appreciate it you'll
make them stronger you'll make them more
robust and you'll give them just some
fresh air more frequently now let's talk
a little bit about nutrients for our
small veg plants we don't need a
supercharged nutrient regimen for these
little plants we don't want to burn them
we don't want to shock them we don't
want to stunt them while they're babies
we want to focus on a balanced diet and
I like to focus like I keep saying on
root development for these small plants
so I like a light vegetative nutrient if
you're working with bottled nutrients
here are a few things to think about if
you are working in cocoa or soil or
soilless mix or hydro you need to pay
attention to whatever product line you
decide to buy and see if they offer a
soil a
or a hydro variety the nutrients will be
show laded differently and they will be
in different ratios because your plants
will uptake things differently in
different mediums many of the companies
that make nutrients offer a soil or a
hydro option when it comes to buying
their products if you are growing in
cocoa I recommend you get the hydroponic
version of the product you are buying
cocoa is more like hydro than it is like
soil or a soilless mix so if you're
shopping for nutrients and you're in
cocoa I would recommend that you buy the
bottle that is recommended for hydro now
when you're looking at bottled nutrients
you're going to find 3 numbers displayed
on the bottle that is the NPK value of
that nutrient the first number is
nitrogen that tells us the ratio of
nitrogen in that product
the next number will be the amount of
phosphorus then the next number will be
the amount of potassium when it comes to
veg nutrients we are looking for a
product with a high and ratio and lower
P and K numbers we don't need a lot of
phosphorus and potassium we want to
focus on that nitrogen for building
strong robust plants with a lot of
energy so we need a good solid grow base
nutrient let's talk a little bit about
base nutrients whatever company you
choose to work with
they probably offer a 2 or 3 part based
nutrient system a lot of them will have
a grow and a bloom that makes it pretty
obvious you use the grow for your
vegetative stage and you use the bloom
for your flowering stage a lot of
companies offer a two-part product which
will be an A and a B grow they also
offer an A and a B bloom but we don't
need those so let's talk about those
later you will take your grow a and grow
B and you will mix those into your water
to create your vegetative nutrient based
solution the reason they sell an A and a
B is because there are things in bottle
a and things in bottle B that will bind
together chemically if they are mixed
together without being diluted in our
water so you would fill your container I
generally use a five-gallon bucket in a
home girl you'd fill your five-gallon
bucket with water you would apply the
correct amount the appropriate amount of
veg a then you would apply the
appropriate amount
HB then you would mix it up then you
would continue to add the rest of the
required nutrients that is a two-part
vegetative nutrient solution other
companies will offer their products in a
different format they will offer what is
called a base and then they will give
you a grow and a bloom to add on top of
that with that type of nutrient regimen
you will use that base product through
the entire cycle through veg and through
flour then you'll use that grow additive
during the growth phase and when you
switch to flour you'll switch to that
flowering additive and they've just put
the appropriate additives in those
bottles to keep everything running
smoothly with that base nutrient in
there now whatever brand you choose be
sure you get the appropriate veg
nutrient set up if it's a two part make
sure you get the a and B if it's the
kind where you have to have a base and a
grow nutrient make sure you get the base
and the grow if you get something simple
where there's just a bottle that says
veg there you go you're ready to go
you've got that one strong veg nutrient
alright I feel like we have a good
handle on base nutrients we need a good
base nutrient with a strong nitrogen
value now I would recommend you feed
those plants maybe a quarter of the
recommended strength for the first
couple times you feed your plants new
nutrients give them a light feeding and
pay close attention write it down so
that you know exactly what you did also
write down the pH write down the EC if
that is an option for you the more notes
you take the more you can do research to
dial in where you went wrong a lot of us
consume a lot of cannabis
some of us consume cannabis while we're
working in the gardens sometimes you say
I wonder what I put in there and you
have no idea where you went wrong
that won't happen if you take notes and
write things down I've done an entire
episode on journaling and I suggest you
listen to that one as well so we've got
a reliable base nutrient we've decided
how much to use it started 1/4 strength
maybe work your way up to 1/3 maybe 1/2
you're definitely not going to need full
strength nutrients for small plants a
lot of your nutrient companies will
offer a feeding schedule a lot of those
feeding schedules will have a small
plant recommendation I still recommend
you reduce that a little bit until you
see how the plants will react so we've
got a base nutrient with small plants I
always recommend some sort of my Co prod
some sort of route inoculant product
something to make those routes go Kapow
I try to avoid recommending specific
products here is a long list of reliable
products that will work great for your
routes
I like mammoth P I like plus life from
veg bloom
I like recharge from Scotty real I like
great white shark and Orca and my coach
um I think that is a great combination
some of those products are a little
expensive some are more affordable I can
also recommend a product called mykos it
is a very affordable bag of micro
products as long as you are using some
sort of microbe product I think you will
see very increased root production
compared to if you did not use it of
course I like the higher end fancier
more expensive products but if you can't
afford that get what you can't afford I
highly recommend a microbe or a Maiko or
a root inoculants for your small plants
it will really speed up your production
and I think the plants will really show
a huge difference and you will notice it
and it will make you a happier grower so
we've got a reliable vegetative nutrient
with enough nitrogen in it we have
decided on a micro product that would be
enough for our small veg plants for two
to four weeks you may want to add some
fulvic acid to your mix I like adding
some fulvic I think it makes the plants
uptake the nutrients more quickly and I
think it's really worth the investment
just a small bottle of fulvic acid will
really improve your nutrient uptake and
your plants now if you've got a good
solid base nutrient and you're feeding
your roots your plants are really happy
you've added a little fulvic acid that's
increasing the uptake as the plants get
a little bit bigger you may need to
introduce some cal-mag be careful not to
overdose small plants on cal-mag
sometimes the young plants really don't
react well to too much cal-mag so be
careful now basically we've got a veg
nutrient we've got some mykos we've got
a little bit of fulvic acid and maybe
around week three we are going to add a
dose of cal-mag this feed should keep
our plants super happy one important
thing we need to think about is the pH
of our feeding solution for plants this
size I generally recommend we adjust the
pH somewhere between 5.9
and 6.2 and again we adjust the pH after
all of the nutrients have been mixed in
you've got your bucket of water you add
in the appropriate recommended amount of
each bottle of nutrients then you give
it a good stir make sure it's nice and
mixed then we check the pH then we
adjust accordingly
so we've got a solid veg mix we've got a
pH adjusted now it it's time to water
our plants I recommend when you water
you saturate your medium thoroughly
don't drown the plants but make sure
that all of the soil or cocoa or
whatever medium you are watering make
sure it is saturated we don't want any
dry pockets your roots will not grow
into dry spots so moisten all of your
medium now is probably a good time to
remind you guys of episode 337 where I
do a lesson on what is called 1 through
5 water tank if you're a new grower and
you haven't heard the 1 through 5 water
tech discussion I highly recommend you
listen to that episode right after this
it is episode 337 and it will teach you
a lot about watering your plants
correctly so we have appropriately
watered our small plants with nutrients
when do we need to give our plants
nutrients again that is a really good
question in cocoa I like to feed
nutrients to my plants at every single
watering every single day I will feed my
plants a solid base mix then I will add
a booster every day and I will rotate
those boosters depending on what the
plants may need in this small veg case
my booster would be the cal-mag I would
water the nutrients I would put the base
nutrient put the full VAT fulvic acid
and I would put the mykos in my nutrient
solution every single day then once a
week I would put that cal-mag in there
that would be my booster for these small
plants now if you're working in soil or
soilless mix you don't need to feed
nutrients as often because they stick
around in the dirt a little better I
would recommend you feed with nutrients
one feed then water the next feed when
you're feeding with just clean water
please adjust the pH just like you do
when you're mixing nutrients fill your
container with water stick your pH meter
in there
see what it says adjust it up or down
accordingly you need to adjust the pH at
every feeding so I would recommend you
do one feeding of nutrient
one watering of pH adjusted water then I
would go back to that basic nutrient
regimen for the next watering these
small veg plants will need frequent
watering pay attention to them don't let
them get too dry don't let them be over
watered once again check out the 1
through 5 watering tank another thing we
need to pay attention to is over
nutrient ting are we over fertilizing
these plants are we burning them pay
attention to the leaf tips if the very
tips of the leaves start to look brown
or of the wrong color or if they start
to curl we are feeding too much if your
leaves look pale and yellow we are not
feeding enough if you have a mixture of
those two symptoms your pH is probably
off one of the very first things I
recommend it in these grow lessons was
that you buy a book and you read it
hopefully you've already done some
reading hopefully you have looked at
some leaf charts and you know what
deficiencies look like so you know what
to pay attention to you know what a
healthy leaf looks like and you know
what an unhealthy leaf looks like and
it's gonna pop out in your head when you
see those leaves doing something weird
you're gonna say that's not what the
book said this should look like so
hopefully you've gotten the book
hopefully you have read the book so pay
attention to your plants if they are
showing you that they need more
nutrients increase your nutrients give
it a little more base nutrients you
probably don't need to increase the
amount of fulvic when it comes to mykos
I have learned that it is better to feed
small amounts more frequently than to
try to feed a whole bunch at one time
you're not gonna do any good by pouring
the whole bottle in there at one time
would be more effective to pour the
bottle in there slowly over a course of
time so maybe if you see a deficiency
just increase that base nutrient what
you're going to run into a deficiency
with and small plants is either going to
be nitrogen or cal-mag that is going to
be your most common deficiency so pay
attention that those two things and
learn what that looks like the next
common thing you're gonna find is
nutrient burn people are going to try to
feed too much to these plants I heard
somebody say the term [ __ ] I just want
to put more on it to make it grow faster
I thought it was hilarious when I heard
that I know a lot of people like that
don't be that guy now if you're running
a hydroponic system
if you're in rock wool cubes and you're
doing a top feed or if you're in some
type of ebb and flow system your small
veg phase will not be nearly as long as
us growing in cocoa or a soilless mix
your small veg phase zips right by
I think the hydro grows go much more
quickly in veg so your small veg phase
may be only about a week long you're
going to need to introduce more
nutrients at a higher rate sooner in a
hydroponic setup but pay attention to
the plants that is very plant specific
and very strain specific but since the
plants grow a little more quickly you
are going to need more nutrients sooner
one thing I'm going to remind you of in
your hydroponics is to stay on top of
your pH and your EC or your ppm s check
it every single day and adjust as needed
water is going to evaporate from your
hydroponic setup but the nutrients will
not evaporate so your pH and your ppm s
are going to fluctuate during that
evaporation also the plants are going to
consume some of the water so the water
is going to disappear throughout the day
which is going to cause changes in your
reservoir as a hydroponic grower you
need to be on top of that every single
day also I'm going to recommend you take
extra notes as a hydro grower reactions
happen a little more quickly and the
plants are a little more sensitive when
you're running hydro because you don't
have that big soil life system to work
as a buffer all right boys and girls I
feel like that is a good talk on small
veg we're going to leave these plants in
these pots for two to four weeks
depending on how quickly they grow
that's a very strained dependent that's
very environment dependent one thing I
want to remind you to do is spread your
small veg plants out we do have them
crush together now because there are
small plants but as they get larger make
sure you spread them out give them more
space they want to grow they want to
branch out if you've got them all
crushed together they're gonna grow
straight up and get really really tall
if you give them space to branch out
they will do so and then when you top
them you've got nice bushes but that's
coming up in the future you guys I know
I didn't talk about soil I didn't talk
about containers in this episode I feel
like I covered that in the previous
episodes so we were up to speed there
we're gonna leave these plants in these
containers for two
for weeks then we will pop them into
three gallon or five gallon or perhaps
seven gallon containers maybe some of
you out there are gonna go huge and go
into a twenty or an even larger
container but we're gonna work on that
on the next episode so we've got a
little time to let these plants grow
your job now is to keep them healthy
keep them happy
keep them pests and pathogens reaching
on those roots if you see any yellow or
funky leaves make sure you pull that
stuff off just take good care of your
new sweet little babies make sure they
don't have any problems so that when we
transplant them into their bigger pots
they're ready to go they've got a fat
root system and they don't go into any
shock from the transplant I just
realized that I did not cover any pest
management for our small plants let's
talk about that really quickly
hopefully you have decided on an
integrated pest management system for
your garden before this point hopefully
that was part of your planning phase
hopefully we don't have any pests or
problems on our small plants some folks
will choose to apply a pesticide as a
preventative some folks will wait until
they see a problem to use a pesticide on
a plant this small I would like to wait
until I transplant these into their
three gallon pots before I put any
pesticides on them however in some
environments I don't trust the place and
I need to put a pesticide on it I would
use something like evergreen and I would
probably use it around 15 mils per
gallon I would make sure to apply it
while the lights were off and I would be
sure that the plants were completely dry
before I turn the lights back on and I
would probably do this approximately
every five to seven days while the
plants are little if I were in a place
that had a reputation for getting a pest
infestation alright I feel like that
should keep us pest free for the first
four weeks and then we can really start
implementing our integrated pest
management once we transplant into those
three gallon pots all right podcast
world I feel like that is a solid show
about small veg if you feel like this
episode was educational informative or
entertaining and you would like to make
a financial contribution to the show I
encourage you to do so and you can do
that by going to patreon.com slash grow
from your heart all the information you
need to become a patron will be right
on the screen and I do appreciate all of
the support now while I'm talking about
patreon let me bring up something I keep
forgetting to mention on the podcast
recently patreon changed the way the
contributors cards are billed during
that process many contributors were
removed from content creators pages if
you feel like you are contributing to a
patreon campaign I encourage you to log
into your patreon account and check the
status of all your content creators
please make sure you were still signed
up and contributing to all the people in
which you have been supporting support
from our community means a lot to
content creators and it would really
break our hearts to lose contributions
because of a technical glitch so again
please check on your patreon campaigns
make sure you were contributing to all
of the creator's which you believe you
are creating and keep the vibe alive and
keep showing them love and support all
right you guys that's all I've got for
you for this week I would appreciate it
if you find me on the social media on
Facebook simply search for the girl from
your heart podcast on Twitter it's @gf
wih podcast of course I do have an
Instagram feed it's Irie underscore
genetics find me on instagram jump into
my Instagram live videos you can hang
out take dabs chat ask me some questions
maybe I will answer your questions there
on the live feed I encourage you to join
don't forget that I added some new
merchandise to my webstore go to I read
genetics Colorado calm slash I read -
store there are a growth from your heart
podcast t-shirts there are growth from
your heart podcast hoodies there are I
read genetics t-shirts and hoodies and
there are new Irie army t-shirts I think
they would all look great on you so
support the webstore if you've got any
questions you guys you can reach out to
me via email my email address is grow
from your heart at hotmail.com I do love
all of the interaction make sure you
support our sponsor the hell a dank seed
company of course they are at dank seed
dot store you guys my voice is burning
out just in time so thanks for listening
to this episode I'll be back in a couple
of days with another grow lesson I want
to give you a huge shout out to my buddy
stabby mixed a Burson and until next
time take a phat dad and give your mom a
hug for me welcome to the show podcast
world it's time for episode 369 if the
growth
our podcast this episode is brought to
you by the hella dank seed company if
you need new seeds for your garden I
highly recommend the hella dank seed
company and you can find them at
www.cdxzipstream.com --scent rates from
contraband have that dryer sheett Terp
I'm not sure which turf that is it
really smells great my body really likes
it it's kind of sweet it's kind of sharp
it's got almost a citrus thing to it and
if you let it sit on the nose for a
minute and you just give it a nice smell
and let it rest it has a really warm
aroma to it something warm in the
background that may sound crazy a lot of
people tell me that my strained
descriptions are completely crazy but if
you bought a gram of this and you
cracked it open and gave it a smell you
would say that is sweet with a hint of
citrus with a little warmth at the end
and you would probably agree with me you
guys I always loved the high of the
products I buy from contraband
concentrates it's always got that nice
head buzz I feel like maybe that sharp
dryer sheett sort of aroma has something
to do with the head buzz that I get from
this concentrate anyway they always do a
good job big shout out to the fluffer
nutters sauce from contraband
concentrates it's obviously got me nice
and rambley this will be a great podcast
I do have a lot of great information
written down for you in this episode but
before we get to it I would like to give
a few people some shout outs let's start
off with Brett Gorman how about a big
giant shot at the Brett Gorman thanks
for all the support dude also a big
shout out to Aldridge once again I
totally appreciate that support and also
a shout out to Sam and Steve
F thank you for all of the support on
patreon I truly do appreciate that if
you would like to learn how to become a
patron you can do so by going to
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
all the information you need will be
right there
and once again thanks for all the
support everybody it does mean a lot to
me
all right podcast world in this episode
I am going to do another grow lesson if
you have been following along you
I've been doing a long series of grow
lessons in that series we set a goal for
our grow we found a safe place for our
grow we've selected the appropriate
equipment for our grow we've also
selected the appropriate nutrients and
pest management system for that grow now
we have either sprouted seeds or potted
some clones now at this point of our
grow we have got clones or seedlings in
small pots that are probably 6 to 10
inches tall at this point and they are
developing nice fat roots that's where
we are in these grow lessons in this
lesson I plan to talk a little bit more
about small veg we're going to continue
that conversation since time has
progressed since we put our plants into
the small pox then I want to work my way
into talking about microbe products and
root development and the importance of
healthy roots and the benefits of using
a quality microbe product some of this
episode may feel like a recap some of it
will be a recap but we will work our way
right into our current state so be
patient sometimes I feel like it's good
to remind people not everybody listens
to every episode so I like to get people
up to speed before I move forward I do
need to correct myself I made a mistake
on the last episode in the last episode
I was talking about ideal lighting for
our small plants and I feel like I
completely overlooked ceramic metal
halide lighting ceramic metal halide
lighting is a very viable and useful
option for your small plants if you feel
like I left you out by not mentioning
the CMH lighting I apologize those are
quality lights and I recommend new
growers to use those lights for small
plants if that is an option they are
affordable they don't put out a lot of
light and they don't use a lot of
electricity so a ceramic metal halide
light is a very viable option for a
small grow for a new grower for small
plants also if you want to step up move
up from the 315 s to the 6 30s I've seen
great results with those in a flowering
room as well so don't let me forget the
ceramic metal halide lighting anymore
that is always a viable option in a
cannabis grow now let's get back on
track and talk more about continuing our
small veg phase again what I consider
small veg our small plants anything
basically from a cloner or a ceiling
that is in a small pot maybe like a four
inch pot maybe a six inch net pot maybe
all the way up to an eight inch pot but
our smaller plants that don't have a
super strong healthy developed root
system
our plants that are probably only eight
to ten inches tall those are what I am
considering my small veg plants now up
to this point we've mainly been focusing
on healthy pests and pathogens free
plants I suggest you check every day for
the presence of pests or pathogens even
as the plants are small we still need to
pay close attention flip a leaf over see
if you see any weirdness on the bottom
of the leaves pay attention to the tops
of the leaves do you see any stippling
that's a sign of spider mites do you see
any gooey stuff that's a sign of thrips
just pay attention flick some of the
plants flick some of the containers do
you see anything fly out that is a sign
of either fungus gnats or white flies if
they're white they're white flies if
they're black they're probably fungus
gnats just pay attention for pests in
our small plants it's really easy to
take care of them if we do get them but
we need to identify our problems early
so that we can conquer them before they
get out of control so go in and check
for pests every day check for powdery
mildew you should be able to spot it on
these little plants very easily it will
start in the center of a leaf it will
usually start at the widest point of one
of your biggest leaves and it will look
like somebody just took a little drop of
donut powdered sugar and just dropped it
right on your leaf it'll look like some
sort of white powdery water that dried
up and just left a little stain right
there that is the first indicator of
powdery mildew it will probably happen
in a low light area we are not getting a
lot of light but there is a lot of
moisture oftentimes it will happen or
that little bit of water just hangs on
that one leaf in that one spot it never
quite goes away that's where you're
going to get the PM so pay attention for
bugs pay attention for powdery mildew
our main goal right now is to keep these
plants pests and pathogens free and keep
them developing strong healthy root
systems so that we have strong healthy
plants when it's time to transplant them
and then later move them into flower now
that your plants are starting to grow
and you've spent some time with them
you've probably seen what happens when
you over and under water them a little
bit you've probably done one or the
other which has probably caused a little
bit of funky leaves I encourage you to
pull off all of the ugly leaves if
you've got yellowing crispy leaves take
those off those yellow leaves are an
invitation for spider mites that's why
we use yellow sticky cards in the garden
to help the pest go
those cards we see them on the cards and
we can tell that they're there but the
past loved to go to that yellow they
think that is a weak leaf imagine you're
a hungry spider mite and you see a big
healthy robust leaf that's got a really
thick layer of healthy vegetation to
chew through before you can get some
nutrients out of it or imagine just a
little lower on the plant you've got a
weak leaf it's yellow on the outside
it's got a real thin layer and you can
just poke right through it suck all the
juice you want right out of it like a
hungry little vampire bug you are you're
gonna go right to those weak yellow
leaves it's not as much work for food
you can get right in there and get what
you need
the spider mites are going right for
that yellow weak part so pull off all
those weak parts pull off all the yellow
leaves that's where the problems are
going to start anyway that's where the
plant is the weakest get that out of
there now while you're pulling off
leaves you may notice that the couple of
branches at the very bottom of your
plant are just weak and shitty and kind
of in the way if you've got a couple of
leaves that are hanging down into the
dirt pick that stuff right off we don't
need that very bottom crap on the plant
by the time it makes it to flower we're
going to clean up the bottom eight to
ten inches of that stalk anyway those
bottom branches will not even be there I
feel like if you take some of those
little sucker branches off the bottom
now it will encourage growth up to the
top of the plant we don't need that
stuff on the bottom the lights not going
to get to it that's where the problems
are gonna happen why not cut that stuff
right off if you're happy with the way
your plants look without pruning
anything off the bottom you don't have
to do it but if you've got two or three
branches on the bottom that just aren't
growing
to reach the rest of the branches if
they look weak why not take them off we
don't need that weak [ __ ] down there at
the bottom of the plant wasting energy
wasting nutrients and wasting water
let's just cut it right off and send
that energy right up to the top of the
plant
now as the plants get bigger you'll
notice they're starting to branch out a
little bit on the bottoms of some of the
branches you may start developing shoots
if those little shoots are weak you can
pinch those off as well you don't have
to take off the entire branch you can
just take off the shitty shoots at the
bottom and you can still leave the ends
of those branches and you can still have
more bud sites and more branches don't
take off too much now you can always
take off more in the future
you cannot glue branches back onto the
plant and keep in mind the plant grows
out of the top so the [ __ ] you take off
the bottom will not replace itself
you're cleaning up the
that is gone it's going to grow out of
the top keep that in mind now let's talk
a little bit about nutrients I always
recommend starting off with light
nutrients if your plants are showing any
yellow or if they're not growing as
quickly as you would like them to you
may need to increase the overall amount
of nutrients we are giving the plants I
always recommend starting low and
increasing as time goes on if your
plants are a little bit pale or
yellowish if they're not as green as we
would hope it would be at this point it
is probably time to increase our
nutrients also it may be time to add
some cal-mag to the mix if your plants
are growing properly if they're nice and
robust if they've got a nice root system
in this small pot I would recommend
adding a small dose of cal-mag once a
week to your feeding regimen if you feel
like you're feeding your plants properly
you're giving them a proper amount of
nitrogen you're giving them the proper
amount of Calem AG you're also giving
them some beneficials for the roots and
you're not seeing the growth you would
like to see I would suspect that it's
probably a pH issue check the pH of the
solution you are feeding your plants if
your pH is off your plants won't be able
to uptake nutrients which means they
will not grow so once you have mixed up
your nutrients put your pH pin in there
and see what the pH of that solution is
before you feed it to your plants if
it's not in the appropriate range adjust
it this is such an overlooked step most
of the time when people send me pictures
of their plants they say what is wrong
with my plant
I asked them what was the pH of your
last feeding solution you know what most
of their answers are I don't know
so I usually tell them check the pH and
get back to me because I would assume if
you're not checking the pH that is
probably the issue you didn't even
bother to check how do I know if you've
got another nutritional problem how do I
know if you're overfeeding or under
feeding a specific nutrient if I don't
know what the pH of your solution is
you've got to dial in the pH I've done
an entire episode on the importance of
pH for these small plants I really think
they would be happiest with a pH right
around 6 1 or 6 - you can go 5 8 2 6 3
if you really want to have a wide range
but I think 61 or 62 in cocoa or
soilless mix is going to be ideal for
these small plants we may increase that
pH as we go along the growth process as
we
pay attention to the plants and see how
they react to certain things but for now
I think this six point two is right
about where we need to be all right so
we've got clean healthy plants we don't
have any bugs we don't have any powdery
mildew we have increased our nutrients
to increase our vigor and increase
growth speed it is probably time to
spread your plants out if they are too
pressed together if they're too crowded
they're not going to branch out properly
so if you've got them crushed in there
real tight it's time to spread them out
if it looks like your plants are getting
too tall and too skinny and too stretchy
it's one of two things they either want
more light or they are too close
together which probably just means they
want more light if you've got branches
pressed together if you've got leaves
pressed together if you've got plants
overlapping each other if you've got one
plant pressed up against the wall they
know they're too tight together and
instead of branching out they're gonna
go straight up and try to get some light
they are all competing for light space
and you're probably running your small
veg under smaller lights which means
they're really competing for that space
if we crowd them in spread them out let
them get some light light is the number
one desired nutrient and source of
energy for our plants over their entire
life cycles they want light more than
anything light is the key
these plants think they're going to get
the Sun and we brought them indoors and
wired up little t5 bulbs and we're
trying to make them grow with that so
spoil them and give them as much of that
t5 lighting as they can get give them as
much space as they can handle so that
you can get maximum performance from our
small plants so now I feel like we've
got healthy plants that are pest free
they're probably about eight to ten
inches tall we're starting to get nice
branching on the bottom we've cleaned up
those crappy branches on the bottom
we've pulled off any funky leaves we've
spread them out so that they're not too
crowded we are probably going to
transplant these plants into their
forever homes within the next week or
two that's going to be the next grow
lesson that I provide will be
transplanting into our forever homes
I think one thing we should really focus
on until we transplant is fat root
development I like my plants to be
nearly root bound in these small pots
before I transplant them I like to have
to kind of break that root ball up at
transplant to make it explode it sounds
crazy but if you get that root ball kind
of
in a small pot when we transplanted into
the next pot it will really take off we
will really see explosive growth we will
have a really robust and healthy plant
from the very beginning with a solid
foundation so let's let these plants
grow and get kind of tight in their pots
you may see some roots coming out of the
bottom of your container that is a good
thing if those roots are nice and white
that means you were feeding those roots
very well that your plants are very
happy if they are getting a nice amount
of moisture that they're getting a nice
amount of dry thyme that everything is
going well
inside here rhizosphere now if you want
to take a look at your roots and see
what kind of root development you're
working with don't be afraid to grab a
cup or a pot with a plant in it and put
your finger over the pot and kind of
make a spa Kent where you're spreading
your ring finger and your middle finger
apart put the stalk of the plant right
between those two fingers and then just
flick that pot upside down and give it a
little bit of a shake if you're
confident you can pull that pot off and
you can look directly at the root
development if you start lifting that
pot off and the dirt starts falling out
like crazy and it's not compact and
pressed together push it back in there
and just leave it alone
the roots are not developed enough to
try this experiment if you start lifting
that pot off and all the dirt stays in
one piece and you can see those roots
you can just lift that pot right off and
you can take a look at the root
development if you can see those roots
wrapped around inside of there and all
the dirt and all the roots are tight
into one piece that is what we're aiming
for you are almost ready for transplant
I like to let those get almost rootbound
where the plant is almost filling that
container with roots to where it is
almost panicking time to put that into a
new pot I feel like if we wait that long
to put it into our next pot we get
explosive root growth when we transplant
it into the next container I also feel
like we get less transplant shock and I
feel like the plant is more developed
and more prepared to go into its larger
container so if you are experienced or a
confident grab a plant flip it upside
down and knock the container off of it
and see what comes out if all the dirt
goes flying and the roots come on
ravelin and hanging out just plant that
back in there really carefully and it
will be okay
if you're careful about it do your best
not to break any of the roots don't
disturb the roots you can get them back
in there while you've got it out
sprinkle a little bit of root or knock
youlet powder on there sprinkle some
plus life or some
right right onto the roots and put it
back in there and that inoculant will
encourage those roots to grow even more
quickly than they already were all right
podcast rolled I'm going to press pause
for a moment I need to take a drink I'll
probably take a couple of dabs while I'm
at it when I get back we will talk more
about developing healthy roots and we
will also talk about Michael Raizel
fungus so take a dab with me and I will
be right back all right podcast rolled I
am back I am well medicated I am well
hydrated let's talk more about healthy
roots and mycorrhizal fungus before we
transfer our small plants into their
forever homes
we want to develop thick healthy white
roots we want a big fat root system so
that we've got a well-established plant
to go into a larger pot a good microbe
product will encourage explosive root
growth let's talk about some of the
other advantages of our Michael Raizel
fungus the first obvious advantage is
more roots more roots means our plants
can eat more which means our plants can
drink more which means our plants will
grow more quickly which means we will
produce more branching which means we
will produce more buds which is our main
goal so the first benefit more roots
which means more productivity overall
from our plants another great function
of our beneficial fungus is they work as
a protective layer or a security guard
for our root zone they protect against
pathogen problems and illness in our
plants there's already a colony of
beneficial fungus gathered around the
roots if anything else tries to get near
it those colonies say hey this is our
turf bro and they fight off any
potential pathogens that want to get to
your root zone some of our beneficial
bacteria work in a similar function as
an enzyme it will break down decaying
matter it will break down nutrients and
it will make it more bioavailable to our
plants so our plants can take that waste
and actually turn it into food and
consume it and use it to its benefit now
if you are using a microbe product I
don't recommend that you stop using your
enzymes I recommend you use them
together let them team up and create a
beautiful environment in your raizo
sphere that will also create a lot of
diversity you will have multiple things
in there breaking down the decaying
matter that should really encourage a
clean healthy raizou sphere another
function of some of our beneficial
bacteria is the aid and the processes
that encouraged branching and bud set so
by introducing these beneficial bacteria
you may see more branching and you may
see more bud sites in your plants now
another great thing that these
beneficial bacteria is do is they were
to increase essential oil production now
what are essential oils essential oils
are our terpenes and cannabinoids you
can increase the overall production of
your plants you can increase the overall
flavor aroma and potency of your plants
by using the correct mycorrhizal fungus
now I try to avoid recommending brand
names there are several great micro
Raizel products available at your local
grocer or there are tons available
online I will list a few products that I
have had great experience with of course
I have to recommend recharge I really
like recharge recharge made my plants go
crazy one of the good things about
recharge is it contains dried molasses
which is constantly feeding the microbes
the microbes do need some sort of feel
it's already got feel in that container
another acceptable myko product is
called extreme mykos and they spell
mykos with a k' it's a great product it
is very affordable you don't have to buy
a very expensive micro product if you
want something that's affordable if
you're just gonna try it out
extreme mykos is probably one of the
most affordable microbe products on the
market if you want a liquid microbe
product you can get hydro guard from
botanic care I really like great white
great white is a powdered microbe
product I like the powders because you
can sprinkle them directly onto the
roots we're gonna talk more about that
when we get to the transplanting episode
but during transplant I like to sprinkle
the powders directly onto the roots and
into the hole where I'm transplanting my
plant
I also trance prinkle some right around
the outside where it's gonna grow these
beneficial fungus do not work unless
they actually touch the roots of the
plant so they have to touch the plant
that triggers them to germinate and
become alive so they have to come in
contact so sprinkle those powders right
onto the roots I really like that if you
want to stick with liquid and use
something similar to the great white
they make a product called orca orcas is
very similar to the great white they
took out two specific beneficial
funguses but I don't think you'll ever
notice they're miss
is just easier to keep them in a liquid
solution without that fungus in their
great white also makes a product called
my coach um I spoke earlier that I like
recharge because it's got a product that
feeds their beneficials that comes in
one package the folks that make great
white and Orca have put out a product
called my coach um that product will
feed your beneficials that also contains
unearth other things that will encourage
root growth and healthy plants the folks
that make great white and Orca and my
coach um also make a time-release
granule if I'm working in a large
container I like to start that pot with
some of the time-release granules
already in the soil I'll mix up a large
batch of soil with my amendments with my
perlite with my purse alight and then I
will just pour a big bag of the dried
granules from great white right across
the top of that makes it right in put
that into the pot and plant right into
that the plants go crazy I feel like
giving them plenty of that beneficial
bacteria really reduces transplant shock
and it really encourages explosive root
growth
another powdered root inoculant i can
recommend is the plus life from our
friends at veg bloom many of the
commercial grows in colorado are running
veg bloom so i would encourage them just
to add the plus life product right along
the veg bloom base mix i have had great
success using the veg bloom product line
and adding the plus life root inoculant
powder along with that mix and i've used
that and grows of all different sizes
I've used it in for light grows and I've
used it in 400 light grows and I like
the way it works in all conditions all
right I've got one more product to talk
about another great liquid microbe
product is mammoth pea mammoth pea is a
great product one of the great things
about mammoth pea is it is highly
concentrated another great thing is you
do not have to add anything to feed the
microbes mammoth pea uses microbes that
can sustain themselves off of the carbon
in the breakdown happening within the
rhizosphere so that is a list of great
microbe products I would recommend they
vary in application rates they vary in
amount of microbes per container and
they are going to vary widely in prices
find what works best for you and your
garden some of you are going to Anne
the dried powdered forms more some of
you are going to like the liquid forms
more some of you simply cannot get the
overpriced expensive products some of
you will only buy the overpriced
expensive products I get it everybody's
got their style that's why I recommended
several products I have used each of
those products I've had great experience
with those products and I feel like I
can recommend those products to you with
confidence that they're going to work in
your garden under just about any type of
conditions or any type of environment
now keep in mind that you may need to
feed your microbes I mentioned earlier
that some of the microbes do contain
other additives it will feed themselves
I will still encourage you to feed the
microbes the microbes want to eat carbs
the plants want to eat carbs add a
little bit of carbohydrates the
carbohydrates will give your plants
energy and the carbohydrates will feed
your microbes it's a win-win situation
don't overdose the carbs trying to feed
them both
I generally suggest starting off with
half of the recommended dose if you buy
a bottle of a carbohydrate product and
it says feed 40 I recommend you start
off with 20 pay attention if the plants
seem happy you don't need to increase
the dosage if you want to you can
increase the dosage until you see the
plants react poorly that's what a lot of
growers like to do push it as hard as we
can and then back off that's how you
learn the limits of a plant but if
you're a newer grower if you're not
super experienced just feed it half of
that recommended dosage and the plants
will be receiving that nutrition even if
you don't see anything happening be
careful overdoing it with a carbohydrate
product late and flower because it will
make your buds burn like a rock they'll
just turn into a charcoal briquette and
they won't burn very well if you overdo
it with the molasses or a carbohydrate
product late in bloom now earlier I
mentioned my coach um if you want a
quality product to feed your microbes
and encourage micro growth and encourage
root growth and overall plant health
check out my coach um from the same
folks that make the great white product
line now when it comes to feeding your
microbes
I recommend more frequent smaller doses
now the first time I introduced microbes
to my feeding regimen I usually give it
what the bottle says if the container
says one gram or 25 milliliters I will
add that to my nutrient solution and I
will water that right
my goal is to get a good start of a
colonization of microbes I just want to
give it a good head start just put them
in there and get them going
then my subsequent waterings I will
probably give it half of the recommended
dosage but those products usually say to
water it in once a week instead of doing
it once a week I'll reduce the dosage to
half and water it every time I water for
a couple of weeks to build a nice solid
colony of beneficial fungus in my raizo
sphere now after I transplant into my 3
gallon pots and I get the roots on
crankin and I've got a nice fat root
ball in that pot I will start reducing
my frequency of inoculant feedings in a
commercial grow when I'm in flour I
generally feed plus life once a week and
that's enough through the flowering
cycle once I've got the roots nice and
healthy and everything is developed I
will generally use the plus life to keep
problems away it keeps the root zone
nice and clean a nice enzymatic product
and a nice micro Raizel product again
will work to keep the roots clean and
healthy and happy and pathogen free so
I'll just continue the once a week
feeding just to keep everybody clean and
happy and kind of it's sort of like
plant probiotics it's like giving
probiotics to a plant if you take
probiotics for your gut health it just
has it good you've got a good gut biome
we're making a good gut biome for our
plants by feeding them probiotics which
are actually Michael Raizel fungus when
it comes to the plant world
all right podcast world I've got one
more thing to talk about and then we
were going to start wrapping up this
episode when you were listening or
reading or learning about mycorrhizal
fungus you will hear three words quite
frequently that basically mean the same
thing you will hear the word inoculated
you will hear the word of vaccinated and
you will also hear the word infected
these words all basically mean that the
root zone shows the presence of a
mycorrhizal fungus we inoculate our root
zone with a fungus by adding it
ourselves we have now inoculated it once
that takes hold it is basically
vaccinated once it travels across the
root zone it is infected that is a
positive thing I know they sound like
scary words but in this situation all
three of those words are positive thing
that we want happening within our raizo
sphere so when you hear the word
inoculated vaccinated or infected keep
in mind it just means basically the
presence of mycorrhizal fungus within
our root zone all right podcast world
that is my talk about continuing small
healthy feds that is also my lesson on
micro Raizel fungus i want to thank you
guys for listening to this episode if
you were interested in learning a lot
more about michael Raizel fungi I highly
recommend a podcast called cannabis
cultivation and sciences by tad Hussey
tad recently had Jim Egan on the show
and they do a deep dive into Michael
Raizel fungus and I highly recommend the
episode it was great timing I had
already planned this episode to come out
this week I was writing this episode and
then Monday this episode popped up it
was beautifully time so you've got a
nice introduction from me and then tad
takes it really deep if you're going to
listen to Dad's podcast I highly
recommend a notebook and a pen you are
going to learn a lot about cultivation
you will learn a lot about organic
cultivation you'll learn about
sustainability you will learn about
permaculture and he will certainly learn
about Michael Raizel fungi again the
podcast is called cannabis cultivation
and Sciences and I highly recommend it
if you want to expand your cultivation
knowledge podcast world that's all I've
got for you for this episode I want to
thank you again for listening again if
you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
and you would like to make a financial
contribution to the show I would
appreciate your support and you can
contribute by going to patreon.com slash
grow from your heart all the information
you need to become a patron will be
right there on the screen and just a
reminder patreon recently did an update
that discontinued a lot of auto
subscriptions if you feel like you were
signed up to contribute to a patreon
campaign I encourage you to log into
your patreon account and make sure you
were still supporting all of the content
providers which you think you were
signed up to give contributions to and
once again I owe a huge thank you to
everyone who is contributed to my
patreon campaign thank you all for all
of the support I would also appreciate
it if you find me on social media you
can find me on Facebook simply search
for the Grove from your heart podcast on
Twitter it's at
fyh podcast if you want to follow my
personal Twitter account it's at Rasta
Jeff 420 if you've got something you'd
like to say and you're not into the
social media maybe you'd like to sponsor
the podcast perhaps you've got a product
you'd like me to review maybe you've
just got a question you can reach me
through email my email address is grow
from your heart at hotmail.com
I would love to hear from you don't
forget that the show is available on
iTunes stitcher and most reputable
podcast services also every episode is
available on youtube go to youtube.com
and search for the Grove from your heart
podcast I would appreciate it if you
click Subscribe maybe type some comments
and some videos show the podcast a
little bit of YouTube love and support I
would appreciate that
all right podcast world I will be back
Monday with a fresh new episode we will
talk about transplanting our small
plants into their forever homes I look
forward to that episode I can't wait to
join you there I want to give a huge
shout out to my friend Hot Sauce Herman
and until next time take a phat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
welcome to the show cannabis community
it's time for episode 370 of the Grove
from your heart podcast this episode is
brought to you by the hella dank seed
company if you need new seeds for your
garden I highly recommend the hella dank
seed company and you can find them at
www.cdxzipstream.com farms this stuff
smells like skunky strawberries and just
funky fruit and if you dab it in a nice
low temperature it tastes like
strawberries and cream with a hint of
skunky gas enos in the background it is
very delicious it's almost like eating
some strawberry shortcake at the gas
station that's what it kind of smells
like to me the lab tests on the front
here says seventy two point three
percent THC with a total cannabinoid
content of 83.9% I really like this
concentrate it tastes delicious the high
is great and the texture and consistency
are beautiful there's just enough Terp
sauce in here and it's got some nice
chunky crystals I am really happy with
that purchase great concentrate from our
friends and apothecary farms all right
my next order of business is to give a
couple of people some shout outs on
you shot at a brick Gorman how about a
giant shout-out to Riley Hanson a big
shout-out to my co Panther a big thank
you shout out to Sam and also a giant
fist bump and a shout-out to Aldridge
thank you guys for the continued patreon
support all right podcast world this is
going to be another grow lesson if
you've been following along you know
I've been doing a long series of grow
lessons that series starts at episode
351 in this series of lessons we started
by setting a goal for our grow then we
decided a good place for our growth then
we acquired the appropriate equipment
and set it up then we either acquired
seeds or clones and we got those growing
at this point in my grow lessons we
should have small plants that are
approximately 8 to 12 inches tall and
they are in small pots they are probably
in either beer cups or 4 inch pots or
maybe six or eight inch net pots but
we've got small plants they should be
nice and healthy at this point they
should have nice branching coming out of
them they should not have any bugs or
any powdery mildew hopefully at this
point we don't have any burned leaves or
any signs of deficiencies hopefully we
have got a nice developed thriving root
system to work with now if most of those
things are accurate we've got a nice
healthy plant that is growing it's
branching it looks healthy its thriving
it's not struggling and we've got a nice
healthy root system it is time to
transplant our small plants into our
larger pot our finishing pot and start
the large veg phase now these plants
will probably finish out in these pots
unless you want to transplant one more
time into an even larger pot I like to
go from the small pot into my finishing
pot I'm generally going to go into a 3
gallon or a 5 gallon or a 7 gallon in an
indoor garden you guys may choose to go
larger you may want to go from the small
6 Internet pot maybe to a 1 gallon then
maybe into your 20 or 30 gallon if
you're gonna do something like that I
talked in a previous episode about why
it's a good idea to use a smaller
container for smaller plants we don't
need to water this giant area when we've
got a tiny plant right in the middle so
if you're gonna go to like a 20 or 30
gallon pot you may want to go from the
cup to maybe a 1 gallon maybe a 3 gallon
bin later on transplant that into your
20 or 30 but it gets challenging when
you go to transplant larger plants if
you're not experienced with it
you can cause damage you need to lay
that larger
on its side you need to remove that pot
Benini Department a much larger plant it
does get difficult but I have faith in
you that you can do it if you choose to
transplant twice just be careful in this
lesson we're gonna focus on
transplanting one time we're gonna go
from this small beer cup or our four
inch or our six inch net pot or maybe an
eight inch pot and we're going to pot
into a three or a five or a seven gallon
pot for my example alright let's talk a
little bit about pots and soil I did a
long episode about choosing pots and
soil but let's do a brief recap I like
to use the plastic nursery pots in a
home grow in a commercial facility I
like to use a root pot one of the fabric
pots in most applications I am using a
three gallon pot you can use whatever
kind of pots make you happy as long as
it's going to get you to your goal the
thing I find most important is to make
sure that whatever container you use
that it has plenty of holes for drainage
make sure that when you water this plant
the excess water has some way to escape
from the bottom of that pot the nursery
pots have plenty of holes in them
already
the fabric pots will drain naturally
just because they're match those work
perfectly if you're going to use a home
depot bucket or something like that
make sure you drill plenty of drainage
holes in your container now let's talk
briefly about soil or soilless mix you
don't have to buy a really expensive
soil if you're going to feed your plants
with bottled nutrients you can buy an
inert medium
you don't need a soil or soilless mix
with a lot of nutrients any lot of stuff
in there you're going to be on top of
fertilizing these plants with your
bottled nutrient so we don't need to pay
extra money for a soil or a soilless mix
it's got a bunch of stuff in there that
will give us the opportunity to burn our
plants because we are going to add them
to a soil that's got nutrients in it
then we're going to add bottled
nutrients on top of that we do run the
risk of over fertilizing the plants in
that situation so we don't really need
an over fertilized soil or soilless mix
we need something more inert maybe
something with some mykos or some
beneficial fungus in there that would be
advantageous but we don't really need a
lot of nutrients whatever medium you
choose to purchase I reckon
you get something with a lot of aeration
in it either a lot of perlite or a lot
of personal light and if it doesn't come
with plenty of aeration product already
in it buy a bag of perlite and amend it
yourself now the amount of perlite or
personal light you're going to need to
add to your soil or soilless mix will
depend on the fluffiness and the amount
of aeration in that medium when you
purchase it I'm not sure what you're
going to purchase so I'm not sure what
to recommend as a ratio of how much
perlite I like it fluffy when I'm
working with Coco I mix three bags of
cocoa and one 5-gallon bucket of perlite
and one 5-gallon bucket of personal
light now that gives me about 25 to 33
gallon pots worth of material to work
with you guys can reduce that recipe as
needed for your garden now if I were
working with soil or a soilless mix I
might not use as much perlite I may
reduce that perlite by about half you
don't need in my opinion I don't need as
much aeration in soil and soilless mix
as I do in the cocoa I feel like the
cocoa holds a lot more water so it also
pushes out a lot more air and it kind of
crushes the plants a little more it gets
heavier because it's got so much water
in there the soil and soilless mix
doesn't hold as much water so it doesn't
get is heavy and it doesn't crush the
roots as much so you don't need as much
perlite maybe go half as much maybe if
you're doing three bags of soil do half
of a 5-gallon bucket of personal light
and a half of a 5-gallon bucket of
perlite if you guys aren't going to buy
the personal I understand it's more
expensive it's another product to buy
you will get by with just using perlite
perlite is just fine for this situation
if you only want to buy the one product
that will be fine so three bags of soil
and maybe one bag of perlite for this
application and I know I work in larger
batches than a lot of people if you want
to reduce this recipe for a smaller
garden I think they sell the bags of
soil in 1.75 cubic yards is what I think
most of those bags if there are or at
least the bags of cocoa I was buying her
1.7 7 cubic yards if you buy a 1.7 7
cubic yards of dirt makes that with a
third of a five-gallon bucket of perlite
so just fill the bucket up about a third
maybe half way if you want to go hard
then mix that in really well with your
soil
so that it's nicely even evenly mixed in
there with everything else so that you
just see the little white spots
everywhere then you know you've got
plenty of aeration throughout your
entire root zone now while we're mixing
up perlite into our soil why not mix in
some sort of root inoculant powder in a
previous episode I talked all about
Michel Raizel fungi let's add a
mycorrhizae product to our mix right now
and get it distributed all throughout
the soil something like the great white
granulars would work perfectly you can
use great white shark on its own just
sprinkle it in there right now you can
use plus life right now any sort of
powdered myko product would work
wonderfully right now sprinkle it right
into the dirt as you're mixing it up so
I feel like that's a great way to segue
into actually starting to do the
transplanting process we've got healthy
plants we've got a container we've got a
good soil or soilless mix it's well
aerated we've put a myko product in
there now let's actually get to work
step number one you guys is always find
the Bluetooth speaker and put on the
growth from your heart podcast it helps
you grow it makes the plants happy and
it puts you in a good mood to create a
positive garden environment so step
number one find the Bluetooth speaker or
find your earbuds get your earbuds in
get hooked up with the growth from your
heart podcast that is going to make your
garden grow so much more rapidly it's
gonna make you grow more rapidly it's
gonna make everything go better so step
number one find the growth from your
heart podcast get it at an acceptable
volume and get that going in the growth
step number two get some rubber gloves I
often overlook this step we should
always be wearing gloves if we're coming
in contact with mykos if we're coming in
contact with the roots if we're coming
in contact with bottled nutrients we
should be wearing gloves also if you're
gonna be sprinkling those myko products
over your topsoil just all willy-nilly
maybe you might want to consider some
sort of a mask we don't really want to
breathe in microbe products so we've got
the pod cast on we're gloved up we've
got a face mask on you got your
dreadlocks tied up hopefully your nicely
medicated if that's appropriate wherever
you work or whatever you're growing now
let's actually get to business here we
need to fill our container whatever size
container we chose we need to fill it
with our well
next medium we've got our soilless mix
we've got our cocoa hopefully we've got
a bunch of perlite in there hopefully we
added a myko product to there we've got
it all mixed up now it's ready to go
into a container I like to fill my
containers by using a smaller container
just a scoop dirt out of the bag or
whatever container it's in and just dump
it right into the pot that it's going
into just fill it up fill it up most of
the way if you're filling up a three
gallon five-gallon or seven gallon pot
fill it up most of the way believe
yourself about an inch and a half or
maybe two inches at the top or you don't
fill it all the way up all the way to
the brim leave yourself about inch and a
half two inches so that when we water
we've got some room to put water in the
pot you don't want to pour water on the
pot and watch it run right off the top
you don't want to have to stand there
and pour water really slowly to where
you can get that whole quarter or half
or gallon of water into the pot so you
can water it appropriately I like to be
able to just splash a gallon of water on
top of a seven gallon pot and just watch
it saturate that whole top area and then
you can just walk away and do the next
pot if you fill it up too far you got to
just stand there and pour it slowly
toward the water saturates into the
medium and drains down a little bit then
you can pour a little more leave
yourself some space also in the future
we may choose to top dress these plants
we may want to add some worm castings
you may want to add some bat guano you
may just add some fresh soil with some
charged up nutrients in it to the top
layer so leave yourself in the room so
that you've got options and you've got
watering space now as you are filling
your container pack your medium in there
slightly tight you don't want it packed
real snug but you don't want it fluffy
and loops we want to make the roots work
to dig down into the dirt and have some
more to grow and kind of do a little
exercise to get in there but we also
don't want to suffocate them and make it
so hard that the roots simply can't grow
into the medium so you have to pack it a
little bit but don't crush it so tight
to where the roots can't even grow now
if you packed it too loosely you will
notice on the first couple of waterings
you'll just get a giant hole in the
center all the dirt will just cave in
you'll create a hole in the middle
and then you'll have to repack it put
more dirt in there then rhe water it
that's okay
you didn't mess up you just should have
gone a little harder in the first place
you will learn if you go too hard the
roots just aren't gonna grow if you go
too soft the water is just gonna fall
right through and you
we'll definitely get indicators so fill
your container pack it slightly tight I
usually just use the palm of my hand and
I give it just a few Pat's I throw in
just a few scoops of dirt just to give
myself a few inches of dirt and then I
just Pat it in and then I throw in some
order and then I just Pat it in you can
hear me just happen on the table here
it's not that hard just patting it down
just getting the dirt nice and even in
there then I just pour more dirt on top
of it just Pat it down I'd rather pour
some in and then pack it down and then
pour some in and pack it down instead of
fill it up and then try to pack all that
down I feel like that's kind of it's not
really as productive as packing each
little layer so pour some dirt in there
pack it down pour some dirt pack it down
get yourself up to about an inch and a
half or two inches to the top now here's
where it gets fun we have got our three
our five or seven gallon pot filled with
our appropriate mix and it is leveled
off and we've got about an inch and a
half or two inches of space so that we
can add water or top dress later in the
future now in the very center of that
pot we need to create a space for our
transplanted plant we need to create a
little hole in which to place our small
root ball the way I like to do it is
find the middle that top soil and just
dig out about a fist-sized worth of dirt
just take out about just a fist I've got
a pretty big fist so just take out about
a fist-sized worth of dirt right in the
center of that top soil then whatever
size pot my plant is already in say I'm
in a beer cup or maybe I'm in a six-inch
net pot I will take a beer cup or a
six-inch net pot and I will dig a hole
in my new pot soil right at the top
right in the center and I will actually
plant the cup in that hole I will dig a
hole perfectly to where that cup will
fit then it will backfill dirt around
that cup kind of snug then I will pull
the cup or the six-inch net pot out of
that made hole now I have got a perfect
template that is the exact shape of the
incoming root ball from my small veg
plant
so I basically leveled off the dirt I
dug out a hole I put the previous pot in
that hole I back filled it then I just
pulled that pot right out so I made an
impression a template just a little gap
for the next plant to fit perfectly into
so you've got a top layer of soil with
this little round hole perfectly waiting
just chill and wait for a pot to go in
it now our next step is to pot our small
veg plant
into that hole but before we do that you
know what I'm gonna recommend let's
sprinkle a little mica powder right into
that hole our fresh exposed roots are
gonna go right there let's just sprinkle
some mica powder right there let's just
give it some love give it a boost give
it a head start
that's just like laying out some cookies
for Santa just get it nice and ready put
some micro powder right in the hole
now our next challenge will be to get
the small plant out of that small pot
hopefully it is grown really tight into
your beer Cup or really tight into your
six-inch net pot it is nicely rootbound
there's a lot of root mass in that
container so it's gonna take a little
effort to get it out the way I do it as
I make a Spock hand I've got my first
finger in my middle finger together I've
got my ring finger and my pinky finger
together I place the stick of the plant
between in between my middle finger and
my ring finger sticking up the root ball
the soil is in my palm then I flip it
upside down so now the plant is hanging
upside down and I'm holding on to the
root ball with my Spock hand I'll take
my I do that in my left hand cuz it did
I don't need as much coordination it can
just stay there then I take my right
hand and I kind of just squeeze the cup
or the beer or the beer cup or the
six-inch net pot just squeeze it all
around just squeeze it
if you've ever rolled a joint too tight
and you're trying to loosen the joint
it's the same idea we're just trying to
loosen the dirt out of that cup so just
squeeze all around it just squeeze it
that's all you really got to do and
you'll feel it loosening up maybe
squeeze it and work it to the left and
right just a little bit you'll feel how
to loosen the dirt inside of that pot
once you start doing it all you're
trying to do is loosen the dirt so that
it will fall out give it a little shake
and it's gonna fall out you're gonna
have an exposed root zone in your hand
now it's okay
hopefully when it came out it all stayed
together in one big chunk hopefully
you've taken good care of it you've
properly watered it you've given a
proper dry time and the roots have
developed nice and fat in there so it's
all just one chunk if it came out as a
mess that's okay we're just gonna pop
that whole mess into that hole that we
already made and it will be just fine
once you get the root ball out of the
container you already know what I'm
gonna say sprinkle a little mykos on it
why not
we've got exposed roots those roots love
mykos those
those are activated by touching roots
sprinkle them on there give it as much
mica powder as you can afford to
sprinkle on there at this time just give
it a nice little coating just in fact it
was brute an ocular outer van we want to
if it came out in a mess
you need to gently place it in that hole
get as much of that original dirt as you
can in there set the root ball down put
some soap maybe put the if there are
dangling long roots set the dangling
roots in there put a little dirt on top
of it loader the plant in a little bar
put some dirt on top of it lower it in a
little bit more so that you don't bind
to those roots up we're trying to give
those roots space we don't want to just
drop them right in there and smother
them with fresh dirt so if they came
apart keep them apart when you're
putting them in there then backfill it
with all the dirt from that container
and you should have enough dirt there to
level everything off if you lost some
dirt during the movement just grab some
more dirt out of your mix and just top
it or you have a nice even layer kind of
pack it in not super tight just tight
enough to keep that plant staying
straight upright now if it came out nice
and smooth now we've got another option
if it came out nice and smooth and you
feel like those roots are perfect and
they aren't super bound but they're
growing well you can just set still
sprinkle some Aiko's on it then you can
set that perfect root ball right into
that perfect hole maybe sprinkle a
little bit of dirt on top of it and Pat
it in and you've got a beautifully
transplanted plant it didn't get any
shock or any stress whatsoever during
the transplanting process our other
option when you take it out of the small
container if it is really bound up in
there if you see a lot of white roots
and it is growing in a circle and it's
getting spiraled you do have the option
to kind of break those roots up just a
little bit the way I do it is I hold it
with my left hand and I take my middle
finger and my ring finger on my right
hand and I come straight up from the
bottom of that root ball and I just plow
my fingers through it and just pull it
apart just spread it right in half
you're gonna tear some roots up you're
gonna mess some stuff up if you've got a
nice healthy root system that is only
going to encourage growth you're
spreading it out a little bit then when
you set it in that template hole that
you've got the roots will spread out a
little bit and instead of drawing in a
perfect spiral they're gonna take off a
little bit for you and fill that pot so
either way
my cows on the roots on that root ball
that you pull out of the pot sprinkle
mykos on there always sprinkle some
Aiko's into the hole then gently place
that small root ball into that fresh
hole and just cover it with dirt gently
again don't pack it down too tightly but
pack it down tight enough tore you know
it's not gonna cave in when we water it
and then it's tight enough to give that
plant enough support to stay upright you
will know on the first watering if you
did not do it tightly enough if you
didn't do it tight enough you're just
gonna need to add more media now that
plan is basically transplanted I
recommend you label that plant at this
time before you forget the next step is
to move that plant under the appropriate
light I should also mention you may need
a saucer or some sort of a catch tray
underneath your plants when we water
these plants we expect to have some
runoff so now it was a good time to
consider placing your plant on a saucer
or some sort of a catch tray so we've
got the trays down let's talk about the
lighting in which we are going to place
these plants under you can use tee fives
for your fresh transplants you can get
the tee fives
really close you can get those t5 lights
three maybe four inches away from your
canopy just make sure that you adjust
them every day because the plants are
going to grow rapidly and they will grow
into those lights if you don't pay
attention you can also use ceramic metal
halide for your fresh transplants I like
the 315 s or the 630 s you need to keep
those a little bit further away than the
t5 is probably about a foot maybe 18
inches away led's are very brand and
power specific I would follow the
recommendation from the manufacturer on
your LED I don't have enough experience
with your LED to know what it's going to
do to the plants there are so many
vendors so many different makes and
models that it is hard to give advice
for LED lighting but you certainly can
use LEDs through the entire cycle and
you can absolutely use them right now
for your fresh transplants you can also
use metal halide or high pressure sodium
also known as high-intensity discharge
lighting if you are going to use
high-intensity discharge lighting pay
close attention to how the plants are
reacting if you're using a 400 you can
probably get 12 to 18 inches away
and not have any problems if you were
using a 600 you could probably get 18
inches away and not have any problems if
you're using a thousand watt light you
may want to start off about two feet
away from the canopy maybe even more as
you start introducing these plants to
that larger light as time goes on you
can get closer they will grow closer to
the light but when you were introducing
young plants to large lights pay
attention to how they react we don't
want to burn these lights we don't want
to stress them I said lights we don't
want to burn the plants we don't want to
stress the plants we don't want to put
them into any kind of shock right as we
transplant them this is a critical time
we were trying to put them into turbo
mode right now we don't want to slow
them down we don't want to punish them
and put them on timeout we want to give
them encouragement to take off right now
so we have our plants under the
appropriate light we've got our light
the appropriate distance away from our
canopy let's talk about the amount of
light hours we are going to give these
plants I've talked earlier about
lighting schedules and apparently in a
previous episode I did make a mistake at
some point I said something about 18 on
and 16 off or something like that
somebody said your light cycle will
always add up to 24 hours if my light
cycle I said didn't add up to 24 hours I
was too high to be doing a podcast and I
do apologize honestly when you talk as
much as I do I think you're gonna make a
few mistakes and I encourage you guys to
let me know when I make a mistake so
that I can't correct it and I do
apologize somebody said I did make a
light cycle mistake I apologize for that
allow me to correct myself in this part
there are several cycles that work very
well for our veg plants one common cycle
is 24 hours on and zero hours off I
mainly recommend this if you have mother
plants they tend to auto flower on you
or when you were cutting clones our next
option is 20 hours on and 4 hours off I
like to give the plants a few hours to
sleep this also gives my equipment 4
hours to rest when you're running a
bedroom with 25 lights that is a hundred
hours of lights that you don't have to
run that's a lot of electricity that you
save you're also not paying for as much
cooling and humidity control it makes a
big difference so the 20 on and 4 off is
good for your equipment all
so the plants get to take a nap who
doesn't want to take a nap I feel like
the roots do a lot of activity in the
dark cycle I feel like the plants grow a
lot in the dark cycle sugars are
processed in the dark cycle so 20 on 4
off is great that will make any plants
that may want to Otto flower and a
lesser cycle that will prevent them from
autoflowering and it will also give you
maximum growth and will keep your mother
plants really happy another very common
veg
on and 6 off this is very common because
it very closely mimics the outdoor cycle
of the natural light
another option is 16 on and 8 off this
is very similar to outdoors as well the
reason people will adjust between the 16
and 8 and the 18 and 6 is because some
plants will try to flower on their own
with the 16 hours of daylight once they
get large enough and once they get root
bound also I feel like more light is
more energy light is the number one
desired source of energy and nutrient
for our plants so why not maximize the
light input of course some plants will
only take so much light per day and
they'll just shut themselves down but I
don't think you're going to overload
them with light in a small grow room
with a grow light so again our options
are 24 hours on and 0 hours off I
wouldn't really recommend that for these
large batch plants the next option is 20
hours on and four hours off in a
commercial environment that is what I
would do in another environment you can
go 18 on and 6 off that is very
acceptable
another option is 16 on and 8 off that
is very acceptable another thing I found
advantageous of the 20 on and 4 off is
when I do induce that 1212 flowering
cycle those plants really notice a
change in photo period and they really
go into flower really quickly so that's
something that I found has helped quite
a bit
any of those light cycles will work for
your veg plant find what works best for
you
you will find pros and cons to each of
those options based on your environment
your location your setup and your
overall grow you're going to have to
things through trial and error when it
comes to growing try some things out see
what works best for you and your plants
ultimately it's going to come down to
what works best for your plants they are
the boss alright at this point our small
veg plants have been up potted they are
now large veg plants we've got them in
there forever pots we've got them
underneath a good light we have got that
light on a solid schedule we've got our
pots sitting on a saucer or some sort of
a catch tray it is now time to water our
new transplants
I recommend feeding these transplants
with a strong vegetative nutrient if
you've got a bottle that says veg that's
the one you need right now you need
something with a good NPK ratio you need
more n then you do P and K you need a
high end ratio for this time also I
would recommend a Mico product if you
haven't put plenty of powdered mykos in
there I recommend a micro Raizel fungal
product that is in liquid form that you
can feed right in your nutrient solution
right now mix that in also a small dash
of carbs a little bit of carbohydrates
will help feed those mykos also it will
give the plants a little bit of energy
I also recommend a little bit of cal-mag
at this time the plants are big enough
to take cal-mag give them a little bit
of a boost I would also recommend a
little bit of enzymes at this time that
will speed everything up it'll help keep
the root zone nice and clean the micro
products and the enzymes will work
together they will make a happy
rhizosphere
your plants will thrive you may also
want to add a little bit of potassium
silicates at this time potassium
silicates make for robust plants and it
will also help with any stress if you
have any environmental stressors that
potassium silicon will make the plants
just a little more resilient and a
little tougher for the mistakes that you
may make now I recommend you adjust the
pH of your feed solution to somewhere
between 62 and 64 if we were in cocoa in
a commercial facility I would tell the
guys to adjust the pH to 63 if we were
in a soilless mix in a commercial
facility I would tell them to go six
three two six four so mix up your
nutrient solution put your pH meter in
there see what the value is and adjust
up or down as necessary right
that down then water the plants with
that solution since we're talking about
watering plants I highly recommend you
go back and take a listen to episode 337
which is titled one through five
watering tech one through five watering
tech will help all growers if you're a
new grower if you're an experienced
grower if you're a professional grower
you will learn something from the one
through five water tech episode if you
are an experienced grower and you're
trying to teach a new grower how to
water your garden one through five water
tech is a great training exercise so I
recommend everybody listen to episode
337 and learn about one through five
watering tech now before you water your
plants we talked about the pH I did not
talk about the temperature of the water
it's winter time in Colorado and it is
really cold if you're pulling water
right out of the tap it's coming out of
the tap way too cold to apply to the
plants we need the water that we feed
our plants to be right around 70 degrees
maybe 65 would be acceptable but I
wouldn't go much lower than 65 imagine
sticking your feet and some 65 degree
water first thing in the morning that's
what it's like when you water the plants
with 65 degree water so I wouldn't go
any lower than 65 I would stay closer to
70 maybe up in the 75 not much warmer
than that right around 70 degrees is
just about ideal for watering the plants
in a home grow you can always just turn
the hot water on as you're filling up
your container in some environments we
don't have the option for hot water if
your water is coming out too cold you
can either get a bucket heater from your
local tractor or farm supply store they
just sell bucket heaters they also saw
them at the farm supply store for
troughs so that you can warm up the pig
and horse water so they don't have to
drink ice water in the morning or if a
bucket heater is not an option for you
you can always fill up containers of
water you can take them into the
flowering rooms or the bedrooms the day
before and let that light and that grow
room environment warm up the water for
you of course that's only if you
remember to do that the day before so my
point is don't feed the plants water
that is really cold we want that water
to be right around 70 degrees now in
this first watering make sure you really
saturate the medium make sure you have
plenty of water
coming out of those drainage holes we
want to make sure to soak every spot of
the container we don't want a dry spot
because roots will not grow into dry
areas nutrients aren't getting into
those dry areas so make sure you fully
saturate the pot I like to soak it every
time I water but it's mostly important
this very first time water until you get
a lot of water coming out of those holes
also don't leave the plant ever standing
in stagnant water if that water in the
bottom of your trailer doesn't
evaporates sucked up by that plant
within a few hours
get a shot back and suck that out of
there all right so now our plants are
all successfully transplanted they have
now been fed they're big-kid nutrients
let's talk a little bit about the
environment in which to keep these
plants we know where to keep the lights
we know what cycled I have the lights on
let's talk about the temperature during
the day I try to keep the temperature
between 70 and 80 degrees then I try to
keep the night around 65 to 75 I really
try to have no more than a 10 degree
swing in my temperature between day and
night
meaning if it's 70 during the day I want
it no lower than 60 during the night I
honestly try to keep about five to seven
degrees in that swing I know it's
difficult on a home grow sometimes we
don't have the appropriate equipment to
monitor and/or adjust things all the
time but do your best to keep it within
a ten degree differential between night
and day now at this point in the large
veg phase I try to keep the humidity
between 40 and 60% right around 50 is
ideal if you want to understand more
about why I keep the humidity and the
temperature the way I do I recommend you
check out episode 314 and it's called
vapor pressure deficit and you can learn
about VPD and why it's important to keep
the temperature and humidity in the
appropriate range for our plants another
thing I like to add to our large veg is
a fan I like to have wall fans or those
fans on stands depending on your setup
but I like to have a fan just
oscillating in the room circulating the
air
the idea is to circulate the air I want
to move the stale air around and move
that fresh air around so the plants have
fresh air constantly you don't need to
beat the [ __ ] out of the plants with a
fan I go in some grows and they're just
terrorizing plants with fans and just
beating them to death and
wondering why the plants look like [ __ ]
we just want to rustle the leaves we
just want to move the air around so I
like to put a fan about one fan every
one or two lights depending on the size
of the room and the environment but make
sure that every area is getting fresh
air in that room at this point I feel
like we have officially entered the
large veg phase our main goals in focus
now are to keep the plants pests and
pathogens free we need to avoid nutrient
and pH mistakes make sure not to over
feed our plants at this time also pay
very close attention to the pH of your
feeding solutions we need to keep these
plants healthy and vigorous we need to
work on the top part of the plants now
we'll be focused on the bottom for the
first half now we're gonna focus more on
the top half that means in the upcoming
episodes we're going to work on shaping
and structuring these plants we're also
going to talk about popping and twisting
then we'll talk about bottoming and
topping and lolli popping our plants but
that is all in upcoming episodes I've
got two quick things to cover before we
start wrapping up this episode and then
we are out of here for this week you
guys one thing I should talk about is
pest management now is a good time if
you are going to apply pesticide sprays
today is a good day to start that IPM
program those plants are moving into the
bedroom they're in their big pots let's
go ahead and hit them with a light
pesticide spray turn off the lights
douse the plants give them a couple
hours to dry off turn the lights back on
to their regularly scheduled program and
pay attention to those plants see how
they react
hopefully you wrote down exactly what
you sprayed on those plants you wrote
down the product and you wrote how much
per gallon you applied you wrote down
what time you applied it and now you
have a good frame of reference so you
can go in and look you can see how the
plants reacted if they look angry you
need to reduce the application next time
if they look happy about it you can do
the same thing or consider increasing
the application rate if necessary so I
generally start my heavy pest management
application right when I move them into
the large pots
another thing that will be important to
think about is flip time how long are
these plants going to veg in this
environment how much space do you have
depending on your genetics depending on
your lighting
depending on your overall environment
these plants could double in size if you
were working within a rise cross there
is a good likelihood that by the time
you finish that plant it will be twice
the size it was when you started the
flowering process so if that plant is 24
inches tall when you induce flowering
there's a good chance that plant will
end up 48 inches tall before it is done
so as a grower you need to plan ahead
you need to make sure that plant does
not grow up into your lights and burn
itself you need to save depending on the
type of light you're using you need to
save some space between the bulb and
your top cola so plan ahead now is the
time to start thinking about how long
we're going to veg if you veg to long
the plants will get too tall you'll have
problems we're also going to do things
like topping and bottoming and Lolly
popping and twisting and cracking and
trellising and manipulating these plants
so we're going to need to give them a
little bit of time to recover from some
of these techniques before we initiate
the flowering process so if we plan
ahead and know how long we anticipate to
veg we can predict when to do these
steps to increase production and flower
at the ideal time and fill our grow
space perfectly we can end up with our
canopy right about eight inches below
that light and it'll be nice and even
and look beautiful you won't have any
wasted space in there once you're an
experienced grower your goal will be to
fill your grow space if you've got a 5
by 5 grow tent you want a 5 by 5 canopy
or at least a four and a half by four
and a half canopy because when it when
the air flows it sucks in a little bit
but you want to fill most of that space
a very experienced grower an older guy
he said one day if you had a cooler and
you could fill it with beer would you
fill it most of the way to the top with
beer or would you fill that cooler all
the way with beer I'm not even a beer
drinker and that makes sense to me I
want as many beers fit in that cooler
that's just the way you do it so do you
want your grow room to be halfway filled
with buds or do you want to fill that
[ __ ] up with buds the goal will be to
maximize that canopy space so in future
episodes we will talk about trellising
lolli popping will talk about sticks and
cages and cracking stems we will go in
depth and a lot of techniques like that
on ways to fill up your cooler for
maximum production
all right podcast world that is a
podcast for this week ona thank you guys
for
I will be back in a few days with more
fresh content for you I would appreciate
it if you support the show on patreon
you can support the show by going to
www.petland.com
slash grow from your heart all the
information you need to become a patron
will be right there on the screen once
again I owe a huge thank you to
everybody who has contributed to the
patreon and thank you to everyone who
will contribute in the future I would
also appreciate it if you follow me on
social media you can find me on Facebook
search for the girl from your heart
podcast on Twitter it's at G fyh podcast
if you'd like to follow my personal
Twitter it is at Rasta Jeff 420 I also
recommend you follow my Instagram feed
on Instagram I use Irie underscore
genetics check out the IRA genetics
Instagram feed for fine cannabis
photography also you can join me on
Instagram live drop-in instagram live
videos ask cannabis questions and I will
answer your questions right there in the
live feed if you've got a question or if
you'd like to sponsor the podcast or if
you've got a product you'd like me to
review maybe just got something you'd
like to say and you're not into the
social media you can reach me through
email my email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com I would love to
hear from you don't forget to support
our sponsors the hell a dank seed
company you can find them at dank seed
dot store ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls smokers and growers I want to
thank you again for listening to the
girl from your heart podcast I want to
give a huge shout out to the can of
Kratt and until next time take a phat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
welcome to the show podcast world it's
time for episode 372 of the girl from
your heart podcast this episode is
brought to you by the holiday exceed
company if you need new seeds for your
garden I highly recommend the holiday
exceed company and you can find them at
www.steveadubato.org
[Music]
my head spin makes my eyes vibrate makes
it hard to think the banana OG is kind
of more of a mellow thing it's got me
kind of chilled out it's kind of slow
motion it's got my highs nice and heavy
it's got my shoulders nice and chilled
out and I really dig the flavor of the
banana OG so that's what I'm dad and on
today I hope you guys are taking dads or
something delicious I'm not sure if you
can tell but I still have a little bit
of that head cold hanging around I'm
trying to get rid of that I'm not gonna
let it slow me down I am going to
deliver a quality podcast and this
episode I plan to bring you another grow
lesson before we get to the grow lesson
I've got a couple of quick things to
cover I am working on the website of
course I am I read genetics Colorado my
website is I read genetics Colorado calm
we are currently doing some updates
during the process of updating the
website something went completely
freakin wrong and the podcast does not
work from the website anymore all of the
episodes that were up before the update
are still accessible none of the new
things add to the website are posting to
the RSS feed my web guy is working on it
it is the holiday weekend so he has
taken a few days off but I'm sure he
will get back on it as soon as the
weekend is over my point is I know the
website is messed up and I apologize for
not having the episodes out on iTunes
and stitcher as regularly scheduled I
was just recently bragging about not
missing a Monday in five years and now
here I am I've missed the least one
Monday it looks like I may potentially
miss two mondays in a row I do apologize
however the episodes are recorded and
the shows are posted on YouTube so I
have not stopped recording I haven't
stopped doing the shows I'm just unable
to post them to iTunes and stitcher
because of a glitch with my website so
please be patient with me and please
keep listening to the show and please
find the show on youtube if that is your
only option of listening for the next
couple of weeks and also real quick I
want to give a shout out to the guy who
works on the website for me I don't know
if he listens to the show regularly or
at all but hey if you're listening man
big thanks for keeping the website
updated big thanks for all the updates
lately and also big thanks for getting
it fixed when you do get the RSS feed
back in action alright since I'm given
shout outs let's give some shoutouts to
a few of our patreon supporters I owe a
big shout out to Jade how about a big
patreon shout out to grimbo
druid and also a patreon shout-out to
Tanner Martin wick and of course another
shout-out to my friend Mel thank you for
all the patreon support I truly do
appreciate it and if you want to learn
how to become a patron you can do so by
going to www.hsn.com slash grow from
your heart all the information you need
will be right there on the screen and
again thank you for all of the patreon
support all right podcast world I said
earlier this was going to be another
grow lesson so far in my series of grow
lessons we should have plants that are
probably 12 to 14 maybe 16 or 18 inches
tall they are probably in three or five
or maybe seven gallon pots hopefully
they are nice and healthy they have got
a fat root system hopefully their pest
free at this time hopefully you haven't
over or under fertilized them we've
talked a lot about the proper
environment and conditions and feeding
for these plants so I think we know how
to take care of them by now let's talk
about a few ways to improve our
productivity and the vigor of our large
veg plants now none of this stuff is
required none of this stuff is mandatory
these are the little tips and tricks and
bonus things that I do to boost
productivity and boost vigor to kind of
turbocharged the overall performance of
my garden one really easy thing I like
to do to all of my plants to increase
performance is just clean off the crap
on the bottoms of the plants you've got
a stalk coming out of the dirt and then
you've got a few crappy branches coming
off the bottom and then the next couple
of branches will be more substantial and
then you'll have some solid branches if
those very bottom branches are crappy
don't be afraid to remove them if you
feel like they are a waste of growth on
the plant feel free to take them off we
are going to lollipop heavily once we go
into flower so don't be afraid to move
some of the crappy bottom branches if
it's a long healthy branch that has the
potential to reach the canopy level you
can leave it but if it's ugly if it's
droopy if it's sucking up energy and not
going to produce anything that would be
worthwhile feel free to take it off then
that plant can focus its energy moving
up toward the top of the plant where we
want to build that lush
so feel free to take crap off of the
bottom so now we've removed the crappy
bottom branches there are kind of a
waste of energy here is another thing we
can do to the bottom section of our
plant to improve the performance and
move the energy up toward the top
we've still got bottom branches because
we left some of those bottom branches on
the plant the inside bottom branching is
not going to receive much light so what
I like to do is find that branch and
just follow it up and remove any shoots
that I feel like are a waste of space
so you'll having a thick arm coming off
and then off of that you'll have like a
little tiny sub arm coming off those are
the shoots those are on the bottom of
the plant those are a waste of space
those are gonna turn into buds we do not
want to trim that is gonna be fluffy lar
fee useless little crap it is a trimmers
nightmare by removing that crap from the
bottom we direct the energy up toward
the top we can make bigger top chunky
buds those are better for trimmers those
are better for the market those are
better for the consumer
everybody wants those big fat buds so
let's clean off that crap off the bottom
so you've got the main stock coming out
then you've got your bottom to your
bottom four branches follow those
branches up and where you don't see any
light touching those little shoots feel
free to just pinch them or cut them
right off while you're cutting or
pinching or cleaning stuff off of plants
always keep this in mind you can go back
later and take more off but you cannot
glue the leaves and the shoots back on
to the plant so pay attention to what
you're doing but on that bottom section
just pull that crap at the inside right
off of there I go fairly hard on the
bottom parts of the plants I plan on
lolli popping heavily early in flower
anyway so why not pull off a lot of that
crap now and send the energy up toward
the top of the plant now while you're
cleaning the bottoms of the plants keep
in mind that it may be wise to take some
clones before we put these plants into
flower what are you going to grow next
are you growing from seed that you spent
a lot of money on if you paid a lot of
money for those seeds I definitely
recommend you take a clone off of each
seedling and market we're gonna talk
about this in depth in a future episode
but if you've got a plant from seed I
recommend you take a clone from it mark
that plant plant a mark your clone clone
a
go on down the line with every seedling
plant that you've got then grow them out
either grow out the clone or grow out
the original plant and if you've got
something amazing now you have got a
keeper clone of that to keep around
we're gonna talk about Fino hunting
we'll talk about mother plants we're
gonna talk about that sort of stuff in a
future episode but this is something to
think about while we are cleaning the
bottoms of our plants do you want to use
those two bottom branches may make
excellent clones some of those shoots
may have grown big enough to turn into a
clone keep that in mind while you're
cleaning up the bottoms of your plants
now let's talk about another way to
improve the productivity of our plant
and also a great way to score a great
clone from a healthy plant and of course
I'm talking about topping topping our
plant can greatly improve the
performance of our plant if it is done
at the appropriate time and at the
appropriate place in the plant
now when I say appropriate time we can
do this at just about any point in veg
once the plant is large enough the
plants we are talking about are
certainly large enough if we are in
large veg this is prime time for topping
we have to top approximately ten to
fourteen days before we enter the
flowering phase when we top a cannabis
plant our mission is to remove that top
node out of the plant that giant one
that's sticking out of the top making it
look like a Christmas tree we want to
remove that and our goal is to make the
next set of branches become two tops and
that will create competition within the
branches of the plant it will make all
of the branches try to reach up and
become the next top basically somebody
killed the king and now all of those
next soldiers are trying to be the next
king the hormones in the plant will
indicate we're missing a top somebody
needs to take over cannabis has a trait
that is called apical dominance it
really wants one dominant top when you
remove that dominant top the rest of the
tops no there's an opportunity for them
to become that main top so you can top
the plants at various ages and at
various stages let's talk about the
process of doing it let me back up and
talk about doing it find that top branch
where it's too tall trace it down the
way I like to do it I kind of find a
spot where I'm
thinking about cutting it and I bend it
over and I look at the plant I say what
would the plant look like without that
section is that too much to cut off is
that going to be beneficial what is my
goal in topping right now mainly my goal
instead of having one giant top I want
to create sort of a bush so that I can
grow space and not have one giant bud
hitting the light but instead I can have
a four by four section of a bunch of
buds growing in the light instead of
just one by taking out that main top you
create that whole section into a bush so
see which one is gonna cut out and make
the others look like a nice even canopy
you will see it you'll get good at it
it'll take a little bit of trial and
error it'll take some confidence it is
also very strain specific topping an OG
Kush or something like that can be a
real [ __ ] because the nodes are so far
apart that you just make it look like a
Charlie Brown Christmas tree but once it
grows out of that it is going to be
amazing the more sativa dominant stuff
if you top scarlet begonias if you top
storm shadow it makes a beautiful bush
and they go crazy so kind of grab the
top and follow work your way down with
your hand and just kind of look and see
what it would it look like if I took
this off and you'll come to a point
you'll take off one and you'll see two
branches that stick up evenly toward the
top and the two branches and underneath
that almost come right up to that top
section as well you'll have four nice
new tops and you'll say that's what
Rasta Jeff is talking about I want to
make these four tops the tops then just
cut that one out and you'll see exactly
what I've got you're probably gonna
screw up a couple of plants that's how
you learn stuff musicians have to [ __ ]
up songs to learn BMX racers have to
fall on their face to learn
skateboarders get stitches and break
bones to learn luckily we mess up plants
we can grow more plants
it doesn't hurt us that bad when we cut
up a plant the wrong way hopefully
you've got a couple more and you're
gonna learn the cost of cutting that one
plant from what you learn from it is
invaluable so get in there and just play
around with the scissors top some of
them bottom some of them up see what
they do finish them that way you have
some data now keep in mind that data is
very strain specific like I said earlier
if you're topping an OG Kush plant
you're gonna have totally different
results than if you're topping something
like a haze or
more sativa dominant like a golden goat
kind of a thing the growth structure is
just naturally different in those plants
now when you're topping your plant do it
at the intersection where it's going to
encourage that plant the most expansive
growth so if you've got two branches cut
you've got the main stock coming up
you've got a branch coming out and then
maybe an inch up you've got a branch
coming out cut right above that top
branch you don't need to leave anything
hanging off or anything extra cut it
right at the intersection where you want
to encourage the spread you basically
want to take an upside down peace sign
and you want to turn it into a Wye and
those new tops of the Y are going to be
the new two tops of the plant and then
the next two branches hopefully they'll
catch up now that puts me back to why I
said we want to do this at least 10 to
14 days before we go into flower or much
sooner than that if it's an opportunity
when we make that cut we've just cut out
the king like I said earlier we need
time for those hormones to move around
into the plant and that helps us when we
go into flower we get much larger bud
sets if you if you flower too soon after
topping your plants just create little
popcorn buds the hormones haven't moved
around they're not exactly sure what to
do they're not sure where the top should
go so you just get a bunch of little
popcorns so give the plant plenty of
time to recover plenty of time to move
the hormones and plenty of time for it
to decide where the tops are going to be
after topping and before moving your
plants into flower earlier I mentioned
that this would be a good opportunity
for a clone that top you just cut off
should be the most robust hardiest part
of your plant that will make a great
candidate for a clone so why not snag
that up now you've got a big fat healthy
clone for the next crop while you're
increasing the productivity of the
current crop all right so we've covered
two great ways to increase the vigor and
productivity of our plants we've figured
out how to properly move the energy to
the part of the plant we want to grow
you can move it up to the top by taking
stuff off the bottom you can spread it
out by completely eliminating the top
and that process we've also created the
opportunity to create clones now let's
talk about another great technique that
I use in a personal garden I use this in
a breed
program I use this in a large commercial
grow this is something I implement in
almost any grow I get to play in I call
it the pop and twist technique you may
also know it as super cropping it has
got a lot of names it is the same thing
no matter what we call it I like to pop
the stems of the plant I like to kind of
pop their knuckles I don't know if you
can hear that on the microphone I tried
to get it in there that's basically the
sound I am looking for once the plants
are a little bit thicker than a pen or a
pencil maybe a sharpie I like to grab
them right where they come out of the
dirt
I grab the stock kind of firmly with one
hand then I grab it with another hand
right above it and I twist my top hand I
don't twist that hand that's coming out
of the dirt I don't want to twist that
dirt I twist the top hand tour I break
the cellulose of the plant break that
outer structure toward you hear it pop a
little bit it'll go crunch just like my
knuckle did and it'll make a little pop
sound and you'll feel it and you'll be
freaked out the first time it's okay
don't freak out you're doing exactly
what I recommend this will increase
vigor and productivity in a couple of
ways this will be beneficial in a couple
of ways let's talk about that real quick
and we'll talk more about how to do this
throughout the entire plant the first
thing you'll notice when you're popping
the knuckles on these plants is they
will start to make little knuckles on
the branches I feel like these make the
plants more stout more robust so that
when they start to grow buds those
branches can hold up bigger buds bigger
branches bigger buds right that makes
sense you want more support bigger legs
you can lift more right you're stronger
I don't know if that mats out I'm not
kind of a weight lifter guy but if you
got more you can lift more right so you
want something able to support bigger
buds also those bigger stems can
probably feed those bigger flowers
better so you've got more movement
another way this is beneficial is it
will slow down the vertical growth of
the plants they won't get so tall so
quickly because they will be spending a
little bit of their energy on getting
fatter and more robust they'll be short
and stocky which is way beneficial to
almost any grower where most of us are
limited by height in a home grow in a
commercial grow in a giant warehouse
grow most of us are still limited by
height so
having this one tip to control the
height of our plants just a little bit
can be very advantageous later on we're
gonna talk about trellising if you can
use cracking and trellising together you
can really control the height of your
plants and you can really maximize
productivity so those are a few reasons
why I like to track the stems now let's
talk a little bit more about actually
doing it now that I've given you a good
reason why to do this like I said I
grabbed the stick with one hand I
grabbed a stick with another and I just
twist opposite directions and you'll
hear it it will go pop and crunch then
just move up I start with the main stalk
of the plant and I work my way almost
almost 90% of the way of the plant as
long as I can feel it's still crunching
as long as I'm not feeling like I'm
about to rip the top off the plant when
I give it a twist I'll work my way right
up then I go to the bottom branch and
work my way right up the bottom branch
then the next branch and give it a crack
I'll give it a crack I'm looking at the
microphone stand here trying to think
about the distance of cracks I go one
and then it's only four to six inches
apart depending on the size of the plant
I will crack it maybe if it's a tiny
plant if they're short and squat I would
go every three inches if I feel like
that plant could take it most of them
will take it about every four to six
inches without any problems give it a
little crack move up give it a little
crack move up give it a little crack
just do that to every plant in the
garden it will slow down their growth
it'll make them more robust they'll be
more vigorous and you can continue to do
this all the way in to about week three
of flower so if you start it early in
veg you can get a good cracking in there
give them about seven maybe ten days to
heal up go back give them another good
crack throw them into flower as they get
bigger they will recover more quickly
from being busted on so go in there and
give them a good crack on day one a
flower right at the start of the
flowering cycle slow down that stretch a
little bit and then think about it this
way if you crack spot one and then spot
two there's a spot in the middle of that
that you can crack next time so you can
go back in a week and even if they
haven't healed up from all of their
cracking you can crack those middle
spots and make even another little
knuckle another little knurled spot on
your plants don't be afraid to get in
there and do some work on them and bust
them up a little bit they will recover
and they will
really show progress from this I know I
probably sound like I'm crazy because
for the past ten minutes I've been
telling you to cut stuff off of your
plants and break them and bend them and
that's going to increase productivity
but how do you get stronger through
stress through proper training and
that's what we're gonna do to these
plants we're gonna tell them what we
want from them and we're gonna show them
what we expect and they're gonna give it
to us with the proper guidance
speaking of guidance let's work our way
into talking about canopy control
earlier I mentioned that our plants are
apical dominant meaning they want to
grow straight up unfortunately for us as
growers it does not benefit us for the
plants to grow straight up
we need to fill horizontal space we need
to spread them out a little bit we have
several options for encouraging our
plants to spread out our earlier work of
topping them was a great start but we
can go much further than that a very
easy affordable and effective way to
spread out our plants a little bit is by
using sticks you can get bamboo sticks
at the local gross store for very cheap
I like to put about four sticks per pot
and I like to put them toward the outer
edge of the pot don't go too far in
because you've got a lot of root
development there you don't want to go
shoving a bamboo stick right through a
bunch of roots so go out toward the edge
of the pot put the stick in there if
your plants are gonna grow six feet tall
get a six-foot stick if your plants are
only gonna grow three feet tall get a
three-foot stick you don't want a stick
too big tor you can't lower the light
close enough to the canopy so get the
appropriate sized stick put three or
four five or six of them in the pot
depending on how many giant floppy
branch branches you've got then you can
just pull those big branches down just a
little bit and attach them to the sticks
now instead of just having them going
straight up you've kind of pulled them
down a little bit now they're probably
one or two maybe three inches shorter
depending on how far you pull them down
pull them down and a fix them to those
sticks now you're doing a couple of
things you're making the plant overall
shorter and you're also widening the
plant up to let some light get into that
inner part of the plant where you don't
have to clean off as much of that crap
in the inside more of the light can
penetrate in there and you will get more
production from the inside part of the
plant
now these sticks will also work for
another purpose when those buds start to
develop and get fat and big those
dicks will support your buds you're
going to need something to hold up the
big buds so now is the time to think
about it let's work that into our canopy
control and also our plan for supporting
our buds so sticks is the easiest most
affordable option if you've got a small
grow if you've got a homegrown sticks
are probably the most economical if
you've got several plants a bunch of
sticks can become a pain in the ass in a
commercial environment I wouldn't even
mess with sticks in a commercial
environment you may want to start
working with tomato cages you need to
get the tomato cages on the plants
before they get too big I usually like a
tomato cage with about a 16 inch top
sometimes I will cut the very bottom
ring off of the tomato cage right flip
it upside down right where that bottom
ring is cut it off you've just made it a
little bit shorter but it's also a
little bit wider you can customize them
for your situation so slide the tomato
cage over the plant
spread the plant out nice and wide let
it spread is why it is it will go
encourage it to spread out if you need
to pull some of the branches out of the
cage pull it out of the cage and as it
grows it'll work itself up and when it
gets real tall put the branch back into
the cage or use those runners up the
side the side supports and you can
always a fix
the branches to those side supports by
using a bread tie or a twisty tie or
some sort of garden supply twist I there
are thousands of options for that get
creative I've used a bunch of different
things we don't need to be too specific
I use zip ties in most cases but don't
go too tight so if you got your tomato
cage on your plant the branches are
falling out and gaining support from the
outer perimeter of the tomato cage maybe
you've worked some of the branches up
the side of that tomato cage maybe you
pulled some of the branches down and
spread them out by using those outer
rings of the tomato cage the tomato cage
give us a lot of creative options for
controlling the canopy of our plant
while at the same time providing support
for our tall heavy buds now if you're
using a tomato cage and you did not top
your plant which is just fine that is
always an option you do not have to top
the plants a lot of people like that one
big glory but at the top if you're going
for that glory bud and you were using a
tomato cage you still may need a stick
to support that giant bud if you grow a
big fat
so don't be afraid to make them work
together you can have a tomato cage with
a stick holding up that giant bud in the
middle again if you're gonna put a stick
in a giant pot I would kind of recommend
putting it toward the outer edge and
then angling it toward the center if you
need support in the center I don't like
to Ram a bamboo stake right into the
root zone that just feels rude to me if
you want it to be right in the middle
because you've got some kind of OCD or
that's where you need to do it you can
do it but just you'll feel it when you
go through those roots and it won't feel
right so those are two very effective
methods of controlling your canopy and
also supporting the large branches and
being prepared for having large buds I
know I kind of glazed over those two
methods those are things you're going to
have to perfect and work on it's going
to be things you have to put your hands
on to learn how to do it it's kind of an
art there will be things that you learn
when you're doing it it will work
perfectly for your situation it would
not work for the next guy the sticks are
really easy because you can just stick
as many sticks into a pot as you need I
mean I've seen people go completely
excessive try not to be too crazy but
you can stick as many sticks into a pot
of soil as you need to support as many
branches branches as you need and you
can use fuzzy sticks or bread ties or
zip ties whatever you need to fix those
branches to those sticks however you
need it's a little harder to lower the
canopy that way but you can get big
branch support that way really easily
the tomato cages
you can use the zip ties or the twisty
ties and you've got round circles to
work with you can use those to keep the
plants down you can bend the branches
underneath the rings of the tomato cage
or you can use those to support the big
buds you've got a lot of options there
to work with but you're gonna have to
play with it to figure it out I can walk
you so far through it but it's going to
be strain dependent situational
dependent but those are very versatile
tools to work with and I'm sure you'll
find some use now let me quit rambling
and talk about one of my favorite
methods of canopy control which is using
trellis netting also known as scrog
netting and of course strog SC ROG just
means screen of green we're using a
screen to create a nice green canopy
let's talk about creating a screen of
green the number one most common mistake
I see people make when they are setting
up their screen
or their trellis netting for their
screen of green or for their canopy
control as they put the netting way too
loose it needs to be tighter you want
that stuff really tight you want it
almost scary tight you want a wide
attention on there you don't want those
squares you don't want the net to move
at all you want those squares to stay
right in place because that is what is
going to control the shape of your plant
if those things move the plant moves I
like them tight nice and firm like a
guitar string so let's talk more about
the netting now that I've already
pointed out the number one mistake let's
say we're setting up a net in a five by
five 10 it's really easy to set them up
in a tent they've already got the poles
if you don't have poles or something to
fix it to you're going to need to design
some sort of system you can attach it to
the wall a lot of people will get a
five-gallon bucket from Lowe's or Home
Depot they will fill it up with quikrete
and then they will stick a six foot tall
PVC pole into their sticking straight up
now you've got a nice vertical pole that
you can work with to attach your net to
and that will hold a lot of weight you
can probably get it tight enough with
that five-gallon bucket filled with
cement that'll be enough weight to be
able to pull those screens super tight
so get yourself four buckets fill them
up with the quikrete put a six-foot pole
in each one now you make a little square
now you can make just about any type of
length or width of shape you need to put
your trellis netting
I think they sell it in five by five
squares five by ten squares if you want
to go commercial-grade you can get it in
much larger segments sections whatever
the word you want to use right there you
can get it in a commercial environment
I recommend the six-foot wide commercial
greenhouse tables I have found a six
foot wide roll of plastic trellis
netting it works beautifully for that
application at a six feet wide and it is
I think 75 or 120 feet long and it is
one roll so you just put it up on top of
the trellis you got one guy on one side
one guy on the other and it's on a roll
so you just walk and it you zip tie one
end of it down one and if it down and
you walk the length you need to be he's
hip tie the other end a zip tie the
other end and he cut it off and now the
trellis net is up yeah of course you got
to go back through and tighten it by
using more zip ties but that's almost
kind of fun once you've got it put up
that easily so the long roll
are amazing they get a little bit heavy
but if you've got two big dudes I'm 65
my buddy Brian he was six-foot something
we just grab it lift it just above plant
height walk right down the rows stretch
out a long enough piece to cover that
whole row zip tie it at the end and cut
our section off we'd have another guy
following behind us and he would put zip
ties in place to keep it real tight and
it would take us just a few minutes to
get each row done so you've got to start
by spreading out your trellis netting
that's always fun if it comes folded up
in that little baggy it is such a [ __ ]
to get that undone good luck you look
like Spiderman attacked you in [ __ ]
one you're gonna be there for a few
minutes getting that unfolded the bigger
than that the longer it takes don't get
frustrated go smoke a dad and no you
know what don't smoke a dad because when
you get all stone and you're trying to
look at that netting that [ __ ] doesn't
work for your face so just unfold that
and then once we get it put up we'll go
take some tabs so unfold the trellis
netting the best you can it's gonna take
you a few minutes get it put up on
whatever poles you've got available I
said we're gonna work in a 5x5 ten
hopefully you bought a 5x5 section of
netting it may be too big you may need
to go in a square you may not need to
use that outer square you may need to go
one or two squares into that grid to
make it fit tight enough you don't have
to necessarily use every square of that
netting we want it tight more than we
want the amount of squares so get that
net up there tight use a bunch of zip
ties go excessive if you need it too we
want that thing fairly tight then lower
it down onto the plant canopy you'll
watch the plants kind of Bend you want
to just keep going just kind of bend
them down just a little bit not too far
maybe like three or four inches they'll
Bend they'll be okay if you see
something that's about to crack of
course grab it and give it a hand the
idea here is to actually lower the
height of all of the plants and we were
going to use that net to control the
height of the plants don't worry because
we're gonna go back and manually adjust
each branch by hand and work it into
this net correctly but right now we just
kind of want to lower it down and watch
that canopy just become even now you can
see how this works we have instead of
one giant bud here one long branch here
one giant but on a long branch over here
now we've got a nice even space to work
with we want to fill all that five by
five net with a bunch of small bud sites
that will actually turn into more
productivity than one giant bud
one giant butt here that are trying to
touch the light we're fighting those
from getting too hot getting burnt
getting crispy and then we've got a
bunch of buds down here that aren't
getting enough light instead we've got a
nice five by five screen of green of his
beautiful even buds so let's talk about
how to work these branches into this net
to create this desired canopy working a
section of plants into a trellis net is
a bit of an art and it will take some
experience to perfect it think of it
sort of like weaving we want to weave
these plants that want to go vertical we
want to weave them into the net to
encourage them to go horizontally now
almost no matter what we do to these
plants other than kill them they're
going to try to grow up because earlier
we spoke of that hormone that gives them
apical dominance so we are going to need
to stay on top of canopy control in this
trellis system
the idea is to fill each square of that
trellis net with a branch that will
develop into a substantial bud sight the
way to start that process is to train
these plants to spread wide instead of
tall so we use this first layer of
netting to actually spread the plants
out now what we have to do as the plants
grow is they will try to pop up out of
the net we need to go in there everyday
and grab those branches that tried to
get away and just push them back under
that next piece of net so as soon as
they're long enough to go under net
underneath the next section just weave
them right underneath there and what
will happen is you will develop long
arms that fill up the entire space and
when we flip it to flower all of those
branches will develop bud sites that
will fill up each square of that trellis
netting now instead of having plants
that just grow big giant buds and grow
up into the light and are really good
for pictures we are actually producing a
large crop by utilizing the entire five
by five canopy space now this will take
some practice to figure out exactly what
I'm saying some of you are going to try
to force those plants down too much
somebody that taught me a lot of tips on
trellis work will tell you give it a
[ __ ] chance you've got to give it
some more to grow up and win the tips of
the branches like to go up give them a
chance to win but don't be scared to get
in there and bend them down now
something that is hard to convey
you just audio without any sort of
visual is you may think that to get this
branch the tip of this branch under this
net that you may need to bend it at risk
type I'm showing myself I'm comparing
the microphone stand to my wrist the
microphone stand is horizontal my wrist
is growing up like a plant
I want to tuck this my wrist underneath
this piece of trellising instead of
grabbing at my wrist and bending there
and tucking that part under I would
actually go down to elbow height to my
elbow joint and pop it down there and
bend it underneath the trellis at that
height that gives me a lot more room for
when that plant starts growing
vertically it's gonna grow out
horizontally because of gravity for a
little while the tip will start growing
up and it's gonna take it a little bit
longer to grow up out of that net again
don't be afraid to crack it lower than
you think you need to is what I'm trying
to say hopefully that gave you enough
different explanations to try to catch
on to what I'm saying but if you think
you need to crack it here to get it
underneath the net that's right here go
a little lower so you've got more
bending room to work with and you've
also got more room for future growth you
guys trellising and canopy work is an
art but when you get good at it it will
drastically improve productivity and
will also make the garden much easier to
work in because it's much more organized
and you don't have that one giant bud
that's trying to grow into the light
which is so photogenic and it's so
beautiful to have but it's also such a
pain in the ass because that's the one
bud you were working your whole garden
setup around so you will learn how to
weave your plants into this nap
perfectly you will adapt your own style
you'll I'm sure you're going to the
Internet to look at pictures of how to
do it already you'll see a lot of great
stuff on there you will also see a lot
of trellis nets that were not filled
sufficiently before the plants were
flipped into flower fill that [ __ ] out
it takes a little bit of time it takes
more work but it is much more rewarding
than just growing that one glory bud so
if you're going to use the screen to
spread them out make sure you fill up
that canopy before you flip now I also
recommend a second layer of trellis
netting I probably would put that one
depending on the power of your light
depending on your genetics I would
probably put my second net somewhere
between 6 and 12 inches above that first
now the bottom net will fill up you'll
leave it all in and it will get full now
you want to let those branches start
drawing up into that second net you want
to fill it up Tori you've got one branch
coming out of each of those bottom
squares and those will grow up into the
top squares as soon as they hit the top
squares you want a flower now you've got
a nice six to twelve inch section of
just rows of buds just rows of branches
sticking straight up I would almost
lollipop and bottom and D foliate almost
everything underneath that first net
that all gets cleaned off all that Laura
fee stuff the canopy is the lights not
gonna penetrate the canopy far enough to
make that worth anything
I generally clean all that off so that
bottom net is there to spread them out
and give them control you want to spread
the plant that would be growing five
feet tall straight up we've got it three
feet tall but it's also spread five by
five feet wide so we're trying to fill
in all that net space then we're gonna
let it grow a little bit vertically out
of that until it kind of gets close to
that next net then we're gonna flower
all those branches that are sticking
straight up are going to turn into big
fat buds that will grow into that second
net that second net at that point is
going to work as a support it's only
going to be there to hold up all of your
giant buds quite often in a commercial
environment I've had to use a triple
trellis and sometimes we have considered
a fourth that's all going to pinned on
your genetics and what kind of lights
you're using of course we're using
things like a rise underneath Gavita
lighting in a commercial environment we
were getting serious growth if you're in
a tent you're only going to need the
spread net and then the one net up top
for support now if you want to use the
trellis netting and you don't want to
work it into the net as far if you just
want to use it more for a spread and not
kind of create the scrog you can do that
you don't have to work them as far you
can just put the net on and spread them
out try to get one stick per branch if
you can try not to overcrowd anything
the idea is just to spread it out you
kind of want to spread them make them
shorter than they were tall you want to
use more of that vertical space somebody
taught us a long time ago if you've got
a cooler do you just want to put one
layer of beer in that cooler or do you
want to fill that whole cooler up with
year that's kind of what we're trying to
do with our canopy we don't just want a
couple of beers touching the white we
don't want to make a beer tower we want
to knock all those beers down and put
them in one nice a case just like they
were sold in because that's how they
stack the best that's how you can fill
it the best I'm not even a beer drinker
and I still want to fit as many beers as
we can in a cooler also I should
recommend an article I read a long time
ago by an author named Eric Bix ax the
article was called growing on the grid
and it was exactly on this subject it
talked about maximizing your growth
potential by utilizing the horizontal
space not just the vertical space that
our plants try to create so one thing I
should mention is that you will not be
able to move these plants once you put
the trellis net on so you've got to do
this in whatever room these plants will
be flowering in I started the example by
using a five by five grow tent so in
most cases we would vention that five by
five put up the sprog then flowered in
that five by five not a big deal if you
are vegging and flowering in a different
environment you will have to veg them
drag them to the flowering room try to
put that trellis up on day one spread
them out nice and wide you're not going
to be able to work them in too much but
you can kind of bend and manipulate the
plants a little bit without causing any
problems use the cracking technique I
talked about earlier grab the branch
give it a little bit of a twist and bend
it over just a little bit you'll be able
to create a little knuckle there also
create a nice smooth bed you can control
the plant aim it any direction you want
move it over to the section of the
trellis you need it just be very gentle
with them give them several days to
recover before you go back in and crack
them again this is pretty much how we're
forced to do it in a commercial
environment because we don't veg and
flower in the same room we usually have
one large veg area and multiple
flowering rooms so that we can keep our
petrol cycles going in a commercial
environment one of my major goals is to
harvest and refill a room in the same
day I know that doesn't sound like a big
challenge but imagine if you've got 300
plants in one room you've got a bunch of
trellis netting it takes half of the day
to get it cut down then you got to clean
the room spotless then try to refill it
that's always fun
then we throw the net on then we spend
the rest of the day just spreading those
plants out and adjusting that net tore
those plants aren't too angry with us so
that is my long sigh
Trek rambley talk on sticks cages and
trellis netting and canopy control I've
got a couple more quick things to cover
on this list of ways to improve our
productivity while in veg the next thing
on my list is integrated pest management
and scouting we should probably be
applying a preventive pesticide regimen
to our plants at this time if you're
going to use a spray application now is
the time to get started if you're going
to use predator bugs now is the time to
order them and get them prepared so that
we have a nice colony before we go into
flower one thing a lot of growers
overlook at this stage of the game is
manually scouting for pests one of your
best tools and finding bugs in your grow
is your own eyes spend a little time
walking through the garden and just
looking for pests or signs of pests
nature really likes to give us hints
that there are problems in our garden
every pest that comes in gives us some
kind of a warning if you were on top of
your game you've got some yellow sticky
traps hanging up and you were checking
those on a daily basis they will give
you a fair warning that you've got bugs
coming in you know how they'll tell you
there will be bugs stuck to the yellow
card how much more obvious can it get so
check the yellow sticky traps then walk
every row every few feet reach into the
canopy and grab a leaf pull it right off
flip it upside down look at it do you
see any bugs on the underside of the
leaf do you see any eggs on the
underside of the leaf look at the top
side of the leaf do you see any
stippling that is spider mite damage do
you see any honeydew that is thrip
damage do you see anything that just
doesn't look right that could be a sign
of over feeding under feeding or pH
problems pay attention to the plants and
they will tell you when something is
starting to go wrong and you won't need
to panic
so scout on a daily basis walk through
the grow look at the plants look for
might damage look for thrip damage go
smack the pots just give a couple pots
of good smack does anything fly out if
so you've got fungus gnats those are
really easy to treat if you find them
early scout for bugs teach all of your
helpers to scout for bugs
look for spider mite webbing also look
for powdery mildew look for anything
that just doesn't look right if you were
a crew leader teach people how to
properly report the things that they see
so they know when to come to you some
people say how doesn't look like a big
deal teach them what is a big deal and
what is not a big deal
so always be on the lookout for bugs
always be scouting and know what you're
looking for you're looking for mites and
mite damage which is webbing stippling
while you're looking for thrip [ __ ]
you're looking for thrip honeydew that
glazy stuff on the lower leaves that's
from your thrips when you tap the pots
those little black things that fly up
those are fungus gnats when you shake
the leaves those little white bugs that
fly out those are white flies be aware
of what you're looking for and
constantly be looking for them healthy
plants will be much more vigorous and
much more productive than plants that
are fighting off insects also scouting
is free it doesn't cost you anything to
walk through your grow and look for bugs
you should enjoy it put on a podcast put
on the grill from your heart podcast
there on the dude grows put on some Joe
Rogan and just stroll through the garden
and go see what you can find a day go
find the problem chances are there's
something wrong you just need to go find
it
alright I'll quit ranting about IPM
hopefully I have inspired you to go look
for bugs in your garden you know what
else is free it will really improve the
quality of your garden overall is
note-taking write down everything you do
that way when something goes wrong you
know what to blame it on and you know
what not to do next time I've done an
entire episode on journaling I'm not
gonna rant too much on that right now
I've got one more thing to talk about
and then we're gonna wrap up this
podcast because my throw is starting to
burn out another way we can increase
productivity and vigor of our veg plants
is to augment the co2 levels in our grow
room the ambient co2 level in your
environment is probably hovering
somewhere between 300 and 400 particles
per million that is just about the
standard on earth and my last research
depends on where you are your elevation
what kind of city you're in but it's
somewhere between 300 and 400 particles
per million our plants would prefer
somewhere around a thousand particles
per million vacant take up to 1,200
maybe 1500 I've even seen
I'll push them closer to 2,000 particles
per million of co2 and the plants just
explode with vigorous growth now there
are several ways that you can increase
the co2 in your room one thing I need to
mention once you start increasing the
amount of co2 in your grow room
environment it is very unhealthy for the
plants to let the co2 levels decline
past what you have now increased it too
so if you start boosting it to a
thousand you either need to keep it at a
thousand or increase through flower your
plant is expecting this co2 as a new
food source it is now feeding itself
like it's got another food source you
have now put your plant into another
level of high performance it's expecting
to get that high performance fuel it's
adjusted its diet accordingly if you cut
off that co2 that extra co2 it will not
be feeding itself properly you will
start seeing nutrient burn so make sure
you keep up on your co2 habit if you
start that habit and also if you run out
and the plants start acting a little
funny that is probably what is causing
it as they're still craving that co2
they're still trying to readjust their
metabolism because they're still on that
high performance mode and they're not
sure what to do yet so that was my last
tip for increasing performance and
productivity and vigor of our veg plants
I shared a lot of my dirty secrets a lot
of the things that I use in my personal
grows a lot of things that I use in the
commercial grows I hope you learned
something from my talk today I want to
thank you guys again for listening if
you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
and you would like to make a financial
contribution to the show I would
appreciate your support and you can do
so by going to patreon.com slash grow
from your heart all the information you
need to become a patron will be right
there on the screen and again I do
appreciate all of the patreon support I
would also appreciate it if you follow
me on social media you can find me on
Facebook simply search for the girl from
your heart podcast on Twitter it's at G
fyh podcast if you'd like to follow my
personal twitter feed it's at Rasta Jeff
420 if you've got something to say and
you're not into social media you can
reach me through email my email address
is grow from your heart at hotmail.com
and I would love to hear from you don't
forget that the podcast is available on
YouTube
I will get the iTunes and stitcher feed
corrected very soon don't forget to
visit our sponsor that he'll a dank seed
company at dank seed dot store I'll be
back in just a few days with a fresh new
episode I want to thank you guys again
for listening I want to give a huge
shout out to my buddy Jesse James and
until next time take a phat dab and give
your mom a hug for me welcome to the
show cannabis community it's time for
episode 374 of the girl from your heart
podcast this episode of the show is
brought to you by the hella dank seed
company if you need new seeds for your
garden I highly recommend the hell a
dank seed company and you can find them
at www.ge.com I know what I'm smoking I
just took a gigantic dab of sour Klem
ambrosia the label says it has 71 point
1 percent THC and a total of eighty five
point seven percent cannabinoids it does
not have much more information on the
label here this came from our friends at
apothecary farms in Pueblo that's right
apothecary has recently opened a Pueblo
location so make sure you check that out
but today I picked up the sour clam
ambrosia I think it is Sour Diesel and
clementine it's got a really sweet
delicious orange e citrusy Clementine
aroma followed by a funky Sour Diesel
lis just nasty aroma in the background
and I say nasty but I mean it in the
best way it is delicious it is pungent
so it's a little sweet it's a little
sour and then when you dab it it goes
straight to the brain and makes your
eyes open wide up it makes you talk a
lot it makes you real rambly so I think
this will be great podcast dabs shout
out to our friends and Apothecary farms
and an extra big shout out to the pueblo
crew i'm really digging this batch of
sour Klem ambrosia all right you guys
let's jump into a podcast I want to do
another grow lesson I've been doing a
long series of grow lessons if you're a
new listener I suggest you go back to at
least episode 351 and start on the grow
lesson series if you feel like you're
caught up welcome to the grow lessons
today we are going to do a before flower
checkup so far in my grow lessons we
should have healthy happy veg plants
that are in their final finishing pots I
suggested 3 5 or 7 gallon pots if you
want to go larger you do it your way it
is your grow
hopefully you've topped these plants
you've got a nice canopy going hopefully
you've got a big fat healthy root system
going we're aiming for healthy happy
plants that are thriving hopefully we
don't have any bugs hopefully you
haven't over fertilized hopefully you
haven't had any pH issues hopefully we
haven't had any environmental problems
that we didn't expect hopefully
everything's going well and you've got
big fat healthy plants that are almost
ready to flower they're probably about
knee-high at this point maybe a little
bit taller depending on what kind of
lights you're using what kind of
genetics you're working with how often
you've been feeding them what kind of
treatment you've been giving them our
plants are probably getting large enough
to consider putting them into flower
very soon
before we go into flower I feel like
there are a few important points we
should cover so let's go over my before
flower checkup as it gets close to
flower time one of the first things I
think about is do I have clones
do you have clones for the next run do
you want to be self-sufficient if so you
need to create clones for your next run
before you put your plants in the flower
I don't recommend taking clones from
flowering plants some people will do it
some people will teach you how to do it
that is not my style I highly recommend
that you get your clones from your
vegging plants so before you put your
plants into flower
do you have clones do you have a way to
supply plants for your next cycle if you
plan on growing from seed again or if
you plan on purchasing new clones from a
friend or a dispensary or however you
get your clones that's cool
if you're trying to be self-sufficient
now is the time to think about making
clones from your current plants now if
you decide that you want to be
self-sufficient you've got a couple of
options you may want to designate one of
your clones as a mother plant
here's the idea behind a mother plant a
mother plant is a clone of a plant that
we have grown and tested and we know is
reliable we know that that plant is a
female we know that it puts off a good
harvest weight we know that it is potent
we know that it tastes good and we
hopefully have learned that it is
pathogen and pest resistant so we've got
a reliable strain that we want to keep
around in the garden and the way we do
that is just by keeping it in a
vegetative stage perpetually and then we
can take clones from it as needed the
way you keep that mother plant in a
vegetative stage is by leaving it under
at least 18
hours of light everyday for mother
plants sometimes I would recommend 20 on
and for off maybe for stubborn mother
plants I may even go all the way up to
24 hours on we've talked a little bit
about that in previous episodes I've
also done a full episode about mother
plants I suggest you check out episode
315 for a full breakdown of mother
plants now if you don't have room in
space for an extra plant maybe you just
can't have that extra plant because of
your plant count because of state laws
another option is to clone off of your
veg plants perpetually a lot of people
will say that will create something we
used to call genetic drift I do not
believe in that if the plants are
healthy I've done a full Episode on that
as well let's get back on track the idea
of taking clones from your veg plants is
very simple you've got veg plants
they're about to go into flower right
before you take them into the flower
room take a couple of clones off of each
of your veg plants if you have faith in
your clone taking skills and you don't
have room for an extra mother plant this
is an ideal way to do things again some
people may claim that this will result
in genetic drift I do not believe in
genetic drift I don't believe in it so
much that I have changed my vocabulary
to where I call what is known as genetic
drift to regenerative mutation I've done
a full Episode on genetic drift if you'd
like to learn more about it I recommend
you listen to the episode and that's
episode number 343 and it's actually
titled genetic drift I suggest you give
it a listen and understand why we now
call it regenerative mutation so the
point of that rant is to make sure that
you have got clones for your next run if
you don't have a supplier a provider or
a source for your next batch of clones
it may be really advantageous to take a
few clones start vegging them out so
that way you've got another crop lined
up before you even have this one
finished if you really want to max
productivity of your grow you'll start
running what is known as a perpetual
grow where you use two spaces you've got
a veg space you've got a flowering space
as soon as that flowering crop is done
you cut it down you clean the room you
reset the room and you drag a set of
flowering plants right back in there and
you never miss a beat that room never
gets a break so you're always on top of
production which means you always have
to have a supply of clones so you'll
have veg plants you'll cut a few clones
off of them
cut down your flowering plants you clean
up that room drag those veg plants right
into there and then you'll start growing
those little clones up into the next
batch there'll be your veg plants you
have to top them you have to train them
you've got a full nine weeks to get them
as big as you need them and get them
prepared for the next run so when that
flowering crop gets done that you've got
in the flowering room you cut it down
clean it up drag those veg plants right
in there but before you do that you take
a few clones so that you can keep the
cycle going the idea is to create a
perpetual cycle for yourself so you're
always self-sufficient you never have to
bring anything in from outside that way
you can keep the grow clean that way you
know if you get any bugs or any pests
it's your fault you can't blame anybody
else but it really limits the
opportunities to bring in problems and
it also helps you develop a relationship
with one strain if you run a perpetual
grow with just one maybe two strains max
you can really dial those strains in you
can build a relationship with them and
then you can get them to reach their
full potential there are several ways to
do perpetual grows you can do it by
swapping the whole room you can do it by
having part of the room harvest every
couple of weeks I've done a full Episode
on that but I do plan to read to it in
the future for a six plant count because
Colorado is now limited to six plants
for recreational or medical patients so
I will do a revised perpetual grow
episode based on a six plant count if
you're interested in listening to the
current or maybe the old scheduling a
perpetual grow episode that is episode
number 73 I think it is a great episode
I put a lot of time and effort into
creating that episode so episode 73 all
about creating a perpetual grow alright
let me get myself back on track my point
is to make sure you have got either a
source for clones or clones for your
next run and also it is always a good
idea to think about becoming more
self-sufficient and you can do so by
creating a perpetual grow now the next
thing on my checklist that I would think
about in this brand new grow room that
we just recently built is do we have any
light leaks do we have grow lights
leaking out into the outside and do we
have outside lights leaking into the
inside this is very important to find
out before we go into the flower phase
we need to go in that grow room and turn
off the grow lights and
sit in there for fifteen or twenty
minutes and let your eyes adjust to the
total darkness and see if you see any
light at all in your flowering room if
you can see any light that is too much
you should not be able to see your hand
in front of your own face it needs to be
completely dark I've done an episode
called total darkness check that one out
also any light leaks in the flowering
phase are going to cause your plants
problems you're either going to get no
flowering at all you're going to get
slow flowering or you're going to get
hermaphrodites you'll get plants that
will start to flower and they'll never
finish or you just may get crazy weird
mutated plants because of an odd light
leaked so go in the grow room turn off
all the grow lights and just sit there
for a few minutes put your phone away
don't have any light making your eyes do
weird things just let there be total
darkness let your eyes adjust and if you
see any light you need to correct it you
need some of that silver foil tape or
maybe you need to fill the gaps with
some caulk and cover it up with some
duct tape just seal up all of those
light leaks now if your grow room is on
an exterior wall meaning that wall is
next to the outside or if there is a lot
of activity on the opposite side of the
wall of what you are growing I suggest
you go in your grow room and turn off
the grow lights during either the
sunshine hours or the busy hours of that
room and see if any of the light from
either the Sun or that adjacent room are
leaking into your grow room during their
busy hours if your grow room has a
window and the sun is shining on that
window and the curtains aren't thick
enough to block out that Sun or whatever
you've put over that window is not thick
enough to block out that sunlight we
need to know that before we go into the
flowering phase the Sun may come up an
hour before your grow lights come on
they may start getting a full hour of
sunlight coming through that window that
you're unaware of and that's going to
disrupt their flowering cycle so go in
there and check it all hours and see if
you are getting total darkness
especially the hours you plan on putting
your plants in their night cycle make
sure that room is actually dark and if
it's not correct it now the next thing
we need to do is the opposite we need to
go outside and make sure that none of
our grow room lights are leaking to the
outside especially if you're running
your grow lights during the outside
night cycle you were lighting up the
outside neighborhood with your grow
lights those grow lights are going to
bring unwanted attention you will bring
thieves and law enforcement so make sure
you're not leaking any light out of your
grow room now is also a good time to
start thinking about when am I going to
run my flowering cycle do you want the
lights on when it's dark outside do you
want the lights on when it's light
outside electricity is cheaper during
off-peak hours which means when all the
business is closed and everybody goes
home electricity gets cheaper you can
look on your bill and find out when peak
and off-peak hours are since electricity
is more affordable at off-peak hours
many growers will choose to run their
lights during those hours also when the
Sun is not up we don't have to try to
keep the room cool with the grow lights
and the Sun competing against us when
the Sun Goes Down it automatically gets
a little bit cooler outside you can fire
up your grow lights and you don't have
as much heat to deal with if you're in a
place that gets really cold you can run
those grow lights at night and it will
really help keep your house warm if
you've got a small house and you run the
ducting right and you plan properly I
know several East Coast growers that
used to keep their apartments warm by
setting up a four or six hundred watt
light in the winter it would kick out a
small winter crop of super potent
cannabis out of their very small
apartment and they would also use that
same light to keep themselves warm so
there's a very efficient way to do
things back in the day so now is a good
time to start thinking about when you're
going to run your lights in your
flowering room you probably have to go
to work part of the day do you want
those lights to come on right when you
get home from work do you want those
lights to come on so you can work on the
plants before you go to work you've got
a lot of things to plan and think about
now I suggest you work on the plants
after work because you don't want to go
to work smelling like dank most people
work a day job nowadays so you're gonna
go to work and then you'll get off
hopefully in the evening come home work
on the plants that works out really well
because you are now on off-peak
electricity hours and it is nighttime so
you're not fighting that heat you don't
have to run as much electricity so you
get off work come home work on the
plants then you can take a nice shower
then you don't stink for work next day
and nobody knows if you're growing
cannabis if you were in a place you need
to keep it on the down-low
all right and since I'm talking about
being careful and keeping it on the
down-low do you have a carbon filter set
up as your filtration in place are you
ready for a stinky crop of flowers in
just a few weeks these plants are going
to start stinking very heavily you may
get a nice aroma around 20 days in
depending on your genetics and what
you're using for nutrients and the
airflow in your room now is the time to
order a carbon filter if you haven't
already you need to get that set up you
need to get it in place and you need to
start controlling the aroma leaving your
grow space now I need to back up and
cover one thing that I overlooked when I
was talking about light leaks when you
were using vented lights which means you
have got a light with glass between the
bulb and the plant canopy and that's all
sealed up in there and it's got a duct
coming off of one end and off of the
other and you're blowing a blower over
it to get that heat from the light out
of the grow space a lot of people will
run that ducting to the outside of the
house they'll run it out of a window
just to make it go outside of the house
somehow a lot of times the sunshine will
reflect write down that ducting and come
into your light reflector and work just
like a light you were channeling that
light down that ducting right into your
grow space if you are not doing that
while the lights are on you were
lighting up the plants and disrupting
your night cycle if you were using
ducted hoods and you were running that
to the outside of the house you may need
to adjust the duct to where the light
does not make it into your grow room
unfortunately the inside of that ducting
is quite often made with a very
reflective material you're probably
going to have to give it a lot of bends
or you'll have to create a baffle at the
end of it to where the light is not
allowed to even enter down that ducting
another option is to get a can of flat
black spray paint and spray paint the
inside as far as you can make that spray
paint go just put a nice little black
layer in there and take that reflective
layer off and that will prevent the
light from getting in there as much you
still may need to make a bend you may
need to put some sort of light baffle
over it but please check
and see if the light is coming through
your ducted hoods and disrupting your
night cycle the sunshine will make it so
far down that ducting you will be amazed
and just one little speckle of sunlight
will completely disrupt your flowering
cycle if you think the plants are in the
dark and they're getting that one little
pinprick of sunlight they're not in the
dark and also take a quick look at all
of the equipment in your grow room does
your air conditioner have blue and red
lights on it is there something in the
grow room that's illuminating a blue
display if you have any lights in there
you need to put some tape or some sort
of a flap over it so that light does not
disrupt your flowering cycle the only
color of light that is acceptable during
the night cycle is a green light and
there are still situations where I have
seen those green lights cause problems
with people's plants by running that
green light too much during a dark cycle
I would prefer it be completely dark in
your grow room there's nobody in there
the plants are sleeping we don't want
any light make it as dark as you can get
it you want it scary dark and then a
little bit darker you don't want to be
able to see your hand in front of your
face when you're touching your nose
that's how dark we need it
again I've done an episode called total
darkness so give that one a listen if
you don't understand why total darkness
is so important in our indoor grow
environment all right the next thing on
my pre flower checklist is can you
correctly identify females males and
hermaphrodites if you are running from
seed especially you have got the option
to run into females males or
hermaphrodites you need to be able to
identify these very early if you find a
male in the garden it needs to be cold
immediately if you come across a
hermaphroditic plant early in flower you
need to know what that looks like so you
can get it out of the grow room before
it causes you problems your plants are
going to start showing sex somewhere
around 10 days into flower by day 12 or
14 it will be really obvious if you've
got male or female plants by day 12 or
14 your female plants will be able to
receive pollen from the male plants if
you're not paying attention
sometimes by day 10 or 12 a male plant
can open up and start dropping pollen
now your whole crop is pollinated
everything is going to have seeds in it
and you didn't even know because you
weren't paying attention so before we
get to this risky phase open up some
books do some Google searches and learn
to identify a female cannabis plant
learn to confidently identify a male
cannabis plant and learn how to identify
a plant this shows both sexes in the
same plant in the next episode I plan to
talk about Fino hunting and selecting a
mother plant from that Fino hunt in that
episode I will also include a talk about
sexing our cannabis plants it is very
important at this phase in this stage of
the game so we need to know how to
confidently identify males and females I
will be able to provide you detailed
descriptions but I recommend you look
online for pictures of males and females
of cannabis plants they are very easy to
spot once you looked a few times it will
become very obvious you just need to
develop the confidence so I will include
a talk about it on the next episode but
you will still need to go look in a book
or look online and get a good visual
understanding of what you are looking
for so you can spot it right away if
something should pop up in your garden
now another thing you should think about
before you put your plants in to flower
is are they healthy have you burned them
with nutrients are they nutrient
deficient we may want to get them a
little healthier before you put them
into flour we want these plants as
healthy as we can get them before they
go into the flowering phase another
important thing to think about is do you
have any pest infestations we aren't
able to spray the plants with as many
products once we get bud set so we want
to eradicate any pest problems before we
go into the flowering phase if you do
have a pest problem at this time it is
time to step up the frequency of the
sprays and quite possibly increase the
potency of your sprays if not start
introducing new products we do not want
to enter the flowering phase with a
known pest problem it is much easier to
combat a pest problem while in veg so
let's focus on getting rid of any
problems now and then we can move to
flower a week late if that's what we
to do or we can adjust our plans
accordingly but let's make sure to get
rid of every bug before we move to
flower so at this point we should have
some backup clones for the next run we
know that the room is dark we know there
are no light leaks there's no light
getting in there's no light getting out
we've got our aroma control there's no
stinky air getting out of the grow room
you guys the number one way people get
in trouble is by having stinky air
coming out of the house control that
aroma make sure you take care of that
we're allowed to grow cannabis in
Colorado you were just fine until
somebody complains and says they can
smell your garden at that point they
send out an investigator and they come
knock on your door and ask to look and
see how many plants you've got if you've
got too many plants you do get in
trouble so no matter how many plants
you've got I recommend you've got some
sort of odor control so none of your
neighbors get mad
nobody snitches on you nobody comes
knocking on your door even if you are
within your legal amount of plants it is
still nerve-racking and stressful to
have to deal with law enforcement
because of your cannabis so simply
control the odor so again we've got
clones for the next round we've got a
nice dark room we are controlling the
odor that is leaving our room we know
how to identify males females and
hermaphrodites we know what to call so
that we don't cause any problems in the
grow so that we don't seed up our whole
grow we know there are no pests we know
we haven't overfed the plants we are
almost ready to flower now how do we
know when to flower these plants there
are a couple of things that will help us
determine when to initiate the flowering
phase for our plants one of the main
factors will be the height how much
ceiling space do you have in your grow
most of us are in a residential area a
lot of us are going to be modifying a
bedroom or something similar a lot of us
may be using grow tents you're going to
have to flower your plants at a height
where they have plenty of rooms to grow
to where they don't work themselves into
the lights and you run out of space you
need to plan to leave depending on what
type of light you were using you need to
plan to leave an appropriate gap between
the top of your plants and your light
source if you're using LEDs you can get
much closer if you're using the ceramic
metal halides you can get kind of close
if you're using a high pressure sodium
light you need to stay kind of a disc
it's away if you're using a double-ended
Gavita you need to stay even further
away so plan for that when you're
planning your flowering time now a good
thing to think of when you were new at
growing and you haven't grown a lot of
crops and you want to prepare for
flowering time and have enough space is
prepare for your plants to double in
height if you were growing a sativa
strain or something a sativa hybrid with
a lot of sativa genetics in there it
could double in height throughout the
flowering phase so if you veg your plant
and the plant is 3 feet tall you
initiate flower by the time it is done
you can expect a six foot tall plant if
you're not doing anything to control
that vertical growth so in that case I
would plant a flower that plant if you
have got if your light is 6 feet tall
we're gonna say if your light is 7 feet
tall because we need some space if your
light is 7 feet off the ground
I would veg those plants the first time
I grow them I would veg them until they
are 3 feet tall once they are 3 feet
tall initiate the flower phase they're
gonna double in height they'll end about
6 feet tall
you'll still have that 1 foot of space
between the white and the canopy now
this is not a rule this is just a guide
if you have not grown your strain before
if you don't know what these genetics
are going to do allow yourself room for
these plants to double of course if
you've got plants with big obvious fat
white indica leaves you may not get that
doubled growth you may only get a little
bit of growth you're going to get
stretch for about three weeks and then
they'll slow down on the stretching and
the bud sets will really set in but try
to plan ahead for too much head space
there's nothing worse than having a big
giant beautiful top Cola that is just
beefy and covered in trichomes and then
it starts murdering itself by growing
directly into your lights it starts
touching the light it starts burning
itself it starts getting ugly colors you
have to think about do I want to bend
that butt over do I actually want to cut
part of that off what do I do at this
point that is really heartbreaking so
plan ahead and try to give yourself
plenty of headspace also keep in mind
spacing you don't want the plants
touching each other too much just think
about if you and I and another couple of
dudes we're hanging out in a room if we
all just started spreading our arms
just touching each other all weird
you're gonna get kind of weirded out
you're like bro why you touching me and
you're gonna want your own space the
plants are very similar when one plant
feels another plant touch it it
indicates to itself
I probably shouldn't grow much further
that way because I'm already touching a
limit and the other plant says the same
thing so now you've got two plants that
have just stopped out branching and
they're gonna start growing up so allow
your plants plenty of space spread them
out a little bit yes we do want to
maximize canopy space we do want to
maximize the space of our grow but we
don't want to crush them in so much we
can't get airflow we don't want to crush
them in so much that they're
uncomfortable we need a little bit of
airflow and we don't want leaves
stacking on top of each other because
that's where you start causing problems
so give them some space space your
plants out give them some breathing room
give them some growing room and keep in
mind that when you put your plants into
the flowering phase they are only
halfway through their lifecycle they
still need to Bush out a little bit
they're gonna grow much taller you're
only halfway there so allow that extra
space for flowering now if you're
running a screen of green or a trellis
system I suggest you veg until you kind
of fill out most of that screen system
the idea is to try to get one little
branch coming through each of those
squares in your trellis system if you
can maximize that that's when you really
start cranking out as much but as you
can produce in your space so I suggest
you fill that canopy up and fill that
screen up before you flower because
you're spreading it out nice and white
it's not going straight up like the guys
without the screen if you're spreading
it out you've still got all that
vertical growth left for you so you can
spread it out then put it into flower
and it's gonna grow vertically for you
so I recommend you use all of that
screen space to the best of your ability
all right I feel like that is a good
explanation of when to flower the plants
you want to give yourself about double
the space you want to allow some space
between the whites and the plants and
you also want to give the plants some
space so they can breathe and so they
can stretch out now if you've done any
topping I would definitely recommend 10
to 14 days of recovery time before you
move the plants into flower so plan
ahead do all of your topping plenty of
time in advance so the plants can heal
so they can redistribute the hormones
that way the plant can produce big fat
chunky top buds if you top a plant and
move it into flower
soon you'll notice those top buds don't
really produce the colas that we were
expecting so give your plant time to
recover from topping let those hormones
move around and it will make a huge
difference in the productivity of your
plant so I feel like that is a pretty
good before flower checklist make sure
the plants are healthy make sure you
understand how to find males females and
hermaphrodites make sure your pest free
and make sure you've got a good idea of
when to flower those plants try to set a
schedule try to stick to it as long as
you are pest free I would suggest that
you keep twisting and popping the stems
making those stocks nice and robust
until it's time to flower
keep pulling off any yellow or funky
leaves keep the plants looking nice and
healthy
keep them thriving and when it's time to
flower flip that timer to 1212
make a note of what day you did it and
now you were in the flowering phase
several people have asked me when
flowering starts does flowering start
the day you change the timer to 1212 or
does flowering start the day you start
seeing buds set if you were looking at a
package of seeds and it says these seeds
will take 8 to 10 weeks to flower that 8
to 10 weeks starts the day you change
your timer to 1212 the day you do the
flip is the beginning of your flowering
phase that's when that new schedule that
new calendars the new countdown that is
when that begins so if you were running
24 hours or 20 on and 4 off or 18 and 6
in veg you just go in and you change
that timer to 12 hours on and 12 hours
off and that is day one of your
flowering phase in about 10 to 12 days
you'll start seeing pre flower the
plants will start showing you sex you
need to go through and start pulling out
all of the boys by this point by day 14
the boys will be very obvious they will
be getting ready to pollinate if they
have not already dropped pollen pay
close attention to the boys and get them
out of there for the first two or three
weeks of flowering you're going to focus
heavily on looking for male plants and
plants with hermaphrodite traits and
removing them from the garden safely so
again I suggest that you start now doing
some research on understanding what a
male and a female and a hermaphrodite
cannabis plant look like so that when
you're 8 10 12 or 14 days into flower
you were a certain
you see and you were confident so that
you can make the correct decision to
keep your garden in top shape all right
I feel like that is a great place to
stop because my next lesson is going to
be about Fino hunting and sexing the
plants and selecting a mother plant from
that Fino hunt process then we are going
to work our way into the flowering stage
of the grow lesson that's right it is
almost time to flower the hypothetical
plants in the grow lesson so that is
coming up very soon I will talk in depth
about probably three week chunks of the
flowering phase will probably do week
one through three and then we'll do four
through six and then we'll to seven
through nine that was hard for my brain
to process that quickly but that is my
idea for the flowering phase I'm going
to break it down into three three week
chunks and then we'll talk about
finishing the plants up so that is
coming up very soon so I feel like this
is a great place to wrap up this episode
I want to thank everybody for listening
thank you for all of the support I have
been getting a lot of interaction on
social media and it really means a lot
to me
it means a lot that people are listening
that you're enjoying and that you are
learning from the podcast that means the
world to me so thank you for all of that
support if you would like to support the
show financially you can do so by going
to a website called patreon that is
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
all the information that you need to
sign up and help the show will be right
there on the screen and again I want to
send a giant thank you shout out to
everybody who is helping the patreon
campaign so far and everybody who will
help in the future thank you guys it
does not go unnoticed I would also
appreciate it if you follow me on social
media you can find me on Facebook simply
search for the Grove from your heart
podcast on Twitter it's at gfy each
podcast if you want to follow my
personal Twitter account it's at Ross to
Jeff for 20 I also encourage you to
follow my Instagram feed on Instagram
I'm Irie endure score genetics
I read genetics as my seed breeding
company I post a lot of great cannabis
photography there I think you would
enjoy it if you'd like to reach out to
me and you are not into the social media
you can send me an email my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
and I would love to hear from you maybe
I will answer your questions on a future
episode ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls smokers and growers I want to
thank you again for listening to another
episode of
grow from your heart podcast I'll be
back in just a few days with another fun
episode I want to give a huge shout out
to my friend Ashley in New Mexico
everybody better step up their game
because there's a young girl grower in
New Mexico coming to take all the
cannabis cups big shout out to Ashley
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
welcome to the show cannabis community
it's time for episode 376 with a girl
from your heart podcast this episode is
brought to you by the hella DANC seed
company if you need new seeds for your
garden I highly recommend the hell a
dank seed company and you can find them
at www.sedar.com fighting you know what
I am smoking I just took a dab of some
strawberry diesel batter from apothecary
farms the label says it is 60 1.9
percent THC with a total of 70 3.7%
cannabinoids this stuff has a really
funky sort of a sour strawberry smell to
it it's definitely got the strawberries
with a hint of diesel coming through the
background
it tasted like strawberry incense and I
really like the flavor the flavor is
just hanging out on my tongue I could
use a drink but I don't want to drink
anything to wipe that strawberry flavor
off of my tongue I want to let that
linger as long as it can so I'm really
digging the flavor and the high is nice
it goes straight to the brain it's a
nice high-energy sort of a buzz I really
like the strawberry diesel batter from
apothecary farms alright let's get right
into the podcast you guys this is going
to be another grow lesson if you've been
following along you know I've been doing
a long series of grow lessons this
episode is going to be about Fino
hunting so far in my series of grow
lessons we have talked about setting a
goal for our grow we have chosen a white
spot for the grow we have selected and
purchased the proper equipment we have
set it up we've tested it we have
actually sprouted seeds we've acquired
clones we've got little baby plants
going we potted those into our three or
five maybe seven gallon pots we are
currently in the veg phase and my grow
lessons we have topped our plants we've
been doing lolli popping we've been
doing copying and twisting we've got
some canopy control techniques happening
we are almost ready to flower in my grow
lessons before we get to the flowering
phase I feel like there are a few things
we should understand we need to know how
to sex our appliance if you are growing
from seed you've got the opportunity to
find males those
ants won't reveal their sex until we are
early and flower we need to be able to
identify the male plants so that we can
remove them from the garden before they
pollinate our females another thing
we're going to talk about is selecting
mother plants and we're going to do that
through a Fino hunt let's jump right in
to talking about a Fino hunt and what a
Fino hunt is and what is the purpose of
Fino hunting now what do I mean by a
Fino hunt when I say a Fino hunt I am
referring to finding a desired phenotype
from a package of seeds now let's say
you acquired a package of seeds from the
hella dank seed company I would
recommend 10 seeds for a Fino hunt I do
sell packs of 5
I sell packs of 5 to make them
attainable so that everybody can afford
them I understand not everybody can buy
a 10 pack of seeds I would recommend 10
seeds for a fee no hunt so in this
situation we're going to run 10 seeds
you just got a fresh 10 pack of a rise
you don't know what's in there we need
to find that phenotype that works best
for you and your garden so sifting
through those seeds is a Fino hunt we
are going to grow them out and you were
going to find the phenotype that works
best for you the phenotype that works
best for your patients or your customers
and also you need the phenotype that
works best for your garden so the goal
here is to find a custom-tailored
phenotype out of this pack of seeds so
let's talk about a little bit how to do
that
doing a Fino hunt is one of my favorite
things to do in a grow environment I get
to do a lot of observation I get to find
surprises I may find the next best thing
I may find that next ken-dog I may find
the next golden coat I may find the next
Gorilla Glue I may find the next Girl
Scout cookies you never know what you
could come up with in a Fino hunt that
is one of my favorite parts it's like
opening Christmas presents you never
know what is in that box
suddenly I want to make a Forrest Gump
reference because you never know what
you're gonna get so this is how I would
do a Fino hunt I would get a ten pack of
seeds
I would germinate those ten seeds I
would carefully make sure that every one
of those plants is treated the exact
same I would put them all in the same
medium the same pot I would feed them
the same thing that would go under the
same light and it would be all in the
same environment because I don't want
any variation I want all of these
seedlings to get the same opportunity to
show me this
same potential so I germinate these
seeds I get them into pots I get them
going
I've edged them I start taking notes on
these plants very early I label them one
through ten so I've got whatever the
strain is we're gonna say a rise one a
rise to all the way up to number ten I'm
going to pay attention to these plants
and take a lot of notes if I see
anything weird I'm going to document
that if I get a plant that's just
growing like [ __ ] it's not keeping up
it's having problems it gets pulled out
of there I don't want to keep a shitty
plant around there's no reason to have a
shitty plant when you can Fino hunt
seeds and find a keeper
so I'll pay close attention to my plants
as they grow I'll take a lot of notes in
veg if I top the plants if I lollipop
the plants I make sure to do it equally
across the board I want all 10 of these
seedlings to get the same treatment
again we want them all to have the same
potential we were trying to audition
these two find the best one for our
situation so if you give them different
treatment they're going to come out
differently how do you know what the
best one is they all need to be treated
equally in my opinion so I grow these
plants out as soon as they're big enough
I take a clone I am confident in my
cloning skills 99.9% of my clones will
survive if you were not confident in
your clone skills I suggest you take two
maybe three maybe five clones from each
plant so let them get large enough to
provide the amount of clones you need
get a clone from each plant carefully
label your clones you will have a rise
number one a rise number two you should
have clone a rise one clone arise to
carefully label them this will be very
important in the future this is your
reserve this is how you are going to
keep your plants around this is going to
segue into selecting a mother plant this
is how we're going to have a mother
plant to keep these genetics around
forever so you can continue to produce
this select phenotype until the end of
time that clone that we labeled is going
to become your future mother plants so
make sure it is labeled accurately so
again we label them arise one arise two
all the way up to a rise number ten then
we also label the clones a1 a2 a all the
way up to number 10 so we've got the
cloned owner and the corresponding
clones properly labeled there's no
confusion there
as I've done a complete episode on
cutting clones so if you need help
cutting your clones I recommend episode
number 346 for an in-depth lesson on
cutting clones and if you want a really
in-depth talk about mother plants check
out episode 315 that one will teach you
all about healthy and happy mother
plants the goal here is to get a clone
off of each of these seedlings before we
put them into flour
that way when we find the champion out
of this batch we've got a clone of that
so that we can continue to grow that
clone forever you keep that one clone
wife as a mother plant you never flower
it out and you can cut clones from that
as long as you keep it healthy so it's
always there to give you clones you have
now got a mother plant from your Fino
hunt that is your custom phenotype that
is for you maybe you like the more
sativa dominant phenotype maybe you like
the phenotype that smells more like
golden goat maybe you like the phenotype
that smells more like dirty feet maybe
you need the one that finishes quicker
maybe you're the kind of person that
likes to let them flower for a really
long time
that's up to you you get to find that
one it works best for you in your grow
if you get a clone you've got a clone
that all of your other friends have
everybody's grown it everybody in the
neighborhood has it everybody has smoked
it there's nothing setting you apart
from the competition if you were growing
for a retail market purpose so growing
from seed you could find gold growing
from seed you can also find that custom
phenotype that works for you that works
for your garden and that works for the
market and honestly when you're growing
from seed I always recommend taking a
clone because who knows what you've got
what if you grow from seed and you find
the most amazing product you've ever
found and you don't have a clone you're
gonna be heartbroken you're gonna try to
revenge it which is a whole another
podcast that's a pain in the ass but if
you have got a clone it's already ready
to go if you cut a clone before you put
your plants in to flower that clone is
gonna go into a pot about two weeks
later then it'll be ready to go into
another pot a couple of weeks later you
can cut a bunch more clones off of that
and have that ready to go by the time
that first crop is finished so you will
have decided which one is the keeper
probably around week seven or eight and
you can take a bunch of clones and have
them ready almost on time to fill that
room when you cut down from the
you know hunt you don't have to skip
anytime it helps you move along quite
quickly so now our original plants have
grown out nice and large we have got
clones from everything they are properly
labeled we are confident that will at
least one of those clones from each
phenotype is going to root then it is
time to flower my Fino hunt that's when
the fun begins
we can tell a lot about our plants
during the veg cycle we can tell if you
like the growth structure if you like
the node spacing if you like the leaf
size that's going to indicate a lot of
things the real things we want to see
will not reveal themselves until they
are in flower so early and flower the
first things we need to pay attention to
we need to look for males if you're
growing from seed you've got the
opportunity to have males pop up in your
garden even if you are running feminized
seeds not all feminized seed makers make
seeds the same way some feminized seeds
were made with poor practices some
feminized seeds were made without
auditioning the parrot plants properly
before breeding with them you still may
find males or intersex traits in
feminized seeds just because the package
says feminized doesn't mean you can get
lazy and stop paying attention so we
need to look for males or hermaphrodites
in our garden early in flower I would
start looking day three day four day
five you're gonna start seeing signs of
male pre flower as soon as you are
certain that that plant is a male it
needs to come out of the garden we do
not want boys in there the girls are
going to start developing pistols
they'll be able to receive pollen when
those males drop pollen are gonna seed
your plant we need to get the boys out
as soon as possible I do plan to talk
more in depth about sexing our plants in
a future episode when we get into the
flowering phase but quickly let's talk
about identifying a male and a female
cannabis plant early in flower when I am
trying to identify the sex of a cannabis
plant there are two spots I like to look
and I find those spots very reliable the
very tip-top bud will be the first spot
to show you sex when you throw those
plants into flower also lower on the
plant where you've got an intersection
you've got the little peace sign you've
got two branches coming off and you've
got the main stock coming up right there
at that intersection it
to tell you if it is a boy or a girl so
a few days into flower our plants will
start giving us signs of male or female
sex if you grab a branch and look
closely there will be the main branch
coming up then there will be a little
chute coming off of that where that
chute splits off there will be signs of
sex right at that intersection right
inside of that little V there will be
signs of sex
if you see a wart like thing popping up
right there
if you see a little tiny acorn popping
up right there if it's got a ball coming
out of there that is probably a male
plant if it looks like it's got a hair
coming out just one little pistol maybe
two little pistol hairs doing a peace
sign that is a female so at the
intersections at the nodes you will see
either little hairs coming out or you
may see what looks like balls now be
careful in early flower because
sometimes those little balls are
actually calyxes and it can be confusing
so if you've identified something that
you think may be a male flower mark that
plant say arise number seven looks like
it could be a boy write that down
somewhere and then every day when you go
in that garden head right over to number
seven and look at the progress if those
balls that are on the plant start
drooping and hanging down that is
definitely a male it's growing a set of
balls you need to get that boy out of
there if that ball starts putting out a
long hair that is a calyx and you've got
a female plant up toward the top of the
plant we should see a little bit of
production you will either see buds that
look like dandelions those are your
girls if they're getting hairs the white
furry pistols are popping out those are
females that's what you want if it looks
like you're making little sets of
bananas up at the top
those are your boy plants we need to get
rid of those it may look like you've got
a little bud that is already loaded up
with seeds those are not seeds
those are pollen sacks we need to get
that boy out of the room immediately I
can only describe males and females so
much through words with the podcast it
is your responsibility as a ganja farmer
to Google what a male and female
cannabis plant look like you need some
images get ahead of yourself go look
before you put your plants in to flower
do not make the mistake of thinking I
can identify a male plant and then let
that male go
by day 10 day 14 he's gonna be dropping
pollen and you're going to have a
pollinated crop if you're a new grower
that is very discouraging everything
just went to [ __ ] your main goal is to
produce a crop with no seeds you just
reduce potency you just reduced harvest
weight you definitely reduced retail
value everything is not how you want it
if you've got seeds in there so be very
careful to get the boys out very very
early now if you were observing your
plants and your plants show ballsacks
and they show hairs they need to go
immediately those are hermaphrodite
plants
I know it's 2018 and we're supposed to
be acceptable I do not accept
hermaphroditic plants in my garden for
any reason they must go we're trying to
produce high-grade seedless cannabis and
a hermaphrodite plant is going to ruin
our whole goal of a seedless garden so
get rid of the males and get rid of the
hermaphrodites if you were not sure if
that plant is a male or hermaphrodite
pay very close attention to it keep an
eye on that part you think may be a male
part it will start to open up it will
start to hang it will give you plenty of
warning that it wants to release pollen
pay close attention now once you've
called your boys and you think you are
past the part of the plants revealing
sex if you were growing from seed you
still need to pay attention for
hermaphrodites it is not uncommon for
things to reveal intersex traits late in
flower sometime around week 7 or week 8
or especially week 9 and if you push
them real hard its way likely to see
them toward week 10 so pay attention to
the hermaphrodite traits in your plants
if a plant shows herm late in flower
you've got some considerations to make
if it didn't pop up until week 9 that
may be okay if that weed is fire if you
just produce some amazing product and
that plant Herms
late in the bloom cycle that may be okay
we're gonna cut the plants down before
that hermaphrodite is able to cause us
any problems also a lot of their
hermaphrodite plants that show intersex
traits late in flower produce sterile
male flowers they won't even produce
pollen that can pollinate a room it'll
pop out a couple nanners and they'll dry
up immediately they won't ever produce
pollen so that is up to you if you get a
plant that does hermaphrodite late and
flower if it's not going to cause
problems and it produces amazing product
it
maybe worth keeping around that is
something for you to consider also if
you ever share that clone with people
maybe let them know hey bro at the end
of week 9 this one might throw a couple
of nanners on you as an experienced
grower that's something I'm familiar
with
that's something I'm comfortable with
that's something I can deal with very
many of the chem dog derived strains
will Herm on you if you let them go past
nine weeks that is not rare if you let
it go too long it'll throw out a couple
nanners but those nanners
don't contain any pollen they will not
pollinate anything they'll just pop up a
couple of male bananas right at the end
so the way to solve that either cut it
down right before that happens because I
know when it happens it happens at day
70 so cut them down about day 68
everything should be cool and I've also
grown that plant enough to know that
those male flowers don't produce any
pollen so even if I do let it finish if
I let it go 70 72 days it's still not
going to cause a problem and even if
they did spit out pollen I'm 72 days in
the flower there's no time for anything
to happen all of my pistols have been
shriveled up by then there's nowhere for
that pollen to be received so you have
things to consider if your plants are
hermaphroditic late in flower if it's
early in flower call them get rid of
them if it's an obvious from Aphrodite
toss it if you've just got one flower
laid in I would think about it now if
you've got one hermaphrodite flower late
in and that plant is only a six on a
scale of 10 you still call it if you've
got a 9 or a 10 and a hermaphrodite
flower that's when you kind of consider
your like is it worth that one herm or
not but that is a growers decision to
make
so that is a quick rant on sexing your
plants I do plan on going into more
depth on that in a future episode you
are looking for the little hairs or the
balls if it's got balls it's got to go
if it's got hairs and balls it
definitely has to go now once we call
the males and the potential
hermaphrodites you have probably got 40
to 60% of your remaining stock cannabis
plants average about 50% male and 50%
female so by day 14
you have probably eliminated forty to
sixty percent of the room if you started
with ten seeds you were probably down to
about five you may have six you may have
four I'm gonna go with five for the rest
of this lesson so we've got five plants
there in there finishing pots they're
about two weeks into flower we've pulled
out all the males we've pulled out all
the hermaphrodites we are still paying
attention
for intersex traits we're also keeping a
lot of notes write down everything you
feed these plants write down everything
you spray on these plants right down the
reactions of the plants to those
procedures if you see one plant do
something different than all of the
others as a reaction to something you
did document that that may mean a lot to
you in the future let's say that plant
one and plant five become the two best
keepers out of this phenol hunt and you
need to narrow it down to one maybe
that weird note you wrote about plant
number one will be the reason you call
that one and the reason you keep number
five so keep a lot of notes so I do plan
to do in-depth lessons on each week of
the bloom cycle I'm going to break it
down in two trimesters will do weeks one
through three four through six and seven
through nine and we'll talk about that
in depth we're gonna fast-forward a
little bit through the grow cycle here
in the phenotype talk and we're gonna
get toward the end of the harvest during
the grow phase during the bloom phase
our plants got the same exact treatment
we've only got five of them it should
have been fairly easy to treat them all
the same they got the same amount of
light they got the same amount of
lollipop being the same type of pruning
the same type of topping the exact same
feedings the exact same pest management
the exact same foliar feeding 's you get
my point we treated them all the same so
that we can see reliable outcomes from
each seedling now just like any crop
make sure you flush for ten to fourteen
days before harvest then harvest I have
done a long and in-depth episode on
harvesting and drying and curing our
plants if you need tips on drying and
curing your freshly harvested cannabis
plants I recommend you listen to episode
326 titled drying and curing I will give
you a detailed step-by-step lesson on
drying and curing your freshly harvested
cannabis so you've got to grow it you've
got to flower it then you've got to
flush it then harvest it then dry it and
cure it and trim it guess what you get
to do next you get to have a smoke party
depending on how much you grew depending
on how many people you trust and how
many friends you've got you get to have
a few people come over and test your
pinot hunt this is one of the most fun
and rewarding parts of growing cannabis
you started with ten seeds about a
hundred and twenty days ago and now
you've got a small group of close
friends at your house helping you narrow
it down to decide what plant is going to
be part of your future grow now when you
and your friends are narrowing down
which phenotype to select you get to
make the final decision don't let
anybody sway you on the final decision
because you are the grower you are the
one doing the work this is your art you
get to decide but what I like to do is
after everything is dried and cured and
we're ready to smoke it I get Mike over
I get Kevin over I bring a couple other
folks over and I give them five little
buds and if we've got time to do it
we'll smoke them all right here we'll
just take a couple bong rips of each or
whatever and see what it all tastes like
see what it smells like and look for
what you're looking for are you looking
for flavor are you looking for a
specific aroma are you looking for a
specific effect are you looking for a
bag appeal if you're growing like I said
earlier if you are a retail market
grower you're probably going for some
bag appeal you're going to need the buds
that look the best also you may want
something that is unique if you've got
something that smells like oranges or
strawberries or blueberries we've all
got that if you've got something that
smells like oranges and gas and cherries
and dirty feet and gets you high as [ __ ]
and finishes in 60 days you just found
gold that is probably the one you want
to keep so find the one that works best
for you let your friends do a little
tasting and let them kind of vote on it
they may agree they may not decide what
works best for you it's just great to
have input from your friends and it's
always a good time to have a little
phyno hunt party with the crew so here's
a quick breakdown of a phyno hunt the
main point is to find the outlier in a
population of seeds we do so by
germinating a batch of seeds in that
process we remove the problematic plants
which may be males hermaphrodites or
mutants
then we take clones before we flower our
plants we carefully label those plants
to match the clones so we've got plant
one and clone one plant two and clone
two that way when we're done we've got
mother plants we're gonna talk about
that a little more in just a second so
we've pop seeds we've removed the
problems we've got clones
now we flower out our plants in that
process take a lot of notes
so you know what you did we are cannabis
consumers week may have fuzzy memories I
like to smoke before I work in the
sometimes I may forget some details
that's why I write down everything that
notepad isn't gonna forget anything that
Google document won't forget anything my
high ass will probably forget a couple
of details write your [ __ ] down so
finish the crop get it all the way to
the end
flush it harvest dry and cure do a
little smoke test with your friends
decide which one you like the best what
works for your garden what works for you
what works for your clientele are you
growing for a medical patient what works
best for them when I get the opportunity
I like to send my finished products to a
lab for testing
you would be surprised at how many
plants we select as the keeper that are
not the highest tester in the batch
sometimes the highest tester isn't the
one with the best flavor sometimes the
one with the highest test does not bring
the best high when you smoke it
sometimes those lab results are
impressive but we did not choose the one
that gave us the best results based on
our smoke test sometimes we did choose
the one that matches up with the test
but not always and if it's more common
that we don't agree with the lab test is
which one is our keeper another thing
you're gonna find when you do a phenol
hunt you will find two that you really
really want to keep it'll be one that
smells real well and smokes real well
and gets you super-high and there will
be one that does all of that pretty well
but it harvests way better being a
grower that's always hard to decide I
always keep the one that smokes better
we can just grow more next month
try not select because it's pretty try
not to select because it harvests the
most try to select based on effect based
on potency based on desirability based
on marketability there's enough [ __ ]
out there that looks really good on
Instagram and doesn't smoke worth a [ __ ]
so even if your plants aren't super
photogenic if they do what you need when
you smoke them when you and your market
consume them that's exactly what you're
aiming for so that is the phenotype you
want to find find the one that works
best for you that is a custom phenotype
for you your clientele and your garden
now earlier I mentioned mother plants we
took clones off of these plants before
we flowered them so in a grow room
somewhere we've got five plants just
hanging out there in veg maybe you were
proactive maybe you decided around week
seven that you really like to rise
number three so you went in there and he
found that arrived
mother plant number three and you took
ten clones they're already vegging
they're getting big so that as soon as
you harvest you can throw those plants
in there and you can run a rise number
three again maybe you were waiting for
this smoke test to find out which one to
run again either way you have got that
number that you decide that plant is
hanging out in the bedroom it's in there
you just got to go get it and take a
bunch of clones off of it and run it
again if you narrowed it down to two
that you like cut a few clones off of
each one run them again side by side now
you've got a larger batch of each one to
decide from you can run it again maybe
change the nutrients maybe change
something in the room and see if the two
phenotypes do something different with
different environments maybe that will
help you decide on which one to keep
either way you choose to do it after
your tasting party with your friends
you've got that backup plant in the
bedroom you've got a rise number three
just over there waiting to take a bunch
of clones so you can grow it again
forever the thing is keep that plant
alive listen to that episode about
mother plants then you can keep that
arise number three around forever you
can have a reliable consistent medicine
that works for you that works for your
garden and your people learn to rely on
you for that product ladies and
gentlemen that is my quick talk on Fino
hunting I hope I made that nice and
clear for you phenol hunting is one of
my favorite things to do in a grow
that's always a great time you get some
seeds you get to find out what's in
there you narrow it down to one and then
a guy like me as soon as you're down to
that one you start another phenol hunt
and then I'm always adding a new one and
pulling an old one out of the garden
there's always something coming in and
something going out so that I've always
got some fresh stuff in my grows I want
to thank everybody for listening to this
podcast if you feel like this episode
was educational informative and/or
entertaining and you would like to make
a financial contribution to the show I
would appreciate your support and you
can do it by going to patreon.com slash
grow from your heart it's patr e0n
dot-com slash grow from your heart all
the information you need to become a
patron will be right there on the screen
and again thank you to everybody who's
contributed to the patreon campaign I
really do appreciate your support I
would also appreciate it if you find me
on social media you can find me on
Facebook search for the grow from your
heart podcast on Twitter it's at G fyh
podcast if you'd like to follow my
personal Twitter account it's at Rasta
Jeff 420
also love it if you follow my Instagram
account I post a lot of great fine
cannabis photography I also go on
Instagram live and do some rants I like
to take dad's hangout talk to my friends
if you ask questions in the Instagram
live feed I will do my best to answer
your questions to the best of my ability
of course I don't have time to research
or anything because people are just
asking questions on the fly so that is
always fun people ask me questions I
rack my brain and try to answer right
there in the live feed so join me on
Instagram I use my seed company I'm
Irene underscore genetics I RIE
underscore genetics on Instagram
give me a follow I just may follow you
back if you've got something you'd like
to say you'd like to reach out and
you're not in all of the social media
maybe you've got a product you'd like me
to review maybe you'd like to sponsor
the podcast you can send me an email my
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com and I would love to hear
from you don't forget that the podcast
is available on iTunes stitcher Google
Play and YouTube find the show where you
can listen give us a subscribe and make
sure that you don't miss an episode I
want to thank you guys again for
listening to episode 376 of the grove
from your heart podcast I'll be back
Thursday with a fresh new episode I want
to give a huge shout out to my friend
Eric in Massachusetts and until next
time take a phat dad and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]