[Music]
welcome to the show podcast world it's
time for episode 404 of the grow from
your heart podcast this episode of the
show is brought to you by my friends at
the he'll add a seed company if you need
new seeds in your garden I highly
recommend the hella dank seed company
and you can find them at www.ctvn.org
green dot labs
once again the label says it is a
combination of golden pineapple and jet
fuel gelato the flavor on the label is
described as citrus cleaner haze and
fruit cheese I think it tastes just like
a pineapple Fanta I think the flavor and
aroma even include the fizzy part of the
Fanta drink I think it's delicious
and amazing on the back of the product
container it says it contains 50 9.81%
THC I really enjoy the pineapple Fanta
live batter from Green Dot labs ladies
and gentlemen this episode is going to
be another compilation of reposted grow
lessons in this episode we are going to
revisit episodes 378 380 383 385 387 and
388 so ladies and gentlemen with no
further ado let's travel back in time
and revisit these grow lessons
welcome to the show podcast world it's
time for episode 378 of the drove from
your heart podcast this episode is
brought to you by the hella tanked seed
company if you need new seeds in your
garden I highly recommend the hella dank
seed company and you can find them at
www.sedar.com off by
you know what I'm smoking honestly today
I feel like total [ __ ] and I haven't
been dabbing I'm giving my body a little
bit of a rest I've got a head cold I've
got a chest cold I've got the sinus
thing going on that is driving me
completely crazy so I'm not gonna take
any dabs before the show gonna try to
keep my [ __ ] together and deliver you
guys a decent podcast in the last
episode I promised another grow lesson
if you've been following along you know
I've been doing a long series of grow
lessons the grow series started at
episode 351 if you haven't caught up I
suggest you head back to episode 351 an
episode 351 we set a goal for our garden
and then we move on to selecting a space
for our garden we also select the proper
equipment then we build the grow room
then we talk about seeds and clones then
we veg our plants then we talk about a
few tricks and tips to get our plants up
to speed for quality production and at
this point in my grow lessons it is day
one of flower it is time to flip our
crop from the vegetative phase into the
flowering phase of our grow so I'm gonna
press pause for a moment I'm going to
listen back to this intro and see how I
sound and when I come back we are going
to talk about flowering our new cannabis
garden all right podcast world I
apologize that I do sound kind of crappy
but the show must go on I've been
promising this episode I may make this
one kind of quick and then recap next
week and move forward my original idea
was to do a three week chunk of
flowering episodes we would do week one
through three and then four through six
and seven through nine but we were going
to focus on day one of week one today
and then we will adjust from there in
the following episodes so let's get
started on flowering our cannabis garden
what do I mean by flowering we want to
initiate the budding phase the flowering
phase for regular cannabis plants is
triggered by reducing the light cycle if
you were working with Otto flower plants
you are in a total different ballgame
those plants will flower when they are
ready for this discussion we're going to
focus on regular photoperiod plants and
photoperiod seeds so let's talk about
flowering our photoperiod garden
initiating flower is very easy all we do
is reduce the timer to 12 hours on and
12 hours off we need 12 hours of
uninterrupted darkness every day to
trigger these plants to flower I've set
up several times but I'm going to repeat
myself we
need total uninterrupted darkness during
the night phase for our flowering plants
a little bit of light is too much if you
can see a pinprick of light coming in
that room it is too much light if you
can see your hand in front of your face
during the dark phase in that room it is
too much light those plants know that
that light is there they will not go to
sleep properly they will not flower
properly if they do try to flower
properly you give them the chance of
hermaphroditic on you in mid flower
which will produce seeds in your garden
which will ruin your whole goal so we
need 100 percent total darkness in our
flowering room during the night phase so
switch the timer to 1212
be sure that you have got total dark in
that dark phase you need to go in there
and look you probably need to hang out
in the grow room for about 15 to 20
minutes for your eyes to adjust properly
to identify the most minimal light leaks
you could possibly have so go in there
and check for light leaks on day 1 of
flower if you have any light coming in
you need to correct that that will ruin
your garden so we've set the timer to
1212 now it is on for 12 hours a day and
it is off for 12 hours a day put a lot
of thought into the hours which your
lights run do you want those lights to
come on in the morning when you wake up
so you can water the plants before you
go to work and then the plants are on
all day while you're gone at work
hopefully you get to come home and check
them out before the lights turn off or
do you want those lights to come on in
the evening right when you get home from
work and the lights can run all night
while your home and you can check on
everything maybe you can get up before
work and they're still on you can check
on them again before you go to work and
make sure everything's cool I would put
a lot of thought into scheduling my
flowering cycle another thing to
consider while you're planning your
schedule is electricity is cheaper
during off-peak hours that means that
during the evenings when everybody goes
home and they're chilling electricity
gets cheaper during the daytime business
hours when everybody's using all the
electricity The Electric Company does
charge you more for those peak hours
what many folks will choose to do is run
those lights during off-peak hours and
save money on electricity this is also
advantageous because it is cooler during
the evening so you don't have the Sun up
keeping your grow room extra hot you're
not heating the outside with the Sun and
the inside with the grow lights the Sun
Goes Down and gets a little cooler
outside you can use that cool
outside air to your advantage and keep
the grow room cool so think about your
scheduling when do you want that 12:12
on cycle to be when do you want that
12:12 off cycle to be if you do decide
to run your lights at night and have
your dark cycle during the natural light
cycle be sure that no sunshine is
creeping into your grow room during that
night cycle again we need total darkness
a very common mistake is that people
flower their plants at night which means
they're in the sleep cycle during the
day which means there's the opportunity
for the sunshine to sneak into your grow
room if you've got a window if you've
got a doorway if you've got some kind of
insecure structure you can get light in
there very easily and it will destroy
your crop so you've thought about
scheduling and you know how it's going
to work around your work schedule you
know how it's gonna work around your
life and you know when you're going to
flower these plants you know when you'll
have time to give them maintenance and
work on them and water them so plan your
scheduling around that so we have set
the timer to twelve twelve that is day
one of flower that first short day is
day one right that day down too many
people forget to write that down and
they don't know how long their plants
have been in flower
write down your flowering start date
another thing I want to make clear is
this is day one of flower if you've got
a package of seeds and it says takes 70
to 80 days to flower this is the first
day of that 70 to 80 days of that
finishing time a lot of folks like to
start the flowering phase when they see
bud set starting when they see pre
flowers you are 12 days into flower by
then and you were ripping yourself off
flowering starts the day we changed the
timer to 1212 that is day one of flower
so we've now switched the timer to 1212
the plants will be on for 12 hours a day
and off for 12 hours they are going to
start flowering let's talk about the
environmental conditions we need to
provide for our flowering plants here at
the beginning of flower this will change
as the plants progress right now we
don't have any buds to worry about
they're much less opportunities for
mildew and molds to take hold because
when you get those chunky buds the
mildew likes to start in the middle of
those buds that's not really a worry
right now so we can have the humidity a
little higher at this point we can have
the temps a little higher at this point
but as we progress we are going to lower
the humidity and the temperature
in our flowering room to accommodate
those big chunky buds and to prevent
problems so at this phase of the game it
would be ideal to have your grow room
between 70 and 80 degrees Fahrenheit I
do not recommend higher than 80 I do not
recommend lower than 70 I understand
that you're struggling to keep your room
cool a lot of new growers have issues
keeping the grow room cool 84 is the max
you ever want to hit when you hit 85
degrees in higher your plants will stop
producing they will just go into a
stagnant dead slowdown mode how
productive do you want to be when it's
110 degrees outside
you just feel like [ __ ] you don't want
to do anything you don't want to move
the plants feel the same way the plants
can't move themselves to some shade the
plants can't grab some water and take a
drink those plants are stuck there so
give them the proper environment don't
go too hot don't go too cold at this
phase of the flowering cycle I would
recommend 70 to 80 degrees Fahrenheit
during your lights on cycle now let's
talk a little bit about the humidity of
this grow room during the start of the
flowering phase I like to have about
forty to fifty percent humidity earlier
I said we don't have those big buds to
worry about so we've just got a bunch of
lush happy plants they're just in there
sucking up all that humidity and growing
like crazy so forty to fifty percent
relative humidity and seventy to eighty
degrees during your daytime cycle if you
really want to dial that in I recommend
you check out my episode about vapor
pressure deficit and that was episode
number 314 if you're interested in
learning more about the vapor pressure
deficit which I find to be very
important when it comes to dialing in
the grow room perfectly
VPD will really improve the productivity
of your plants if you understand it and
dial it in correctly so that is the
daytime condition we want 70 to 80
degrees during the day forty to fifty
percent relative humidity let's talk
about the nighttime temperatures when we
turn off the white things are going to
change in that grow room I try to keep
the humidity right around the same
levels at nighttime at this stage of
flowering I want that forty to fifty
percent humidity during the night cycle
now during the night cycle I like it to
get a little bit cooler it naturally
cools off at night so I feel like the
plants probably enjoy a little bit
cooler of a temperature at night I try
not to go any more than ten degrees
these different on a day-and-night
temperature that is called your diurnal
temperature variation and you don't want
that to sway more than ten degrees so if
during your day cycle here at 75 you do
not want your night cycle to get any
lower than 65 degrees I would generally
try to keep it about 5 degrees
difference but I understand we're
building new grow rooms we are learning
our setups we are learning to dial these
rooms in 5 to 10 degrees is acceptable
for a diurnal temperature variation but
if you go any more than 5 to 10 degrees
differential in your day and night
temperature you will cause problems
within the plants the plants will be
confused the plants will begin to grow
slowly and this is also a great way to
invite powdery mildew so try to keep
your temperature swings within 10
degrees from your day and nighttime
temperature now when you're walking
through the grow sometimes just reach
out and grab a plant and feel the
temperature of the plant as the plant
warm is the plant cold how does the
plant feel to your hands if the plants
feel really really cold they're probably
really cold and you could probably
increase the temperature of your room if
the plants feel like they're warm
they're probably warm you can probably
lower the temperature of your room in
the future I do plan to do a discussion
on leaf surface temperature versus
ambient room temperature but we are not
there yet so let's stay focused here now
one thing I may have overlooked when I
talked about equipment is a hydrometer
and a thermometer or some sort of a
monitoring device
to know what is happening in our grow
room at all times
most of us growers can probably afford
the hydrometer thermometer combo that
sits in the grow room and it marks the
humidity and temperature of the room but
it will also mark the highest and lowest
points of your humidity and temperatures
so you can find your peaks and your
valleys and identify the temperature and
humidity fluctuations in your room it's
always nice to know where the peaks and
valleys are but I like to have more data
I like to have something in the room
that can tell me what's going on at all
times for a reliable monitor that can
keep you up-to-date on what's happening
in your grow room at all times
I would suggest something like a Pio
grow systems minder unit or perhaps a
smart bee unit you can use both of those
units to monitor your grow room at all
times you can pull up the data on your
phone you can see what's happening in
the room in real time some of these
types of units allow you to actually
plug in other two
and trigger them from your smartphone so
if you were away you open up your
application you see that it's too warm
in that room you can say hey let's just
easily turn on the air-conditioner you
can click a button on a tab on your
phone and it will fire up the
air-conditioner in your grow room and
you can rescue your garden while you're
at lunch hanging out with your friends
and you don't even have to leave the
table so my point is have some way to
monitor the temperature and humidity in
your grow room at all times I like to
have a report of what happens when those
lights go off
you've been running that grill light for
12 hours in that room you have created a
lot of heat you have created a lot of
energy all of that heat all of that
light energy has created humidity
there's water rising up in the air now
when we kill that light everything
changes all of that humidity in the air
is no longer being heated it's got the
opportunity to start falling it becomes
kind of thick in the grow room that
short time period while the room
stabilizes itself out from that change
is quite often the cause of many of our
powdery mildew and botrytis issues and
many growers don't even know that that
is happening in the room at that time
they look at their hygrometer they look
at their thermometer they say oh it was
72 degrees in here that's acceptable oh
it was 45% humidity in here that's
acceptable you don't realize that there
was a point where it was 78 degrees and
about 82% humidity in the room and
that's because we turned off that light
all that moisture that was in the air is
now falling now the plants don't have
light anymore so they are starting to
respirate a little bit they're letting
out a little more moisture and all of
that chaos can really cause problems for
our plants in that type of environment
so my point is try to know what's
happening environmentally in your rooms
at all times all right it feels like we
know what our environment should be like
let's talk a little bit about feeding
our transitioning cannabis plants if you
are working in a no-till bed or you're
working with super soil there's no need
to adjust anything at this time just
keep doing what you're doing you
basically need to water the plants
throughout the flowering cycle if you
plan on adding a cover crop or a top
dress or maybe feeding some teas you
will need to adjust your teas at this
time I would take the nitrogen products
out and focus more on the phosphorus and
potassium at this time if you're running
teas or top dress or a cover crop now if
you are working with bottled nutrients
you can probably just swap out that veg
bottle and replace it with the flow
in nutrients most of the bottle nutrient
companies make it very easy to follow
their nutrient schedule so simply swap
out that veg bottle put in the bloom
bottle and everything should be good to
go the main difference in our feeding
schedule at this time is that we are
going to reduce the amount of nitrogen
and we are going to slowly start
increasing the amount of phosphorus and
potassium our plants take up
approximately 80 to 90 percent of their
nitrogen during the veg phase once we
switch them into flour they are done
sucking up nitrogen and they want more
phosphorous and potassium
so they can build robust branches and
big fat buds so let's reduce the
nitrogen and start increasing the
phosphorus and potassium that part
should mostly be covered by your base
nutrients if you're running a one bottle
based nutrient a 2-part or a 3-part you
should be getting the proper nitrogen
phosphorus and potassium from your base
nutrients now there are a few more
things that these plants can use at this
phase I like to add silica when I am
mixing up my nutrient solution I always
put potassium silicates in the water
first the potassium silicates go first
then I mix in my base nutrients these
plants can probably use cal-mag at this
point in time I also like to give the
plants some sort of a root inoculant
early in Flour don't cut back the
microbes keep them going keep those
roots growing strong keep them healthy
the plants will continue to flourish in
flower I also like some enzymes those
enzymes serve several purposes the
enzymes will basically help to keep the
root zone clean and they will also break
down any decaying root matter and turn
that into usable energy for my plants I
also like to add some carbohydrates the
carbohydrates serve a couple of purposes
those carbs will feed my microbes those
carbs will also give my plants energy
between the carbs the enzymes and the
mykos my root zone is really healthy and
really active which will show up top at
the top of our plants so we are focusing
on nitrogen phosphorus and potassium at
this stage we are shifting away from the
nitrogen more toward the phosphorus and
potassium it's always good to add
cal-mag a little bit of a root inoculant
I like some enzymes always some carbs
and to make everything pop I would add a
little bit of fulvic acid now if you've
chosen to work with a specific bottled
nutrient company
most of those companies have a nutrient
calculator on their website so you can
go to whatever nutrient company.com you
can find their nutrient calculator you
can type in how many weeks are going to
flower you can click on which products
of theirs you have purchased and it will
tell you week by week how much of each
product to use most of those charts are
reliable but keep in mind they want you
to continue buying products so they may
recommend you use a little more than
necessary for an ideal crop situation I
generally reduce the recommended dosage
by about 25 percent if it says to feed
100 milliliters of your base product I
would start off with 75 milliliters and
see what happens we can always feed the
plants a little more later but we can
never take out the feeding once we've
put it in so don't burn the plants wait
for them to show you that they are happy
or that they're angry and adjust from
there
most of these nutrient companies offer a
fairly balanced diet within their own
product line you shouldn't have to reach
out to another brand or another company
and fill in anything that they are
missing if you do choose to mix nutrient
lines be very careful that you don't
double up on anything when nutrient
company a made their product lines they
made 5 bottles and they put the base
notes in one they put the cal mag in the
other they put the humic acid in another
and a bloom booster in another they know
what is in each bottle and they can
recommend your feeding because they know
they're not going to overdose anything
with their design when you introduce a
product from another company you run the
risk of doubling up on specific
nutrients nutrient company a and
nutrient company B did not talk to each
other about their designs so you may be
running a base product from nutrient
company a then you may have a bloom
booster from nutrient company B those
companies didn't talk company a was
putting cal-mag inside their base
nutrient to help you out and save you
with the bottle company B was putting
the Cal mag inside the bloom boosters to
help you out and save a bottle and you
didn't know that so now you just spent
two doses of Cal mag because you
combined nutrient companies and didn't
read the bottles so if you choose to use
products from two different companies be
sure not to overlap with any nutrients
if you know what's in each product and
you understand how the plants use each
of those products and you're not going
to cause any problems there is nothing
wrong with combining nutrient companies
if you feel like the brand you were
using is lacking something
feel free to purchase another product
from another company and add that into
your mix as long as you don't double up
any specific elements a good example of
what I'm talking about is in a
commercial environment I like to run veg
bloom powder nutrients in my opinion veg
bloom could use a little bit of fulvic
acid added to the mix in my opinion veg
bloom can use a little bit of
carbohydrates add it to the mix later in
Flour so I am comfortable adding those
products and I've done my research I
know how much carbs I know how much
fulvic acid is in my starting product so
I know that I'm not going to overdose my
plants alright I'm confident that we
understand the environment I'm confident
that we understand what to feed the
plants let's talk about some more
techniques to do at the very start of
flower if you are using sprayed
pesticide applications now is a great
time to apply a pesticide application we
are running out of time
for sprays we are going to start
developing bud sites very soon so we
need to treat these plants today let's
apply a preventive product to our plants
to ensure we do not get any pests in our
veg cycle if you are not going to use
spray pesticide applications now is a
good time to release your beneficial
insects we want to get them colonized
and built up in the grow before other
insects have an opportunity to take hold
in our flowering garden once the plants
are flowering we don't have a lot of
options for pest control so let's do
everything we can now to prevent a pest
infestation while we have big chunky
buds so I would treat for pests at this
time spray pesticides if that is your
approach another thing I like to do on
day one a flower is trellis my plants in
a commercial environment I am NOT able
to move my veg plants into a room and
trellis them I have a veg room and I
have flowering rooms the flowering rooms
are constantly flowering so I can't veg
in that room so I moved the plant into
the flowering area and I put the trellis
up on day one and I bend and pop and
work those plants into the net on day
one this gives them plenty of time to
recover from the stress of getting beat
up while they transition to the
flowering phase we've got about seven to
ten days where they're just
transitioning there won't be anybody
won't be any major activity
so if we beat them up on day one we've
got plenty of time to recover so I like
to get in there and get them under the
trellis I also do popping and twisting
which is also known as super cropping
I've talked about this in depth in other
episodes but I'll give you a quick
rundown I start at the very bottom stalk
of the plant where it comes out of the
dirt
I grab the base of the stalk with my
left hand I put my right hand above that
and I grab the stock and I twist my
right hand counterclockwise you'll hear
a pop sounds kind of like a knuckle
popping I pop my knuckle into the
microphone I don't know if it picked up
you'll hear a little pop sound that is
the sound you're looking for you just
want to break the cellulose structure of
that plant so I'll break it once then
I'll move my left hand from the bottom
right up above my right hand and I'll
give it another break then I'll move up
and give it another break I work my way
up the main stem all the way until it
gets real thin and I feel like I could
cause problems by snapping it up there
once I've done the main stalk I go back
down to the bottom of the plant and I
find the lowest branch and I work that
branch all the way up then I work every
single branch on every single plant this
takes hours in a commercial environment
your hands will be sore but the plants
will thank you for it in the future
right now they look like they got
twisted they got a little bit beat up
but in a few days all of those twists
will create what looks like a knuckle it
will make the plant more robust it will
make it stronger it will give it more
strength I feel like those thicker
stalks can move more nutrients which
makes a more productive plant I feel
like a bigger stock and hold up a bigger
bud so we're working those plants to be
more robust by cracking them they heal
themselves and they become stronger so I
like to do popping and twisting at this
time I also like to do a nice
defoliation on day one of flower take
out all that excess leaf we don't need
it while I'm there I like to clean up
the bottoms quite a bit take off some of
the crappy bottom branches take off some
of those sucker branches take off all
the bottom leaves we don't need a lot of
that crap on the bottom of our plants
some people like to wait a little bit
later closer to week two to do the
bottoming and the wall-e popping I like
to do it early in a commercial
environment things will get ahead of you
so if you don't start it right away it
gets really easy to fall behind very
quickly and in a commercial environment
that only compounds so on day one I move
the
into the flower room I set up the
trellis I give the plants a nice pop and
twist and work them into the trellis
I'll do some defoliating I like to do a
bunch of bottoming and Lolly popping and
then right before we leave for the night
we give the plants a nice pesticide
spray another important thing to think
about at this transitional time is bulbs
what kind of bulbs are you going to use
for flowering I usually recommend a
metal halide for vegging and a
high-pressure sodium for flowering
lighting technology has advanced so far
in recent years but you may be using
LEDs you may be using ceramic metal
halides there are tons of options but
consider changing your spectrum early in
the flowering phase one useful trick I
have learned to help reduce their early
flower stretch is to leave the metal
halide bulbs in for the first two weeks
of flowering a lot of people will swap
out the metal halides for the high
pressure sodium Zonday one of flowering
I have learned that if you leave those
howards in there for two weeks your
plants will not stretch as ridiculously
when you initiate flower that is natural
for plants to stretch they just want to
take off but cracking them popping them
twisting them and keeping in that metal
halide will drastically slow down that
stretch all right podcast rolled I feel
like we have a good solid foundation on
transitioning our plants from veg to
flower at this point if you are growing
from seeds you will need to keep a close
eye on the plants and look out for males
you will need to look out for
hermaphrodites and you will need to pay
attention for mutants if you've got a
plant in there doing some weird [ __ ] you
need to decide if you want to keep it or
let it finish sometimes those mutant
plants put off amazing products they are
also a pain in the ass to grow and they
are problematic so sometimes it's not
even worth it
so if you've got a mutant it is up to
you to decide what to do another thing
we need to stay on top of is scouting
for insects yes we did just apply some
pesticides we may have released some
predator bugs but that does not mean
that we are bulletproof always be
scouting for pasts every day as you walk
through the grow just to go from one end
to the other to go get the scissors you
forgot down there or to go find the
broom just glance at the plants as you
walk by that is when I make the most
random discoveries I'm not even looking
for something I was just walking by and
I said what the hell is that out of the
corner of my eye now I know there's a
problem
now we can solve it always be paying
attention always be scouting for bugs
and problems in the grow keep your eyes
open
we need to look for hermaphrodites we
need to look for males we need to look
for mutants and we need to pay close
attention for signs of pests
all right podcast world I can feel the
cold medicine that I took starting to
kick in my face is going numb my nose is
starting to run kind of weird I need to
wrap up this podcast before I get too
lit to be on a microphone I want to
thank everybody for listening to the
grow lessons if you feel like this show
is educational informative or
entertaining and you would like to make
a financial contribution to the show you
can do so by going to patreon.com slash
grow from your heart all the information
you need to become a patron will be
right there on the screen and I would
appreciate your support I would also
appreciate it if you follow me on all of
the social media you can find me on
Facebook simply search for the girl from
your heart podcast you can follow the
show on Twitter it's at G fyh podcast
and if you want to follow my personal
Twitter account it's at Rasta Jeff 420
if you've got something you'd like to
say and you're not into all the social
media you can reach me through email my
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I would love to hear from
you if you'd like to advertise on the
show or if you've got a product you'd
like me to review simply reach out I
would love to connect with you and get
your product on the show don't forget
the shows available on iTunes stitcher
Google Play and on YouTube I would
appreciate it if you subscribe to the
show on YouTube and leave some comments
on the videos I'll be back Thursday with
a fresh new episode I want to give a
huge shout out to my friend hash masta
and until next time take a phat dad and
give your mom a hug for me
welcome to the show everybody it's time
for episode 380 of the girl from your
heart podcast this episode is brought to
you by the hell a dank seed company if
you need new seeds in your garden I
highly recommend the hell a dank seed
company and you can find them at
www.sedar.com i letting you know what
i'm smoking today I've been taking dabs
of Starr dog ambrosia from our friends
at apothecary the label says 64.7% THC
and a total of seventy six point four
total cannabinoids I always love star
dog it is one of my favorite strains to
grow it's one of my favorite strains to
take photos of it is always one of my
favorite strains to smoke I love the
aroma I love the flavor and I always
love that nice head buzz from the star
dog so today I'm taking dabs of star dog
I feel like that will make for a great
podcast this episode is going to be
another grow lesson if you've been
following along you know I've been doing
a long series of grow lessons we started
by setting a goal for our garden we
found a right place for our garden we
selected and purchased the appropriate
equipment at this point in the grow we
are past week one a flower and we are
entering week two of the flowering phase
this episode will highlight weeks two
and three or days eight through twenty
one of the flowering phase if you feel
like you need a better foundation and
you haven't been listening to the show I
recommend you head back to episode 351
and start on the grow lessons in episode
351 if you've been following along and
you feel like you're up to speed let's
jump right into a grow lesson in this
episode we're going to focus on weeks
two and three of the flowering phase
also known as days 8 through 21 before
we get there let's recap a little bit of
the previous episode in the last episode
we changed our timer to 12 hours on and
12 hours off to initiate flower we are
now seven days into the flowering phase
hopefully at this point you have not
over fertilized or ran into any pH
issues with your garden hopefully at
this point you have not interrupted the
dark cycle at all interrupting that dark
cycle will disrupt the flowering phase
and throw your plants into shock and
possibly cause hermaphrodites hopefully
the garden has remained pests and
pathogens free so if everything is on
the right track
let's move in to week 2 or day 8 of the
flowering phase at this stage of the
flowering process we're not going to
notice much change from the vegetative
cycle you may notice a little bit of
stretch the plants may have taken off
they're starting to get a little bit
taller on you some of your plants may be
showing pre flower some of your plants
may start indicating sex around this
time don't stress if they are not
showing you sex yet we still have plenty
of time but the main thing you're going
to see at this point is stretch those
plants are starting to grow taller that
is okay that's exactly what we're
expecting for the first three weeks we
are going to see a lot of stretching
happening to these plants now we will
probably start seeing pre flower and bud
sets starting to develop around day ten
or twelve we will definitely have little
dandelion looking bud sets popping up
around day 14 so things are about to
start getting very exciting in our
garden now let's talk about the
environment and conditions in our grow
room during weeks two and three of the
flowering phase at this stage of
flowering during the day I try to aim
between 70 and 80 degrees Fahrenheit for
my daytime temperature I also aim for
forty to fifty percent relative humidity
for my daytime temperature now let's
talk about nighttime temperatures in the
night time I like to have my temperature
between 60 and 70 degrees Fahrenheit
I also aim for 40 to 50% humidity during
my nighttime cycle at this stage of
flowering now I want to remind you try
not to have more than a 10 degree
temperature difference in your day and
nighttime cycle that is called your
diurnal temperature variation try to
keep that less than 10 degrees too much
of a drastic swing from day to night
temperature will start causing your
plants to grow slowly they will get
stagnant they will slow down it will not
be happy also this will encourage
powdery mildew so let's aim to keep that
temperature within 10 degrees from the
day and night cycles something we should
add into our flower room that I've been
overlooking on previous episodes is more
fans we need more airflow as we are
entering the flowering stage we are
going to develop big fat chunky buds
we need more airflow once we have those
buds in the room we're going to have a
lot of moisture we're gonna have big fat
chunky
those buds will act like a sponge if
there is too much moisture so we need to
blow some air around the room and keep
that moisture moving I feel like a
little bit of wind and airflow is really
good for the plants it makes them active
I feel like some wind and a little bit
of pressure makes the stalks more robust
it makes them want to stand up on their
own a little better imagine if I shove
you a little bit you would spread your
feet for a little more balance I think a
little bit of wind it makes the plants
want to spread their feet for a little
bit more balance so add a little bit of
wind and airflow to the garden don't go
crazy we don't need a wind tunnel and
there we're not trying to dry out the
plants we just want the air moving if
some of your leaves start looking dry
and leathery and kind of potato-chip
like they're probably getting beat up by
that fan too much you were ruining the
VPD around those leaves in that
condition just reduce the wind just a
little bit but it's never a bad idea to
have some airflow in your grow if you
notice your grow room is consistently
too humid it may be time to invest in a
dehumidifier or maybe a larger
dehumidifier or possibly add some sort
of extraction fan to remove that humid
air from the room and replace it with
fresh air if you do add an extraction
fan keep in mind that as the air gets
sucked out of the room it is also going
to try to draw air into the room through
every open opportunity most of the time
you're going to get air pulled into the
room underneath the door most of us
don't seal the bottom of the door well
enough I feel like that is a great place
for fresh air to come in as long as the
air coming in is clean if that air is
coming from within your house it is
probably safe if that crack leads to
outside I would cover that up and find a
safer source for the air that's just
going to bring in bugs it's going to
bring in whatever is by that door if
it's powdery mildew if it's just dirt
and dust it's going to suck all of that
right under the door into your grow room
so as soon as you cut a hole for an
extraction fan start thinking about
where the air is going to come in when
you start blowing that air out if you
cut a hole in a wall and add an
extraction fan and blow that air out of
the room it may create a whistling noise
underneath the door from all the air
flowing underneath that door if it
creates a big whistling noise you may
need to add a passive hole for air to go
into the room this just depends on the
size of the extraction fan that you set
up if you put a little 4-inch extraction
fan you
definitely pull enough air under the
door you don't need to make any passive
holes if you go setting up an 8-inch
vortex fan in there and you just blow an
air out of that room first of all I
recommend a carbon filter on that
extraction fan that's going out you need
to filter that air but also you may need
to make about a 4-inch hole to allow air
to get into that room somehow you are
sucking all of the air out you need to
allow fresh air in cutting holes in
walls and adding extraction fans can
lead to a lot of problems think about
this very carefully before you go this
route also if you're using co2 you may
want to think about this option because
then you're going to fill the room with
co2 and then you're just gonna use that
exhaust fan to suck the co2 right out of
the room you're kind of blowing your
expensive gas right out the window
literally I've kind of opened up the
conversation for negative pressure
versus positive pressure in a grow room
environment but I feel like that is a
lesson for the future I will write a
note and we will talk about that in a
future episode let's get a little bit
more on track with this grow lesson and
focus let's talk a little bit about the
nutrients we may need at this phase of
the flowering cycle during this part of
flowering we are mainly focusing on a
smooth transition from the vegetative
stage to the flowering phase at this
point in flowering we are mainly
focusing on a smooth transition from the
veg stage to the flowering stage of our
plant cycle week 2 is very similar to
week 1 we will mainly focus on our NPK
we need a low nitrogen high phosphorous
high potassium diet at this stage I said
earlier abandon the veg bottle and start
using the bloom bottle also we need
cal-mag at this stage we also need
potassium silicates in my opinion I also
like to add a Maiko product some sort of
root product is always good at this
stage also enzymes and carbs are great
for week 2 as we work toward week 3 I
like to increase my carbohydrates the
plants are getting bud set at this point
they're going to start taking off I like
having some sugars in there to feed the
microbes and then I like having the
carbs and the sugars in there to give
the plants energy that will encourage
rapid growth so at the beginning of week
3 I will start increasing my
carbohydrate feeding just a little
bit and it will slowly increase that
through the flowering phase now we don't
need to add a bloom booster yet we are
not quite there yet
so let's just focus on getting these
plants through the stretch phase and get
the bud sites developed and then when we
work on the next lesson we will start
adding bloom boosters now we are rapidly
running out of time for pesticide
applications we need to do a very
thorough pest scouting and see what
we've got in the grove we may have
thrips we may have spider mites we could
have fungus gnats we could have white
flies there could be a myriad of
problems popping up at this point in the
grow let's do an inspection and find out
what we're dealing with if you find any
pests now is one of your last times to
apply a sprayed pesticide I don't like
to spray anything after day 14 if you've
got an obvious problem we may extend
that just a few days with very specific
products but I really don't like to
spray anything past day 14 so let's do a
quick scouting let's identify any
problems we may have and let's spray
before day 14 approaches at this point
we're at day 8 so we can get two or
three solid pesticide spray applications
in if they are required if you don't
identify any pests I may still suggest a
preventative spray around day 14 just to
make sure nothing pops up now is the
time to get in there and identify pests
and work really hard at getting rid of
them before we move deeper into the
flowering phase and we really limit
ourselves on pesticide applications this
is also a good time to start ordering
your predator bugs if you are going to
use biologicals as your pesticide
treatment if you plan on using
biologicals think about your spray
applications and use a strategy that
will not cause harm to your beneficials
when they do arrive there are pesticides
that you can apply to your plants today
and you can release beneficial insects
tomorrow and they will work together if
you apply the proper pesticide you will
not kill your beneficials you will have
to do some research on the pesticide and
the beneficials and see if they get
along some of the pesticides are based
on pyrethrum some of them are based on
neem some of them are beneficial
and bacteria those beneficial fungus and
bacteria may not kill or disrupt your
predator bugs but it will make the
environment uncomfortable for the spider
mites because they intend to eat those
leaves the Predators are going to eat
the spider mites not the leaves so they
may be able to survive with certain
pesticides it's your responsibility as
the grower to do the research on the
pesticide you're going to apply and also
do research on the predator bugs which
you plan to use in your integrated pest
management strategy and find out if they
can work together some of the newer
pesticide and fungicide products
actually advertise safe for beneficials
or well not harm beneficials that is
saying that they recommend that product
in a garden that is also using
beneficial insects as a form of pest
management so let's get on top of pest
management let's do some scouting and if
you see anything now is the time to work
on getting rid of that before we get
deeper into flower now while you're
scouting for pests that is a great time
to keep an eye out for male plants if
you are growing from seed you've got the
opportunity to find males in your garden
you have also got the opportunity to
find hermaphrodites in the garden and
you may also find some mutants in your
flowering room the male plants are going
to start popping up around day ten they
usually open up and start dropping
pollen right around day 14 so we've got
a very small window of time to discover
these males and get them out of the room
before they cause problems don't be lazy
when it comes to pooling males out of
your garden if you've got a small garden
if you've got a large garden you need to
look at every single plant and pull
every single male out of that grow you
also need to pay very close attention
for hermaphrodites when you're checking
for males and hermaphrodites on new
plants check in several spots on each
plant the top may not reveal
hermaphrodite traits down lower we're
not getting a lot of light penetration
those plants may show intersex traits
you may get male flowers popping up in
your female buds lower on the plant pay
close attention to the entire plant I
feel like I gave a pretty good
description of what a male plant looks
like and what a female plant looks like
on a previous podcast but I do encourage
you to google male
and female cannabis plants and see what
they look like before the time comes
that way when you've got a boy in the
garden you are sure and you've got
confidence and you can remove that male
plant from your garden confidently and
know you are not going to cause any
problems you want to find the boys
before the pollen sacks start opening
let's talk about what happens if you
find a boy and one of those sacks is
starting to open the first thing I would
do is spray it with water water
deactivates pollen spray that pollen
with water you'll shut it down also
spray the girls with water if you've got
clean water around just spray some water
on the plants yes I said we don't want
to spray plants that are in flower
I'd rather get them a little bit wet at
this point then I would rather get
pollen on them also this is just water
there's no pesticide in here the plants
would get hit with rain it would get hit
with Dew this is going to be just fine
spray them with some water that will
deactivate the pollen it will also make
the plants unable to receive the pollen
at that point you can either cut down
that male plant or you can slide up
trash bag right over it like a condom
then cut it then get it out of the room
is try not to spread that pollen I know
we've sprayed it with water but as you
bump it around it's gonna open up more
pollens gonna come out do your best not
to spread that stuff it was water put
the trash bag over it either take the
whole plant including the dirt out of
the grow or cut it at the base and just
get that plant out of there as soon as
possible
leaving a male plant in the grow room
for too long will result in a seeded
crop most of us are aiming for a
seedless crop if you were growing a crop
for a commercial reason and you're
trying to put it out on the black market
a couple of seeds will ruin the value of
your entire crop so don't be lazy keep
your eye out for males know what males
look like and get them out of the garden
also keep an eye out for hermaphrodites
and get them out of the garden once we
are past weeks two and three you cannot
get lazy if you're growing from seed
just because they look like females
you've still got the opportunity for a
hermaphrodite to pop up all the way
through the flowering cycle it may not
show itself until week nine it may not
show itself until week ten but you need
to see it if it does happen I've said
earlier if it pops up late in flower it
may not be a big deal it is too late for
the plants to receive pollen they won't
any seeds that lead into flower and most
of the time if they throw a male flower
past week seven or eight
they're usually sterile male flowers
that will not contain any pollen so
there's not much to worry about but if
you're getting hermaphrodites early in
flower they must be removed from the
garden all right we've got our
environment dialed in we know what to
feed our plants we are scouting for
pests we have applied our final
pesticide application we have considered
releasing predator mites we know how to
look for males and hermaphrodites we are
on the look for trouble we're looking
for bugs we're looking for males we're
looking for Herms now let's talk about a
few things we can do to improve the
quality of our garden this early in the
flowering phase if you're running a
trellis or a sprog net now is a good
time to continue working those buds into
the net you can still work those
branches into the net I would stop doing
it probably toward the end of week three
but you've still got time if you've got
a branch that's popping up too high feel
free to give it a little crack bend it
down under the net and work it into the
canopy we can keep working on a nice
even canopy all the way through the end
of week three so let's keep popping them
let's keep twisting them and working
them into the canopy let's talk a little
bit about popping and twisting I've
talked a lot about popping and twisting
in the beginning of flower I continue to
do this all the way through weeks four
and five I will pop every stem right at
the beginning of flower give it about
two weeks to heal up and go back and do
it again give it about two weeks to heal
up and go back and do it again so grab
the base of the stock grab it with your
other hand and twist your top hand and
as you twist you'll hear a little pop
that's exactly what you're looking for
as that heals it will create a knuckle
that knuckle will make a strong spot in
the plant I like to do that tour the
entire plant is covered in knuckles it
looks really knurled and I feel like
that that plant is very productive it's
got a nice thick stalk that can hold a
lot of weight it can hold fat buds it's
also got nice thick stalks that can move
a lot of water which can carry a lot of
nutrients so I feel like it is a very
beneficial thing to crack all of the
stems so continue working your plants
into the trellis if you're using a
trellis continue cracking and popping
the sticks to make robust plants I also
like to do a bit of lolly
popping if you've got some crappy
branches on the bottom of the plant
feel free to remove them if you've got
branches that come off the very bottom
of the plant and reach up for the top
and those top branches the tops have
potential to create good usable buds you
can clean up the bottom suckers off of
that long branch and keep that arm and
grow but at the end of the arm and take
off all that little crap at the bottom
of it that you don't need it is very
common to see plants that are three and
four feet tall that are completely naked
for the first 18 inches of the very
bottom it's just a bunch of sticks
coming out of the pot you don't have any
foliage you don't have any little
branches you don't have any tiny bud
sites for 18 inches to maybe even two
feet off the ground depending on the
growers environment and the growers
style and what type of lights they are
using so feel free to get in there and
cut out any shitty branches that aren't
going to be productive and feel free to
clean up all that stuff real down low on
the plant that's not going to get any
light when harvest time comes we're
going to have to trim everything we cut
down if you cut all that little fluffy
crap off the plant you don't have to
trim it now you're saying yeah I could
have used that for concentrates or
something right if you cut it all off
the bottom we can move that energy right
up to the top of the plant instead of
growing that crappy little fluff at the
bottom we just basically moved that up
to that top Cola to make all those top
buds just that much heavier that much
fatter that much more density so clean
up any crap on the bottom that may be
slowing your plants down and move that
energy right up to the top now another
thing I find advantageous is defoliation
there's a lot of debate in the cannabis
industry about how to do foliate what
level to do foliate and when to
defoliate I like to do kind of a hard
defoliation right at the start of flower
if there is a large leaf shadowing
another branch or shadowing another bud
site I will remove that leaf without
question then I'll go through the grow
and anything with a purple pee daeul
gets removed at the very start of flower
I do this in a commercial environment
for several reasons removing all of
those extra leaves removes opportunity
there are less places for pests to hide
and there are less places for pathogens
to hang out so remove the opportunities
also a root
uses humidity in the room without as
many leaves doing as much transpiration
and respiration there's a little bit
less moisture in the room so it makes it
easier to balance the humidity in the
room I also think a well-timed
well-executed defoliation will increase
the vigor of our plants now a lot of
people will say you don't want to pull
off the leaves because that's where the
sugars are stored and they're going to
use that for nutrients and energy but we
are feeding the [ __ ] out of these plants
they don't need to use anything that is
stored we are pouring expensive
nutrients into these plants on a daily
basis don't worry about the stuff stored
in those leaves we're gonna replace that
right away another argument to the
defoliation is that those leaves are
used as solar panels and they need to be
there yes they do but there is a point
where sometimes a leaf is blocking a bud
site where if you remove that leaf it
would be more beneficial to put the
light closer to the bud then on that big
ol solar leaf so selectively remove your
leaves if you're new at defoliating go
in and just tear off a few leaves and
see how the plants react then the next
time take off a few more and see how the
plants react this will be very strain
dependent sativa leaning strains won't
react as well as indica leaning strains
will react to heavy defoliation another
thing I'll recommend is leave those two
leaves at the top of the bud you'll have
one bud your main top sticking up then
at the top of that there are two leaves
sticking out when you look in the grow
room you'll see the two leaves I'm
talking about I like to leave those on
every plant those two mains that are
sticking out of the top of the main bud
I'd like to leave those until late in
flower but quite often those will be the
only large leaves I leave on every plant
so I recommend a semi heavy defoliation
here at the beginning of flower then
we'll do it again around a week four and
we'll do it again
around week six defoliating and cracking
and twisting and working into trellis
work is kind of an art you will have to
get good at this over time which will
require confidence so don't be scared
just get in there and learn how to do it
you are going to make mistakes I have
made countless mistakes
in my own Gro I've made mistakes and
commercial grows I have made tiny
mistakes and I have made huge mistakes
but you know what that's how I became a
good grower experience includes mistakes
don't be afraid to make mistakes this is
not the last crop you are going to grow
this is a practice crop the next one
will be your pro crop don't act like
these plants are the last plants are
ever going to get to touch this is your
first time this is your second time have
some confidence build some confidence
let's just get in there and break some
[ __ ] and ruin some [ __ ] so that you can
see what can go wrong then the next row
will be really easy so don't be afraid
to wreak some [ __ ] don't be afraid
because some problems that's how you
learn things if every grow goes smoothly
for you you're going to think growing is
easy and you're not gonna learn anything
then your egos gonna get in the way and
that's when you're really gonna run into
problems and then you will have no idea
how to solve them so my point is don't
be scared just get in there and play
with the plants you may kill one you may
kill two but you will learn what they
can take these plants are way more
resilient than you would imagine if this
is your first grow if this is your
second grow you're probably touching
those plants like there are delicate
little babies when you see me in a
commercial environment you're going to
think I am an abusive odor to these
plants but then at the end you will see
the highest quality most beautiful buds
come out of these plants that I kind of
beat up through their whole life I
really care for the plants I really have
a passion for the garden sometimes I'm
going really fast
and I don't have time for [ __ ] and I
need to get a lot of stuff done in a
small amount of time and sometimes I get
a little rough and sometimes it looks
like I'm being aggressive and I am but
at the end of the day the plants show me
that they were satisfied with what I did
these plants are used to being outside
growing on a hill these plants are used
to being stuck in one place and can't
walk away when [ __ ] gets weird they've
been in the wind they've been in the
rain they've been beat up by Nature some
of them probably got peed on by a goat
cannabis plants are amazingly resilient
plants and they can take some abuse
so let's abuse them let's beat them up a
little bit and see what they can take
because I think when we push them to
their limits that's when we see their
full potential so don't be afraid to get
in there and
break some [ __ ] you guys this is not
going to be your last crop I understand
that seeds and clones are very expensive
and that this crop means a lot to you
but if you can take one plant and
dedicate it to experiments you can learn
a whole lot from that one plant and
still produce a very viable crop so if
you're new and defoliation if you're new
at popping and twisting if you're new at
cracking the stems maybe just pick one
plant defoliate the crap out of one
plant and then don't do the others and
pay attention to what happens something
very important to note here take a lot
of notes when you're doing experiments
like this write down what you did to
plant a write down what you did to plant
B and then take great notes of the
outcome that is a great way to have
documentation to find out if the
techniques and methods you were using
work for your garden and work for you
and work for the specific strain which
you are growing I've said it before but
most of us growers are also consumers
which means sometimes we may forget some
details write some [ __ ] down and you
will not forget that way when the end
comes and plant B is way better than
plant a you know exactly what you did to
make plant B stand out from the crowd
then we can repeat that then we can
improve upon that and have a better
garden each and every time so feel free
to experiment with one or two plants in
the garden until you develop confidence
and while you're experimenting make sure
to take notes now the next thing I want
to talk about before we start wrapping
up the show is bulbs and lighting as we
approach the third week of flower it is
time to remove our metal halide bulb and
start using the high-pressure sodium
bulb if you're using an LED it's time to
switch from the blue to the more red
spectrum if that is an option I like to
leave my veg bulbs in for the first
couple of weeks of flower because I find
it helps reduce the stretch for the
first 21 days of flower our plants are
going to take off and stretch extremely
fast they're going to get really tall
proper nutrients will help reduce the
stretch the right amount of phosphorus
and potassium or reduce the stretch also
I feel like keeping in the blue light
the metal halide light for the first two
weeks of flower will really help keep
the
plants short and squat and bushy now we
are approaching the end of the stretch
phase it is time to swap out that blue
bulb for the yellow orange reddish bulb
which would be the high-pressure sodium
so if you have not already changed out
your bulb or hit the switch on your led
to change into the flowering mode now is
the time to swap out those bulbs or hit
that switch I wouldn't wait any later
than day 21 to change my flowering
spectrum any later than that we start
hitting a point of diminishing returns
we do reduce the stretch but we also
reduce the bulking when it comes time to
develop buds
all right podcast rolled I feel like we
are caught up on weeks 2 &amp; 3 we've got
our nutrients covered we've got our
environment dialed in we've added a fan
we have applied our final pesticide
applications we have released our
predators if we're going to do so we're
going to continue popping the stems
we're gonna continue working the tall
plants into the trellis we're going to
keep deep foliated hopefully you have
selected a plant to do some experiments
on and you are taking good notes we are
well into the flowering cycle we do need
to continue keeping our eyes open for
males and hermaphrodites and mutants as
well as pests and pathogens hopefully we
haven't made any nutrient mistakes
hopefully we haven't had any pH issues
if we haven't had any light leaks we're
developing bud set it looks like
dandelions forming on the tips of all of
our plants hopefully we have removed all
of the males from the room we're still
keeping an eye out for males and
hermaphrodites and mutants now as long
as we don't run into any equipment
failures or human errors we are well on
our way to a great harvest
all right podcast world I feel like that
is a great spot to wrap up this lesson
on weeks two and three or days eight
through 21 of the flowering phase I want
to thank you for listening to this grow
lesson if you feel like this lesson was
educational informative or entertaining
and you would like to make a financial
contribution to the podcast you can do
so by visiting patreon.com slash grow
from your heart all the information you
need to become a patron will be right
there on the screen and I do truly
appreciate all of your support I would
also appreciate it if you find me on
social media you can find me on Facebook
search for the girl from your heart
Podcast you can find me on twitter its
@gf wih podcast if you'd like to follow
my personal twitter account it's at
Rasta Jeff 420 I also encourage you to
follow my Instagram page on Instagram I
use Irie underscore genetics I RIE
underscore genetics on Instagram check
out my fine cannabis photography I would
also appreciate it if you find me on
YouTube just go to youtube and search
for the girl from your heart podcast
click subscribe leave some comments on
the videos I sure do love the
interaction there podcaster old I am NOT
going to put out an episode on Thursday
it is the holiday season I plan to spend
some time with some friends and some
family I hope you do the same I'll be
back Monday with a fresh new episode I
look forward to joining you then I want
to give you a huge shout outs my friend
mangled remains and until next time take
a phat dad and give your mom a hug for
me welcome to the show everybody it's
time for episode 383 of the grow from
your heart podcast this episode is
brought to you by our friends at the
hella dank seed company if you need new
seeds in your garden I highly recommend
the hell a dank seed company and you can
find them at www.sedar.com by letting
you know what I'm smoking today I've
been taking dabs of goat power from
apothecary farms I picked this up at
their Pueblo medical location big
shout-out to our friends at apothecary
the potency label on this concentrate
says it is seventy four point eight
percent THC and eighty six point four
percent total cannabinoids this stuff
smells delicious if you have ever
smelled or smoked a golden goat this is
exactly what golden goat smells like to
me I'm giving it a fresh smell so I can
give you a fair description it's got a
hint of citrus not overpowering citrus
but it does have a citrus base to it
with a tropical pineapple and a juicy
fruit gum sort of aroma on top of it -
that stickiness that a juicy fruit
piece of gum would have I know it's
weird to say something smells sticky I
think that stickiness is part of the
flavor and aroma of the gum it doesn't
have that it's got that tropical
sweetness it's got some citrus it's got
a hint of pineapple mostly a citrus and
tropical fruit sort of a thing going on
I would really describe it as a orange
pineapple tropical fruit Jolly Rancher
would probably be the most a cure
description that I could nail it down -
so that's the aroma and flavor it has
got a beautiful golden color to it it's
got just the right amount of diamonds
just the right amount of sauce in there
beautiful beautiful goat power from our
friends at apothecary farms and
obviously it has got me amped up and
ready to talk my face off so this should
be a great podcast if you've been
following along you know I've been doing
a long series of in-depth grow lessons
in episode 351 we talked about setting a
goal for the garden then we talked about
picking a space for the garden then we
talked about the appropriate equipment
and setting up the grow safely and
effectively then we work our way through
getting clones and starting to grow at
this point we are all the way to week
four of the grow in this episode we're
going to talk about weeks four five and
six if you're a new grower or if you're
new to the podcast I suggest you head
back to episode 351 and start with the
Dro lessons there if you are an
experienced grower or if you feel like
you were up to speed or if you've been
following along let's jump right into a
grow lesson in this lesson we are going
to focus on episodes four five and six
of the flowering phase at this point of
flowering it should be obvious where the
bud sites are going to be you should
have little buds popping up they should
look like little dandelions they're
starting to actually form into buds by
now it should be clearly obvious where
the buds are it should also be more than
obvious which plants are males and
females all of the males better be gone
by now or you have pollinated everything
and you're going to have a seeded crop
so all of the males are gone at this
point at this point your buds are
starting to form you're seeing little
pistol hairy covered buds you're
starting to get minimal bud mass at this
point we are also coming out of that
rapid stretch phase for the first three
weeks of flowering our plants really
like to stretch and take off that is
pretty much over our plants are still
going to get taller hopefully that top
bud grows gigantic but that rapid
stretch phase is over we don't have to
worry so much about the plants just
taking off on us anymore they're going
to stop stretching and they're going to
start focusing their energy more on
developing the fat chunky buds we want
now at this point if you don't have a
carbon filter it is really time to get a
carbon filter in your grow room if
you've got any air exit
the grow going outside that the
neighbors may smell you need a carbon
filter by now things are going to start
getting really aromatic from here on out
it is only going to get worse so keep
your odor under control I've said it
before a very common way for your garden
to be discovered is for the aroma to be
noticed by a neighbor the neighbors call
the police the police driver on the
block they narrow it down they knock on
your door by the time they hit the front
porch they can smell it they know it's
you they come knock on the door if you
are in a legal state they want to count
your plants it's still a pain in the ass
you've got law enforcement in the house
in the Gros it's stressful if you are in
a non legal area if whoever shows up at
your front door feels that they have got
probable cause to come into your house
they can come they can discover your
grow you may be handy with the laws you
may speak well you may know how to keep
them out of the house for now but if the
aroma was strong enough if their
suspicion was strong enough they're
going to contact the judge they will
have a warrant and in several days it
will be back they'll pull off the front
door it will come in armed it will be
scary as [ __ ] it will destroy your
entire garden and ask questions later so
now is the time to have a carbon filter
always be thinking about safety and
security if you were growing in a legal
or not legal state you probably don't
even notice how pungent your garden is
because you're there every day but the
first time the mailman walks in front of
the house and catches a little whiff
he's going to know exactly what that is
the first time a little bit of aroma
while and hits your neighbor right in
her nose she's going to know exactly
what that aroma is immediately in this
scenario we are only four weeks into
flower and our plants are beginning to
stink it is only going to get worse by
week seven eight and nine it is going to
be pungent as soon as we start
harvesting these plants and trimming the
plants that aroma is going to increase
exponentially don't add that extra
stress to yourself by stinking up the
entire neighborhood with your grow I
understand that buying a carbon filter
and an extraction fan sound like just
another expense to a new grower but I
would much rather invest that money in a
filter and a blower than my lawyer and
bail alright I feel like I've made my
point it is time for a carbon filter if
you don't have one now it is time to
start taking the steps
to get a carbon filter in your garden
all right I feel like that's a good
overview of what's going on in the
garden buds are showing the stretch
phase is over and it is starting to
stink
now let's talk about the environment in
our grow for weeks four five and six
let's start with temperature for a
daytime temperature four weeks four five
and six I would suggest a range of 70 to
80 degrees Fahrenheit now if you can
dial it in a little tighter I would like
to be between 74 and 77 degrees now
during the night I would suggest a
temperature in the range of 60 to 70
degrees if you can dial it in nice and
tight I would recommend 65 to 68 degrees
again I'm going to suggest no more than
a 10 degree difference in your day and
night temperature what that means is if
your day temperature is 77 degrees you
don't want your night temperature any
lower than 67 degrees we don't want to
see any more than a 10 degree diurnal
temperature variation if we allow
drastic temperature drops in the night
cycle we will slow down the plant growth
and we will also encourage powdery
mildew development so again during the
day we want to be between 70 and 80
degrees at night we want to be between
60 and 70 degrees now as time goes on we
are going to want to reduce the
temperature of the grow room later in
Flour we want to make the room a little
bit cooler so if you are struggling to
get the room to 74 at this point maybe
just keep it up there at 78 79 degrees
so that when weeks 8 &amp; 9 come around we
can reduce that temperature down to as
low as you can get it if the lowest you
can get it is 74 let's wait until weeks
8 &amp; 9 to get it there and leave it
around 77 now now I know a lot of people
are going to say why do we want to make
it cooler there are several reasons
think about a plant outside as the
seasons change it gets colder it knows
oh [ __ ] the end of the season is coming
I need to ripen up I need to finish so
that will encourage the plants have
finish it will also encourage beautiful
colors it will also encourage more
terpene production heat and light break
down terpenes so why not make it a
little bit cooler where we can preserve
a little bit more Terps I also feel that
that little bit of coal
old toward the end will increase in
density you will get tighter more dense
buds it also will help reduce humidity
and late in flower we need a little bit
less humidity because we've got those
big chunky buds and we don't want to
develop bud rot in the middle of our
flowers so reducing the temperature
later in flower has many advantages I
understand that not all rooms are set up
to be able to reduce the temperature
late in flower you may be running a
perpetual cycle you just simply may not
have the equipment to get it that cool
in flower it is not a requirement it is
just a little bonus it's a little tip
and trick that may help increase aroma
and color and density and also help you
avoid powdery mildew and boy Titus
toward the end of your flowering phase
so that is why I suggest reducing the
temperature late in flower we will talk
more about that as we move through these
grow lessons now let's talk about
humidity four weeks four five and six
I suggest forty percent relative
humidity we have reduced the humidity by
10 percent from last week we don't need
as much moisture in the air we're
starting to develop buds those buds act
like sponges they will gather all of
that moisture in the air which will lead
to Boyte Rytas which is our worst
nightmare when we get giant buds in a
commercial facility so let's reduce the
humidity let's get it down to about 40
percent now let's talk a little bit
about nutrients for weeks four five and
six I know I don't give detailed
information when I talk about nutrients
in these grow lessons that's because I
don't know what brand of nutrients you
were using I don't know if you're using
bottles I don't know if you're using
powder nutrients I don't know if you're
running organics I have no idea what you
have chosen to do I can't be too
specific with the nutrient suggestions
what I can do is make sure we cover the
bases and I give you a solid foundation
so here are the things I would make sure
to have in my nutrient mix four weeks
four five and six if you were running
bottles you need a basic bloom nutrient
you may have a bottle that says bloom
you may have a bottle that says bloom a
and a bottle that says bloom B those
bottles are what we need for this stage
of flowering you'll notice that those
bottles have three numbers printed on
them that is an
PK value at this stage of flowering we
do not need a lot of nitrogen we just
need a lot of nitrogen to provide energy
to the plants at this stage of flowering
we need more phosphorus and potassium
than we have previously needed in the
grow so you will see a low n number and
higher P and K value numbers on your
bloom nutrient bottles so if you're
growing with bottles hopefully your
bloom base has covered your nitrogen
phosphorus and potassium you will also
need cal-mag at this phase of the game I
also recommend enzymes and microbes I
would also introduce a kelp product to
my feeding regimen I think help has a
lot of great benefits that we will talk
about in a future episode this is also a
great time to start introducing a bloom
booster again I don't know what products
you're using I don't know what brand you
have chosen most bottled nutrients offer
a very obvious bloom booster now is the
time to start implementing that into
your feeding schedule if you really want
to provide energy to your plants you can
feed them a carbohydrate product at this
stage of flowering the carbohydrates
will give the plants energy and the
carbohydrates will also feed your
microbes if you are growing with veg
bloom powdered nutrients I would have
added shine by now I definitely would
put shine in there by week 3 now is
basically the time I start tapering off
the microbe products and start adding in
the bloom booster products the roots
should be big and fat and healthy by the
time the plant is done I want that plant
to be nearly root bound so we are well
on our way to filling that pot with
roots now I want to start focusing on
moving that energy up top and making big
giant buds so through weeks 4 5 &amp; 6 I
start tapering off the microbes and I
start increasing the bloom booster
product now be careful with your bloom
boosters a lot of people want to
overfeed the bloom booster most bottled
nutrient companies have a very clear
suggested dose printed on the bottle
most of the time that is too much they
want you to feed your plants too much so
that you have to buy more of their
product more frequently I would suggest
that a new grower starts off with 50% of
the recommended bloom booster dosage the
first time you add that bloom booster to
your plant feed only put 50% of the
recommended dosage and see how the
plants respond if the plants don't show
any sign of burn or stunted growth maybe
increase the feeding just a little bit
next time and increase it until you see
the leaf tips just barely burn I like to
call it getting their nails done because
it starts to look like the end of the
fingers are just getting their
fingernails on there when you see them
starting to get their nails done that's
when you know you're pushing them to
their limit and they're just starting to
get burned you can either give them that
much again and just keep burning them
just a little bit or you can reduce it a
little bit but do not go any harder with
the bloom booster once you see the
fingernails start happening now it
sounds natural and feels natural to want
to add more bloom booster that's going
to give you bigger fatter buds that's
what everybody wants but there is a
point of diminishing returns if you add
too much it will burn the plants once
the plants begin to burn it will start
to lock out nutrients once they lock out
nutrients they will not take any of your
bloom booster then it all becomes a
waste of money and you have a shitty
harvest so don't be that guy don't over
bloom boost your plants five or six
weeks into flower and completely burn
them and make them look like [ __ ] and
ruin your trop when you've only got
three weeks to go now those are just the
basic nutrients I would recommend if you
are growing from bottled nutrients every
company is going to have other products
to offer some companies may offer a
silicate product some companies may
offer a terpene enhancer some companies
may recommend a bud hardener I'm not
sure what company you have chosen but be
careful when adding your additives and
just pay attention when mixing make sure
that your pH is correct and tried to
make note of your EC or your ppm s if
possible now if you're growing with
organics if you're growing with super
soil you have probably mixed up your
soil at the beginning and there's not a
lot you can do to it at this point other
than adding teas or maybe adding a cover
crop or possibly a top dress to be quite
honest with you that is not my area of
expertise if you are growing organically
and you want to boost up your plants a
little bit I would probably suggest a
compost tea that included worm castings
and it would probably include some sort
of guano but again I am NOT the organic
expert I am NOT the no-till guy I am NOT
a super soil guy I honestly grow in a
commercial environment and I grow from
bottle and powdered nutrients most
of the advice and guidance that I give
you on the show will be based on bottled
or powdered nutrients so I feel like
that covers the basics of nutrients for
weeks four five and six basically we
want to give them a solid NPK a little
bit of cal-mag some enzymes some
microbes some carbs I would introduce
kelp I would introduce a bloom booster
and basically at this point I would
start reducing the microbe product and I
would start replacing the microbes with
a bloom booster product over the next
couple of weeks all right now I feel
like we know what type of environment to
keep these plants in I feel like we know
how to feed them we know what's going on
in the grow now what can we do to these
plants to increase production what can
we do to make sure they stay healthy and
pest free all the way up to the end of
the flowering cycle one thing we need to
keep in mind is that we need to be very
selective on sprays this late in flower
I would prefer not to spray anything at
all on these plants but if we do run
into issues there are very limited
options of products we can use to spray
on these plants so let's do our best at
this point to keep bugs out of the grow
room we should already be implementing
an integrated pest management system
which includes a spray rotation and
possible release of predator bugs
I would also avoid going to other
gardens if you have friends that grow I
would stay away from their grow I would
also never take anybody else into my
grow especially other friends that grow
you are inviting their spider mites
right into your garden also change
clothes if you go to another grow if you
work in a commercial grow and have a
private grow at home change clothes
between those grows I would also
recommend changing clothes between stops
at the grow store and going to your
garden don't go straight from the hydro
shop to your garden you are picking [ __ ]
up at the gross store all day long all
of the dirty growers are going there all
the soil is being shipped there that is
a hotbed for pests
don't take your pests from the gross
store right to your garden I would also
recommend a dedicated pair of shoes for
the garden or for the grow room if you
work in multiple facilities I would have
a pair of shoes for the grow at work
would have a pair of shoes that I wore
after work then I would have a different
pair of shoes that I put on to go in my
personal garden also if you have an
outdoor grow and an indoor grow change
clothes and shoes between those Gardens
it sounds really tedious and it sounds
like overkill but we do not want to
spread spider mites from one Garden to
another the most obvious and easy way
for mites to spread is for them to
travel on a grower so let's do our best
as responsible growers as responsible
farmers to not spread spider mites to
our other grows and to our friends grows
it's pretty easy to get rid of spider
mites early in flower and veg but it is
a pain in the ass to get rid of spider
mites late in bloom so let's not drag
them into the bloom room if you do have
multiple rooms or multiple facilities
and you do find a pest issue in one area
treat that area as a contaminated space
notify everybody that works there hey
there are spider mites in here don't go
in here unless it is required then if
you do have to go in that area make sure
you change clothes before entering
another grow area and carrying those
spider mites throughout the facility
with you if you have one room that is
not infested with mites and you have
another room that is infested with mites
work on the clean room first when you
get to work do all the work that needs
to be done in there close that room up
and be done then go to that spider mite
room do your work in there and then when
you're done leave the growth facility
remove your clothes clean them put them
in the laundry and don't take those
dirty clothes back into that clean room
work on the clean room first
then work on the dirty rooms last so
that we don't drag those spider mites
into the room that is clean and if you
know that one room is contaminated and
you have to go in there I would almost
suggest a lab coat or a Tyvek suit that
you can swap between rooms if you've got
to go into the meited room throw on the
lab coat
throw on the Tyvek suit go into the
spider matted room do what you need to
do come out of that room remove the lab
coat or Tyvek suit replace it with a
fresh lab coat or Tyvek suit and then go
into the room that you need to work in
next again I know this sounds tedious I
know this sounds like overkill but
imagine if you've got 500 plants in one
room and you're expecting to harvest
over a hundred pounds and we distract
spider mites into their from the other
room now we've got one room that is
almost ready to harvest and we've been
fighting spider mites almost gone we're
almost through that battle but guess
what you just walked into the other room
and we're five weeks into flower and you
just dropped a spider mite bomb in there
because you were lazy and didn't bother
to change your lab coat small problems
are small problems when they are small
problems but when we go to a large scale
cultivation facility a very small
problem will multiply overnight those
spider mites are going to have a party
when we turn off the lights and
everybody goes home you will come in the
next morning and now it is spider mite
world so let's do our best to not
introduce spider mites to the grow
because we are very limited on plans of
attack to get rid of those mites in this
point of the game there are very limited
sprays we can apply one thing we can do
we can release predator bugs now if you
were planning ahead part of your
integrated pest management system did
include ordering predator bugs to be
released early in Flour hopefully around
week 3 you released an army of predator
bugs so now if any spider mites do show
up those predators are already colonized
they're already there claiming their
turf and no spider mites will start
infesting your grow now if you didn't
get those predator bugs in there early
it is not too late to order predators to
come attack your spider mite infestation
but you need to act quickly don't say
I'll order them Monday when you see
spider mites in the grow order those
predator mites today when that box of
predator mites comes you need to stop
what you were doing and release those
bugs into the garden immediately we need
to win the war we need to release our
troops to get in there and destroy those
spider mites that are sucking the juices
out of our plants they are destroying
our potency and they are diminishing our
yields we need to get rid of them
immediately so if it's too late to spray
I highly suggest you order predator bugs
order more than you think you need we
want a large army to get in there and
wipe out the infestation as quickly as
possible now earlier I did say we are
very limited on the products we can
spray to our plants this late in Flour
there are a few beneficial fungus based
products that can be applied to the
plants this late in Flour that
will not affect the taste if you
understand the products you were using
you can apply a sprayed pesticide and
you can release predators and they will
work together the proper pesticide at
this stage of the game will not harm
your flowers and it will not kill your
predators again I do not suggest
spraying plants with bulky flowers but
sometimes something has to be done we do
have a few spray application options do
not spray anything oil-based this late
in flower it will ruin the flavor and
aroma of your plants the only things I
would recommend to spray this late in
flower would be beneficial fungus type
products I would never apply an oil this
late in flower and I don't even want to
spray them unless it is absolutely
necessary
I would rather release the Predators and
let them do their thing but I understand
sometimes you're going to go into panic
mode
sometimes it's more than what the
Predators can handle sometimes you may
have already purchased the pesticide and
you don't have funding to order insects
I do understand that things come up in a
garden and life does happen and we can't
always control things one thing we can
do from this situation is take note we
can try to understand how did we get
spider mites and how can we prevent this
from happening next time so it is time
to stop spraying the plants it is also
time to stop running the sulfur burner
if you've got a sulfur burner in your
grow turn that [ __ ] off it is making
your plants taste terrible it is making
your concentrates taste terrible let's
stop using sulfur burners in the grow
and let's start correcting the true
issue what is causing the powdery mildew
people use sulfur to prevent and cure
powdery mildew how about we find to the
cause instead of burning sulfur in the
room and making the room smell like [ __ ]
making your bud smell like [ __ ] making
your concentrate smell like [ __ ] making
the final product completely tastes like
[ __ ] let's find out what's causing that
powdery mildew and cure that instead of
just burning sulfur in the room now I
know a lot of people have a sulphur
burner and that is their method that's
how they learn that's what they're going
to do they're not going to stop doing it
because I said so let's compromise
you insist on using a sulphur burner in
your garden perhaps you can stop using
it around week three or around week four
when those buds start popping up earlier
in the episode I suggested reducing
humidity perhaps reducing that humidity
a little bit will help prevent that
powdery mildew since we're getting the
fat buds we need to reduce humidity
anyway let's get it a little cooler
reduce humidity and stop burning that
sulfur and I'm sure the product will
taste better if you've ever smoked to
concentrate the tasted like fish or fish
oil a lot of the times that is because
there was a sulphur burner being used in
the room during the flowering phase so
no more sprays and no more sulfur
burners after week three please
so now that we are approaching week four
it is time to reduce some of the
physical stress we have been performing
to the plant I still want to do some
popping and twisting and I still want to
work them into the Nets but I don't want
to go as hard and as extreme as I was
before I want to allow these plants to
use their energy on producing buds now
and not recovering from all the popping
and breaking and not being stressed out
I want them to just focus on making fat
chunky buds and sweet trichomes for me
so I'm going to reduce the stress a
little bit that doesn't mean I'm gonna
stop beating them up but I am going to
mellow out just a little bit on these
girls so we're gonna reduce the stress
we're gonna do a little less popping and
twisting but we are still going to pop
and twist the stems we're also going to
continue working these plants into the
trellis if you've got a trellis net and
you've got a plant that's taken off
getting too tall don't be afraid to grab
that one crack the stem and work it
right back under the net the star of
week 4 is also a good time to do our
final bottoming we've got those little
bud sets showing we know where the buds
are gonna be if you've got a stick with
a bunch of little tiny shitty buds on it
just clean those little popcorn balls
right on off and leave that stuff at the
end of the branch to develop into a nice
chunky bud in a previous episode I
talked about taking off all those little
tiny sucker buds you can leave the thick
branches but those little buds that grow
off the base of that branch toward the
bottom those can get cut off if they're
just a waste of space and energy and
they're not going to produce anything
except their pain in the ass you can cut
those right off of the plant some
growers like to say that's what I was
going to make concentrate out of that
I was going to make my edibles out of
that's fine if you want to leave that
there I feel like if you cut that stuff
off that doesn't get a lot of light you
take that energy and you move it right
up to the top of the plant instead of
the plant feeding those twelve little
tiny [ __ ] buds at the bottom it can just
put that energy right up at the top
where it's getting light I can use that
energy to make that top coal of that
much beefier that much fatter and it
also sucks to trim that bottom stuff
nobody wants to trim those little
popcorn buds nobody wants to waste time
cutting that off and if you can cut
something off to make something better
why wouldn't you do it so now is a good
time to go do a final bottoming just
clean up that messy crap on the bottom
that's not going to turn into any usable
bud
now I also like to do a light
defoliation at this point any leaf with
a purple petiole will get taken off at
this point in time so if you've got a
big leaf it's got a purple stem you can
see that long purple stem just go ahead
and break that off break that stem off
as close to the branch as close to the
bud as you can so you don't leave that
little stand there with moisture hanging
out just break that stem right off get
those leaves out of the room we don't
need all the excessive leaves so
anything with the purple stem I'll go
kind of light I'll do one layer I'll
look at the room I'll say yeah I could
do more and then I'll go back and take
off more leaves and then I'll stand back
and look into the room and I just try to
make sure that I've gotten all the giant
leaves that are blocking the light from
hitting the buds if they're if I can see
light coming down and it's hitting a
leaf and I can clearly see that that
leaf is hanging over a bud site I will
remove that leave so that bud site can
get the light now a lot of old-school
growers are going to tell you don't
remove the leaves because that's where
the nutrients and sugars are stored but
I'm pretty sure earlier in this episode
we talked about feeding these plants a
whole bunch of nutrients there's not
really a reason for these plants to
store nutrients we are feeding the [ __ ]
out of them these are high performance
plants that are going to get a high
performance meal every day they don't
need that stored stuff we can pull those
leaves off those leaves will give us
opportunity for powdery mildew those
leaves are places for pests to hide
those leaves have to come off when we
trim anyway why not take those leaves
off now and save us the trouble
now don't go extreme and make the plants
naked take off the leaves with the giant
pea Deol's and the leaves that are in
the way this is kind of intimidating for
new grower
and honestly this is an art and a skill
that you will have to develop over time
a good way to practice defoliating and
seeing what happens to the plants is to
get four plants of the same thing so
you've got four clones of let's say
golden go you got four golden goat
plants they're all in the same room
they're all in the same environment why
not defoliate one really hard defoliate
one kind of hard be fully eight one a
little bit and then don't be fully eight
the other one at all then take pictures
if you can then take as many notes as
you can and then keep an eye on those
notes and pictures and see which plant
came out the best did the plant that you
left alone come out the best did the
plant that we beat to [ __ ] and almost
made it naked come out the best or was
it the one that's right in the middle
it's going to be strange specific on how
hard you want to go with defoliation but
most strains will benefit from a medium
defoliation and they will definitely
benefit from removing all those super
large leaves that are blocking your bud
sites now if you go too hard your plants
will look naked and the growth will stop
you'll just slow them down so don't go
extremely hard on your first defoliation
kind of practice going there and pull
off some leaves I like to say this in
the podcast all the time you can take
more off but you can never blow those
leaves back on so pull a few off take a
step back look at it see what you think
if you want to take off more get in
there and take them off if you're
intimidated by it leave the leaves there
one thing I will suggest is that if a
leaf is yellow or funky you remove it
don't hesitate and don't be shy to take
down the ugly leaves those need to go
those yellow leaves are invitations for
pests a spider mite will see a yellow
leaf and they will head right to that
leaf because it is weak the outer layer
isn't as thick and crunchy so that
spider mite can get it's shitty little
fangs right through that skin and it can
get right in there and start sucking the
juice it doesn't have to do with that
thick healthy plant flesh so get rid of
those yellow leaves and remove them from
the garden as soon as possible something
else I would suggest at this point in
flowering is to increase air flow it may
be a good time to add some fans to the
room if you don't have an oscillating
fan in the room now is the time we want
those leaves rustling we don't want
those buds sitting
still and letting stagnant air buildup
in those buds now we don't want the
plants being bent over and getting [ __ ]
whipped by the fan all day
we just want every leaf to rustle
occasionally you just want that fan to
pass by and just give those leaves just
a little rustle just move the air around
just stir the air just so that nothing
can get still just move that air I just
keep doing this motion with my hand like
you guys can see me just moving that air
but like I said earlier our buds are
going to start developing they're going
to start getting fat and chunky those
buds work like sponges if there's too
much moisture in the air that moisture
will get trapped inside those buds then
we'll start getting bud mold inside the
but if you've got a fan moving that air
and moisture around that will reduce the
opportunities for bud mold now that
you're adding fans you may need to add
some sticks or some sort of cages for
supports if you're not using a trellis
net your buds are going to start
toppling over let's not wait till weeks
five and six when those buds are big and
chunky and sticky and they're falling
over trying to break the sticks let's
get some steaks
let's get some tomato cages let's start
supporting these plants early if you've
got a big long branch and you can tell
that it's going to turn into a giant bud
go ahead and stick a long steak into the
pot stick it into the soil try not to
cut up too many of the roots it's going
to happen
I understand but shove that steak
straight into the soil get that stick
straight up sticking where you need it
then use a twisty tie or a zip tie or
something gentle to just gently attach
that top police stick to that branch you
don't want to squeeze that branch at all
it needs to be loose so that you don't
pinch that branch you want some freedom
in there but you don't want it flopping
around too much don't pinch or crush or
squeeze the branch at all be very gentle
so use a few steaks and stick them in
the dirt and have them sticking straight
up and attach those floppy branches to
those steaks as needed don't be shy
I've seen people use a [ __ ] ton of
steaks in each pot if that's what you've
got to do that's what you've got to do
to keep that plant upright so get some
sticks or get some tomato cages and be
prepared to start supporting your plants
I hope your buds get so chunky that
those plants just want to fall right
over that's what I hope for you but I
also hope you've got some sticks or a
tomato cage on hand so that those plants
don't die when that
starts happening so we've got some
airflow we've got some sticks on our
plants another thing we need to focus on
is to continue scouting for pests and
p.m. just because we're this late in
Flour
doesn't mean that problems can arise
keep your eyes open for pests and
powdery mildew and boy try this now
while we're scouting for pass and boy
Titus we also need to pay attention to
plant problems do you see any nutrient
burn do you see any pH issues pay
attention to the leaves a few crunchy
leaves here and there that's acceptable
a few shitty leaves low in the canopy
that's acceptable if you start getting
large clusters of shitty looking leaves
you've got a problem that needs to be
addressed hopefully you were taking
notes of what you've been feeding the
plants hopefully you've got some kind of
record of what the pH was that was going
into the plants and maybe you've even
been taking notes of what is coming out
of the plants have you been measuring
the EC and pH of your runoff if so that
will help you diagnose problems if a
problem should arise now while you're
scouting for pests and while you're
looking for nutrient issues also don't
forget about all of the equipment in the
grow room just do some visual
inspections while you're walking through
the room listen look you may notice
things always be paying attention to the
plants and the equipment while you are
in the grow now while you're looking
around for equipment problems you're
looking around for pests and we're also
looking around for yellow leaves we
still need to keep our eyes out for
hermaphrodites if you are growing from
seed it is still an opportunity to
reveal hermaphroditic traits this far
into flower so keep your eyes out for
firm flowers and I think we've talked a
little bit in a previous episode about
what to do if you do discover a
hermaphroditic plant this late into
flower you've got several options you
can pull out the flowers you can cut off
the main bud that's got the male flowers
on it
you can cut down the whole plant or you
can choose to ignore the immediate
threat and you can keep an eye on that
male flower and see if it opens and
drops pollen just keep in mind that if
you do see male flowers you do run the
risk of having pollen in that grow room
and at this point of flowering those
female plants are really eager to
receive that pollen and create seeds so
keep your eye open because it is not too
late to find hermaphrodite
in fact that is always the case keep
your eyes open through the entire grow
on your first or second run with the new
cultivar or if you're growing from seed
all right podcast world this episode is
starting to get long so let's start
recapping and start wrapping up the
episode let's recap week four and week
four we are going to continue working
the plants into the Nets we're going to
continue popping and twisting we're
going to bottom the plants a little more
and now is the time to put on sticks or
tomato cages we need to reduce the
stress of the plants and start letting
the buds develop but we still need to
work the plants and pop the stems and be
foliate a little bit then we'll work
into week five that is when we're going
to do our final bottoming we need to
finish bottling the plants by the end of
week five we will do our final popping
and twisting then we're going to let the
plants just settle in and develop buds
we will do our final major defoliation
we will continue to lightly be fully
through harvest but this is the last big
defoliation we will do we will also pull
all of the shitty leaves we'll take off
all the small popcorn buds any branches
that don't look like they're worth the
[ __ ] will get taken out at this time now
is the last chance to get supports on
these buds if you don't have some sticks
or some tomato cages in there now by
week five you are going to see problems
in week six or plants are going to start
toppling over so now is the time to get
in there and make sure you've got sticks
and some sort of twisty tie or something
like that holding your buds up it is
also time to increase air flow we are
going to start gettin chunky buds so if
you don't have the air flow moving now
is the time to do it we also need a
carbon filter in week four I forgot to
recap that we need that carbon filter I
feel like I covered that very well now
in week six we are going to need that
air flow you better have those sticks
and supports done we are done bottoming
we are done working we are done cracking
popping and twisting these plants it is
time to let them grow and let the buds
get fat stay on top of scouting for
problems we need to look for bugs we
need to look for powdery mildew we need
to look for hermaphrodites we also need
to pay attention to environmental
nutrient or pH stresses and if we see
anything caused by those things we need
to adjust accordingly now my favorite
part about weeks five and six this is
when the good photos happen those buds
are starting to get
chunky the buds are nice and fluffy all
of the pistols are still nice and white
all the leaves are still lush and green
now is a great time to start taking
photos so that is my favorite part of
week six
so when week four you got little nugs
you got those little popcorn balls
developing then in week five you're
starting to get actual buds you can see
the buds growing up the stick they're
starting to get chunky then in week six
you actually start developing photogenic
colas it's time to get in there and
start taking pictures you're seeing some
beef you're starting to get some good
colors the trichomes are coming in week
six is when it really starts getting
exciting now the thing to think about is
keeping these plants healthy pest free
problem free all the way till the end
keep yourself out of trouble don't brag
don't start posting photos just yet if
you do take a sweet-ass photo in week
six I suggest you save it until harvest
then start flooding the pictures out
after harvest that way nobody knows when
you're cutting down your crop that's
just kind of a wheat grower trick from
back in the day another thing to start
thinking about is is the next run ready
we're going to harvest these plants in
two to four weeks depending on your
strain do you have plants lined up for
the next run do you have clones that are
getting rooted have you ordered seeds
are you prepared for the next run we
don't want to miss any time so let's get
on top of the next run that feels like a
great opportunity to pitch my seed
vendor if you need some seeds I highly
recommend the hella tanked seed company
and you can find them at
www.strohldigital.com slash grow from
your heart all the information you need
to become a patron will be right there
on the screen
again that's patreon.com/lenguin
it will explain exactly what I intend to
do with the funding that I received from
my contributors there is also a list of
rewards or services which I will provide
for my patreon contributors so check it
out
see if anything gets your attention and
I would appreciate your support also big
thank you in a giant shout out to
everybody who's contributed to the
patreon campaign in the past I truly do
appreciate all of the love and support I
would also appreciate it if you find me
on social media you can find the podcast
on Twitter simply search for @gf wih
podcast if you'd like to follow my
personal Twitter account it's a trois to
Jeff 420
give me a follow I also think you would
enjoy my Instagram feed on Instagram I
use my seed company name it's Irie
underscore genetics iri e underscore
genetics check out my fine cannabis
photography and come join me in my
Instagram live feeds I hang out on
Instagram live I answer grow questions I
take dad's sometimes it gets silly it's
always a lot of fun I encourage you to
join us that's Irie underscore genetics
on Instagram don't forget about the web
store if you're interested in an IRA
genetics or a grow from your heart
t-shirt or hoodie or an Irie army
t-shirt or perhaps you want a Rasta Jeff
sticker those are available on my
website the website is Irie genetics
Colorado calm just click on the high
restore you'll be taken right to the
store where you can grab a t-shirt you
can grab a hoodie or you can get some
fresh new stickers don't forget that the
podcast is available on iTunes stitcher
Google Play and every episode is now
available on the youtube channel just
search for the drove from your heart
podcast find the show on YouTube click
subscribe and leave some comments on the
videos I do love the interaction ladies
and gentlemen that is all I've got for
you this week I'll be back Thursday with
another mic episode then I'll be back
Monday with another grow lesson we will
focus on week 7 through 9 of flowering
our plants I want to thank you guys
again for listening to the podcast oh to
give you a huge shout outs my friend
James but erson and until next time take
a phat dad and give your mom a hug for
me everybody it's time for episode 385
of The Grove from your heart podcast
this episode is brought to you by the
hella dank seed company if you need new
seeds in your garden I highly recommend
the holiday exceed company and you can
find them at www.sedar.com filing you
know what I'm smoking today I've been
taking dabs of goat power ambrosia
from our
and apothecary farms this smells just
like golden goat it tastes just like
golden goat and it has got that sativa
punch that golden goat brings and I love
it I've always been a big fan of golden
goat so this is a delicious concentrate
the label says it is seventy four point
eight percent THC with a total of eighty
six point four percent total
cannabinoids I really like smoking the
goat power it gets my brain fired up and
it tastes amazing
so that is a quality concentrate ladies
and gentlemen this is going to be
another grow lesson if you've been
following along you know I've been doing
a long series of grow lessons in this
lesson we are going to do week seven
through nine we are wrapping up the grow
it's almost time to harvest so we're
gonna talk about the final weeks of
flowering we'll work our way into
Flushing and a little bit of defoliation
if you haven't been following along I
recommend you go back to episode 351 and
start listening to the grow less ins if
you are an experienced grower or if
you've been following along or if you
feel like you were up to speed let's
jump right into this Gro lesson at this
stage of the flowering cycle we are
entering what I call the third trimester
most of our plants are going to take
between eight and ten weeks to flower I
think nine weeks is a good template to
set up these grow lessons if your plants
are going to take more than nine weeks
I suggest you extend my advice for week
seven one more week just repeat the week
seven feeding the temperature the
humidity just repeat week seven one more
time if you've got a longer flowering
cultivar now I understand if you're
growing from seed you may not know how
long your plants are going to take to
flower you're going to have to pay
attention to the trichomes you're going
to have to be prepared to flush about 10
or 14 days before harvest this is going
to take a close eye you need to pay
attention to your trichomes often times
when I'm running seeds that are brand
new and I don't know what to expect
I already decided they're going 70 days
I want to let them flower 70 days and
see what they give me if I decide 70
days was too long I can run them less
time next time but I like to give them
the opportunity to show me what could
happen if I go a little bit too long
some plants really like to bulk up that
last week some plants really put on some
extra trichomes that final week some
plants really don't do [ __ ] for that
last week except over ripen you're going
to have to learn
your specific cultivar in most cases you
will discover that nine weeks is just
about right for most plants some will
take ten weeks if you want to get them
perfect some already in eight weeks
which is really advantageous because
that puts us a week ahead we can produce
another crop in a commercial environment
that really helps out but for these
lessons we are going to focus on a nine
week cultivar so we are now at the start
of week seven in our flowering phase at
this point the buds are starting to get
really fat they should be getting really
sticky they should be putting off some
very nice aromas by now they may be
starting to make some very nice colors
if you are growing from seed different
phenotypes will start becoming very
obvious at this point in the flowering
stage you may have one phenotype that
has gotten way taller you may have a
phenotype that has stayed shorter you
may have one that is way branch here you
will really start seeing the different
traits
now that we are later in flower so week
seven is what I call the fill week the
buds will really start filling in the
trichomes will really started getting
dense this is when the photos really
start getting hot I think weeks six
through nine are great for photos it
only gets better as we go on until it is
time for harvest so get out your camera
and take some great photos you're gonna
get good beefy buds you're gonna get
good trichome development and soon
you're going to start getting those
sweet fall colors now let's focus in on
the environmental conditions for our
grow room in week seven of flower our
buds are getting big and beefy so we
need to reduce the humidity if we have
too much humidity in the room we do run
the risk of bud rot we run the risk of
powdery mildew so let's reduce the
humidity let's bring it down to around
thirty or forty percent relative
humidity in the room this will help us
reduce the risk of bud rot so the first
change is that we should reduce the
humidity by five to ten percent if
possible the next thing I would
recommend is to reduce the temperature
by just a few degrees if possible we
have been running our flowering room
somewhere between 70 and 80 degrees
during the day I would like to knock
that down just three to five degrees if
possible let's try to get it 77 to 75
degrees in there and as the week's go on
I would like to reduce it about 3 to 5
degrees every week until harvest so this
week let's draw
down by three degrees if you're already
at 80 degrees let's get it down to 77 if
you're down at 77 let's crank it down
about 75 let's make these plants think
that winter is coming that colder
environment will bring out more colors
that colder environment will bring out
more terpenes that colder environment
will make your buds more dense and I
feel like it also speeds up the
finishing time of our plants so let's
make it just a little bit colder during
week 7 now let's talk about our
nutrients for week 7 this is going to be
our last opportunity for feeding our
plants we can start reducing our base
nutrients we don't need as much nitrogen
phosphorus and potassium as we have in
the past
you can almost eliminate the nitrogen at
this phase of flowering we don't want to
overfeed them but we do want to make
sure that they get a nice boost for
their last feeding so make sure you
include some phosphorous and potassium
to make those buds swell I would also
include some cal-mag don't go too hard
on the cal mag at this point because it
is really hard to flush it out and you
may taste it if you go too hard with cal
mag at this point I would always
encourage a kelp product this late in
Flour that will add to your flavors and
aromas I do like an enzymatic product
this late in Flour because it keeps my
root zone healthy I also use a microbe
product this leigh-anne flower I have
mentioned that we should taper off the
microbes and start increasing the bloom
boosters but if your budget will allow I
would include microbe products this late
in flower now the thing to focus on on
this feeding is one final bloom booster
feeding I don't know what product you're
using is a bloom booster but this is
probably your last opportunity to add
that bloom booster to your nutrient
regimen so make sure you get that in
there at this feeding time this is the
last week to fertilize our plants next
week we are going to begin the flushing
phase so if you want to boost those
plants up one last time if you've been
saving one bottle of something or one
little scoop of something this is the
last time to fertilize those plants
because at the start of week 8 we are
going to begin the flush phase now at
this point in the game we've got big fat
chunky buds I shouldn't have to say this
but I want to remind everybody it is too
late to spray any pesticides on these
plants they are coming down in 21 days
we don't want the plants to taste like
anything we apply it as a pest
side so please do not spray your plants
also do not use a sulfur burner I've
mentioned that in previous episodes
using a sulfur burner at this point in
flower will make your plants taste like
total [ __ ] it will taste like smoking a
pack of matches or it will taste like
smoking a can of fish so please turn off
the sulfur burner and flower I wish
everybody would just get rid of the
sulfur burner and find out what is
actually causing the problem and cure
the problem so no pesticides no so four
burners this latent flower what is
acceptable is predator bugs if you have
got a pest issue release an excessive
amount of predator bugs hopefully you've
been on top of that hopefully you don't
have a problem but I understand [ __ ]
happens in cultivation so predator bugs
are the way to go at this stage of the
game the little sachets that you hang
the little teabag look of things it's
too late for those you need the live
predators that are ready to release that
are hungry that are ready to get in
there and destroy your spider mites or
whatever pests you may have acquired you
need the live active bugs they're a
little more expensive but they are the
only thing that are effective at this
stage of flower so again do not spray
anything do not use a sulfur burner and
if you do see any insects any pests get
in there with some predator bugs and
hopefully those predators will eradicate
your infestation another thing you can
do is defoliate if you do see any signs
of pests remove any infested leaves mark
the plants so that you know where that
infestation was and come check
frequently do what you can to minimize
the problem in that area at this point
in the game I also suggest you defoliate
any yellow or funky leaves any leaves
that look unhealthy are pests
attractants so get those dead funky
leaves out of the grow defoliate
anything that is obvious that needs to
come off if you've got some nice fall
looking colors and you want to leave
those pretty leaves on there for photos
you can do that but the minute it starts
getting crunchy and it is dead decaying
matter it needs to come off of the plant
it is okay to have a few dead leaves at
this point in the game we've got a full
grow we've got a full canopy we've got a
lot of space there will be some dead
funky leaves in the garden
sometimes a leaf just doesn't get enough
light sometimes a branch gets bumped
things will happen you will have some
funky leaves don't freak out if it is
excessive you may have a problem that
needs to be diagnosed
but a few funky leaves at this stage are
not a problem now another thing we
should keep our eyes open for at this
stage of the game are late flower
hermaphrodites you should be scouting
daily for pests you should be scouting
daily for powdery mildew and botrytis
during that visual inspection you should
also be looking for hermaphrodites look
at the top buds of the plants look at
the middle buds of the plants and
definitely look at the lower part of the
plant where you are not getting a lot of
light do you see any male flowers do you
know what a male flower looks like could
you identify a hermaphrodite flower if
it walked up and bit you on the nose if
not I recommend you do a little bit of
google research and know what a
hermaphrodite flower looks like so you
do not allow them to happen in your
garden so at this point of the game we
still need to keep our eyes open for
pests and mold problems and we also need
to keep an eye out for hermaphrodites
now I've spoken in a previous episode
about how to handle the Herms if you
should get one don't freak out don't go
crazy spray it with some water and think
of your options do you want to remove
the male flower do you want to remove
the bud do you want to remove the branch
or do you want to get rid of that whole
plant it is up to you it is your garden
you're going to have to make decisions
like that if there is just one little
hermaphrodite flower I would spray it
with water pick it out with tweezers if
you've got two or three that are on one
bud maybe cut that butter that branch
off if you've got several hermaphrodite
flowers popping up in different spots on
a plant it may be time to get rid of
that plant
you have a lot of things to think about
because this lay in flower will those
male flowers do anything to the rest of
your crop if you're just running one
flowering cycle you're probably too late
into the grow to seed anything if you've
got a perpetual cycle going on those
plants that are earlier and flower may
be ready to receive that pollen should
that hermaphrodite release pollen so
you've got things to think about now if
you do have hermaphroditic plant in your
grow room don't give clones of that to
anybody
please don't pass out hermaphrodite
clones to your friends if you want to
continue to grow it that is fine but
don't give our amount to anybody you're
setting them up for failure
we don't want to do that to our friends
and fellow growers now the last things I
have written down for week 7 is plenty
of airflow we need a lot of airflow
the grow room as these buds start
getting chunkier we may need more fans I
want to see every leaf move
I don't need every plant and every leaf
getting beat down by the wind but I want
every leaf just to get a little rustle
occasionally as the fans oscillate I
want every fan to just feel that fresh
air just change that air around my
leaves that way I know the environment
is getting shuffled we don't have a
bunch of co2 in one area we don't have a
bunch of humidity packed up over here I
want to mix that air all day long and
keep that air fresh for my plants so
have plenty of airflow in your grow as
we get late into flower now the next
thing I want to talk about is kind of
preparing us for the future we plan to
cut this crop down in approximately 21
days do you have seeds or clones
prepared for your next run if you have
another grow space now is the time to
get your seeds or clones prepared for
your next run that way we don't have a
bunch of downtime that way as soon as
these plants are harvested you can move
fresh plants right into that grow room
and never miss a day in the future I do
plan on updating my perpetual grow
lesson I did write a very long perpetual
grow podcast I think it is episode 73 so
if you're interested in scheduling a
perpetual grow go check out episode 73
but I will update that because in
Colorado we have made quite a few
changes to our laws I want to write a
perpetual grow episode based around our
Colorado plant count limits so that is
coming in the future but let's focus on
today you need to get plants prepared
for your next run if you have got an
available veg space so now's the time to
buy clones or acquire clones from either
your fellow growers or a dispensary or
however you get them or now is the time
to start germinating seeds and getting
them started so that when that grow room
is empty we can clean it up and we can
refill it and you never miss a day in
there so that is the basics of week
seven of the flowering cycle let's move
right into week eight in week eight we
want to continue to reduce the
temperature and humidity let's get that
humidity down between 25 and 35 percent
relative humidity this will make it a
little bit dry in the room for the last
two weeks but it will also help us
prevent powdery mildew and boy try this
we don't want to get mold right at the
center of our big giant buds so let's
start by reducing the humidity the next
thing we can
do is we can reduce the temperature by
three to five degrees at this plane of
the face I would like to be somewhere
between 70 and 74 degrees Fahrenheit
during the lights on cycle now week
eight is what I call the final swell
week you will see your buds take off
they will get huge they will get chunky
they will start becoming covered in
trichomes it is time to really start
paying attention to your trichomes with
a 60 or 100x powered microscope you need
to get in there and look at those
trichome heads see what color they are
are they clear are they getting that
milky whitish blue color have they
started becoming amber that is how you
determine the ripeness of your cannabis
plants so it's time to get in there and
start paying close attention to the
trichomes on our cannabis plants now
these plants are also going to be super
sticky and super stinky but they should
also be putting off some amazing colors
so now is another great opportunity to
take more photography as we enter the
flush phase we will start seeing more
colors come from the plants we're going
to start removing nutrients from the
plant we're gonna push some of the color
out some of the green is going to
disappear which will allow room for reds
and golds and a lot of great colors that
you didn't know we're coming from these
plants this is going to be an exciting
two weeks so we've reduced the humidity
we have reduced the temperature now
let's start flushing our plants flushing
is free I have done an entire episode on
flushing our cannabis plants it is
episode 320 by go into great detail
quickly here I will explain how and why
we flush for the past at least nine
weeks we have been shoving nutrients
into these plants they are filled with a
lot of nutrients we do not want to smoke
all of those nutrients they are stored
in the buds they are stored within that
plant by flushing the plant we are
starving it of nutrients we will make
that plant use up all of the nutrients
stored within its systems we will also
remove all of the nutrients from the
soil so we basically want to wash out
the medium to make no nutrients
available to allow that plant to starve
itself so that it will use up all of the
nutrients that is stored over its
flowering cycle by removing the
nutrients from all of the buds it will
make the buds burn and smoke and taste
much better if they are properly dried
and cured we still need to get all the
way through a har
mist and drain cure phase but at this
point flushing is the first step to
getting a tasty final product so let's
start flushing flushing is very easy
when you water the plants don't add any
nutrients you can adjust the pH
somewhere between six two and six five
and just water the plants until you get
twenty percent runoff if you pour in a
gallon of water in a pot you want twenty
percent of that gallon to run right out
of the bottom of that pot so give them a
few heavy waterings and you will wash
out all of those nutrients then just
continue to water until harvest time
that is flushing it is simple and it is
free and it will make your plants taste
so much better if you do it correctly
have you ever smoked flowers that taste
like you just stuck your tongue in a
light socket chances are those buds were
not flushed properly that person did not
allow a 10 to 14 day flush phase before
he harvested his plants and now they
taste like complete [ __ ] flush your
plants I centered a couple times already
it is free why don't you want to do free
[ __ ] to your plants you don't have to
use nutrients and it saves time all you
gotta do is fill the container with
water adjust the pH pour it on the damn
plants let's flush the plants that is
what we were going to focus on in weeks
eight through nine is flushing the
plants for harvest so that they taste
good once we dry and cure them now
before I harvest I like to do a pre
harvest defoliation I generally like to
do this seven to ten days before harvest
so that may happen in the middle of week
eight or at the beginning of week nine
any leaf that has a pea deal that I can
grab I just go in there and peel it
right off I don't need a bunch of leaves
at this point of the flowering phase
those leaves have done their job it is
almost time to cut down these plants I
want to make the harvest crews job just
a little bit easier so I like to go
through and pull off all of the big
leaves seven to ten days before harvest
now that is a good way to segue us right
into week number nine at the beginning
of week nine if you haven't done it
already feel free to go in there and
pull off all of the big leaves those
leaves have done their jobs we don't
need them anymore let's take them off of
there and get them out of the room now
let's talk about the environmental
conditions in our grow room for week
nine this is the final week of our
flowering phase I like to reduce the
humidity
- approximately 25 to 30 percent
humidity at the end of the flowering
phase my buds are huge my buds are
chunky I do not want to risk bud rot in
the middle of those buds so I reduced
that humidity down to about 25 percent
relative humidity in my flowering room I
also like to get it nice and cool if I
can get it about 70 to 74 degrees for
the last week of flower that really will
make the colors pop out of the plants it
will make them more dense and it will
give you more trichomes
and I really think the plants pack on a
little beef once it gets colder and it
will also speed them up I feel like
making it nice and cold at the end of
the season tricks our plants into
believing it is fall winter is coming
they say oh I don't have a lot of time
left to live so you really start doing
everything they can do to ripen up and
reach the end of their life cycle so
that's why I try to make it a little
colder in the grow room at the end of
the Dro cycle another thing that a lot
of growers like to do at the end of a
flowering cycle is reduce the lights
currently you're probably running 12 on
and 12 off toward the end of the
flowering cycle you can always reduce it
to 10 on and 14 off reducing your light
cycle will also make the plants think
that the end is near they will speed up
a little bit and they will finish more
quickly I think that having it a little
bit cooler and having a little less
light in the room makes the plants
finish a little sooner it also makes
them pack on a little more trichomes it
makes the buds a little more dense and
also I think it gives us a little more
terpene presence terpenes are destroyed
by light terpenes are destroyed by
warmth why not give them a little cool
and a little dark and we can have a
little more Terps and we're also saving
a little bit of money we're not using
nutrients because we're flushing and now
we're running the lights for two hours
less per day so we're saving electricity
we're saving the electricity on running
the bulbs plus we're probably saving a
little bit of electricity on cooling
since we don't have to cool to fight
those lights so we're saving electricity
and we're also saving time on our gear
so why not reduce the lights just a
couple of hours at the last week of
flower now here's a little secret that I
haven't shared with a lot of people if
you've got a plant that takes way too
long to flower and you need to speed it
up just a little bit you can reduce
those lights by 4 hours at the end of
flowering and those plants will finish
approximately a week
earlier if you've got a ten-week strain
or an 11-week strain and at the end of
week 9 you crank those lights down to
eight hours on at 16 hours off that
plant will finish one solid week early
now you may not get the harvest weight
you would get if you let it go for that
full 11 or 12 week period but sometimes
we just need the plants to be done we
need that space we need that room so
that is always a trick you can use to
speed up some plants so we have reduced
humidity we have reduced our
temperatures now we've reduced our light
cycle we are on the final homestretch
here in week 9 keep flushing don't add
any nutrients obviously please do not
apply any pesticides or any foliar feeds
to your plants this late and flower you
will taste it you will notice it it will
ruin the entire crop this week is our
final bulking and ripening week you will
see that final book come on they'll
start getting fat and chunky all of your
leaves are gonna start getting yellow
and starting to droop down and get a
little crinkly because we've been
flushing and hopefully you're paying
attention to those trichomes because
this is when the trichomes are really
going to start turning amber and showing
their progress so week 9 is the bulk and
ripen week it is almost time to chop
down the plants so keep a close eye on
the trichomes we've been flushing if you
decide the plants are not done and you
want to let them go a little bit longer
you can let them flower for an extra
week and you don't have to give them any
more nutrients don't mess your whole
cycle up by adding nutrients in and then
trying to cut it down seven days later
you've already been flushing you're
already doing it perfectly don't mess it
up now if it needs to go longer
let it go longer if you are early in
flower and you anticipate you may need
an extra week or two again repeat my
advice from week seven week seven is
where you extend your schedule if you're
going to go longer than three weeks so
let's act like we are right on schedule
we're ending up week nine we have d
foliated the plants we haven't ran into
any problems the next thing to think
about is do you have your harvest and
drying and curing area prepared are you
ready for a sticky stinky time consuming
and space consuming harvest when you cut
down the plants where are you going to
hang them they're going to be there for
at least a week maybe 7 to 14 days
depending on your environment do you
have space for that
it's secure is it safe will people be
showing up when people show up are they
going to smell your hanging plants do
you need to plan ahead to keep that
aroma away from visitors do you need to
do something to keep intruders and
thieves away from that harvested product
now is the time to start thinking about
that you don't want to say hey it's the
time to cut down these plants and walk
in there with scissors and cut them down
and then you're stuck you don't know
what to do start thinking about that now
ladies and gentlemen the next step in my
grow lessons is harvest our next step is
to harvest these plants that is only
followed by drying and curing and the
next step after that is to clean and
reset our grow rooms so if you've made
it this far you are one episode from
cutting down your plants then after that
all we've got to do is dry it and cure
it and the step after that is finally
sampling our finished product
ladies and gentlemen I'm proud of you I
hope you've made it all the way through
nine weeks of flowering without any
issues if you did run into issues I hope
you were able to solve those problems
without messing up your crop if you've
got any questions about anything I've
said in this nine week flowering episode
or throughout this entire grow series
please send me an email and ask me those
questions my email address is grow from
your heart at hotmail.com
I would love to answer all of your
questions about growing cannabis about
the cannabis industry just about
anything cannabis in general please
reach out with any questions
all right podcast world that is all I've
got for you for this episode thanks
again for hanging out if you feel like
this episode was educational informative
or entertaining and you would like to
make a financial contribution to the
podcast you can do so by going to
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
all the information you need to become a
patron will be right there on the screen
I'd also appreciate it if you find me on
social media you can find the show on
Facebook simply search for the grower
from your heart podcast on Twitter the
show is at G f YH podcast my personal
Twitter account is at Ross to Jeff 420
also I would appreciate it if you find
my Instagram account on Instagram I use
Irie underscore genetics make sure you
find me on Instagram check out my fine
cannabis photography you can also join
me in my Instagram live feeds if you've
got something you'd like to say if you'd
like to reach out you're not into all
the social media again you can email me
grow from your heart at hotmail.com
don't forget the podcast is available on
iTunes stitcher Google Play and every
episode is archived on YouTube just
search for the Grove from your heart
podcast you guys I do have a few more I
read genetics t-shirts and hoodies and
also some grow from your heart podcast
t-shirts and hoodies available on my
website if you are interested in some
new gear the website is Irie genetics
Colorado calm just click on the I
restore you'll be able to grab yourself
some new gear there are some shirts
there are some hoodies and there are
some sweet new stickers make sure you
check that out I want to thank everybody
one more time for hanging out for a grow
lesson
I wanna give you a huge shout out to my
buddy Juan's illa and until next time
take a phat dab and give your mom a hug
for me welcome back everybody it's time
for episode 387 of The Grove from your
heart podcast this episode of the show
is brought to you by the hella dank seed
company if you need new seeds in your
garden I highly recommend the hella dank
seed company and you can find them at
www.ge.com a tradition that I started
the podcast off by letting you know what
I'm dabbing I just took a ridiculous dab
of star dog ambrosia from our friends at
apothecary farms everybody knows I love
the star dog it is one of my favorite
strains this is going to be a great
podcast intro if you've been following
along with the podcast you know that
I've been doing a long series of grow
lessons this episode is going to be a
repost of an episode about determining
ripeness this was originally posted as
episode number 319 this episode does
feature white Mike the original episode
was about 45 minutes long but I cut out
the part about determining ripeness and
that was approximately 20 minutes I plan
to be out of town for a couple of days
this week so I won't be able to put
together a quality podcast I've got this
episode about determining ripeness and I
feel like it falls perfectly in line
with the grow series that we have been
doing so ladies and gentlemen with no
further ado let's jump right into this
old-school episode of The Grove from
your heart podcast featuring white Mike
ladies and gentlemen this is episode 319
determining ripeness reposted as episode
387 I do hope you enjoy it
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for another episode of the
grow from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation a try to hear a new grower
if you're a professional grower if
you're a new smoker or a dedicated
dabber if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who is just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me this episode of the podcast
is brought to you by my friends at the
hell a dank seed company if you need new
genetics for your gardening I highly
recommend the hella dank seed company
you can find them at dank seed dot store
ladies and gentlemen roll up a fat joint
pack up the bong or start heating up
that daybreak because it's time for
another episode of the grill from your
heart a podcast
[Music]
what's up podcast world it's time for
episode 319 of the girl from our podcast
thanks again for joining me sitting
across the table is white Mike welcome
back to the show bro thanks man thanks
for having me oh man thanks for taking
time out of the busy schedule of two
kids congratulations
those new notes it's a lot we're from
welcome well we're gonna show from
Pueblo Colorado Spanish I was just an
Instagram wives live feeding somebody's
trying to throw out some German and I
responded in German and the whole room
just went silent that was funny welcome
to the show ladies and gentlemen welcome
Mike's on the show we're gonna do a show
about what are we gonna talk about
determining ripeness
and when to harvest your cannabis plants
before we get there you know I like to
start the episodes by stop my talk by
stalking about let's talk about let's
talk about what I've been dabbing that
was hard to say I've been taking dad's
of some viola labs Clementine cookies
live resin I'm opening it up to smell it
right now it is like spicy orange candy
and I really love the smell and flavor
of this I picked up three grams today
when I went I usually just get one gram
of usually I was like they have more of
that they do I'll just take three and I
will be on my way Mike is it time to
change that microphone cover is that
what your supplemental e telling me
right now it's
first spot but I've got Malamutes I'm
used to free spots we're gonna blame
that on your Malamutes
it's not Malamute hair but it's not
hippie hair either song cool just
pointed off and rolling with it cover
after the show welcome to the furry spot
back on track we've got a couple of you
should shout out shout out to my friends
at the holiday exceeding company shout
out to water shout the water you're
drinking water now you guys mike is
drinking water this is like a rare
occasion I didn't pack properly for this
mission then some waters happening you
need some water anyway Brite I don't
feel bad for you and then he went
spilled half of it right down your face
Mike sure you can water you guys that's
a rare occasion ah the hella dank seed
company if you need new seeds for your
garden I highly recommend the hell a
dank seed company at dank seed dot
stores support our friends at the Helen
tank seed company also support more of
my friends PL grow systems guys I know
you want to know what's going on in your
grow room at all times
sometimes you're away you know like I
wonder if that air conditioner clicked
on it's pretty hot outside I wonder if
that air conditioners working I wonder
you can't even focus you can't even
think about what you're doing like aa
conditioner working you want to drive
home and look but you can't drive home
you're just freaking out you know what
bust out your phone check out your peel
minder unit you can see what's going on
your girl room at all times how do you
get a peel how do you get a peel miner
unit you go to peel growth systems
that's how check them out appeal growth
dot systems you guys appeal growth
systems minder unit well let you know
what's going on in your grow room at all
times
you can relax you can enjoy what you're
doing it's awesome alright let's move
forward YouTube you guys all of the
YouTube videos are caught up I did it it
took a long time but they are finally
there that was a multi-year project
YouTube got evil right at the scariest
time yeah I was just about caught up and
then all of the YouTube channels started
disappearing
I don't put videos of myself consuming
on this channel I talk heavily about it
they don't see it so unless they're
looking for it and someone reports it we
should be okay we'll see how long it
lasts either way if it does disappear
I'll find any place to put it don't
worry
YouTube is uh that's just another place
for more people to listen to the show I
think we'll probably
to get more more lessons more views more
interactions alright Mike you got
anything to say before we start talking
about determining ripeness on cannabis
plants you got me topics you want to
bring before we get on a ramble here not
yeah well suits Mike says we'll see
where this takes us alright so a lot of
people were talking on Instagram live
and on chat rooms right now about how to
decide when to harvest their cannabis
when is my cannabis ripe the seed packs
are gonna tell you a certain timeframe
they're gonna say 56 to 63 days they're
gonna say 63 to 70 days they're gonna
say 9 to 10 weeks the first time you run
that pack of seeds I would say go the
longest time frame that they give you as
an option at least plan for it for sure
yes
yeah if it says 10 wheat 9 to 10 weeks
go to 10 weeks because maybe in that
last week that's when you're gonna see
extra trichomes pack on you're gonna see
the extra weight come on you're gonna
see maybe some cool colors you might you
may you may see some [ __ ] you don't see
if you cut it down at week 9 so let it
go 10 weeks if it says 10 weeks if it
says 56 to 63 days let it go 63 well let
it go 65 if it looks okay and see what
happens
so that being said the way to determine
ripeness of your cannabis plants is not
by looking at the hairs
it is not by looking at it's not looking
I'm just I'm hearing different people
throughout my cannabis career like
speaking at length about how all of
those are telltale signs of like either
perfect they're pretty good or completed
or ready to harvest and it's all
nonsense yeah what we are growing
cannabis for the viable part that we
want are the trichomes why would we look
at anything but the trichomes right we
want to harvest those when they're at
the right best point so we should be
paying attention to the trichomes the
only way you can do that you can if
somebody tells you they can see the
trichomes with their naked eye either
steal their eyes or kick them in the
dick because they're a liar
you cannot see amber trichomes without
some sort of magnification you need at
least 60 X maybe a hundred X
magnification to see if a trichome is
clear cloudy silver milky amber busted
ruptured if the heads broken off of it
you need magnification you cannot see
that with the naked eye and if you can
you're [ __ ] awesome send me a message
I want to hear about it good get on
Amazon start looking the scopes folks
yeah get yourself a like a jeweler's
loupe I have a scope from Dino light
that hooks up to my computer I plug it
right into the USB slot it took me just
a few minutes to mess with the drivers
to make it link up to my computer once
it linked up it was no problem ever I
opened up the application I'm able to
run the scope over the plants and I can
focus it in and I can see those
trichomes very large on my computer
screen
and it makes it very and I can take
pictures so if I can't tell exactly what
I'm looking at I can reach over and I
think I press f11 and I take the photo
right there boom then I can go look
later and I can see if that plants ripe
or not the the computerized scope makes
life a lot easier but you can pick up
something kind of like a jeweler's loupe
it's a lot less expensive and just as
functional the 420 scope will work for
you just a basic jeweler's loupe will
work for you there's one that Hydrofarm
sells it spreads in half it's got
batteries in it and it splits in half
and the batteries are in one side and
the optics are actually on the other
side they make a 60 and a 100x I would
recommend the 100x if you go for that
that's probably the best one on the
market if you're gonna get something
like that but I'm aware of there's
probably something better by now but get
some magnification
magnification will help you out in so
many ways you'll be able to tell if your
trichomes are clear if they're silver if
they're cloudy if they're milky if
they're amber if they're ruptured also
you'll be able to identify the pests and
the funguses and the problems on the
undersides of your leaves more
accurately if you've got a scope to look
at those there's a really useful tool
throughout the growth cycle for sure
yeah once you've got all of your tools
dialed in and you've got some money to
spend on a couple extra toys for the
grow room
get yourself a scope it will really help
a scope or a loop or something that
hooks up to your computer
all right so the hairs are not gonna
tell you how ready your plant is Mike
just tapped his headphones are you too
hot there no I just got it all right
scratch it up buddy good boy good boy
he's like starting to go scratching
behind his ear you guys which are the
trichomes we're drawing for trichomes
that's what we want if you're going to
make quality flowers if you're gonna
make edibles if you're gonna make
extracts if you're gonna make anything
the trichomes are what matter so pay
attention to that nothing else now the
way that you can tell the trichomes
you're gonna see the trichomes develop
on your plant if you have a scope and
you can pay attention through the entire
process do that
watch those trichomes go from a little
bitty stalk watch them develop a head
watch the head of that trichome fill up
you'll watch it fill up it'll get juicy
and then it'll start to change colors
it'll go from clear then it will slowly
turn to like a silver ish color then
it'll get cloudy
you'll be once you see it you'll know
right now you're going what does he mean
by cloudy you've got to imagine if you
got a fishbowl and then you put some
dish soap in there and stirred it up
it's cloudy that's what you're cloudy
trichomes are gonna look like that's
cloudy now your next step after cloudy
is milky sometimes they turn kind of
bluish in my opinion they have a hint of
blue they have that if you stir it like
certain white paints and whatnot you'll
start to see a blue kind of undertone a
little bit yeah yeah and it's yeah a
nice patch of milky trichomes I always
see just a little hint of light blue in
there so the fishbowl I talked about a
minute ago imagine if I took your
fishbowl that had we dumped out the dish
so because this is just gonna get gross
if we keep adding stuff I'm gross let's
do this differently imagine if you took
a fishbowl that's got water in it and
you poured just enough milk in there to
make it turn light white light white not
it's not gonna be [ __ ] boom like ice
cream but it's gonna be light white like
you poured some creamer in your coffee
you just lighten it up you can see it
now now that trichome is what I would
call milky that is a milky trichome
you're almost ready for harvest the next
step that's gonna happen is gonna look
like you had a spray bottle imagine if I
took like the little spray bottle that
you're spraying your plants with or
little mr. bottle what if I poured some
dr. pepper in there and I walked right
up to your trichomes and just just give
it a little spritz of dr. pepper your
trichomes are gonna have a little amber
spritz on them now and that's exactly
what I think it looks like is like you
sprayed some soda right onto your
trichomes they're gonna go from milky
and then you're gonna see just a couple
of them get this amber color this dr.
pepper color right across them and
you're gonna see it happen toward the
top and kind of right in the middle and
then keep pay attention to the whole
planks it's gonna move around but when
you see that first bit of amber really
start paying attention because you've
got a very short time now they're gonna
start that amber is gonna start
progressing throughout the plant really
quickly and when you look at the scope
and you can see you're gonna have to
look around the plant when 30% of those
trichomes start becoming amber that's
when you want to cut down 30% now I say
look in several places you're gonna be
like 30% how do I know and I can see a
hundred trichomes in there just look
around and use your best judgement you
guys about 25 to 35 percent is where you
want to aim for you're not gonna notice
a difference if you're a few days off on
your harvest honestly you are not going
to notice a huge difference you've got a
drying cure period once you cut down
these plants those trichomes are going
to continue to change all the way until
the moment you combust them you're gonna
cut them down you've got this dry period
they're gonna get beat up and harvest
they're gonna get cured they're gonna
change there's going to be so many
different changes in those trichomes so
just a couple of days in your harvest
window will not make a huge difference
you're not gonna notice it it's not
gonna hurt your feelings so pay
attention to those trichomes get
yourself a scope they're gonna go clear
then they're gonna turn silver then
they're gonna get cloudy that's when it
starts getting excited their filter
that's getting exciting they're filling
up with trichomes or with cannabinoids
now they've got different things in
their different psychoactive ingredients
inside of there that are changing every
day then they're gonna get milky they're
gonna turn a little bit blue then
they're gonna look like I sprayed them
with dr. pepper when three out of ten
when
30% of them have that dr. pepper stain
on him that's when it's time to cut so
you're gonna say but it's my first grow
with this plant how do I plan that how
do I properly be able to flush and look
out for trichomes to be Amber I thought
of a great way that we can all be safe
you keep in mind this isn't gonna be the
last time you're growing this strain
hopefully this is the first time you
drew it that's why you don't know when
the trichomes are gonna change colors
that's why you don't know how long it's
gonna take it's the first time you're
developing a relationship with this
plant the first time you got to learn it
the second third time you dial it in the
fourth and fifth time you [ __ ]
perfect this grow so you're just
learning this one so keep think about it
this way if you're growing a 60 day
plant if the package says grow it fir 55
to 60 days go that 60 days if you're
gonna go for 60 days flush it day 50 and
really start paying attention to those
trichomes if you want to cut it down at
a specific day just make sure you
flushed 7 to 10 days pretty heavily I'd
like to go 14 but 7 to 10 days should be
plenty if you want to let your plant go
70 days if you've got something I bred
you probably want to let it go 70 days
if I bred it 70 days no problem start
flushing at day 60 and pay attention to
your trichomes you can cut down at day
70 if you don't feel like it's ready let
it go a little bit longer it doesn't
need nutrients to keep going it's just
gonna start getting tired but then you
can give it time to ripen up so I think
the way to judge when to harvest your
cannabis is by paying attention to the
trichomes if you don't have a way to
look at the trichomes you don't have a
way to accurately judge the ripeness of
your cannabis plants and you run the
risk of cutting them way too early is
what most people do if you feel like
they're done wait three to five more
days if you can wait seven more days
wait because they're only gonna get
better and don't cut too early because
you're anxious and eager patience you
cut clones or you grew from seeds and
those took time then you've edged it out
you spent a lot of money on nutrients
you've already spent
you're probably gonna put a hundred and
fifteen days into it why not put 120 -
what's another week right I know you
start getting itchy start getting that
crackhead lips and he started scratching
your neck like yeah I want to cut it I'm
thinking of a friend of mine who was
always in that clip in lower nut he'd
start at the bottom of the planter
taking notes and drying him out as fast
as he could to keep himself covered and
by the time we got the harvest it was
just like the top coal is left on the
plan yeah and then there's nothing to
enjoy because you fast ride everything
and you could have just had one huge
harvest and actually saw his dog see you
can see what it looks like what your
work actually did instead of just
destroying your work slowly not getting
any reward yeah so be patient you guys
that's that's one of the main things
that it's hard to learn when you're
growing cannabis sometimes you just need
to hide your scissors send Mike home
with the scissors like you're on suicide
watch or something so I guess that was a
pretty quick way to do it but I mean
that's right to the point there's no
other way to explain that get a
jeweler's loupe get some sort of
magnification and look at your trichomes
I know I keep saying it we're drawing
for trichomes you just got to get in
there with some magnification and spend
some time reading the plant yeah we
don't we're not worried about all the
green leafy part I mean that part tastes
good that's fun to smoke that's a cool
carrier but the trichomes are the goal
so make sure they're ripe something that
I should add if you are growing for
concentrates maybe cut a little bit
early start flushing early and harvest a
little bit early because once the if you
want nice and clear concentrates maybe
this is some industry secrets secrets I
shouldn't be sharing with the general
public but here you go guys I love you
and this is free if you want nice and
clear concentrates cut your plants down
before the trichomes start getting dark
if they start getting dark what you are
extracting is trichomes your
concentrates will come out a little bit
darker cut them down when they're nice
and clear and guess what nice and clear
concentrates it's easier a lot of a lot
of concentrate makers can make super
clear concentrates out of everything now
but it's easier it's less to clean up
it's less work if you're pulling it down
when you have got nice and clear
trichomes early and process quickly yep
they cut them down I don't even want to
tell you what week sometimes like
sevenish I've seen it go the
concentrates yeah a little bit
ridiculous but then you can pull a whole
one more harvest a year if you cut
everything down at the end of week six
that you could feel one more harvest a
year in your schedule that's business
unfortunately you guys do not do that be
patient let it go long enough let it be
done like Axl Rose said all we need is
just a little patience all right podcast
world I want to thank you once again for
listening to this episode about
determining ripeness of your cannabis
plants I'll be back in just a few days
with another episode don't forget to
support the patreon page at patreon.com
slash grow from your heart please follow
me on all of the social media on
Facebook search for the Grove from your
heart podcast on Twitter it's @gf wih
podcast you can always follow my
personal twitter page which is a trust
to Jeff 4:20 and don't forget to follow
me on instagram my instagram account is
Irie underscore genetics I would love to
see you there ladies and gentlemen
that's all I've got free for this
episode I look forward to seeing you in
just a few days I want to give a huge
shout out to James but erson and until
next time take a phat dab and give your
mom a hug for me welcome back we've
world it's time for episode 388 of The
Grove from your heart podcast this
episode is brought to you by the hell a
dank seed company if you need new seeds
for your garden I highly recommend the
hell a dank seed company and you can
find them at www.ge.com a tradition that
I start to show off by letting you know
what I'm smoking today I'm taking dad's
a fatso OG from Green Dot labs this is
the fat sow OG full-spectrum extract
it's nice and chunky it's got just the
right amount of chunky crystals and just
the right amount of Terp sauce in there
I really do approve of that ratio the
cross on this or the blend actually is
GMO and legend OG the flavor is
described as dark roast coffee garlic
and fuel and I feel like that is
absolutely accurate it has given me some
ridiculous cottonmouth I feel like you
can almost hear it on the microphone
ladies and gentlemen I've been having a
really busy couple of weeks I've been
out of town twice I'm going back out of
town Thursday I have a comedy show in
Denver then I will be attending the endo
Expo in Denver on Saturday and Sunday so
I am doing another repost for this
episode the last episode was determining
ripeness now that we know when the
plants are ripe it is time to begin
flushing our plan
I feel that many new growers and many
experienced growers overlooked the
importance of flushing our plants and it
is not happening properly I'm gonna say
this in the episode over and over again
but flushing is free and it can improve
the overall quality of your finished
product so why wouldn't we focus heavily
on flushing at the end of the growth
cycle I'm sure I'm gonna say that plenty
of times through this episode so with no
further ado let's jump right into an
episode about flushing our ripe
cannabis plants before harvest welcome
back cannabis community it's time for
episode 320 of the girl from your heart
podcast this episode is brought to you
by our friends at the hello tank seed
company if you need new seeds for your
garden I highly recommend the hello tank
seed company and you can find them at
dank seed dot store also make sure you
check out our friends at pol grow
systems you can find them at pol grow
dot systems ladies and gentlemen first
off let me apologize for my terrible
sounding voice our friend Brett also
known as Mary's motivation at a going
away party I went to that going-away
party and I smoked way too much flour
and way too much concentrate and my
voice sounds like crap I got a little
bit of a chest cold
I got a throat thing going on I got a
sinus thing happening and before we get
too far I just want to apologize and I
want to thank you for listening to this
episode while I sound like poop all
right I'd like to start the episode off
by letting you know what I'm smoking on
today I'm taking little baby dabs of
gorilla glue for ambrosia and also I've
got some of the New York City bezel
ambrosia batter both from apothecary
it's been a nice mix fiscal and light
today just trying to stay lightly
medicated and not mess up my lungs and
throat again I'm on the path to recovery
and I want to keep moving forward so a
minute ago I mentioned that I went to my
friend Brett also known as Mary's
motivation I went to Brett's going-away
party Brett is leaving the country
Brett's a little scared and nervous
about his trip but honestly I don't
think anybody deserves this more Brett
needs to make this adventure happen I
think it's going to be a great
experience for him so I am super proud
and super excited for him his party was
awesome at the party we were joined by
of course the always awesome Brett was
there dabbing granny and and Kevin
showed up also Lucy
mama bear dabs is there always good
see Lucy I got to bump into my friend
twisty seeds who I don't see very often
I got to have a conversation a long
conversation with Chandler dabbing that
was pretty cool Earle tycoon was there
the dude from hits on hand was there LJ
fresh was there and several other new
and old friends who they're hanging out
it was a great party there were a couple
of folks there who brought Koenig ours
which are basically blunts rolled with
cannabis leaves as the wrapper that
really [ __ ] up my lungs you guys my
lungs did not like that at all
they were delicious to smoke and we got
really lit but that is why I think I
sound like crap today so shout out to
Bret for the great party the party was a
private party so not a lot of people
were invited the event was at cultivated
synergy I owe a huge shout out to
everybody at cultivated synergy every
time we do an event there every time we
do a large or small party there it goes
very well the place is very inviting the
staff is very accommodating and I always
have a great time so big shout out to
everybody who came to the party extra
huge shout out to Bret for inviting me
who's only able to invite 30 people I
was honored to be amongst those 30 it
was a great party you guys we smoked
that place out for how few people there
were in there is a pretty big building
and we smoked that [ __ ] out pretty good
you can hear to my voice still alright
while I've still got some good voice
left let's do a quick podcast about
flushing your plants before harvest
before we talk about flushing I should
do a quick recap in the last episode I
talked about determining ripeness Mike
and I went fairly fast and we got kinda
rambly so I hope I made it clear that
determining ripeness is usually done by
using some sort of a loop so that you
can see the trichomes I mentioned using
a sixty or 100x loop one of our friends
from Instagram what's up dank Sinatra
our friend Dane Sinatra I shear photo
and seeds sent me a message and he says
now I can't see trichomes with my naked
eye but I can tell ripeness of a
trichome with a 16 acted jeweler's loupe
they said of course in my mind I'm in my
mid-20s
so my eyes may work a little better yes
dude you are a little bit younger than
me you got those fresh new eyes but he
corrected me he says he can see the
trichomes with this
sixteen axe Jewelers loop so you may not
need that bigger loop that 60 that 100
he says the 60 is working or the 16 is
working for him so I stand corrected you
may not need that big loop 16 may get
you through all so let's recap a little
bit about what I said about harvest
times I said that if you have a plant
that is said to go 60 days let it go the
full 60 days and start flushing at day
50 if you've got a plant that's supposed
to go 70 days let it go the full 70 days
and start flushing around day 60 now you
may say Russ - Jeff I want to dial it in
and cut these plants down at the perfect
ripeness yes
you're going to have to dial that in
something I wanted to stress is this is
not your last grow with this strain
hopefully this is your first run with
this cultivar with this cut so now
you've got a new girlfriend that you've
got to learn a little bit you've got to
take her out a couple of times you got
to see if she wants to come down at day
60 day 63 maybe day 67 maybe day 72
you've got to dial it in exactly to the
right day now you're gonna see
differences if you use different
nutrients you may get different ripening
dates if you have a little bit of
temperature difference you may get a
different ripening date so you're gonna
have to find the window and dial that in
hopefully this is not your last girl
with this cut hopefully this is the
first of many grows with a good cut so
if it's your first run with the 60 day
cut start flushing around day 50 if this
is your first time with a cut that you
think may go 70 days start flushing it
around day 60 now when you get to day 60
or day 70 on whichever plant you're
running you don't have to cut it down
just because you've been flushing for 10
days start paying more attention to the
trichomes if they are not amber don't
cut it down keep flushing for a few more
days it's better to over flush then
under flush the only thing you're doing
is not giving it nutrients it may have
gotten a little bigger it may have
gotten a little beefier but we're just
trying to figure out the plant for the
first time so that is how to determine
when to begin flush if you don't know
the cultivar that you're using maybe
it's a brand new seed maybe it's a new
clone maybe you're just new at growing
and you don't know when to cut it
allowing the plant 60 to 70 days to grow
and then giving yourself extra time at
the end is always your best
that with a new cut all right so I feel
like I have established how to tell if
the plant is ripe and ready to cut down
and I feel like we have a good idea of
when to start flushing let's actually
talk about flushing our cannabis plants
I think flushing is super simple and
it's something people could easily
improve and they are really skipping
that step and I'm not sure why because
it's free it's a really easy step to
improve your cannabis and it is free
maybe people simply don't understand the
importance of flushing and why it's
important so let me tell you quickly why
flushing matters just imagine you've
been pouring salty nutrients into this
plant for nine weeks of flower plus
another three or four weeks of veg
you've just been filling it up with
nutrients you've been pouring whatever
nutrient brandy you're using you've been
pouring nitrogen
you've been pouring phosphorus you've
been pouring potassium and you've been
pouring carbohydrates into these plants
for the past twelve weeks now all of
that stuff is built up inside of that
plant the plant is not using all of it
it's letting some of it go it's turning
some of it into a gas and transpiring
some of it out but some of it is still
in the plant
if those nutrients are left in the plant
when we harvest dry and cure that plant
we're going to taste it the plants are
going to taste like crap if you feed too
much cal-mag too late in flower you're
going to taste it if you feed your
plants too much potassium silicon late
and flower you're going to taste it also
the plants are not going to burn
properly when you dry and cure these
buds they're not gonna smoke you're
gonna grind it up in a grinder you're
gonna roll a joint and it's just gonna
burn black and make a funky weird
charcoal that's because they're leftover
nutrients that you did not flush out we
can get that stuff out of there by
properly flushing the plants you were
mostly flushing the soil you want to
clean out the soil so there's nothing
left in your media but whether it's soil
soilless mix if you got peat whatever
you're working in you're gonna want to
flush that if it's rock wool if it's
cocoa you need to clean it out each
thing is going to take a different
amount of time to clean out but you want
to clean that out so the roots don't
have anything to eat then the plant will
start starving itself and it will start
showing as harvest fall colors and it
will taste proper
would you dry it cure it and smoke it so
that's why flushing is important you
want to get all those excess nutrients
out of there all those excess salts when
you roll a joint and smoke it you don't
want it to turn into a little briquette
you want it to turn into a nice white
fluffy ash and just flake away so that
comes from a properly flushed plant then
that also comes from a properly dried
cured and trimmed plant but that comes
in the future today we're focusing on
flushing so that's why flushing is
important you guys you want your herb to
taste good you want it to burn well and
you want it to leave a nice white clean
soft - with no weird Chuck
so let's actually talk about flushing
the plants flushing the plants is really
easy about 10 to 14 days before you plan
on harvesting the plants prepare the
amount of water that you would normally
water the garden with if you've got
1,000 watt light maybe you've got a
five-gallon bucket full of water right
so get that amount of water ready when
you would normally put nutrients into
the water don't do that just don't put
nutrients in there maybe if you're gonna
add anything put some enzymes in there
if you're using an enzyme that will help
break down all the the decaying roots
and all the matter inside of the root
zone and it will speed up the process of
the flush it will help speed everything
up but enzymes are pretty much the only
thing I would put in there other than
maybe a little bit of shine maybe one to
two grams of shine from veg bloom but
you really don't need it mostly all you
would need is some enzymes for the last
couple of days if you're gonna flush for
14 days maybe go for like 4 to 7 days
add 2 grams of shine and add some
enzymes but then cut out the shine and
just keep the enzymes going until the
end of the process so the only thing
you'd put in there are enzymes and
possibly some shine but you would be
probably just fine with nothing at all
so clean water add the enzymes if you're
gonna do so for four to seven days add
the shine if you'd like to do so then
adjust the pH to somewhere between 63
and 65 you'll be just fine 63 and 65
that's a good window to adjust it to
then simply water the plants with that
minimal solution all you've got to do is
pour that right into the plants just
like you normally do when you water soak
the plants and let it run
now what you're doing pouring the
enzymes in there is going to help the
natural decaying process happen inside
that root zone there's dead things in
there the roots that are dying are dying
in there the enzymes are gonna eat that
and they're gonna speed up that process
also that shine is going to keep adding
density and trichomes
and essential oils to your plants if you
choose to add the shine you still need
to flush for the last week without the
shine you guys so make sure you cut that
out you can leave the enzymes in there
if you'd like to at the end but cut out
that shine for the last week
now you're probably at day 50 right if
we're gonna cut down at day 60 we're at
day 50 we just mixed up a bunch of water
and we just soaked that root zone so now
you've got pH water with enzymes and
possibly some shine running through
there those plants are gonna start
looking for phosphorous and potassium
and believed in them and all the other
things that they want there's 16
minerals that the plants really want you
guys start thinking about that and learn
all 16 of them that will really help you
think about what you're feeding your
plant maybe we'll talk about that in the
future but the plants gonna start
looking for that stuff and all its gonna
find our enzymes and shine it's gonna be
like well I've got essential oils I'm
gonna go beef up my trichomes and it's
got stuff to build trichomes but it
doesn't have the building blocks to grow
more plant material it doesn't have all
the nutrition that it needs to keep
building bigger buds and fatter stems
and going so it's gonna start showing
you its fall colors it's gonna start
turning into these yellow golden colors
you may get some reds you may get some
purples you'll get some unique oranges I
really like taking pictures of my plants
right right at the flush phase because
they really start showing great colors
the buds are nice and fat the trichomes
are all greasy and shiny and then the
leaves start getting these cool golden
tones to them but that's when you know
that the flush is working there are no
nutrients left in that soil for the
plant to eat and it is getting hungry
which is a good thing because now you
know that bud is gonna burn smoothly
it's not gonna have nitrogen phosphorus
potassium believed in them iron calcium
magnesium it's not gonna have all this
other funky [ __ ] in it that we don't
want to smoke it's just gonna be nice
and clean it'll burn nice and smoothly
and it will taste really good so you're
gonna start seeing these fall colors
come on that timing is going to depend
on your medium how much nutrients you
have been putting into the plant it's
gonna be very
strain-specific and also temperatures
are going to have a huge effect on this
if it's a little cooler in the room your
plants are gonna turn a little more fall
colors if you have a lower nighttime
temperature you'll see a little more
purple from the buds you'll get a little
more fall activity from the plants like
what happened in nature so you're gonna
mix up the solution you're gonna ph it
you're gonna water in the plants it's
gonna run out of the bottom then
depending on your container size and the
vapor pressure deficit in the room you
are going to have to water again repeat
the process you guys mix up your
container put the enzymes in there put
the shine in there pH adjusted to 6.3 to
6.5 and water it right through the plant
repeat this process right up to a week
before harvest and then do the same
thing but simply take out the shine add
the enzymes adjust the pH and then feed
it right through the plants now the
enzymes are totally not necessary the
shine is totally not necessary you can
do all of this with plain water if
you're adding the enzymes and shine you
were going to have connoisseur quality
cannabis that's what I would do I would
do the shine up to the last week then
after that I would just do the enzymes
and then I'd probably do just two or
three days of plain water just to give
them time to finish up there if I was
going at 60 days I would end up going 63
in that last three days would just be
plain water and my grow is what would
happen there so just keep repeating the
process you want to rinse these plants
out do you want to rinse the soil out as
many times as you can between the start
of flush and harvest so if you can get
it to dry up and re water it every other
day that's great if it takes three or
four days that's fine you're still going
to get if you do it twelve days we get
three waterings in there if you go every
four days but if you're taking that much
time to water that means you've got a
large container or that much time
between waterings means you've got a
large container which means you're using
quite a bit of water to flush that out
which means you need to make sure to get
at least by 10 to 30 percent runoff
water so if you got like a ten gallon
pot you're gonna want to get at least
one to two gallons of runoff coming out
of that that's how you know you're
flushing well so get plenty of water
coming out and then flush the [ __ ] out
of those plans
I do it as many times as you can but be
careful not to drown the plant don't try
to sneak in another flush time just to
get more water in there because that may
do more harm than good that may you may
kill the [ __ ] plant right there you
may just drown it you may suffocate it
that maybe be a maybe cutting down early
so don't ruin it right at the end be
careful to stay on your normal watering
schedule just make sure you soak the
[ __ ] out of it let it dry out water it
again do that as many times as you can
in the last 10 to 14 days and if you
want to add the enzymes do that you want
to use shine do that those are the only
things I would really add at the end so
we've determined how to tell if the
plants are ripe we've determined a good
time to start flushing we know what to
put in the water to flush the plants we
know why we're flushing we know how to
flush you basically don't mix anything
up and you run that through the plants
this will clean out the soil that is our
main goal as that's happening we're
gonna see colors changing we're gonna
see trichomes ripening we're gonna see
plants finishing up now you're gonna get
a bunch of funky you may I'm not
promising it depends on your genetics
your environment it depends on a lot of
things you're going to get funky yellow
leaves you're gonna get dead foliage
pull that stuff off there's no problem
with just yanking that dead stuff off
make sure you throw it away get it out
of the grow room but just pull all that
dead stuff off and throw it away now
about a week maybe five or three days
before you harvest go in the grow room
and to start stripping off all the big
leaves this is going to save you a lot
of time when it does come time to
harvest there won't be all these big
giant leaves in your way just cut them
off while the plant is standing up while
they're still stiff while they're still
alive you can just snap them right off
you can go really fast you don't even
need scissors for it once you get the
thumb technique you just pop in a leaf
off you can just go in there and
defoliate a whole section really quickly
so a few days before harvest go in there
and pull off all those big leaves and
that will save you a big headache and a
bunch of time when it comes time to
harvest the plants you hang them upside
down dry and cured when it comes time to
trim half the leaves are already gone it
will save you a lot of [ __ ] and a
lot of trouble so what do you see them
starting to get funky take off the dead
ones then just a few days before harvest
problem
when you cut out the shine maybe then go
in there and start pulling off the
leaves now another thing you might want
to do is you might want to reduce the
temperature just a few degrees do not
create a large swing and temps between
your day and night do not go too cold at
night do not try to create something
drastic if you can bring it down two or
three degrees during the day and two or
three degrees during the night do that
but don't go crazy you guys don't shock
the plants right at the end don't give
yourself powdery mildew right at the end
just try to mimic nature and get a
little bit colder right at the end
because what happens right at the end of
the season it gets cold that's how
things know oh [ __ ] it's wintertime and
those plants will hurry up and finish so
you'll see more color you may get a
little more density and cool temps are
good for terpenes so lower the
temperatures a little bit right at the
end now one thing I'm sure people are
going to send me messages about and ask
is do I use any flushing agents no I do
not use a flushing agent I think all of
the flushing agents are kind of a sales
tactic they are not necessary and I
think they make your herb taste like
whatever they taste like it's the very
end why would I want to put in a new
ingredient I want to get everything out
so I do not use a flushing agent if I
were to use anything I would just use
the solution I told you the enzymes in
the shine and then I would add powdered
coconut water would be the only flushing
solution that I would use and a lot of
people are saying what yea coconut water
would be ideal but that would get very
expensive to buy it have that much
coconut water imagine trying to get a
five gallon bucket of coconut water
shipped to your house every three days
for 14 days that's gonna add up it's
gonna get real expensive but you can buy
powdered coconut water it is readily
available from a lot of gross stores
bill the soil can take good care of you
they do not sponsor the show or anything
but I know that that's a reliable source
for powdered coconut water also
something I should mention a lot of
people are growing no-till a lot of
people are growing in living soil or
super soil or some sort of live soil you
guys if that is what you're working with
you probably do not need to flush
because you have created the perfect
environment inside
plants rhizosphere tor it's taking up
what it needs you're not feeding it
bottled nutrients it's not being
force-fed [ __ ] so it doesn't need to be
flushed anything our buddies sub cool
when he would mix up a batch of super
soil and put a plant in there he would
just feed it water for the whole
flowering phase and he would say I've
been flushing the entire time so before
people started sending me emails yes
there are some situations where you may
not need to flush if you were going
no-till if you're going all organic
flushing is not a thing now
if you're running that you're already up
to speed and you know that we don't need
to teach you about flushing you were in
the advanced blackbelt class already
I've got one more thing I should mention
before I wrap up this so called quickie
episode that's gone on for 20 minutes
you guys are very welcome thank you for
listening
good thing to do is to measure the EC or
the ppm of your runoff water you are
pouring a bunch of water into your
plants right collect it collect the
water that comes out of the bottom of
your plant into some sort of a vessel
put your pH pen in there put your EC or
ppm pen in there and see what the EC is
now if you're in a soil or a soilless
mix you're only gonna get down so low if
you're in cocoa you can get those PPM's
down really really low see how low you
can get it maybe before you start
flushing that day the first day you
flush measure what comes out then
measure each time and see how low you
could get it and then just keep
experimenting see how low it goes every
day and see how low you can get the ppm
s I don't want to give any
recommendations on how low to try and
get it because it's going to vary based
on your medium and I don't want to [ __ ]
up your Gro you're going to have to
learn this based on your grow cocoa
you'll get it really low because cocoa
is inert cocoa is not gonna hold [ __ ]
same thing with rock wool you'll be able
to get the PPM's of your rock wool and
your cocoa down to amazingly low levels
soil soilless mixes those are still
gonna have some high PPM's because they
are soil and soilless mixes there's just
a lot of [ __ ] in there but play with
your runoff pay attention to that see
how low you can get it and it'll be a
lot of fun it'll be a fun experiment and
then you'll actually see what's going in
and what's coming out of your plants
maybe we should just talk about
measuring runoff anyway in a full
episode we'll talk about checking the EC
or the PPM's of a solution before you
pour it into your plants and then we'll
remesh that same solution the EC
the peope PPM's when it comes out of the
bottom of your plants and we'll compare
that to the ph going in and the ph
coming out and we'll see what's
happening in your rhizosphere
anyway that's a future episode I'm just
getting excited you guys measure the
electrical conductivity or the particles
per million of what's coming out of your
plant and you will know if you need to
flush more or not and then when you cut
it down right down the ppm s and then
pay attention and then if you are
satisfied hit that number next time if
you're not satisfied maybe flush a
little longer and try to go lower but
they'll be discouraged because it's not
all about the flush you still have dry
and cure to [ __ ] this up you could ruin
your whole crop after you cut it down so
ladies and gentlemen I want to thank you
for listening to my flushing episode so
so far we have done determining ripeness
determining when to flush we've talked
about flushing I think the next episode
in line is harvesting and then after
that we're going to do the dry and pure
episodes there will be some
interruptions to that schedule because
scheduled with some friends and things
always pop up but those are on the chart
to come up in order ladies and gentlemen
I appreciate you listening to my podcast
thanks for letting me ramble for so long
if you felt like this podcast was
educational and he learned something and
he would like to contribute to the
podcast financially I would truly
appreciate the support and you can do so
by going to patreon.com slash the road
from your heart and all of the
information that you need to sign up
will be right there
it is really simple and I would
appreciate the support I'm not begging
for payments or contributions or
anything I will do this podcast for ever
for free I'm really not trying to get
rich off of podcasting but there are a
few people who said they would like to
contribute to the podcast I'd like to
make sure there is an opportunity for
that it is patreon.com slash grow from
your heart what I will do with those
funds is I will pay for my website
you guys I host this podcast on my
website it costs a little bit of money
to do that every year
also I purchased a better MacBook so
that I can record more efficiently my
old computer was not efficient is the
polite way to say it but the
contributions will help to go pay for
the MacBook that I bought and also cover
the cost of the website also you may
have heard Mike mentioned that the
little microphone cover needed a
replacement I use the funding for things
like that so if you'd like to contribute
I would appreciate it I will quit
because that got uncomfortable quite
quickly ladies and gentlemen I would
love it if you would stop me on all of
the social media that is free all you
got to do is click around find me on
Facebook simply search for the girl from
our podcast you can find me on Twitter
it's at g f YH podcast you can find my
personal account if you're interested in
trolling me I am a Rasta Jeff 420 on
Twitter also you should check me out on
Instagram
Eirene or genetics on Instagram I like
to do live feeds where I go on Instagram
live and I hang out take a couple of
dads and then I take questions from the
Instagram live feed and I will rant
about your question and teach you how to
grow cannabis right there on the spot I
think it's fun because there's no notes
there's no preparation today's somebody
asked me a fairly in-depth question and
I had to stare into the sky and wall my
eyes for about two minutes and try to
bored out the reply I was trying to give
them because I wasn't prepared and it's
really a lot of fun for me it's kind of
like it's like a game of stump the
grower or stump the breeder or something
like that and I really find it it's good
for my brain it keeps my brain going it
keeps my growth knowledge on the tip of
my tongue and it keeps my brain active
you guys know that I had a brain injury
a few years ago so I like to do things
to keep my brain going the right
direction anyway I'm [ __ ] ranting
today you guys who needs a quick episode
right find me on Instagram I think you
would enjoy my Instagram live videos
also why wouldn't you want to check out
some dope-ass cannabis photography go
check it out
also you guys one more thing YouTube
I've got all of the videos up on YouTube
you can find every episode as the growth
of our podcast on YouTube now hopefully
we're able to get a larger audience we
could reach more people we can teach
more people how to grow better cannabis
you can dispel more myths we can educate
more people by having another platform
so make sure you support the YouTube
channel go click subscribe go like some
videos to leave some silly comments I
would appreciate the support because I
think that's all I've got for you today
this was a super rambling episode I
wanna thank you guys for hanging out
with me I want to thank you again for
tolerating my raspy crappy voice I feel
like I talked it right out by the end of
the episode I finally sound pretty
decent now that the show is over so
thanks for tolerating that at the start
of the show
you guys I'll be back Monday with a
fresh new episode I want to give a huge
shout out to my friend Texan toker
and until next time take a phat dad and
give your mom a hug for
and gaudy they landed