[Music]
welcome back podcast world it's time for
episode 405 of The Grove from your heart
podcast this episode is brought to you
by our friends at Oregon elite seeds if
you need new seeds in your garden I
highly recommend Oregon elite seeds and
you can find them at www.imtcva.org
ambrosia from apothecary farms the label
says this is 66.3% THC with 77.8% total
cannabinoids if you listen to the show a
lot you know I am a big fan of the Starr
dog I'm also a big fan of the ambrosia
so this is a wonderful concentrate
ladies and gentlemen if you've been
following along you know that I have
been reposting compilations of grow
lessons this will be the final
compilation of reposted grow lessons in
this episode we are going to revisit
episodes 389 391 393 394 and 395 I want
to thank everybody again for listening
to these compiled grow lessons ladies
and gentlemen with no further ado let's
jump right in to these old grow lessons
welcome to the show cannabis community
in it's time for episode 389 of The
Grove from your heart podcast if you've
been following along you know I've been
doing a long series of grow lessons also
you may know that I've been out of town
and I've been reposting old episodes
that fall right in line with those grow
lessons this episode is going to be a
repost but it is a good lesson on
harvesting our ripe cannabis plants I
cut out a long intro and I cut out all
of the advertising so let's jump right
into a lesson on harvesting our ripe
cannabis plants all right guys let's do
a podcast all
about harvesting your cannabis we've
done an episode about determining when
your plants are ripe we've done an
episode about flushing your plants
before harvest now it is harvest time in
the garden there are a couple of things
we need to think about before we go in
and cut down the plants first of all I
should mention if this is your first
time cutting down cannabis plants you
thought they smelled strongly when they
were growing as soon as you cut those
[ __ ] down it's gonna double and smell
I know that sounds like I may be making
it up it sounds like I'm joking
no it is going to stink it's going to be
ridiculous if I grow one plant in a
small house we'll see in the attic or
the basement and then I chopped that
plant down and hang it up in that
basement the stink of that plant so
normally you can smell it to the living
room right to the to the living room of
the house as soon as you harvest you can
smell that [ __ ] to the driveway I don't
know the science behind that I don't
know if it's paranoia I don't know if
it's because we're moving in and out of
the grow room or I don't know exactly
what it is but as soon as you cut down
that crop it's gonna stink more than you
were expecting so try to be prepared for
that some things you can do to be
prepared are maybe getting some ona gels
if you know what ona gels are ona gels
are jars filled with this gelatinous
substance that just eats up odor it
doesn't put out an odor but it eats up
the odors in the room so you open the
jar I used to just set a jar of it
behind a house plant or behind a picture
you know you got a picture your daughter
up on the coffee table or up on the end
table you just stick one of these ona
jars opened right behind it and that DES
starts sucking up all the odor out of
the room so put those by the doors in
the entryways of your house where people
may come in and that way there you're
sucking up that odor and then also if
you can't do the ona gels maybe do
something stronger to cover the smell
it's gonna be hard like if you're you're
spraying lilac air freshener you're
gonna smell while AK and weed the ona
gels are gonna be your best bet some
people neutralize the owner odor would
be your best bet another good idea if
you can afford it would be a carbon
scrubber most of us have a carbon filter
that blows air out of the grow room keep
that running because that's going to
keep filtering the air and make it smell
good but also
get a carbon filter with a blower on top
of it and just plug it in and let that
air run through the carbon filter and
now you're just sucking stink out of the
air cleaning up that environment so be
prepared it's gonna stink that is
something we need to start with it will
be stinky now before we even start
chopping down there's a few more things
to talk about
where are all of these plants going to
go once you cut them down let's plan
this before we even get to harvest time
are you going to use those circular
racks that they sell to grow store the
multi-tiered circle racks are you gonna
be able to make a line some more with
string and hang them that's what I
prefer do you have a space that you're
going to be able to control the
temperature and the humidity and
hopefully keep the aroma under control
and hopefully keep light out and also
keep people away start thinking about
that around week six or seven guys let's
not wait until week nine to start
figuring out where these plants are
going start thinking about that early so
you need a place for them to hang that
you can control the temperature a place
you can control the humidity in a place
you can keep people out of there and
also you're gonna have to control that
aroma so have a place prepared and keep
in mind that if you're gonna dry your
buds
if these buds hang and your dingy funky
basement they're going to taste like
funky dingy basement you've tasted that
smell on buds before and you probably
didn't realize why does this taste like
the damn basement you know why because
it was dried and cured and hung for
seven days and somebody's funky damp
dirty [ __ ] basement that's exactly
why so have some air exchange have some
temperature control and have a good
environment you guys create a good
environment for your plants you've
gotten them this far let's not ruin them
if you're growing in a grow Hut and you
don't have another crop coming up right
behind it why not just use that grow Hut
as you're drying space that would not be
a bad idea you're controlling that
environment already anyway so that is
always an option create a good
environment you guys will talk more
about the space in a minute you can just
use the grow room if you need to if you
don't have another crop coming up just
use your flower room or remove the
plants into flower use the bedroom
that's always an option but we'll get
back to that don't worry you guys let's
talk more about the things we need to
prepare for before harvest time comes
you're going to need a few to
I highly recommend gloves the black or
the blue fin nitrile gloves they don't
have to be super thick you're just
trying to not get sticky you guys when
you're trimming weed and when you're
harvesting and handling this amount of
weed you're gonna get sticky you might
want to wear long sleeves you might want
to wear just a long sleeve over shirt
that you could take off when you're done
you're going to get sticky you are going
to stink some people have an allergy to
cannabis I've got a friend if she rubs
up against the blue dream plant she's
gonna break out into a giant rash so
maybe cover yourself up certainly wear
gloves also if your eye itches do never
rub your eye with a trichome Laden
finger if your eye itches and you're
trimming we'd take off your gloves and
then it's your eye with a clean hand or
if you've been trimming and not wearing
gloves go wash your hands before you hit
your eye or scratch your eye because if
you get resin in your eye it is one of
the most painful experiences you will
ever endure it hurts and it won't stop I
don't know what makes it stop it just
burns and burns and burns and it's
sticky and when you blink you expect it
to feel better but it's just stickier
it's so [ __ ] miserable
so gloves a long-sleeve shirt you're
also gonna need some scissors
I recommend quality scissors you can buy
some cheap shitty scissors but they're
gonna break I also recommend using a
different pair of scissors for cutting
down the plants than you use for
trimming the plants when you're trimming
you're getting in there and getting the
fine details when you're cutting them
down you're using brute force and
cutting down tough plants you may need
some some thicker pruners you may need
some choppers to cut down a big plant I
don't know how big your stalk is but you
want to be able to get in there and cut
it down easily without hurting your
wrist without breaking your scissors so
I like something that has got a metal
solid piece to it for cutting them down
not the plastic scissors for cutting
them down metal to solid pieces of metal
from the handle to the blade then also
for trimming that's when I like the
little Fiskars the diamond tips or
something similar to that so something
to cut down the plants with scissors
shears whatever you're going to use be
prepared and if you're gonna have more
than one person doing the chopping down
get more than one [ __ ] pair of shears
there's nothing more frustrating than
watching people stand around and not
able to do work because you don't have
enough scissors or you don't have the
right tools if you're gonna have a group
of people doing it get a group of shears
I know most you guys probably have a
small garden it's probably one or two of
you and you don't need giant bolt cutter
style shears or giant Fisker shears or
anything but I've been in that situation
before where I'm watching five guys wait
for work because it's just me with a set
of shears chopping down every plant so
have enough shears have enough gloves
maybe get a few different sizes of
gloves if you're gonna go buy a box of
gloves buy two maybe three get small
medium and large --es or maybe small
large and extra-large it depends on
who's coming over to help you out but if
you're gonna have people helping if
they're gonna be harvesting and trimming
with you maybe you want a few different
size gloves and here's something I
should mention if you have applied any
pesticides to your cannabis plants and
you're gonna cut them down and have
other people work with them maybe you
should politely let those people know
what pesticides were applied to your
plants so that they can wear long
sleeves they can wear a mask they can
dress appropriately based on their
decisions based on what pesticides you
have applied some things don't bother me
some things I would want to put on some
long sleeves for I'd not get that on my
arms just personal preferences safety
it's always polite anyway so the next
thing we should talk about is how are we
gonna hang these plants because the next
thing you gotta buy is something to hang
them on are you going to use so the
gross store sells this really nice
hanger it's about three feet around and
it hangs in the middle and then it's got
four or five shelves on it that you can
just fill with buds that's acceptable if
you want to cut your buds into small
pieces or your branches into small
pieces and hang it on there that's just
fine but that's not the way I would
prefer to do it I prefer to hang the
branches so that the buds aren't
touching anything so that they don't get
a flat spot so that there's not a spot
where air can't flow around it I just
prefer to hang them so in Colorado were
allowed to grow six plants let's say
we've got a six plant harvest I would
get six coat hangers or clothes hangers
and then I would get some fishing line
or some thick hemp twine and I would
anchor that to two opposite ends of the
room so I've just got a nice piece of
string hanging across the room now you
can hang the plants on that string if
you want to but if you're using multiple
strains maybe you've got six to
plants maybe you've got giant plants
that's when you can cut the plant into
smaller pieces and put it on the coat
hanger and you can label the coat hanger
this is all sour tangi this one is all
black cherry now we even have one long
line of buds that get confused also it
makes more space another thing you're
gonna need is some sort of labels you
might want to get just some white duct
tape you can always just peel off a
piece of duct tape right on that stick
it wherever you want it or you can get
some real labels or you can improvise
however you need to but you're going to
want labels if you've got more than one
strain there's nothing worse than
getting [ __ ] confused right at the end
that's really frustrating so you've got
some way to control the odor
you've got a place thought of and
prepared where you can control the
temperature the humidity the lights the
air flow the aroma and the security
you've got that all prepared and you've
got the proper tools you've got gloves
you've got something to cut it down with
you've got something to hang it on now
let's talk about the room just a little
bit you're going to need I would
recommend a humidifier and a
dehumidifier and also some sort of
exhaust fan to get the stale air out of
the room if it's a small space you
probably just cracked the door open but
if you've got a lot of plants and then
you're gonna need to exchange some air
gonna need to get that humid air out of
there or the plants will never dry
they'll just get stagnant and funky also
I may recommend a small fan you don't
want air blowing directly on to the buds
but you want to move that air around you
just don't want it stagnant and funky in
there you really want to be able to
control the climate also you're gonna
need something to tell you what's going
on in there a thermometer a hydrometer
perhaps a pol grow unit you want
something in there so you know what the
temperature is what the humidity is so
you can adjust accordingly now it feels
like we've talked a lot about what to
buy and how to prepare so let's talk a
little bit about the settings in the
room since we're talking about all this
equipment I like to put a humidifier and
a dehumidifier in the room and I set
them both at 50% that way I know that
that room is staying right around 50% if
you can set them up to something like a
PL Gro unit or if you can set them up to
something that'll trigger them to go off
and on based on certain parameters
put them both at 50% have the
dehumidifier work to 50% have that
humidifier worked to 50% and keep that
room at 50% humidity as consistently as
possible now it may be a good idea to
have some sort of exhaust fan in the
room nothing major just maybe a little
4-inch exhauster if you can do it if you
can just suck the air out of that room
occasionally that would help you out
that would get that old stagnant funky
air out of there if that is not an
option
open the door put a fan by the door just
make sure that air exchanges
occasionally so you don't get old air in
there
now inside this room where you've got
your dehumidifier your humidifier and
some air exhaust try to keep it
somewhere around 70 degrees in that room
65 to 75 degrees will be ideal any
hotter you're gonna speed up the drying
it's also gonna get funky it's gonna
increase humidity any cooler the room
will start getting too dry and your buds
will get crispy too quickly so you've
got your temperature you've got your
humidity under control you've got some
air exchange let's put a small fan in
the room perhaps on the floor just to
keep the air moving around or up high in
the room you don't want it right in the
middle blowing on the plants too much
that's gonna create a dry spot and just
dry out some of those buds too quickly
we just want to move the air around so
it doesn't get stale I usually get one
of those fans that would sit on your
computer desk just a desk fan it's a
little tiny like a 12 or 14 inch fan put
that in the corner on the floor if
you've got a small room that is plenty
just move the air around all right so
that sounds like we've got a pretty good
idea of a dry and cure space basically a
small room or a grow tent that you can
control the environment in and you can
hang those plants in safely securely and
in the dark if you need to use a small
closet you can do that just make sure
that door gets opened and those buds
don't get stale in there also like I
mentioned earlier if you don't have
sufficient drying space go ahead and use
the flowering room that you flowered the
bugs in or maybe move your next round of
plants from the bedroom into that flower
and user bedroom grow tents always make
nice dry and cure areas if you're
growing in a 5 by 5 tent
you could easily dry your whole harvest
and maybe a 3 by 3 tent that wouldn't be
a problem at all you don't need that
much room to dry your harvest well
hopefully you do [ __ ] hopefully you need
a ten-by-ten but that's not gonna be
logical all right now we know what to
buy we know what supplies we're gonna
need we've got a safe space set up for
our plants hopefully you've been
flushing your plants for ten to fourteen
days there's one more thing we should do
before we get to chopping these plants
while they are still standing up we
should go and take off all of the big
leaves any leaf that you can break off
with your hand now just go ahead and
take it off the plants don't need leaves
you're about to harvest them you can do
this seven five three days before
harvest you can do it right up before
the moment you harvest just start taking
off all those big leaves those leaves
are unnecessary I like to just go in and
throw them right on the floor to start
turning leaves off throw em right on the
floor and sweep up when you're done
because there's gonna be a lot of them
there's tear off all of the leaves you
can get you don't need those this is
gonna save you time when it comes
harvest time we're gonna cut these
plants down and let them dry all those
long leaves are just gonna dry on there
and be in the way and smell funky and
there are sticky [ __ ] to work through
once they dry they're much easier to get
off now so just snap them right off of
there do you leave this [ __ ] out of the
entire room before you cut down any of
the plants once they are all Preedy
foliated that's what I call it the pre
harvest defoliation then it is time to
start chopping down these plants I don't
know how big your plants are but this is
basically how I chop down a plant I
kneel down or if it's on a table
whatever I walk to it
I usually kneel down to one knee and I
grab the plant right above where I'm
gonna cut so I've got the stalk just a
couple inches above the dirt I get my
loppers or whatever you want to call
them your pruners your shears and get in
there and cut right above the dirt right
below my hand Chuck and that's gonna
fall over it's gonna timber on me if I
got a little plant no problem if I'm in
a three or five gallon pot I got this by
myself if I've got a bigger plant
I will ask somebody to help me Hey Dude
hold the top of this because when I cut
it it's gonna [ __ ] timber down on us
so I would get in there and cut it right
at the base if you have got maybe a
tomato cage or some trellising or
something like that maybe figure out how
to get the plant out of there by cutting
from the top down I like to cut the
whole plan out in one piece and hang the
whole thing upside down and let it all
dry in one piece
that's the way I like to do it if you've
put the plant in a screen of green or a
tomato cage you may have to start at the
top and cut out individual branches that
is just fine make sure that you keep
each branch of each strain together so
that you don't mix anything up I
mentioned earlier how frustrating that
[ __ ] is don't mix stuff up so separate
your plant free your plant from its
tomato cage free the plant from the
trellis however you need to then chop it
down now if you've got the whole plant
chopped down in one piece
just get a I get a fuzzy stick is what
they're called they saw them at Hobby
Lobby or you can use the twisty ties
that come with your trash bags because I
never use the twisty ties in the trash
bags anyway they always end up for this
purpose wrap the twisty tie around the
base of the plant do it kind of do it
securely put another put a branch in
there because it may slide off and then
tie that to either your coat hanger or
the line that you're gonna hang it from
if you've got the line hanging across
the room attach it to that securely
hanging it on there in a way that you
know it's not gonna fall if you've got
to cut it down into branches try to cut
to where you create little v-shape
intersections and if you hang the plant
upside down you'll see the little
wishbone shaped intersections that you
can use perfectly to hang your branches
on your coat hanger or on your line so
cut the plant flip it upside down and
just hang it in the size of sections
that you need to here's some advice if
you have to cut your plant down into
smaller sections to make it fit make the
sections similar sizes that way they dry
at similar speeds if you've got one big
piece and one little piece that big
piece is going to take longer to dry
then the little piece it's gonna cause
unevenness and you're gonna be confused
on what to do so chop everything if
you're gonna chop it let it all hang in
one big piece if you're gonna let it
hang in one big piece so cut the plant
at the base or pull out the branches
hang them on the coat hanger either by
using the twisty ties and securing it to
the coat hanger there or just by using
the v-shaped intersections and hanging
it like a little hook on the v-shaped
intersection and just get everything
hanging safely in your drain cure room
chop everything down and just go hang it
all up you're gonna be super excited now
you're gonna want to go post all your
social media about how you just took
down your first harvest but do not do
that
here is some old-school advice don't
post any pictures or talk about your
harvest until it's gone if it's going
out for retail if it's going into your
jar and you're safe that's when you talk
about it don't talk about it while that
[ __ ] is hanging in a room don't talk
about it while you're trimming it don't
talk about it yet just wait okay just
wait because right now it's hanging in a
room and when you go to Walmart and you
post it back to facebook also someone's
going on your back [ __ ] door and
getting all your weed and they're gonna
trim it for you and you're never gonna
see any of it so don't post yet hold off
just wait now if you're chopping down
multiple strains carefully carefully
carefully label these plants you're
gonna so I'll go back recap a little bit
cuz I feel like I went fast grab it
right above the dirt chop it down it's
gonna flip upside down and hold it
upside down either put one branch over
your line that you're gonna hang it on
and let it hang right there put a label
on it or put it on a coat hanger just
slide the one branch through the coat
hanger swear it's got one arm through
and then it's just hangin put it on the
co hanger or cut it into smaller pieces
and do it that way label the coat hanger
what strain you've got so cut it down
hang it up
label it it's gonna hang there for
somewhere between five and fourteen
maybe a couple more days I haven't seen
them gone go more than 14 days in
Colorado but if you're on the coast
where you've got humidity you may get
some more time so you've chopped them
down they're hanging upside down you've
got them labeled you've got the lights
temperature humidity and air flow all
controlled in your room now you're just
gonna have to wait somewhere between 5
and 14 days for those sticks to start
snapping when you bend them you just
want him to go crunch you don't want him
to explode you don't want to just
crumble up like an old bag of Doritos
you just want him to snap you don't want
a bunch of moisture in there and check a
few of them before you get excited but
when they start snapping consistently
that is when the dry phases ended and it
is time to work yourself into the cure
phase all right now I did skip the part
about putting them on to dry racks that
I talked about you could get from the
gross store the gross store sells these
dry racks they look like a 22 inch kick
drum head I think they're about 24
inches around
they're messy and they're kind of cheap
but they work really well you just hang
it up and for this I would probably take
the buds off of the sticks and just put
just the buds into those racks
I wouldn't put the sticks in there I
feel like the sticks are gonna take up a
lot of space in there and they also get
stuck in the [ __ ] netting all a lot
they're a pain in the ass
I would cut every single bud off of the
stick if it were me and I would lay the
buds in there and I would spread them
out kind of far and then every morning
when I wake up I would go in there and
just move those buds around and kind of
shuffle them around a little bit that's
not the ideal way to do it but I
understand that some of us are limited
on space if that's what you've got to do
that's what you have got to do I would
rather see you hang them until they dry
and get a little drier and as soon as
the stick snaps then get it off the
stick but I understand that sometimes
you've got to improvise that's part of
being a good grower being able to adjust
adapt and improvise with what you've got
when you've got it people are so [ __ ]
spoiled now we've got these giant
facilities with parking lots and
security cameras and loading bays and
Friends when I first started doing this
you couldn't talk about it you couldn't
have your friends help you carry your
groceries into the house because now
they know you're growing and they're
gonna want something or they're gonna
[ __ ] steal it if you need more space
you just call a contractor and you get a
building permit and you just build out
another room and you've got a dry and
cure area back in the day we couldn't do
that you would catch people driving
their [ __ ] weed in the bathroom hey
man I got a piss well at your house no
bro you can't be here what man I just
got a PETA knob bro you can't pee then
you catch on later that he was drying
and curing his [ __ ] weed in the
bathroom anyway I got rambley there
those dry racks are cool if that's what
you got to do of course I would prefer
to hang it I'd prefer to hang it whole
plant I prefer to hang it till it starts
snapping like I said that's when we
enter the Cure phase now if you didn't
have time or the forethought to start
defoliating your plants before you
harvested don't be afraid to go in there
and take off all the excess leaves while
they're hanging upside down it is never
too late to do that all right you guys I
feel like I can reek wrap reek wrap
let's reap wrap what I said probably a
recap would be better for a podcast
let's recap a little bit you need the
appropriate tools you need the
appropriate equipment you need a good
room you need to be able to control the
temperature and humidity
you don't want people getting in there
you need to control the aroma you're
gonna need some gloves you're gonna need
something to hang your plants on and
you're going to need some sort of labels
if you're drawing more than one strain
it's a good idea to start pre D foliated
get in there and take off the leaves
before the chopped down process is
fairly simple grab it chop it hanging
that [ __ ] upside down and let it
start drying we know what temperature
and humidity we need to keep the dry and
cure room we want about 50% about 70
degrees let those plants hang for four
or five days and start snapping the
stems and see if they pop it'll be 5 7
10 maybe 14 days before they're ready to
go into containers that's when we're
gonna jar em up that's where we're gonna
put them into containers that's when the
cure process is gonna start so I think
we've got a good grasp on how to harvest
our plants the next step in harvesting
you guys is to get in there and clean
and reset the grow room that's right it
may be time to buy new bulbs it may be
time to change your air conditioner
filters it is certainly time to clean
the cover on your carbon filter also
maybe get in there and scrub the lenses
if you've got glass lenses on your
ducted hoods it's a good time to get in
there and scrub that [ __ ] out make sure
that everything is nice and clean clean
the room with a cleaning product maybe
some bleach maybe some flies in whatever
you've got get in there and clean the
[ __ ] out of the grow room but get in the
corners get in all the spots you've been
missing if you plan on using your grow
room or your grow Hut as your drawing
space that's a good excuse but you're
gonna have to clean it as soon as you're
done with that as soon as those plants
come out of there and you're trimming
you should take a break and go clean the
[ __ ] out of your grow space before you
put more plants in there that is the
completion of your harvest that is also
the completion of your harvest lesson
ladies and gentlemen thanks for hanging
out with me I think the next episode I
have a guest scheduled so there will be
another episode before the dry and cure
episode but there is an in-depth dry and
cure episode coming up we'll also talk
about trimming a little bit and then I
think we're gonna continue with grow
lessons and we're gonna start over we're
gonna go right into germinating seeds
and cutting clones and getting a grouse
started all over again
I've got a lot of fun things planned out
for the podcast
please stick around you guys I think you
will enjoy what I have planned for
everybody you guys I want to give some
shout outs let's give a huge shot a 20
friend Melanie Alexander and also a
gigantic shout out to Erin Johnson I
also want to give you a huge shout out
to everybody who contributed to the
patreon campaign thank you I appreciate
it and also a shout out to everybody who
messaged me and let me know that
stitcher was not working properly
that's huge help if nobody tells me I
don't know it's broken I can't fix it so
thanks for reaching out ladies and
gentlemen I want to thank you guys for
listening with a podcast I would
appreciate it if you find me on all of
the social media outlets you can find me
on Facebook search for the girl from
your heart podcast you can find me on
Twitter it's at G fyh podcast you can
also search for my personal profile on
Twitter it's at Rasta Jeff 420 you can
find me on Instagram
it's Irie endure score genetics i RIE
underscore GE and epi CS I read genetics
on Instagram join me I do a lot of
Instagram live videos where I talk to my
friends and hang out and we just do
on-the-fly grow talks and I take a bunch
of dads and it's a really good time so
check me out on Instagram I read
genetics if you'd like to interact with
me if you've got a product you'd like me
to review if you'd like to sponsor the
show if you just like to say what's up
and you're not into the social media you
can send me an email my email address is
grow from your heart at hotmail.com I
would love to hear from you also all of
the episodes are caught up on YouTube
you can hear all 322 episodes on my
youtube channel grow from your heart on
youtube I keep mentioning my patreon
campaign let me tell you guys about that
if you feel like this podcast was worth
a couple of bucks and you'd like to
contribute to the show financially you
can do so by going to patreon.com slash
grow from your heart all the information
that you need to contribute will be
right there I would appreciate your
support
all right podcast world I'm going to
jump in and cut off this old episode I
want to thank you again for listening I
want to give a huge shout out to my
friends at Oregon elite seeds and until
next time take a phat dab and give your
mom a hug for me hey welcome to the show
podcast world it is time for episode 391
of the growth from your heart podcast
this episode is brought to you by Oregon
elite seats if you need new seeds in
your garden I highly recommend Oregon
elite seeds and you can find them at
uw-w Oregon elite seeds dot-com it has
become a tradition that we start the
podcast off by talking about what I'm
dabbing on today I'm taking dabs of star
dog ambrosia from our friends and
apothecary farms you guys know that I
love the star dog I love the aroma I
love the flavor and I love the head buzz
that it gives me if you've been
following along with the podcast you
know that I've been doing a long series
of grow lessons at this point in the
grow lessons it is time to dry and cure
our freshly harvested cannabis crop for
this lesson I'm going to repost episode
number 326 my original dry and cure
episode so ladies and gentlemen let's
time travel back to episode 326 and
let's recap drying and curing our
freshly harvested cannabis welcome back
cannabis community it's time for another
episode of the growth of their heart
podcast your source for cannabis news
education and conversation new grower if
you're a professional grower if you're a
new smoker or a dedicated dabber if
you're a cannabis activists or even
someone who is just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host my friends call me Rasta Jeff I
want to thank you guys again for joining
me this episode of the podcast is
brought to you by my friends at the hell
of date seed company if you need new
genetics for your garden I highly
recommend the helideck seed company you
can find them at Bank seed dot store
ladies and gentlemen roll up a fat joint
pack up the ball or start heating up
that daybreak because it's time for
another episode of to grow from there
our podcast
[Music]
welcome to the show internet world it is
time for episode 326 of the girl from
our podcast thanks again for joining me
I have got a very detailed episode
planned out for you this is going to be
the long awaited long anticipated dry
and cure episode we have done an episode
on determining ripeness we did an
episode on harvesting your plants now it
is time to dry and cure our cannabis
plants before we get there let's cover a
little bit of business this episode of
the grow from your heart podcast is
brought to you by my friends at the hell
a dank seed company if you need new
regular or feminized seeds for your
garden I highly recommend the hell a
dank seed company you can find them at
dank seed dot store ladies and gentlemen
please support my friends at the hella
dink
seed company also this podcast is
brought to you by our friends at pol
grow systems you should know what's
going on in your grow room at all times
and you can pay close attention with a
Pio grow minder unit so check out my
friends at pol grow systems at pl grow
dot systems one more order of business a
lot of people let me know that the
episode with dad and granny and giddyap
and Max had an audio issue ladies and
gentleman that audio issue has been
corrected if you were frustrated
listening to that show I encourage you
to go back and check out the corrected
audio version of that podcast thanks for
being patient with me and big thanks to
everybody who let me know there was a
technical issue
and speaking of technical issues I am
still working with stitcher to resolve
the technical issues that happen
randomly some episodes will play for
some people some episodes randomly will
not play for people the only people
experiencing the technical issues are
people who are listening to the podcast
through the stitcher application on an
Android device sometimes it works for
you sometimes it doesn't I'm not sure
what's causing it we thought we had it
narrowed down we corrected a couple of
things it has done it again I will keep
working at getting that resolved if you
can't listen to the episodes through
stitcher through the application you can
always go to the stitcher website you
can find the show there also you can
find the show on YouTube I'm trying to
keep all the episodes updated on youtube
so I apologize if stitcher is fighting
you I am working on it the tech team and
the customer support
team institure are helping me and we
cannot find the problem alright I feel
like I've gotten most of the technical
business out of the way let's get into a
podcast ladies and gentlemen you know I
like to start the episodes off by
letting you know what I am smoking on
today I've got the honor of dabbing some
sauce made by a friend this was locally
grown and locally extracted my buddy
doesn't want to be mentioned on the show
so I'm not gonna say his name but dude
thanks for the great work my friend
gruesome cream of course I bread the
cream the cream is cookies and cream to
arise I passed along some seeds he grew
it he harvested it he extracted and made
sauce out of it then he was kind enough
to bring me a couple of sample jars and
you guys this stuff is tremendous it's
almost gone because it is so delicious
he brought me a little sample of
straight isolated crystals he brought me
a little sample of straight isolated
Terps and he also brought me a sample of
the two combined so I've got the Terps
I've got the crystals and then I've got
the saucy mixture put together at a
beautiful ratio you guys the mixture
smells like cupcake frosting and cookie
dough and then we need to take a dab of
it it tastes like you just took a big
bite of cookie dough with cupcake
frosting on it and then when you blow it
out it smells like somebody's baking
fresh cookies in the room it smells like
warm chocolate chip and cinnamon cookies
filling the room this concentrate is
excellent it is super smooth I took a
couple of gigantic dabs there was no
throat tingle
there was no heaviness on the exhale
super smooth super clean super delicious
concentrates dude I know you don't want
me to say your name on the air but great
product great work you did a hell of a
job with this this stuff tastes amazing
the only problem is that it is almost
gone I've probably got one or two dabs
before this stuff is extinct so bro come
back with a bigger jar and let's uh
let's make a deal all right you guys I'm
obviously loving these cream dabs grown
and extracted by a local farmer hey bro
great work I truly do appreciate it in
fact this episode is gonna be really
long so I've got all the opening
business covered I'm gonna press pause
I'm gonna take a DAB probably the last
two dabs of this cream and when I get
back I will give a long lesson on drying
and curing your freshly harvested
cannabis plants
all right podcast rolled I am back I am
well medicated I am well hydrated and I
am ready to talk about drying and curing
your freshly harvested cannabis plants
now let me do a quick update from the
last episode in the last episode we
talked about harvesting your plants we
talked about cutting them down we talked
about hanging them in a room upside down
in a climate-controlled room one thing I
failed to mention you should only hang
one crop in a space at a time to prevent
remoisturize
the first crop don't cut down one crop
and then let it hang for four or five
days five or seven days and then bring
in a fresh crop and lock that in the
same room because what you're doing is
just introducing a whole bunch of
moisture into that room and it's just
gonna go into the other plants they're
going to re moisten the other plants and
make them take longer and now you've got
to kind of restart your dry anchor
process so one one crop at a time is
ideal hanging in the room that's
something I should have mentioned on the
episode before and I didn't remember to
mention that so now we are up to speed
now let's actually get into drying and
curing our freshly harvested cannabis
plants now after spending four weeks and
vege eight to ten weeks and flower you
really don't want to mess these plants
up at the very end here curing is a very
critical process curing you can make the
most delicious buds taste like total
[ __ ] from drying and curing them
improperly you can ruin the entire crop
at this point don't get too scared
because I'm gonna guide you through not
ruining it but keep in mind that this is
one of the most critical parts in the
growing process this is a huge process
and a lot of things can go wrong if you
don't pay attention so take your time
and pay attention and don't rush to
smoke your new crop you've waited what
what do we say about 14 weeks probably
is what we did the math on 120 days
you've grown these plants for 120 days
is about how long it takes why not wait
a couple of days longer until they are
perfect before you start smoking it so
let's get it actually drying and curing
these plants now the last grow episode
was a harvest episode and it left us
with our plants hanging upside down in a
room with proper temps proper humidity
and minimal light now we've been waiting
for the sticks for our plants to snap
we've got plants hanging upside down
they've been deleted we're just waiting
for the right humidity within the plants
for the sticks to pop the sticks should
snap we're waiting for him to snap but
not explode when you grab a branch of
the plant and you just bend it you want
it to sound kind of like that you don't
want it to go
you don't want it to explode with
dryness you don't want it to fall apart
and you don't want it to be gummy or
rubbery or bendy you don't want it to
defend you want it to snap and pop so
the stick should snap the bigger sticks
and larger plants are going to take a
little bit longer the skinnier sticks
and smaller plants are obviously going
to dry more quickly because they don't
hold as much moisture also if you took
off Leslie for more relief they're going
to dry more quickly without the leaf and
they're going to take a little longer
with that extra leaf on there because
it's going to hold more moisture
there'll be more moisture in the room
just more moisture overall to deal with
so but waiting for is those sticks to
snap when the sticks snap that's when
the container curing process begins I
use two different methods for this based
on crop size don't forget that I run
commercial grows in a commercial setting
we do things a little differently than
we would do in a home setting I'm used
to pulling down 50 or more pounds in a
commercial environment you don't want a
bunch of jars you don't really have the
space for a bunch of jars you don't have
the manpower to open a bunch of jars all
day so we do things a little differently
in a home grow it's not as many pounds
it's less jars so I use jar technique in
a home grow but let's talk about the way
I would do it in a commercial grow in a
commercial grow I'll chop the large
stalk and naked stems out of the plants
and place the buds still on sticks into
large Rubbermaid containers so you've
got a big plant
you've lollipop tup probably 12 to 18
inches of it so you've got some naked
sticks right that's what I mean by naked
sticks that the shaved legs and that
main big stock I'll cut all of that out
and that goes to waste and a commercial
grow that's actually got to be weighed
and documented as removed waste so now
I've got two piles one pile is naked
sticks that need to be documented as
waste they'll be chipped up and thrown
away then there's another pile that's
the usable product of the steaks with
buds up it they need to be trimmed those
buds still on the sticks get
put into the Rubbermaid containers
untrimmed there's something to keep in
mind
carefully label your Rubbermaid
containers do not label the lids never
label lids in a facility and a home grow
don't label the lids lids are
interchangeable label the container so
chop the sticks out put the good usable
buds into the Rubbermaid container don't
squish them in there too tight fill it
up pretty well but don't cram anything
in there you need some air space in
there and you don't want to smash
anything and if it's too tightly pressed
together it'll get funky it'll start to
smell bad
Moisture get trapped in there and you'll
start to get that stale ammonia smell
and that's what we were trying to avoid
with proper drying and curing so I would
go through and remove all of the sticks
get all the good buds into the
containers and then once they are all
completed I would go through and put the
lids on every container at that point I
would have everything labeled it all be
sitting open and then when we're done
with every plant that's gonna get been
that day that's when I start putting the
lids on and sealing up the containers
now I feel like I haven't described
these containers properly these
Rubbermaid containers are like the size
of maybe a laundry basket they're about
three feet wide I guess and then maybe a
foot or so wide I know I said wide but
three feet long and a foot or so wide
and then probably about eighteen maybe
twenty inches deep they're the one that
you are use for packing or you just put
a bunch of clothes in there just a bunch
of bullshit's the one when the kids come
to the front door they're trying to sell
candy for church like I got some candy
for church sir would you like to reach
the money I think at the big Rubbermaid
container that's the container I'm
talking about it's just like a moving
box or something is what it looks like a
storage container we can fit three or
four large plants in those containers
from the commercial grow so I guess I
should have mentioned that a little
earlier but it just dawned on me that I
did not describe these containers in any
way so now let's talk more about what
happens to these plants once they are
put into this container and the lid is
put on them they need to be opened and
rotated every day until they're dry
enough to seal up without risking any
mold development the first day is always
scary when you seal them up and then
leave overnight that is always a scary
feeling until you get there the next day
don't be afraid to leave them open if
you feel like they're a little too moist
if you cut them down and get
in the bin and realize aw [ __ ] a couple
of these are too wet don't be afraid to
leave those open open overnight you
would rather leave them open and get
them a little too dry then close them up
and get them a little funky a little
funky doesn't go away a little too dry
we can work with so you seal them up you
put the lids on them and then you might
want to check on them before you leave
for the day make sure that nothing needs
to be rotated nothing needs to be
flipped around nothing needs to be left
open like I said if it needs to be left
open
leave it open don't be afraid then
you're gonna leave you're gonna come
back the next day you're gonna have a
bunch of sealed containers they need to
be popped open immediately I would pop
them open for four maybe six maybe seven
hours and check on him while they were
sealed a lot of the moisture that was
inside those sticks reconstituted
throughout those buds and a lot of
moisture built up in that container
you're gonna find a lot of spongy and
wet buds when you come in in the morning
that's expected don't worry it'll be
okay you're gonna leave it open and get
some of that [ __ ] out of there that's
the idea you want to open it up every
day and let that stuff out of there when
they start getting dry again some of the
sticks might not even snap again some of
them may have remoisten tore they don't
snap that that means you may have done
just a little bit too early but it's not
bad because we can get that moisture out
you don't want it to get too dry so
you're gonna pop them open you're gonna
see how what they are leave them open
you may just want to leave them open for
an hour if they're real dry an hour is
fine four to six hours is not uncommon
on the first day if you chop those
plants down or if you bend those plants
a little bit too early they may be
really wet and you may have to leave
them open for four to six maybe the
whole shift of 8 to 10 hours they may
have to stay open that's not uncommon
try not to cut them down and put them
into the bins so early next time but
you'll be okay this is something you're
gonna have to dial in with your facility
and with your technique so the duration
of burp time is going to decrease as
slowly as the buds dry these bins are
going to sit in a room ideally that is
at 50% humidity and 70 degrees until you
have time to trim them I run a
humidifier and a dehumidifier at the
same time and they're both set at 50%
humidity so if that room gets to fifty
five percent humidity that dehumidifier
kicks on immediately if he gets to forty
five percent
the humidifier comes on immediately I
don't get out of that 10 degree range
and it stays pretty close with both of
those machines and they're fighting each
other they pretty much just stay on all
the time so I've got these buds they are
in containers they have not been trimmed
yet and they still need to be burped on
a daily basis the first thing the dry
and cure manager or the trim team
manager should do when they get to the
grow is pop open these bins and see what
type of situation you've got they should
be getting drier and more smokeable and
they should start smelling more like
dank cannabis every day that fresh green
wet smell should be going away but
you're going to have to pop them
everyday and pay attention to how long
they need to be open like I said that
first day you're gonna get four to six
hours maybe the second day four to six
hours maybe the third day four hours
maybe the fourth day three hours then
maybe you're gonna have to pop them open
for an hour every day and see what's
going on and check it out eventually you
won't have to open them anymore once
you've gotten them to about 65% humidity
inside the container consistently you
don't have to burp it that is cured
where you want it and it's also in that
room with 50% humidity so it's gonna
stay about 50% humidity and it won't get
less than that and they can the
containers hold moisture in there so
it's gonna stay above 50% trust me so
while you're drying and curing inside
those bins be sure to burp the bins
every day and rotate the buds to prevent
mold and funky aromas until they get dry
enough to leave alone don't be afraid to
take the buds and pick them up right
outside of the container and flip them
over and set it back in so all the buds
that were on the bottom are now on the
top and do that you can do that once or
twice a day if you feel like you need to
if they are really wet something I want
to keep stressing is if they are too
moist don't be afraid to leave the lid
off the containers and tell the buds are
nice and dry and you feel comfortable
closing them up and you're sure there's
not going to get any mold in there
because if you leave it closed for too
long or you bend these buds too early
you're going to create an ammonia type
funky terrible smell inside your buds
they're not going to burn well they're
gonna taste terrible they're gonna smell
funky and it's not going to be desirable
and you're not going to be able to sell
it at your dispensary or however you
plan on selling
so one problem you may run into if you
leave it close to long is funky aromas
the only thing you can do to fix that is
try to air it out just leave it open let
it dry try to let that smell go away and
it's probably not going to you've
probably gone too long so make sure not
to seal it up for too long and make sure
not to seal it up when it's too moist
another problem you could run into
during the drying and curing process as
the buds could get too dry if your buds
get too dry in those containers a trick
you can do is to go pull a few leaves
from your growing plants if you've got a
flower room you probably need to be
foliate a little bit and pull some plant
pull some leaves off those flowering
plants anyway so go get I would say four
to six large leaves per Rubbermaid
container is more than enough to
rehydrate some semi-dry buds in one of
those containers we tried to put too
much in there and it made it really wet
really quickly so 4 to 6 leaves is more
than enough to remoisten an entire
Rubbermaid container if you left it open
just a little bit too long if you got it
down into that Colorado crunch zone then
you've done [ __ ] up and you might not
be able to fix it but we'll talk about
that a little bit later in the episode
but if you didn't go too far just grab
four or five maybe six leaves throw them
in in the container and seal it up for
just a few hours then go check on it
that moisture will reconstitute the buds
and give you a second chance I would not
recommend using anything other than
cannabis leaves maybe Boveda packs
Boveda packs however you like to say it
the Boveda packs come in sixty two
percent humidity you can use those if
you'd like although I do not prefer them
myself I think they make a weird flavor
in my cannabis buds I think that using
the leaves of the same plant is the best
idea alright so that is basically the
commercial grow version of drying and
curing your cannabis plants on a large
scale now I'm going to take a giant dab
and when we get back we will talk about
drying and curing your cannabis on a
smaller scale for the home grower
let's get back to this dry and cure
episode the home row or the connoisseur
version of drying and curing your final
product is a little bit different than
the commercial grow version but it's
basically the same idea we want to slow
down the drying process we want to get
those buds to feel nice and sticky we
want them to smell nice and sweet we
wanted to burn nice and smooth so this
is how I would dry and cure my product
in a small connoisseur batch in a
smaller grow a home grow or a boutique
grow or maybe something I was going to
enter into a competition if this was
going into a cup this is how I would
cure my product the main difference is
that I would not be using the gigantic
Rubbermaid containers I would use court
size widemouth glass jars I don't want
to use bigger jars I feel like maybe too
much moisture gets stuck in there you
have the same conditions that you create
in those Rubbermaid containers I like
the smaller more focused jars another
note before we get too far make sure you
label each jar if you're working with
more than one strain label the jars not
the lids lids are interchangeable be
careful with this please if you're
working with different phenotypes label
the jar
whatever arise phenotype to arise
phenotype 3 if you're running a pack of
seeds or whatever label the jars so that
you know what you're working with
basically everything up to the point of
the sticks snapping is the same we're
waiting for the snakes to snap once the
sticks snap that's when we can start the
jar curing process four jar tech I would
take the snappy sticks and chop off
every bud into a bucket just get all
those buds off the sticks into the
bucket throw those sticks away get rid
of them do whatever you do with them
compost and shred them up toss them
those are done then I hand trim the buds
I'll do another episode all about hand
trimming the buds I don't like trim
machines and I don't like wet trim but
I'll talk about that in the trimming
episode that is coming up so I trim the
buds they should be dry enough by now to
knock off most of the leaves with your
thumbs and thumb nails so trim them up
pretty closely with your thumb then put
the trimmed buds into the glass jars
that we talked about the why
mouths quart-size mason jars fill those
jars about 75 to 90% fool if your buds
are fluffier if your buds are bigger
you're only gonna be able to get 75% in
there because of all the air space I get
it it makes sense if you've got smaller
buds you can put up to 90% in there but
do not press them down into the jar and
don't overpack them and don't squish
them in you just want them lightly
sitting in there now once the jar is
full I add the lid and I set a timer I
like to check my buds about 4 hours
after being sealed up for the first time
this first check lets me see how much
moisture is trapped in my butts if the
inside of the jar is extremely humid
I'll just leave that lid off for an hour
or more and the commercial grow we were
talking about four to six maybe eight
hours maybe even 10 hours those are much
larger plants much larger batches and
much larger containers there is much
more moisture in there so for these
smaller jars I only want to leave it off
for a little bit at a time these smaller
batches can get away from you quite
quickly so pay more attention so open it
up see how humid it is if it's really
humid and really squishy you're gonna
want to leave it open for an hour maybe
a little bit more just keep checking on
it and do not forget about it set
another timer if the humidity has not
made the buds squishy again I'll leave
the jar open for only like 15 to 30
minutes to let the moisture out and that
old funky air out of the jar and then
it'll kind of refresh with fresh air in
there then I'll reseal the jar and let
it sit for another 4 to 6 hours I set a
timer for this then in 4 to 6 hours I
pop that jar and I gently stir the buds
around and check the aroma that comes
out of there what I'm looking for when I
smell is an aroma of ammonia or funk or
just you'll notice it your nose will
crinkle up in your eyes will make a
weird splint you'll go [ __ ] I [ __ ] up
looking for that aroma I'm hoping that's
not present it shouldn't be also I'm
looking to see if it smells less wet
does it gone from that wet juicy hey
smell two more of that cured chronic
smell that I'm looking for because it'll
start doing it quickly and then it will
improve over time
so I'm cracking the jar open I'm looking
to see how much humidity is in there
I stir him around if the buds seem damp
or extra spongy at this point I'll dump
him out of the jar and let him sit for a
few minutes until that excess moisture
evaporates you don't want the buds super
soggy and sealed in a jar you don't want
the buds super wet and press together in
a jar if they still feel wet and spongy
on the outside I'll dump them out and
let them sit out for a few minutes until
they feel dry on the outside but when
you squeeze them they're mushy still a
little bit you just want them dry on the
outside wet on the inside is what you're
going for at this point if the buds are
sticking together then I dump them out
completely and let them dry more before
putting them back in now we want a
little bit of moisture in these buds the
little bit of moisture is going to make
the drying and curing process happen but
we don't want enough moisture to cause
mold and funk
so we burped the jar about every four
hours to make sure we don't seal too
much water in the jar for too long we
let some of the curing process happen by
opening the jar letting that old gas out
that contains the chlorophyll that
contains the sugars that gas evaporates
out of the jar we replace it with fresh
air we seal it back up then when we seal
it it's allowed to restart the curing
process it'll start deteriorating and
eating up more of that chlorophyll more
of those excess minerals and sugars
inside of there and they will start
evaporating out of your buds you'll get
them out so let's get back on track here
after the first couple of days you can
slowly increase your burp intervals as
the buds get drier you may only need to
open these jars up every 6 to 8 hours
after a little bit and the time that you
leave them open will also decrease so
maybe after a few days you pop it open
every eight hours maybe you pop it open
right before you go to work you leave it
open while you're brushing your teeth
and getting your shoes on and then you
close it up and you leave you come back
from work and then you pop it open it's
probably been 10 hours by now pop it
open again stir the buds around make
sure nothing's gone funky if nothing's
gone funky just leave it open for five
minutes let that air exchange in there
seal it right back up then you can go 10
hours and you know you're safe at 10
hours see what happens at 11 hours see
what happens at 12 hours just start
stretching it every day by the end of
two weeks you'll just be popping these
jars open once a day you'll check it out
you'll give it a good
you'll say that is so close and then you
can close it back up by the end of two
weeks these buds will be beautifully
beautifully cured so the bud should be
sticky on the outside and spongy but not
dry and crumbly they should almost have
a little bit of squeeze a little bit of
give to them and then stick to your
fingers they shouldn't fall apart and
just crumble up like a lot of the
Colorado dispensary bud does
unfortunately and the reason for that
you guys is because it's sitting on the
shelf out there all day they're opening
up those jars and showing it to you all
day this stuff is just getting dry so
that's the problem with the Colorado
crunch I apologize for that the Grover's
work hard to get it proper and then it's
sent to the dispensary and left in those
jars and the bud tenders don't do us
justice so I apologize so on day one I
chopped the buds off the sticks and I
trim them up then I filled the jars
about 90% full then I seal the jar I
checked the jar in about four hours I
opened it long enough for the excess
moisture to come out of the jar that
could be a little while that could be a
short amount of time it kind of depends
on how wet the buds were when you jarred
them up then I check it again in about
four hours I shuffled the buds if I feel
that's necessary it's likely necessary
then I check again in four to six hours
and leave open as necessary if they're
getting too sticky again I'll dump them
out you'll want to check as soon as you
wake up the next day the burp process
will slow down over the next few days
you want it to take as long as possible
without allowing mildew to develop you
want to slow it down the longer it takes
the better the more time that it takes
for that moisture to come out the more
opportunity you have for chlorophyll to
be removed the only thing to worry about
very similarly to the rubbermaid
technique is trapping too much moisture
in your containers for too long and
causing yourself mildew or funky flavors
if you walked your buds up in these jars
long enough to where you got like white
MOLLE webbing growing on there and it
looks like some cotton coming out you
[ __ ] up and didn't pay any attention
throw that away if your jar is starting
to get an ammonia smell you've sealed it
up too long you've got to open it more
frequently and longer next time you may
be able to save it but it's unlikely the
only thing you can do is leave it open
and let it dry out and hopefully that
smell will go away
so don't leave it close to
don't let mildew happen don't let that
funky smell happen once you're past the
first few days you'll kind of be out of
the mildew danger zone but still be
careful also keep your jars in a cool
dark place while you're curing your buds
but also don't leave them somewhere
where you're going to forget about them
also here in Colorado I'm running a swap
cooler in the main portion the living
area of my house don't go dump your buds
on the table near the swamp cooler this
is not going to do you any good this is
going to reconstitute them and make them
wetter think about wetter is that a word
anyway think about the environment where
you were drying and curing your products
if you're gonna dump them out on the
table and an attempt to get them more
dry make sure that the room is drier
than the butt or it's not going to work
just keep that kind of stuff in mind you
guys think about your environment think
about your products so I feel like we've
got a basic understanding of how to cure
our buds now let's get into the
technical talk about why we do it and
what's technically happening so curing
your buds properly makes your buds burn
and smoke smoothly and it also brings
out the best flavors and aromas proper
drying and curing will also increase
your potency now why why does that
happen because your buds contain
chlorophyll chlorophyll is what gives
your buds that harsh smoke and hay like
flavor that burn your throat kind of
funky flavor that's from too much
chlorophyll that's from excess minerals
in the plant that could also be from an
improper flush but it's usually from an
improper cure so curing the buds will
remove chlorophyll and increase your
potency at the same time the only way to
remove chlorophyll is by turning it into
a gas sealing our moist buds in a jar
creates an environment that will break
down the chlorophyll and turn it into a
gas darkness moisture and oxygen will
create a bacteria within the jar that
bacteria will break down the sugars and
leftover minerals created by the
decomposition of the chlorophyll and it
will turn into a vapor that can escape
the jar when you pop it open that was
what I was talking about earlier when I
said we pop open the jar and let the
chemical reaction happen now this
process is going to make your bud burn
smoother
it's going to take make it taste better
it's gonna bring out the proper aromas
the proper terpene profile that you're
looking for and it's also going to
increase the overall potency of your
finished product now if you really want
to nerd out and dial this in and create
a connoisseur product find yourself a
hygrometer that fits inside of your
mason jar there are a couple available
that fit right inside the mason jar you
can press it up to the front of the jar
where you can read the display without
opening the jar find yourself
hygrometers that will fit in the jar and
here are some suggestions on when to
open and close your jars and how to dial
them in perfectly if your buds feel wet
or if they are above 70% humidity if the
little display on that hydrometer inside
of your jar reads
above 70% humidity you need to dump
those buds out of the jar and let them
dry until they get to 65 to 70% humidity
now when you dump them out and you leave
them somewhere that's not by the fan
that's not by the swamp cooler that's
not by the air-conditioner that's not by
something that's going to drastically
affect the rate of their drying
don't forget about them set a timer and
go find them some of you are a little
obsessive you're definitely not gonna
forget some of you are gonna take a
couple of dabs and go play fortnight and
your buds are gonna dry up to [ __ ] don't
let that happen to you guys so if they
are too humid dump them out let them dry
out a little bit get them down to 65 to
70% humidity now if your buds feel moist
to the touch if they're sticky and wet
to the outside of the buds and the
display reads 65 to 70% humidity pop the
lid off of that jar for fifteen to
thirty minutes and let a little moisture
evaporate out if you think they need
longer than fifteen to thirty minutes
let them go longer but like I said don't
start playing for tonight and start
building [ __ ] and shooting people and
forget about them because you don't want
them to get too crunchy so fifteen to
thirty maybe 45 minutes maybe an hour
seal them back up set yourself a timer
to remember to check on them in a little
bit and now you can go play fort night
and relax now your goal is 60 to 65%
humidity you want that hydrometer to
read between 60 and 65 percent humidity
and you want them dry but not crunchy
they're gonna feel squishy and sticky
hopefully but they're not wet you just
want them dry but not crunchy you might
need to let your buds sit out for a
little bit before you roll a joint if
it's cured perfectly the display will
say 60 to 65% you may need to take a
couple of buds out of there and set them
I just sent them right here on the front
of my computer if I'm gonna roll when
it's a little warmer right there to sort
of chill they're not like in the path of
the fan or anything just let them chill
right here that's what I'm gonna roll
the joint within a few minutes and just
let them sit there you know just just
for a little bit just maybe if I'm gonna
go to lunch and come back and smoke a
joint I'll set them out right before I
go to lunch and then you go to lunch and
then you come back and then they grind
up nice and fine and they're still
sticky they're still juicy and then your
joint burns super smoothly and if your
joints not burning super smooth then you
probably have too much moisture in there
and you got to let it dry and cure just
a little bit longer now if you hit that
55 percent or lower mark you're entering
what I call the Colorado crunch area and
your buds are gonna burn too fast and
you're also losing weight if you're
working with more than a quarter pound
there and you're drying it up do you
risk losing you know a quarter of an
ounce or whatever depends on how much
you let it dry so if your buds get too
dry don't add anything funky to
rehydrate them the only thing I would
use are fresh cannabis leaves and a
little bit goes a long way so take them
out when the moisture comes back and
don't let those leaves mold up in there
and [ __ ] up your crop check on them
frequently if you put wet leaves inside
of either your curing jars or your packs
or your [ __ ] turkey bags however you
do it make sure you take them out and
don't leave them for too long check on
them after an hour one hour is more than
enough go check on it set yourself a
timer don't get stuck doing an Instagram
live video and forget to check on your
buds all right so it's gonna take a
little bit for your hydrometer to
measure the humidity in the jar but it's
gonna get you a pretty good idea of when
to open and close those jars and it's
gonna give you some actual data to go by
you'll be able to squeeze those buds and
feel how wet they are and you'll be able
to compare that number or that moisture
to the number on the hydrometer and
you'll go oh that's what 65% feels like
that's what's Jeffs trying to get me to
so that gives you something to work with
it's a little bit of a cheater but if
you're using one hydrometer you're gonna
have to seal it into the jar for a few
minutes and wait for it to get to where
it needs to be enough it's jumping real
fast go ahead and pull it out leave that
jar open that means it's really humid in
there and that you're just gonna seal it
up and cause problems all right so we've
got a little tiny hydrometer in our jars
we're watching the numbers we're trying
to get ourselves to 60 to 65% humidity
inside of those jars make sure you don't
forget about your buds make sure you
don't get that funky aroma in there make
sure it doesn't smell like ammonia and
mildew make sure you don't ruin it you
should be paying attention to the number
on the hygrometer and then pulling some
buds out and seeing what they feel like
so that you know what 50 what 60 what 70
what 80% humidity if you get to 80 you
[ __ ] up but so that you know what the
percentage of humidity feels like inside
these jars what the bud feels like this
will give you a really good idea start
paying attention to that stuff and you
will get ahead of the drying and curing
game now once you've gotten your buds
dried and cured to 55 to 65 percent
humidity and you don't see any
fluctuation inside that jar on the
hydrometer
you only need to crack them open to
check on them or pull out some buds to
smoke you don't need to keep popping
those jars open they're gonna get too
dry if you do that so you can trap the
moisture in there leave it right at that
point and your bud will be perfectly
cured for whenever you need it now
I've said before that I don't like the
Boveda packs but they work if you do
[ __ ] up the Boveda packs I would buy are
the sixty-two percent and you could just
drop them right inside your jar it'll
help reconstitute that package or that
jar and then sometimes I feel like they
leave kind of a watery flavor on the
buds but I guess I'd rather have a
properly cured but it has that aroma
than some Colorado crunch it's just
gonna burn up when I light my joint at
the show so ladies and gentlemen that is
my dry and cure episode I want to thank
you guys for listening if you have
questions please send them to me my
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I would love to continue the
conversation and clear up anything I
left out for you just let me know also
this is a good time for me to recommend
my patreon campaign patreon is a website
that gives you as a podcast listener the
opportunity to contribute financially to
my podcasting efforts if you feel like
this podcast was worth a couple of bucks
if you feel like you had some fun if you
feel like you learn
something I would encourage you to go to
patreon.com/scishow on pain I know that
not everybody is able to financially
contribute to the show I will always
keep this show free for everybody I want
everybody to be able to hear my message
I want everybody to be able to improve
their garden I want everybody to have
better medicine I want better cannabis
worldwide and I'm gonna do my part for
free but there are people who would like
to contribute there are people that feel
like they can help out I would
appreciate that help what I do with that
funding is I pay for my website I
actually bought a MacBook so I need to
pay for the MacBook I actually buy these
little microphone covers so that when
granny and giddy are on they don't have
to spit into these same microphone
covers over and over again so there are
things like that that do need to be
covered and I do appreciate the support
you guys are not begging if you don't
know that it's an option you don't know
how you can help out so I do appreciate
everybody that has helped out with the
patreon campaign it blows my mind every
month to see that come in thank you also
you guys thanks for listening to the
podcast just thanks for putting your
trust in me thanks for believing in me
you guys are risking your gardens on my
advice and that means a lot to me so
thank you you guys I'm gonna start
wrapping up this podcast ona thank you
again for listening to the show thanks
for hanging out for the drain cure
episode I hope you learned a lot I will
have a trimming episode coming up and
then we're gonna talk about restarting
the garden I've got a bunch of great
plans for the podcast thanks for hanging
out thanks for all the great emails
thanks for all the great messages I've
been getting it is really encouraging
you guys I would appreciate it if you
stalked me on all the social media you
can find me on Facebook simply search
for the girl from your heart podcast on
Twitter it's at G fyh podcast on
Instagram I use Irie underscore genetics
I RIE underscore GE and ET ICS I re
underscore genetics on instagram check
out my cannabis photography also join in
on my live videos I drop into Instagram
live and I hang out with my friends I
take a few too many dads and we talk
about growing cannabis who knows what we
may talk about on the live feed so pop
in check it out say what's up hangout
maybe I'll answer your questions in the
live feed also if you've got something
you'd like to say and you're not into
the social media or if you'd like to
sponsor the
or if you've got a product do you like
me to review you can send me an email my
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com you know I would love to
hear from you ladies and gentlemen don't
forget that the show is available on
iTunes and stitcher and every single
episode is available on youtube simply
search for the girl from your heart a
podcast on youtube you guys I want to
thank you for listening thank you for
all the love and support I cannot wait
for the comments from this episode you
guys I'll be back in just a few days
thanks again for hanging out with me I
usually in these episodes by giving a
shout out to one specific person but on
this episode I want to give a shout out
to everybody who is listening if you
hear this big shout out high-five fist
bump
however you do it thank you shout out to
you ladies and gentlemen until next time
take a phat dad and give your mom a hug
for me
[Music]
hey welcome to the show podcast world it
is time for episode 393 of the Grove
from your heart podcast this episode is
brought to you by Oregon elite seeds if
you're looking for new seeds for your
garden I highly recommend Oregon elite
seeds and you can find them at
www.artoffire.com contraband extracts
available at a cut above in Colorado
Springs this concentrate has a great
aroma and flavor it is sweet orange and
candy with a hint of pepper and spice at
the backend and the high is tremendous
it goes straight to my head
it goes straight behind my eyes it kind
of makes it hard to think it makes it
hard to pay attention but that is
exactly what I'm looking for in a
concentrate so shout out to our friends
at contraband extract and a big shout
out to everyone at a cut above if you
have been following along with the
podcast you know I have been doing a
long series of grow lessons this is
going to be a nother grow lesson however
this is going to be a reposted episode a
while back I did an episode about
trimming our freshly harvested cannabis
it was originally posted as episode 327
it falls right in line with our grow
lessons so I'm going to repost it as
episode 393 I hope everybody enjoys this
repost ladies and gentlemen let's jump
right in to trimming our freshly
harvested cannabis
welcome back cannabis community it's
time for another episode of the grow
from their heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
that's right after a new grower if
you're a professional grower if you're a
new smoker or a dedicated davor
if you're a cannabis activists or even
someone who is just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host my friends call me Rasta Jeff I
want to thank you guys again for joining
me this episode of the podcast is
brought to you by my friends at the hell
a dank seed company if you need new
genetics for your garden I highly
recommend the hella dank seed company
you can find them at dank seed dot store
ladies and gentlemen
roll up a fat joint pack up the bong or
start eating up that daybreak because
it's time for another episode of to grow
from your heart live text
[Music]
welcome back podcast world it's time for
episode 327 of the girl from your heart
podcast thanks again for joining me you
know I like to start the episode off by
letting you know what I'm smoking on
today I'm taking dad's of this New York
City diesel ambrosia batter from
apothecary farms I'm giving it a nice
smell right now this stuff smells like
like diesel fuel with a little bit of
lemons maybe a hint of oranges and then
there's kind of a sweet tart sort of
smell on top of it that I really enjoy a
one thing about the New York City diesel
and broza batter here that I'm smoking
on my eyes really don't get red when I
smoke I can smoke and I don't get red
eyed but when I take one dab of this New
York City diesel my eyes go fully
bloodshot red I'm not sure what does it
but I get super red I get super head
height from it and I really enjoy it and
if that weren't enough I've been adding
this sour amnesia high cannabinoid
full-spectrum extract into the mix and
it just adds a really nice it's like
turbo charging my dad it is really nice
I like the lung expansion and the flavor
from the New York City diesel then you
put the high cannabinoid full-spectrum
extract on top and it really makes it
like a turbocharged dad so I am in the
mood for a podcast you guys I feel super
rambley I feel like they got a lot of
energy let's get into a podcast this
episode is going to be all about
trimming your cannabis plants that's
right we've learned how to tell when the
plants are ripe we've learned how to cut
them down we've learned how to harvest
them we learned how to hang them until
they're ready to snap
we know pretty well how to dry and cure
now let's talk about trimming our plants
now there are two different ways you can
trim there's wet trim and there is dry
trim I definitely prefer dry trim I'm
gonna say why is dry trim better
I think dry trim is better because it's
less sticky and it's much easier to work
with it's also less work the leaves are
dry those leaves are gonna fall off all
you have to do is just brush them with
your thumb maybe touch them with the
scissors and those brittle leaves will
come right off of there the buds have
dried and tightened up and then it's a
little more obvious for a new trimmer
what to take off you just want to take
off that fluffy outside [ __ ]
so it's a little less work it's less
sticky and there's also less chance to
ruin your buds by improperly storing
them a lot of people once the buds are
trimmed if they wet trim they like to
just shove them into a container or a
package and then those wet buds go into
the container and that's when they get
ruined so we're not even gonna let that
happen we're gonna let the buds dry then
we're gonna trim them then we'll put
them in a container now a lot of people
have listened to the dry and curing
episode you may be trimming these buds
before they go into the jar for cure you
may be trimming these buds after they've
been in the cure jar for a little while
it's all the same process the leaves
should be similar in dryness they should
just be popping right off of there you
might not even need scissors for this
sometimes when I'm dry trimming the only
thing I use my scissors for is for
cutting the plant into smaller pieces
and cutting the sticks out and cutting
the bigger buds down to smaller buds now
let's talk about a few preparations we
can make in a few items we can have to
create a comfortable and successful trim
environment for ourselves
trimming sucks it's going to take a long
time you're sitting in a chair with your
elbows up high staring straight into
something for a long time your neck your
elbows your eyes your back that stuff
all gets sore and tired so let's try to
make it as comfortable as possible I
like to have a nice clean space I've got
this table where I like to do my work I
clean the whole table off there's
nothing on the table except my dr.
pepper and some trim supplies maybe my
phone for some entertainment but it's
just there for music I'm not gonna be
touching it don't have your phone out if
you're trimming here guys it's so
[ __ ] distracting and it'll slow you
down it'll take twice as long put on a
podcast hit play
start [ __ ] trimming anyway I like to
have the table nice and clean I don't
need [ __ ] in my way I need maybe my
scissors
my buds into smaller pieces and then
just a few basic essentials and we'll
talk about those a nice clean space I
also like a nice comfortable chair
you're gonna be sitting there for a
while get a cozy chair so a nice clean
workspace in a cozy chair are super
important for me for trimming but then
you need some sort of entertainment
hopefully you've got somebody there to
talk to
usually I got Mike or somebody around to
[ __ ] with some sort of conversation
makes trimming go much more smoothly but
if you don't have that option put on a
podcast you guys I like to put on a
podcast of course I recommend old
episodes of the growth from your heart
podcast put on some Joe Rogan something
like that maybe a YouTube video
something to entertain yourself to
listen to but nothing to look at back in
the day we used to trim all around the
TV and we would watch youtube videos and
trim I found that that is super
distracting don't watch videos people
will put their [ __ ] scissors down and
you'll catch them just watching TV if
you're paying people to trim don't have
a TV in the room podcasts maybe some
stand-up comedy it's hard to get
everybody on the same page when it comes
to music but maybe play some good music
just some sort of stuff to make it
comfortable and help the time pass
without your brain going crazy is what
I'm getting at you guys so you got a
clean space you got a chair to sit in
you got a good YouTube video on you got
a podcast going to know your cozy your
mind is entertained now you need some
gloves put some rubber gloves on you
want to wear gloves and you're trimming
you're going to get extremely sticky you
don't want to have to itch your face
and have to go wash your hands just to
scratch your face you're gonna be your
hands are gonna be covered in trichomes
and resin you guys wear gloves also you
need some good scissors I like the
little tiny Fiskars diamond tip scissors
that you get you can they're expensive
at the gross store they're cheaper at
Hobby Lobby they saw them in the craft
section right the craft section of Hobby
Lobby that's all of Hobby Lobby there's
some in the fabric section over the buy
the fabric there are Fiskars diamond tip
titanium scissors I really like those
they work really well for trimming
they're super light get something with
the spring in it that opens on its own
because you don't want to have to be
opening and closing scissors you don't
want the kind of scissors that have
loops that go around your fingers
because you're gonna be cutting for so
long those little loops around your
fingers are gonna dig into you you just
want lightweight super fast trimming
shears they're easy to find and they're
affordable maybe get yourselves two pair
so that you can set one in the rubbing
alcohol to clean off you can dirty up
another pair swap them out real quick
not have to spend a lot of time cleaning
so you need some good gloves some good
scissors then you need some containers
you need a container for untrimmed buds
I recommend a five-gallon bucket for the
untrimmed buds maybe you don't have that
much herb maybe some smaller will work
then you need another container for
trimmed buds then you need another
container for savable trim and then we
need another container for waste so you
need trimmed buds untrimmed buds usable
trim and waste a couple other things I'm
gonna recommend you're gonna say why the
hell would he recommend this for a grow
i would recommend either some coconut
oil or some baby oil for your trim
session you're gonna say why do we need
that here is why when your fingers and
hands and arms get all sticky you can
use the coconut oil or the baby oil to
remove the trichomes that's right if
your hands are all covered in resin my
thing is that my arms get covered in
resin because I'm the one cutting down
the plants I'm reaching in there and
playing with them and carrying them
around my arm hair and [ __ ] gets all
coated in trichomes and and plant resin
so I use a coconut oil or baby oil to
just rub up on my arms and rub that [ __ ]
right off and all the resin comes right
off and then you're not all sticky
alright so that's the basic breakdown of
things that you're going to need for
your trim session you need a nice clean
space in which to work you need a nice
cozy chair in which to sit need a good
podcast to listen to probably the girl
from Earhart podcast then you need some
gloves you need scissors then you need
your containers then you've got your
cleanup supplies now let's talk about
doing the manual work hopefully a few
days before harvest you went in and did
a pre harvest defoliation now what I
mean by that is while the plants are
still alive while you're flushing
anywhere between I don't know seven days
before harvest up to the day of harvest
you can go in there and just start
pulling off all of the big leaves the
plants are done growing they're just
flushing out they're just finishing up
the trichomes are ripening up you don't
need all that excess leaf in there so
just go ahead and tear all that leaf out
of the room having a pre harvest
defoliation session will save you a lot
of time when it comes time to trim
because all of that long straggly leaf
is already gone it's not even there to
deal with it's already been removed and
it will also help your drying and curing
time so go in and pull off all the big
leaves before you harvest then it's
harvest time I've done a highly detailed
harvest episode if you haven't listened
to that go listen to that then come
catch up at the end of the harvest
episode we're left with our plants
upside down in a controlled environment
now we want those plants to get to where
the sticks snap once the sticks get
snappy you can start trimming you can
also start trimming them after they've
been in their cure containers for a
little while I like dry trim I'm just
waiting for the buds to be dry enough
toward the leaves kind of just flake
right off there's still gonna be
moisture inside those buds there's
moisture in the middle but the outside
is dry enough to where you can just kind
of knock the the buds off the leaves off
the buds with your thumb I'm making a
little motion with my hands that sort of
looks like I'm playing a video game like
I've got a game controller in my hand
but my hands are really close together
in my mind I'm just holding that little
bud with my four fingers or maybe with
my left hand and I'm just knocking the
leaves off with my right hand just like
I'm just it looks like i'm playing a
video game i'm just holding the bud and
just rubbing the leaves right off if you
hold it with the bud facing up if you
rub down those leaves will just rub
right off you'll see what i'm talking
about when you figure out the technique
you go oh man that is so easy so my
point is that I want it to where the
buds are dry I want to be able to just
knock those leaves right off so here's
how I actually do my trimming whenever
I'm working with the plants I like to
wear gloves so step one of trimming is
put on some rubber gloves I like the six
millimeter nitrile gloves I don't care
if they're black I don't care if they're
blue I just care that they fit that
they're comfortable so glove up I don't
want to get all sticky and also I don't
want to get my skin all over the bud so
step one is glove up step two of
trimming is to knock all of the buds off
of the sticks into a five-gallon bucket
this makes it so much easier just go and
get everybody off the sticks into a
bucket and then discard all the sticks
now you've compressed your work into a
much smaller space it looks way less
overwhelming and you can see what you've
got ahead of you you've got a five
gallon bucket filled with buds that you
need to trim it doesn't look like this
big sprawl of branches and leaves and
[ __ ] everywhere just a bucket it's way
less intimidating and you can get
through it so knock all the buds into a
bucket maybe you can use just a small
bowl maybe you can use something smaller
I'm not sure how much you grew maybe you
need five buckets I hope you need ten or
twenty five gallon buckets but find the
container that's the right size for what
you need a five gallon bucket from Home
Depot or Lowe's is really affordable and
they're disposable so I like to use the
buckets so I knock every bud into a
bucket now I've got a five gallon
bucket full of buds my next step is just
to reach in grab the butt off the top
and start trimming now I'll actually
start talking about trimming a little
bit and the actual trimming of the bud
process the idea is to knock or cut off
all of the excessive leaves and stems
and give yourself a nice pretty
presentable but you guys know what a
good trimmed bud looks like when they
start off they're covered in leaves it's
our job to knock those leaves off we
don't want to smoke leaves leaves
contain chlorophyll leaves don't taste
good leaves don't get you high what we
want is a nice frosty green nugget so
once you guys get started trim and
you'll see what's leaf material and what
is a usable but once you start digging
in there and just start knocking off
some of the leaf you'll find that bud in
the middle and it will start to become
very obvious what you do and do not trim
if your buds are kind of airy and fluffy
don't trim too deeply just knock off the
leaves I like to grab the bud by the
base by that little stick at the bottom
of the bud and just use my thumb to push
the leaves off I just kind of spin the
bud in a circle with my left hand I will
turn it I'm looking that's
counterclockwise no that is clockwise
I'll turn the bud clockwise and as it
comes toward me I'll use my right thumb
I'm using my left hand to spin the bud
toward me and is that one side come
towards me comes toward me my thumb just
knocks the leaves off right there I'm
just wiping them off like I'm just just
scraping the leaves off they're so dry
that they knock off on their own and
don't press so hard that you're [ __ ]
up the shape of the bud and knocking off
trichomes you can do this really gently
you'll find the technique after you do
it a few times it'll be really
comfortable and you'll get really fast
at it a lot of people like to do this
with scissors they'll hold it in the
left hand and it'll take their scissors
and just turn it and trim it the leaves
are sticking off horizontally just keep
your scissors horizontal you can get
adjust your angle as you need and just
spin that button and keep cutting just
like you're giving it a haircut you just
want to take off those leaves and leave
that bud there so just knock off the
leaves don't carve too deeply into the
buds and don't squish the buds while
you're trimming them don't squeeze them
super hard and try not to handle them
too much a little tiny bud doesn't need
a lot of handling you don't want to get
all those trichomes on your gloves you
want to leave the trichomes on the bud
so you can use scissors if you want I
like my thumbs for most trimming you
guys the little edge of my thumb and my
thumbnail is a perfect little trimmer
for me I've mastered that technique I
knock off the little leave
and cut the big buds into smaller sizes
if you guys can see a stick in there and
it's like one bud and then a little
stick in another bud take that [ __ ] out
nobody wants to buy a stick connoisseur
quality bud is taken down to the small
part if you want to leave your buds in
big buds that's fine it's up to you I
like them smaller a lot of people don't
want to buy a big stick you'll see
people I don't know you'll have some
customers that want big buds I used to
have people that just wanted big buds
and then some people know better they're
like man I don't want to buy that
quarter that one one bud that weighs a
quarter because I know right up the
middle of it as a gram of stick and I'm
getting ripped off so some people want
it some people don't
that's up to you so once you've got it
trimmed up to the size you want it and
the the amount of trim you want I cut
off all the little leaves at the bottom
also there's like a lot of people leave
little cabbagey looking leaves at the
bottom I cut that [ __ ] off
I call it cabbage and I also take out
the handlebar sticks on the bottom
you're gonna have the branch that the
bud was actually stuck to the branch to
and then there's two little sticks that
come out that those first leaves were
attached to and they're all dry and
shitty look and cut those off of there
if you've got a pound of weed and you've
got all those little tiny sticks in
there those little sticks make your
pound look like [ __ ] just take it out
and your pound is gonna look so much
better it's gonna be so much more
desirable it's gonna get you more money
all right so that's the bottom line here
trim it and it's worth more money so
take off all the leaves take off that
little stick at the bottom knock off all
the crow's feet if you've got a little
tiny pointy leaf sticking out of
somewhere cut that out or knock it off
with your thumb
those little triangle leaves make you
look lazy if you did a whole good job on
most of the button you just left one or
two little triangles at the tip you look
lazy take that stuff out of there so
while I'm doing this all the trimming
work I trim over a tray or a container
to catch what I trim off all that little
stuff that gets clipped off is going to
be used to make concentrates or edibles
in the future so gather all that stuff
up take care of it don't just don't trim
into the floor and then sweep it up
don't trim onto the table and then scoop
it up trim onto a tray trim into a
container so that it is kept clean so
it's treated with respect because it may
go into edibles and things that you're
gonna eat need to be treated with
respect things you're gonna smoke need
to be treated with respect this is our
medicine so gather this stuff up and
vacuum seal it I like to keep the trim
in a vacuum sealed bag
in the dark until I'm able to use it get
that to your extractor as soon as you
can
now the sticks those are thrown away I
throw all the sticks away in a
commercial grow they're thrown away in a
home grow those should go to the compost
pile or they could be burned or
something but the sticks are trash
don't try to extract sticks you guys
that's a waste of time it's a waste of
energy they're not gonna get anything
out of it and also if you're adding the
sticks to the trim you're just making
the hash worse you're not making it
better what goes in comes out and if you
just put [ __ ] in to make more you're
gonna get more but it's gonna be [ __ ] so
gather up all your trim vacuum seal the
trim keep the trim in a dark place and
get that to somebody that can turn that
into concentrates for you also if you've
got like yellow or brown or funky leaves
that are falling off as you're trimming
separate those pull those out of the
trim don't send that to the extractor
that's gonna make your hash and dark
it's gonna make your hash taste like
[ __ ] it's gonna make it less potent and
it's gonna make it less desirable so do
a little work clean it up get it out of
there and you will have a better product
so use your thumbs or some scissors to
gently remove the excess leaves and the
little stems from the buds get rid of
the handlebars get rid of the crow's
feet
now once the buds are trimmed to your
satisfaction you can place them into a
container for finished products now when
I say to your satisfaction how you want
to trim your buds is up to you if you
want to leave it a little fluffy go for
it if you want to trim it nice and tight
go for it that is up to you if your
product is for you personally then you
can leave it as leafy as you want you
can knock those leaves off right before
you smoke it you can clean it up
yourself if you plan on getting top
dollar for your product you'll need to
have a tight clean trim job one thing I
should mention that will help us speed
up the process of trimming is the rule
of thumb if the bud you were trimming is
not bigger than the tip of your thumb
it's probably better to let that bud go
to your hash pile and trim something
more substantial put those little
popcorn buds in the hash pile put it in
your trim pile and you can make better
hash that will improve the quality of
your concentrates so if it's a little
tiny bud don't waste time trimming it
just throw it in the hash pile and don't
waste your time trimming little tiny
buds if you feel like that little tiny
bud is worth less money than the time it
is taking you to trim it
set it aside and put it in the hash pile
you don't have to trim that if herb
costs ten dollars a gram and it takes
you like a minute to trim that little
nug it's not cost-effective so toss that
little nugge to the trim bin we'll add
that to the concentrates grab something
that we can trim and get on the Shelf
and make it purchasable for the consumer
so if it's real tiny if it's ugly
don't bother trimming it you can put
that in your hash pile you can add that
to the to be extracted pile and that
will just improve your concentrates it
will also speed you up of course if you
need every little half gram every piece
of gravel out of that crop to make your
goal to make your wait go ahead and trim
that up add that that'll be weight in
the bottom of the bag but if it's not
necessary if it's just for you
put that in the concentrate pile and
speed yourself up in the commercial grow
the growers are expected to kick out a
pound minimum per person per shift some
people turn in two pounds every day and
if they spend time trimming that little
gravel [ __ ] they would never get there
we have a way of separating all those
little tiny buds all that little stuff
gets filtered out it gets pushed to the
side and then all of that those little
buds and the trim they're combined and
it gets turned in to concentrates so do
a nice tight trim if you want to sell it
but don't go overboard don't trim it too
tight and also don't try to ram it all
those little buds or you're gonna put
yourself in debt you've got to pay your
trimmers you're spending your time make
it cost-effective
now something I want to mention trimming
will be very strain dependent some buds
are tight some buds are real fluffy some
buds are a little compacted little rocks
you can just kind of rub your fingers
over those and those are gonna trim some
buds are airy and have a lot of texture
to them those are gonna be a little
harder to trim because you don't want to
knock off all those calyxes you're going
to have to adjust also if you're working
for somebody else you're going to have
to adjust to how they want it trimmed
when you go to a grow and you're working
for someone else they get to dictate how
tight your trim is don't over trim don't
under trim you trim to their expectation
if you're not sure what they want
have them trim up a bud and show you
have them trim up two or three buds and
set those at your workstations so you
have something to refer to as the day
goes on so that you don't forget and
also if they come by and say hey why you
doing it like that you've got a couple
little buds to show them you could say
these are what you showed me this is
what I did show me the difference show
me
gone wrong then they can say [ __ ] you're
doing it just like I showed you I'm
sorry so we've got a nice tight trim
we're setting the trim in one pile we're
setting our little tiny buds in another
pile we're mixing that up so we can make
good concentrates out of it
we're getting rid of all the sticks you
guys I think we have covered most of
trimming one great thing about trimming
is scissor and glove hatch all that
sticky [ __ ] that builds up on your
gloves and scissors is smokeable you can
smoke that right away Mike loved scissor
hatch Oh what I like to do if I've got
if I've been trimming to see even trim
and you've got this weird layer of like
sticky gooey looking [ __ ] all over your
gloves that's resin that's trichomes
that is potency rub your hands together
and you'll start figuring out how to rub
your hands in a circle to make that
stuff stick together a little bit of
heat goes a long way so if your hands
get warm it'll start taking that resin
right off of your hands I don't want to
smoke it off your skin back in the day
we used to call it finger hatch but
please wear gloves now and we're gonna
call it glove hatch you can scrape it
off your scissors you can smoke it off
your gloves then put it in a bowl you
can put it on top of some pot or just
put it in an empty bowl and just put a
flame to it and melt it just slowly melt
that [ __ ] until it starts smoking and
you can smoke that sizzurp hash that
glove hash you can smoke it right away
but please don't pass that [ __ ] to me if
you did that off your skin and weren't
wearing gloves I don't want to smoke
your skin so that's one good thing about
trimming is you get scissor hash right
away I think that anything that sticks
to your gloves
that's yours you get to smoke that if
you come trim for me and that should
stick to your gloves I have no problem
with you rolling that right off your
glove put that in a pipe and smoke it
right in front of me you earned that
that is your scissor hatch that means
you're trimming your ass off if it's on
your scissors scrape your scissors off
smoke that [ __ ] what a lot of people
will do all the trimmers in the room
will just gather all their scissor hash
into one pile and put it into a big ball
and then at the end of the day you guys
all smoke that together it's like a
little celebration but it's smokeable
that's my point
you can make edibles out of it if you
want to but I would recommend smoking it
Mike loves smoking it's not my favorite
to smoke it's a little lots heavy on the
lungs and it tastes kind of wet but it
is potent and it will give you a big fat
hit another great thing about dry
trimming that I didn't mention is that
when you are done trimming you can now
weigh your product
you've been cutting off the extra crap
and throwing that one pile that you've
been throwing those finished
into one pile all you got to do is set
that container on the scale and weigh it
now one thing I would recommend it's a
good idea whatever container you're
going to throw your buds into your
finished buds if it's gonna be a bucket
if it's gonna be a Tupperware container
waive that and write the weight of that
on your container so that when you're
done trimming into that container you
know how much that weighs
so just subtract the weight of your
container and now you know how much
product is on the scale so it's always
rewarding knowing how much product
you've got right at the end of the trim
process when you wet trim you don't know
is you've got a way for it to dry still
so when people say how much did you trim
today and they said I trimmed a black
pound how do you know bro it was wet
it's got a dry we'll find out in a few
days so if you're paying people to trim
by the pound dry trim is the way to go
because now you've got dry pounds to
weigh you don't have a wet pound to
guess on the weight so here's one more
thing I should definitely mention to all
of my friends who have never trimmed
before everybody who is new with
cannabis here's something that I have to
tell you when you were trimming or
working with plants in general do not
touch your eyes with sticky trim fingers
don't rub your eye with the back of your
hand go wash your hands before you touch
your eyes if you rub your eyes with
trichomes or plant resin on your finger
it is going to burn for the next hour
and it is sticky every time you blink
most of the time you think you can blink
and it will fix your sticky eye or
whatever is in your eye not when you
have resin in your hai every time you
blink it gets [ __ ] stickier and it
feels like your eyelid is sticking to
your eyeball and it just burns so wear
gloves and if you need to itch your eye
take your [ __ ] glove off your hand
VIN it your eye I would almost consider
washing my hands before the itch take
the glove off go wash the hand VIN
scratch the eye but I understand
sometimes you just got to stick your
finger in your eye cuz shits going weird
take that glove off you guys don't put
plant resin or trichomes in your eye it
will [ __ ] suck that's the technical
term for it it [ __ ] sucks there's no
other way to describe it it [ __ ]
sucks you guys alright so I feel like
I've given you a pretty good lesson on
trimming I know I didn't teach you
exactly how to trim the act of holding
the bud and putting the scissors to it
is something you're going to have to
experience you will develop your
technique in your style I feel like I've
given you a pretty good outline you know
what to do with the product you know how
to get it there
you just need some practice doing it get
some buds and
put some scissors to him it's the only
way you're gonna get good at it it's the
only way you're gonna get faster at it
when we hire new trimmers if they grow
we don't always hire the people that
claim to be the fastest trimmers we hire
the people that interview well and seem
like they're gonna fit in with the crew
if they say they can only trim a half a
pound of weed when they start that is
fine if that is real if they say they
can trim a half a pound and they only do
a quarter pound then I've got issues but
they say I can trim a half a pound in a
day I'm fine with that we will train
them we will teach them our system we'll
teach them some tricks they'll get in
they'll get a rhythm they'll get a
routine and eventually they'll be
trimming a pound and a half a day so
it's all about just finding the rhythm
it's all about finding the groove and it
takes you a little bit of time and
experience to get in there and do it
also these are buds these are precious
to people I've been in this industry for
a long time I can grab a flowering plant
that's a few days in and just cut that
[ __ ] down and feel no remorse or
anything if that's what needed to happen
in a commercial grow I kill the plant a
lot of people treat little buds like
they're the most precious thing they've
ever seen which I respect you don't get
to grow a bunch of plants I have
produced over a ton of cannabis in my
life I am responsible for a ton of
cannabis but having been produced a lot
of people don't have that under their
belt so every bud is precious to them
they don't want to [ __ ] up one single
but I get that so when they're new at it
they go really slow especially a hired
trimmer that is not their product that
is your bud that they're playing with
respect them for taking their time and
going slow with it
but also encourage them to go faster you
have to learn and go faster but people
like to go slow in the beginning because
they're playing with gold they don't
they're playing with little pieces of
gold they got little babies in their
hand and they're new so they're kind of
intimidated so keep that in mind you'll
get faster as time goes on is what I'm
trying to say you guys you just need
some practice you'll become a good
trimmer if you want to become a good
trimmer and if you want to get your foot
in the door in the commercial marijuana
industry
being a trimmer is probably the number
one way to get in the door trimmers and
bud tenders are how you get started so
trimming can be really time-consuming
and tedious but it is the last step
before you claim victory in your garden
if your garden is for sale you're one
step away from money if your garden is
for medicinal uses you're one step away
from feeling better
so trimming sucks but you're almost
there it's it's the hardest most
time-consuming tedious part in my
opinion it is my least favorite part but
it is one step away from sweet success
all right podcast ruled I hope this
trimming lesson made sense again the
only way to get good at trimming is to
get sticky and get some practice get in
there get your gloves dirty get your
scissors all sticky and start trimming
up some weed if you want to learn and
you've got friends that are harvesting
volunteer to trim for free everybody
could use a free trimmer and we know
we're gonna have to teach you that's
fine but we hope that in a few harvests
you're gonna show up and you're gonna
trim your ass off like a savage so there
are people that will help you learn by
letting you trim for free if you get
those opportunities please do take them
ladies and gentlemen I'm sure I left
something out I'm sure I miss something
if I sparked any questions with this
episode I invite you to email me all of
your questions my email address is grow
from your heart at hotmail.com
I would love to hear what i skiped I'd
love to hear what I left out or if
you've got some other random questions I
will answer those also once again it's
grow from your heart at hotmail.com
ladies and gentlemen thanks for
listening to the trimming episode here
is the part where I pitch my patreon
campaign I would truly appreciate your
support on patreon if you feel like this
podcast was worth a couple of bucks and
you were able to contribute financially
you can do so by going to patreon.com
slash grow from your heart that's p80
r0 n patreon.com slash grow from your
heart if you'd like to contribute to the
podcast all the information that you
need will be right there if you
contribute to the podcast I will use
those contributions to pay for the
website that keeps the podcast free for
everybody and I will also use those
contributions to pay for the upgraded
MacBook I bought so that I can keep the
podcast coming and keep the videos
coming to everybody for free you guys I
will never charge you for this podcast
as long as I am able to put this podcast
out for free it will be free for you as
well I may in the future release some
paid content which will be bonus content
but this version of the podcast in this
format always will be free iTunes
stitcher and the YouTube channel as it
is will always be free I do this because
I love cannabis and I love you and I
want you to be able to medicate and
wreck create the best ways possible
the highest quality cleanest safest
products available and I think the only
way you can do that is by growing it
yourself so I've got to teach you how to
do that so that you don't have to rely
on anybody else
so my point is that the podcast will be
free but I know there are people out
there who would like to contribute
because they emailed me and they said
hey Jeff how can we help you out
so patreon is the best way to do that
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
also I would appreciate it if you stock
me on the social media you can find me
on Facebook simply search for the girl
from your heart podcast on Twitter it's
at g f YH podcast and on instagram i use
my other company name it's I read
genetics I RIE
underscore genetics on Instagram make
sure you follow me there you guys don't
forget that the podcast is available on
iTunes stitcher and every single episode
is archived on the youtube channel
simply search for the girl from your
heart podcast you guys don't forget to
check out our friends at the hell a dank
seed company you can find them at dank
seed dot store thanks again for
listening to this episode everybody I'll
be back Monday with a brand new episode
I want to give you a huge shout outs my
friend grim bolt the druid and until
next time take a phat dad and give your
mom a hug for me welcome back podcast
world it's time for episode 394 that
grow from your heart podcast this
episode is brought to you by Oregon
elite seeds if you need fresh seeds for
your garden I highly recommend Oregon
elite seeds and you can find them at
Oregon elite seeds dot-com it's become a
tradition that we start the podcast off
by talking about what I'm dabbing today
I'm taking dabs of vanilla cookies
batter from apothecary farms and it
tastes delicious if you let the nail
cool nice and cool you get the real nice
vanilla cream kind of a flavor out of it
if you're a savage and you hit it while
the nails a little bit hot you get that
spicy Durbin poison part of the Girl
Scout cookies flavor and I really love
both flavors and it really gives me a
great buzz so I really enjoy the vanilla
cookies from apothecary farms big shout
out to everybody at a Pathak airy big
shout out to all three locations they've
got a Pueblo location they've got a
Colorado Springs location and by the
time this comes out they will have
opened a Denver location so big up and
congratulations to all of my friends at
apothecary ladies and gentlemen this is
going to be another repost episode if
you've been following along you know
I've been doing a long series of grow
lessons and the timeline of those grow
lessons and has become time to clean up
and reset our garden for the next run I
originally did this episode as number
327 i'm reposting it now as 392 so
ladies and gentlemen with no further ado
let's clean up and reset our garden for
the next run welcome back cannabis
community it's time for another episode
of the grow from your heart podcast your
source for cannabis news education and
conversation but right here at NU grower
if you're a professional grower if
you're a new smoker or a dedicated
dabber if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who is just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host my friends call me Rasta Jeff I
want to thank you guys again for joining
me this episode of the podcast is
brought to you by my friends at the hell
of dank seed company if you need new
genetics for your gardening I highly
recommend the hella dank seed company
you can find them at dank seed dot store
ladies and gentlemen roll up a fat joint
pack up the bong or start heating up
that daybreak because it's time for
another episode of to grow from your
heart podcast
[Music]
welcome back podcast world it's time for
episode 328 of the girl from your heart
podcast thanks again for joining me you
know I like to start the show off by
letting you know what I'm dabbing today
I'm smoking star dog and Broza batter
from our friends at apothecary farms if
you know me you know I love the star dog
I love the aroma I love the flavor I
love the high I love the way it grows
and of course I love taking pictures of
star dogs she's a very photogenic stream
so today I'm taking dabs of star dog and
Broz your batter from our friends at
apothecary now if you've been following
the show lately you've probably caught
the episodes about determining ripeness
of your cannabis plants then we did an
episode about flushing your plants then
we did an episode about harvesting then
we did an episode about drying and
curing your canvas plants then we did an
episode about trimming now it is time to
clean up the grow room and get restarted
for the next cycle let's talk a little
bit about after harvest cleaning it
sounds pretty basic but there are a few
things you may overlook now if you had
bugs or powdery mildew you may want to
step up your cleaning product you may
want to step up your cleaning regimen
but if you didn't have any bugs or any
issues I think a light bleach and water
solution should work or maybe you might
want to get yourself some flies in and
use 15 to 20 mils of 5n per gallon of
water use that to clean up your whole
grow either way whatever product you use
let's clean everything let's clean the
walls wipe down every inch of every wall
start at one section at the top and just
work your way down and to the right and
then just keep going until you've
covered every inch of that grow room
also if you can reach scrub the ceiling
if you can't reach find me I can
probably reach if not get a ladder scrub
the ceiling let's clean it with either
bleach and hot water or flies in and hot
water and just get anything off of there
that may be hiding that we don't want in
that grow room maybe you've got a spider
light up there chilling out maybe you've
got a little bit of powdery mildew Spore
that you don't know about maybe there's
a piece of pollen up there that you
don't know about let's clean everything
just to be sure so clean the walls clean
the ceiling clean your light reflectors
clean the lights the top of the lights
they're probably dusty up on top the
reflectors they're dusty on the inside
clean those things take this opportunity
while the rooms empty and clean
everything you guys so take the light
reflectors down if you think they need
some cleaning clean them hang them back
up clean your fans take the fans off of
the wall take the little grate off the
front unscrew the little thing that
holds the blades on take the blades off
clean the blades I know they're dirty
fans get disgusting the grate on the
back is filled with muck and hair and
just weird random gunk that I can't even
tell you what it is clean that [ __ ] out
of there you're probably gonna be
disgusted that you've been blowing that
[ __ ] around in your grow clean your fans
while you're cleaning the fans look at
anything that moves air or blows air
look at the air return on your
dehumidifier that thing's pulling in a
bunch of water and a bunch of air and
then it's blowing air back out does that
filter need to be changed does that
dehumidifier need to be cleaned off is
the water line that's draining water out
of your dehumidifier as it gunky does it
need to be cleaned is the reservoir that
you're dreaming your dehumidifier water
into starting to develop slime and algae
if so you need to clean that stay on top
of those sort
things so clean the walls clean the
whites clean the fans clean your
dehumidifier dust everything the top of
everything is dusty the top of
everything is funky you've been spraying
pesticides in there
imagine you sprayed some stinky
pesticide like a Xamax in there then it
got dusty it's just sticking to the eyes
of AX it's funky it's gross clean
everything wipe it and dust the tops of
everything clean your hydro tables if
you've got tables in the room clean them
if you've got trays and you can take
them outside take them outside spray
them down with the hose if you've got a
power washer it'll look the power washer
if those tables are real dirty scrub
them down with some Faiz and scrub them
down with some bleach make sure you
rinse them out real good and just get
them real clean you guys the Phi's head
is gonna foam up be prepared for that
you're gonna make foam with flies an and
make sure you clean everything out when
you're done using cleaning products
clean out your tables and reservoirs
really well if you use a cleaning
product but rinse the [ __ ] out of those
hydro tables rinse the [ __ ] out of all
your tubing and all of your lines clean
that stuff so that it's not clogged and
so there's no algae in there here's
something people don't pay enough
attention to clean the floor yes I know
we just walk on the floor all day right
sweep it mop it clean it up if you've
got some sort of poly film or pen to
film on the floor
some sort of subfloor does it need to be
replaced are there holes in it as your
poly or your Panda film started
stretching and getting holes from the
staples you need to duct tape some spots
check that kind of stuff out clean your
floor's everything lands on the floor
the floor is gross clean it up also
here's something I should mention if
you've got light reflectors with glass
on them so that they're air-cooled clean
that glass take that glass out wipe that
[ __ ] down with some Windex let it dry
and put it back clean the reflector
glass also clean all of your air
conditioner filters check them make sure
they are clean if you've got ducting
anywhere check your ducting make sure
the ducting isn't bent in any weird
places make sure there are no clogs make
sure all of your duct is secured
make sure it's duct tape four clamps
somewhere so that the air you're trying
to move away from the grow doesn't
accidentally end up being blown right
where you don't need it if you've got a
leak that air is just gonna come flying
out of there you may just be moving the
heat from the light right
into the grill room then your
air-conditioner has to work harder and
you can't figure out why the room isn't
cooling down and it gets frustrating so
check all of your ducting check your
carbon filter is that carbon filters
still filtering can you smell the herb
outside when you grow did anybody
mention that your harvest stunk really
badly how long have you had that carbon
filter did you write it down you should
know when that carbon filter needs to be
replaced a lot of the brands say they
will last two years I never believe in
that I've never had a carbon filter last
two years also that carbon filter cover
maybe you're gonna leave that filter
there for two years and it's got that
little dust cover on it take that ugly
thing off throw it in the washer with
some oxy clean and clean that thing
nobody wants to see your pictures of
your black and gray carbon filter dust
cover that is gross also you guys get in
there and clean out the reservoir if
you've got a reservoir that you mix your
nutrients in or that you use as part of
your hydro system that you're pumping
your nutrients from right to your plants
clean that reservoir why wouldn't you
want a clean fresh start you don't want
biofilm and funk in there because that's
going directly to your plants also clean
all of the tubing I've already said that
once but clean it all because all that
gunk will end up into your plants
another thing we should remember to
clean is the emitters if you've got a
hydro system with some sprayers or
emitters or sprinklers at the end of a
line make sure you pop those emitters
off and clean them they like to get
filled with some gunky funk now is the
perfect opportunity to take all those
off and clean them up real well another
really important thing we can do while
we've got the room taken down we can
decide if we need to replace any bulbs
how long have your bulbs been in the
grow depending on what type of lighting
you're using it may be time to swap out
some bulbs when bulbs get old they still
draw the same amount of electricity but
they do not put out the same amount of
light so you're paying for that
electricity and it is not making it to
your plants so check your bulbs and see
if they need to be replaced
a good way to find out if they need to
be replaced is to get a lumen meter a
lumen meter will measure how much light
is coming from your bulb if your bulb is
putting out less than 75 or 80 percent
of it
maximum output it is time to replace it
now how do you know what the maximum
output of that bulb is the way to find
that out is to buy a brand new bulb put
the bulb in your reflector and turn it
on then you've got to wait a few minutes
and let that bulb get to its maximum
brightness it takes a little while for
the bulbs to heat up and get to the
right spectrum and get all the way
bright once it's bright and all the way
heated up go about 12 to 18 inches from
that bulb and measure what the lumens
are right there and write it down write
down the date and the amount of lumens
then check it now when you're cleaning
the room go the same distance away with
that lumen meter and see how many lumens
are popping up if you're not satisfied
with the amount of power you're getting
out of that bulb it is time to replace
it if you feel like you're paying for
electricity that it's not making it to
your plants it is time to replace your
bowl lumen meters may be expensive but a
lot of times the grow shop will let you
borrow one because they know that if
your bulbs are bad you're probably just
gonna come buy more bulbs when you
return the lumen meter so ask them at
the gross start they may have one
available that you can borrow all right
guys most of the cleaning stuff should
be fairly obvious clean the [ __ ] out of
everything scrub everything if you're
gonna put plants in anything that had a
cleaner in it make sure you get that
cleaner out replace the bulbs replace
the filters some other things we may not
remember to think about our check and
reset your timers and all of your
programs if you've got your lights on a
certain schedule fix that schedule if
you've got your co2 or your auto
watering on a schedule make sure you
correct that schedule before you put new
plants in here did daylight savings time
happen check that is the timer on the
right time is your timer on the right
day a lot of the controllers have a day
that you can set is it Monday Tuesday or
Wednesday is that the proper day do you
have AM and PM set properly make sure
you check out all of your controllers
before you put plants in there and you
accidentally flower them way too early
also check out all of your co2 controls
another thing I like to do at this point
in time is calibrate all of my pins and
meters I like to calibrate my pH pin I
like to make sure that my EC meter is
working properly these are all things
that you should check on between
harvests I like to calibrate my meters
about once every
two weeks to tell you the truth probably
every ten days I just like to check on
them and make sure that those things are
accurate another thing you should have a
fire extinguisher near your grow check
on that look at the little gauge on
there make sure it's in the green if
your fire extinguisher gauge is not in
the green either buy a new one or take
it to the fire department and have it
refilled correctly I really hope you
don't have to use that fire extinguisher
but if you need it I really want it to
work for you also check the batteries in
your smoke alarm yes I said smoke alarm
your grow should have a smoke alarm you
don't want to burn down the house
because something went wrong in the grow
room and you did not have a smoke
detector and a fire extinguisher so be a
responsible grower make sure that the
safety precautions are in place now
since we're checking on the fire
extinguisher and the smoke alarm it is a
good time to check on your respirator
are you using a respirator to apply
pesticides
I really hope you're using something to
keep yourself safe if you're using a
respirator now is the time to check
those cartridges how long have they been
on there is it time to replace them is
that respirator clean maybe it's time to
watch a google video and learn how to
properly clean and take care of your
respirator that thing is going to save
your life over time take care of that
also it's a good time to replace your
gloves do you need more nitrile gloves
do you need more time exits now is a
really good time to make a list and go
to the gross store and stock up on those
types of items alright so we've got the
drill room nice and clean we have
checked all of our safety precautions
we've refilled all the necessary
supplies now is a good time to do a
quick inventory of your pesticides and
nutrients and any accessories you think
you may need if you're gonna need
pesticides or nutrients start ordering
that stuff now so that when you move
your plants back into the room you have
got all the nutrients and all the
supplies you need so that you don't miss
a day of the grow cycle so we've got
everything cleaned up we've checked out
all of our safety equipment we've
restocked of our personal protective
equipment we have reordered all of our
nutrients now if we didn't have any
problems with pests or powdery mildew it
is time to start running that room and
get it prepared for the next cycle now
if you did
have pests or problems there are a
couple of more steps that we need to
take we need to clean this room
thoroughly we need to spray it with some
products we might want to go a little
harder with the bleach water we might
want to go a little harder with some
Faiz an you might want to get a product
called procure if you had powdery mildew
you're gonna want to spray something to
get rid of the spores in that room if
you had bugs I would recommend spraying
some sort of pesticide through the
entire room just mix up your pesticide
sprayer your pump sprayer if you don't
have one go get one from Lowe's get a
good one
get a deck sprayer that can handle
bleach because you're gonna be putting
some chemicals in here they're not that
expensive you just need one that holds
about a gallon maybe two gallons of
water fill it up with water put your
cleaning product in there whether it's
five in whether it's procure whether
it's a bunch of bleach maybe you want to
use granulated sulfur if you had a PM
issue mix that up spray the [ __ ] out of
the entire room this is your best
opportunity to spray everything and
eliminate your problem there are no
plants in there so you can use products
that you wouldn't spray when you've got
plants in there so get in there and
clean the [ __ ] out of the room I would
start with the normal cleaning I
recommended take everything down and
clean it then put it back up then setup
the room and before you put the plants
in there go in there with this
extra-hard commando cleaning spray and
go really hard you guys you got to get
all of the bugs out of there or you're
just gonna bring plants in there and
they're gonna get bugs or they're gonna
get PM and you're gonna have another
struggling harvest and nobody likes to
struggle through a harvest so now we've
taken everything apart we've cleaned the
[ __ ] out of the room we've replaced the
bulbs we've replaced all of our filters
we have calibrated all of our equipment
we've got new protective equipment we
have tested our safety equipment we've
put the room back together we've gone in
there and done another final spray maybe
we hit it with fyz in maybe we sprayed
procure on everything to try to get rid
of our problems
maybe we just spray bleach water real
hot bleach water in there maybe we went
in there with some h2o too that would
work really well also but if you use any
type of products like that you guys make
sure you wear personal protective
equipment some goggles and a respirator
you don't want to spray bleach you don't
want to spray h2o to
you don't want to spray Faiz in without
some sort of protective equipment that
[ __ ] will be terrible for your eyes
terrible for your skin please take care
of yourself and if you're using a
sprayer to spray anything please use
some sort of respiratory protection
please
now once the room is put back together
here is something I suggest I would turn
on the lights I would turn on your
blowers I would turn on the fans I would
turn on the air-conditioner and I would
let everything run for a few minutes and
I would stand in the room and pay
attention is there anything wrong is
there anything you could dial in is
there anything you could adjust do it
while you're in there then go outside
and walk around your grow space if your
grow is at your house just go walk
around the house just go pick up trash
around the house or whatever and see if
you can identify any light leaks do you
see light coming out of your grow room
if you see light coming out there is
light going in we do not want and cannot
have light leaks in our grow room so
walk around the house walk around the
perimeter identify any possible light
leaks also listen do you hear the
blowers do you hear the fans do you hear
your air conditioner is anything outside
making it obvious that you're running
aggro in that house this is a good time
to discover that we've got light leaks
or that we've got noisy equipment so
that we don't get ourselves in trouble
you do not want to attract law
enforcement it may be legal where you
grow it is legal where I grow I am still
stealth because you know who's worse
than law enforcement [ __ ] thieves you
don't want people to know you've got to
grow in your house because somebody may
come and take your crop from you that is
a real thing keep that in mind you have
to be careful even in a legal state keep
your grow stealth so walk around outside
look listen smell pay attention see if
anything is going wrong outside once
you're sure that everything is fine
outside that's when you can go back in
the grow room turn off the lights in the
grow room and stand in there for about
ten minutes let your eyes adjust now is
the time to find out if any light is
leaking into the grow now is it time to
find out if the sunshine from outside
is coming through your ducts for your
vented hoods right into your light
reflectors into your grow room and
shining light on your plant during a
dark period now is the time to find that
out now the catch to these last two
things you're only gonna be able to tell
if you have a light leak outside if you
go walk around the house and it's dark
outside the only way you can tell if you
have a light leak inside is if it's
light outside and you go in the grow
room and you turn off the lights on the
inside of the grow room so you're gonna
have to find the time of day to do that
you're gonna have to do some
investigating and some inspecting but
these are very important details to not
overlook make sure your grow room is
light proof make sure there's not a lot
of noise coming out of there and also
find out if you've got too much aroma
and correct it if you do you don't want
to attract attention that you don't need
once you've been growing for a while or
if you're somebody who is looking for
grows so say myself I've been growing
for a long time when I used to go walk
my dog in my neighborhood I would always
discover a new grow I would go a
different route I'd go two blocks that
way three blocks that way a block that
way and then I'd come back and then the
next day I'd just do a different pattern
I would always find a new grow about
once a week because I know what I'm
looking for listening for and smelling
for I know the details I know the clues
if I hear you're weird blower at 3:00 in
the morning going from your basement
window chances are you got to grow in
there if you've got an air conditioner
in your basement window in the middle of
winter chances are there's a grow in
there if you've got one window by the
basement it has no snow and the rest of
the backyard is snowy there's a grow in
there if there's one spot on your roof
above one bedroom that there's no snow
on it there's a grow in there there are
really easy signs that give it away so
pay attention you guys because if I can
see it law enforcement can see it and so
can the thieves so be careful with your
grow try to stay stealth even in legal
states there's no reason to brag there's
no reason to set bait all right podcast
world I feel like that is a pretty good
clean and reset episode hopefully I
mentioned some details that you would
have overlooked hopefully I rescued you
through a couple of pitfalls now you
don't have to make those mistakes
hopefully everything was well in your
grow and you don't have any problems
hopefully you
have anything funky to deal with also
now that the grow is nice and clean
let's [ __ ] keep it clean let's get in
there with a mop and a broom every day
if we need to and mop and sweep that
[ __ ] let's get in there with a shop vac
and suck out you know that [ __ ] in the
corner you've been looking at get the
[ __ ] shot back and back that out it's
not gonna shot back itself that's a
great place for a spider mite to hang
out that's a great place for some aphids
to hang out and breed it's a great place
for some powdery mildew to start that is
just a vector for problems so now that
you've got it nice and clean don't be
lazy get in there and clean it as often
as you can
they say that cleanliness is godliness
and I think that most applies in
kitchens and grow rooms you guys so
clean up a grow room give yourself a
nice clean environment give your plants
a nice healthy start I think your plants
will be more comfortable and I think you
will also notice working in a cleaner
more organized environment will make you
happier
it'll make you faster and more
productive [ __ ] now that you're done
cleaning up the grow room why don't you
clean up all your supplies go organize
your nutrients go organize the
pesticides the measuring devices your
cleaning supplies go write down a list
of anything that you can need anything
that you're low on go get yourself
organized also get a notebook and start
making detailed notes start documenting
when you changed your bulb start
documenting when you change your carbon
filter start documenting the last time
you change your air conditioner filters
had calibrated your meters start writing
that stuff down so that when something
comes up you can look in there and go oh
that's why my pH meter isn't work and I
haven't calibrated the [ __ ] thing in
two months you may find some things you
were slipping on if you start taking
more notes
all right podcast world I feel like that
pretty much wraps up my clean and reset
the grow room episode I want to thank
you guys for listening thanks for
hanging out with me for another episode
this is the part of the podcast where I
remind you about patreon if you feel
like this podcast was worth a couple of
bucks you can contribute by going to
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
and all the information that you need
will be right there
you guys don't forget to check out my
friends at the Hell a dank seed company
you can find them at dank seed dot store
also I would appreciate it if you stalk
me on all the social media you can find
me on Facebook simply search for the
girlfriend heart podcast you can find me
on Twitter
it's @gf wih podcast and on instagram i
use my other company name i use i re
underscore genetics make sure you check
me out on instagram if you'd like to
reach out to me if you've got something
you'd like to say you're not into the
social media if you've got a product you
like me to review or you'd like to
sponsor the podcast or maybe you've just
got a question you'd like me to read on
the show you can send me an email my
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com i would love to hear from
you ladies and gentlemen don't forget
that the show is available on itunes
stitcher and every single episode is
archived on youtube go to youtube and
search for the girl from your heart
podcast and you can listen to every
single episode of the podcast right
there on the youtube channel big thanks
to everybody who is subscribed and left
comments on the YouTube channel I
appreciate your love and support I want
to thank everybody once again for
listening to a rambly podcast I will be
back in a few days with a fresh new
episode I want to give you a huge shout
out to my friend mama bear dabs and
until next time take a phat dad and give
your mom a hug for me all right podcast
rule that concludes a long series of
grow lessons I want to thank everybody
for listening to the grow lessons I want
to thank you again for listening to the
repost episodes I really hope you
learned a lot from this grow series I
hope you gained some confidence and I
also hope you're going to have more fun
in your grow with the knowledge and
confidence you have gained if you feel
like this episode or this grow series
was educational informative or
entertaining and you would like to make
a financial contribution to the podcast
I would greatly appreciate your support
you can support the show by going to
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
and all the information you need to
become a patron will be right there onto
the screen once again that's
patreon.com/lenguin
[Music]
contributors alright you guys I'll be
back in just a couple of days with fresh
new content I'm going to get back into
the emails I've got some great content
put together if you've got a question if
you've got a grow question a cannabis
industry question a cannabis culture
question I would love to get that
question on the podcast and answer that
for you right here on the show you can
get that question to me by sending it to
me via email my email address is grow
from your heart
at hotmail.com and I do look forward to
hearing from you ladies and gentlemen
that's all I've got for this episode I
want to say thank you once again for
listening to the long series of grow
lessons I'll catch up with you guys in
just a few days I want to give you a
huge shot it's my friend love for the
plant and until next time take a phat
dad and give your mom a hug for me this
is Doug Benson and you're listening to
the grow from your heart podcast welcome
back cannabis world it is time for
episode 395 of the girl from your heart
podcast this episode is brought to you
by Oregon elite seeds that's right organ
elite seeds if you need new seeds for
your garden I highly recommend Oregon
elite seeds and you can find them at
www.archives.gov/calendar what I am
smoking today I've been taking dad's of
gelato cake batter this is from our
friends at apothecary farms the label
says it is 62.2% THC and seventy three
point four total cannabinoids this stuff
tastes delicious it has a really unique
funky aroma I can't find the right words
to describe it it is gross it is funky
and it is sweet spicy and sour and
delicious all at the same time I really
can't get enough of the gelato cake
batter the aroma is remarkable the
flavor is incredible and the buzz is
beautiful it's got me nice and high and
it's got my eyes kind of droopy and I've
got the best cottonmouth right now it is
delicious
so big shout out to all my friends at
apothecary farms thank you for the great
gelato cake batter all right podcast
world if you've been following along you
know that I've been doing a long series
of grow lessons in a previous episode I
mentioned that those lessons were over
well I was wrong since that time I
realized I left out a very crucial part
of our grow experience we started off by
making a solid plan for our grow we
thought out our equipment we thought out
our space very well we thought out our
genetics hopefully we successfully ran a
full garden cycle we have harvested we
have dried and cured that product we've
got some beautifully trimmed up buds you
know the one thing I left out we never
smoked this
so this episode is going to be the smoke
that [ __ ] episode we've ran a full
garden let's reward ourselves and enjoy
our finished product there's really
nothing like smoking your own product
any flowers that you've grown harvested
trimmed you spent a bunch of time with
it you've really got some attachment to
it there's really a rewarding feeling
that comes with smoking a crop that you
grew I've been growing for quite a while
I've grown many many small personal
crops I have grown many large commercial
crops I've done a lot of Fino hunts of
plants that I have bred I have grown a
lot of plants and it is still very
exciting to me to get to try the first
little batch of smoke from each crop
that I grow there's something very
rewarding and very satisfying and very
funny I feels like a kid inside like a
kid on Christmas morning I get to try my
new thing you know let's see what it's
like I spent all this time with it and I
finally get to enjoy it every time I do
it especially something that I've just
bred and it's his first run with it
so I bred something I made some seeds I
grew those seeds out I Fino hunted those
seeds I know I finally have a finished
product that is real satisfaction to me
there's nothing like that feeling so
this may be your first time getting to
enjoy this experience I want this to be
a great experience for you I want every
harvest to be a wonderful experience for
you there's one thing they can really
ruin your experience when it comes to
testing your cannabis for the first time
the one thing that can really [ __ ] it up
is by being impatient if you cut down
your plants too early they aren't going
to be the quality you deserve if you
dried and cured your plants in a rushing
manner you are not going to get the
quality that you deserve so make sure
those plants got to finish
make sure your plants were flushed make
sure they were harvested dried and cured
and trimmed correctly let's not try to
smoke our first crop too early and put a
bad taste in our mouth literally about
our new crop you're gonna take a bud
you're gonna dry it fast you're gonna
try to smoke it it's gonna taste like
[ __ ] and you're gonna feel like [ __ ]
about your whole crop you're gonna have
just a bad feeling about it
you spent all this time be patient let
each bud be ready before you smoke them
so the first thing we need to test
before we get down to smoking this
product is is it ready is it dry enough
have you dried and cured
this product properly before we go
putting it in a grinder and try to roll
it up or put it in a pipe it is
acceptable for a cured herb to be kind
of sticky and a little bit moist that is
the way a lot of people like it you
don't get a lot of that in the Colorado
area because we have what is known as
the Colorado crunch here and I do plan
to do a podcast all about the Colorado
crunch in the future but let's stay
focused let's talk about your dried and
cured herb before we smoked it it may be
a little spongy it may be a little
sticky if you have cured it properly
that is okay
you may need to take a couple of nugs
out of the jar and set them on the table
for three four maybe five or six hours
before you decide to smoke it is not
uncommon to see a connoisseur smoker
pull out his jar of nugs crack the lid
take out three or four nuggets set him
on the table
seal the jar up put it back in his
little stash spot and then leave those
nuggets on the table throughout the day
and that's what we smoked on as the day
goes by they may be a little bit damp as
soon as we pull them out of the jar but
as the day goes on they're gonna dry out
perfectly to roll a fat joint and pack a
couple of bowls so make sure your herb
is cured and dry enough to burn properly
so you don't disappoint yourself with
your first experience now if you're
confident that your buds are dried and
cured and ready for consumption let's
talk about taking that first taste test
of our new crop for me testing a new
product is sort of a combination between
a science experiment and a ritual I like
to be in my environment I like to use my
equipment I like to know what to expect
I like to take away variables that way I
can see what the actual product is
telling me now I know that may sound
weird to some people but a lot of
stoners are very ritualistic and by
ritualistic I don't mean some fancy
ceremony I just mean I like to be in a
certain place I like to be right here
this is my comfortable smoking place if
you gave me a new concentrate if you
gave me some flour and you said I want
you to judge this or rate this this
would be the best place for me to
conduct that experiment so that I could
give you a proper review this is where
I'm comfortable I know that the door is
locked i know i can consume safely here
I know that nobody can bother me here
I can control the environment here I can
control the music here this is a great
place for myself to consume any type of
cannabis product I'm comfortable here
nothing could go wrong there's a couch
over there there's a bed about 50 feet
away there's snacks in the fridge I'm
set up here I'm really comfortable also
I've got my little chair this is my zone
I got my drinks right here in front of
me I got the computer so I could browse
the Internet I've got my my next step in
this talk is my equipment I've got all
my favorite smoking equipment just to
the right of me my favourite pipe is
here
my favorite dad rig is here all my tools
to keep those things in proper smoking
condition are all right here so a part
of the ritual is being in the right
place
you've probably got that little place
it's your little chair it's that little
spot on your bed everybody's got that
one little cozy spot where they want to
chill and smoke so get in your little
cozy place get comfy put on the music
that you like get the air the way you
like it be in your right place also get
your favourite piece maybe you've got
that favourite bong maybe you've got
that favourite daybreak maybe you've got
that favourite pipe find your favourite
piece be in your comfort zone also maybe
there are certain people you do or don't
like to smoke around do you want to
smoke your crop for the first time by
yourself or do you want to make it fun
and bring your friends along and be like
bro check out what I smoked let's try it
together for the first time it's always
fun to have your friends around also
that puts you on the spot maybe you
smoked it and it tastes like you just
stuck your tongue in a light socket and
everyone's gonna get to smoke that with
you and experience it that's a learning
experience just be honest
go ahead and share with your friends see
what everybody thinks we're gonna talk
more about that reaction in just a
minute another thing that is really fun
to involve your friends in is if you do
a Fino hunt so if you grew five seeds
you've probably got five different
phenotypes or maybe two or three
different phenotypes to select from out
of those five it's always fun to load up
five balls or roll five joints and label
them somehow right on the end of the
filter right number one number two or
just remember and then smoke them with
your friends and see if you guys like
plant number one plant number two plant
number three better see if different
people in the room like number one or
number three better maybe everybody in
the room says bro number five was
amazing that's always fun to bring your
friends around to consume with you to
see what you have just done so do you
want your first try your ritual
do you want that to happen with friends
around or do you want that to be a
little isolated situation I could go
both ways in my little comfort zone
right here there are two chairs right in
front of me where Mike is always invited
Kevin likes to take this spot right here
there are several other folks that come
over and smoke they're always invited
that's always fun to me I've got a
couple other chairs we can pull out if
it gets crowded I like to smoke with
friends I don't know if you want to
smoke your first crop with friends you
may be timid you may be shy that may not
be your thing but think about that do
you want some friends around another
thing I recommend when you come to
sampling your new product is make it
your first smoke of the day don't smoke
anything before that don't eat any
edibles before that go in totally sober
go in fresh so that you know exactly
what your product has done to you so let
me back up a couple of steps I've gotten
ahead of myself let's start off by
grinding up our product once you were in
your comfortable spot with your people
with your music plan with a drink on
hand you're ready to rock the first
couple of things to consuming your new
flowers are a visual inspection let's
take a look at it let's look and see
what we've done let's enjoy the beauty
of this product what colors do you see
did you trim it well could you trim it
better next time by looking at it
how did the trichomes look is that plant
real frosty is it just kind of frosty
give it a nice look enjoy it smell it
hold it up to your face give it a nice
smell enjoy that it is yours you put a
lot of work into it I think the next
step is to give it a little bit of a
squeeze yeah you may break it up a
little bit that's fine we're about to
put this in a grinder and smoke it we
can destroy this but it is yours enjoy
it so I'd give it a little squeeze how
moist is it do you think it's ready to
smoke is that ready are you gonna
embarrass yourself by trying to put that
in the pipe do you really need just
another day or two of curing that or
does it need to sit on the table for a
couple hours
is it ready this is your last chance
before you grind it up in front of your
friends so make sure how does it feel in
your hands is it real sticky now that
you've played with it a little bit smell
the inside of the bud
smell your fingers how does that smell
try to absorb and enjoy all of this
stuff especially if it's your first crop
and if this is like your thousands crop
slow down for a minute
stop and smell the flowers this is one
of the most rewarding parts of the
entire process we've done a lot of work
let's enjoy this stuff let's not think
too much about how much did we harvest
what is it weigh what is it worth let's
enjoy the actual flowers that we have
grown let's enjoy the effort we made
that turned into a consumable product
that is beautiful that has a great aroma
to it that is a work of art and nature
and science all put together that you
did take a moment enjoy that [ __ ] so
smell it
break it up smell your fingers now it is
time to put it in a grinder when you put
it in the grinder and give it a couple
of turns if that grinder is really hard
to spin your buds may be too wet when
you open up that grinder if it's a
little moist in there you'll be able to
tell at this point if that one bud is a
little bit too wet
you still need to let the rest of the
buds dry and cure just a little bit
longer don't worry you can dry them a
little bit more and you will be just
fine now if you feel like the bud that
you have ground up is ready to consume
let's talk about consuming it how do you
want to smoke it what is your favorite
way I spoke earlier about your favorite
piece are you gonna roll a joint
are you a joint kind of a person are you
a bond kind of a person are you a pipe
kind of a person you're gonna throw in
the vaporizer how do you want to do it
that is up to you please please you can
do it however you want it's your herb
but please for me don't wrap it up in a
blunt wrap you just spent so much time
growing the most delicious herb you dry
it and cured it why are you gonna wrap
it up in a paper bag I am all about
smoking a fat joint but I do not
appreciate smoking a blunt if you're
gonna roll it up get yourself some good
papers get something like some Raw's
some elements something quality but
please for this first test
please don't roll it up in a blunt and
since we're on this subject if you're
gonna pack a bowl clean your pipe you've
got some fresh herb you've got your
friends over you want to impress
yourself and your friends the best you
can with this new herb so clean your
pipe and if you're smoking through the
bong dude
clean the bong and change the bong water
you wouldn't believe how many places I
go to smoke a bong load and the water
looks like muck and I will not smoke a
bowl so just change the bong water clean
your piece and everybody will enjoy it
much more and it will make your product
taste much better we're trying to
impress everybody you guys so let's do
the best we can to make your product
taste the best that it can all right so
you grind up your herb you've got a fat
joint rolled you've got a bong load
packed
you've got a pipe loaded maybe you
filled up the vaporizer maybe you've got
a volcano bag going on however you
decided to do it now it is time to take
our first puff of our freshly dried and
cured cannabis crop like I said earlier
I recommend this being your first puff
of the day that way you know exactly
what your herb does to you we have now
come to my favorite part of the entire
process it is now time to smoke the
first sample of our newly harvested crop
so if you rolled up a joint now is the
time to spark it up if you packed up a
bowl now is the time to start taking a
couple of puffs if you've got the
vaporizer going now's the time to start
taking a couple of pools take a couple
of pools a couple of draws a couple of
totes off your new product and sit back
for a couple of seconds and let it sit
in and see what it does to you I don't
know how much you consume but depending
on your consumption level you should
probably be able to take two three maybe
four good draws or whatever you're
smoking on if you're smoking a joint
maybe two or three good draws if you're
smoking a bowl maybe two or three maybe
three or four good puffs off of that if
you're hitting the ball hopefully you
only need one or two good bong rips
before you start feeling it I find
vaporizers to be unpredictable I never
know if I'm gonna need 1 or 6 pools off
the vaporizer but take as many as you're
comfortable with get a little buzz on
and sit back for a couple of seconds and
just see what happens are you stoned did
you get mallow did you get low are you
high did you get giggly and goofy are
you paranoid you have the munchies how
do you feel give it a couple of seconds
if you've got other friends in the room
start conversation you guys will start
talking about the product you start
talking about the herb somebody will
mention the taste
somebody will mention the aroma
conversation will start pay attention to
how your friends react to your herb make
a mental note of what you think of the
herb do you like it do you like the
aroma do you like the flavor
do you like the buzz that you've gotten
from the way you've consumed it now it
may be time to take a couple of more
puffs and go to the next level now what
do you think now that you've pushed it a
little bit how do you feel now are you
super stoned or you stuck to the couch
or Eve flying off the couch and just
hanging on for dear life how does it
making you feel how's it acting to your
friends are they lit are they bored see
how they're enjoying it pay attention to
the words that they're saying and try to
make a mental note of their review of
your product now let's talk about a few
things to look for while you are smoking
your first sample let's look for some
things about the product to pay
attention to how does your product burn
does it burn smoothly did it burn like a
charcoal briquette or did it burn a nice
white ash if the ash that you knocked
off the end of your joint or that chunk
that you dumped out of your bowl at the
end if that was chunky in black you may
not have flushed your product long
enough you may want a longer flush time
also you may not have dried it properly
it may still be a little bit wet if it's
not burning properly it could still be a
little moist and it needs more dry time
so pay attention to how it burns also
how does it smoke is the smoke nice and
smooth is that smoke thick and harsh
does it hurt your throat does it make
you cough or can you just toke on it all
day and blow clouds and it doesn't
bother your lungs and throat at all pay
attention to that you can make
improvements in your next grow based on
the quality of this product how is the
flavor how is the aroma are those things
on point because if the flavor and aroma
and burn factor are not on point you can
absolutely correct those in your next
grow I was talking about paying
attention to what your friends say
because they are going to be honest with
you you're going to be very proud of
your crop you spent a lot of time on
this you're going to think it is the
best herb you've ever smoked that is a
very natural thing for new growers
to experience listen to your friends
they smoke a lot of herb also they're
going to have very influential feedback
don't let their criticism hurt your
feelings you're going to take their
compliments when one of your friends
says brother this [ __ ] smells so good I
can't believe you grew this you're gonna
glow when the other guy says bro this
kind of burns my throat you have to take
that compliment just as strongly as you
did or that criticism as strongly as you
did that compliment they both matter
equally so use the compliment as a
driving force to move you forward use
the criticism as a way to improve your
crop next time don't be hurt when one of
your friend says bro that weed burns my
throat that's cuz you did something
wrong and you need to improve and he was
honest with you because he's a good
friend
I mentioned earlier that some of the
things that you may need to improve that
you'll notice right away are your flush
how is that product burning again is it
a dark chunk or is it a nice white clean
ash does it burn all the way through the
joint or do you need to keep relighting
it if it's burning real black and chunky
and you need to keep relighting it you
probably needed to flush longer if it
just keeps going out but it's not
burning real black it may just be too
wet and you need to dry and cure it a
little bit longer how is your cure
process does the herb taste good does it
smell good is it crunchy
is it dry is it moist did you dry and
cure it to your liking do your friends
think you dried and cured it properly
what do you think as long as you're
happy that's what matters as long as you
were consuming it if it's going to
market it's got to satisfy the market so
pay attention to what the market says
also how did you trim it are you
satisfied with the trim are your clients
satisfied with the trim maybe you can
improve on the trim a lot of new growers
don't trim enough in my opinion you
could go a little bit harder on your
trim job now that you were consuming the
product and you can actually tell what
type of buzz it gives you do you think
you should have flowered a little bit
longer or do you think you should have
flowered a little bit shorter if you pay
attention to the finished product and
how things came out this time if you
took plenty of notes throughout the grow
you can look at your notes you can look
at your finished product and you can see
things that you can improve for the next
run which will make you a better grower
so take all of those compliments and
take all of that criticism and ball it
all up into one big learning lesson and
think of ways to improve your crop next
time now the overall deciding factor on
the quality of this product is how do
you feel do you like it were you going
for a low couch lock kind of a buzz or
were you going for a big psychedelic
head spinning high and did you get what
you were after
do you think if you would have let that
plant flower a little bit longer that
you would have gotten better quality do
you think maybe you would have gotten a
fatter yield do you think maybe if you
have chopped it a little later that it
may have started to diminish the flavor
do you think if you were to cut it a
little bit earlier that it would have
been a little more head buzzy and a
little bit racier there are things to
think about as you were testing the
final product are you satisfied with
your finished product is the bottom line
if you're satisfied don't change a thing
if there are things that you're not
satisfied with look at your notes and
think of ways that you can improve those
things for your next run now I started
off our little science experiment slash
ritual of testing our first crop by
sitting in our little comfortable
environment cannabis consumers stoners
pot heads whatever you want to call us
I'm okay with all of the above we have
this tendency to smoke and get trapped
in our little spot we don't want to go
anywhere we're nice and comfortable here
like I said earlier the music is just
right the air-conditioner is just right
the fridge is full of snacks my bros are
right here at the table why would I want
to go anywhere why because when you step
out of this little comfort zone you may
be twice as stoned as you even noticed
it's really easy to smoke a whole bunch
of product and sit here and be blazed
out of your mind to be comfortable
because this is the zone you know where
everything is I know there's a drink
right here I know the dad rig is right
here I know the pen is right here I know
where everything is there's no chaos
right here maybe go somewhere go for a
walk maybe call an uber and have them
take you to the mall or to the park just
go somewhere just get out of the house
maybe just go get some food some more
with your bros and just get out of the
house while your freshly buzzed on that
fresh new product and see what kind of
brand new experiences the world brings
to you out there there's this thing
about stoners that once you smoke you've
got about 10 minutes if you don't get up
and leave in ten minutes you're [ __ ]
stuck wherever you just smoke so smoke a
little bit if you're comfortable just
hanging out at the house do that see
what you experience but next time take a
few puffs of that new product call an
uber and go some more exciting and see
what life brings you you may get into
some cool new adventures
all right podcast world that is my talk
about sampling and trying our freshly
harvested cannabis crop I hope you had
as much fun as I did I hope you learned
something if you found this episode
educational informative or entertaining
and you would like to make a financial
contribution to the show I would
appreciate your support and you can help
out by going to patreon.com slash grow
from your heart all the information you
need to become a patron will be right
there on the screen just so you know I
use the funding from patreon for things
like keeping the website alive I do host
a website I read genetics Colorado comm
is my website that is where the podcast
is hosted that's how
able to keep the podcast coming to you
for free it does cost me a little bit of
money to host the website every year so
I do pay for that out of the patreon
contributions I also use last year's
patreon contributions to fund the
MacBook that I am using to record the
show on right now I also use some of the
patreon funding for a little microphone
covers and for equipment that breaks
occasionally I've had to replace this
headphone amp a couple of times I buy
memory cards and things like that with
the funding from patreon so it mainly
pays for the podcast and the equipment
and the little microphone covers so I
want to thank you guys for contributing
to patreon and I look forward to all of
the future support I would also
appreciate it if you find me on all of
these social media on Facebook simply
search for the girl from your heart
podcast on Twitter it's at g f YH
podcast if you want to follow my
personal Twitter account it's at Rasta
Jeff 420 also I encourage you to check
out my Instagram on Instagram I go by
Irie underscore genetics I read genetics
on Instagram that's my seed company I
post a lot of pictures of cannabis
photography I think you would enjoy it I
also go on Instagram live and I do live
videos or I hang out with my friends I
talk about growing and I answer grow
questions so follow me on Instagram and
catch my Instagram live videos and maybe
I will answer your question in the live
feed there if you've got something to
say and you're not into the social media
maybe you've got a question maybe you've
got a product you'd like me to review
perhaps you'd like to sponsor the show
you can reach out to me through email my
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
and I would love to hear from you don't
forget that the show is available on
Apple podcasts stitcher radio google
play tune in radio and of course you can
find every episode on youtube I want to
thank you once again for listening to
this podcast zona thank you again for
listening to the long series of grow
lessons I hope you had as much fun as I
did
ladies and gentlemen I'll be back in
just a few days with fresh new content I
want to give a huge shout out to my
friend Kelvin Medina and until next time
take a phat dad and give your mom a hug
for me