welcome to the show podcast world it's
time for episode 407 of the drove from
your heart podcast this episode of the
show is brought to you by our friends at
Oregon elite seeds if you need new seeds
in your garden I highly recommend Oregon
elite seeds and you can find them at
www.juergenschreiter.com
I love the flavor and aroma of this
batter
and I really love the lung expansion
from a nice batter this stuff is perfect
ladies and gentlemen I'm excited to be
back on the microphone I haven't
recorded an episode in a couple of weeks
so it feels wonderful to be in front of
the computer and behind the microphone
and it really feels great to be back I
hope everybody enjoyed those long grow
lessons I reposted I hope we got your
garden up in tip-top shape and I really
hope you enjoyed the lesson with Mike
and I to top it all off I had a great
time while I was away from the
microphone I got to go see Bert
Kreischer at the Paramount Theatre in
Denver I also got to go visit our
friends Scottie real and guru from the
dude grows podcast I was honored to be
invited as a guest on to their podcast
by the time this episode comes out I'm
sure you will be able to catch my
episode of the dudebro show on YouTube
on iTunes or anywhere you find a
respectable podcast so make sure you
give the dude grow show a follow I want
to give you a huge shot it to all of my
friends at the dude grow show a big
shout out to Scottie big shout out to
guru a big shout out to jr. token and
also a huge shout out of course to my
friend the dude so thanks again for
having me on the dude grow show I had a
great time on the podcast I had a lot of
fun and I had a really good time hanging
out with Scottie real so thanks for the
hospitality and I look forward to doing
it again now since we're talking about
the dude grows show let's talk about the
dude grows cup the dude grows cup is
coming April 13th that cultivated
synergy in Denver Colorado if you were
interested in more information about the
dude grows cup please send me an email
to grow from your heart at hotmail.com
I'll make sure to link you up with the
dude and we will get you all of the info
you need about the dude
bros Cup in Denver and
for all I look forward to seeing
everybody there all right podcast world
in this episode I do plan on reading a
couple of listener emails but before we
get there I Oh a couple of my friends a
shout out from patreon how about a big
shout out to Richard goals a shout out
to Richard memo and a giant Viking
handshake to my friend Grimble the druid
and if you'd like to learn more about
becoming a patreon contributor all you
need to do is go to patreon.com/scishow
and it to me at grow from your heart at
hotmail.com and I will try to work your
email into a future episode the first
email on today's episode goes a lot like
this Rasta Jeff I'm a new grower and
your podcast is one of the best I've
heard it is full of specific practical
and reasonable suggestions for
successfully growing the plant keep up
the good work your latest compilations
of grow lessons are golden hey that is a
great way to start an email I love
hearing that I'm helping people I love
that you love the compilations and I
love that you think I am the best I'm
honestly not in competition with anybody
but when you're told the best it
honestly makes all of the work and all
the effort worth it so thank you for
starting out with a huge compliment the
email continues he says I have got one
question / comment he says what is the
basis for the really hard insistence on
having absolutely no light during dark
periods and flowering then he quotes me
by saying if you can see your hand in
front of your face after five minutes in
your grow tent when it's dark then
that's too much light and he's
absolutely right I do remember saying
that and I still stand behind that
statement and I will explain why in just
a second the message continues he says
from an outdoor grow perspective this
would never be the case because of the
simple fact of moonlight all outdoor
plants deal with significant moonlight
for two or three weeks every month and a
cannabis plant is likely to have at
least two cycles of this during early
and late fall right outdoor grows don't
seem to suffer from this light so what's
the issue is
is a natural strike against was possible
in an outdoor grow I'm just curious
about this and I'm very interested in
what you think thanks again for the
great and generous podcast I'm learning
a lot and I trust what you're teaching
hey thanks for the trust that means a
lot to me now this is a great question
and I have a really great answer you can
tell that my voice is kind of burning
out so I'm going to press pause and I'm
going to get my voice fresh and I'm
going to come back and give you a solid
answer on this question you take a DAB
while I take a drink
all right podcast world I am well
hydrated and my voice feels fresh let's
talk about why our outdoor cannabis
plants don't have light interruption
problems from the moon there are several
things that contribute to this question
the main thing is the Sun when we are
growing outdoors we are growing under
the most powerful most efficient grow
light known to man that is the Sun this
comes into play for a lot of reasons
first off as the Sun sets the Sun puts
off a spectrum that is known as a far
red light spectrum now this far red
light spectrum is picked up by our
plants by something called phytochrome
red phytochrome red is a protein it
works as kind of a it has several
functions first of all it is a receptor
the phytochrome red can see that far red
light it knows that it is what receives
far red light it goes hey it is my turn
to fire up I'm a phytochrome red little
protein and I see that far red light
it's my turn to do my job
that phytochrome red protein tells the
plant that it is sleepy time and it
makes the plant effectively go to sleep
it turns the plant off for the day now
that plant is much less susceptible to
light interruptions because the Sun put
out a far red spectrum that was received
by a protein inside of the plant called
phytochrome red the function of that
phytochrome red is to start triggering
one of the functions of phytochrome red
is to start triggering that plant to go
to sleep so it is basically I guess a
good way to describe it
it is like when you get one of those
hypnotist so when you say when I snap my
fingers you will fall asleep sleep and
phytochrome read far-red sleepy time
it's hypnotized it went to sleep and
then you need the opposite to wake it up
in the morning but we're gonna talk
about that spectrum in another episode
we're trying to focus here on why we
don't have light interruptions under the
moon so the main contributing factor is
the Sun the Sun is the brightest grow
light we could imagine so we have the
Sun the brightest light you can imagine
all day long the Sun goes down it puts
out the far read that far red is our
second contributing factor the far red
tells the phytochrome red which is
factor number three that it's time to
tuck those plants in so now they are
sleeping know those three things that
bright bright ass light all day that
phytochrome red and that far red are
going to put the plants in such a deep
sleep that you're going to need a
significant light interruption to cause
any noticeable problems now I've got to
wrap that rant up with one of my
favorite things to say of course this is
very strain specific this could be very
phenotype specific the moon is not going
to disrupt your plants however a
flashlight or some car headlights may
disrupt some of your plants that is
where it becomes plant and
strain-specific
these plants are under such a powerful
light all day long I mean the Sun that
your flashlights at night probably and
I'm saying probably will be very
insignificant if you hear something out
in the garden and you just shine the
flashlight real quick who's out there
you're probably not going to disrupt the
flowering period our plants are more
sensitive to photo period disruption
early and flower so once you get peak
flowering time you don't have as much to
worry about early and flower is where
they will be more sensitive but with
this super combination of that powerful
light all day that far red spectrum
telling the plants hey you need to go to
sleep and that phytochrome protein
within the plant saying hey you're right
we do need to go to sleep all of those
things working together should touch
your plants in quite nicely now don't
get me wrong
enough intense light at a long enough
duration does have the potential to
disrupt your outdoor flowering plants
but it is probable
we going to take a much more powerful
and a much longer duration of light
interruption to cause any problems than
it would in an indoor environment in an
indoor environment you don't have the
Sun in an indoor environment you are
probably not getting far red lighting
some companies have started making red
lighting available to the home grower
but it is uncommon so most folks don't
have that at this time so you're not
getting that Sun you're not getting that
far red which means you are not getting
that phytochrome red protein which is
telling your plants to go to sleep so
your plants are kind of napping indoors
and it takes them a little bit longer to
actually get to sleep let's talk about
that for a little bit
several times I have been asked why do
my plants go into flower outdoors before
we have reached an actual 1212 cycle
someone will say where I'm getting 14
hours of daylight and my plants have
started to flower what's wrong there are
two major contributing factors that
decide when your plant flowers outside
the first one is what is known as the
critical period every plant has a
critical period that means how many
hours of continued darkness does this
plant need before it starts flowering
now based on where your plant is from
geographically it will possibly have a
different critical photo period
flowering time some places like Alaska
don't get much darkness ever so the
plants from Alaska have adapted to
flower with less dark time places like
here in Colorado we get a really nice
night cycle so the plants that are from
here have adapted to expect more of a
night cycle you'll need to give them
more uninterrupted hours of darkness
before they will initiate flowering most
of what modern breeders have bred will
flower under a 12:12 condition that's
what we have found works best for
indoors if it doesn't work that way we
have probably eliminated it by now and
it's been removed from the gene pool of
course there are auto flower plants they
will flower under whatever light
conditions you put them under because
those are bred from those plants that
came from the environments that did not
get any darkness so one of the main
contributing factors is what is known as
the critical period now the other thing
that is
contributing to our outdoor plants
flowering with more than 12 hours of
daylight time is that far red spectrum
again as the Sun starts to set it puts
off that far red spectrum the Sun is
still up we can still see there's still
enough light illuminating the sky to
where we can function but that far red
spectrum is telling the plants hey I'm
starting to activate my phytochrome red
protein and it feels like I want to take
a nap so they start putting on their
night clothes they start doing whatever
they're drinking they're sleepy time tea
they're smoking that nighttime joint and
they are getting themselves ready to go
to bed even if there is still a little
bit of light out so that is my long
rambling explanation of why the moon
does not cause light interruptions in
our outdoor cannabis garden and I also
touched briefly on why our outdoor
plants are beginning to flower when
there is still more than 12 hours of
visible daylight all right I want to
thank you once again for a great email
I'm not sure if you want me to see your
name on the show but you know who you
are
thanks for a great message thanks for
great content and I look forward to your
next question if anybody else out there
has a grow question I would love to hear
from you my email address is grow from
your heart at hotmail.com I've got
another email in front of me and it goes
just like this Rasta Jeff in advance I
would like to thank you for any advice
that you have to give I have recently
installed a mini-split system in my
small grow the mini split is overkill
but for my circumstance it's more
stealth than a window unit yeah I
understand that completely he also says
I covered the green light display
sufficiently so I thought and I ran my
new seeds my Bodhi seeds did great he
got some seeds from Bodhi who was a
great reader big shout-out to our friend
Bodhi he said those seeds did great no
hermaphrodites the freebies that came
with the Ken Kesey were labeled Diesel
Pakistani one of the diesel Pakistani
herm Don me and you guys when we say it
herm Don him that means at some point in
the flowering phase that female plant
decided to display male parts which
means that that male flower can produce
pollen which can pollinate your female
crop which will put seeds in the whole
female
which lessens the quality lessens the
potency lessens the desirability and
kind of ruins the whole project unless
you wanted seeds so one of the diesel
Pakistani has become a hermaphrodite
this message continues to say I have
always just sat for a few minutes in my
darkroom to notice the most obvious of
light leaks I take your advice and I
hang out in the room for twenty to
thirty minutes to ensure there are no
obvious light leaks is it the green
light display leaking through the top of
the mini-split do you think that that
super dim green light could have caused
the hermaphrodite should the whole room
have hermaphrodite it or would it be
more likely to be an unstable diesel
strain I've got one more diesel
Pakistani to double check in the back
corner and I just can't really get a
good look at the lower limbs so I am
unsure if all of the diesel Pakistani
have become hermaphrodites he wraps up
the message by saying thanks again for
the advice and then he signs his name
now I've got a couple things to say
about this message first of all that
plant that is in the back that you are
unable to check check that check it soon
that plant
quite possibly has hermaphroditic
tendencies it came from a pack that is
proven to have hermaphrodite traits so
it is possible it is very likely also
the parts that you can't see are where
you are very likely to get her flowers
that section that's not getting enough
light that part down there on the bottom
that's where you're gonna get a bunch of
boy flowers so I recommend you get in
there and check immediately now let's
address the actual question the main
question was do I think the green light
leaking from your mini-split caused this
hermaphrodite issue no I do not think
the green light was the overall cause of
your hermaphrodite I think the
hermaphrodite is most likely a genetics
issue you said the bodhi seeds did not
have any problems but that diesel
Pakistani is the one that earned I would
assume that that's where the problem
lies is within that diesel Pakistani it
was also a freebie so that may be a
small indicator of problems just because
it was the freebie now everybody's gonna
be afraid of the freebies that I give
out you guys those are the same things
that I put in packages
I'm just generous and I like to give
extra
so when you get a freebie from me it's
the same [ __ ] that went in the packaging
I just put it in a plastic baggie
instead of putting an insert in there
and I saved myself a buck and you get
free seeds so don't be afraid of my
freebies but those random freebies that
come from vendors sometimes those are
just random freebies for a reason
because they want to make it look like
you got something but they're just
giving you a seed that's a piece of [ __ ]
so be a little weary of that sometimes
unless it's from a reputable breeder I
don't know who these Diesel Pakistanis
came from so I shouldn't even talk like
that but a lot of times free stuff is
problematic in this industry and that's
unfortunate so I'm going to say that
your problem was probably these Diesel
Pakistani seeds
since the bodhi stuff didn't herm I'm
not going to blame the issue on that
green light until recently it's been
believed that plants do not absorb the
green light they are green so they
should in turn reflect green light but
there has been some argument recently
that the green light does have some use
and it may cause problems but your green
light was very minimal and I do not
think it was the culprit I am really
going to blame this on questionable
genetics so if you have any more of
those diesel Pakistani seeds I would
probably get rid of them I would feed
those to a bird I would feed them to a
squirrel I just would not grow them
however I would highly recommend you
grow more of the Bodi seeds if you have
more of those plant those grow those
that is good [ __ ] and if you need more
seeds you can get them through Oregon
elite seeds dot-com they carry Bodhi
seeds they carry I read genetics seeds
and they've got seeds from all of your
favorite breeders hey I want to thank
you again for a great email that was
great content a really great question
that was a fun one to answer again if
anybody else out there has an email they
would like answered on the show my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com you know I would love to
hear from you ladies and gentlemen let's
jump into another email this one is
short and it goes like this hi raasta
Jeff I hope you are well
I love the podcast keep up the great
work hey thanks for starting out with a
great compliment I promise I will keep
up the great work
the email goes on to say seriously I do
not listen to a lot of podcasts but I
listen to pretty much only your show
religiously hey that feels great thanks
for being a dedicated follower I think
the correct words for that thank you
that means a lot to me so the message
goes on and it says I'm wondering if you
have any thoughts on the pros vs. cons
of decarboxylation outside of making
cannabinoids active for edibles I have
read that it also makes the flowers
stronger for smoking is that true take a
fat dab and give your mom a hug for me
signed J and then they say PS long live
white Mike hey white Mike you got a
shout-out on the show bro all right so
let's talk about decarboxylation briefly
honestly decarboxylation is not
something I am super educated or
informed on decarboxylation is more
something done in the edibles game I'm
not an edible maker so I don't have too
much practice at this but I do know a
little bit about cannabis and about our
bodies the goal of decarboxylation as
mentioned earlier in this email is to
actually make the cannabinoids more
bioavailable when consumed the main way
decarboxylation happens is through heat
cannabis flowers and/or concentrates can
be heated to specific temperatures to
activate the cannabinoids for specific
effects now I am honestly not educated
in the knowledge of D carving at
specific temperatures for desired
effects but I know that that is a thing
now decarboxylation happens through heat
so we take cannabis flowers or oils and
we heat them to a specific temperature
which makes them more bioavailable a lot
of times this would happen in our liver
inside of our bodies if we ate raw
cannabis by heating it up we are
speeding up that process so that when we
eat it we can get more of the
cannabinoids so d carbon is absolutely
useful in an edible product what I think
happens is when you are baking the
product I think you were doing a lot of
the D carving during that baking process
now if you want to eat an oil as just an
oil or use it as a mixing with something
else then it is wise to D Carr be role
first so if you're making like a brownie
or some cookies or something traditional
like that I do not believe in my opinion
that it is necessary to D carb
baking I think the baking will handle
that part for you if you are going to
use the oil or butter to make something
else and use the butter or oil as a
topping and it's not going to get rekt
then you may want to consider the D
carving process before putting the
cannabinoids into the fat carrier which
is your oil or your butter now when it
comes to D carving before smoking that
doesn't seem to be necessary to me
because what I've mentioned this whole
time is that decarboxylation happens
mainly through heat and again this is
not my wheelhouse I am nowhere near an
expert in this realm I am talking from
my my new amount of experience in this
realm but that D carving happens through
heat when we're smoking you're putting
fire to it so I think you are basically
instantly D carving it that way you're
activating it through fire so I don't
think a D carb is going to make smoke
product more potent again I am NOT an
expert in this department so if somebody
would like to email me and correct me I
love Corrections Corrections are a great
opportunity to learn something so feel
free send me an email grow from your
heart at hotmail.com this is an
opportunity for you to educate me and I
do appreciate that so the main portion
of this email was asking my opinion on
the pros vs. cons of D carving I
absolutely agree with D carving for
making an edible I don't find it
necessary for smoking flowers
alright this email was wrapped up with
the great slogan that says take a phat
dab and give your mom a hug for me I can
promise you both of those will happen I
also want to thank you once again for
the great email he also ended that one
with PS long-lived white Mike that is
super cool hey Mike you've got another
fan all right podcast world it is time
for me to start wrapping up this episode
yes I know it was a little bit short but
it was super sweet I feel like I gave
you a lot of great information I want to
thank everybody once again for all of
the great emails I look forward to
seeing everybody at the dude grows cup
that's right April 13th a cultivated
synergy send me an email if you need
more information also send me an email
if you are interested in being a
competitor in the dude Crowes Cup but
act fast because there are only 50 spots
total available I
I think 30 of those spots were already
taken the last time I spoke with the
dude so if you're interested send me an
email grow from your heart at
hotmail.com don't forget about patreon
if you'd like to become a patron you can
visit patreon at patreon.com slash grow
from your heart while we're talking
about patreon I owe a huge shot it's my
friend Artem also a big shot it's a
brick Gorman and a big beautiful
shout-out to our friend miss mell thanks
for all the support you guys I do
appreciate it
ladies and gentlemen I would also
appreciate it if you find me on social
media you can find the show on Facebook
simply search for the grow from your
heart podcast you can find the show on
Twitter it's at Qi fyh podcast if you
want to follow my personal Twitter feed
it is a trois to Jeff 420 on Instagram I
use my other company name and his Irie
underscore genetics give us a follow
check out my fine cannabis photography I
think you would enjoy my photos I also
think you would like my Instagram live
feeds I go on Instagram live I talk
about growing cannabis I take a few dabs
and hang out with my friends I answer
questions on the fly I think you would
like it check me out on Instagram and
Irie underscore genetics again if you'd
like to make contact and you're not into
all of that social media nonsense you
can send me an email my email address is
grow from your heart at hotmail.com
don't forget to visit our friends at
oregon elite seeds get yourself some
fresh seeds for your garden get some
fresh new seeds for the outdoor season
get some fresh new seeds for your tent
get your garden all laced up with some
fresh new genetics ladies and gentlemen
I will be back Thursday with fresh new
content I'm gonna give you a huge shout
out to our friend James butter sin' and
until next time take a phat dab and give
your mom a hug for me