welcome to the show podcast world it's
time for episode 408 of the Grove from
your heart podcast this episode is
brought to you by our friends at Oregon
elite seeds if you need new seeds in
your garden I highly recommend Oregon
elite seeds and you can find them at
www.seannal.com it has become a
tradition that we start the podcast off
by talking about what I am dabbing today
I've been taking dad's of screaming
tangerines ambrosia from our friends at
apothecary farms this is labeled as
70.4% THC and 82.1%
total cannabinoids this is a little
saucy I would prefer a little more
crystals in here but the turkey flavor
that ridiculous
screamin tangerine flavor makes it worth
that saucy consistency so I'm loving the
flavor of this and it's got a great head
buzz to it and I'm gonna go back for
more so big shout out to our friends at
apothecary farms all right podcast world
I want to give everybody a huge thank
you for the reaction to my appearance on
the dude grows podcast I've gotten a lot
of great emails a lot of great Instagram
messages I've gotten a lot of great
responses to that show I want to thank
everybody for all of the support and
again I want to thank all of my friends
at the dude gross show and of course all
of the dude grows crew I can't wait to
see everybody at the dude grows Cup on
April 13th at cultivated synergy and I
got a lot of great messages but my
favorite messages were about my dread
dude are those dreadlocks real how old
are those dreads killer dreads lots of
compliments on the dreads yes the
dreadlocks are real these dreadlocks are
14 years old if I would untie them from
the bun in which they were in when I was
on the show they go down to my knees
that's a little bit ridiculous because I
am 6 foot 5 so yes the dreadlocks are
real they are 14 years old and they go
down to my knees so if you've never seen
a photo of me or if you've wondered what
I've looked like I encourage you to go
check out the episode of the dude grow
show that features Rasta Jeff from Ira
genetics go look at a video go see why
they call me Rasta Jeff now in this
episode i do plan on reading a few
listen or emails i do enjoy doing the
listener generated content but before we
get there i owe a few people some shot
from patreon about a big shout-out to
Steve F a shout out to Keith Klump a
giant shout-out to Riley H about a big
girl from your heart shoutout to matthew
KW and of course a big shout-out to my
friend todd k and if you would like to
learn how to become a patron you can do
so by going to
www.onproperty.com.au/plus what's up
Rasta Jeff great podcast on the moon
questions read proteins what makes total
sense then he goes on to say my arise
platoon got a little stretch but they
are starting to put some meat on their
bones the last day or two then he goes
on to say also Gollum has devoured her
twin
okay now that is a funny conversation we
were talking about he grew some seeds he
grew some arise seedlings and one of
them grew two seedlings two sprouts out
of the one seedling we were talking a
little bit about that and I told him
that he should name it after the nurse
with the conjoined twin in South Park so
that plant got named nurse Gollum and
apparently eventually nurse Gollum
devoured her twin it is now just one
plant which is kind of how nurse Gollum
turned out so the message continues he
says question when I transplant into one
gallon fabric pots can I plant them a
little deep to help him out what is the
rule of thumb on this so here's what it
sounds like is happening this guy
sprouted some arise seeds and they are
getting a little tall they're probably
getting stretchy because of a lack of
light the white is probably not intense
enough or it is probably too far away
your little plants your little seedlings
are trying to stretch toward that light
that light is their main source of life
so they want to get as close to that as
possible
they're expecting sunshine and they're
not getting it so they're trying to
climb up trying to get to that light so
they've gotten a little bit stretchy
a bit leggy they're kind of tall on you
now it is time to transplant these arise
seedlings into a one-gallon fabric pot
I'm assuming at this point you've got
them in something smaller something like
a beer cup or maybe something even a
little smaller maybe you've got them in
a jiffy pot still I'm not exactly sure
what you're doing but it is time to put
these babies into a 1 gallon fabric pot
and you're asking if you can plant them
a little bit deep to help them out which
I'm thinking you mean you've got a 1
gallon pot you're gonna fill it up and
then where it should be full you're
gonna knock out maybe one or two inches
worth of soil and then plant your plant
there and then overfill it with that one
or two inches of soil so that you're
going to bury part of the plant as to
make it appear shorter so it's not
popping out of the soil as much but in
reality you still have that three inch
long ceiling or however long it has
grown so it looks like you've got an
inch popping out of the soil because
you've buried two inches if you feel
like those plants have gotten too tall
for you and you really need to minimize
their height to kind of keep them from
toppling over this is something you can
do you can do this with a little tiny
seedlings you can do this when you're
planning from your beer cup into a three
gallon you can do this when you're going
from a three gallon into a seven gallon
or a three gallon into a 50 gallon but
the thing you need to be very careful of
is keep in mind that you were burying a
portion of the stem however much of that
stem is going into the dirt that wasn't
buried before that part is not
comfortable and not familiar with being
buried with dirt and being submerged and
possibly being soaked with water for
long periods of time so the first few
times you water you need to be careful
to not soak that part of the plant
you've got a fresh part of the plant
that has been exposed for the entire
time of its life up until this time that
you're burying it and now you're gonna
get it really really wet you're going to
run the risk of some kind of soggy root
rot or something similar happening to
that stock I guess would be stock rot at
that point it's just gonna get funky in
there if you overwater your goal is to
get the water down deep into the medium
into those roots and you don't want to
drown that fresh stock part you need to
give that some time to adjust to
acclimate to its new surroundings so if
you're going to do that be very careful
with a smaller plant you're just gonna
have to water maybe a little bit less
less water at a time and more frequently
with a larger plant what you
and you in which you should be doing
anyway with larger plants as water the
outer perimeter of the pot as to not
soak the inside of the pot so much where
that main stock is it's going to be hard
to control where the water goes but if
you've got a really large pot you just
water that outer part where the so if
you got a three gallon pot and you just
put it into maybe a ten gallon you just
want that edge of the three gallon that
outer exposed roots to be hit by that
water not the inside of the stick so try
to aim the water I know that sounds
ridiculous but you see what I mean
you're trying to get right at that edge
there's a ring you're trying to hit the
out of the three and the start of that
ten that fresh dirt you're just trying
to wet that part for the first couple of
waters to give that stick some time
don't go too deep now don't get
ridiculous and go bearing it really deep
use some judgment think about the health
of your plant think about the size of
your stock think about the root mass
you've got just pay attention to what
you're doing and think about the plants
give the plant some breathing room and
do not drown it and do not smother it by
trying to do this but yes it will work
if you do it properly now something I'm
going to recommend is get a fan on those
seedlings if they're getting too leggy
if they're tipping over they need more
light and they need a fan so brighten up
the white get a fan on them give them a
chance if you kind of give them a little
struggle give them some adversity
they'll come out stronger in the end so
give them a little bit of a struggle
with that fan make them kind of reach a
little bit so that they stand up a
little bit now something I've never
really said here on the podcast I don't
think and I'm gonna touch on this just
because I was talking about watering the
outer perimeter think about the way your
cannabis plants are shaped if we don't
interact with them they grow up and then
they grow leaves they kind of point down
kind of in a cone shaped fashion the
plant gets wider as it gets older it
gets taller and wider and taller and
wider but one thing it continues to do
is create the same type of effect as a
shingled roof if you look at the way the
water flows go spray the top of your
plants the water will run from the top
leaves down to the next set of leaves
and as they do it they come outward and
they come out word they come further and
further from the center of the plant the
more they drip down the plant that water
will keep continuing downward and
outward further away from the center of
that plant and if you look at a plant
after it rains right underneath the
plant is not wet but that ring right
around the plant it's really soaked with
water
because all the water has run down and
out and down and out and it's just
making a whiter and whiter ring as it
runs down and then right around the
plant it gets nicely watered so think
about that when you're watering your
container plants we want to water the
outer part where the most active root
tips are searching for water and food so
I hope there's some usable guidance in
there for your situation the email does
continue he says I've got some papaya
females I'm hoping to cross with one of
these arise males for my first cross
what are you looking for in King Solomon
I am super picky and super meticulous
when it comes to male selection but I
have done an entire podcast about
breeding and male selection episode 174
will help you out tremendously
but the most important part after you do
the male selection after you do the
breeding the most important part of the
whole project is to test your progeny
you have got to grow the offspring and
see what you've got that is the only way
to know if that male is delivering
traits that are desirable so the most
important part is to test that offspring
you know what the most important part is
to have fun with your breeding project
so do a good male selection pollinate
properly let the seeds finish harvest
and dry them properly grow them out but
most importantly make sure you have fun
with this breeding project I don't know
why I tried to make it so uptight I
forgot to grow from my heart for a
minute there I'm sorry you guys he wraps
up this email and he says what's up Nemo
punk 15 so we've got another listener
centered a big shout out to white Mike
white Mike is on vacation but as soon as
he gets back I'll give him a high-five
for you big shout out to white Mike also
a big shout out to our friend it left
field farms for this great email they do
thank you for the great email I hope I
answered all of your questions and I
look forward to hearing from you again
in the future
all right podcast world I do have a
medical marijuana renewal appointment
set for just a few minutes from now so I
am going to press pause I'm going to
take several ridiculous dabs because I
know I'm going to be in the waiting room
for several minutes then I'm going to
head to my medical marijuana renewal
appointment then I will be back to
resume this episode you guys take a few
dabs and I'll be right back
all right podcast world I am back and I
am officially a registered Colorado
medical marijuana patient for one more
full year my appointment was fairly
quick and fairly easy I spent more time
in the waiting room waiting to see the
doc than I did anything else I'm pretty
familiar with that paperwork I've done
the paperwork several times I've been to
that doctor's office and seen that
doctor several times so I'm very
familiar with the process and it went
fairly quickly and fairly smoothly this
time so I am a registered Colorado
medical marijuana patient for one more
full year it is done it is complete I
don't have to go back for another full
year let's continue on with this episode
ladies and gentlemen I was reading
emails I've got another great email here
in front of me and this email goes a lot
like this thank you for the grow series
and has been super informative you did
not mention if the temps in veg through
harvest are the same when using co2 most
people say to run temps at 85 degrees in
veg with co2 but I'm not sure if you
agree what about temps through flowering
with co2 and would you stop using co2 at
some point in flower thank you
signed Andrew M 14 hey Andrew M 14 thank
you for a great email and thank you for
pointing out that I missed a detail so
let's talk about this I did a long
series of grow lessons and we talked
about growing all the way from the
beginning to the end I talked about
temperatures and humidity levels and one
thing I overlooked was augmented co2
when we are increasing co2 to
high-performance levels we are able to
run the plants at higher temperatures so
yes I did overlook that one detail I
would agree where you say some people
say to run temps at 85 degrees in veg
with co2 I would say that that is
acceptable 80 to 85 degrees would be
great for a room running co2 I would
also run these high temperatures through
flower
however I would slowly reduce the
temperature through the flowering phase
we like to reduce the temperature kind
of mimic the outside fall conditions
bring out some of those colors they'll
also help bring out some of those sweet
flavors
it also helps speed up the ripeness on
some longer flowering cultivars so bring
out that cold a little bit later in
flower maybe weeks seven eight nine kind
of reduced the temperature a little bit
every week
and bring it down now the second half of
this question is would you stop using
co2 at some point and flower co2 can
become very expensive depending on the
size of your room and the efficiency of
your room
how sealed up your room is how often
you're exhausting the air maybe you're
just blowing the co2 right out with your
HVAC co2 can become very costly in an
ideal world I would not stop using co2
ever the plants would go into a room
with co2 from day one and all the way up
to harvest they would be in a high co2
augmented environment so no I do not
stop augmenting co2 later and flower I
like running it all the way through even
when I do begin reducing those
temperatures I find that once you've
started increasing co2 it is really
detrimental to the performance of the
plants if you stop giving it that co2 so
think about it this way in my opinion
co2 is kind of the last thing you should
add to your growth that is the turbo
charge that's your nitrous you've
already got the nutrient regimen dialed
in you've got the light dialed in you
know how to take good care of the plants
you were a professional then you add the
co2 that's like the last bonus step of
the way that co2 is what is gonna push
you over the limit
but learn how to grow before you add
that so now you've got the co2 now you
are turbocharging your plants
you've got everything dialed in and
you're pushing that turbo button now
you've been pushing that turbo button
for six weeks now you were feeding those
plants a high high performance diet I
feel like if we've got all of the
nutrients dialed in if we've got the
wide styled in the co2 is dialed in we
are certainly in a high performance
environment now think about if you take
that co2 away and you try to feed those
plants the same feed regimen
they're not going to have one of their
things that works amount to make that
high-performance diet all click together
you're going to burn them they're not
going to be able to metabolize as much
food if we are not giving them the co2
that they were familiar with getting in
the past imagine if I put you on a solid
workout routine and I started feeding
you like a savage we give you the best
athletic diet that science could dial in
for you then once you got that diet
solid you're good at your workout you've
got a good foundation now we're gonna
give you some steroids now you're
lifting more
never you're running faster than ever
you're the 420 million dollar man at
this point but now one day I'm just
going to stop giving you all of your
protein but I'm going to keep giving you
the steroids and everything else and I'm
going to expect the same performance
from you something is going to go wrong
you're not getting all of the parts of
the cogs that make those wheels turn so
somewhere something is going to blow out
and when you stop inducing co2 in the
plants after they're really used to it
they really let you know that they miss
it they're like hey we want that [ __ ]
back I am NOT going to run laps as fast
as I used to
I'm gonna start getting slow I'm going
to start getting droopy and all of that
money that you spent on co2 for those
six weeks and flour and however many
weeks and vege now they're kind of not
even worth it because you're just
negating that by not inducing or
augmenting or increasing the co2 levels
to a high performance environment later
in Flour so that is my long answer no I
would not stop using co2 at some point
in Flour I would use co2 all the way
through flour try to plan ahead plant it
in your budget if you can predict that
you are going to be low on funding
toward the end of flowering try to
budget your co2 money late and flower
don't use as much co2 for the first
couple of weeks so that you can save
that funding for the last few weeks of
flower when that co2 is really going to
push those big beefy flowers to that
extra limit so think about your budget
and try to plan ahead and try to spend
your co2 budget wisely hey andrew m14 i
want to thank you for a great email
again if anybody out there would like to
send me a grow question or any type of
grow or a cannabis related email my
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
you know i would love to hear from you
the next email in my pile goes like this
hey Jeff first off thank you for the
hard work you put into the podcast and
for sharing your knowledge
I truly appreciate it and I have learned
an absolute ton you are very welcome
thank you for the great email the email
continues he says secondly I have a
couple of questions that I hope you can
find the time to help me with so here it
goes
it seems that lemon Jeffrey is sold out
online at the several seed banks you
supply do you have any sort of timeline
when you
to have those genetics available again
yes I do that is a great question
because I can tell you that from the
time of this recording those lemon
Jeffrey seeds will be available in
approximately 80 days I'm recording this
in the first week of April so you've got
about 80 days and we will have more
lemon Jeffries seeds available and those
will be available at Oregon elite seeds
com they will get the first batch so
make sure you check there in about 80
days from now it's going to be April May
probably the middle of June
possibly the start of July we will have
lemon Jeffrey seeds and several more
feminized golden goat crosses available
through Oregon elite seeds calm and
again that is at Oregon elite seeds
dot-com make sure you check them out so
the email continues the next part says
also I purchased a pack of a rise from
hella dank and I am super excited to
grow those out well thank you for
purchasing those and thanks for having
the enthusiasm about a rise that is one
of my favorite crosses super high THC
super hyper vigor just a great plant to
grow overall he goes on to say I think I
would like to cross a strong indica to
your arise for my own personal use and I
do encourage breeding have fun with that
I have no problem with you using my
stuff once you've bought my seeds
they're yours
feel free to breed with it however make
sure you give me credit when you post
pictures or if those seeds go anywhere
just make sure you put a rise in the
little listing of what the cross is so
that people know what you used let's
continue with the email where was I I
know you were a big sativa guy but I am
wondering if you can suggest a strong
indica strain you think may be a good
pairing to match with the arize he wraps
up this email by saying if you do end up
reading this aloud feel free to use my
name thanks so much
from Kevin hey Kevin thank you for the
great email let's talk a little bit
about a great pairing for arise arise
was bred from a golden goat female so
it's got that tropical sativa flavor
going on it's got a really nice
structure it can take a lot of nutrients
really vigorous plant it is also bred
from a Daybreaker male Daybreaker is
chem d and joseph OG it sort of has a
fresh tennis ball fresh rubber kind of a
smell along with that Oh G cush funky
dank dirty feet kind of a smell so a
rise is a very unique cross it is very
beautifully balanced 50/50 hybrid with
very unique parents and grandparents it
is a really great cross in my opinion
that's why it works so perfectly for so
many environments and it produces so
well you want to cross this arise to
something more indica dominant so where
you can create an indica heavy product
for yourself you like to smoke more of
an indica type of a thing I feel if you
cross the arize to something more indica
dominant you could possibly carry that a
rise potency that a rise hyper vigor
into something that is more indica heavy
maybe something that grows shorter and
squatty ER you can get that indica
potency up a little bit so let's talk
about how you would do this do you
intend to use and arise male or do you
intend to use and arise female that is
the first thing you need to think about
the second thing I would think about is
when it comes to the opposite are you
going to use another male or female
where are you going to acquire this do
you have access to good seeds do you
have access to a large variety or is
your access slightly limited
if you've only got access to clones
you're either going to be using this
other cross as your pollen receiver as
the female or you may be making a
feminized cross there are a lot of
variables to think about here I'm trying
to think of some of my favorite indica
heavy cultivars or varieties that are
available that you may be able to get
your hands on something I would honestly
enjoy seeing worked would be an arise
male put to an LA Confidential female
from DNA genetics
I think the progeny would be amazing so
if you have access to LA Confidential
from DNA genetics I would certainly
recommend that another thing I would
recommend would probably be the cataract
cush or the kosher cush I would love to
find a good male of the kosher cush
unfortunately they are only selling
those in feminized seeds at this time
yes I have considered getting a female
or getting a clone and reversing it but
that is not what I want to do at this
time I would love to have a kosher
mail from the old school kosher OG seeds
the DNA released years ago that is not
an option what I would like to see
happen is do you find a good male from
that arise pack and put that pollen on
the kosher the cataract or the LA
Confidential and yes all three of those
are from DNA genetics or reserve a
privado which is their little offshoot
company but I really appreciate their
indicas I think they make a good Oh G
cush indica kind of a line and I really
respect those guys and all of their work
so if you plan to use and arise male and
you can't name him Solomon that's mine
you gotta come up with your own name but
you can still using a rise male that is
fair if you're going to use that I would
recommend pollinating something on the
OG Kush heavy side if you want something
more indica dominant to come out of your
across something short something stout
something with big fat leaves something
that doesn't take very long to flower
maybe bubba kush would be a fun cross to
go to the arize now let's talk about the
other way maybe you want to use n arise
female as your pollen receiver I would
still consider those first three strains
I mentioned the cataract the kosher and
the LA Confidential but I would also try
to find something with big fat leaves
short and squat with really indica
dominant traits again I don't know what
is available to you I know you've got my
seeds so it sounds like you've got
access to plenty of good seeds I would
find a super heavy indica strain that
gets your attention something that has
the traits which you were looking for
because that is what you were going to
get from your progeny what you put in is
what you get out so you're going to get
50% of the male 50% of the female you're
gonna mash it up and you're gonna get
all kinds of different expressions of
the different traits that are available
so I would find a male with big fat
leaves and a short squat stature because
that arise probably gets fairly tall
it's probably got fairly skinny leaves
and like you said it is sativa dominant
so you need to find something with heavy
indica genes so that way you can kind of
dominate that cross that way those
indica genes are real dominant real
prevalent in your cross in your
offspring ooh something that just in my
mind is strain that I should recommend
um durango OG I think the Rango OG would
pair beautifully with the
arise I'm kind of hosing myself now I
can't make these crosses since I'm
giving everybody else the ideas but I
think durango OG and arise either
direction either one is a male either
one as a female i think they would both
work beautifully what would be fun is if
you got a pack of seeds of durango OG
you got a pack of seeds of a rise and
you grew both of them out and you found
a stellar male from each pack and a
stellar female from each pack so you've
got a boy arise and a girl arise and
you've got a male durango OG and a
female durango OG then do two separate
breeding projects cross the male arise
to the girl durango and the girl arise
to the male durango and then observe the
differences in both of the progeny of
your projects then you can really dial
it in and find what you want for your
personal medicine to be quite honest
with you this breeding project any kind
of breeding arise back to some indica
sounds like a very exciting project and
I'm sure that if you start with a good
solid indica plant that is either going
to be the male or the female I'm sure
you will get something that satisfies
you in the offspring you will make a lot
of seeds you'll have a lot of stuff to
play with and something in that batch of
seeds will be your keeper I think
cracking a pack of seeds is a lot like
buying a pack of baseball cards or I
guess nowadays you'd say Magic the
Gathering cards but when you open the
pack you go through you always get a
bunch of Commons maybe it kind of but a
couple of uncommons but then toward the
back there's always that one rare car
that you were super excited about so I
hope you find your Mickey Mantle early
on in your female huh that is the best
part you get to do the breeding you get
to do the male selection the female
selection you get to be the pollen
chucking you get to watch all the time
of those seeds develop you get to
harvest it then the funnest part in my
opinion is growing out those seeds to
see what you've got to look for that
Mickey Mantle card so I really hope you
enjoy this breeding project I hope I
gave you some good advice I know I
recommended a few strains and I know I
went both directions I'm not sure your
goal or your intention other than to
make an indica dominant cross from the
arize I hope I have led you in the right
direction a thank you for the great
email and I really look forward to
seeing pictures of the offspring once
you make these seeds I want you to grow
them out and then I want to see pictures
I want to get details I want to know
what mail you used I want to know what
Phoebe
you use and I want to see how those
seats turn out for you thanks again for
the great email my friend I look forward
to hearing more about your breeding
project alright ladies and gentlemen I
feel like that is enough listen or
emails for this episode again if you'd
like to send me an email I would love to
hear from you my email address is grow
from your heart at hotmail.com before we
wrap up this show I have got one
question for you four-twenty is coming
up I'd like to know what does 4/20 mean
to you send me an email grow from your
heart at hotmail.com or reach out to me
on Twitter on Twitter the show is at G f
YH podcast my personal twitter is a
trois to Jeff 420 again I would love
your feedback on what does 4/20 mean to
you alright ladies and gentlemen I want
to thank you again for listening to
another episode of the Grove from your
heart podcast I'll be back Monday with
fresh new content if you feel like this
episode was educational informative or
entertaining and you would like to make
a financial contribution to the show you
can do so by going to patreon.com slash
grow from your heart all the information
you need to become a patron will be
right there on the screen I would
appreciate it if you stalk me on all of
the social media on Facebook simply
search for the girl from your heart a
podcast again on Twitter it's @gf wih
podcast and on Instagram I use my other
company name I use Irie underscore
genetics follow me on Instagram
check out my fine cannabis photography
check out my live feeds join me on
Instagram I think you will enjoy it
again if you've got something you'd like
to say and you're not into all of that
social media nonsense you can send me an
email my email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com don't forget about
the YouTube channel every episode is
available on YouTube I would appreciate
your YouTube subscription by me on
YouTube simply search for the girl from
your heart podcast click Subscribe leave
some comments on the videos I would love
to hear what you think of the show
ladies and gentlemen that is all I've
got for you for this episode thanks
again for hanging out I'll be back
Monday with fresh new content I want to
give a huge cannabis pioneer shout out
to Neville show and mocker and until
next time take a phat dab and give your
mom a hug for me