welcome to the show podcast world it is
time for episode 409 of the Grove from
your heart podcast this episode of the
show is brought to you by our friends at
Oregon elite seeds that's right it's
time to add fresh genetics to your
garden and you can get them at Oregon
elite seeds dot-com ladies and gentlemen
I would like to welcome to the show an
international traveler welcome back
white Mike welcome to the show bro
what's up buddy welcome home man yeah
man thanks for taking time home uh you
uh you look and sound like you've been
on the road for way too long
yeah it good trip long trip glad to be
home yeah it looks like it could be the
NAP from your heart podcast over on that
side of the table yeah it uh I've been
in France for the last ten days so you
just got back yesterday was twenty-four
hours of straight travel when we landed
at DIA and then drove home
don't blow so far all of the stories you
have told sounded amazing and then you
topped it off with that and that sounded
grueling yeah the the trip was amazing
but the ride home was pretty brutal yeah
that sounds like a terrible terrible
right but worth it right well uh so so
we're the awesome uh we don't want to
talk too much about France but I'm glad
you had a great time I tell us one cool
thing about France since we got you on
the show we don't want to go too deep
into it most people don't don't wasn't
everything uh the thing I like is unless
you're directly intruding on someone
like poking them with your finger they
don't care what you're doing
cool and so like pretty much anything
goes everywhere which is really nice
in our conversations one thing you
mentioned is several times without any
prompting was you can smoke anywhere
there and you're a cigarette smoker so
like outside there's a lot of non
smoking inside spaces and like you can't
smoke in the museums and [ __ ] but yeah
hopefully every outdoor cafe has
ashtrays on the table there's people
smoking everywhere cool for you not for
guys like me grossed out by cigarettes
but I mean but it's yes it's part of the
I don't care what you're doing yourself
attitude so it should be other than me
having to smell your damn cigarettes but
you're gonna have to smell my reefer so
that leads me into my next question and
we can edit anything out if we need to
did you have any cannabis experience in
your journey the every time we or the
first three times I should say it kind
of tapered off after that the first
three times when
mentioned that we were from Colorado the
person we mentioned it to wet weeds
legal there that's awesome the kid that
was selling Nutella waffles like these
bomb ass [ __ ] fresh waffles and then
they just slather him with Nutella and
you eat it like they're like hot dog
vendors they're [ __ ] everywhere it's
awesome um he basically was like my
shift ends in a couple of hours if you
want to score like I'll hook you up with
good weed nice how we didn't want to
hang out for a couple hours and buy we
buy from some kid by a tourist
attraction is it Nutella or Nutella it
depends I call it both depending on how
I feel you know that's how I am treated
with viola and viola extracts I'm wrong
wherever I go so just say it how you're
comfortable right
I didn't as it try to search out in here
boy I was there I figured that would be
wasted time yeah just enjoyed the trail
was there doing other stuff so it wasn't
was the thing enjoy the sobriety the
tolerance break that's the word I'm
fishing for yeah yeah any wife there's
plenty of dude I've seen your photos it
doesn't look like there was time to
really waste smoking anything you were
busy and entertained the entire time yep
it's uh we didn't stop the whole time
we're there so now we're [ __ ]
exhausted I can see it I can hear it
let's move forward from that because it
sounds like I'm just worn you out
talking about that it is a tradition
we'd like to start the podcast off by
talking about what we are smoking on I
just took a dab of gg4 batter and then I
rolled that batter around in some
screaming tangerines ambrosia Terps the
liquid turkey part at the bottom of the
container was leftover I just scooped
that orange flavored deliciousness up
off the bottom then I had a little bit
of Killer Queen High cannabinoid full
spectrum extract I crunched that up and
put a little bit of I caught the
sprinkles you know put some sprinkles up
on top of there I took a dab of that and
obviously it is working it's got me nice
and rambly it's got me talkative I'm in
the mood for a great podcast it's okay
that mic is a half asleep over there
because I will keep the party movement
half asleep and the other half is
completely glazed tolerance brakes are
nice folks yes I let Mike finish my dab
I left a little in there toward the end
and I just passed the rig and the carb
cap to Mike and he basically I took the
leftover of that then he took a little
tiny
tiny batter dab over there yeah yeah I
like that gg4 batter that stuff tastes
really nice yeah I uh I'm a big believer
in tolerance breaks take one every every
now and again folks it'll be good you
don't have to go nuts with a long a long
break either five ten days is more than
enough did I talk about that on the
podcast or on Instagram live somebody
asked me about a tolerance break and I
said well if you're a medical patient
don't do it because you wouldn't tell me
stop taking your diabetes or your
cholesterol medication for a week so
that it works better one of the things
I've talked about with people who do
other herbal medications is that type of
medicine works best with breaks not
frequent breaks but you got to give your
body a chance to chance to breathe a
little bit I mean it varies so much from
person to person right I've got I've got
a stomach thing and I can tell I'm like
oh I'm gonna need to take a couple dad's
here the next hour or two or this
stomach thing is gonna start bugging me
so I don't know if I'd imagine if I
didn't smoke for two full days my
stomach might just start flaring up and
the little problem that the problem that
I have mandated for years it may really
swell up if I don't give it that yeah so
I don't and I don't want to risk it like
it ain't broke don't fix it that's the
way I've been thinking but you're right
sometimes and see both things are true
it's not like either one of these
positions is mandatory or the right
position I'm getting myself a way off
track but this is this none of this is
written down this is all chatter with
Mike and I so thanks for hanging out
hashtag they like it when we ramble they
both certainly do I feel like that first
dad I took when you sat down at the
table with me that first one that may
have been a medical marijuana dad like
that one took the back pain away to the
potential stomach issue away that second
one where I put all the crystals and
[ __ ] that was a recreational dad that
one was purely just because I want to be
a little silly for the show and have a
good time maybe I kind of do take a
tolerance break by only minimally dab
Sundays you know what I mean just enough
to kind of keep the the whatever's away
a DAB a DAB every few hours would keep
the doctor away in my my world so maybe
I just maintain that and then there are
days trust me like the weekends or I'm
hanging out going places or a comedy
show those are the days when I really go
in and then I'll find myself the next
couple days I not purposefully but I'll
kind of go a little lighter and give
myself not a plan to tolerance break but
like my lungs will say hey you need to
go lighter and my system ago I'm
saturated bro even if you dab so hard
you're not gonna get anywhere and my
body and brain know that's all take
Monday will be a real light that day a
lot of the time but Friday Saturday and
Sunday I sure did put it in to where I
had to take that break Monday my body
just said not today bro like you've been
working hard
yo party that throw pour and after a
good party yeah yeah very yeah the lungs
retired it just it uh I'm a firm
believer and like there's a line and if
your body's hurting and you're using
cannabis to treat it or you've got a
medical condition that you're treating
it takes more consumption to get baked
then if you didn't have that condition
that first bit of THC and CBD and
whatever else is the other cannabinoids
in the plant they're all going to
medical uses it's going to help relieve
inflammation relieve pain relieve you
know whatever and then after a certain
point your body's like okay you can
enjoy that part of it now we've gotten
what we need to start taking care of
this I agree I feel like the herb is
really smart it knows the other's pain
over here we're gonna we're gonna go
there first it'll start with your
negative like you're already it like you
got pain so that put you on the negative
side you know oh oh negative let's go
fix the negative then we'll get you back
to even and when you're even they're
gonna go well now let's kind of make
them happier and then it makes you a
little Irie and then right after that it
goes well now you had another dad that's
when we're gonna go super positive now
you're like oh my [ __ ] and just there's
just there is that line yeah it's uh the
wife will ask me like you know you say
gonna smoke real quick like real quick
it's 40 minutes with the [ __ ] yeah it's
like well I hadn't smoked today and I
was hurting so the first six hits I
didn't get stoned it was just for my
shoulder the three after that were for
my head and it just takes a minute to
take nine good ribs
you can't just inhale and exhale a bunch
of dabs part of that sitting down so for
me like I'm gonna move my
no look it's actually gonna do this
because talking about it is I mean what
else could go better here part of the
thing is sitting here with you right
yeah I got the dabber in my hand and we
both stared at the pilot concentrate
it's like ooh which one is he gonna pick
that's part of the fun yeah I get to
choose which one of these and I'm
spoiled my and I we live five miles away
from there's a dispensary north south
east and west from us within five
minutes of here so we were spoiled
little [ __ ] we know that but you have
to grab a dab I'm gonna grab two of them
gonna grab the gg4 batter and the
Tropicana cookies HCF se and I'm gonna
mix this up and then I get to mix them
like it did it's just like it's the same
thing with herb though like sitting down
figuring out which one which train
you're gonna smoke tonight picking the
nug you're gonna smoke out of the
container oh that's so much fun oh this
bud right here grinder yeah I just stuck
the dabber in the gg4 batter I get to
like smell it look at it and pick a
little piece and this is so pretty
people turps they're just the whole
ritual of it it's just so nice and you
know what this ritual is more enjoyable
no I'm saying that wrong this is more of
a solo ritual the dad thing but the
smoking a bowl at the friend is such a
like there's even more to that you can
make that take an hour just smoking one
bowl at the friend and so that's part of
medicating is what I think I'm saying
the whole ritual is part of it it's not
just I'm going to consume this since I'm
gonna sit here for a few minutes and get
my head right get my back right it's all
part of the unity sort of a thing you're
connecting with yourself I'm not gonna
go all hippie dippie on you but you take
a minute and just get this in for a
moment like people that even roll their
own cigarettes they'll talk about like
the process is like part of it taking a
minute away completing something just a
simple routine it's it's the same thing
with our hash it's like karate students
they will take time cleaning the dojo
because that's part of the art that
makes the karate come from your heart a
good drummer will clean and tuna's drums
and cymbals like it's just you got to do
the things that make it mean something
to you yeah I just always be bashing to
getting loud right
it's the same thing like when I go to
clean a piece of glass the ritual of
that is is always real enjoyable you
enjoy cleaning glass it makes me
paranoid I read this great thing a long
time ago that was like the nature of
glass is to break like that's what the
glasses purpose is it so many people are
cringing hearing you say that but you're
like it's true it's not it's not
permanent it's [ __ ] glass it's gonna
break and if you just sort of accept
that when you buy it every day after
that is a cool bonus day with that glass
and going through and cleaning it I've
broken enough pieces to know like
definitely don't do this even when it
seems like a good idea or it's the only
way to get that little piece of resin or
that little ball of hash out of there
this is just keep putting ISO and salt
in it and keep shaking it don't drop it
on concrete yeah please yep it's it's a
ritual that I enjoy
i buy fairly cheap glass because well
it's not cheap but I mean that's not a
super expensive piece because I agree it
is glass and I could be shaking it
cleaning it my grubby little paws could
be a little slippery from that alcohol
and it may hit that porcelain or
whatever a sink is made out of these
days and kaboosh there as it goes
there's it goes there it goes and I need
a new rig now I remember I have I put it
was just a cheap like an $80 bomb no
downstem just the slide in and out pull
put that under the sink and it was a
great setup it would sit just perfect
with the the sink spout and it would fit
so wouldn't move around and I could just
turn the hot water on and let that [ __ ]
run for a while and clean out and I
turned the water on and I turned around
I was [ __ ] around in the fridge and I
heard the sad oh that turned around I
was like I know what the [ __ ] happened
before I even turn around and sure
enough right in the middle is that
little air bubble and that cheap-ass
glass pop there it goes
yeah glass breaks it's not a big deal
glass does break you guys we do have a
topic but I think we've been having a
good time just rambling about random
stuff hey Mike I've got this dad meal
right at the perfect temperature so
you've got the toss for a couple of
seconds say some should I dive into the
topic or go through
I got one more thing before that's a
free-form okay so a fun thing that
happened here in Colorado recently our
governor jared Polis added autism
officially to the list of conditions
that you can get a medical marijuana
card in Colorado I was pretty sure that
this was the first condition we had
added but we added PTSD recently as well
so huge news for folks with autism and
Colorado good news for our medical
marijuana industry that has been slowly
shrinking and did non-existence for the
last couple years our rec industry has
been siphoning off patients left and
right so the industry was happy to have
another condition on the list especially
one that shows as much promise as autism
yes absolutely it is great to have more
qualifying conditions that we see some
compassion coming along the way now it
was nice to have a governor that was out
loud and proud about supporting this
bill supporting our industry jared Polis
is very very Pro cannabis would you like
a small dab my friend
no thank you right I tasted amazing I
will hold off for now folks save you the
coffin yeah he got for quite a while
yeah he's been here for over an hour
let's see what's next patreon shoutouts
we've got a lot of people who take
really good care of us who support us I
appreciate them so I like to give them a
shout out about this point of the show
it is a good time for that let's give a
big shout out to my friend Remy redeye
how about a big shout out to Eric Ross a
giant girl from your heart shot it to
Eric Gorman a shot at the Steve F of
course a shout out to Farmer John and
always a big shout out to our friend Sam
all right Mike you there you're gonna
say something important ah thank you
folks keep keep it the patreon this
microphone doesn't smell like dog he's
ask so I appreciate that
we should elaborate on that statement
the reason why the microphone cover does
not smell like donkey ass is because of
our friends from patreon that help out
with the support ah I used that funding
to buy new microphone covers so that
when Mike comes over I can frequently
change that thing out so that he doesn't
have to spit that same microphone cover
Davin granny has used that microphone
Clint has been on that microphone a lot
of people have been spitting into that
thing over the years I do like
swap out these mic cover so they don't
smell like other people's breath or
donkey ass my clean put it like 12
different hippies talking to the same
microphone cover each one spitting a
little yeah after a while it just it
gets a little funky yeah you got to
clean it just like you do the rig so
swap out those covers and that happens
because of the loyal listeners and the
supporters that help us out on patreon
if you want to learn how to become a
patron you can go to
patreon.com/crashcourse and then time
let's do it in colorado currently at
this time it is illegal to offer
delivery medical marijuana on the legal
market that part of my argument is
already happening on the black market
can't do legal delivery the only thing
that comes close legally is if you're a
caregiver caring for a homebound patient
and you filed paperwork with the state
as such yes happened during the doctor
appointment so yep there's a lot of
Hoops to jump through there actually saw
that happen I talked about going to the
medical marijuana doctor on a recent
episode I watched somebody have to fill
out their homebound paper and that was
took them five times as long as it did
me to get my paperwork done in that
place that is much more complicated
there's a lot of extra paperwork so
currently oh the delivery is banned
there is no delivery allowed and I'm
reaching for my phone Mike if it looks
like I'm playing with my phone here I'm
not playing with my phone I've gotten
notes in here and I'm just drawing for
the Nerds however my phone also I
ordered a new phone so I'll never have
this excuse again it is fifth great
frozen and it's taken a minute well you
won't have an excuse to the nice one
gets released oh thanks conspiracy Mike
over there so
delivery is not allowed at this point
there's a big debate on so right now
there is a bill being proposed that they
do allow medical marijuana delivery they
want to start with medical marijuana for
one year they want to give it a test run
and then if it works they want to
introduce the delivery system to the
recreational cannabis market some people
are afraid of this some people really
look forward to it I thought it'd be fun
to
mic on the show Mike's kind of
unprepared I told him when he got here
basically what the topic was gonna be so
he hasn't had a lot of time to research
any time to prep
yeah I like it when you're just fresh
and you got a rant think off the top of
your head so it's a little better than
giving you too much time to prepare um
so let's talk about it do you think that
a delivery system is a good or bad idea
and do you see any pros and cons to
having your medical marijuana delivered
there's so many different takes on this
I think it we deliver everything else
like yeah right if I if I find the right
app I can get cigarettes delivering it
alcohol delivered I can get my
prescription medications delivered my
patent it I've had wine shipped to the
house it's like a giant [ __ ] box of
wine like it would have been a weird
party but I there's no reason I
shouldn't be able to use a delivery
service to get cannabis delivered as
well I agree with that so far I think
it's gonna most of the heat against the
bill from the anti pot crowd and the law
enforcement community is enforcing that
it's going to be hard there's so many
different ways to skirt any sort of
official rule and the video requirements
that we have on site in the cannabis
industry help keep everybody on the
up-and-up
I only takes one delivery boy to [ __ ] it
up for everybody right I bet the fines
will be huge yeah then the news station
that sets up the sting operation where
instead of you know [ __ ] just have
some teenager answer the door and be
like no my dad ordered it let me sign
right the first dude who lets him do it
and gives them the [ __ ] herb like
that's a slap across all our faces very
true well it's not and just this is how
I see that system let me touch the
computer just to keep it going
that screensaver makes me paranoid I
like to see the recording I what I feel
it'll happen is the product will be
checked out from somewhere and this is
gonna lead into one a part of my so
people are worried about where's the
herb gonna come from and it's gonna put
out the dispensaries out of business I
think the product is going to come from
the dispensary
yeah it's not like the delivery service
isn't going to appear to have product
the time Domino's isn't worried their
drivers gonna swing by Pizza Hut and
pick up pizzas to sling on the side
exactly so the product is going to come
from a dispensary we aren't going to
shut down dispensaries it's not going to
come from somewhere else it's gonna come
from the dispensary it has to be picked
up at a dispensary so the patient is
probably going to have to go to the
dispensary already be registered there
you're gonna have to go there and show
your paperwork show your ID this is me
the first time it establish establish a
connection there sires isn't delivery at
least what I know this bill there's no
formal system to it right so it is fully
and it's gonna be like a GrubHub app
cool hey but you have to prove that
you're a medical marijuana patient and
that you're old enough somehow for the
first year under medical but rec there's
probably gonna be a lot less registering
you probably just go online creating a
create an account you probably have to
scan in your driver's license but take a
picture of your driver's license and
attach it to your yeah whatever was it
so however then at that point the driver
will pick it up and now it's on that
driver's responsibility if there has
that has to he's got to pay for it
somehow you know what I mean
dispensaries are really that stuff's
expensive so at the end of the day he's
either got to pay for it at the end
after the trade is made after he makes
money and brings it back or he's got to
pay for it at the start of the day it's
got to go somewhere it's got to be
accounted for so the only like the like
you said the only real loophole that I
see where it is really gonna go wrong is
when he gives it to like if my daughter
answers the door when I'm pooping or
something and he's like here you can
just sign for a little girl and she
signs it and sets it on the table and I
smoke it later that's where it's gonna
go wrong but for the most part I think
the accountability unless somebody wants
to be Shady
I think for the most part it could go
right if we wanted it to I don't think
that the deliveries will hurt the stores
like I said because they're gonna get it
from somewhere there's the worry from
the industry that I've read about is
that a couple of chains or an
independent delivery service will
dominate that particular piece of the
market
[Music]
like it's kind of a silly worry and they
let Walmart dominate that particularly
see the market they let best to dominate
that part like what the touch it goes
when it becomes business there's a
handful of like really large chains in
Colorado and the independent operators
have trouble competing with the larger
chains because the larger chains are the
only ones that have the cashflow size to
really advertise a specific brand like a
lot of the smaller stores that we have
in town they haven't heard up in Springs
and just like we haven't heard a lot of
a lot of the smaller ones that Springs
or a lot of the smaller ones and in
Trinidad the South here they just don't
have that level of marketing budget and
they're worried that one of the big
chains I'll have a delivery service that
won't operate with the small-time
operators that the deliveries that
customers will be able to get will
predominantly be from the big chains and
so the people who are adamant about
getting their delivered will end up by
default shopping with the big guy rather
than the little guy it's kind of a silly
fear people go where the products good
that's true that was gonna be my next
thing so I would would you use a
delivery system depending on the system
[ __ ] yeah yeah you've got two kids at
home I mean note there's finding time to
go to the dispensaries pain in the ass
yeah sometimes it is on Monday I
generally like to shop at the dispensary
on Monday there it's dad on Monday so
it's a really good day to go to the
dispensary so I'll stop in on Monday and
I will get my I try to get my supply
that will last me until about Thursday
and then I go Thursday because I don't
want to go Friday Saturday or Sunday
that kind of sucks for the dispensary if
you've got the option don't go it's just
the busiest Thursday's are cool people
don't get paid till Friday so Thursday
you beat you jump the gun go in there
and get what you need for the weekend so
Monday and Thursday or my favorite days
to go if I went Monday I would take a
good look at all the product see what
they've got give it a good once-over
make a nice selection make a mental note
of what I want to try next time and then
Thursday if I don't really feel like
putting on shoes and driving all the way
over the dispensary your fries is simply
half time I made just take that delivery
of my last order exactly what I got you
know what I mean just remember what I
got the budtender probably hasn't a
computer or something you can just text
it or whatever however you do and then
or maybe order that otherwise I was
looking at just look we have the tech to
make it super easy yeah I can judge this
with a with a little work on the shops
and to keep their online menu current
yeah I just jump on a couple of shops
before I even leave the house well I'm
pooping in the morning I'm looking at
the weed maps and a couple other
websites to see who's got what I want to
go shop for today and then I already
know where I'm going or what I'm getting
when I get there that makes it real easy
no jobs have that component taking care
of what we really need to make a
delivery system safe and functional is
banking access yes like every shop needs
to be able to take all major credit
cards that would be just like every
other business and that would solve a
couple of the problems with this system
because right now you're totally right
like you're gonna have to go into the
shop you're probably gonna have to do a
couple of things way above and beyond
but you'd have to do to get your
prescription meds or alcohol delivered
to your house ah and they're starting
with medical first which will give a
real slow rollout to this yeah it makes
it easy to test it though so I would
take that midweek delivery I think I
would just say send me that order in the
middle of the week I like to go look so
they think it's gonna hurt business I
don't think about her business coz I
like to go look people want to see their
product that's not the whole industry
it's just a little piece of it honestly
the part that worries me is delivery
drivers you're gonna be sitting ducks
like just bad Oh easy targets if if they
mark themselves if nobody if they just
pull up in a Ford Escape and a t-shirt
and Dickie's nobody knows who they are
fair but where to Jimmy John's uniform
nobody gives a [ __ ] about the Jimmy
John's guy but the Jimmy John's guy gets
jacked from time to time because people
know he's got 60 bucks and change on him
no they usually that's why I said Jimmy
John's cuz they go back and forth so
quick they only have like 12 bucks
but there's plenty of places where
delivery drivers like [ __ ] I've lived in
neighborhoods and pueblos or places
won't straight won't deliver yeah well
because they've had so many problems of
with their drivers and those there is
that's Pablo for you so the I think our
deliveries you guys would have a
slightly more / slightly more problems
than your average delivery driver well
that's what I'm saying you gotta go
that's why I was thinking you have to go
to the dispensary and register that way
you're like hey here's my name here's my
ID here's the only get 1 address to
deliver to and then that would be they
know you got a callback hey it's me
here's my address
it's got a cus I'm just substantially
more creative than your average which is
good that's why I call you sometimes
when I'm like a mind that's why I call
you for the half but yeah if we had
banking I think this would be a pretty
simple system and easily trackable and
and you keep it on the up-and-up but I
don't know I don't see a passion in
Colorado this year that's a bummer I
think it would increase dispensary sales
I think it would increase some and
that's honestly the best argument for
having this system now is is to take
another swipe at the black-market I've
got one real good argument but I'm
trying to save it for the very end mmm
the black market delivers that's not
even my my ace in the hole the black
market delivers all day you can get a
black market delivery so they're
delivering and if you want to corner the
market that's the one big piece that
they're missing ah but how many sick
days have you had what if what if you
got explosive diarrhea you don't want me
at the dispensary you don't want me
standing in line what if I'm sick you
don't want me smelling the jars you'd
rather just bring me the eighth just
bring me a quarter or some good weed so
I could smoke a couple of bulls and go
back to bed like yeah I think that
that's a good advantage what about you
got two kids man like I was saying
earlier you can't get away no it's I
mean honestly it's a pain in the ass cuz
you can't like any other store I can
just put my kid in the car and be like
don't touch the stuff yeah there's like
I don't want them grabbing at the teddy
bears or the Christmas cards or anything
else so there's usually not even [ __ ] to
grab at a dispensary but you're not
allowed to take your kids in you're also
like hey if you're a decent person in
like
CPS if they found out would definitely
not appreciate
just leaving the kids in the parking lot
for [ __ ] 40 minutes while waiting in
line and waiting to shop and you there
way too young for that [ __ ]
so if minimum I have to either have
someone to watch the kids or someone to
sit in the car with the kids um there's
two of them and so they're gonna murder
you chose an S at the end of that yeah
that's mischief it's so it's just kind
of a pain like I have to find a good
spot to do it so when I go to the
dispensary now I'm getting like three or
four weeks worth the product just that I
don't have to figure out how to get away
for another hour and forty again during
business hours during but yeah like this
podcast happens late at night folks is
the only way we're able to get this done
what's wacky to me is that if we go to a
park aeri the dispensary four and a half
miles from here they have one entrance
where you walk into the lobby and then
you see the reception person the intake
person I don't know the appropriate word
for that it's 2019 I'm sure that there's
a better word now I'm trying to use it
whatever word that is you walk and you
say hi to the marvelous person that
greets you and then you either are a
medical or a recreational shopper if
you're rec you go on one side of the
store
if you're medical you go on the other
side of the store it's two different
shopping experiences for some reason we
have voted that the medical side is open
until 7 p.m. and the recreational side
is open until 11:00 so if I smoke
cannabis after seven I'm like a [ __ ]
gremlin right it's like a Mogwai it
becomes recreational if I started
smoking weed after seven o'clock and I
get high but if I smoke it before seven
and I'm just medicating I don't know why
those it's pretty funny are it's kind of
silly yeah I find it silly yep it's it's
those little little tidbits that I'm
useful for leisure usable for something
but I don't have to there's a bunch of
other marijuana bills going on in
Colorado odds are there's several
marijuana bills going on in your state
if you'd like this to cover one shoot me
a message on Twitter there you go send
like a Twitter message it's at Nemo Punk
15 I haven't given the opportunity to
plug himself yet but now is a good time
yep let's talk about your social media
there's an emo Punk 15 on the tweeter
yep and then what's the other one Pueblo
for sensible cannabis laws on Facebook
yeah yeah see I've been doing my best
friend
what makes you support Mike's Facebook
page well for sensible cannabis laws he
posts a lot of good cannabis rants lots
of good news to keep you keep you
up-to-date and informed it will keep you
updated your gonna post any pictures of
your France trip on that page probably
not maybe probably not maybe I doubt it
I'm lazy if if people will like post
photos of your cannabis social media hi
man there you go
speaking of photos even planner not
talking about that when you asked me I
was surprised but yeah that's why I
sound like I'm half a sleeper over
glazed folks I'm just exhausted
no thanks for coming bro thanks for
coming and hanging out with us oh yeah
if you guys are looking for my Instagram
Instagram has shut down my account I'm
going to do my best to get it back and
make no promises if I don't get it back
I may make another one I may not I don't
know it's been kind of nice ah not
opening my phone to check my Instagram
every 30 minutes
I do miss it I miss all of my friends
that I was communicating with also there
are about 500 direct messages now that
I'm like that was a lot of message just
to try to keep up with oh my goodness
when you get like a hundred messages a
day and you're just trying to field them
you're like hi I'm not ignoring you I'm
just I only poop so often so I only have
so much time to read these messages it
was a lot to look at oh and by the way
did you realize it only takes you like
four or five minutes to prove if you
don't have Instagram the elects don't go
numb on the toilet without Instagram
it's just a weird
I've got other apps okay the best I can
thanks for hanging out bro ladies and
gentlemen thank you guys for hanging out
thanks for listening to episode 409 of
the girl from your heart podcast this
was a good time I hope you enjoyed these
rambles I hope it was worth your time
and energy thanks for listening
everybody if you feel like this podcast
is educational informative or
entertaining what was the other word I
used to use there I think that's all
that I used to say if you feel like this
podcast is worth a buck you can feel
free to throw a buck our way on patreon
you can do so by going to patreon.com
slash grow from your heart all the
information you need to become a patron
will be right there on the screen again
I do appreciate all of the patreon
support I would also appreciate it if
you find the show on Facebook simply
search for the girl from your heart
podcast on the Twitter it is @g fyh
podcasts don't forget about that Twitter
question I asked on the last episode 420
is coming up
what is 420 mean to you somebody asks do
you mean the number do you mean the time
or D me in the date I don't mean
anything I mean what does it mean to you
you tell me what it means that's what
I'm asking what does 420 mean to you you
define it in your way I'm very curious
what you think let me know @ g f YH
podcast on twitter or you can send me an
email because twitter limits you to so
many characters if you're long-winded
the email is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com i would love to hear from
you also don't forget about the youtube
channel please please please subscribe
to the youtube channel I would
appreciate it don't forget to visit our
sponsor Oregon elite seeds put some
fresh new genetics in your garden they
have got the brand new blue raspberry
truffles from ira genetics that'll be
dropping on 420 jump on there before
they run out of that one Mike you got
any words of wisdom before we wrap up
this podcast nope did you just staring
off into space over there well we had
I'd known you were gonna ask about
where's the wisdom at the end of the
show I might have had some we're gonna
start doing like some Mike's moments
some some Jerry's exactly exactly yep
some Mike's final thoughts of Mike's
moments we'll start doing those at the
end of the show or something like that
ladies and gentlemen I want to give you
a huge shot it's my friend Full Monty
and until next time take a phat dab and
give your mom a hug for me