welcome to the show podcast world it's
time for episode 410 of the growth from
your heart podcast this episode of the
show is brought to you by Oregon elite
seeds if you need new seeds in your
garden I highly recommend Oregon elite
seeds and you can find them at
www.ctvn.org
the package the flavor is described as
tropical fruit cocktail I would totally
agree with the tropical fruit cocktail
there's also something real Jolly
Rancher and kind of sweet candy flavored
in there it really sticks around on your
mouth for a long time and it makes the
room smell amazing after you smoke some
dabs I left the room I came back and it
smelled amazing in here so I'm really
enjoying the mai tai full spectrum
extract from Green Dot labs on the back
it says it contains sixty five point
four one percent total THC all right
podcast world I am recording on a cold
April evening if you hear some smacking
noises or some weird random noises in
the background that is because we are
currently experiencing a windstorm that
is including small bursts of hail so if
you hear weird noises in the background
hopefully that is just the wind and the
hail beating against the side of my
house I really hope all of this weather
passes and clears up quickly because
this weekend is the weekend of the dude
grows cup that's right it cultivated
synergy on April 13th I will be
attending and vending at the dude grows
cup in Denver I look forward to seeing
everybody there come say hi by the time
this comes out it will be really close
to cup time if you are interested in
attending the cup send me an email my
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I will forward your
information to the dude and the dude
will get you all of the information you
need to either enter or attend the cup I
do encourage you to enter they are
accepting 50 entries at last count there
were about 40 so there still may be room
by the time this episode comes out once
again if you're interested in attending
or entering the dude grows cup at the
last minute send me an email I will see
if it is still an option I will forward
your contact info to the dude and the
we'll get in touch with you I will also
have the debut of the blue raspberry
truffles at the dude grows cup it will
be the first few packs available at that
event so come say hi all right I do have
a lot to talk about in this episode but
before we get to it I would like to do a
few shoutouts from patreon I want to
give a giant shout out to my friend
Joseph G a big shout out to basta how
about a big shot at the air across Iowa
big thank you to blend your own a giant
Rasta fist bump to Remy redeye and a big
grove from your heart thank you to my
friend Full Monty
all right podcast world a few episodes
back I talked about using co2 in your
garden and somebody asked if I
recommended or suggested turning off or
reducing co2 late in Flour
or at some point in the flowering phase
I recommended to use co2 throughout the
entire grow cycle as soon as you can
start using it start using it and use it
and increase it all the way up to
harvest time I received a comment on my
youtube video from a viewer and the
comment goes like this they said hey
Rasta Jeff thank you for all you do I
think the guy asking about stopping co2
and flower was talking about comments
from ocean grown seeds a few of their
breeders strongly recommend stopping co2
at week six a flower to avoid too much
leaf production what are your thoughts I
would love to know and that's from a
friend on YouTube I don't know if they
want their name said on the show however
if you scroll and troll the YouTube
channel long enough you will find their
comment and you will know who they are
so I am going to completely disagree
with the recommendation of another
breeder however I'm going to do it
completely respectfully I don't know the
rest of their grow tactics we are not
doing everything the same we are
probably doing everything completely
differently growing has a lot of freedom
there are a lot of options there are a
lot of methods there are a lot of
techniques and tactics and many of them
will work I've said before the only way
you're doing it wrong is if the plants
die or if you are not happy with the
final outcome I've got nothing but love
and respect for the folks over at ocean
grown seeds I don't know what they're
doing I don't know they're growing
method
it sounds like they may recommend that
we stop using co2 around week six I
respectfully disagree they recommend to
stop doing it because it produces too
much leaf I am known for defoliating
quite heavily throughout the entire
flowering process so creating too much
leaf is not really a problem for me I
like to go in and D foliate I really
like spending time in the garden doing
that I've got a crew that does it in a
large facility so too much leaf is
really not an issue for me I'm
defoliating anyway I'm in there taking
out leaves to increase light penetration
I'm in they're taking out leaves to
increase airflow I'm in there taking out
leaves just to minimize the amount of
leaf in the room when it comes time to
harvest it helps with respiration and
transpiration it helps keep the VPD in
line I just think it's very advantageous
to defoliate heavily throughout the
flowering period anyway so we grow
differently I'm not disrespecting them
I'm not arguing with that company I'm
just saying we do it differently that is
not how I do it
I feel that you may get a lot of leaf
development if you're using a lot of co2
and certain nutrients I haven't seen
that also you get a lot of blood
development so I think it is worth it I
think it's a positive trade-off I do it
differently I'm not disrespecting
anybody again I completely respect
everybody's grow method as long as it is
working for you however that is not the
way I do it so if you're following my
grow method if you're using all of my
grow methods and techniques and lessons
I would recommend continuing the co2 if
you want to grow with the way the other
guys taught you do that if it works for
you do that do what works for you and
makes you happy or try to make a hybrid
of all of the above as long as it works
out the plants are the boss as long as
the plants are happy and as long as you
were happy with the final outcome
everything is working but that other
company and myself we just do it
differently no hatred no animosity just
different things like I said earlier
different bands playing different songs
so that's my answer to that YouTube
question hey thank you for the great
YouTube question I do like answering the
YouTube comments however it would be
easier for myself and it would probably
be more beneficial for you and more
likely to get your question answered and
acknowledged if you reach out to me
through email my email address is grow
from your heart at hotmail.com that's
the best way to get a hold of me I do
love the Utes
new comments please keep leaving those
but if you want something answered
directly the email is your best pet oh
and if we were having a conversation on
Instagram on my ireon dur score genetics
account I did not block you I did not
abandon the conversation Instagram has
taken down that account I am doing my
best to get the account back but I
cannot make any promises I do have
another account it is Rasta Jeff 7:10 on
Instagram but I haven't posted anything
but a profile picture on that account so
follow me there if you'd like to and in
the meantime I will try to get back the
original IRA underscore genetics
Instagram account alright you guys I
would like to read some Apple podcast
customer reviews on this episode so
let's jump right into it if you would
like to leave a review on Apple podcasts
all you have to do most of you are
probably using an iPhone or some sort of
an Apple device if you open up your
podcasting app and you go to the Grove
from your heart podcast I'm doing this
right now so I can give you a really
good description open up the girl from
your heart podcast if you look at the
available episodes right under there it
says best of the podcast keep scrolling
right past where it gives you best of
the podcast then it comes to ratings and
reviews you can either click all and you
can read all of the ratings and reviews
or you can write a review there's a
little tab you click write a review it
also gives you the option to leave an
amount of stars you can leave up to a
five-star rating so far most folks have
left a five-star rating I'm looking on
my phone so I can't see the exact amount
of stars it shows me that at least one
or two people have left a one and a four
star rating which is just fine with me I
am not for everybody I encourage you to
leave the amount of stars which you feel
I deserve after that type in a little
comment and let everybody know what you
think about the podcast I'm going to
read some recent reviews for the show
let's start with this one it comes from
somebody who calls himself
Darth Knight 3 this was left on February
28th the headline is the cannabis
content I've been craving and the review
goes a little bit like this I am
planning my first grow it was very
excited to find this show and it is no
disappointment jeff paints a vivid
picture and has a passion for educating
people in all aspects of cannabis mike
is awesome he sounds kind of like Joe
Rogan in my opinion this show is so good
we
let the podcast play over the shop
stereo for hours while we work I love
this show man that is a great message
I'm glad that you found us while you're
planning your first grow I hope you have
checked out the grow lessons I hope
those did you very well I enjoyed that
you think I paint a vivid picture and
I'm glad that you can see my passion for
educating and my passion for canvas it
means a lot to me
cannabis means a lot and I want to
dispel all of the rumors about cannabis
and I want people to just do the best
with cannabis put it in the best light
so I'm glad that you see that and thank
you for trying to do that for us
dude you say mic is awesome yes mic is
awesome mic is a cool dude he's a good
bro he's a good father he's a good
husband just one bad [ __ ] so mic
is cool thanks for being my bro Mike
thanks for noticing that and then you
say he sounds like Joe Rogan in your
opinion you probably mean mic because I
don't think I sound like Rogan but to
have somebody on the show called like
Rogan you got the word Rogan in there
that's always a compliment to us so
thank you for that the show is so good
you just let it play over the shop
stereo that is awesome I'm curious what
kind of shop you've got is it a retail
shop is it where you're working are
there more people walking in and being
exposed to the show as you're listening
to it I'm just curious
my mind gets curious when you say you're
playing it in a public area makes me
want to know who's listening but man I'm
glad more people are being exposed I'm
glad you're playing it and most of all
I'm glad you love the show so big thanks
for listening to the show big thanks for
the great review an extra big thanks for
that five star rating alright I do have
a few more comments let's get right to
the next one this next one comes from a
person who calls themselves willies
armpit what's up willies armpit I love
that name for some reason the headline
says bad memories let's read this it
says love the podcast very informative
with easy-to-follow descriptions
absolutely love the idea of having all
the past episodes to refer to in 87 I
tried my first indoor girl with
absolutely no idea what I was doing what
a miserable failure it was isn't it so
much easier now that we've got the
Internet and a little bit of guidance
I'm so glad I can help you out the
review keeps going and says if I only if
only I had someone like Ross to Jeff I
could have listened to every Monday and
Thursday I might not have wasted those
huge watermelon sized skunk seeds oh I
bet those were great I'm sorry we wasted
those but
we've got more seeds don't worry he goes
on to say it was the nastiest skunk
smell losing from the bags at that time
four years in Florida you could not
count on the skunk bud between or you
could count on the skunk bud between
October and December like clockwork
deliciously nasty skunk bud you're
making my mouth water every time you say
that you were in love with that skunk
but and I think my taste buds and my
nose are into that why do we love the
most disgusting like the worst aromas
are really the best when it comes to
cannabis you like it kind of smells like
puke and skunk and dirty feet and like
cool I'll take two please it's really
strange they were like that the review
continues it says never to be smelled
again now I'm heartbroken I just built
myself up to get my heart broke and
that's miserable then it says what I
would give for another try at those
seeds
damn it man bad memories well if you're
a seed shopper if you were into shopping
for seeds on the internet I would
recommend you find something called road
kill
skunk if you can find some good roadkill
skunk they'll be hard to find they may
not be available on a lot of the
commercial websites but if you can find
some of the rks grow that out you may
get some of that old nasty disgusting
delicious skunk smell that you're
talking about I am sorry and you're
welcome that I'm bringing back terrible
memories of your failed to grow
experience but now that you've got me
around now that you've got the Internet
hopefully we can fix that hopefully your
next grow is top-notch hopefully we can
put some fresh new memories in your head
and wipe out that old memory or maybe
you can compare the two we'll leave them
both in there you probably smoked enough
to wear that old memory is kind of hazy
anyway so let's get you growing some new
stuff you've got some girl lessons
you've got some good guidance you've got
some good advice and I'll answer your
questions so let's get you growing let's
get you a new harvest and then you can
look at the new harvest and then you can
try to remember back on that old one and
you can just feel proud inside for how
much you've improved and how much you've
learned and how far you've come and well
he's our pet I'm glad that you find the
episodes to be informative and easy to
follow I'm glad you like my descriptions
and I'm glad that you were learning
along with the podcast let me know how
your next crop goes let's erase those
bad memories and replace them with some
pride hey Willy's armpit thanks again
for the great review and of course
Willy's armpit and the Dark Knight gave
us five star reviews thanks to both of
you for those let's move forward this
next one comes from a person who calls
themselves dean tutu
they gave us a five-star rating the
review goes like this most informative
and entertaining gross show ever I
should just stop reading right there oh
no I should keep going because it says
Rasta Jeff is my hero man that is the
coolest review ever most informative I
like that you didn't say best because
best is a relative term I like that you
feel I am the most informative as well
as the most entertaining that means a
lot to me thank you being your hero is
kind of a lot of pressure and you need
better heroes but thank you that is a
great compliment I'm just trying to play
that one down because I don't know what
to say about that but thank you let's
continue with the review where is it I
lost it here it is it says I'm a Brent I
am brand-new to stealth growing personal
medicine and I listen constantly I'm 63
and I feel born again thanks Ross - Jeff
Wow ah it is great to be a 63 year old
person's hero usually we look up to
somebody who is our senior and I've got
somebody who is my senior looking up to
me so that means a lot to me
you were brand new to stealth growing
your personal medicine if you have any
questions please send me an email I will
answer your questions via email we don't
have to read them on the show we can
keep it between us and tueur stealth
growing it sounds like you may be and
somewhere we can't discuss everything on
the show so send me questions if you've
got them I would love to help you out
maybe send me a few good questions and I
will put together another stealth
growing episode those always seem to be
a lot of fun and keep listening but most
of all thank you for the great review
and also thank you for the 5-star rating
I really appreciate that Dean
two to one and I look forward to getting
some emails with stealth growing
questions from you
all right this next review comes from a
person who calls themselves daddy Oh 45
they gave us a five star rating the
headline of the review is Rasta Jeff and
white Mike killing it once again and the
review goes just like this killer show
like always plus it's a white Mike
episode so they were they thought they
were commenting on a specific episode my
hey Mike it looks like people are
enjoying your episodes so you need to
find time to come back and record more
frequently my friend they keep going the
review says that means it's a very fun
and informative show thanks for all the
advice that seems to just fall out of
your guy's minds when you two get
together that's pretty awesome hey
thanks for the great compliment
we're listening to the show and thanks
for the great review and thanks for the
five stars and I will pass the message
along to Mike he is probably listening
so he's gonna hear it right now hey Mike
people do approve come record bro I miss
you I miss hanging out Mike come take a
DAB all right I'm going to move forward
we've got another review this one is
titled this is the one they gave us a
five star rating this one is left by our
friend Glenn Girone big shout out to
Glenn Geron thanks for all the support
the review goes like this fantastic
content specific actionable and clear I
think those were the exact goals so
thank you I appreciate that
I love how Jeff doesn't babble in tribal
knowledge and bro science well I
appreciate that sometimes I try to make
things understandable for everybody and
I'm glad it doesn't seem like I'm bro
sciencing things when I do that I want
everybody to be able to to enjoy and
appreciate the show I want everybody to
be able to learn from the show people
who are thinking about buying grow set
up and people that have been running
commercial facilities I want them both
to be entertained so sometimes I do have
to take a huge concept and kind of make
it a little simplified for the new
people to figure it out but I also have
to stay entertaining for the people have
been doing it so I'm glad you don't find
it to be bro sciency I appreciate that
is what I think I'm trying to say the
message continues he says this show
along with the DG see that is the dude
grow show have brought me from growing
some slightly dank popcorn baby buds to
cultivating massive dank bud so I'm glad
we could improve your grow that is the
main goal here is to get everybody
growing massive dank buds I'm glad we
got you up to speed the review continues
it says I look forward to each episode
also I will take a fat dad and give my
mom a hug for both of us much love
brother Glen in Oklahoma those folks in
Oklahoma are killing it right now
Oklahoma is kind of the new Colorado
it's the wild wild west I hope you guys
are having a great time while you can
down there enjoy it while it lasts I'm
not saying it's gonna go away it's just
going to change it will tighten up right
now it's the wild wild west you're
running freestyle get it while you can
my friend also Glen Jerome thanks for
the great review thanks for the
five-star rating and also thanks for the
great compliments I do thanks for doing
a great job in your gar
I'm glad you've gone from little popcorn
buds to massive tank buds I'm glad I'm
glad that between the dude bro show and
myself we were able to get you up to
speed big shots all my friends at the
dude Gro show I love that we've got a
good network going on we've got one more
customer review to read in this episode
this one comes from a friend who calls
himself Charlie Moody the title of the
review is really enjoying this and of
course we got another five-star rating
the review goes like this
I started where did it go the screen
move there we go I started with the
planning your grow episode when I got to
the repeats I went back to the early
hundreds
I just finished number 161 man you've
heard a lot of content and I think you
did very well by starting with the
planning your grow episode and your all
the way back to 161 that is crazy you
have listened to a lot of content he
goes on to say I appreciate the detail
the wealth of experience and the good
humor I love that and all of the reviews
every time I read a Bachelor of reviews
there's always one person that mentions
the attempt at humor I'm glad that
somebody enjoys it I try to have fun
with this I did not have fun in school I
loved learning but I did not like
sitting somewhere for eight hours being
told that I can't tap my foot or that I
can't just stare off into space yeah I'm
listening I'm just staring off into
space because that's how my brain
absorbs stuff they want me to look at
the teacher I just didn't like being
there I had teachers that were
entertaining I had teachers that told me
jokes those are the classes that I chose
to go to more frequently later on in my
school career there were a lot of
classes I would skip because the teacher
was not enjoyable I hated that class I
just wouldn't go if the teacher was
better if he was funny if she was funny
I had much more of a chance of going to
that class so I try to teach with a
little bit of humor I think I think it
makes everything stick a little bit
better I fill you up with a whole bunch
of knowledge and then I just seal it in
there with a joke so that it you kind of
whole bunch of stuff whole bunch of
stuff and then a joke so it doesn't feel
stressful normal learning can be kind of
stressful trying to cram a bunch of
stuff into your brain can kind of be
stressful and overwhelming sometimes
then if you tell a joke at the end wash
it off with a little bit of laughter
hopefully a lot of that knowledge
retains and then it doesn't feel
stressful at the end of the lesson so
I'm glad you enjoy my attempt at humor
and I want to give you a big thank you
for the great
review and also a big thanks for the
5-star rating I want to thank everybody
that is left in iTunes customer review I
really do appreciate it it really does
help us move up in the iTunes rankings
it helps more people see the show the
more people that see the show the more
people are growing better cannabis and
that is our goal here we want everybody
growing the best cannabis possible
all right podcast world that's all I've
got for you for this quick Thursday
episode I want to thank you again for
listening the next episode will be a
strain review and description episode
stay tuned for that after that I will
get back into the e mail episodes if you
feel like this episode was educational
informative or entertaining and you
would like to make a financial
contribution to the podcast you can do
so by visiting patreon.com slash grow
from your heart all the information you
need to become a patron will be right
there on the screen once again big shout
out and big thank you to everybody who's
contributed to the patreon account I
would also appreciate it if you find me
on social media on Facebook it is the
girl from your heart podcast on Twitter
it's at G fyh podcast if you'd like to
follow my personal account it is at
rasta Jeff 420 I would also appreciate
it if you find the show on YouTube
simply search for the girl from your
heart a podcast on YouTube
give us a subscribe leave some comments
on your favorite video I would
appreciate all of that support if you've
got something to say and you're not into
all the social media of course you can
send me an email
it is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I would love to hear from
you and get your message on a future
episode ladies and gentlemen you can
hear my throat burning out I'm gonna
wrap up the podcast I'm gonna give you a
huge shout out to my friend Aldridge and
until next time take a phat dab and give
your mom a hug for me