hey it's time for episode 411 of the
drove from your heart podcast this
episode is brought to you by Oregon
elite seeds if you need new seeds in
your garden I highly recommend Oregon
elite seeds and you can find them at
www.juergenschreiter.com
was really impressive I generally go for
a more THC heavy sativa dominant style
concentrate but this one seems to have
mellowed me out it made me sit back in
the chair a little bit and it kind of
calmed me down so this should be a fun
podcast ladies and gentlemen I do have a
great episode planned for you but before
we get too far let's do some shoutouts
for our friends on patreon let's start
off with the big shout out to our friend
David O'Quinn about a big shout out to
Ryan Schmidt a huge shout out to Riley
Hanson a big girl from your heart
podcast shout out to Jon milk a big
shout out to Sam and of course another
ganja grower shout out to my friend
farmer Jon podcast world this episode is
going to be another strain review if
you've been following the podcast for a
while you know that I like to talk about
strains that I have bred and featured
them here on the podcast of course I am
I read genetics I've read a lot of fine
quality cannabis I use a male plant
known as a rise I also make some
feminized crosses with various selected
females that are reversed and turned
into males that's a whole other podcast
in this episode we're going to focus on
one of my new most recent and most
favorite creations this will be the
debut most of you haven't heard about
this one yet this is the first time we
will talk about blue raspberry truffle
here on the podcast so ladies and
gentlemen pack up the bong roll up a fat
joint eat up the dad nail and let's talk
a little bit about blue raspberry
truffle
when this episode originally comes out
blue raspberry truffle will not be
available blue raspberry truffle will
not be available until 4:20 and it will
be released first at Oregon elite seed
bank and you can find them at Oregon
elite seeds dot-com so make sure you
look for the blue raspberry truffle
around April 20th on Oregon elite seeds
also I will have very limited packs with
me at the dude grows Cup so if you're at
the dude grows Cup on April 13th at
cultivated synergy stop by the booth you
may have an opportunity to get some of
the first released packs of the blue
raspberry truffle I like to let things
go with the events in person face to
face before some of the vendors even
have it so this will be your first
opportunity so let's talk a little bit
about blue raspberry truffle what is
this blue raspberry truffle that I keep
talking about blue raspberry truffle is
of course a cross of my arise mail I've
got a prized arise mail that I've named
King Solomon I use in many of my crosses
a rise is a golden goat female
pollinated by a Daybreaker male we'll
briefly talk about a rise I've done a
full Episode on a rise
it is episode 329 and I do a full
feature of the strain arise we'll
briefly talk about it here arise is a
golden go female pollinated by eight-day
breaker male golden goat is kind of
tropical kind of sweet at his island
sweet skunk Hawaiian sativa and a
Romulan so it's got that tropical sativa
flavor to it it's got a really nice head
buzz to it is a really great growing
plant and it is very potent the
Daybreaker male used in that cross is
Kim D crossed it Joseph OG the Kim D has
kind of a fresh tennis ball kind of a
fresh rubber sort of a smell and then of
course Joseph Bo G smells like swampy og
cush it's kind of piney kind of gassy
it's got kind of a really unique funk to
it so I like that one for its funky
flavors and aromas it had a short
squatty structure with really wide
leaves so it really contrasted that
golden goat quite well so I bred those
two together and I made that arise cross
out of those arise seeds came a very
standout male that male has been known
as King Solomon King Solomon basically
turbocharges everything he pollinates
you can take a plant that has great
flavor and great trichome production but
maybe doesn't grow the best and King
Solomon will fix that growth he gives
plants hyper vigor he also increases
potency he also increases yield
I feel like King Solomon is a very
special plant that is why I breed him to
so many different things so that is a
quick rundown of King Solomon King
Solomon is the male I used in the blue
raspberry truffles now let's talk about
the female they'll be used in this cross
I know I'm good at building suspense
everybody wants to know what was the
girl in that cross the female that I
used for the blue raspberry truffle
cross was the blueberry cookies cross
and that blueberry cookies is actually a
cross of blueberry Tahoe and platinum
cookies it's got a very very blueberry
dominant kind of a blueberry skittles a
nerds kind of a flavor and a really
funky aroma going on I've been working
for a little while with the blueberry
cookies and I have only seen impressive
results I've ran the blueberry cookies
in commercial environments I've grown it
in my personal grow I have seen it grown
in
there grows by growers who are not as
experienced by myself and it always does
a great job the blueberry cookies was
one of my favorite strains to smell to
grow to smoke to work with I quickly
fell in love with that I had to cross it
to my prized arise King Solomon mail so
I did that I pollinated the blueberry
cookies with my arise mail and the
offspring are impressive
I could tell early on in the veg phase
that these plants were going to be
impressive they had amazing growth their
structure was beautiful they were
perfectly shaped and early in veg I
could smell a blueberry sort of a
rubbery tennis ball sort of a burnt
muffin sort of a thing coming off of
these plants in their veg faith so I was
super excited to get these plants into
flower and when they went into flower
the aroma is only intensified these
plants took off when I put them in
flower they did get kind of tall kind of
quickly but we're gonna talk about the
growing and stuff in a minute let's talk
about the aromas and smoking this plant
while it was growing
it smelled like blueberries and almost
like hot chocolate or really dark
chocolate which is where it got the
truffle name from the blue raspberry
truffle it's got that blueberries with
something sour which is where the
raspberry comes in and then that dark
chocolate was kind of truffle II blue
raspberry truffles was what I thought of
the first time it got real real musty in
the grow room so it's kind of got a sort
of a blue skittles or a pack of nerds
and dark chocolate and blueberries is
really dominant in there so that is
where I got the name is the blue
raspberry truffles as it got older in
flower the truffle II smell that chem
dog OG Kush Joseph OG really came out in
it it started off sweeter and more candy
like most of the phenotypes got a little
bit more of the truffle flavor toward
the end some of the plants honestly I
let go too long I should have cut some
of them down a little bit earlier I feel
like there is a nice window with some of
the phenotypes where it will change from
that blueberry thing sort of over to a
musty er more of the truffle II it's got
a foot kind of a thing going on if you
let it kind of transfer
into that phase at the end if you let it
go a little bit too long we're gonna
talk about those phenotypes here in just
a minute
so as the grow went on many of the
phenotypes got a little bit musty ER is
the word that I like to use for it a
little more truffle II a little more
dark chocolatey a little earthy is kind
of the flavor and aroma I think I should
be saying as earthy they got a little
more earthy but when I cut them down it
kind of seemed like I just broke open
the blueberry Terp jar it was just
blueberries and raspberries and kind of
a skinny flavor just filled the room it
was crazy that it produced that much of
a different aroma I thought it was very
interesting so as it grew it started off
with the real blueberry raspberry sort
of a thing as it got older many of the
phenotypes shifted to sort of an earthy
truffle kind of a flavor some of them
did maintain their blueberry thing we're
gonna talk about the phenotypes and the
the division of that just a minute here
but when I cut it down it exploded with
blue raspberry nerds and remember those
blue lollipops we used to get back in
the day that would turn your whole face
blue it kind of reminded me of that the
flavor and aroma was very reminiscent of
that blue raspberry lollipop and a
package of nerds so I cut it down I
dried it i cured it as I cured it I
noticed that that musty smell kind of
got lighter and as it lightened it
balanced out the blueberries and the
earthy smell really nicely I think it
really balanced them out very well
toward the words blue raspberry truffle
just made more sense as time went on
when I started smelling it I was like
that's blue raspberry truffles and as
time went on it just proved itself that
that name was perfect for it so I really
think that it smells and tastes like a
blue raspberry truffle so I dried it i
cured it then what's next I got to smoke
it first before we get there let me say
this stuff destroys a grinder your
grinder will be sticky your fingers will
be super sticky this is some extremely
resinous and sticky herb so when I
smoked it I tried to roll a joint and it
got really sticky maybe I needed to let
it dry a little longer but it was really
sticky but it tasted amazing I had to
try again and put it in a bowl the bowl
tasted even better
it had that blueberry thing come out
right away
as soon as you hit it it was like ooh
that is blueberry skittles or blueberry
nerds or something really blueberry like
a blueberry muffin not the not like the
real blueberries it smells like fake
blueberries like if there were a
blueberry air freshener that's what it
would be don't think it's fresh fruity
blueberries this smells like straight-up
fake blueberries and candy like if they
had blueberry candy Terps at the candy
store that's what it would be like it is
not like a fruit blueberry it is like a
very powerful almost a sour blueberry
candy and it is delicious but as soon as
that green ball started to burn that
blueberry aroma hit the room it was like
you cracked open a blueberry air
freshener and then it was like ooh
that's delicious but then on the exhale
that's where that warm cushy flavor
comes through so it filled the room with
sweet blueberries and then right after
cushion truffles so that was pretty nice
it gave me intense cottonmouth
immediately it was I never drink but it
tasted so good that I did not want to
drink anything to wash away that complex
flavor it's really neat when you've got
you go blueberry ooh and chocolate your
brain has to figure that out you're
going oh how did I get such a range of
flavors I really enjoy that wide range
of flavors it was very reminiscent of
some of the old blueberry strains I've
smoked back in the day also very similar
to the blueberry cookies mom that it
came from but also that arise it took
that Kim D flavor and it really put the
tennis balls of the Kim D that chocolate
flavor that Kim D sometimes has it
really brought that out into this cross
so the cottonmouth happens instantly the
hi is crazy
the head-high comes on super quickly
when you hit it you're like oh I'm high
now and I smoke a lot of dabs so to
notice a bowl or a joint of flour come
on that quickly that means that it is
potent so that the head buzz comes on
quickly it went to my eyes it kind of
went behind my eyes it made my eyes feel
heavy but not like droopy like they were
being pushed on I kind of kind of
intense I was high I was really high
then it kind of slowly drifts over my
body
I could feel it it went from my brain
and then it was like oh I'm really high
I'm really high and then I felt it like
kind of radiates down my spine across my
shoulders down
arms and then worked its way all the way
down my back to my hips and my knees and
my shoulders are kind of where a lot of
my my pain and stress are I keep my
attention and my shoulders into my gut
and then my knees are distressed because
I'm old so it gets to the knees and it
relaxes them and my whole body just
feels like it's in a cozy blanket I
described it the other day is a
superhero cape because it just made me
feel good I was like I want to get up
and do some [ __ ] and somebody's like
what do you want to do is like [ __ ] I
don't really know I just want to get up
and do some [ __ ] I didn't really have
any goals or anything but I felt like I
should be doing something damn it
but I love it it comes on super quickly
it spreads throughout your body it makes
you feel all warm and tingly is a really
great feeling if you've got some pain
I'm sure that this one would be great
for your pain so that is a basic smoke
report it tastes amazing the smoke was
great my first sample I did not let dry
long enough but once I let it dry and
cure properly it really had a great
amazing flavor and it burned beautifully
so now let's talk a little bit about the
growing aspect of our blue raspberry
truffle most of the time the first
question people ask is how long does it
take I would recommend nine weeks maybe
a little longer but you probably don't
need to go past ten weeks maybe 72 days
at the absolute longest I don't think it
would take any longer than that I've
gone 72 days honestly some of the
phenotypes had gone too long at that
point growth structure she gets a little
bit tall but she makes huge colas if
you've seen pictures of a rise if you've
seen pictures of the blueberry cookies
you know that both of those plants make
monstera stop colas these plants will
get tall on you quickly but it is worth
it because they put out quite a bit of
weight you will have big fat chunky
colas that are covered in tri cups if
you've seen photos of the blueberry
cookies if you've seen photos of any of
the arize crosses all of them are coated
in trichomes this one is just like that
it will put on a layer of crusty
trichomes so you'll have giant colas
these plants grow with what I call hyper
vigor I have had a few people tell me
that plants crossed with the rise grow
too quickly for them and they need to
reduce their veg time by at least one
full week so be prepared for fast
growing hyper vigorous tall plants the
we'll take off on you now they do like
to be topped and spread out if you were
the type of person that tops your plants
you can top these they will make a giant
glory Cola at the top if you do not top
them if you choose to top them you're
going to get nice branching that's going
to spread out very far you'll have a
nice full canopy these plants can take
some abuse they like to be cracked they
like to be popped they like to be
twisted these plants like to get worked
into a trellis if you've got a net or
something like that I highly recommend a
trellis system if not you're going to
need some sticks some stakes some cages
or something to keep some of these
taller bigger buds up when they get big
they may get a little bit floppy I
recommend you top them and spread them
out I like to spread out my plants kind
of far these are gonna get a little bit
bushy on you when you top them blue
raspberry truffles can take a [ __ ] ton
of nutrients in my experience of course
I have only grown this plant in soilless
mix and cocoa I've tried to feed it too
hard I gave it a little bit too much
shine it didn't react too poorly to me
it can take a beating I really like to
push my plants and I really like to see
what they can take and the blue
raspberry truffle can really take a lot
of nutrients I've grown it in the cocoa
I've grown it in the soil and it can
really take abuse in both of those blue
raspberry truffle will react a little
bit poorly if she gets too hot you'll
get taco leaves and it will stunt her
growth and she will get extra stretchy
she's already a stretchy plant if you
get her too hot she will start
stretching on you she wants to get away
from herself and away from the other
plants she wants to stretch out and find
some fresh air she will get growing when
she gets too hot she also does that if
you cram her in with too many other
plants she wants to be up high so she
will grow give her space
topper maybe give her a trellis to hold
her down but if it gets too hot you'll
get taco leaves you'll get massively
slowed production from this plant so
don't get it too hot and I'm sure at
that point somebody's going to say what
is too hot there are so many variables
to think about when you ask that
question which phenotype are you working
with what is the rest of your VPD
looking like in the room it may be able
to take more heat if you've got co2 I'm
not exactly sure what to tell you on
what is too hot
some of
we'll react poorly to too much heat so
keep an eye out for heat stress the
first thing you're going to see is those
leaves at the top they'll start pointing
straight up at the light and then they
will start talking it looks like they're
praying that is not what's happening
that plant is telling you I'm a little
bit too hot please raise the light or
please taught me or please Bend me down
so I'm not getting a sunburn so that is
the basic grow breakdown of the blue
raspberry truffles nine to ten weeks ten
weeks should be plenty I found that she
can take a lot of nutrients I haven't
burned this plant and I have tried so
she can take a lot of nutrients I would
suggest giving it a lot with this plant
you were more likely to under feed than
you are to overfeed make sure you give
her lots of space spread her out and
make sure she doesn't get too hot
because that is the one thing she really
does not like I have seen a lot of
beautiful colors come from the blue
raspberry truffle a lot of dark colors a
lot of dark purples a lot of gold and
amber colors for the end of flower she
really makes gorgeous colors I really
like to drop the temperatures late in
flower in my grow room and for the last
few days I will really bring out the
cold
I really saw a lot of color changing
when the room got colder also I did
throw a couple of plants in the dark for
24 hours and they turned gold and purple
on me so it will give you a lot of
beautiful colors get the temperatures
down low toward the end of flower and I
really think you will see the beauty
come out of this plant it is powdery
mildew resistant I haven't seen powdery
mildew on the blue raspberry truffle yet
so that is a bonus another bonus is this
plant loves to make resin there is a lot
of resin on the blue raspberry truffles
you will see phenotypes then it looks
like the trichomes are fighting for
space so let's move into talking about
phenotypes of blue raspberry truffles
this is a really stable hybrid in my
opinion some of the phenotypes are blue
berry cookies dominant their very
skittles II and I say skittles II they
smell like a bag of skittles more like a
bag of blue raspberry candies or
possibly those blue nerds if heat blue
nerds candies that's kind of what it
smells like to me it's kind of sweet and
sour and blueberry and delicious and it
is so wonderful so you will have some
phenotypes that are blueberry
cookies dominant and you will also have
some arise dominant phenotypes if you've
got more of a lemon more of a citrus
type of a thing that is very arise
golden goat dominant now since the
parent plants are very similar it's
going to be kind of hard to tell the
difference between maybe a blueberry
cookies dominant phenotype and in a rise
dominant phenotype both of those plants
have a similar structure a similar leaf
shape and size they're very different
but they are very similar to a new
grower they've both got long skinny
pointy leaves they both grow tall they
both grow kind of branchy
they both branch out they both have
hyper vigor so the main thing you're
going to notice is the aroma the aroma
is really going to be what stands out
the most now yes you are going to see
phenotypes that will show you golden
goat you'll see phenotypes that will
show you the Daybreaker the cross on the
blueberry cookies is the blueberry tahoe
and platinum cookies so you're going to
see blueberry you're going to see tahoe
OG and you're going to see platinum
cookies come out a little bit because
you're going to find recessive traits
from the grandparents for the most part
these plants are going to look like a
rise that smells a lot like blueberry
cookies so you're going to find
blueberry cookies dominant phenotypes
then you are going to find a rise
dominant phenotypes then in the mix we
are going to find 50/50 phenotypes let's
talk about that the arize phenotypes are
going to be a little airier a little
fluffier just a little more loose also
you may find that the arise dominant
phenotypes will have a tropical citrus
sort of a thing you may also notice that
the arise dominant phenotypes are a
little bit stretchier and I believe that
that comes from the Joseph og side of
things now the blueberry cookies
dominant phenotype seems to stay a
little shorter and the node spacing
seems to stay a little bit tighter
you'll also see a little bit larger leaf
from the blueberry cookies dominant
phenotype I think that comes from the
Platinum cookie side of things also the
Tahoe og has fairly large leaves so
there is one phenotype that is really
tight
really sharp looking buds it's got
little wider leaves toward the bottom
they get thinner leave toward the top it
kinda
gets a nice uh menorah shape toward the
bottom and it's got one glory Cola that
grows out of it it's got a blueberry
skittle sort of a smell to it that is
the blueberry cookies dominant phenotype
then there is another phenotype that is
very similar without a comparison it is
hard to tell the difference it is also
tall it's got a big glory bud but that
bottom branching will be a little bit
stretchier it'll be a little bit further
apart in node spacing it won't have the
blueberry skittles flavor it will have
more of a tropical sweet flavor along
with that earthy flavor as a dominant
sort of a thing so that is the golden
goat dominant phenotype then we've got
the 50/50 the 50/50 is the one that
smells like blueberries and dark
chocolate it is the blue raspberry
truffle scented phenotype I really enjoy
that one the lower leaves are a little
broader as it gets taller it gets the
thinner leaves the leaves get real long
and skinny toward the top my favourite
phenotype of the blue raspberry truffle
is the one with the shorter pea deals if
the leaves are closer to the plant the
bigger Sun leaves if they're closer to
the plant that is one of my favorite
phenotypes and the further out those
beetles get the more I feel like you're
getting that golden goat trait so I
think we're getting more of the 50/50
more of the desirable one when we get in
a little bit some of the leaves will
hang down I've noticed more of the
chocolate flavor comes from the plants
with the leaves that droop you'll see
some that have droopy leaves that
doesn't mean the plant is thirsty that
does not mean the plant is over watered
that comes from Daybreaker that is a
trait of the day breaker mail which I
used that doesn't pop up a lot but it
comes out in this cross so if you see
the leaves drooping that has potential
of being a very chocolate maybe a tennis
ball maybe a rubbery sort of a smelling
phenotype so we've got that blueberry
cookies dominant the real jagged the
real sharp looking one we've got the
arize dominant phenotype the one that
opens up a little bit it's not super
tight it's not super fluffy either it
just has more air space than that
blueberry cookies dominant phenotype
it's got more of a tropical smell longer
P deals that is the golden goat dominant
phenotype we've got the 50/50 it is that
beautifully balanced mix nice tight buds
that blue raspberry truffles sort of
aroma it's got the blueberry skittles
it's got the chocolate kind of
background going on to it that is the
desirable sought-after phenotype
my opinion then there's a phenotype that
I have dubbed the weirdo this one may be
great for concentrates this one is a
little bit Airy it is kind of a
blueberry golden coat but it kind of
gets a little bit fluffy I suspect it is
probably a blueberry Hawaiian sativa is
kind of what we've got going on or
perhaps maybe like a blueberry Hawaiian
sativa is what kind of came out of that
because it gets tall and it gets a
little bit fluffy it doesn't tighten up
it's quite airy I think it would make
great concentrates because it tastes
very very blueberry dominant it brings
out a really sweet blueberry sort of a
thing and it's just covered in trichomes
but it is not desirable for bag appeal
it wouldn't work good on the market
nobody would want to buy it didn't want
to smoke it a few times but once they
saw but it looks like it would change
their opinion so that is the one weirdo
phenotype from what I have experienced
I've grown a lot of these seeds from
what I have experienced I see the
blueberry cookies dominant phenotype
approximately 30 percent I get the arize
dominant approximately 30 percent
I get that fifty 50 percent that
beautiful the one I'm after comes up
about 30 percent of the time then that
[ __ ] weirdo plant that pops up
somewhere between five and fifteen
percent just for math sake at this time
we're gonna say it comes up at 10
percent you may see that weirdo in there
that weirdo is easy to identify early in
flower because it just takes off
immediately it makes little tiny sparse
bud sites right at the very beginning
you can tell everything else is starting
to make in my opinion it looks like
dandelions this one doesn't make the
dandelions it just gets little tiny tiny
bud sets you can see it is it wants to
build calyxes on calyx is kind of kind
of like the old doctor doctor Grinspoon
used to do and just be real galaxies but
it also fluffs out like like a diesel
plant doesn't that probably comes from
the chem D somewhere along the line so
those are the phenotypes are gonna look
for that is how it grows that's how it
smokes that's what the buzz is like that
is my breeder breakdown on my new blue
raspberry truffle if you were into
unique aroma as if you're into
blueberries if you're into fruitiness if
you're into skittles if you're into
earthiness there are a lot of
opportunities for great phenotypes in a
pack of blue raspberry truffles they'll
be available at the dude Gro show on
April 13th that cultivated
energy then after that your next
opportunity will be from Oregon elite
seeds at www.ge.com you can find a full
lineup of I read genetic seeds there
just go ahead and check out Oregon elite
seeds go into the search bar type in I
read genetics my name may not be on the
right on the links yet because I'm
fairly new to the website but if you
type it in it should pop up or type in a
rise or something like that and it will
bring up the I read genetics line all
right podcast world that is all I've got
free for this episode thank you for
letting me talk about my new creation
the blue raspberry truffles thank you
for hanging out with me I'll be back in
just a couple of days with fresh new
content if you feel like this episode
was educational informative or
entertaining and you would like to make
a financial contribution to the show you
can do so by going to patreon.com of the
information you need will be right there
on the screen don't forget you can
follow me on all the social media you
can find me on Facebook simply search
for the girl from your heart podcast on
Twitter it's @gf wih podcast and please
subscribe to my youtube channel simply
search for the girl from your heart
podcast if you've got something to say
and you're not into the social media you
can reach me through email my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
and I would love to hear from you ladies
and gentlemen thanks again for listening
to this episode I want to give a huge
shout out to my friend to the roach and
until next time take a phat dad and give
your mom a hug for me