welcome back podcast world it's time for
episode 412 of the girl from your heart
podcast this episode is brought to you
by our friends at Oregon elite C's if
you need new seeds in your garden I
highly recommend Oregon elite seeds and
you can find them at
www.gamingcypher.com like us Tropicana
cookies Fambrough jaar jaar it started
off as a 4 gram jar it is quickly
depleting the label says this is 72
point 4 percent THC with a total of 83
you know that says 85 percent total
cannabinoids this is a tasty concentrate
I really love the Tropicana cookies if I
remember correctly the Tropicana cookies
won the dude grows Cup last night we
will talk about that in just a minute
before we get there I owe a few people
some shoutouts from patreon how about a
big shot it's my friend squirrel tactics
a huge shot at Tabata another giant grow
from your heart shout out to my friend
Aldridge how about a big giant shout out
to Eric Ross and of course another shout
out to Tanner Martin Oh a thank you guys
for all the continued patreon support if
you'd like to learn how to become a
patreon all you need to do is go to
patreon.com/scishow to put out on Friday
I put out an episode all about the blue
raspberry truffle stream which I debuted
at the dude gross show so I hope
everybody got to listen to that quite a
few people mentioned they did listen I
got a great response to it people seem
to like the way I describe cannabis so
thanks for the support thanks for
listening to the show and thanks for the
huge reaction at the dude gross Cup a
lot of people were really interested in
the blue raspberry truffle ladies an
gentlemen my Instagram is back on the
last few episodes I've been crying and
complaining like a little girl that my
Instagram is gone I sent a bunch of
emails I filled out a bunch of customer
request forms and I have back I'm back
on Instagram they got my account going
they didn't remove anything they cleaned
out my inbox so all my messages are gone
but all my posts are back all my
hashtags are back I am back in action on
Instagram if you're not already
following me on Instagram I highly
encourage you to give me a follow on
Instagram I use ie
underscore
attics is my company name I post a lot
of great cannabis photography I do live
feed they go talk about cannabis growing
talk about cannabis culture if you come
into my life eat and ask a cannabis
question I will answer your question
there in the live feed it is a great
time I do encourage you to join me there
one more thing I want to talk about
before we get to the dude gross cup
that's what my voice is all burned out
by the way you guys I smoked a bunch of
flour and a bunch of concentrates at the
dude gross cup my voice sounds like poop
I apologize for that but before we get
there only shot it's my friend Kelvin
Medina Kelvin is from Oklahoma he was
attending the dude grows cup in Denver
on his way from Oklahoma he stopped at
the spot right here at the dad table and
he took a couple of fat dad I promised
helvin I was gonna get him uncomfortably
high I'm pretty sure mission
accomplished
dude Kelvin thank you for stopping
through that was a great time it is
great meeting people that I've made
friends with through the podcast through
social media it's always a good time
making new friends and meeting the
people that I've been helping in their
gardens man thanks for coming through
big shout out to Kelvin now let's talk
about the dude grows show let me tell
you what the dude grows show and the
dude grows cup that's actually what
we're gonna talk about let me tell you
what that is the dude gross show is a
podcast it's another growing podcast I'm
sure you've heard me mention that on the
show the dude grow show is hosted by my
friend the dude it's co-hosted by a dude
named Scotty real it is engineered by a
guy known as the grow guru we've got
quite a few guys behind the scenes big
shout out to all of them it is a great
podcast they have developed a great
community the community is known as the
dude grows crew our friend the dude and
Scotty put together a great event that
event was last night at cultivated
synergy in Denver I think this was the
fifth event if I am correct I am often
wrong on things like that it was at
least the third dude gross cup anyhow
they threw the dude gross cup it
cultivated synergy it is sort of a it's
designed to be a community event the
highlight of the event is sort of a grow
off people are invited to enter their
grow into the competition then there is
a blind taste test everybody who enters
everybody who attends the event is
considered a judge you are given tokens
you are offered a one-hitter pipe as you
walk in and you're allowed to sample all
of the entries so they've got a little
bud bar all the sand all the entries are
numbered you get to sample those then
when you find an entry that you deserves
your vote you put your little toke
in the corresponding jar and you say
that is the one I vote for there were
over 35 entries that were approximately
40 I don't remember exactly how many the
day of recording I don't have that info
available the dude and Scottie haven't
posted that I'm sure they will post all
of those details very soon however a lot
of people got to smoke approximately 50
entries of cannabis I did not get the
sample anything I had a booth I was at
my booth all evening I got to smoke the
concentrates I brought plenty of friends
brought me plenty of great samples to
enjoy and smoke big shout out to all my
friends that brought me stuff to smoke
let me stay on track here the dude grows
cup the dude crows cup was a cool kind
of smoke off girl off sort of event
thing the event is aimed more to be a
community get together sort of a vibe
there are a lot of people a lot of
members in the dude gross crew they want
to meet up we all talk on line we're all
in the Facebook groups we're all in the
social media group they're all on
Instagram talking it's a good time to
get together once a year and actually
put some faces to all of those funny
Instagram names and see who's posting
those memes and see who's growing the
dank so it's a good time to get together
it's kind of like a family reunion so
that's what the dude grows show is it is
a celebration of the podcast that it's
basically highlighted by a little grow
competition a friendly little grow
competition so let's talk about the day
the day was great to drive up there was
a little hectic I had to travel i-25
anybody that knows about i-25 knows how
unpredictable that can be it was a great
drive until approximately Monument and
then suddenly snowstorm from hell
it was white just white you couldn't see
the car in front of you the windshield
was caked in [ __ ] it sucked for a few
minutes then we got to Castle Rock after
Castle Rock it was sunshiny again it was
like we're on two different planets for
that drive it was kind of strange but we
made it we got there we got to the dude
gross show it was an easy time to load
in everybody that it was super kind
super friendly super polite they helped
us load in we got set up super quickly
then I spent a few friends I mean I met
a lot of friends there a few of my
friends were kind enough to enter some
IRA genetics strains into the dude gross
Cup so I got to see and sample a few of
those entries our friend Bruce brought
me his entry he let me see the scarlet
begonias that he entered Kelvin came up
and he let me see the Donatello that he
entered it was really great to see the
work that people are doing with the
seeds that I am providing them great job
to everybody who grew
my genetics Kelvin he did a great job
dude Kelvin brought some strawberry
starbursts
to my house and shared it with me it
wasn't quite dried and cured enough to
be an entry for that Cup but it was
amazing product it smelled like tangi
plus oranges plus strawberries plus funk
it was really great
Kelvin actually had some of that flour
pressed I into our in a rosin press by
our friend Pedro's grow if you know
about Pedro if you don't know about
Pedro make sure you follow Pedro's grow
room on YouTube give him a follow
he pressed some amazing rosin out of
that strawberry starburst let me say
this here on the show a lot of times I
talk a lot of [ __ ] about rosin I am NOT
a fan of rosin most of the time it
tastes like burnt popcorn I cannot stand
the flavor of a popsicle stick or when
the doctor uses a wooden tongue
depressor it drill it drives my body
crazy something about the feeling of
that wood on my tongue it's making me
like shake and act weird right now just
thinking about it it gives me the chills
I do not like it
something about rosin has that flavor it
tastes like a popsicle stick or burnt
popcorn to me most of the time when
you're just taking raw flour and
pressing it it usually doesn't taste
desirable in my opinion to my taste but
that's just me I'm not a hater on you
and your rosin but what I'm getting to
is this strawberry starburst rosin that
Kelvin grew and Pedro pressed was
delicious I would go back for another
dab of that one right now so I owe a big
shout-out to first of all to Kelvin for
growing that strawberry starburst
like a champion that [ __ ] was it was
perfect he grew that sample that he gave
me to perfection and also I want to
extend a huge shout out to Pedro for the
marvelous job at squishing that product
most of the time like I said I'm not
impressed with the squish and that was
delicious even German from 5-8 was
loving it ah hey Kelvin I apologized
that Jaron and myself pretty much smoked
all of your strawberry starburst
concentrate while you watch but that
[ __ ] was delicious dude thanks for
sharing and dude you got a lot of great
dabs I hope you had as much fun as we
did
so let's talk more about this dude grows
Cup I got to see so many of my friends I
got to meet so many people that I've
never seen before that I've talked to
online a lot so many people were
extremely extremely generous I was given
many wonderful gifts I've got a lot of
seeds I've
a lot of delicious flour I've got a lot
of amazing concentrate one of my
favorite gifts and I hate to highlight
anything because it makes somebody else
feel lesser but somebody gave me a
street sign and it is I read genetics
Boulevard or I read genetics Avenue I
don't have the sign here but it looks
just like the street signs on the corner
you got the stop sign then right above
it it says the street I've got one of
those official street signs that says I
read genetics so now you were on my
block when you come onto my street you
were officially on
I read genetics Boulevard or I read
genetics Street I thought that was a
super cool gift I was really excited to
see that a big thank you if you're
listening to the show that was my
favorite gift of the weekend
super awesome I really enjoyed that I
get to meet a lot of great people I keep
mentioning that I got to meet stabby
stab person in person finally if anybody
knows anything about stabby stabby and I
have been friends online for quite a
while I go on the embracing organic show
and hang out with those guys
stabby doesn't show his face stab you is
one of those guys that would rather
remain anonymous he doesn't live in the
most friendly cannabis friendly
environment so he needs to keep his face
off of the internet he can't be out
there like I am and show his face and be
a blabbermouth
so he stays in the shadows it was an
honor to finally meet my friend stabby
mixed a Burson what's up dude I hope
you're listening to this it was great to
meet you brother it was also great to
hang out with the rest of the embracing
organics crew I had a great time with
those guys they kind of hang out hung
out at my booth for a few minutes it was
a really good time to see everybody I
took a really hilarious picture with
dirt man Dan if you're following dirt
man dan on instagram go check out the
photo that I took with Dan I think it is
hilarious everybody calls Dan a hobbit
or a troll because he's about 5 foot 2 I
am 6 foot 5 I know I don't talk about
that on the show people often make
comments when they see me there first
thing they say is holy [ __ ] you're tall
the second thing they say is your dreads
are crazy
yes I'm tall and I've got dreadlocks to
my knees dirt man dan is a gnome he's
basically a garden gnome when he stands
next to me so when he put the six foot
five Rasta Jeff next to the 4 foot two
garden gnome it was really a hilarious
picture so that was a good time taking a
photo with dirt man Dan it was a
wonderful time seeing jinx proof and
dung beetle what's up guys I see you at
every event it was great to hang out get
a chat with you big shout out to miss
Rosa I wish she would have been at the
event
so it always is a pleasure to see that
crew I hung out with a lot of great
people and I could run through a really
long list of name dropping and shout
outs of all these fun great people but I
got to hang out with and spend some time
with but I don't want to miss anybody it
feels worse when you leave somebody out
so I don't want to miss anybody so just
a big shout out to everybody who showed
support and showed love at the dude bros
cup and if you were too shy or too
intimidated to come say what's up cuz
that everybody always emails me the next
day they're like hey I saw you I was too
intimidated to come say hi you looked
busy bro that's what I'm there for
I want you to come say hi come shake my
hand you were too shy this time I'm just
a normal person I got stoned as [ __ ] I
had a good time just like you did come
say what's up come shake my hand but I
want to give you huge shout out to
everybody who showed me love who showed
me appreciation who has shown the growth
from your heart pod cast some love who
has shown just me personally some love
and of course everybody who supports my
other company I read genetics I really
appreciate all of the support from the
entire cannabis community you guys have
really embraced me lately and has really
made my life amazing so thank you I
appreciate that
then I want to extend an extra special
shout out to everybody who was in my
corner so to speak the IRA genetics
booth was kind of tucked over into the
corner it ended up being kind of where
the cool kids hung out you guys we were
all just hanging out taking dad's jesse
grows was over there stabbed emic
stabbed person was hanging out over
there Shawn was over there the beautiful
miss amy was over there it was a good
time just having kind of a I read
genetics girl from your heart sort of
sub click over there just having our own
little it wasn't a private party but we
had our own little crew over there and
everybody was welcome to come hang out
and a lot of people did trust me a lot
of people came and went but it was cool
having everybody just hanging out in the
corner jesse and shawn hung out in the
corner for quite a while stabbed he
mixed a Burson hung out for quite a
while
Kelvin and Quique held it down for quite
a while they had some nice little space
over by my booth so it's really cool
just to have the Irie army and the girl
from your heart crew just showing love
and showing support and nobody would let
me get anywhere near white-eyed if my
eyes started to get white if I looked
like I didn't have cottonmouth properly
somebody passed me a joint somebody lit
me up a dab it was a great time I had a
bunch of fun and if you can't tell by my
voice I smoked a ton of product
yesterday and I want to give a shout out
to everybody the product is improving
your guys's flowers are getting better
the concentrates are getting better when
I used to go to events people would pull
out their concentrates and they'd be
like hey dude look what I brought would
you like to take a DAB
this and I would be backpedaling trying
to figure out how am I gonna tell this
guy I don't want to dab his concentrate
because that looks like [ __ ] motor
oil or some kind of poop soup is well we
used to call it and I really don't want
to either put that in my banger cuz
that's gonna ruin my nail and make my
nail taste like [ __ ] for the rest of the
event also I don't want a dab bat it's
gonna burn my throat and it's gonna make
my lungs taste like [ __ ] and also the
high from that is just gonna give me a
headache so back in the day I would be
trying to figure out how to politely
tell my friends hey I don't really want
to smoke your concentrate and I found
out that the best way to do it is to
just gonna be like oh man that looks
delicious have you tried this and then I
pull out my concentrates and I give them
a dab of that and I take a dab and they
kind of forget that they offered me a
DAB and then that's usually my way to
shake that off however I did not have to
do that at this event every dab that was
offered to me was acceptable and I
smoked it also every flower that was
offered to me I smoked it and I enjoyed
it I did not smoke any blunts if you had
something rolled in a blunt wrap or a
blunt I did decline on that my voice and
my throat took enough of a beating at
that show I did not really need to add
the tobacco blunt wrap to that and I do
not enjoy a blunt wrap at all honestly I
feel like we put a lot of time and a lot
of work and a lot of energy into growing
the finest cannabis we can grow we do a
lot of selections we select for flavor
for aroma for production trichomes and
then we wrap it up and basically what
tastes to me kind of like a toilet paper
tube you're just wrapping it up in a
cardboard tube with that blunt wrap and
I do not approve I'm not hating on you
if that's what you're doing do it if
that's your thing but I'm just not gonna
hit it when you try to pass it to me but
I was quite impressed with most of the
product that I saw at the dude gross Cup
this year I saw some product from out of
state it was quite impressive also there
are people in illegal states that are
really killing it with their grows and I
feel like here in Colorado we're kind of
cheating I can drive to the gross store
I can tell the guy hey I want this and
this and he puts it on the counter and I
pay cash for and I put it in my car and
I drove home or I Drive home and then I
use that on my cannabis plants that I
can talk about having there are six
plants legally it's not a big deal
everybody's got [ __ ] six plants there
are people in Ohio there are people in
Kentucky there are people all there are
people in every single state that showed
up at the dude grows cup with quality
product and they make us look like we're
cheating
yeah you
go to the girls store and get all the
[ __ ] real easily here that guy in Ohio
he's got a drive to his friend's house
and parked his car in the garage then
they pulled a friend's car out of the
garage they drive to the gross store in
that car
they discreetly do their shopping they
don't talk to anybody in there somebody
approaches you in the grocery you leave
in those sort of states you don't want
to get noticed recognized you don't want
to be there you go in you get what you
need you put it on the counter you pay
cash get out you drive that car around
the block a bunch of times then you
drive around other blocks a bunch of
times just to throw off your trail yes
you need to be extra paranoid in a non
friendly state so they drive around they
go back to the friends house parked the
car in the garage transfer the newly
purchased girl equipment from friend's
car to your car then you drive your car
around the block a few times drive the
really long way home drive around your
block a couple of times to make sure
there are no strange cars in the
driveway or no strange cars on the block
pull into the garage unload your [ __ ]
really discreetly in the night build
your grow room when nobody can hear it
nobody can see it it's a really
different thing when you're in a non
friendly state you guys in your friendly
states in Colorado in California
Washington Oregon anywhere you've got
grow friendly laws we are basically
cheating when it comes to entering aggro
competition we're a step ahead we're
it's so much easier we're getting we're
handicapping everybody else because we
can do it we don't have to hide it
having to do it under under stealth mode
is a whole extra challenge that we don't
have to think about so keep that in mind
you guys don't take it for granted if
you are in a legal state all right I
feel like I mentioned a bunch of names
had done a bunch of name dropping and
given a bunch of thanks and a bunch of
shoutouts but I haven't gotten to the
people that deserve the largest
shoutouts of the evening and of course
that would be my friend the dude the
dude thanks for a great party and of
course that includes Scottie Riehl
thanks for a great party dude thanks for
the invite and thanks again for having
me on
the dude grows podcast being on the dude
bros podcast really exposed me to a
larger audience I've gotten a lot of
reactions via my email channel via my
social media and through my emails a lot
of people really noticed me there so I
owe those guys a big THANK YOU thanks
for having me on the show thanks for a
great party also a big shout-out to guru
dude I saw you busting ass all night you
were staying busy you didn't get to
party you were working so I do
appreciate that everybody else has
happened fun
guru was running in circles making sure
everything was working smoothly so was
Scottie in the dude but toward the end
of the night they got the chill out have
a good time it was fun watching
everybody just run around in circles and
get it going so I'm proud of those guys
big things for the invite big thanks for
the great party big things for the
dedication and for the what you're doing
for the community those guys do a lot
for the cannabis community a lot for
growers a lot for smokers and a lot for
the movement and i truly appreciate it
so a big shout out to those folks
also a big shout out to jr. token junior
token kind of works behind the scenes
with the DGC crew he does a lot of work
we have communicated a lot and I
appreciate that dude so I own a big
shout out you guys I can't wait for the
dude grows Cup next year it is almost
time almost time to start looking for a
larger venue the place was just
perfectly full I think it sells out at
350 I think there were 349 people there
I didn't count I'm just saying it was
perfectly full it was beautifully setup
I really enjoyed the event this year
every year it gets a little bit better
this year in my opinion it was damn near
perfect there aren't many things I would
change I had a really great time so I
look forward to seeing you next year if
you did not make it to the dude gross
Cup this year do what you can to make it
next year because it is a party it is a
good time it's a great community event
there were lots of great growers smokers
and community members there at one point
hanging out at my booth it was myself
aquaponics Steve Jenks proof and Scottie
reel so it was kind of a podcasting VIP
sort of cannabis community sort of
hangout right there at my booth so come
eat all the cool cannabis people oh and
gern was hanging out quite a bit that's
a funny story
during the award ceremony Jaron from 5-8
new millennium nutrients decided to stop
by my booth and hang out and he was
taking a dab of kelvins strawberry
starburst rosin it was pressed by Pedro
it was hard for me to say strawberry
starburst rosin my brain didn't want to
go down that path he was actually taking
a dab of it when it was announced that
he won an award for his girl I think he
took third place for his entry it was
funny that he was taking a dad right at
time I was like hey you got something to
do bro you're gonna have to set that
down it's just really funny really
casual but if you're into the cannabis
industry if you were into the people who
were on podcasts if you're into all of
that stuff I think you would have a
great time at the dude grows show and if
we got to hang out this year and if I
didn't give you a shout out if your name
didn't
mentioned don't take you personally I
don't want to leave anybody out I know I
mentioned a lot of people there are
hundreds more people I could mention big
shout out to everybody who hung out over
in the I read genetics corner big shout
out to everybody who gave me some
support I hope that covers everybody big
shout to everybody that hears this how's
that
I got big love for the whole cannabis
community so big thanks to everybody the
number one question that I was asked
well the number two and three question I
guess number one is how tall are you and
number two is how long are your dreads
which is really weird it's a cannabis
event come on let's ask about weed stuff
the number three question that I got
asked at this event was do you have any
feminized seeds
unfortunately my answer was repeatedly
no I do not have any FEM see the regular
season at this event
however in approximately 70 ish days
those are breeder terms approximately 70
days
I should have feminized seeds available
they will be available through Oregon
elite seeds so if you're looking for IRA
genetics feminized seeds they will be
back I will have lemon Jeffery available
I will have the golden go feminized
available we will be dropping the first
batch of the orange gasm to hit the
public through Oregon elite seeds those
are approximately two weeks into flower
now they need quite a bit more time to
get going but check back and about 60
maybe 70 days and we will have some
feminized seeds available I also was
approached by another distributor so in
a very soon to come episode I am excited
to announce that I should have been
picked up by another very large
distributor most of you have already
caught on to who I'm talking about if
you're a seed buyer and a seed shopper I
am excited to make that announcement
here honey
very soon to come episode of The Grove
from your heart podcast ladies and
gentlemen my voice is burning out I
think that is all I've got for you for
this episode I would like your feedback
on something a few episodes back I asked
what does 4/20 mean to you 4/20 is
quickly approaching I want to know what
4/20 means to you the first time I asked
it somebody sent me a message they said
do you mean 4/20 the time for 20 the day
or 4/20 the number I want to know what
it means to you does it mean the time
does it mean the number does it mean the
day what does it mean to you what is
4/20 mean to you send me an email my
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com or you can shoot me a
message on twitter it's @ g f YH podcast
on
and I would love to hear what 4/20 means
to you
all right podcast well that is all I've
got for you if you feel like this
episode was educational informative or
entertaining and you would like to make
a financial contribution to the show you
can do so by going to patreon.com slash
grow from your heart and all the
information you need to become a patron
will be right there on the screen once
again I do appreciate all of the support
I would also also appreciate it I was
harder to say than it should have been I
would appreciate it if you finally on
the social media on Facebook simply
search for the girl from your heart
podcast on Twitter once again it is @gf
wih podcast if you'd like to follow my
personal Twitter account
it's at Rasta Jeff 420 give me a follow
of course don't forget the Instagram at
irete underscore genetics I would also
appreciate it if you find me on YouTube
simply search for the drove from your
heart podcast on the YouTube channel
give us a subscribe leave some comments
on the videos I do love and appreciate
all of that interaction if you've got
something you'd like to say and you're
not into all that silly social media
nonsense you can send me an email again
my email address is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com I would love to hear from
you I respond and read and answer all of
those personally it's just me so be
patient and I will get to your email
again don't forget to visit our sponsor
organ elite seeds for all of your
regular and feminized seeds needs I'm
gonna give a huge shot it's my friend
stabby mixed a Burson and until next
time take a phat dab and give your mom a
hug for me