welcome to the show podcast world it's
time for episode 413 of the Grove from
your heart podcast this episode of the
show is brought to you by my friends at
Oregon elite seeds if you need new seeds
in your garden I highly recommend Oregon
elite seeds and you can find them at
www.imtcva.org
that will be available on 4/20 at Oregon
elite seeds dot-com it has become a
tradition that we start the podcast off
by talking about what I am smoking today
I've been taking dad's of Tropicana
cookies Fambrough Jie from our friends
at apothecary farms I picked this up at
the ambrosia days I was really lucky to
score a four gram jar of this amazing
concentrate the label says it contains
72.4% THC and a total of 85 percent
total cannabinoids this concentrate
tastes delicious I took a big chunky dad
it made me kind of sit back in the chair
for a couple of minutes but once that
initial punch to the face wore off this
got me in a really good mood
ladies and gentlemen in this episode I
am going to read a couple of listener
emails but before we get there I owe a
couple of people some shoutouts how
about a big shout out to my friend Tyler
Radke how about a big shout out to john
milk
another big shout out to joseph gotta a
big shout out to keith Klump
how about a big shot it's my friend
artem zernoff and of course a shout out
to our friend Sam I really do appreciate
all the patreon support and if you would
like to learn how to become a patron and
get a patreon shout out at the start of
the show all you need to do is go to
patreon.com/scishow bye said that in
this episode I was going to read some
listen or emails let's get right to it
this first email goes just like this it
says hey Jeff I wanted to start off by
saying that your podcasts are the best
hands down hey I appreciate that great
compliment thank you I do appreciate
hearing that people think I am the best
I'm not in it for competition but it
always feels good knowing that you're
winning then he says I've learned so
much hey I appreciate that I'm glad that
you're learning the message that goes on
to say so I have a question I am
starting my second grow using roots or
soil and canna viga organic supplements
which works great on my first grow hey
congrats on the first grow I'm glad that
worked out for you he continues to say I
am growing in a 4 foot by 3 foot by 6
foot tent with 2h LG v to 288 LED lights
alright so I got a good visual of your
setup that is a great way to diagnose a
problem or help me figure out what
you've got going on
give me a good description of your setup
I've got a good visual of what's
happening in this grow the message says
so I am growing to pineapple Express by
fast buds and one pink cush CBD by
seedsman
all are Auto flowers I was told by a few
people that it's not safe with my other
plants since this is a 30 to 1 CBD plant
and can affect my two pineapples I'm not
sure how but has me concerned with their
background I'm not sure how that would
make a difference since they are all
auto females but I've heard hemp plants
being an issue with pollinating non CBD
plants the plants just started veg
should I separate them then he says
thanks Russ to Jeff you are a beast take
a fat dab and hug your mom then they
sign their name from BAFTA shout out to
Bassett thanks for the great message
let's talk about this for a second
you've got a really great setup it
sounds like and you've got some quality
genetics you've got to pineapple Express
in there from fast buds those are
quality seeds you've got one pink cush
CBD from seeds man who is also another
reputable breeder those are all auto
flowers so far everything should work
well but you were told by people that is
not safe to have your CBD plants with
you're not CBD plants and then you said
you're not sure that it makes a
difference because they are all females
they are all females so you have no
chance of pollination you have heard
that hemp plants being an issue with
pollinating non CBD plants that would be
possible if you had a male but you don't
have any males you need a male to create
pollen or you need to do some reversing
or some stressing to cause a
hermaphrodite but you don't have a male
hopefully you've got three solid females
so there will be no problem there is no
way that your CBD plants are going to
affect your non CBD plants that is not a
thing that's nothing to worry about in
your indoor environment now if you were
in
outdoor environment those plants would
be able to receive pollen from cannabis
or hemp if there were a male hemp plant
or a male cannabis plant somewhere in
the vicinity and some wind picked up
some pollen or a bird picked up some
pollen or an insect one of our
pollinator friends grab some pollen
traveled from that male plant over to
your female Auto flower plants yes they
could be pollinated that way but again
we need a male we need a pollinator
plant to add pollen to your females you
said you've got three females unless you
introduce some pollen you will be just
fine there should be no issues so I
completely understand what you're asking
and I hope I have answered your question
thoroughly in short you've got three
girls where's the pollen going to come
from that is going to pollinate these
plants you either need a male you need
to reverse a female or you need one of
those females to hermaphrodite due to
stress or poor breeding which is always
an option but that's not we're talking
about now
now we're talking about you've got three
females so you are not going to have any
pollen now let me elaborate a little on
this subject because something that I
see happening in the near future is a
very realistic concern many people in
many places are growing large-scale
outdoor hemp projects in those same
areas people are growing large-scale
outdoor cannabis projects now the
Department of Ag and horticultural
experts and other people will argue this
statement but currently what we are
deciding what differentiates your
cannabis from your hemp is basically a
lab test at this point if you are
finished dried and cured product the
product that is tested by the lab if
that product contains 0.3 percent THC
you have got a cannabis plant if that
product contains less than 0.3 percent
THC you have got a hemp plant but in all
reality there is nothing stopping a
cannabis plant from receiving hemp
pollen there is nothing stopping a hemp
plant from receiving cannabis pollen we
have got a lot of new farmers that are
jumping on the hemp and CBD bandwagon
they're buying big chunks of land which
may be right next to our medical and
recreational cannabis farms and there's
setting up their hemp farm in that same
area many of these people are growing
from seed there are a lot of new seed
breeders and vendors in the hemp game
I'm sure many of those seeds are
problematic I'm sure that a lot of
people are selling feminized seeds that
are not done properly I think it is a
safe guess to predict that in the very
near future some of these outdoor hemp
fields are going to get out of control
they're going to miss a mail and we are
going to pollinate some of our outdoor
medical and recreational cannabis crops
with rogue pollen from hemp that came
from another farm from an irresponsible
farmer I see it happening I know it will
happen in the future I can see it
there's nothing stopping it there are
things that we can do agriculturally we
can set up barriers kind of nature wise
but it's not going to stop every piece
of pollen we can't stop a pollinator
insect or a pollinator bird we can't
stop all of the wind it is going to
happen so I bet that in the very near
future we are going to see outdoor
cannabis and hemp crops that are kind of
not destroyed but partially ruined
because they were pollinated by
irresponsible farmers that did not
identify and cull the males in their
outdoor hemp or a cannabis garden this
could happen in a hemp or a cannabis
garden I'm kind of assuming it's going
to be more common in a hemp field
because those are that's a little bit
more new of an industry to a lot of
people but this is going to be a thing
in the very near future however let's
get back on track mr. basta I do not
believe that this is an issue you need
to worry about in your indoor grill you
don't have a male plant so nothing is
going to get pollinated Bastyr wraps up
this message by saying thanks Rasta Jeff
you are a beast hey I appreciate that
I like supporting the community I'm glad
that you find me to be a beast and then
he says take a phat dab and hug your mom
I just took a gigantic dab and I promise
you I'll give mama a hug the next time I
see her hey pastor thank you for the
great message I look forward to hearing
from you in the future
all right I've got another email in
front of me this one is good it goes
like this first and foremost thank you
for doing the podcast it is excellent
hey you're very welcome thank you for
the great compliment they said you make
the world a little better man much
appreciate it hey I appreciate those
kind of compliments that means a lot to
me the email goes on it says
my question is about how to rejuvenate a
flowered plant I have an amazing
Jamaican blueberry that I do not have
clones of and I would love to save
Jamaican blueberry that sounds delicious
I would have definitely taken a clone of
that one the message goes on it says I
always take clones off of my cultivars
before they flower but something weird
happened with this one it all of a
sudden started flowering in the veg room
at first I thought I had received some
Otto flower seeds by mistake seeing that
other plants from the same seeds in
different parts of the bedroom were not
flowering I investigated further
I found a nearby plant of a different
cultivar supposedly feminized and
hermaphrodite it and developed just one
small set of pollen sacks it is my
understanding that if pollen sacks show
up in a veg room
they can cause female plants in the
bedroom to start to flower I believe
that is what happened to me I would
strongly disagree I do not think I do
not believe I do not understand why I do
not think that a hermaphrodite in plant
in that room would encourage the other
plants to flower that is not a thing I
do not believe that pollen sacks from
your hermaphroditic feminized plant are
what caused your other female plants in
that bedroom to begin to flower I would
strongly disagree with that from your
message what I strongly believe has
happened is you do not have enough light
in your bedroom you've either got too
little light not enough intensity or
you've got the wrong spectrum or perhaps
it the light is too far from the canopy
or even you've got the plants to squish
together and they are just frustrated I
would guess that that one feminized
cultivar that you found be
hermaphroditic flowers on I'm going to
guess it is in the corner it is farthest
from the light and that hermaphrodite
flower is somewhere near the bottom or
it is not getting enough light the main
thing that decides when a plant flowers
is genetics you said you believe you do
not have OTO flowers and we are seeing
that some plants in your room are
flowering and some are not so that leads
me to believe you don't have OTO flowers
the next contributing factor that
decides when your plants flower is light
light interval light intensity light
duration is it all dialed in you're
telling me that these plants are
starting to flower while they are in veg
it leads me to believe that you don't
have enough light
in there and those select phenotypes
that are flowering just having a little
bit different light sensitivity than the
phenotypes which have not chosen to
flower on you so my first question is
going to be what kind of light are you
using how intense is that light how
close to the canopy is that light
fixture then I want to know what is your
light schedule how many hours per day
are you running that light how are the
plants reacting to it they're obviously
trying to flower so I don't think
they're getting enough light also you
have got two Jamaican
blueberry plants in here think about
where those plants came from they came
from Jamaica think about the environment
in Jamaica think about the photo period
in Jamaica
these plants want bright intense long
daylight so these plants probably expect
really bright long hot days and they're
probably not getting that in your grow
environment the message goes on it says
to Jamaican blueberry plants have
started to flower I immediately took
clones off of both I was able to get
clones to root no problem on one of them
but none of the clones of the other have
survived now as they are nearing
completion as fate would have it the one
I could not get clones to root looks
unbelievable which leads me back to my
original question can you help me
rejuvenate this plant after flower is
there a podcast number that discusses
this topic or is there any other advice
that you can give thank you in advance
signed TJ hey TJ I don't remember if I
have done a rejuvenation episode so I'm
going to press pause I'm going to search
for that right quick and then when I get
back I'll let you know what number it
was if I've done it and if not we're
going to talk about rejuvenating and
Reve edging your Jamaican blueberry
plants alright I gave it a quick check
and I have done a region or an entire
episode on rivetting or cannabis plants
it is episode number 152 I'm sure I go
into great detail in that episode so if
you want to learn more about reef edging
your flowered cannabis plants I highly
recommend revisiting episode 152 but we
are here now and you were asking the
question today so let's talk really
briefly a quick lesson on Reve edging
flowered cannabis plants this may sound
crazy but successful reef edging simple
successful revenge
starts late in Flour when you start
flushing approximately two weeks before
harvest I suggest you turn the lights
back to 24 hours on and zero hours off
what everyone's head just blew up we're
in the end of flour we were trying to
flush our plants and you're telling this
person to put his lights on 24 hours on
at zero hours off yes we are so late in
the flowering cycle that we are not
going to disrupt the flowering we're
about to cut them down so as soon as we
see any problems we're gonna chop the
plants don't even worry about it we want
to reverse the hormones in this plant
this plant is full on an old-lady mode
it is at the end of its life cycle we
need to convince this plant that it
wants to go from old lady
back to a young girl so that we can
start fresh with her the only way we can
do that is to make this plant think it
is a different season we need to make
this plant think that it is spring and
it is time to start over so we want to
put the light cycle in a spring type
condition we don't want this plant to
sleep at all that is when the flowering
is induced is during those dark cycles
so we want to leave it on as much as
possible 24 hours of the most intense
light you can give it you can put it
under a thousand watt light that is
where you want it 24 hours a day of a
thousand watt light for our revenge
process so start that 14 days before you
intend to harvest your plant you can
flush this plant just like you're
flushing the rest of the plants continue
to flush do everything just like you
would except we want the lights on for
24 hours on and zero hours off now in
harvest comes harvest almost like you
would any other harvest except we want
to leave the bottom two or four or maybe
six little tiny popcorn buds on this
plant just some bottoms we don't need
much here to revenge the less is better
when it comes to trying to revenge a
plant so you've got it on 24 hours for
two weeks before harvest harvest time
comes we chop down the majority of the
plant we leave for little tiny buds on
the bottom maybe six maybe eight just
just a bunch of little buds on the
bottom we don't need a lot to work with
so you've got these little buds on the
bottom just leave those on that 24 hour
light cycle feed them a heavy veg mix we
need a lot of nitrogen we need minimal
amounts of phosphorus and potassium I
would recommend high doses of kelp and
of course a lot of micro
the soil that root ball has been around
for quite some time it's probably root
bound if you can put it into a larger
pot without causing damage that may be
advantageous also so get it in a bigger
pot if you can feed it some strong
VegNews with a lot of nitrogen again I
recommend a kelp product something like
liquid karma or something in that vein
would work wonderfully for you keep it
on a 24 hour light cycle until you see
those buds start producing normal
looking leaves for several weeks that
plant is going to kick out weird weird
looking leaves they're going to be
twisted they're gonna be spun around
they're gonna look like a cloth they're
not going to be the right shape that is
to be expected for several several weeks
depending on your cultivar depending on
the plant you're working with reeve
edging this plant could take you six
maybe eight weeks from the time you cut
the rest of it off so keep watching
those leaves eventually it will grow out
of that little bud you've got a little
bud right now that bud is going to
develop new leaves it'll start stacking
up and getting taller new growth will
come out of it eventually that new
growth will start to look like a normal
plant it will look like what we expect
and what we're hoping for and what were
what we are familiar with so once you've
got that nice healthy familiar growth
happening then I suggest you take a
clone from that if you've got several
healthy tops on that plant and you are
not a really good cloner maybe only take
one or two clones and leave one or two
behind in case you don't have good luck
with your clones so once you've got that
good growth coming out of the plant it
is time to clone it take one or two
clones those become the mother plant you
don't want to run those in my opinion I
would grow that out and I would take
five or six clones off of that and that
would be the next crop that I run so
let's recap real quickly my Reeve edging
process it starts approximately two
weeks before harvest put your lights on
a 24 hour on and zero hours off light
cycle then at harvest time chop it down
but leave a few bottom buds somewhere
between two and eight bottom buds I
don't know how big of a plant you've got
I don't know what you're working with
leave some stuff on the bottom that's
the important part
leave that part in veg leave it on a 24
hour light cycle with as much light as
you can give it continue to feed it
heavy veg feed you want a lot of
nitrogen and again a kelp product leave
it on that veg cycle until you see it
starting to produce normal-looking
leaves let it grow a little longer once
it's got those normal leaves the longer
the better
but then clone that good-looking growth
and that clone becomes your new mother
plant use that to take clones from and
grow those clones and you should not see
any loss in quality or vigor
there will be no what is known as
genetic drift which we have disproven on
this podcast that is not a term that
applies in this situation in any way so
that is my quick review on how to Reve
edge our cannabis plants now don't
forget that you had problems cloning
this specific cultivar in the past so be
sure to be extra careful when you were
cloning at this time what did you do
wrong why would it not clone last time
do you remember what the issue was this
is your last chance if you can't get
clones off of it this time it is time to
let it go you're going to be wasting too
much time space and energy in this plant
if it doesn't work this time so make
this one count I have done entire
episodes on producing clones I've done
an episode on cutting clothes into rapid
rooters I've done an episode on cutting
clones and an easy clone machine if you
need help cutting clones I recommend
checking out those episodes my most
recent cutting clone episode is number
364 so I highly recommend that one
before you try cutting clones again I'm
not disrespecting your clone tech I'm
just saying maybe a little bit of advice
will help you out since you had troubles
with this specific cultivar in the past
I'd really hate to see you revenge and
take all of that time and then not even
be able to get a living clone off of it
so maybe check out that cutting clones
episode again that is number 364 all
right I hope I answered your question JT
hey I may have called you TJ at the
start of the email I apologize if I got
your name wrong I have a friend named TJ
when I saw those letters I just wanted
you to be my friend
anyway JT thank you for the great email
I hope I answered your questions if you
have any more questions I would love to
hear from you my email address is grow
from your heart at hotmail.com if
anybody out there has a grow question
needs to grow advice as cannabis
industry questions whatever you like to
ask me I would love to hear from you
girl from your heart at hotmail.com is
the best way to get in touch with me
I look forward to getting your questions
on a future episode of the podcast
ladies and gentlemen that is all I've
got for you for this episode of the
Grove from your heart podcast I wanna
thank you again for listening if you
feel that this episode was educational
informative or entertaining and you
would like to make a financial
contribution to the podcast you can do
so by visiting patreon.com slash grow
from your heart all of the information
that you need to become a patron will be
right there on the screen and just to
let you know what I do with the funds
that I receive from patreon I do things
like I pay for my website I hosted this
podcast on my website I read genetics
Colorado comm I use those funds from
patreon to pay for the website to keep
the podcast free for everybody I also
use those funds to pay for my internet
connection which also helps us get the
podcast out to everybody for free I also
use the funding for things like these
little microphone covers so that I don't
have to keep smelling my own breath and
spitting into the same microphone cover
forever also when Mike comes over he
gets a freshie cover when Davin Granny's
on the show she gets a freshie
whenever I have somebody on the show a
new person comes we get a new microphone
cover so you guys are covering things
like that also when equipment breaks a
while back we had a headphone amplifier
take a [ __ ] on us things like that are
replaced with the generosity of our
friends from patreon so that is why I'm
doing with the funding and I do
appreciate all of the past present and
future support from my patreon
contributors
thank you guys it means a lot to me also
I would appreciate it if you stock me on
social media you can find me on Facebook
simply search for the girl from your
heart a podcast you can find me on
Twitter it's at G fyh podcast if you
would like to follow my personal Twitter
account it is a trusted Jeff 420 my
Instagram is back I was crying like a
little baby for a while about my
Instagram being gone we have got it back
it is Irie underscore genetics come
check me out on instagram check out my
fine cannabis photography check out my
Instagram live videos hangout I take
some dabs and answer Gro questions I
think it is a good time if you're not
into all the social media you've got
something you'd like to say of course
you can reach me through email again
that email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com and I do enjoy all
of the listener interaction don't forget
there is a YouTube channel I would
appreciate it if you subscribe to the
YouTube channel click around give me
some comments click like that means a
lot to me
ladies and gentlemen my voice is burning
out so I'm gonna wrap it up make sure
you visit our sponsors at Oregon elite
seeds I'll be back very soon with
another episode I'm gonna give a huge
shout out to my friend reefer madness
and until next time take a phat dad and
give your mom a hug for me