hey welcome back it's time for episode
414 of the grow from your heart podcast
this show is brought to you by our
friends at Oregon elite seeds it is time
to add fresh genetics to your garden and
you can find them at
www.opm.gov/openseason 420 so don't miss
that it has become a tradition that we
start this podcast off by talking about
what I am smoking today
I've been dabbing on lemon G batter from
apothecary farms the label says this has
68 point five percent THC and seventy
nine point one percent total
cannabinoids I'm cracking it open now so
I can get a fresh smell to give you an
accurate description
at first waft as I wave the container
past my nose it is oranges lemons and
candy it is really pungent on the lemon
side the candy comes in there there's a
hint of oranges in the background then
as the container gets closer to my face
it brings out a garlic and onion and
armpit sort of a thing this may sound
crazy but it is deliciously disgusting
it is something you put in front of your
nose and you go ooh that is grow away
bring that back oh that's so gross let
me smell that again ooh I like that it's
really really delicious ly disgusting I
can't stop dabbing it I really love it
the high from this stuff is obviously
tremendous because I can't quit talking
or talking about the concentrate itself
it feels like it goes straight to my
head it feels like I kind of have maybe
like a little bit of pressure right
above my eyebrows kind of squeezing in
on my temples a little bit it's got me
kind of in the zone it's got a little
bit of tunnel vision going on to it it
is obviously great podcasting
concentrate because I cannot stop
talking ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls 4/20 is quickly approaching and I
want to know what does 4/20 mean to you
on a previous episode I asked what is
4/20 mean to you somebody replied and
they said do you mean what is 4/20 the
number mean what does the date mean what
is the timing to me and I said I want to
know what is 4/20 mean to you when I say
hey 4/20 what does that spark in your
mind I would love to know what 4/20
means to you send me
email my email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com I would love to
hear from you or you can reach out to me
on Twitter on Twitter it is at GF y th
podcast tell me what is 4/20 mean to you
and I will include that in my 4/20
celebration episode that I'm putting
together now alright ladies and
gentlemen in this episode I am going to
read a couple of listen or emails but
before we get that far let's do a few
shout outs from patreon how about a
giant shout out to my friend Richard
goals let's give a big shout out to Ryan
Schmidt Iowa giant shout out to Brett
Gorman always a big shout out to Todd
Kay of course a big shot at the Steve
earth and last but not least I want to
give a big shout out to my friend Remy
redeye big giant thanks to everybody for
all the patreon support and if you would
like to learn how to become a patron all
you need to do is go to
patreon.com/crashcourse in the future
alright ladies and gentlemen I did say
that we have a couple of emails to read
I am reaching over to the email pile to
get the first victim let's start with
this one right here on top of the stack
and this one goes just like this
greetings Rasta I initially heard you on
the dude grow show so I thought I would
check out your podcast I've been diving
deep and I'm really loving all of the
great knowledge you're putting out there
for everyone hey first off I am really
honored to have been a guest on the dude
gross show that really helped out build
my audience so big thanks to the dude
big thanks to Scotty big thanks to guru
big thanks to junior token I big thanks
to the maestro big shot to everybody in
front of the cameras and behind the
scenes at the dude grow show they treat
me like royalty
the dude grows crew treated me like
royalty at the dude gross Cup so I've
got nothing but love and respect for
everybody that is part of the DGC and
also and I'm glad that you're diving
deep into the show I like it when
somebody discovers us and they go deep
and start listening to all of the old
episodes it's a little embarrassing
honestly but it is a time capsule and
I'm proud of it so I'm glad you were
listening to the old stuff and I love
that you are finding knowledge and that
you are appreciating it so you're
already pushing all the right buttons
this is a great message it continues to
say there's some
for everyone from the newbie all the way
to the ones that think they know
everything already and that is the goal
so thank you for noticing also the
quality is top-notch which is always
welcome keep up all the great work and
knowledge hey thanks a lot for that that
is a great way to start an email there
is more it goes on to say I also had a
question that I wanted to ask a
real-deal grower not a grower that is
about passing on bad or misguided
knowledge hey I appreciate that you know
I am all about doing a little bit of
research and not trying to pass on
[ __ ] knowledge because that
frustrates the crap out of me if you
listened to the last episode we had to
correct a couple of errors or
misinformation that people were given
and that is kind of what I'm here for I
want to spread the truth I don't to
encourage everybody to be positive about
cannabis so thanks for noticing that
there's more to that he says since you
always say to shoot you any questions I
do I encourage all of the questions it
creates amazing content for listeners I
know that I'm helping somebody by
reading your message right now I am at
least helping you so that means a lot to
me if you have this question that means
there are probably 20 other people out
there that have this same question so
I'm helping you and hopefully a lot of
other people with this great listener
generated content
I am super rambley from those lemon Jie
dads let's try to keep me focused here
we go here is the question so I grow in
cocoa with an auto feed system I like it
so far I'm in a 4x4 tent under a 1,000
watt light you are cranking that light
that is pretty intense in there usually
I'd start my plants under a small t5
until they can take the 1k metal halide
dim down to 500 Watts then when they are
a couple of weeks away from flower I up
the power to 750 to give them a boost of
growth and to get them used to the
increased intensity so far that sounds
right this time when they are under the
750 one plant seems like she just
doesn't like the increased intensity at
all she droops really badly after about
10 to 12 hours should I not flower her
and just get rid of her I'd like to
flower very soon and this has been going
on for a week or longer I feel like she
might just be a weak seed and she's also
considerably smaller than all of the
other girls of the same age sorry for
the long winded email I do hope to hear
back from you from a fellow grower
signed Mitch alright let's talk about
this one a little bit there's something
that stood out to me these are from seed
you've got one runt that is not
forming up to speed I'm going to guess
that is probably you may be right that
is probably just a run it is probably
just not the most vigorous seedling ever
that does happen so you've got your runt
plant that is the main start of this
problem I think then when you ramped up
your lighting like you normally do which
is correct you shouldn't start those
small plants under that super intense
light because that will kind of roast
them that will overcharge them you don't
need that it's also I excessive and
expensive so you start them with a low
light you work your way up no when you
worked your way up you noticed that this
plant did not seem to like the increased
intensity so there are a couple of
things making that happen she's small
she didn't grow to the size of the other
plants I don't have a size comparison
because I don't have any pictures in
front of me here but I'm going to assume
that that plant is small enough to where
the light that it is receiving is far
more than it needs because it is smaller
than the rest of those plants who are
large enough to receive and
photosynthesize that much light so that
light is probably getting too much light
it is reaching it's a daily light
integral it's getting as much light as
it needs and it's saying I'm done and
it's just kind of shutting itself down
and it's taking a little break and
that's basically because you've got a
tiny plant that's getting a lot of light
and it's getting all the light that it
needs so it's just like hey I'm done
I've gotten what I need I'm gonna
basically if it were an animal it would
walk away from the food bowl and it
would go lay down somewhere and that's
what your plant is doing it's had enough
light it's gonna go take a little break
if it had one it would walk up to a
hammock smoke a joint and chill out for
a little while ooh that's weird would a
would it smoke a joint is that that's a
whole nother podcast is that cannibalism
if a cannabis plant rolls up the joint
and smokes it to relax that's
cannibalism right that's weird
anyway let's get back on track here I
told you guys that lemon G dab really
got to me
so my first suspicion is that that
seedling that grew smaller was just a
run maybe something happened to it and
it's very early stages of life that
stunted its growth but you got a run
somehow it was either a runt by genetics
or it was damaged early on it is a run
then you put it in the room with the
other plants and tried to increase the
white intensity and it was not prepared
for that so it is reacting to that it
will probably continue to grow slowly it
will never catch up with those other
plants your next question is should I
not flower this one and just get rid of
it I don't know what your garden looks
like I don't know what your space looks
like I don't know what the rest of the
plants look like I don't know
what your canopy looks like if you can
call that plant and still have a full
canopy and produce your expected harvest
your expected yield if you can meet your
medicine demands by calling that one
plant and still having the appropriate
sized harvest if you can meet your
whatever production needs that you have
set for yourself your production goals
if you can reach those by calling that
plant by all means get rid of it if that
one plant is going to make or break you
keep it maybe keep it off to the side
forever since it's already a runt
it'll just be off to the side it'll be
that plant in the corner feed it the
last of the nutrients water everything
else and give that one the crap at the
end it may not be the best plant but it
is another plant it's a little bit more
product a lot of people are making
concentrates anyway so if it's not the
prettiest the tightest buds you can
still squish it
you can still extract it you can still
do whatever you're going to do with it
if that plant is the one that is going
to put you over your numbers get rid of
it if you're in any illegal State and
that plant is not up to the performance
level of the rest of your plants get rid
of it but if you've got time and space
for that plant keep it around let it try
if you are in a tight space in a tight
position she needs to go that is where
you need to make a judgment call my
friend if your canopy is spool and the
rest of the plants look great get rid of
it if that one's not gonna reach the top
if you've got to lift it up on two or
three pots to make it taller and it's
gonna be a pain in the ass and cause you
problems and frustrate you get rid of it
try to look forward to about week four
or five and see if that plant is going
to be more frustration or if it's gonna
be more pleasure if it's gonna just piss
you off and that's the one plant in the
room that's causing all the problems
get rid of it we don't need that kind of
stuff around in the grow I don't know
your situation so it's kind of hard to
say I would probably just toss it I
don't need something that grows poorly
like that I would just get rid of it
when you're growing from seed and you've
got a little one like that you're
generally doing a Fino hunt so you
should expect some males and you should
expect some runts and some [ __ ] this
is your runty [ __ ] get rid of it you
already planned for this hopefully
that's what I would do I don't know your
situation
I am [ __ ] rambly from that lemon g
dab so I want to thank you for that
great email you gave me a lot of
opportunity for a lot of good
information so fellow grower Mitch thank
you for that I do appreciate it
let's move on to the next email in this
episode this email goes just like this
hey Geoff first
I want to thank you for all the content
you have provided me I have gone from a
hypothetical noob and growing to
actually knowing enough to keep me going
for a long time
hey that is my exact goal I'm trying to
what do they say you give a man a joint
he'll be stoned for an how are you teach
a man to grow you'll get the whole crew
stoned for the rest of your lives so
that's what I'm trying to do I'm trying
to keep the whole crews stone and now
that's your job dude now that you're
learning how to do it you've dedicated
yourself it's time to step up anyway I'm
glad that I've got you going for a long
time the message continues to say I
started listening to your podcast around
the time that grow compilations were
released I am now starting from episode
1 and I have managed to get 200 episodes
and man I love when people go back and
listen to the old episodes honestly it's
a little bit embarrassing cuz I was not
very good at podcasting now I am quite
comfortable on a mic it feels so weird
to hear the old stuff I'm sure everybody
who does recording and broadcasting says
that I digress the message says so I'm
not doing too bad you are a smart dude
and you are very easy to listen to even
with the American to UK accent barrier
hey thanks for listening to me man I'm
glad that the accent doesn't drive you
crazy
I hope it's easy to listen to some folks
with accents are hard to understand I
hope I'm doing a great job for you the
message continues with keep up the
amazing work and I will keep
recommending you to my English buddies
hey thanks for that I appreciate all of
the recommendations that really does
help to spread a podcast and help us
grow also helps us spread the positive
message of cannabis so I appreciate that
thank you now he keeps going he says I
have one request and I hope this is
something you could maybe dedicate an
episode to would you be able to do an
episode on making crumble wax I'm
investing in the kit very soon and I
want to have your knowledge as well as
the 100 YouTube videos I have watched
you were the best dude and say hi to
Mike for me Cheers
just Baz PS I will be doing this BHO in
a very safe environment so you do not
have to worry about that so first off
let's make sure that we say shout out to
white Mike hey Mike
our new friend just Baz says hello I
want to make sure I cover that for you
because he said specifically here in the
message say what's up to Mike so there
you are Mike by the way Mike
record come hang out I miss you bro hope
you're doing well no I do really
appreciate that this person started off
with a paragraph of compliments and then
they made a request that I cannot
fulfill I am NOT a BHO hash maker I am
NOT a crumble wacked maker that is not
my expertise that is not my wheelhouse
by any means I cannot safely and
effectively teach you how to make BHO
concentrates without feeling like I am
going to set you up to hurt yourself
that would be irresponsible of me to try
to teach you that I don't know what I'm
doing
first off you wouldn't come out with the
quality product if I taught you because
I don't know what I'm doing and second
you would hurt yourself you would
potentially hurt yourself and/or others
and I don't want to be responsible for
that so I just have to respectfully and
politely say dude that is not for me to
teach I don't know what I'm doing there
I have no problems admitting that I
don't know how to make pho I know how to
do with the basic ways but I do not know
how to teach you how to do it safely and
effectively without feeling like I'm
setting you up to hurt yourself and
you're my friend and I would feel like
[ __ ] if I ever hurt one of my friends or
if one of my friends caused a problem in
their life with my shitty advice so I
apologize that I cannot help you out
with your requests on making pho crumble
wax I can give you some advice my first
advice is be more careful than you think
you need to be everybody thinks that
they're good at [ __ ] everybody like you
said you do not have to worry you do
have to worry don't get overconfident
with volatile gases you can really hurt
yourself overconfidence is a big cause
of problems I'm not I don't know who you
are I don't know your science level I
don't know your level of thinking I'm
just saying don't get overconfident and
cause problems don't have a cellphone
around light switches and light bulbs
can cause problems when there's enough
butane in the air for a legal BHO
extraction facility in Colorado we must
be inspected by the fire department
there are several building inspections
and Fire Department inspections required
just to be allowed to run a hydrocarbon
extraction in a legal facility there are
reasons for that you can see on the news
about once it used to be more frequent
it used to be about every two weeks it
is slowed down now it's about every two
months you can read an article or you
catch an article online of some person
blowing their house up because they were
making BHO in their bedroom in their
basement somewhere they should not have
been so if you do decide to make pho
concentrates on your own please be extra
careful be scientific careful extra
think every step the smallest mistakes
caused the largest problems when you are
using hydrocarbons for extractions it is
also probably illegal to make
extractions where you are so I've got
several reasons why I have to politely
decline on giving you lessons on making
crumble wax or BHO also there are much
better techniques and products to focus
on making than crumble wax learn to make
diamonds and sauce if you're going to do
it if you're gonna put yourself in the
situation do it correctly and make the
diamonds and the sauce don't waste time
with the crumble wax that is so 2005 now
I am pretty sure that you are going to
go against my friendly advice and you
were going to make your own BHO
concentrates because you are an adult
and that is what you want to do and
there is no reason why I should stop you
do your thing I'm just saying I can't
help you too much but do your thing have
a great time I hope it goes very well
for you now let me try to give you a
couple of resources that may help you
out since I don't have any resources
from my experience our friends at the
dude grow show have done a great show on
making BHO extraction so you can check
out the dude grow show probably just
search for the dude grow show BHO
extraction and you will get a great
lesson from those guys then I would join
a few cannabis related forms and I would
join a bunch of groups and learn as much
as you can from those groups about
hydrocarbon extraction find people in
those groups that have experience and
ask them specific questions and learn
from people who have actually done it it
sounds like you're watching a lot of
YouTube videos and you were following a
lot of resources I hope they are able to
help you out more than I am because
again this is not my wheelhouse
hey just as I apologize for letting you
down on this one sometimes I don't have
an answer for every
but I do hope you keep listening to the
show and I do hope you keep recommending
the show to your English buddies I want
to give you one more thanks for sending
this great email and I look forward to
hearing from you again in the future
and if anybody else out there has
questions I would love to answer your
questions as well again there are some
things I can't help you with but I will
do my best
on most grow questions my email address
is grow from your heart at hotmail.com
and I would love to hear from you ladies
and gentlemen I'm going to wrap up this
quick
midweek bonus episode of the growth from
your heart podcast don't want to thank
you for listening again I want to know
what 4/20 means to you send me an email
send me a tweet let me know what is 4/20
mean to you if you feel like this
podcast was educational informative or
entertaining and you would like to make
a financial contribution to the show I
would appreciate your support and you
can do so by going to patreon.com slash
grow from your heart all of the
information you need to become a patron
will be right there on the screen again
I want to give a big thank you to
everybody who has helped out with the
patreon campaign in the past in the
present and in the future
thank you I'd also appreciate it if you
support me on all of the social media
you can find the show on Facebook simply
search for the girl from your heart a
podcast on Twitter it is at G fyh
podcast and if you'd like to follow my
personal Twitter account it is at Rasta
Jeff 420 I also invite you to follow my
Instagram feed check out ireon ders core
genetics on Instagram look at my fine
cannabis photography join me in an
Instagram live feed hangout I take dabs
and answer Gro questions maybe I can
answer your grow questions right there
in a live feed don't forget about the
YouTube channel click Subscribe leave
some comments on a video I do appreciate
that type of interaction don't forget
about organ elite seeds if you need new
seeds in your garden I highly recommend
organ elite seeds you can find them at
Oregon elite seeds com also if you need
some I read genetics beans that is your
go-to place Oregon elite seeds com4 I
read genetics beans they will have the
first drop of blue raspberry truffle on
4/20 don't miss it because they will go
very quickly that is all I've got for
you for this quick episode thanks again
for listening I want to give a huge
shout out
to Miss Amy and until next time take a
fat dad and give your mom a hug for me