[Music]
yeah what's up ladies and gentlemen it's
time for episode number 42 of the igro
culture podcast they call me Rost to
Jeff dude joining me at the table
tonight we have a brand new guest who's
never been on the show what's up Tony
how you doing um I'm good how are you I
am great bro I'm gonna turn down the
music a little bit we'll talk uh Tony is
the dude that built my website he built
the iy genetics website Tony is
responsible for getting the feed up that
hosts the igro culture podcast so dude
big huge shout out you don't get the
credit you deserve thanks a lot props
for that man gosh Excuse me while I
cough out a lung and as usual well not
usual as often I guess our good buddy
Jesse is back how you doing bro pretty
good thanks for how going podcast land
did you guys have a good Thanksgiving oh
yeah yeah oh yeah I imagine you did
Tony's got an Italian family so I could
imagine how much you guys Hae
yeah yeah no headphones for you
sometimes this thing cuts out bro I
apologize it's uh it's this headphone
jack here did it come back yeah cool
cool yeah once in a while it'll just
fart out on you just give me that same
where the [ __ ] are my headphones signal
and we'll correct it yeah I don't have
it right now either uhoh we'll keep
going you back yeah cool cool uh how was
your Thanksgiving bro I almost skipped
you it was pretty good good I uh I have
the privilege of going to four
Thanksgiving dinners nice so yeah I had
two Thanksgiving dinners incidentally uh
shout out to my at least she made a huge
Thanksgiving dinner for the whole family
that's really super cool of you I
appreciate it it was tasty I'm a
vegetarian so she was really nice and
made some things differently than she
would have she didn't put beef broth and
bacon and some [ __ ] you know so I had a
lot of options to eat also huge shout
out to Angela uh Angela doesn't uh have
any family here in Colorado so I totally
invited her to come eat dinner with my
family and I and she had a great time
nice uh she was totally cool my family
loved her so thanks for coming I really
appreciate that Angela I hope all the
listeners had a good Thanksgiving or if
you're not into that then I hope you had
a great Thursday and a good weekend some
people hate Thanksgiving uh I don't uh
I'm impartial and I go eat with the
family to be uh to be social like we
should I think it's one of the better
holidays there's uh you know it's just
oh at its core it's one of the better
holidays what about 420 bro oh yeah
that's awesome holiday that's like
Christmas for the potheads yeah all
right let see do I have any other stuff
we got to do let's get to some ads real
quick so we can get right down to
business on this episode I do plan on
doing a little lesson on uh nutrients
and stuff and I also have a good
question for my buddy Tony Tony is a uh
he's an organic chemistry student how
far are you from your degree bro um
about 5 10 credit hours okay I don't go
to college so what does that mean for
humans uh a semester a semester cool
Tony's a new father so he's distracted
from school congrats on that yeah uh
yeah dude congrats he hasn't been around
as much so I'm sure he's not at school
as much but turn down that music Turn
try to yell over it it feels way better
so we'll have Tony talk about a couple
things here in a minute before we can
get that far this podcast is brought to
you by Nature's green remedies.com visit
Natures green remedies.com for gag green
genetics llata Labs Sin City rare
dankness mile high can Adventure the
Cali Connection MTG iy genetics and many
more trusted Brands you guys will be
glad to hear this Nature's green
remedies is running a special for the
loyal podcast listeners type in coupon
code Frosty for 15% off any order and
free priority shipping at naturegreen
remedies.com uh the coupon code is good
for any brand in stock but it does
expire at the end of this month so take
advantage of the coupon code before the
31st once again the coupon code is
Frosty ironically I made up that coupon
code and I texted uh Yankee from
Nature's green remedies I said the new
code will be Frosty and he said that's
funny bro that's my dog's name awesome I
was just thinking it's winter and
everything's Frosty it's cold our butt
should be Frosty so that worked out
pretty well uh big thanks in much
respect to Nature's green remedies and
Yankee uh he's out with his kids tonight
at a slip knot concert I hope you guys
had a whole [ __ ] ton of fun yeah not my
thing but if you're into that dude I bet
that's fun as hell trying not to sneeze
into the microphone tonight I got that
peblo stuff that's going around
everyone's got a cold around here also
this podcast is brought to you by Highly
Educated titanium if you're using high
quality concentrates you deserve a high
quality titanium nail made in America
don't trust a cheap Chinese nail or an
American knockoff made of cheap Chinese
Metals trust the industry leader trust
highly educated titanium uh task is
actually up for all kinds of awards
again for uh product awards for his
stuff so you know he's killing it he's
going to win big shout out to task much
respect to what you do those new carb
caps are looking sweet I can't wait to
get my hands on a couple if you're
listening I like the ones with stars and
I like red golden green stuff but
anyway I've got the coughs from some
dabs this podcast you're gonna cough too
do it I'll turn your mic off just those
dabs were killer yeah they were kind of
bigger than what we uh should have taken
right before a show that was heavy duty
we wanted to get it done and get to the
show if you take two dabs that are
really big you just move on you don't
have to sit there and dab out all day
that's what I think uh big love to tree
Thugger decom this episode is brought to
you in part by our good friends at tree
Thugger decom live music lifestyle
magazine check out tree thug.com for
concert and Festival news and reviews
look out at the cookout with tree
Thugger dcom I'm going to save this one
for a little bit here we'll talk about
that in a minute uh big love to all the
sponsors dude we really appreciate you
guys helping us out
also a big shout out to cot dog and
Katherine of the Mystic Roots band they
let me play all of their music on the
podcast how cool is that can't go much
cooler than that I want to give a big
shout out to Spence and Maddie they came
over the other night and help me do a
chore uh I wish you guys great luck with
the secret cup that you're headed to I
hope you guys bring home a trophy and a
whole bunch of prizes and a new rig I
want to dab out of your new rig on the
podcast next week that'll be super
awesome and get the respect that you
totally deserve and are worthy of did
you hear that I didn't say that I didn't
didn't say that that was my homie Jesse
I butter him up a lot but uh Jesse just
said that you guys deserve respect I
agree also a big shout out to Laz I
don't know if you listen to the show but
I met a dude named LZ recently we
finally met in person we've been online
buddies we got to hang out cool ass dude
shout out also last shout out for a
minute Mr omnio what's up bro uh you're
finally caught up on episodes it's like
we're hanging out in his kitchen uh he
was he left a tweet that says uh I'm
listening while I'm making beef buan and
it's like they're hanging out in my
kitchen so dude we record this show
about 10t from my kitchen so that could
have been a reality almost it's kind of
you were almost there come cook for us
no come cook yeah yeah come cook for us
anybody can come cook for us I'm a
strict vegetarian uh Jesse will eat
almost anything Tony uh you cool
anything anything all right come cook
for us guys you could be the IG gr
culture Chef all right I've got a couple
topics written
down one of them this just came up I was
kind of rude to somebody the other day
uh I realized that they were
selling their plants their crop got
powdery milw
and instead of salvaging it they decided
to cut the crop down and make live resin
out of it and I would not have known
about it unless somebody else told me
that they were doing that and so uh I
called him out on it and I said you are
the difference between being a caregiver
and a cash Cropper you were the person
that's going to make somebody sick
because we shouldn't be giving tainted
medicine to people who already have a
compromised immune
system uh other people in the room
treated me like I was kind of going
overboard but I felt it was kind of my
responsibility to call this dude out and
let him know that he's really doing it
wrong and he's making us all look bad
you know he's not helping the movement
at all and that's not what I'm working
towards so I wanted to have a little bit
of backup when I approach this dude
saying this is why so that's why I
brought Tony on the show like I was
saying earlier Tony's an organic
chemistry student and he knows a lot
about this so I guess the simple
question I want to ask once again excuse
my dab throat uh if we take these
powdery mude Buds and we blast them with
butane are we gonna get powdery mildew
or what is happening can you tell me a
little about that well you're not gonna
get the powdery mildew itself but you'll
um get the mot toxins or any sort of
toxins that they create which powdery
milu is fairly toxic to uh humans um now
believe it or not you could actually
probably be better off smoking the buds
yourself not Distributing them but it
would be less toxic than blasting it and
concentrating it um that's why they call
them concentrat cuz we're concentrating
everything that's in the plant matter
into a an oil that is far far far more
concentrated than the plant matter
itself I I hadn't even thought about
that route you're making powdery mil do
dabs just like you are ash yeah you're
taking the mot toxins and concentrating
it okay sorry I got to fix the echo I
got that mic up I have a question when
you say fairly uh toxic um could you put
some kind of comparison on that well
it's definitely not like black mole old
or anything like that but um I'm sure
you guys remember the swag days oh yeah
the the cheap brick weed that stuff had
powdery me do in it very often and even
smoking small quantities of that you'd
end up with chest congestion bronchitis
usually sore throat for a week and a
half uh so you can imagine what happens
if you concentrate it 10 to 15 times of
the dosage and then you take a big fat
dab like I like to do oh yeah so you
just probably got a good percentage of
MOT toxins in your body
yeah and the trippy thing about that is
it's not going to show up immediately
immediately it's probably going to show
up in a month or two the really weird
effects uh you're probably going to go
like a little nuts from it a little bit
of psychosis in my mind uh Behavior
change yeah paranoia that's if we smoke
a lot right that's not like from one or
two dabs or some PM dabs it's consistent
small doses okay so if you're smoking it
just once a day for a week or two it's
going to do some weird stuff to you all
right you definitely don't want to do
that
makes you think guys wonder where your
dabs are coming
from and he said this is something that
caught my mind he said it's almost it
would be better if you smoke the buds
than it would be to smoke the hash and I
also like that you said smoke the damn
buds yourself don't give them out to
anybody that's what you should do if you
grew powdery mil do Buds and you have to
do something smoke it yourself that way
you know reap what you sew that way
you're not getting somebody else sick if
you're going to do it do it don't give
it to someone else to smoke all right so
mot toxins uh you said a little bit of
psychosis do you think a little bit of
headache nausea diarrhea vomiting stuff
that would be described as hidden or
mistaken as other things definitely
usually flu like or cold symptoms and
then as it gets later you'll definitely
get like typical mold poisoning uh like
seizures
and very very very very bad things will
happen to you uh kidney and liver tox
toxicity from mot toxins right oh yeah
those those wreak havoc on you and uh
powdery milk do is it's of that type of
organism it's going to produce those and
it's they don't worry about it for food
crops very often because it's only leafy
parts that get affected by it okay most
fruits like tomatoes and stuff won't
show the little patches on them so like
cucumbers or squash that always get
infected the the fruit itself's probably
safe um yeah to consume um not to blast
into hash you probably run into the same
trouble cucumber resin and I'm pretty
that you get some turps bro yeah um and
even then that's not very strong
quantities cuz you have to have a large
amount of leafy matter infected with the
uh the white patches that's the fruiting
body and then it's it's a toxin that's
systemic that goes throughout the plant
so yeah you'll end up with it in your
cucumbers or squash or whatever but not
much however we're uh we're smoking
leafy leafy flowers which accumulate
that stuff with freakishly high
concentrations of self so it's not the
same as a food uh a food issue cuz it's
it's technically considered non-toxic
for food crops even though they don't
let it ever happen but you definitely
don't want to be smoking that stuff
we've had it on like you said the leafy
parts of plants but we've never actually
like I've never actually seen it on the
uh there you go you're into the side of
the mic like some kind of gangster
rapper what was that punk rocker okay oh
yeah but uh I've always um you know
since powdery mildo kind of came around
last few five six years seems like um
I've wondered about those late season
crops that always get infected with
that yeah yeah have tended to throw a
lot of that stuff in the compost pileo
that's probably what you should do well
I don't know is that powdery mildew
going to affect his compost yeah you
don't want to actually put that in
compost either they say really yeah it's
it's not a good one to have okay mot
toxin I figured it got hot enough that
it doesn't kill the spores now okay and
you don't actually have to worry about
inhaling the spores it's the literally
the toxins that you're burning are just
going to wreak havoc on your uh the
mucus membranes at first and then it's
going to make you get a little weird
I've been I've seen some uh big
commercial rooms that I felt like the
the spores actually burn my nose in
there maybe I know who you're talking
about I think I know who you're talking
about possibly so this dude told me that
using a one micron screen would prevent
any of the uh microt toxins or spores
getting into the hash that's completely
[ __ ] cuz he's we're basically
juicing the mot toxins right through
that screen right they're in solution so
you can't uh filter them out as if they
were solid particles just like the THC
is correct correct yeah it's totally uh
same thing as salt and water unless you
actually have a filter that's not even
it's not even a filter anymore they call
it a semi-permeable membrane that's what
osmosis uses okay yeah that's that's
yeah that's not even a filter anymore
you can't filter a dissolved solid out
of a liquid I like that Tony knows a lot
of [ __ ] yeah sorry it's warm in here oh
no it got hot in here today man those
dabs got to
me everyone's a little slow I can tell
on the show all right so basically
powdery mildew is [ __ ] terrible you
guys if you've got powdery mildew on
your buds don't give that to somebody
else smoke that yourself if you're going
to do anything with it don't blast it
please don't blast it if you're a
medical marijuana provider and you are
giving powdery mildew buds to sick
people you're the devil You Are anti-
The Movement you're doing everything
wrong you're making sick people sicker
you're causing more problems and you're
helping you're the difference between a
cash Cropper and a caregiver don't be a
cash croper be a caregiver I me I'm done
with that rant I'll stop also Ryan if
you listen to the podcast I kind of went
off on you kind of hard about this the
other day I apologize I try to be a
leader of the movement and uh a lot of
people will accept that and I want to
speak out about it and make make sure
that you know how passionately wrong I
feel that it is I might have been rude I
apologize bro we're still friends we'll
still dab all right so I promised that
we would talk about nutrients you guys
all feel good about the powdery milw
topic oh yeah thanks for your expertise
Tony Tony will be good at this nutrient
part too Tony's uh I'm not going to call
him a pro level grower he's got a couple
few crops under his belt he uh he's got
that chemistry background so it really
helps him out but it also kind of kills
him all right guys we had to take a
quick break but we are back Jesse had to
dip out he uh well I wish I had a better
story for you he took a dab and turned
green so uh we had to cut out and uh get
Jesse some water and get him to the
couch right now Jesse is uh chilling on
the couch he'll be all right he may come
back to the show but I doubt it he said
go on without him so we're going to do
that um insert your make fun of Jesse
comments right here he is a professional
but sometimes dab will get you so he's
chilling um let's do him some love by
this way this podcast is brought to you
by our good friends at H High gr indoor
growing supplies high gr indoor growing
supplies has two locations to serve
Colorado visit the Denver store on 6271
Beach Street or check out the beautiful
peblo location on 618 East 4th Street in
peblo Colorado check out hyro for
competitive pricing and a great
selection of indoor grow supplies hyro
is running a special for the podcast
listeners when you check out at hyro
tell them you listen to the hro culture
podcast and they will give you
commercial pricing on your entire
purchase Tony you can do that too tell
them I listen to the AG culture podcast
and they'll give you commercial pricing
bro sweet that is pretty sweet uh I got
a $25 bag of dirt for 17 bucks the other
day
so imagine if I was buying something big
yeah also a huge shout out to Hy gr
indoor growing supplies for hooking me
up with a brand new nanolux light to
test big shout out to Nano nanox
lighting uh I can't run it till January
because my rooms are full but I really
look forward to running that light it's
one of the Dual ended light bulbs uh I'm
sure it's going to put out some lumens
it's going to make my room bright it's
going to make my plants happy Jesse was
giving him praise earlier uh he said he
set up one light with a room that had an
uneven canopy uh because a lot of times
your middle plants will grow better cuz
that's where the lighting is uh he said
they evened out within a week or two so
must be doing something right all right
I said we're going to talk about doing
uh nutrients and I was also mentioning
that uh Tony is a chemistry and organic
uh chemistry major uh he's a physics
nerd he's a computer nerd but this dude
knows a lot of stuff I think that his
knowledge of science really helps him
when he grows but I also think it almost
kills him when he grows uh yeah plants
are predictable but plants aren't
science they're nature they have limits
yeah so I see Tony he's like I fed them
potassium why aren't they potassium in
come on do it and I'm like you got to go
to bed and you got to wait like three
days and you got to come back and check
and then maybe you'll see what you did
he's like I want it now he thinks he
should mix [ __ ] up and see explosions
for the way plants work sometimes it
works sometimes it does but it's funny
watching you be baffled I know how much
you know about science and Organics and
to see you look at me like dude how come
and it's just the smallest thing that
you overlooked it's it's great seeing
you learn like that but sometimes it
does slow you down sometimes it totally
shoots you in the foot cuz you don't
believe that the plants will do what I
think they should do on their own yeah
you want everything to be the Incredible
Hulk yes on steroids on steroids raar
all right so we're gonna talk a little
bit about nutrients I was hoping Jesse
would be here because he really has a
lot of cool [ __ ] to contribute but I
will cover I will try to I'll go like
I'll put my voice really deep I'll turn
up the Lowe's on the microphone so maybe
we get no they didn't know but I'll turn
up my voice real deep and I'll do
Jesse's Parts um most of what we're
going to cover will today will be based
on bottled nutrients I think it's a lot
easier for a new hom grower to learn
with the good line of bottled NES uh
next week I'm going to have a guy named
Shawn over you know what it may be two
weeks until I have Shawn over we got to
see what happens with the secret cup no
I should sea will be here next week
maybe Spence will be here the week after
with the secret Cup victory that's what
I'm hoping for uh Sean's going to teach
us about Organics and sustainable
horiculture Shawn doesn't use to the
best of my knowledge Shawn doesn't use
any Hydro Store products uh but for
today's lesson we're going to focus on
Basics uh bottle nutrients are usually
reliable and cons and consistent our
good friend Adam who couldn't be here
tonight he specifically asked me what he
needs to be feeding his plants and he
also asked what the numbers on the front
of the bottles mean so I think the
numbers on the front of the bottle is a
good question and it's a super good spot
to start so we'll talk about that there
are three numbers if you go to the hydro
shop and you pick up almost any
fertilizer bottle there are three
numbers on the front uh the first number
represents nitrogen the second number
represents phosphorus and the third
number represents potassium uh that's
NPK uh those are known as macronutrients
so a bottle of basic grow nutrients like
if you grab botanic here Botanicare pure
blend Pro or maybe some Advanced
Nutrients Jungle Juice grow uh the
numbers on there are going to be like
325 or 216 or something like that each
brand is going to be different so if it
says two three uh 325 that's what we're
going to work with now is 325 it means
there's 3% nitrogen 2% phosphorus and 5%
potassium in that nutrient in that
bottle so the numbers on those bottles
tell us the NPK values of what the NPK
values are of the fertilizers we're
buying but it's up to us to figure out
uh which bottles to use and when to use
them and how much to use most of the
nutrient companies make a really cool
Nutrient calculator that you can get the
hydro shop a lot of times it's in a
little insert thing like a coupon right
next to the brand get those those are
always super helpful a lot of times Tony
will be like how much of this nutrient
do I use and since I'm kind of a nerd
I've happened to have a bunch of those
little inserts laying around and I'll
just pull it out and be like it says
this yeah but I definitely recommend
reducing the recommended dosage to about
half of what they say you use uh
sometimes 2/3 you can tell we'll talk
more about that that I wrote that part
down so uh most of the companies make a
a chart or also online you can go online
to botanic care.com or Advanced
nutrients.com I know they have super
great uh feeding schedule calculators uh
if you use a pre-developed recipe from
there they'll tell you exactly what to
use every week uh I suggest you reduce
the dosage like I was saying to about
half those companies they want to sell
you more they really want you to buy
more [ __ ] so they tell you to use a
little bit extra like 5 or 10
milliliters every week adds up to them
and to you but you don't notice it your
plants won't notice it so they kind of
overfeed your plants on purpose so
reduce what they say uh if you see signs
of a deficiency you can increase your
fertilizer on the next feed but you
can't uh if you over correct it if you
over feed you can't correct that uh
you've got burnt leaves and angry roots
and your plants look all [ __ ] fried
out uh I think have seen a couple of
your plants do that one time oh yeah
I've burned them yeah Tony's not afraid
to mess with some plants Tony is all
about getting in there and torturing the
[ __ ] out of his crop yeah so usually pH
Burns I was going to talk a lot about pH
Burns if we have time I'm going to try
to go about 45 to an hour here but if we
have time for pH we'll get into it uh
something I recommend and this is uh
this is part of what I think Tony shoots
himself in the foot with I recommend
that if you're going to use a brand of
bottled nutrients you stick with the
brand until you become experienced and
you can identify deficiencies and
problems uh which means a few things
first if you use Botanicare pure blend
Pro as a base I totally recommend using
whatever Botanicare pure blend Pro
additives you can afford to add but
don't mix stuff from other brands I know
that sounds ridiculous like brand
loyalty or a sales pitch but I think
it's rational with any brand and I'll
explain why I don't mix Brands because
of Antonio like this sholan buffers and
bonding agents versus Organics a lot of
products have chemicals that make the
products last longer some uh have
chemicals that prevent certain compounds
from bonding inside the bottle and
ruining the solution and many of those
chemicals will ruin all of the
beneficial compounds in an organic
solution uh Tony May correct me on this
I feel like if I poured some synthetic
nutrient like if I got almost anything
from Advanced Nutrients if I pour big
bud and do a batch of organic compost
tea I think the big bud would kill most
of the bioactivity in my compost tea is
that correct um I think big bud
especially like uh overdrive definitely
would wreak havoc okay how about my
micos is it just going to destroy my
micro life destroy your micos and um
actually it's probably going to bring
things out as solution uh like calcium
compounds and those once they're
unavailable to the plant they actually
uh create other
deficiencies it's all about balance
apparently all right you just over uh
you definitely enforced what I was
trying to say i' sound like I know what
I'm talking about now all right so
unless you uh unless you're sure the
product gets along with other products
you shouldn't be adding two things uh
from different brands because you could
cause problems you could have everything
going for the first 6 weeks and then you
go and add in some bud booster that
doesn't match up with your schedule and
it could totally just ruin all the work
you've done for the past veg time plus
six weeks of flower so another reason I
stick with one brand is because as you
learn you need something to be
consistent as many things as you can
need to be consistent it's hard to adapt
to changes and identify problems with
too many variables I feel like if we
minimize the variables we can dial in
our crops to Perfection uh if you're not
truly happy with your nutrients you can
for sure switch them but I recommend
trying the same brand while you learn I
know I keep talking about it but I
personally I like botanic hair I've used
Advanced Nutrients I felt like with
Advanced I got huge Buds and everything
finished really quickly but I also feel
like uh everything looked and smelled
and tasted the same I don't think there
was much variation if I ran OG Kush sour
diesil strawberry Haze they all kind of
had the same Advanced Nutrients they all
smelled like Nirvana oh yeah yeah and uh
Advanced uh it's actually kind of like
junk food it's the wrong kind of
nitrogen that you'd want for healthy
plants they look nice but they're not
actually as healthy as they should be
okay I didn't ever think of that like
all I could tell is that they were taken
off and for what I paid I could tell I
was getting my money's worth I was
getting that extra that they advertise
but I didn't like the flavor and when
you're growing crops for yourself I I
want the flavor I want the flavor I want
uh I grew with psycho I did a couple
rounds with psycho they actually gave me
a free box set and I ran it side by side
next to Botanicare and I have a 5x5 Hut
next to a 5x5 Hut everything is the same
it's in the same room and I did psycho
on one side Botanicare on the other the
psycho side everything turned really
really purple and it was sexy it was
really photogenic Bud once again I
didn't like the flavor oh yeah it didn't
burn as well and it had a funky flavor I
used Soul synthetics from Aurora oh
excuse me from Aurora Innovations and it
has a lot of molasses type stuff a lot
of humic stuff and that made for tasty
tasty buds but uh it didn't give me
enough Harvest and it didn't get real
resiny it tasted super good but I didn't
get the Harvest I wanted uh Humbolt
nutrients that stuff worked well but uh
there's a lot of pgrs and things I'm
trying to get away from in there uh just
like Advanced Nutrients I don't want to
use a lot of pgrs and things like that
Humbolt did well but again I preferred
Botanicare for the flavor that's what I
like the best it's all about tea yeah
now it's turn now it's getting to be all
about the teas the guy that's coming on
next week is all about making super
awesome teas so for my personal I'll
always probably go back to the
Botanicare pure blend Pro with all the
additives recommended I also use
clex uh and uh from the organic hair
lineup and I'll add some kind of
molasses and yucka extract and maybe
some dehydrated coconut water to my
feeding toward the middle of Bloom but
that's our secret so don't ever say that
on a podcast where people could hear you
it's actually good for beginner Growers
pile on the yucka it your eror tolerance
for temperatures and a bunch of things
yeah it's it's very good for you uh it's
kind of like aloe vera on a sunburn
except inside I know that sounds weird
but it definitely works to uh moisten
things up and keep things safe a good
source of yucka extract if you don't
want to just go find yua extract and
figure out how to use that uh humble
honey is actually packed with yucka
extract and it's a great product you
need something with molasses and sugars
in it anyway laate In Bloom so that's
what I would recommend uh if anybody
from banic is listening you can send me
an email and I'll get you my shipping
address and sponsorship info I genetics
on Instagram check out my feed uh yeah
Botanicare I buy a lot of your stuff
guys talk to me hello all right um
another reason I would stick to one
brand is because doubling up on nutrient
Brands uh you could actually double up
on something you don't want you could
have overlap there could be too much uh
magnesium in this one or too much uh I
don't know malum in this one and you
don't realize it because they don't list
all that small stuff on every bottle so
if you use something from Botanicare
something from Advanced Nutrients you
may possibly be overdosing your plant
with something and so Botanicare is not
going to uh Botanicare is not going to
make uh a nutrient a with nutrient B
that would overlap they would and they
kind of wouldn't they wouldn't do that
they know that that's in there sorry
guys my throat's all clogged up from
taking those dabs that killed Jesse now
I should say that uh most of the
nutrient companies make their own mro
products those you can uh go a little
outside the line absolutely as well as
uh there's a few other things like um
enzymes yes enzymes micos for enzymes I
always recommend the hydrozyme and for
micos lately all the ogt products are
freaking awesome and I also like great
white shark myself yeah I put those in
almost every plant yeah if you want to
go the advanced nutrients route and you
want to spend a lot of money that
piranha and tarantula in the liquid
bottles it's
$183.00 per bottle but like 10 or 20 MLS
will give you explosive Roots put that
[ __ ] in your cloner if you've got an
easy cloner your roots will push the lid
off the cloner your plants will get up
and walk away wow yeah so but once you
guys get comfortable and have a good
understanding of your feeding routine
you can add whatever you feel like you
need just read the bottles uh adjust
your ppms accordingly and pay attention
to what you're feeding the plants like
if you're just read the labels like read
them go to the website find out what's
in those products they should be readily
available if a company doesn't want to
tell you what's in their stuff I don't
want to use it is kind of how I feel
anyway yeah I wrote down a side note
talking about PMS a friend of mine was
having problems with this crop uh his
leaves were curling up looking like uh
goofy fingers I thought it was a light
leak during the dark cycle he thought it
was the
genetics uh everybody was real confused
sorry I just burped right into the
microphone everybody was real confused
uh but uh the room was correct he had
good genetics and after a few days we
realized a problem his magnetic ballasts
were causing interference with the PPM
and pH meter and everything was way off
so he's thinking he's balancing out the
pH perfectly you know 65 seven and he's
actually making it 11 or lower he's
probably going down it's probably like
four cuz that low is probably what made
everything curl he's getting it real low
uh so uh what I what I was going to say
is uh try to get away from your magnetic
ballasts so that when you take readings
your magnetic Ballance aren't making
everything jump up and down and also
take good care of your PPM and PH meters
people Overlook those and they're super
important Jesse recommended making the
cords as short as possible uh in your
Grow rooms yeah that would definitely
help with stuff like having your PPM
meter fluctuate so heavily uh but it'll
take a couple weeks but his plants will
be back on track he's just a couple of
weeks behind they'll look good all right
so we're talking about nutrients that
was a side note I wanted to make sure to
get out our main goal here with
nutrients is to have the correct amount
of nutrients at the right time uh to
keep the plants at Peak Performance
without ever overfeeding them and
causing nutrient burn or lockouts uh and
also I wrote down don't forget to pay
attention to your pH and also I said
when you see problems that look like
defici icies they are often from a pH
issue that was overlooked if you're
going to push your plants to perform you
need to have the proper pH I think 6.5
to 7 is ideal for most cannabis strains
you're going to have to adjust to your
room your environment and your strain uh
the Coco fiber people they have a
different range and then the regular
like deep water culture uh Hydro people
I think they want it down in the five
fives yeah that sounds about right most
of what I talk about is soil sorry guys
I'm a soil soiless kind of guy most
everything I do is soiless mix indoors
under thousand watt lights so you'll
have to adjust like I'm everything is
about adapting all right good call right
on for reminding those people or me uh
so during during the veg phase your
plants are going to want uh high levels
of nitrogen as the plants progress into
the flowering stage they're going to
require much less nitrogen and they're
going to want more phosphorus and
potassium so we're going to kind of
shift into explaining the nutrients and
their functions which is cool that
Tony's here for this one CU he knows a
lot uh you hear us talk about NPK we'll
focus on on nitrogen phosphorus and
potassium will go with nitrogen first
you'll almost always hear nitrogen first
uh most of what you breathe is nitrogen
it's an odorless colorless gas that
constitutes over 75% of the Earth's
atmosphere uh despite the overwhelming
presence of atmospheric nitrogen there
are only a few kinds of plants in the
legume family that can make use of it
marijuana is not a legume oh it should
say cannabis geez I cut and pasted this
from the internet I'll give them Credit
in a minute I just don't want to break
away from my focus here where is the web
I that I stole this from yeah I don't
want to stumble around and do too many
things I'm messing with the computer and
getting distracted uh so marijuana is
not a legume so nitrogen must be
supplemented synthetically produced
nitrogen fertilizer is made in the form
of anhydrous ammonia from natural gas
yeah that's what I said anhydr ammonia
from natural gas anhydr ammonia is then
usually converted into ammonium nitrate
for storage and ease of application once
granulated the ammonium nitrate is ready
for use as costeffective and easy to use
plant food natural sources of nitrogen
are numerous and include bloodmeal
manure bird and bat guano among many
others all right guys Sean will be here
next week I'm going to jump in for a
minute uh he'll be here next week to
discuss this all organic method uh he
calls it organic as [ __ ] once you hear
about your nutrients being fed being
made with anhydr ammonia kind of makes
you start getting more interested in
that sub sustainable Horticulture stuff
right it sounds kind of weird and
extreme like some crazy chemistry but it
actually happens in the soil itself
there's a little cycle that
nitrates um ammonium nitrites and
actually pure NH3
ammonia um are converted back and forth
by uh your MOS sometimes uh you'll buy a
pack of mos that'll say uh nitrogen
fixing that's what they're talking about
um they convert nitrates usually into
the
ammoniums so it happens in the soil
anyway um but that's actually what makes
Advanced Nutrients junk food it's all
nitrates you want to have some ammonium
ions in there too wow and they actually
do exist in the uh
composted organic stuff um they're just
produced usually by bacteria aerobic
Decay so Tony's got access to all of the
ingredient lists and studies from the
colleges because he's a college kid and
uh he's read some great [ __ ] and told me
some great things about nutrients and
it's that stuff right there that's
golden yeah yeah all right so uh where
was I'm talking about Sean's coming dude
once I read about this stuff I got kind
of like I want to go more toward a
sustainable way of growing my plants I
think it would be better that's my next
step I can grow I can breed I can select
phenotypes I can identify problems like
everything my game is strong now I just
got to adjust and get more uh more
eco-friendly quit using so much
electricity and photo and hydros shop
stuff uh much love to my hydros shop
sponsor I just got to get away from some
of that stuff you know uh so because uh
what I was talking about nitrogen
because if it's crucial role in
photosynthesis fertilizers high in
nitrogen are used during the vegetative
phase of growing cannabis uh nitrogen is
key to both chlorophyll and protein
production and used throughout
photosynthesis for the conversion of
carbon into sugars and other organic
compounds so grow fertilizers are high
in nitrogen they're used for rapid
growth they're used to build chlorophyll
and promote a healthy green color and
they improve the volume and health of
plant foliage you guys if you see your
plants looking pale and yellow that's
your first sign of probably a nitrogen
deficiency oh
yeah oh we're 35 minutes in we'll get
through these nutrients at least this
will be cool you I should say that the
plants most plants in general will
intake 80% of all of the nitrogen they
use in the lifetime during the
vegetative stage so that's why all your
vegetative cannabis nutrients have a
higher um nitrogen value than flowering
ones then you cut that out right at the
start of flower it stores it up uh for
metal abolic processes okay so it just
saves just chilling in there just saved
part of carbohydrates actually okay and
stores it up as energy and then releases
it during flour so I uh usually feed my
veg nutrients until about two uh two
weeks into flour yeah so that I'm giving
them more nitrogen to have available
should I just switch right away um
that's what I've been doing but mine
turned yellow way too fast all right
then I'll just keep uh feeding that next
that extra two weeks kind of seems to
keep them green for the time that I need
now there's like veganic sources of
plant nitrogens usually amino acids
those usually they direct you to use
those up to flush which I've not figured
out why but it's the good
nitrogen lots of it veganics is way
different I've grown a veganic crop with
some veganic nutrients I was given and
it had the flavor it definitely
had cotton seed or soybean meal those
are very high and weird Oran types of
nitrogens usually amino acids and
proteins that's why all these organic
guys are getting great results they're
using actually naturally occurring but
you nces a high highly active uh
microsphere there lots of bacterias and
romes so you have to be using I can't
wait for Sean to come uh listen to the
next episode with Sean you'll love it
you'll love it all right let's talk a
little bit about phosphorus uh
phosphorus is a vol volatile and
reactive element which is why it is
probably never found in its pure
Elemental form in nature because of its
volatility fertilizer packaging is
actually showing a measure of its oxide
p205 phosphorus is commonly refined from
stone called phosphatide ored from guano
Islands comprised of primarily bird and
bat droppings a common biomassive source
of phosphorus is found in the ground
bone also known as bone meal uh cannabis
plants use the phosphorus throughout
their growing Cycles but at elevated
levels when flowering as the plants
nutrient requirements change the feed
eting schedule is adjusted to include
Bloom foods with higher levels of
phosphorus and lower levels of nitrogen
because plants also use phosphorus in
root formation low doses of it are often
found in cloning
Solutions uh so phosphorus basically uh
Bloom foods are higher in phosphorus
phosphorus improves Bud production uh
phosphorus AIDS in root development and
it's involved in oil and glucose
production in the end of your blooming
cycle yeah you're actually want your
highest phosphorus levels
a few weeks before flour and like for
the first third of flour okay uh so
boost those up just like we did with the
nitrogen um yeah the nitrogen starts to
drop down and that's when the phosphorus
goes up and then towards the middle end
of flower you want lots and lots of K so
you want a very very high last number K
all right let's talk about K potassium
uh potassium is an Alkali metal that
reacts violently with water and oxidizes
quite rapidly when exposed to air this
unstable nature requires that it be
added to fertilizers in the form of
pottassium compounds known as pot ash
not all forms of pot ash are suitable
for plants like phosphorus potassium is
mined from mineral Laden ore uh like n&amp;p
potassium which is K is a key component
in the metabolic functions of plants and
plays a large role in the production of
proteins and photosynthesis potassium
also helps strengthen the marijuana
plant's immune system when to correct
that cannabis plants immune system which
help helps the plants cope with
environmental stresses including insects
and diseases Bloom formulated
fertilizers often include increased
levels of potassium because it helps
improve flower quality also potassium is
found in both grow and Bloom fertilizers
because Tony was saying that it's good
towards the end of edge uh it helps the
plant's immune system and it increases
flower quality you'll see it in most of
your Bloom boosters it'll be real high
in potassium so if you're looking for a
bloom booster and a bud hardener that
last number on the bottle that's the one
you're looking at yeah so uh would you
agree with me that that's the basics of
the NPK yeah you want to start high
nitrogen and then end very low and then
start mid to low pottassium and end very
very high very high yeah and then the
phosphorus kind of like goes in like a
little mountain hump there's some plants
I feel like you almost can't give them
too much phosphorus it's it's a timing
thing actually I feed them a bunch of it
right as they're going into flower and
then when I notice the buds have
naturally stopped uh swelling up I dose
them with quite a bit more and then they
just their little metabolism kicks back
on for like one more week yeah yeah uh
there's some yeah the if you kick a lot
of pottassium in them it keeps them
moving it definitely keeps them from
slowing down your plants don't get as
lazy all right so we'll talk a little
more specifically about when to feed
things to our plants uh when the plants
are young we kind of covered this but
when the plants are young they don't
require as much viralization I focus on
root building when the plants are young
micos are your friend and enzymes are
too uh we've talked about micos and
enzymes on the show before we'll come
back to that uh once we get all the
basics covered uh that's your ogt and
your hygrozyme if you guys are looking
for products use them just like they say
on the bottle those are perfect uh small
plants want nitrogen to grow strong a
little bit of phosphorus will help them
uh build roots and grow Vigor vigorously
a little potassium will keep them
healthy your basic veg nutrients
probably have enough PK to get you
through your veg phase if you veg for
long periods you may need to add some
calcium
magnesium uh that's something that
larger plants will start running out of
so let's talk a little bit about calmag
while we're here calcium and magnesium
are what are known as secondary
nutrients calcium is a big part of the
cell structure and cellular growth
calcium stimulates enzymes that build
strong roots and cell walls magnesium is
essential to absorb light energy if your
plants are slow and lazy they may be
experiencing a magnesium
deficiency yeah there certain types of
uh yellowing between the veins is
magnesium deficiency magnesium is
actually what makes chlorophyll green
little bit of Huma from organic hair
will speed your plants up when they
start getting lazy like that yeah yeah
uh so in the beginning you need nitrogen
a little phosphorus and a little
potassium if you're looking for big
Roots definitely add some type of micos
or root inoculant I always brag about
the ogt and great white shark together
that [ __ ] works great for your roots you
get big fat white roots uh if you feed
ogt and great white shark along with
your mix your regular feed schedule in
the morning right when the plants come
on if you go in about two hours later
most of your leaves will be pointing
straight up and they're praying and
thanking you they're saying holy [ __ ] I
love that that's what they're doing they
love that [ __ ] if your plants get a
little too big in V you're going to need
calag once you enter the flower phase
totally like we talked about reduce the
nitrogen uh the first two weeks of flour
won't show you much keep the plants fed
and happy I use my grow based nutrient
until week three of flour like I was
talking about I feel like it keeps them
nicely uh nitrogen up until the end of
flour I add some CAG and put some
pottassium silicates in um and also some
type of kelp at week three so that's
calag pottassium silicates and kelp at
week three I'll add liquid Karma and
sweet at week three also so when you
start week three of flour you can drop
out most of the nitrogen and really
start pumping up the pnk week four I do
the same thing as week
three um we should be low on nitrogen
and pumping up the pnk I'd add some kelp
and a small amount of molasses by now i'
would also add some enzymes to my mix
I'd be running the whole Botanicare feed
chart by week five um week four so here
we go week five is where I really pound
my plants with food I think uh day 30 is
where they're really ready for sugars
and boosters that's when they're really
ready to get hammered with a lot of
stuff so I've dropped the nitrogen by
now and I'm feeding heavy doses of pnk
I'd be adding my Bloom boosters and lots
of molasses and sugars uh calag would be
super important for the next C couple
weeks uh enzymes and kelp would also be
helpful for big tasty buds I think kelp
uh I use a lot of clex I think all that
kelp really uh adds to the stink and the
density it really adds to the uh some
flavors if they have that foot cushy
skank skunk smell that stank it kind of
makes them come out a little bit better
if you had a lot of uh a lot of kelp so
uh you should add some pottassium
silicat for thick branches at this time
like week five week 30ish uh maybe you
could have put those in at week four but
if you got good healthy plants I think
they're cool on week five you just need
them for to build those branches up a
little bit while the buds grow too super
thick because they're going to start
falling over if you don't have some kind
of tomato cages so week five is
basically your Bloom based nutrients
lots of blood Bud boosters sugars
enzymes potassium silicates and kelp uh
week six will basically be the same
thing focus on your uh Bud boosters and
sugars and get that stuff up there as
high as you can without burning the
plants put a lot of molasses in there a
lot of pnk products uh and some enzymes
in there to keep all of that stuff
moving um you do the same thing up to
however long you need to go uh week
seven week eight usually don't feed
after week nine you should start
flushing by week eight most plants
aren't going to go more than 10 weeks uh
if you're growing a plant that takes
more than 10 weeks I hope you're
experienced and I hope all of this stuff
already makes sense to you because
that's going to be uh it's going to be a
[ __ ] for you to grow an 11we plant
without this knowledge so once you get
to week eight and you've gotten done
feeding these plants and keeping them
happy healthy you need to flush you
we've just talked about how much stuff
we poured into these plants uh now you
need to spend at least 10 to 14 days
with nothing but water in these plants
so on Monday however much if you've got
a 5 gallon pot pour water through until
that shit's running through until your
tray is almost full until you're worried
about it if you have a way to get that
water out of the tray that's ideal and
get that water out of there and let
those plants sit until they're almost
dry and do the same thing all over again
and do that for the next 10 to 14 days
try to get three or four cycles of just
clean water through there so that you
can push out all the nitrogen the
phosphorus the potassium the calcium the
Magnesium the micos that we just put in
there you need to clean your soil out
you want to get all that stuff out of
there now if you have like really clean
really clean sorts of like molasses you
could use that your first flesh watering
uh quite a bit of that and uh sugar
display salts that's why all the like
clearex that they'll sell you
uh cerx is just AE bunch of different
types of sugars um displaces salt but it
feeds all your MOS like basically it
feeds all of them boosts their
colonization up and they end up eating
any residual food that's left they eat a
bunch of it for you like a little
garbage disposals pretty nice he just
said sugars displace salts you guys so
most of the nutrients you're feeding are
salts and your plants are filled with
salts uh salts don't taste so good sugar
sounds like it tastes good right so if
you put some sugars in there when you're
flushing it'll push the salts out of
your plants it'll also clean up the soil
it'll break it up kind of it goes in
there and stirs it around right yeah
feed feeds your hungry feeds your hungry
micos which is always awesome uh I want
to go to a website this is where I got a
lot of the information about um just a
lot of information from this show it's
called marijuana growers hq.com is where
I got a lot of it and I also got some
guidance from the Botanicare website um
I'm kind of looking at their feed charts
to keep in mind what I would feed every
week because I don't have my own feed
chart in my hand cuz it's it's uh it's
in the grow spaces you know I don't
carry that around but yeah so that was a
shout out to the people that made the
the charts easy for me to figure out and
they made NPK easy for everyone to
understand um I think we should stop
there on the nutrient lessons because
we're 45 minutes in 47 minutes and I
think if we go any further we'll end up
running over an hour and you potheads
run out of attention span at 45 minutes
I can tell how long you listen Stitcher
tells me uh Tony can definitely tell how
long you're listening because he runs
all my stats um we've had about 5,000
listens on the past few episodes yeah
which is remarkable I want to thank all
5,000 of you I hope all 5,000 of you
continue to
listen um it seems like it's about time
to wrap up the show I don't feel like I
have much more to cover where was that
page that I had my topics I think I
covered them all we're going to say we
did because I can't find the damn paper
so we had to have covered all the topics
oh the Cannabis Cup was uh over
Thanksgiving uh the Vault genetics and
DNA genetics big shout out shout out to
Crockett I I don't remember exactly who
won everything but big shout out to
everybody that took home prizes I hope
everybody has a safe trip home I heard
the Cannabis Cup got raided and they
shut it down so they had to move
everything there was no big smokeout
Expo uh all that they did have was the
concerts that were supposed to happen so
I hope everybody got home I hope nobody
got in any trouble um so now that the
show's over yes the show is over now
that the show is over dude Tony thanks
for coming yeah no problem it was good
finally having you on the show Bro
you've been it's been a minute yeah
you've been working with me for quite a
while we never had you on a podcast I
appreciate you coming
um dude do you have an Instagram or
something you want people to follow you
on um yeah L lxt rvn lxt rvn on
Instagram follow him he posts a lot of
cool pictures of ghost OG we might kind
of be in a personal friendly conver
competition over growing this ghost OG
it's kind of fun so check out his ghost
picks and my ghost picks and then leave
some comments all right guys now that
the show is over please go to iTunes or
Stitcher also big shout out to Jesse
he's taking an app on the couch dude uh
we'll only make a little bit of fun of
you um it's all right everybody has
their first dab we got to see what
happens
uh now the show's over please go to
iTunes or Stitcher go to the iTunes
store or the stitcher main page search
for the Agro culture podcast find the
review section please give me a
five-star rating after that type in a
comment and let me know what you think
of the show and I will read your
comments on the show don't forget that
the podcast is available on iTunes
Stitcher and every single episode is
archived Forever on iy genetics
colorado.com make sure you follow us on
Twitter Instagram and Facebook just
search for igro culture follow iy
genetics on Instagram if you're
interested in Sp sponsoring the podcast
or if you have a product you'd like us
to review Send an email to ulture
hotmail.com and I will get you all the
info that you need uh we still need our
own theme song I want to give a huge
shout out to the Mystic roots for
letting me play their own music but we
like something that you know says Agri
culture podcast in it uh big shout out
to my ninja Spence guys until next time
thanks for listening take a fat dab give
your mom a hug for
me
sweet burning in the night
sweet yeah going to make you feel
right
sweet burning in the
night
sweet yeah going to make you feel
right I remember the day
when show me the
way I
meditation it is the only
way