[Music]
you're only making criminals on the
decent Road a smoke it should be a crime
it's about time
[Music]
welcome to the show podcast world it is
time for episode 420 of the growth from
your heart a podcast happy 420 everybody
and thank you for joining me for this
420 episode this episode of the show is
brought to you by our friends at Oregon
elite seeds on 420 organ elite seeds
we'll be dropping the first batch of
blue raspberry truffle so make sure you
check them out at
www.thekingofrandom.com v'n I also just
took a big fat dab of grape Cola batter
from apothecary farms and I followed
that up with a dab of fortissimo from
green dot labs I am heavily medicated
but what else would you expect from a
podcast recorded on 419 happy 4/20 again
everybody I am in the mood for
podcasting I am in the mood to smoke
some dabs
I'm in the mood to talk about cannabis
and I'm definitely excited to talk about
4/20 in the past few episodes and on my
social media I've been asking my
audience to tell me what 4/20 means to
them so in this episode we're going to
talk about 4/20 and what it means to you
and we will wrap it up by talking about
what 4/20 means to me so ladies and
gentlemen smokers and growers roll up a
fat joint put some fresh water in the
bong or get yourself a DAB ready and
let's talk about what 4/20 means to you
and to me I've got a bunch of messages
saved here in my phone I'm gonna go
right to the first message this one
comes from you know I don't know if
people want their names set on the show
so I'm not going to say your name but
I'm going to send everybody a big THANK
YOU and give everybody much love and
respect for all of the responses I got
from the listeners thank you the
listener interaction means a lot to me
so this first message goes a lot like
this to me 4/20 means community it means
normalization decriminalization and
legalization I first felt that over 20
years ago as a student in Vermont our
sociology professor told us that on 4/20
at 4/20 it's a tradition for students to
gather on campus in the main lawn and
smoke
together celebrate together in public
the cops practiced tolerance that day it
was a beautiful progressive thing to
take part in and that sense of community
surrounding 4/20 has always stuck with
me then they wrapped up this message
with a green heart emoji which tops it
all off beautifully so to this person
4/20 represents community I'm sure that
we're going to see that as a trend and a
lot of these messages I love that
colleges were accepting to the 4/20
movement I am really I appreciate that
some of the professor's and that the
people at universities and colleges were
kind of tolerant and accepting and
encouraging of the 4/20 movement I find
that to be quite progressive so thank
you for this great 4/20 message let's
move on to the next one this one comes
from a good friend of the show I don't
know if they want their name said you
know what this is from Grimble to druid
I know that's not his real name so we
can say that on the air this message
goes like this hey Rasta Jeff to me 4/20
and other cannabis holidays are an
opportunity to get together with my
closest friends and family and
appreciate this wonderful plant in one
of the best ways I know how smoking as
much as we comfortably or sometimes
uncomfortably can handle and eating
great food and enjoying each other's
company keep up the great work from your
friend Grimbold the druid hey grimm
thank you for the great message dude I
always appreciate having interacting
with you and I always appreciate your
fine cannabis photography and make sure
you guys follow Grimble the druid on
instagram and check out his fine fine
cannabis photography all right let's
keep moving this next one comes from
let's see how they signed it they don't
use a fake name so I'm just not gonna
give them a name it says Rasta Jeff as
always I love your podcast keep it going
brother hey I will do my best I see no
reason to stop can't stop won't stop so
I'm gonna keep it going man there's no
reason to shut this down we were at 420
I'm just gonna keep pushing so thanks
for the encouragement it goes on to say
so I've been smoking for the past 16
years of my life and 4/20 has always
been a day to hang with the bros and
smoke in celebration of this amazing
plant so we see more community coming up
the last three messages have all talked
about hanging out with our friends
during 4/20 so that's awesome so he
wants to smoke in celebration of this
amazing plant then he goes on to say
even in prohibition land the love is
still there so on 4/20 me and the dudes
will have your podcast going and smoke
one for
you happy 4/20 brother hey Bros hey guys
gathering around smoking and listening
thank you for bringing me to the party I
appreciate it man I get to go to a lot
of really cool 4/20 parties this year
this is gonna be cool
I get to say I was at a lot of parties
you guys heard me I was there what's up
you guys
minions a message he says happy 4/20
brother hey happy 4/20 to you too and he
continues one last sense it says as
always take a phat dab and hug your mom
and of course shout out to white Mike
hey white Mike you got a shout-out we
may hear from white Mike toward the end
of the episode happy 4/20 to white Mike
hey our friend that sent us this message
you know who you are dude thank you I
look forward to coming to the party with
you and your bros also bring some ladies
to the party dude what kind of party is
that all right let's move on this one
comes from you know what I can say this
guy's name this is from our friend
squishy Mick rosin he says hey Jeff I
just wanted to share a 4/20 moment since
you asked to me 4/20 means friends and
family I told you we would see a trend
in here you guys to me 4/20 means
friends and family I love hearing that
long ago when I was 17 my dad had a
heart attack just a few days before 4/20
and I had to travel to Vancouver for him
to have an operation and I missed a 4/20
celebration I had planned with my
friends and I really hope in the end of
this story you tell me that your dad is
okay that's all I'm hoping for right now
it goes on to say the operation went
well good I'm relieved already the
operation went well for my dad and
everything checked out okay I'm so glad
to hear that we can continue this
message within peace now he said when I
returned home my friends had shown their
support by planning a two-day 4/20
makeup party in my honor
and they called it and he says his real
name fast I mean this we're just gonna
say squishy fest and uses a Instagram
name here so we don't bust out his real
name
man that is pretty cool that your
friends gave you a two day make up 4/20
party you missed the one day main party
so instead you got two bonus days
everyone had 4/20 then you got to have
for 22 and 23 or whatever it was a great
time so that is cool that they did that
you get they gave you your own little
fest that is some really cool friends
keep them around bro so the message
continues he says so now every year has
420 approaches I'm reminded how thankful
I am to still have my dad in my life now
17 years later yeah man I'm glad he's
still around with you hope you're
enjoying that I'm curious if you smoked
with your dad I am really curious if you
have crossed that line yet the message
continues it says and how
great of a friends I had to do that for
me when my family was going through some
[ __ ] yes that is really cool that your
family pulled it together your friends
they are your family they pulled it
together they threw you a 4/20 party
they took your mind off of things the
best part is that dad's still around so
that is [ __ ] cool hey this year for
4/20 if you haven't already smoked with
your dad I dare you to spark up with dad
good luck dude alright I've got another
message we're gonna go through these
messages quite quickly and then we may
place some more audio messages and then
I'll talk about what 4/20 means to me
this one they did not leave an alias oh
it says feel free to use my name so that
makes it easy the message goes like this
hey I love your show I thank you for
your show it makes Monday another Friday
hey that's pretty cool sometimes Monday
can be a kind of a pain in the ass for
some people and that's why I put out
shows on Monday because it makes Monday
suck a little bit less for those people
who have to go to a job they don't
completely enjoy so that's cool that I'm
making your Monday another Friday that's
pretty rad the message keeps going he
says you are smart very smart and then
here's the part we're looking for he
says 4/20 is to me a day that I'm going
to take off work and literally wake up
in bed with the joint rolled and a hot
nail and keep myself medicated all day
and hang out and smoke with my friends
there we go we got another guy that is
going to spend 4/20 with his friends
that's the way to do it
he says friends that smoke or not then
he also says maybe go for a walk or cook
something or both yeah do definitely
cook something grub down and then go for
a walk that sounds like a great idea
then he says shout out to you and white
Mike there you go Mike you got a shout
out come take a dab bro and he says you
guys are both awesome and feel free to
use my name from Brant hey Brent thanks
for the great message thanks for sharing
what 4/20 means to you alright this next
message came in on my email my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com and it goes a little bit
like this 4/20 brings me back to a
special day my name is Timmy and I saw
you on the dude gross show on YouTube
and I have grabbed some of your beans I
am in New York City so yeah but my 4/20
my first 4/20 was when I was like 19 and
I'm 32 now being my homeboy got some
purple beautiful buds that I've never
seen anything so pretty two years ago my
best friend overdosed on heroin three
days before my birthday well that is a
rough story already
so last year I went and spent all my
money on a trip by myself to the San
Bernadino four-twenty High Times
Cannabis Cup I had to stop myself I
wanted to say San Bernadino the San
Bernadino 420 High Times Cannabis Cup ah
you said also what a mess you feel like
you were ripped off I'm not gonna touch
that statement then you say but stay
positive I guess yes stay positive that
they were at least able to have that
event I understand that it did get weird
that year things didn't go perfectly but
at least you got to go have a good time
be around the cannabis community stay
positive that's all we can do then he
goes on to say I guess I've just shut
down about growing but if cannabis just
makes me happy it gives me something to
be happy about and makes me feel good
and I feel close to my homeboy on the
day of 4/20 I'm glad that 4/20 can bring
back that connection to your friend
that's no longer around it I'm I'm
hoping that you're surrounded by other
good friends this year and that you're
smoking something delicious and that you
guys are laughing and kind of
remembering that your homeboy was there
with you and had a bunch of good times
with you I hope you're doing alright man
if you want to hang out send me an email
we'll take a virtual DAB together let me
know how you're doing bro I hope
everything goes marvelously for you for
this 4/20 I hope we can redeem that San
Bernadino 4/20 because I know how that
was
it'll get better bro alright let's move
forward we've got another message this
one came to us from the YouTube channel
this one says 4/20 means to me it is
time to fire it up bro even if you smoke
all day every day that is from our
friend James but erson big shout out to
James but arson always the first one to
leave a comment on the YouTube videos
much appreciated big respect let's see I
think we have another one here in the
phone there are two more I think this
one goes like this
I currently shift work between 60 to 90
hours a week dude are you a [ __ ]
machine that is crazy take a break my
man
I would like to one day only work 20
hours a week yeah that sounds like a
good idea a one day I'll have to bro
then he says he'd like to work no more
than four days and be off every
afternoon by 4:20 then he says 4:20 is
when I get to chill and relax hey that's
a great one man you work too hard so you
work hard for that 420 break I bet that
is nice after 60 to 90 hours of work
that is tremendous that is putting it in
so you really do deserve that's
that is medical marijuana I don't know
if you're smoking for recreational
purposes that's medical at that point
you deserve it bro and thanks for the
update on what 4/20 means to you all
right podcast world those were all of
the listeners submissions about what
4/20 means to you I think it is time for
me to tell you what 4/20 means to me and
then we will play a couple of audio
clips from some of our friends
what does 4/20 mean to me 4/20 means a
lot of things to me I have been involved
in participating in celebrating 4/20 for
a very long time I probably actually
discovered the phrase 4/20 early in high
school probably around 8th or 9th grade
my first fish show is in 95 and I know
we were talking about 420 at fish shows
so 420 I've been celebrating talking
about participating I've been in the 420
scene since the early 90s 420 has
evolved and changed into a lot of
different things over the years as I
have grown when I first discovered 420
like most of us it was kind of the way
that me and my bros would tell each
other you want to go smoke some weed
without everybody else knowing that we
were gonna go smoke some weed that
didn't last very long when you're a high
school kid you think you've got some
code it's not good code if you're a high
school kid you're listening you should
not be listening but if you've got some
code that you think your teachers or
your parents or somebody know that means
we're gonna go do something stupid
everybody knows you're gonna go do some
[ __ ] stupid your codes not working so
4/20 was our little code that me and Rob
or me and Kris or all of us would be
somewhere and we'd say I think it's
pretty close to 4/20 and other people
that look at their clock and say it's
only 115 I don't know what these
dumbasses are talking about but most of
the other people that knew anybody that
was cool sometimes too many people that
weren't cool well look at us and go oh
yeah it's 4/20 and it come with us or
they would ruin our 4/20 plan so back in
the day when it started that was our way
to say let's go smoke bro is almost time
to go sneak away go smoke a ball
together
go get the crew together and have a good
time then people started catching on
then it started getting really really
popular then around the same time at
4:20 got super popular and super
commercialized I was entering the
commercial cannabis industry that is
where my view my stance my opinion of
4/20 shifted a little bit when you
worked in the commercial cannabis
industry if you were in the production
side if you were in the commercial side
especially if you were in the packaging
side or the retail side 420 can be a
headache it is a pain in the ass it is
almost a lot of my friends this is the
week of 4/20 and I'm not going to see a
lot of my friends because they're
working overtime they're stuck at work
getting prepared
they're running 420 sales many of my
friends that are running their own
businesses are away at conventions
trying to manage their business 4/20
gets hectic when you were in the
cannabis business and you've got
responsibilities about two weeks before
to 4/20 we started getting prepared
we've got to roll all of the pre rolls
people come from all over the damn
planet to Colorado and they all want a
pre-roll we have got to start rolling
pre-rolls all of the employees that
don't have something to do are put on a
pre roll station start rolling joints we
need all of them so there's a lot of pre
rolls to be done there's a lot of
preparation like packaging all of the
concentrates you buy they all come in
ridiculous amounts of packaging they
have to be weighed by somebody to have
to be packaged by somebody somebody has
to do all of that we sell a lot of
product over the 420 holiday season
somebody is putting those products
together around the 1st of April we
start and they'll be continuing through
April 20th then on for 21 they have to
start doing it all over to restock the
shelves because we wipe it clean on 4/20
so it is it's great don't get me wrong
it's great for the industry but for the
people who are part of it it is a
headache
it is like the Christmas rush for the
weed industry it is like the mall at
Christmastime it is like whatever
wherever you go to buy fancy [ __ ] it's
like Best Buy it's like the mall it's
like Guitar Center at Christmastime it
is hectic the people that are working
there have that deer-in-the-headlights
sort of look they just wish they could
get a break so they could go smoke it is
hectic the traffic starts about two
weeks before everything starts going on
sale the prices change new customers
start coming everything is more chaotic
so it kind of changes your whole opinion
oh also a lot of times as it gets closer
to 4/20 there will be a [ __ ] DJ at
your work DJing
spin in terrible music that you're
trying to work over so you got while
you're trying to sell a gram to some guy
from Texas that doesn't know anything
about cannabis I know what I'm talking
about how terrible it is but once you've
done it a couple of years in a row you
kind of you think oh god it's 4:15 I
don't want to go to work this week so
that's what it's like once you enter the
cannabis and is
if you work in the retail side you kind
of just want to punch yourself in the
face from about April 10th right in
through about April 22nd then I've kind
of shifted my position in the cannabis
industry I still work with a lot of
growers I still do a lot of things in
the cannabis industry I'm not so
involved in that retail side I'm not so
involved in immersed in all the people
I'm kind of more I've become sort of a
hermit in my old age which is [ __ ]
great with me the less people the less
places the less drama and [ __ ] let's
stick to the point I've kind of changed
my stance since I am not so heavily
involved I don't have to be anywhere
that I don't really want to be at this
point 4:20 now I miss what it used to be
I miss when me and my Bros could nudge
each other and go down for a little 4/20
like I don't got any weed but I got some
weed and [ __ ] let's go do some 4/20
or one of your friends who just oh
remember the pagers back in the day your
pager would go off and it would have
your friend's phone number and then it
would just say 4/20 and then it would
have like a couple of other numbers and
we knew that if you put these four
numbers that was the Burger King over on
the south side cuz those are the four
numbers for the pay phone and the Burger
King so if you text me you say 420 the
last four digits of the phone number the
pay phone at the Burger King I know
we're gonna go smoke some balls in the
parking lot at Burger King
pretty soon I'll meet you there I missed
those days that was kind of cool being a
sneaky stoner was fun now that it's not
even I don't know everybody just smoking
weed everywhere it's not even like
sneaky anymore something I don't know
something about hiding it made it a
little bit more fun and I missed that
code and that time maybe I just missed
that time period because we were [ __ ]
17 I didn't have to worry about anything
but I missed that part of it
so now being the opposite end of that
being an adult where I don't have to
hide 420 from anybody at this point the
law my parents the teacher nobody cares
you can smoke a fat dad and walk into
class and as long as you can stare at
the teacher properly they don't give a
[ __ ] as long as you paid your tuition
and you showed up nobody even cares so
it's completely different it's a little
it's like when your favorite band puts
out that album and you go ah yeah
probably not gonna listen to them so
much anymore it's kind of that same
feeling for 4/20 don't get me wrong I
love 4/20 I'm smoking down it's for 19
and my eyes are red I'm a little goofy
we're gonna have a great 4/20 but it is
different now I'm an old guy
I'm not into I don't need the code I
don't need that stuff so it's fun to go
to the shows it is great to smoke
I love the communal feeling of it it is
a little overhyped in Colorado because
it is almost like they know all of the
businesses know it's 4:20 time there is
a burger joint that is selling a burger
with CBD and the sauce everybody is
advertising blatant 4/20 advertising any
product that could be used by a cannabis
consumer they're pointing it at you with
some 420 style advertising in Colorado
so it's a little overdone in my opinion
but I still love it don't get me wrong I
still love it I want to smoke with you
every day at four-twenty and especially
even harder on 4/20 so I love 4/20 I'm
all about the 4/20 I used to have a
shirt that looked like it had the 7/11
logo on it but it actually said four or
add the number four and said twenty on
the bottom of it and it real big on the
back everywhere I went all the hippies
love that [ __ ] like deliver 4/20 shirt
bro and then we would smoke together
then in the future
i evolved i got the one it looked like
it's at 7-eleven but it actually said
7/10 because 7/10 is the new 4/20 we got
a couple of months so we talked about
that so that is in a nutshell my
feelings about 4:20 and what 4/20 means
to me I appreciate all of your
contributions and your emails your
messages your YouTube comments anyway
you reached out thank you for telling me
what 4/20 means to you I've got a couple
of audio clips I'm going to play from
friends of ours they want to tell us
what 4/20 means to them before we get
there let's go old-school let's talk
about war 4/20 originated we've all got
our own ideas it all means something
cool to all of us let's talk about the
originators of 4/20 in the early 70s in
San Rafael California there were a group
of dudes who call themselves the Waldos
you may have heard of these dudes just a
normal group of dudes everyday at 4:20
this group of dudes known as the Waldos
would meet up at a spot after school and
guess what they would do they would get
down on a fat joint or a fat bull it
just happened to be 4/20 cuz that's when
everybody got out of class that's when
they could all get together so their
code was hey you want to get together
for a little 4/20 and from there it
really caught on now the Waldos were
also known for being dead heads
so the phrase 4/20 travelled quickly
through deadhead culture deadheads loved
to have some sort of a cool catchphrase
anything to say something without saying
the real word and dead head culture is
always a really catchy thing to do so
it's
spread like wildfire through the
deadhead culture in the 80s deadhead
cultures started becoming like pop
culture it was just becoming mainstream
so that introduced 4/20 to the
mainstream which made it spread through
the high school kids where it became
even more popular that's where I
discovered it I discovered it in high
school and through the fish community at
fish shows when I said 420 at a fish
show everybody definitely knew what I
meant so big shout out to the Waldos I
don't want to blow all of their story
they've got a website and their website
is 420 Waldo's dot-com if you were more
interested in the Waldos I encourage you
to check out their website it is kind of
neat it is kind of fun there's a lot of
archival evidence they can show how far
back the phrase 4:20 went they show how
far back they've been calling themselves
the Waldos then they show how they link
themselves to the Grateful Dead so it is
a really fun website if you're
interested in the 420 culture so I've
told you what 420 means to me we have
talked about what 420 means to a lot of
our listeners I have educated you on
where 420 came from now I think it is
time to play some clips from some of our
friends about 420 all right first off
happy 4/20 Mike thanks for joining me
yeah man so uh I am asking everybody
what is 4/20 mean to you you like myself
have been in and out of the cannabis
industry you've been around for quite a
while also you're an old dude so can you
tell me what does 4/20 mean to you um
it's a big it's the community holiday it
when I was younger I went kind of wild
with it but that was in the heyday where
tens of thousands of people would gather
up at cu-boulder
on Norlin lawn or one hundreds of
thousands of people or a hundred
thousand people would gather in downtown
Denver at Civic Center no concerts no
promotion of food vending just a giant
massive smoke out in the battled
prohibition days because we could in
mass numbers sort of a civil protest if
you will it was the only real act of
civil disobedience I got to participate
in in my generation still a great rite
of passage I was also like I vividly
remember the first time I went up to see
you Boulder and participated in the
smoke out on 4/20
it was insane just like people
everywhere cops everywhere people with
cameras everywhere the school really
didn't want the event to take place but
there's there's nothing you can do when
10,000 or more people decide that
they're gonna show up it a place at a
time and do a thing absolutely
how are in numbers how old were you at
that time mmm I think the first time I
went up there I was 18 cool I mean there
was like in 2000 when these there was no
medical yet
Callie been medical in Colorado would
just pass medical but it didn't mean
anything there were no doctors no cards
no meed no medical marijuana program yet
so everything was black market
everything was illegal basically unless
you were one of those rare med patients
that we had here but that was brand-new
so many there there were almost no
medical patients in like the early 2000s
mm 1 2 3 4 so you 18 and that's what 420
was for you then who sort of a a holiday
a cultural holiday and also a great day
that was it was a mass protest the
beautiful thing about those events in
their original incarnation was all of
these people would show up they would
commit what was considered a serious
crime together smoking pot in public was
not something that didn't get you
handcuffed and dragged off a lot of
places take it for granted but it's not
like that still but at the time it was I
mean it was a serious crime and it was
sort of absurd that this was a crime and
so having all this people come together
hang out for a couple hours in the
afternoon like it's usually half decent
on 4/20 sometimes it's brutal cold lucky
this year it's gonna be beautiful god I
hope so it's been beautiful last couple
days but the first couple times I went
up to 420 it was gorgeous the weather
was nice it was just astounding to see
all those people gather hang out chill
until like 4:18 and then the whole crowd
kind of stands up
starts Chernin Hooten red at 420
everybody lights up and there's just
this massive cloud and then by five
o'clock everybody's gone and there's
like fifteen little groups of ones and
twos walking around picking up trash um
and there's there's no traffic snarls
there's no bodies on the highway there's
no pandemonium later um it was just an
awesome act of civil disobedience and
then when I went down to Civic Center
the next couple of years was I used to
go every year we'd take the the light
rail into downtown and just watch the
show all afternoon but seeing a hundred
thousand people all light up right in
front of the state capitol is something
that you should definitely see in person
if you haven't seen it but I stopped
going the more corporate it got when
there was a promoter and concerts and a
couple of terrible vending attempts it
just
it lost its pre allure is blasted soap
for me that makes a lot of sense
I I see how it has gone from I'm gonna
talk about this when I say what it means
to me I don't want to step on your your
part here but I see how it has
definitely gone from the thing that was
what the bros did it was kind of a
download thing the potheads were doing
it and now 420 is an event we go rent
space and we say hey city we're going to
hold a 4/20 rally so it is definitely
evolved I see how you're talking about
corporate so Mike did working in the
cannabis industry change your outlook in
your opinion on 4/20 if you work in the
industry especially on the retail side
for 20s just a nightmare it's like
working Christmas if you're if you've
worked regular retail right it's it's
pandemonium just endless lines whatever
sales going on dude that the whole week
leading up is just not two weeks this
year it seems like it's been two weeks
ahead it's like every holiday is getting
drugged further and further down yeah
yeah it is added to be at the list of
holidays in most states they don't get
the extra holiday that we get here we
have sales like every store has a sale
right around 4:20 any story that could
apply the gross store the restaurants
like the restaurants where stoners go
the pizza joints all those places are
having a sale right now they may not
blatantly say
420 sale but we all know all the
advertising is green it all it's all the
week before and after 420 we all know
what it is it's really neat to see that
all the mainstream culture is kind of
catching on it the disappointing example
of that that I just saw was Carl's jr.
CBD sauce on one of their burgers I was
like you know your [ __ ] family life
right now I don't know if that's even
real is that real it's 100% real there's
one location in Denver in four four
twenty four $4.20
on 4/20 you can get one of their burgers
in in their secret sauce they're
infusing [ __ ] CBD for that one burger
I want to get one of these burgers and
take it to a lap and have it test it and
see how much CBD is in this burger I'm
just curious
interesting game right just Carol
they're advertising and it's got to be
in there CBDs everywhere no it's it's
the next big pile on it is
I saw a meme on social media that said
folks in Colorado be like my Subaru runs
on CBD and is absolutely [ __ ]
accurate alright Mike we are all
stepping all over your little segment
here in this show I just wanted to give
you a couple of brief moments to tell us
what 4/20 means to you you talked about
it as you were a youngster as you
started off in your activism you went to
a peaceful civil disobedience kind of a
protest many of them I've got some good
old footage used to stand in the crowd
and do the slowly turn in a story or at
all I like to do that to be a tall guy
that's a fun one so then it became kind
of commercialized you quit going to the
events and for a couple of years like
myself you were tied up at a location
either working retail during a couple of
the years you were working at the grow
with me offer at least one 4/20 now that
your time to older dude you're a parent
I you're not really in the industry per
se but you are still on the fringe what
is the word I'm looking for tertiary you
were kind of in the industry you're
right near it you're on the your
industry adjacent how does 4/20 what is
4/20 mean to you these days honestly
it's it's just another day in my book I
don't have any plans to hit up a big
event or to go up to Civic Center or
anything that nonsense just just way too
much at this point if the kids are
chillin at 4:20 you might run to the dad
safe room and take a quick puff at 4:20
yeah then it
it's not like I'm missing the the
tradition of like a family dinner or
something like that with a lot of other
holidays where it's like if I just stop
doing Thanksgiving like there are other
parts than just stuff about the holiday
that I would miss with 4/20 it's it's
just another day in my book
but it gets funded the community has a
date to focus on and kind of go all out
with but most of the stuff I see now I
just shake my head at all right Mike man
that was a great kind of overview of
your beginning of 4/20 in the middle of
4/20 your retail 420 and now the
definitely old man Mike 4/20 good
perspective there it like it's it's a
holiday on the day it's a time code it's
a number like when I was in high school
it was cute to like write 420 in your
notebook and [ __ ] but since I was 15 it
was as good as wearing a shirt that said
pothead absolutely no one was confused
about the number 420 except the most
ignorant among us just the nerds and
they were confused about everything so
all right Mike thank you for joining me
for this quick 4/20 segment in the 4/20
episode it is 4/20 we are celebrating
4/20 here so there's nothing left to do
but to turn off these microphones and
let's enjoy some 3000 we're gonna smoke
some flour and some dabs here in honor
of 420 so ladies and gentlemen I'll be
right back to keep the show moving
thanks for joining me Mike yeah
yo yo big up Rasta Jeff this is coo dog
from the mystic roots and my name is
Pato Banton we're giving shoutouts to
say what 4/20 means to us I'll go first
4/20 to me is a day where people get
together to celebrate the magical herb
it's a peaceful day I'd say it's a day
of peace around all the world where
people can relax and fire up enjoy
however they prefer or as edible or if
it's a smoke or even if it's without any
ganja just to feel the vibes of 4/20
that's what 4/20 means to me
for me Pato Banton 4/20 is something
that happens twice everyday once in the
evening 4:20 and once in a month at 4:20
and every year annually 4/20 is when the
whole world come together to celebrate
the healing of the nation and to remind
each other that we should take away the
stigma from this beautiful plant and
remember that it is a medicine it's a
natural herb and there's nothing wrong
with partaking of this beautiful
medication peace yes pick up yes all
right podcast world that is what 4/20
means to three of my favorite people we
got white Mike in there we got big coot
from mystic roots in there and then we
got mr. Pato Banton and they're
spreading the love big thanks to all
three of them for their contribution to
the show podcast world I think that is
all I have got for you for this 420
episode I want to thank you again for
listening to me I hope you had a
wonderful or are having a wonderful 4/20
I hope you're smoking something
delicious I hope you're hanging out with
great people if you were in prohibition
land I hope you are staying safe if you
feel as if this episode were educational
informative or entertaining and you
would like to make a financial
contribution to this show you can do so
by visiting patreon.com slash grow from
your heart all the information you need
will be right there on the screen
if you cannot contribute to patreon you
can still support me by stalking me on
all of the social media on Facebook it's
the growth from your heart podcast on
Twitter it's @g f YH podcast and on
Instagram I use my other company I read
genetics ireon Durst or genetics on
Instagram give us a follow check out my
cannabis photography I think you would
enjoy my cannabis photography and my
life
if you've got something you'd like to
say you're not into all the social media
madness you can reach me through email
my email address is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com don't forget about the
YouTube channel search for the girl from
your heart podcast click Subscribe leave
some comments on the videos and I will
respond to your comments don't forget to
visit our friends at Oregon elite seeds
they're dropping the new blue raspberry
truffle get it while you can ladies and
gentlemen I usually wrap up the show by
giving one person a giant shoutout I
want to give a giant shout out to the
entire 4/20 community worldwide if you
were smoking growing advocating
participating admiring if you were
involved in any cannabis in any way big
shout out big giant fist bump to you and
until next time take a phat dab and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]
I do nothing the foci only small
sinsemilla I do nothing the coke I only
smoke Miller nervous if coke I only
smoke Camila I do not seek the coke I
only smoke without a doubt I am the
gossan in my class I am the teacher if
music is the fruit of life then I will
be a Reaper if MC business was a school
then I would be at master if a car after
the driver if a biker bidam rider
offensive business for the church Paco
would be the kicker then instead of
calling me and see you or would call me
preacher