hey what's up smokers and growers it is
time for episode 423 of The Grove from
your heart podcast this episode of the
show is brought to you by our friends at
Oregon elite seeds it is time to add
fresh new genetics to your garden and I
highly recommend Oregon elite seeds and
you can find them at www.imtcva.org
sunset herb and purple punch the flavor
description on the container says it
should taste like tropical fruit
cocktail I would say that is accurate
the potency label says 69 point two
seven percent total THC and zero percent
CBD when I crack this open I start
thinking that I don't know if I know
what a Maitai really smells like that is
not a familiar aroma for me but as I
give this a sniff it smells like a Long
Island iced tea it's got a tropical
aroma it has got a very pungent aroma
but that may be a triple sec sort of a
thing definitely dominates the smell of
the mai tai it is delicious it is
obviously quite potent because it has
got me talking my face off this is great
podcast concentrate so big shout out to
our friends at green dot labs for the
mai tai live batter I want to thank
everybody for listening to that short
episode I put out on Thursday with all
of the content I made before 420 I just
needed a little bit of a podcasting
break so I threw out a short episode for
Thursday here we are Monday with a
full-length episode thanks again for
joining me I am going to read more
listener emails in this episode before
we get there let's do a few shoutouts
for our friends on patreon I always want
to give a big shout out to miss Melville
Iowa giant shot it's my friend Tanner M
I want to send a huge grow from your
heart podcast shout-out to my friend
farmer John how about a big giant shout
out to my friend dick goals of course
always a shout out to Todd kay of course
a big shout out to my friend Aldridge
and of course a giant grow from your
heart podcast fist bump to my friend
remy red I wanna thank each and every
one of you for your support on patreon
if you would like to learn how to become
a patron you can do so by going to
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
all of the information you need
become a patron we'll be right there on
the screen and once again I want to
thank everybody for all of the patreon
contributions everybody who has helped
out in the past in the present and in
the future your support really does mean
a lot to me
thank you now I know I said I was going
to read some listener emails before we
get there I've got one more thing I
would like to cover several episodes
back before 4/20 I started asking people
to send in submissions and let me know
what 4/20 means to you I got a lot of
great submissions of course many of you
are cannabis consumers which means that
4/20 came and passed you up you didn't
even realize it was 4/20 a lot of you
messaged me on 4/20 or right after here
is a submission I received on the
afternoon of 4/20 so this is what 4/20
means to a friend of the podcast this
one goes like this
when I see or hear 420 I smile and I say
thank you for saving my life I am in
constant pain from a pinched nerve in my
neck and three screwed-up lower back
discs plus a 15 millimeter by 22
millimeter
crack in my left knee socket I had
enough and wanted to get just high for
the fun of it and hoped it would get me
numb I was getting ready to leave and
I'd started giving my [ __ ] away to all
my peoples I was done with all of my
pains and being angry all the time and I
was stressed out I was overweight I was
at 365 pounds you know I was mentally
and emotionally checking out then I
asked my buddy ender what was good for
pain sleep or just help with stress I
thought the 18 year old kid would
recommend something that was just strong
as hell lots of THC and that would get
me high as hell I thought that's
everyone I thought that's what everyone
was talking about when they said
cannabis helped them that they were just
getting high as a kite so the kid says
something like try Romulan or sleep pain
for sleep or pain or Jack the Ripper for
daytime pain or OG Kush and so on so I
get home it's close to bedtime so
Romulan slept great first time since
1997 so cannabis helped this guy sleep
for the first time since 97 he is it
it's 2019 how would you feel if you
hadn't had a nap since [ __ ] 1997 some
of you say I've been up for two days or
I didn't get any sleep last night this
dude said he's been up since 97
so our friend smoked a little bit of
Romulan on the recommendation of a
budtender and he got his first good
night's sleep since 1997 he goes on to
say then I tried Oh G cush that's when I
got this stuff that really works so I
put the brakes on all that checking out
[ __ ] and started growing and I
haven't looked back at those dark days
until you asked me what does 4/20 mean
to me so in short it sounds like this
guy was done with life he was looking to
possibly take his own life in the very
near future if he hadn't discovered the
proper strains of cannabis his pain his
discomfort his attitude his health his
weight everything was stacking up to
where he was done he had emotionally
checked out he had checked out of his
friends and family it sounds like he was
giving a [ __ ] away when you get to that
point you were close to doing something
ridiculous that you can't stop you can't
undo he was about to get there he smoked
the appropriate strain of cannabis based
on a bud tenders recommendation and he
finally got some sleep imagine getting
some sleep since 1997 you're gonna be
tired you finally get some rest it's
gonna change your life
you're gonna start being nicer to people
your attitudes gonna change when you're
nicer to people they're nicer back that
has a lot to do with your health your
mental health and my opinion will play a
lot with how your body feels so our
friend consumed some cannabis and
basically it saved his life now he is
one of us now he is a grower he's a
smoker and he is an advocate I know this
who this person is he does contribute to
the podcast heavily he gets a shout out
on a lot of episodes he actually says
his name here in the future in the
message so we are going to give him a
shout-out here on this so cannabis has
turned this person's life around he
smokes just for the hell of it because
he was at wit's end what else was gonna
happen is it gonna go bad is it gonna
get worse he was already at the breaking
point smoked a little reefer it made him
feel good it gave him some sleep he got
to break free from his pain from his
suffering now he is enjoying life now
he's one of us also he's part of the
Irie army I want to continue with the
message here he goes on to say thank you
so damn much for all you do for the 4/20
community much love to you Rasta Jeff
and the Irie army hey thank you for this
great message messages like this I know
I didn't have anything to do with your
starting of consumption but knowing that
I'm part of this movement that I'm
helping people with there
as being a part of this and being able
to read these types of stories on my
little show here that means a lot to me
other people are gonna hear this and
they're gonna say man this guy was it
wit sin and cannabis kind of turned him
around maybe that story alone will
change somebody else's perspective on
cannabis so thank you man thank you for
being a part of the community thank you
for supporting myself and the show so
much you have been a big part of the IRA
Army you are part of the IRA army as
well so thank you man it goes it's
reciprocated it goes back and forth
without a listener a guy doing a podcast
is just a weirdo with a microphone so I
need a good solid audience you guys have
a good show it works well for both of us
so thank you he goes on to mention his
social media handles he also talks about
some other things here that we don't
need to share on the show he says thanks
for the shout outs every time it feels
so damn good and then he said sorry for
this long-ass email I'm an old fart
grower and all of this is new to me and
then he gives me it looks like a cloud
emoji I can't read what that emoji as my
computer printed it out kind of oddly
and then a fist bump so big shout out
for the fist bump right there and that
is from our friend Richard memo also
known as 420 per amp --ss so hey Richard
thank you for the great email thank you
for telling me what 4/20 means to you
that means a lot to me that is a very
moving story I hope that changes
somebody's outlook on cannabis and dude
that was kind of brave for you to go out
and share something like that that is
kind of opening up to the whole world
here to the whole cannabis community
especially to myself so thank you dude I
appreciate your bravery and I appreciate
this great message thanks for telling me
what 4/20 means to you it is not too
late ladies and gentlemen I know I asked
several episodes ago what does 4/20 mean
to you it is not too late send me your
responses you could email them to me
grow from your heart at hotmail.com or
if it is short you can send it to me on
twitter at g f YH podcast I'll do my
best to find them all and I will read
your submission on the show what does
4/20 mean to you and somebody said do
you mean the number do you mean the time
do you mean the date I don't know what
do you mean when I say 4/20 what does it
mean to you alright now let's get into
those emails that I keep talking about
I've got one right here at the top of
the pile this one let's see it says no
names I am in prohibition land that
makes it easy so let's get right into it
it says Russ - Jeff please don't say my
name because I am in prohibition land I
do
have an indoor garden going first grow
all oto flowers I'm doing a 20 on and 4
hour off flight schedule some of my
plants are already a couple of weeks
into flower and some have just started
they were all seed in the same week but
there are three different strains so
they are going at different rates yes
that makes sense so far they're from
seed they're from auto flowers they're
different strains they were bred from
different genetics so they were gonna
have different traits they will have
different flowering times they'll start
at different times they'll finish at
different times but variety is the spice
of life we talked about why in a
previous episode let's keep moving
forward he says the weather where I live
has gotten really nice and I want to
move my plants to my back deck for a few
hours each day for their light cycle
when it's nice is there anything I
should know about moving them in and out
as far as temps in humidity also should
I gradually let them adjust to the
sunlight or is it okay to stick them out
there for 12 to 13 hours of daylight in
a row he wraps up and he says I'm a
disabled veteran and I'm growing my own
medicine it really helps with my anxiety
and PTSD hey thank you for your service
and I am saddened that you have got PTSD
but I am happy to hear that you have
found medicine that works for you
because I know that PTSD can be really
torturous so I'm glad you've got
something helping you with that now
let's get into this question he said the
weather has gotten really nice and I
want to move my plants to my back deck
for a few hours in theory that sounds
like a really great option those plants
would love some sunlight that sunlight
would be really good for them it is also
free they're probably also going to love
that outdoor air it is going to be
beautiful for them however my biggest
fear is that you were going to bring
bugs into the grow room when you bring
the plants back in no matter how careful
you are no matter what you do I would be
very afraid that I would bring bugs from
that outside environment into my grow
room we spend a lot of time building a
grow room we put a lot of effort into
there into kind of keeping it isolated
to take those plants right outside that
is kind of against everything that I
would do in my grow environment you
probably play by your own rules that's
why you're a cannabis grower and a
cannabis consumer I would not take these
plants outside because you may likely
bring bugs and when you bring them back
in bugs can fly and land on them
bugs can climb up the pot and get right
into the dirt bugs will climb up into
the dirt then climb up the snake and
hide under the leaves also I had another
friend who listens to this podcast he
was having an issue with his plants we
couldn't figure out what it was one day
he told me what when I took them outside
they looked fine I've been bringing them
back in I realized he had some sort of
soil-borne pests something burrowed from
the bottom of his pot up into the root
zone up into the soil it infested the
entire root zone of his plants it took
him a long time to recover from that one
so I would not suggest taking them
outside you've got bugs out there also
maybe possibly you've got neighbors out
there I don't know your living situation
I don't know your neighborhood maybe
you're out in the middle of nowhere
however I don't want anybody to see
those plants you said you're a disabled
veteran if somebody sees them people are
thieves people are shitty somebody might
call the cops
be very careful I wouldn't put them out
there you say Prohibition land and
plants outside that is another big red
flag for me I would not do that don't
snitch on yourself there could be a
helicopter there could be a [ __ ] Girl
Scout cookie sales girl coming by to
sell you some Girl Scout cookies and see
your weed plan out on the back deck
again I don't know your situation you
may be out in the middle of the woods
where nobody's coming for 20 miles still
I would be very careful just because
you're in prohibition land so I wouldn't
take those plants outside you may want
to do that because you're a grown-ass
man and you can do whatever you want and
I respect that so if you do choose to
take these plants outside let me give
you some advice that can help you out I
would not take them out there and leave
them in the Sun for 12 hours
I would absolutely introduce them slowly
I would take them out when the Sun comes
up for a couple hours maybe an hour or
two and watch them see how they react if
they start getting weird take them back
in put them back under they're normal
grow lights then maybe the next day put
them out there if you went an hour the
first day maybe go two hours the next
day maybe go three hours the next day
slowly increase the outdoor interval and
see how they react you have to pay very
close attention because if they start
acting weird you need to get them back
indoors I think if you put them out
there for 12 hours
underneath that natural light I think
that maybe a little more than what they
were ever used to I would be like if I
just kept you in a dark basement for a
couple of years and then one Friday
night I picked you up and took you to
see the Pink Floyd light show your eyes
would blow out you wouldn't be able to
handle it I think the plants will kind
of feel the same way if we go put them
under the
or too long right away without any
protection if you've got kind of a
shadier spot to put them in at first and
then move them into the Sun that also
may be a good idea it may not look like
you're getting a light a lot of light
out there in a shadier spot but you are
absolutely getting enough rays from the
Sun for it to affect that plant in
comparison to what you were getting
indoor under a grow light that shadier
spot outside is probably more efficient
light than the grow light indoors even
if it's shady because it is the exact
spectrum of light that your plants need
and it's the Sun you're not gonna dim
the Sun too much even with a whole bunch
of clouds even in a shady spot so maybe
start that plant in a shady or area on
your deck and then move it into the
sunlight as the day goes on but pay very
close attention to your plants that
those plants are the boss I can't say
that all three are going to enjoy the
same thing you said you've got three
different strains you may get different
responses from these plants I don't know
what they're gonna do outside so
introduce them to the sunlight slowly
pay close attention to them if you're
going to do this another thing I'm
thinking about and I'm not sure how much
this will apply to your plants but those
plants have never seen the sunlight they
don't know that there is sunlight you
may introduce them to the idea that
there is a light outside much greater
than they have ever experienced inside
that grow room right now they are
growing because they're adjusted to the
amount of light that they are getting
they're meeting their dle because of
that grow light if you take them outside
they may get used to having more intense
light they may get spoiled when you
bring them back indoors and put them
under your grow light that's not gonna
be enough light to stimulate the
photosynthesis that they were receiving
and they may begin to stretch
ridiculously fast that will be strain
dependent that will be genetic dependent
but that could be a thing that happens
that's like introducing somebody to ice
cream somebody who is only eaten just a
plain diet they just have breakfast
lunch and dinner and no snacks nothing
sweet nothing tasty nothing no kind of
personal treats for their mouth ever and
then one day you take them out to some
fancy place and you give them just
pretty good ice cream and now they're
like holy [ __ ] ice cream they're never
going to be satisfied with basic
breakfast lunch and dinner anymore
because you introduced them to ice cream
cool before they did no ice cream was a
thing but now they're like bro ice cream
I need some of that [ __ ] because you
introduced it to their lives I feel like
maybe the plants will react the same way
they'll say hey I was used to getting
sunshine like that's a lot of light
you're not gonna give me that I'm gonna
keep stretching for it because I know
that it is an option so when you take
them indoors that may backfire on you so
I would completely not take these plants
outside you're risking bug problems then
you're also risking snitches and thieves
that is terrible I don't want you to go
to jail then my next suggestion is if
you're going to take them out there if
you insist on doing it I would leave
them out there don't take them out and
bring them back in because then you're
going to contaminate your grow room now
I know that the light cycle is probably
not appropriate at this time for your
auto flower plants to go outside to
continue their flowering cycle but that
would be the best-case scenario would
just be take them outside and leave them
to finish I understand that it's
probably not an option that's why you
want to bring them back in and put them
in your room that scares me honestly we
put a lot of time and effort into these
grow rooms and to take plants outside
just to get them a little bit of
sunlight and bring them back in and then
bring the bugs into the grow room that
really makes me paranoid as a commercial
cultivator I've got a lot at stake so
one bug can become a problem very
quickly it can cost a lot of money this
is your medicine that you're relying on
this is what's helping with your PTSD I
wouldn't risk it my friend I would just
keep those plants in the grow room and
keep them happy now like I said before
you're an adult and you can do whatever
you want so feel free to do what makes
you happy because I know there's nothing
like taking that plant out on the back
deck watching the birds fly around and
the squirrels run around and smoking a
fat joint maybe taking a couple of
pictures of those plants in the sunshine
I understand how good that's gonna feel
so if you want to do that
feel free have fun grow from your heart
make yourself happy just understand the
risks while you were doing so hey I want
to thank you for a great email this was
a lot of great content very very useful
information for a lot of people there is
one more sentence it says do you know
anywhere that has feminized Lemon
Jeffery seeds in stock it sounds like a
great stream but I can't find it in
stock online anywhere thanks again for
all of your help and I will send a pics
when they finish thanks again from
prohibition Lynne and then he signs his
name hey thank you for the great email I
really look forward to
photos when they are finished now about
the lemon Jeffrey feminized seeds I
don't have any lemon Jeffrey feminized
seeds for myself I don't know where they
are in stock anywhere at this time if
everything goes according to plan
there should be lemon Jeffrey feminized
seeds available at Oregon elite seeds
around the beginning or middle of July
that is the earliest I can promise those
they will be very limited this breeding
batch was very small we are very limited
on our numbers here so this batch was a
very small batch but around the middle
or beginning of July there will be very
few packs of lemon Jeffrey feminized
seeds available at Oregon elite seeds
you guys might throat just did a thing
I'm gonna press pause I'm gonna take
like seven fat dabs I'm gonna take a
drink and then I'll be right back
alright ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls smokers and growers as promised I
took way too many dabs I had a good
drink and now I am back heavily
medicated well hydrated and ready for a
good podcast I've got another great
email in front of me this one goes a lot
like this hey Ross - Jeff I am in
prohibition land so no names if you use
this on the show hey that's easy I've
got your back it goes on to say I just
wanted to say that I really enjoy your
podcast I have listened to all of the
grow shows and I am very appreciative of
the information and the help hey thank
you man that means a lot to me just to
know that I'm helping somebody makes it
worth all of the effort the message goes
on it says this is my first grow and I
am doing OTO flowers under LED lighting
that I got from Amazon I think the
plants are about two weeks into flower
but I'm not positive because they are
autos the plants are doing okay they are
just not really big most are about a
foot tall and they have really exploded
in the last couple of weeks I did use
some LST and I have lots of exposed bud
sites so he said he's done some low
stress training I'm not sure exactly
what he's done but he's done a little
bit of training the plants aren't very
big but they're taking off now that they
are in flower that is very common so
you've probably had them long enough
they've reached their age where the
hormones have developed and they have
triggered themselves into flower
they are flowering so far in this email
everything seems okay but there is more
it says anyway my question is this I
have been using too
of Cheaper LEDs which I got from Amazon
after listening to your podcast I have
decided to do a veg and flower room and
the cheaper LEDs are going to veg room
and my new hlg 600 h LED should be here
tomorrow so he's ordered a horticultural
lighting group 600 H LED and by the time
we're reading this message on the show
it has arrived hopefully he's got it
hung up hopefully I'm not too late
hopefully I have still got some useful
information for you in this episode so
you've got your h LG 600 you say this
light is supposed to replace a 1000 watt
DE which means a double-ended bulb
I don't know the par of my current
lights but I know what the power of the
h LG 600 are supposed to be and they
recommend to put the light 24 to 30
inches from the canopy because the par
is so high I obviously don't want to
screw anything up since I am so far
along any suggestions on height to start
at the new lights and what to look for
if the new light was to cause problems
I'd really appreciate everything you
have helped me with so far
keep the grow podcasts coming and then
he signs his name hey thank you for the
great email I promise to keep the grow
lessons coming let's focus on this new
grow light question you've probably
already got the light it is probably
already hung up you've probably already
got the plants underneath there and you
were probably already doing a wonderful
job it sounds like you were thinking and
you know that you need to pay attention
so you probably paid close attention to
the plants and you saw how they reacted
and you adjusted accordingly let me tell
you what I would have recommended had I
read this email before you got your
light delivered I would assume and hope
that your new light is quite a bit more
powerful than your old light so you are
absolutely correct in thinking that you
may need to hang that light a little bit
higher than the previous light was hung
so if the light that was in there before
was let's say 1618 inches above the
canopy this one you're gonna want to
start off maybe 24 maybe 30 inches away
from the canopy you say that they
recommend 24 to 30 inches from the
canopy I would start off at least that
far run the light at full power and pay
close attention one of the things I
should recommend you make sure to do is
to keep this light on the exact same
cycle which your old light was on if
you're on a flowering phase
stay at that flowering phase don't
change anything you're running Auto
flowers keep that light cycle the same
so that you don't disrupt anything so
that we don't have multiple variables to
mess up our experiment so that we can
see what is happening from the new light
so hang a blue light pay close attention
to it you need a thermometer and a
hydrometer in this environment so we can
see if that new light is heating up the
room or if it is drying out the room or
causing excessive humidity you've got a
new light in there we need to pay
attention to what happens in the
environment we also need to pay close
attention to the plants you asked what
we could watch for for these plants to
see if they were frustrated we want to
pay attention to the heat if they get
too hot they will start to make what I
call taco leaves normally the leaves
should be basically flat if they start
to curl up you'll see it when you see a
taco leaf you'll go oh that's what he
meant it starts to make like a canoe the
middle of the leaf goes a little lower
the outer edges come up higher
that leaf you could almost pour water in
there and it would sit right inside of
that leaf it makes a taco or a canoe
that is a sign of too much heat if you
were getting that you've got too much
heat you can use your thermometer and
that indicator right there on the plants
to see if the heat has increased to a
level that has made that plant
uncomfortable if so you need to lower
the heat in there that is obviously the
solution there now the thing we want to
focus on after worrying about the heat
is do we have too much light on our
plants did we just increase the light to
a level that makes them uncomfortable
keep an eye on the leaves of the plant
do they start drooping do they start
pointing straight up those are
indicators of how happy your plants are
if the leaves begin to droop throughout
your cycle that means they have reached
their daily light integral and they
simply can't take any more light and
they have put themselves to sleep you
may see those leaves just start to droop
a little bit that is natural they're
taking a nap they're going to bed it is
nap time they're gonna start doing their
nighttime stuff they've had enough for
the day you may be able to reduce your
light cycle if you see that you may be
able to reduce it by an hour or so if
your light is intense enough if your new
light is giving off enough increased
intensity your plants may be reaching
their daily light integral earlier than
they did before because they're
receiving so much light so pay attention
to the leaf if it starts to droop maybe
an hour before you're used to that is
fine that's expected that's getting
enough light it is tired
it's trying to take a nap it's going to
bed a little bit early that is an
indicator that you may be able to adjust
that light cycle I am NOT an auto flower
grower I do not know enough about Auto
flowers to know if you should adjust
your light to adjust to those plants
that is not my expertise I don't know if
you will answer your questions the
person I think of when I say Auto
flowers is mephisto genetics that is who
I would recommend and suggest and all
things Auto flower so take your auto
flower questions to Mephisto he may be
able to give you more details on that
but let's talk about this light because
I do understand this part the first
thing you're gonna see is leaves
drooping or leaves pointing up you need
to pay attention to the leaves if they
start drooping away early that means
that you are giving it too much light I
mean like within an hour of putting on
putting the light above those plants
they should not droop if you see them
droop that means they are getting too
much light and they're frustrated over a
couple of days if your leaves begin to
twist that means they are getting too
much light and they are pissed off too
much light is kind of a rare thing I
don't know that you can do it with an
indoor light setup you're going from an
LED to an LED your plants should be
excited about this they should be happy
with it I would put that light up there
and pay attention to them hang it as
high as you can get it within reason
start off it says 25 let's see it says
24 to 30 inches above the canopy start
at 36 inches run it for two hours see
what the plants do check on the humidity
check on the temperature see if
everything is right while we're at six
inches pay attention to the plants run
it for a couple of hours like that keep
an eye on the plants you're the one that
knows those plants you should be able to
see how they are reacting you've been
working with these plants for their
entire veg phase plus two weeks of
flower now you should have a good idea
of what these plants look like in the
morning when they wake up you should
know what these plants look like in the
mid-afternoon when you do your afternoon
check and you should know what the
plants look like when it is almost
bedtime when you do the before bed check
on your plants so keep those things in
mind and compare that to how the plant
is reacting with this new light the main
things you're gonna watch for is the
leaves are the leaves drooping are they
falling off do the plants look sad does
it look over watered does it start to
curl downward or upward those are signs
of too much light
now if the whole tip top of the plant
starts bending over it is trying to get
away from the light it is cooking you
definitely need to raise the light or
reduce
power at that point I think since you're
going from led to an improved LED your
plants are going to be happy they're
going to like it the things you need to
pay close attention to are the leaves
the next thing to think about is the VPD
in that room
have you changed the VPD by changing the
light I bet you are getting a whole
different temperature you're getting a
different humidity you were getting a
lot of different changes that you're
going to re need to dial that room in
you need to readjust all of your climate
controls if possible another thing you
can do is grab those plants and see what
they feel like what is the leaf surface
temperature in your garden do the plants
feel cold do they feel too hot do you
see the plants physically sweating if
they are sweating they're too hot they
need to be separated you don't want them
touching in there that's a whole nother
subject but you can tell by looking at
the plants how they are liking or hating
this new light if they are drooping if
they look angry they obviously don't
like the new light if over a couple of
days the leaves start to twist and curl
they absolutely do not like this new
light I think like I said before since
you went from an LED to an upgraded LED
these plants should be happy start out
about 36 inches give them a couple of
hours drop it down to the 30 mark give
it a couple of hours see how they react
maybe go to 24 inches see how they react
if you don't see any adverse reactions
maybe go a little lower
I don't know how low you want to go with
the LEDs I don't know where there are
there's a distance where you kind of it
becomes a point of diminishing returns
when you get your plants too close to
the bulb because that super-intense
coming off of AB light bulb there isn't
even usable by the plants you got to
back it up to make it usable so
experiment that is the best way to learn
start off too high work your way down
get too low watch the plants react to it
if you start seeing what I call they get
their nails done just the tips of the
leaves start to look like [ __ ] that is a
good sign that you are giving them too
much light now what will happen if you
continue to develop buds the buds will
get bigger they'll grow into the light
then those tips of the buds will start
to bleach themselves we've seen that in
a few magazines when it just looks like
a little white tip on the top of the bud
or the top of the bud is just bleached
that is from the plant being exposed to
too much light during the flowering
cycle it simply bleached the chlorophyll
out of the plant
and that can absolutely happen with your
LEDs I don't think you're going to have
a problem I'm looking at this light
right now on the website this is a great
light this is a high quality light
hlg if i can get you to send me one of
these what do we have here at hlg 600h i
would gladly replace one of my thousand
watt HBS lights i would run it side by
side and we can see what's your h LG 600
versus my current HP s setup does i
would love to work with you let's do
that I'm just throwing out a shameless
plug through the podcaster this does
look like a wonderful light it is a
quite pricy light but it is going to
save you money in electricity and in
cooling costs I think you are going to
love this light congratulations on the
great purchase I really hope this does a
great upgrade for your grow room
you just turbocharged your whole setup
since you had the forethought to ask
this question I think you were going to
be right on top of paying attention to
your plants and knowing if they have
gotten too close to the light I think
you were already for thinking you were
prepared and you know what to look for I
hope I gave you enough helpful advice
Tory you don't burn your plants let me
know how it goes by the time this
episode comes out you have got this
light it is hung up the plants are under
there and it is rocking give me an
update pictures or it didn't happen hey
I want to thank you for the great email
I do appreciate listenor generated
content I hope I was able to help you
out also thank you because you've
inspired me to research LED lighting
just a little bit more between this
message and all of the talk about h LG
lighting on the dude Gro show I may have
to reach out to those folks and see if
we can't do some work together all right
ladies and gentlemen my throat and my
voice are done podcasting today so I
want to thank you for hanging out for
another episode of the growth from your
heart podcast I'll be back Thursday with
fresh new content don't forget to check
out the patreon page at patreon.com
slash grow from your heart don't forget
to stalk me on all of the social media
there is Facebook there is Twitter and
on Instagram I use Irie underscore
genetics so check me out there feel free
to send me an email I encourage emails
my email address is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com I can't wait to hear from
you don't forget about the YouTube
channel go to youtube search for the
drove from your heart podcast click on
that big red subscribe button leave some
comments on the videos let me know what
you think about the show I would love to
hear from you don't forget to visit our
friends at organ elite seeds you can
find them at Oregon elite seeds com
I'm gonna give you a huge shout out to
my friend pulsar and until next time
take a phat dab and give your mom a hug
for me
you