hey welcome back podcast world it is
time for episode 424 of the grow from
your heart podcast this episode of the
show is brought to you by our friends at
Oregon elite seeds if you need new
regular feminized or Auto flower seeds
in your garden I highly recommend Oregon
elite seeds and you can find them at
www.ctvn.org forms the potency label
says this product has seventy six point
three percent THC zero percent CBD and
eighty seven point five percent total
cannabinoids I'm gonna crack this jar
open and give it a fresh smell this
concentrate smells amazing it is funky
it is sweet it is sour it is almost like
a grapefruit if you have ever drank a
product called a grapefruit Izzy in my
opinion this smells just like a fresh
cold grapefruit Izzy I can almost smell
the carbonation in here I really enjoy
the flavour and aroma on this product
and the high goes straight to my head it
makes me chattery it gets me creative
and talkative so that is perfect podcast
concentrate it leaves a really great
kind of a sweet and sour sort of a candy
flavor in my mouth which is really
Pleasant so big shout out again to our
friends at apothecary farms for the
delicious Tropicana cookies full
spectrum extract in this episode I do
plan to read a couple of emails I've got
another submission about what 4/20 means
to you before we get there let's do some
shout outs to our friends from patreon I
want to give a huge shout out to miss
Melville how about a giant shout out to
richard memo a giant shout out to keith
kay a big girl from your heart podcast
shout out to Grimble to druid as always
the giant shout out to my friend riley a
big girl from your heart podcast shout
out to Paul tea and of course a shout
out to my friend David o Q I want to
thank each and every one of you for your
patreon support if you would like to
learn how to become a patron you can do
so by going to patreon.com slash grow
from your heart all the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and one more time I want to send a huge
thank you to everybody who is
contributed to the patreon campaign I do
appreciate all of
support and please don't feel bad don't
feel excluded if you cannot help out on
patreon I do appreciate the support but
I just appreciate you for listening I
don't expect anything from you
I don't ask anything of you I just
appreciate you for listening and
enjoying the show so big shout out to
you also thank you for being here
all right podcast world I did say that
I've got a couple of emails to read for
this episode so let's jump right into
that part if you've got a question that
you would like me to read on the show
you can send me an email my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com you know I would love to
hear from you our first email for this
episode goes just like this hey Rasta
Jeff my name is Mike and I'm from
prohibition land first off I want to say
thank you for what you do you know you
help people but honestly you probably
have no clue how much you do help hey
that means a lot to me man I appreciate
hearing that I'm helping somebody that
means a lot to me that's what the show
is for so just knowing that I'm helping
you means a lot I've honestly never
thought about how far my show reaches I
know I get a lot of comments I know I
get a lot of emails I get a lot of
interaction but I'm really not sure
exactly how much help I am providing so
thank you that means a lot to me just to
know that I'm probably reaching further
than I had realized is a great
compliment and a great little boost so
thank you I'm gonna continue with the
email that goes on to say when I decided
to email you my question I just plan to
email you and ask you the question but
you asked on your show what 4/20 means
to me I know it's a little bit late and
I'm not saying this because of a contest
but when 4/20 means to me is seeing my
mom smile so let me explain so what this
email is referring to right here is a
few episodes before 4/20 I started
asking my audience for submissions to
tell me what 4/20 means to you so this
guy is a little bit late for the 4/20
episode but I still want to hear his
opinion and I still want to share his
4/20 story with you and what 4/20 means
to him so let's continue with the
message it goes like this again I am in
prohibition land right now in the Bible
Belt so growing up my mom was a
schoolteacher and of course we all grew
up with the impression that cannabis was
the devil so as a teenager when she
found out I smoked cannabis
she was pissed but even worse she was
disappointed in me
oh that phrase right there have you ever
had a parent say I'm not mad at you but
I'm disappointed in you that's just
that's the worst I'd rather somebody be
[ __ ] mad at me cuz I [ __ ] up when
you feel I'm disappointed in you
I'm not even mad I'm just disappointed
that makes you feel like [ __ ] as a
person that makes you feel about two
inches tall it just makes you feel so
weak
you're like ah you know they're only a
couple of people you really want to make
happy in the world and when you're
younger it's your mom and your dad and
when one of them says I'm disappointed
oh that is [ __ ] everything up so I get
you even worse she was disappointed in
me so let's fast forward I am 36 now
when I was 31 my mom was diagnosed with
severe rheumatoid arthritis and that is
painful and miserable and I'm sorry to
hear that the message says little did I
know what my mother was about to go
through
absolutely RA is miserable to experience
and it is almost as miserable watching
someone you love experience those sort
of symptoms you can almost see the pain
in their hands you can almost see the
pain in their joints when they walk if
you know that person you have seen them
go from a healthy person to a person who
hurts and that's just terrible to see so
let's keep going with the message it
says within four years my mom had both
of her hips and both of her shoulders
replaced from her joints flattening that
sounds painful
then shortly after she was diagnosed
with severe COPD and congestive heart
failure the doctor told my mom that she
had two choices he could prescribe her
opioid pain meds and she would be on
them for the rest of her life and if she
went a day without them basically god
bless her soul the other option was
taking drugs that killed her immune
system so she would get sick easily and
the sickness would get really bad
because her body can't fight it off
naturally so she picked the opioid meds
because it honestly was the safer option
man she didn't have much to choose from
she had crap or a crap and it sounds
like she picked the less crappy crap man
I'm sorry to hear that your mom and your
family are in this type of situation as
if the RA weren't enough then she had to
have surgeries then she ends up with
COPD which is a chronic obstructive
pulmonary disorder which makes it hard
to breathe and you feel like you're
drowning constantly and she's also got
congestive heart failure it sounds like
she's having a string of bad luck then
we've got her on opioid pain medicine
which can't turn out well for her so
let's keep reading it says since we are
in Indiana there is no medical cannabis
so she had no other option than to wipe
out her immune system or just literally
suffer my mom being my mom she just quit
the pain meds and suffered and that is
that's a strong lady right there for two
years she couldn't sleep or walk without
groaning every step because it hurts so
badly she is on oxygen and she can't
smoke any good edible is impossible to
get around here you can get butter
someone made and I'm not even sure is
real but one day my buddy came back from
vacation from Cali and brought edible
gummy bears me being me I had to buy
some and try them I ate two of them that
night and I woke up the next morning
sitting in my recliner with a bowl of
melted ice cream spilled all over my lap
all right so it sounds like the gummy
bears worked you ate two of them they
put you out while you were eating ice
cream you woke up with ice cream all
over your lap dude imagine how asleep
this guy had to be if cold ice cream I
know it was melted but it still wasn't
warm and it was spilled in his lap on
his junk imagine how soundly this guy
was sleep and those gummy bears were
working let's continue with the email it
says so I decide I'm gonna make my mom
try one alright so this guy's mom was a
teacher she was anti cannabis she was
not mad at him she was disappointed when
she discovered that this person was a
cannabis consumer so this guy is going
to try to give his mom one of these
cannabis infused gummy bears so let's
jump back into the email it says I game
planned all day how I was gonna bring it
up to her and had built up the level of
balls to actually offer my 60 year old
ex school teacher mom cannabis which
isn't even legal here so finally I go
over there the next evening and I just
drop it on her I told her I have
something I think will help her sleep
she asked what and I told her and what
happened next blew my mind
so this guy finally got the balls he
drove over there and he said mom I got
something I think is gonna help you and
what happened next is going to blow our
minds because she told me she has wanted
to try it and has been reading about it
but didn't figure she would ever be able
to get any because of their location so
she snatched the gummy bear out of my
hand and couldn't chew it up fast enough
that's pretty cool that your mom was not
only open to the idea but she had been
excited and researching the idea herself
that shows you what pain and suffering
will do to you when you were in pain
long enough and nothing works and you've
got enough things making you
uncomfortable and you've tried something
and it just made you even worse then
will open your mind you may say you know
what I think I'm ready to try just about
anything so that opened this lady's mind
she was ready to try some cannabis she
snatched up this gummy bear she chewed
it up I want to read more into this it
says I lived 30 minutes away from her
and a different City but my brother was
taking care of her that night so I went
home the next day my mom calls me and
tells me she got the best sleep she has
had since she got RA even better than
with any pills my bro said she was
walking to the bathroom without groaning
in pain and was even walking faster than
regular so this lady ate one cannabis
infused gummy bear I don't know how many
milligrams it was I don't know the
potency I don't know the THC CBD ratio
ahh it doesn't seem that that matters
too much because it worked it helped
improve the quality of this young lady's
life her rheumatoid arthritis is not
debilitating her because cannabis eased
up the symptoms enough for her to walk
to the bathroom without groaning imagine
if something you have to do multiple
times a day like simply walk to the
bathroom everybody has to do that you
got to get there somehow
you got to either roll over there you
got to crawl over there you got to walk
over there you can do cartwheels you've
got to get there if you're gonna take a
piss you've got to get there or you get
to wallow around in your own piss all
day imagine if that was painful
just getting up right now to go piss it
hurts my back hurts my hips hurt my
knees hurt it takes effort I have to
grunt and groan
sound like this Oh Oh I'm just trying to
get up imagine if your pain felt like
that and you found something that you
could eat and it would take your pain
away enough to order you don't groan
you're still gonna hurt you're still
gonna have some some aches and pains
some discomfort but if you could just
take that one level up oh I just tone
that down take that off of it you are
improving the quality of your life and
for that not to be allowed because of
some invisible line that separates
States from states and legality from
legality that is [ __ ] stupid this
lady feels better because she ate
something that came off of a plant that
grows out of the ground and the law is
trying to stop that from happening all
right I'm getting way off track let's
get back on track here there is more to
this message it says the problem is I
can't barely get edibles here I've
gotten edibles three more times since
that people have brought from legal
states and every time I get and give
them to my mom she gets the biggest
smile on her face
because she knows she's going to get
some relief and some sleep again that
invisible line that prevents people from
getting relief and sleep is [ __ ]
ridiculous in my mind there's more to
this email and it says even though it is
just a few hours of a break it means
everything to her oh yeah I'm sure
that's like setting down weights that
you've been carrying all day like pain
is terrible pain will put you in a bad
mood pain will make you depressed pain
will make you not able to enjoy your
life so that few hours of relief is
everything to her that is the best few
hours of her month probably when she
gets to eat that edible 3045 minutes
after it kicks in that is the best time
of her month so I can imagine that she
gets a big smile on her face even though
it is just a few hours he says we will
be lucky to have her with us for another
year so I can't think of anything better
that I could give her at this point in
her life
wow that is a bold finishing sentence
right there you'll be lucky to have her
with you for another year oh man I'm
glad you have found something to keep
her comfortable for this year I am
saddened to hear that you've only got
her for another year please enjoy that
year with her I can't encourage you to
acquire edibles in your illegal State I
can't do anything to help you out but
man I hope that somehow you were able
to keep mom heavily medicated I hope
you're able to spend a lot of time with
her I just enjoy her while she's here
and keep her as comfortable as you
possibly can he wraps up this portion of
the message and it says so that is what
4/20 means to me dude that is a serious
heavy deep 4/20 message I appreciate
that thank you for sharing so much with
me we got a lot of really serious really
deep
what does 4/20 mean to you submissions
and I appreciate that thank you to
everybody for opening up so much to me
to the audience for the show for the
sake of cannabis thank you now there is
a second half to this email this is the
question portion and it goes a lot like
this but here is my question
since the cannabis here is all shitty
schwag Mexican brick [ __ ] I've
decided I'm going to grow or hopefully
grow some quality cannabis to make
edibles for my mom like I said earlier I
can't encourage condone or promote you
doing anything illegal but you're an
adult so you're responsible for yourself
and I am proud of you for taking action
to take care of your mom I will continue
with the message and it says I know
hydro isn't the smartest way for a noob
but from what I understand it is quicker
I'm also going to grow three plants in
soil in case I [ __ ] up the hydro but I
have studied a lot more on soil growing
all right so let's talk about one
statement here in that first paragraph
he says I know hydro is it the smartest
for a new but from what I understand it
is quicker your plants will grow more
quickly you may be able to cut off seven
to ten days of your veg time depending
on how big you want your plants but it's
not going to go so much more quickly
than it's going to save you a lot of
time especially in a small home grow
you're probably going to be running
small plants one or two weeks at the
very most is all you're going to save
and a hydro setup and it's going to take
you a couple of runs to get that dialed
in so yes they may grow more quickly you
may see more productivity in a hydro
system but it is going to take more
detail it is going to take more work you
have to pay much more attention you'll
also notice that the plants in soil are
much more forgiving than the plants in
your hydro system if you mess up with
your soil crop you
can rescue it if you make a small
mistake in your hydroponic setup you
will notice it and it may be hard to
recover so soil is much more forgiving
now talking about being faster it is
going to take the same amount of time to
flower if you were in soil soilless mix
hydro whatever you're growing in
whatever your setup is if your plant
takes nine weeks to flower it's going to
take nine weeks to flower you can't make
you go faster because of your medium so
yes in theory your hydroponic plant will
grow a little more quickly it'll have
more vigor it may get larger but it also
is more work it takes a lot more
attention to detail and if you mess up
it is much harder to correct your
mistake it sounds like you've got a
great idea you're going to run a few
plants in hydro you're going to run a
few plants in soil I'm really hoping
that you're going to run the same
cultivar in each setup so that you can
pay attention to what's going on and not
be confused by different plants reacting
differently what I mean by that is in
your hydroponic setup and your soil
setup I hope you've got golden goat in
hydro and golden goat in soil and not
golden goat in soil and [ __ ] blue
dream in hydro because those are two
different plants are going to grow two
different ways it is much easier to have
one plant and learn that one plant I've
talked about that in previous episodes
this is just my suggestion again you're
a grown-ass man or a grown-ass woman or
a grown-ass non-binary gender - dolt
do whatever you want to do hashtag
America but I would suggest one cultivar
I would try to run the same thing
especially as a new grower running
multiple setups you can learn a lot this
way you've got an opportunity to learn a
lot about one specific cultivar so if
you can get six clones or eight clones
of one thing and plant them in your
hydro and in your soil and then you have
some room for experiments with each one
within each setup you can learn a lot of
things that is basically like having two
grows that you can experiment on at the
same time but I again highly suggest one
cultivar I do know that you're in
prohibition land so you're going to have
to get whatever you get you may not have
access to clones I don't know how you
feel about ordering seeds online it
doesn't sound like you're going to do a
female hunt it sounds like you're ready
just to get Starr
so once you get clones or seeds I assume
you're going to just pop some in these
pots and get started I would suggest
doing a quick phyno hunt I've done
episodes on Fino hunting before I would
do a quick phyno hunt find a keeper and
then clone that cultivar and run it
throughout all of your systems learn
that cultivar learn your systems and get
that dialed in if you're interested in
listening to the pheno hunt episode I
did an entire talk about Fino hunting on
episode 376 so I suggest starting with a
Fino hunt narrow it down to one keeper
then work that one keeper and all
systems that is my idea for what I would
do if I were you
alright there is more to this email so I
need to get my rambley ass back on track
big shot at again to the Tropicana
cookies full-spectrum extract it really
got me talkative for this episode there
is more it says my question is this and
it relates to both soil and hydro I
always hear you talk about reverse
osmosis or filtered water being the best
to use how about pH rain water would
that be good to use to put your nuts in
and water your soil plants or to run in
your deep water culture reservoir I'm
just wondering because I went to Walmart
and I have a 20 gallon rez ro water was
six dollars and fifty cents for five
gallons so if I go that route I'll be
spending thirty two dollars a week just
on water if rainwater isn't good is
there a cheaper option rain water is
acceptable rain water will contain trace
minerals just be careful in most regions
rain water should be safe if you live in
a really densely if you live in China
you may reconsider that if you've got a
lot of pollution a lot of fog you may
reconsider most areas you should be okay
one thing to think about when you were
collecting rainwater how are you
gathering it is that water running off
of something before it gets to your
collection vessel is it coming off of
the tin roof which may have rust on it
which may have other stuff on it
just think about where that water is
running before it ends up in your
collection vessel and it should be safe
to feed to your plants of course add
your nutrients then adjust the pH you're
gonna want to put nutrients in it then
adjust the pH before feeding it to the
plants don't adjust the pH then put
newts in it because you're going to have
to adjust the pH once again so nutrients
pH
check your EC and your ppm and then feed
it to the plants if you were in the
acceptable ranges there is a follow-up
question it says also what is the best
temperature to keep my water in my res
I'm reading everything from 55 to 72
degrees thanks again for what you do you
can use my name and location on the show
if you wish
maybe someone important will hear it and
change these BS laws here so my mother
can get the relief she so desperately
needs and deserves
best wishes bro and then he sends a fist
bump hey thanks for the great message
man I hope that somebody realizes that
cannabis is helping your mother improve
the quality of her life and they will
help change those [ __ ] laws that we
talked about so let's address this
question he said what is the best
temperature to keep the water in my
reservoir I'm going to say somewhere
between 62 and 68 degrees is the best
range to keep the temperature of the
water in your reservoir any colder than
that the plants will start slowing down
they won't take up any nutrients the
metabolism will start slowing down their
plants will actually think that it is
becoming wintertime if you are not
flowering the plants they may try to
flower they may try to start finishing
and ripening up because that's what they
think is time for they think oh it's
cold winter is coming it is time to
finish up so somewhere between 62 and 68
degrees would be your ideal temperature
to keep your plants in their most
vigorous state of growth alright that
was a long great email I want to thank
you for the great message big shout out
to my new friend Mike out there in
Hoosier country hey Mike I hope you and
your mom are both doing wonderfully
alright podcasts world I know I said at
the start of the show I had two emails
to read that one email got away from me
I got a little rambling a little
long-winded because of these Tropicana
cookies dabs so that means there is only
one email on this episode which means
I've got a lot of great content for
future episodes I want to thank
everybody for listening I'll be back
Monday with a long full length podcast
if you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
and you would like to make a financial
contribution to the show you can do so
by going to patreon.com slash grow from
your heart all the information you need
to become a patron will be right there
on the screen once again
big shout out and big thank you to
everybody who has helped out in the
patreon campaign in the past in the
present and in the future if you can't
contribute financially and you would
like to support the show you can do so
by clicking on all of my social media
accounts follow me on Facebook simply
search for the growth from your heart
podcast find me on Twitter it's @gf wih
podcast and on instagram i use my other
company name i use re underscore
genetics on instagram check me out
I read genetics on Instagram I post
cannabis photography I do Instagram live
videos every Monday I go on Instagram
and I talk about growing cannabis I
answer grow questions I take questions
from my friends I try to do my best to
answer the questions live on the feed
with no research so jump in every Monday
at 7:10 Mountain time shoot me a
question maybe I'll answer your question
right there in the live feed I look
forward to meeting you if you've got
something you'd like to say you're not
into all of that social media madness
you can send me an email my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I love the listener
generated content don't forget about the
YouTube channel simply search for the
growth from your heart podcast on
YouTube click Subscribe leave some
comments on some videos let me know what
you think of the show don't forget to
visit our sponsor organ meats you can
find them at www.ctvn.org give a huge
shout out to my friend bagsied jesse and
until next time take a phat dab and give
your mom a hug for me