welcome to the show podcast world it is
time for episode 426 of the crow from
your heart podcast this episode of the
show is brought to you by my friends at
Oregon elite seeds it is time to add
fresh new genetics to your garden you've
been growing that same old [ __ ] for way
too long everybody's tired of that [ __ ]
you need to update your grow you need
some fresh new varieties in your grow
tent if you're ready for new feminized
or regular seeds I highly recommend
Oregon elite seeds and you can find them
at www.opm.gov/openseason de kadam inant
the potency label says this contains
68.8% THC and eighty 2.3 percent total
cannabinoids I'm gonna crack it open and
give it a fresh smell so I can describe
it properly for you the first thing I
should mention is the appearance and
texture of this concentrate there is a
perfect amount of chunky diamonds and a
beautiful amount of saucy Terp sauce in
this container the color is the perfect
golden color that I expect the Terps are
not too runny the crystals are not too
big or too small
I really approve of the consistency of
this product this is a great batch of
concentrate here I'm gonna give it a
smell that's what I opened it up for all
right at the first smell you get some
gas with the background of pine and then
as it sits on your nose and you let it
sit by your face for a little bit it
starts kicking in a little bit of a
skunky aroma I really do enjoy that type
of a concentrate that type of flavor and
aroma that classic OG Kush kind of a
skunky earthy sort of a thing going on
there's a really great aroma and flavor
coming from this product but again what
I really like is the size of the chunky
diamonds and the amount of diamonds
compared to the amount of Terp sauce
what happens in a lot of saucy live
resin ambrosia there are a lot of
different names for these types of
products but what happens to a lot of
these products is sometimes you'll get a
really big diamond and a little bit of
Terp sauce in there or sometimes you'll
get a whole bunch of Terp sauce and very
little diamonds in there sometimes it's
hard to work with something that is all
Terp sauce you can't really get it on
the dabber you can't take a satisfying
dab of it
sometimes they give you a giant boulder
of the diamonds in the middle and barely
any Terp sauce and you need some of the
Terps I do like the diamonds the most
because that's the potency but I think
the Terps are important
without the Terps it's not the same so I
really like it when there's a good ratio
and these guys did a very good job at
the ratio of Terp sauce to diamonds and
the diamonds aren't too big or too small
so really great consistency this has
been one of my favorite concentrates
that I've gotten most recently so big
shout out once again to our friends at
apothecary farms for the Larry og indica
dominant ambrosia that's a lot of words
for a product but that is the strain
name and that of course the ambrosia is
their proprietary product go check it
out you guys make sure you tell them
Rasta Jeff sent you alright in this
episode I'm going to read a couple of
iTunes customer reviews and maybe a
couple of emails if we get there before
we get to that part let's give a few
shoutouts to our friends from patreon I
want to give a huge grow from your heart
podcast shout out to my friend Isaac of
course and grow from your heart podcast
shout it to our buddy Tommy always a big
shout out to our buddy Keith Kay a brand
new shout out to our friend sour Dee of
course another shot of two our friend
Eric Ross as always a giant shout out to
Paul T and of course a big grow from
your heart podcast Irie army shatta to
my good friend stabby
makes stab erson I do appreciate all of
the patreon support if you would like to
learn how to become a patron you can do
so by going to patreon.com slash grow
from your heart all the information you
need to become a patron will be right
there on the screen once again big
thanks to everybody who has contributed
to the patreon campaign in the past in
the present and in the future
all right podcast world at the start of
the show I said I was going to read some
iTunes customer ratings and reviews
let's get right into that part of the
podcast if you would like to leave a
review on iTunes it is really easy if
you were listening on an Apple device
such as an iPhone or an iPad it is
really easy to leave a review go to the
podcast app just like you want to listen
to the show click on the show just like
you're gonna listen to it then you will
see a list of available episodes scroll
right past the available episodes it
will say best of the podcast then it
will say ratings and reviews that gives
you the option to
app to rate you get the option of one
through five stars give me as many stars
as you feel I deserve then right
underneath there is a tab that says
write a review that is where you were
able to write a review and share your
opinion of the podcast with the Apple
iTunes community so if you are listening
on an Apple device I encourage you to
please leave a review let's jump right
into the reviews for this episode
the first iTunes customer rating and
review for this episode was left on
where are we April 18th 2019 it was left
by somebody who calls themselves banana
boy 53 the headline says easy to digest
information and they gave us a five-star
rating the customer review goes like
this hey man I love the show I'm not
officially a grower yet but I hope to be
soon I love listening to you and your
buddies sit around bullshitting as well
as the information you all give out keep
up the good work and shout out to white
Mike so this guy is not yet a grower he
plans to grow in the future he's
listening to the show to get his
prerequisites under his belt so that
when it comes time to grow some plants
he actually has a solid foundation so I
really do enjoy that I thanks for
listening he says he likes listening to
my buddies and I sit around in [ __ ]
which that's a lot of fun I'm glad
people are enjoying that and he enjoys
the information so I'm hitting my target
I love knowing that I'm hitting my
target and reaching my goal so thank you
for that great review then he goes on to
say keep up the great work
and shout out to white Mike hey white
Mike you got another shout out dude that
means you need to come be on the show
soon hey banana boy 53 thank you for the
great review and of course thank you for
the 5-star rating let's get into the
next review this one says got to meet
Rasta Jeff they gave us a 5 star rating
it is from our friend Casey penny they
left it on April 18th and the review
goes a lot like this I go by the name of
Casey Benny and a recent astrological
phenomenon seems to have lined
everything up to make it possible for me
to not only come to Denver for the first
time in my life but I was also able to
attend the fable that dude grows cup and
meet Rasta Jeff there man I'm so glad
you made it that's awesome that you
think it was an astrological phenomenon
I think is just fate and the way things
were supposed to go
I'm glad you made it I'm glad you made
it to the dude grows cup if you don't
know what the dude grows cup was there's
another podcast that I encourage you to
listen to it is called the dude grows
show it is hosted by a guy known as the
dude also hosted by his buddy named
Scotty real they've got a producer named
guru who does a wonderful job he
contributes heavily to the show they
have a great podcast with a very loyal
following as do i they threw an event in
Denver that was called the dude grows
cup it was kind of a community base to
grow off kind of an event where a lot of
people came together from all over the
country we got to show off our products
we got to enjoy each other's company we
got to educate each other and mainly
just hang out and smoke down and enjoy
the community that has been created
around the dude grow show so that's what
the dude grows cup was our friend was
able to come out and hang out and he got
to meet me there so there's more to this
revue it says Rasta Jeff was the coolest
vendor at the cup hey that means a lot
to me man thank you we did have kind of
a party going on at my booth the entire
time they got a little bit crowded over
there so that was a lot of fun I goes on
to say it seemed that the other seed
vendors were not priced with love my man
Jeff hooked me up with five packs of
seeds for the price of one pack from
some of the other guys and one pack was
a 10 pack because he was out of five
packs
I actually remember this I gave you a 10
pack of hellfire OG because I'd ran out
of five packs yes many of this seed
companies there are higher priced than
myself that's not a tacit anybody that's
just how it is my seed packs are more
friendly priced than many of the other
seed companies out there you'll also
notice that I've got a smaller crew than
everybody they've got more people to pay
for they've got more stuff to cover I
keep my overheads small that allows me
to keep my pricing down also I want
everybody to have access to quality
seeds that's part of why I started
breeding part of why I started putting
seeds out there I want them to be
affordable there's no reason why
everybody shouldn't be able to afford
quality seeds and that's what I offer is
a quality seed at an affordable price
it's a just as good as the other
expensive seeds just everybody can
afford it you don't have to feel like
you're breaking the bank you don't have
to feel like you're gonna go broke deep
in digging too deep into your pockets to
get started so I do appreciate it that
you notice that my stuff is a little bit
more affordable and yes you asked for
my pack is something I didn't have a
fiver I wanted to make sure you got the
seeds you needed so I gave you a 10 for
the price of a 5 that's what we could do
gotta take care of the people it goes on
to say they all had more than 5 in the
packs yes that's also something I do I
tend to put 6 or 7 seeds in the 5 packs
the 10 packs will have 12 to 14 seeds
and I'm quite often that's just how I do
it when I can he goes on to say it was
so cool to meet Jeff and the cup was the
best party I've been to since my wedding
hey my friend I remember you I remember
this interaction it was great meeting
you I look forward to seeing you at the
next dude grows cup event which will be
on 713 and cultivated synergy the same
exact place where we had the last event
I don't have a lot of details and a lot
of information right now everything is
still being being put together and still
being worked out but there is another
dude grows 710 event on 713 at
cultivated synergy I will keep you
updated as often as I can if you want
up-to-date information
I suggest listening to the dude grows
podcast it's a great show
I feel no sense of competition those are
friends of mine it is all a community I
want everybody to grow the highest
quality cannabis that they can grow and
if you can get more information by
listening to the dude and Scottie and
guru why not do it so listen to my
friends the dude grows podcast and join
us at the dude grows 7/10 event
Casey Benny thanks again for the great
review and of course thank you for the 5
stars
and again bro I look forward to seeing
you in July let's move forward I've got
another review the headline for this one
says Rasta Jeff and the Irie army kicks
butt they gave us 5 stars
this one is from a person who calls
themselves daddy-o 45 they left this
review on April 29th and the review goes
a lot like this that was one kick butt
show on autoflowering and moving plants
back and forth from indoors and outdoors
a lot of good information so he's
talking about a recent episode I did
where I talked about moving plants from
an indoor grow room putting them
outdoors to get some sunshine and
bringing them back in at the end of the
day to keep them in a flowering cycle I
kind of recommend it not to do that
because of the simple fact of bringing
bugs into the grow room so that's what
they're referring to there I'm glad you
liked that episode
I love knowing that my advice is landing
on somebody who is using it sometimes
you give out advice and you're like I
don't even know if anybody needs this
information or if anybody cares but when
I know it's working for you that means a
lot to me it lets me know that the
effort I made actually did something for
somebody so thank you that means a lot
he goes on to say plus thanks for
reading my email it was kind of scary
but so freeing thank you so much I
haven't felt this good since I got my
first good night of sleep well I'm glad
I could put a smile on your face don't
be too scared when I read your email on
there sometimes people get tripped out
because they put their name or whatever
in the email think of it this way if I
say anything about you or anything on
the show
the only people listening are fellow
growers so and they're not gonna know
who you are if I say so my friend bill
has this grow room there are so many
bills on the planet they don't know it's
you bro the only way that people are
gonna know what to you is if you make a
big deal out of it snitch on yourself so
if I ever say your name on the show if I
ever say your nickname on the show
because of an email or something don't
get too paranoid you're the only one
that knows and it's supposed to be for
you anyway you're the one that feels the
pride inside because I said your name
like sour deep we don't know whose sour
tea is we don't know who Keith K is but
Keith K he knows who he is I gave him a
shout-out at the start of the show Keith
K knows exactly who he is there are
thousands of Keith Ches out there a lot
of people are looking over at their
buddy Keith going is that you brother
going wasn't me bro but the one that it
was he's excited inside he feels it so
don't ever feel weird don't ever feel
nervous if I give you a shout-out or say
your name on the show nobody knows but
you bro I'm rambling a [ __ ] today I'm
gonna blame that on our friend caffeine
and also Larry OG ambrosia let's keep
going there is more to this he says one
day I would love to just shake your hand
and say thank you and then he's signed
to the ER the review here with a green
heart emoji and a fist bump emoji hey
that fist bump right there I'm fist bump
in the computer screen right back at you
much respect thank you for the great
review I look forward to one day meeting
you and shaking your hand once again
join me at the dude grows cup on 7:13 I
look forward to seeing you there
alright there is one more review on the
screen let's get into this one this one
was left on May 1st the headline is so
awesome of course they give us a 5 star
rating this one is from a person who
calls themselves how do you say that
Morgan Lucci Morgan lucky
how to say that but I do appreciate the
great review because it goes like this
yo man I just started listening to your
show about two weeks ago hey welcome
aboard then it goes to say I started
from the beginning and I'm already on
episode 107 man you have got a lot to go
and it's kind of embarrassing when
people go listen to that old ship and
I'm glad you're listening I'm glad
you're getting a solid foundation you're
going to see that my growth style and my
approach to growing and my attitude
about some methods and techniques will
change that is acceptable don't be
afraid to change as things evolve but
you will see me evolve and grow so join
me on that journey and thank you for
listening man I'm sure you're probably
up to 200 by now since this was a few
days ago it goes on to say this show
rocks and I appreciate you sharing your
wisdom I will most definitely take it
dad and give my mom a hug for you cheers
mate I'm glad you feel that the show
rocks I hope I'm helping you out you are
very welcome for sharing the wisdom I
feel like I would be cheating or doing
the world some sort of disservice or
being selfish if I didn't share all the
things that I have gathered and learned
along the way so thank you for noticing
and you're very welcome
then he says I'll definitely take a dad
and give my mom a hug so he's following
all the rules this guy's doing it
perfectly thank you for the great review
he ends it out with cheers mate
big cheers thank you for the support I
want to thank everybody for the great
itunes customer reviews once again
everybody left us a five-star rating
which is great I do appreciate that
again if you would like to leave an
iTunes customer review it is really easy
simply open up your Apple device either
your iPhone or your iPad go to the
podcast application if you're not
already subscribed all you have to do is
search for the Grove from your heart
podcast click Subscribe it will show you
the available episodes scroll right past
the available episodes it will give you
the option to leave the amount of stars
which you feel I deserve click on the
amount of stars you feel a spare then
right underneath that is the tab to
click write a review that is where you
can write a review and I will read your
review on a future episode I look
forward to hearing from you ladies and
gentlemen that is all the iTunes
customer reviews for today let's move in
to a quick email this email comes from
our friend Ryan and Ryan ended his email
wit thanks Ryan it's just a first name
bro so
go for it I like that I know that I can
say your name it's not gonna freak
anybody out this email goes a lot like
this hey Jeff I love your show hey
thanks for listening dude the question
is can I vacuum seal my nugs after they
get to the desired ripeness in the jar
yes you can absolutely vacuum seal your
nugs once they have reached the desired
ripeness in your jar just make sure they
are actually the ripeness you want them
to be if you do seal them up and there's
too much moisture in there you do run
the risk of creating a mold problem
inside of that container it sounds like
you were a smart man it sounds like you
know how far to take them before you
seal them so as long as you get them to
the correct ripeness as long as you get
them to the correct moisture level
before you seal them up yes you can
absolutely vacuum seal your product so
that your nubs stay nice and fresh if
you're anything like me you'll probably
write the strain name and then you'll
probably weigh that product before you
vacuum seal it so you'll be able to
write the strain name the amount of
product and the date that it was sealed
up that way you have a lot of
information and a lot of details on that
product because you probably if your
vacuum sealing [ __ ]
you've probably got quite a stash you
may have several things stashed away so
yes you can absolutely vacuum seal your
nugs but make sure to label them so you
don't forget what it is because we are
again cannabis consumers and we like to
forget a lot of small details
all right podcast world that is all I've
got for you for this quick Thursday
episode of the grow from your heart
podcast I want to thank you again for
listening don't forget to visit our
friends at Oregon elite seeds if you
need new seeds in your grow room I
highly recommend Oregon elite seeds you
can find them at
www.www.pinesicearena.com
slash grow from your heart all of the
information you need will be right there
I would appreciate it if you find me on
all the social media on Facebook simply
search for the grow from your heart
podcast on Twitter it's at G fyh podcast
if you want to follow my personal
Twitter feed it is a trusted Jeff 420
also I have made an Instagram page for
the podcast I haven't posted a lot there
yet but if you search for the grow from
your heart podcast on Instagram you will
find the podcast you will also be linked
up to my I read genetics Instagram page
give me a follow there check out my
cannabis photography also you can join
me in a live feed every Monday around
710 mountain time I go live I take a few
dabs I talk about growing and I answer
grow questions for my friends there live
in the feed join me maybe we can get
your question answered in a live feed on
Instagram live if you've got something
you'd like to say you're not into all
that social media junk you can send me
an email my email address is grow from
your heart at hotmail.com you know I
would love to hear from you I want to
thank everybody again for the iTunes
customer reviews I want to thank
everybody again for all of the support
on patreon I wanna give you huge thank
you to everybody who is listening to the
podcast and who has been supporting me
and sending me encouraging emails who's
been leaving comments on YouTube
everybody who's been sending a
supportive vibe and been sending thanks
it is not going unnoticed
I do appreciate all of it it keeps me
recharged and it keeps me encouraged so
big thank you I appreciate all of that
ladies and gentlemen that is all I've
got for you for this quick episode I
want to give a huge shout out to my
friends love for the plant and love for
the bong and until next time take a phat
dad and give your mom a hug for me