hey what's up podcast world it is time
for episode 427 of the growth from your
heart podcast no long fancy intro no ads
we're not gonna talk about what I'm
smoking no patreon shoutouts we're gonna
get right down to business
today I am frequently a guest on a show
called embracing organics embracing
organics is of course an organic based
cannabis growing podcast that is found
on YouTube we record the show on
Thursdays at 7 p.m. mountain time I
encourage you to join us I am on the
show quite frequently I like to talk
about growing and I like to talk about
breeding
but even when I'm not there it is still
a great podcast and the boys have a
great time on the most recent episode I
brought up a great topic that I wanted
to cut from their show with their
permission and replay here on my podcast
I don't feel like it requires a lot of
setup because I do a pretty good
explanation in the rant that I was
delivering I will also be back at the
end of that recording to deliver some
fresh information that I've discovered
since that original recording so ladies
and gentlemen with no further ado let's
time travel back to last Thursday and
revisit my rant about Philo's bioscience
on the embracing organics podcast
[Music]
[Applause]
there's dead air silence the thing that
has been popular in the cannabis
community that I haven't touched on yet
seems to be the the FiOS galaxy news
that has come to light lately sorry I
sound distracted I'm getting a dad
together I know you get your dad
together and you know I'm kind of gonna
play a little devil's advocate here but
personally I haven't dude I haven't
looked into anything about this Philo
stuff you know as far as I know from
what I've seen on Instagram and blah
blah blah blah people are claiming that
they're stealing genetics they're
claiming that you know they're taking
their stuff and heading for the hills
with it I'm seeing a lot of like you
know oh FiOS is doing this file is is
doing that but I haven't really dug
anything up I haven't got any my own
research so you seem to know a little
bit about what's going on so go ahead
and inform me well there's
to it and a lot of it a lot of the
reaction is kind of Miss information and
the cannabis industry loves a nice
witch-hunt we love to hang someone out
to dry as soon as we hear somebody say
something that ruffles our feathers I
tried not to get involved in that
feather ruffling and tried to kind of
wait and see how it unfolded the big
misconception that I see people seem to
think that Philo's has our plants they
think that we sent them clones or small
babies or something that they have made
a tissue culture or a clone of that is
not the case they do not have our plants
they have got our genetic data is
basically what they have when you send
material to Philo so you don't send them
a plant you take a small card that
unfolds you rub part of the plant
material in there to get the juices out
of the plant you fold it back up and you
send it to them just the same way that
you spit into a little package for
23andme it is the same process 23andme
can't they maybe they could but 23andme
doesn't have my arm I didn't have to
send them part of my arm for them to get
my my DNA you don't send them a plant
you send them this juice is basically so
they don't have our plants they can't
regenerate our plants from the small
amount of data we gave them what they do
have is the genetic marker of all of our
plants so now they know what makes up
each plant what they do have is an
advantage now they have already seen
basically what happens if you breed
almost all of the popular cultivars that
are out there they have seen it bred to
all of the other cultivars and they've
got a really good predictive chart and a
map and a kind of a cheat code
inbreeding that is that's basically to
my understanding what they have done
their intention to my understanding is
not to take our plants and reproduce
them they want to use the info that we
have provided to breed better plants for
the future in their opinion better
plants for the future I don't know how
that is gonna go I can't speak for their
intention there but from what they have
released they don't have our stuff they
can't steal our stuff they're gonna use
our data because we all sent them our
plants with the agree you sign an
agreement saying that they can use your
data they can use it for science they
can reproduce it there's a long list of
things you allow them to do when you
send them your material so we gave them
permission to do this also when you say
and a scientist or a laboratory any sort
of material they're not storing it and
doing you a favor they're going to use
that that is part of their job that is
what science is for you don't get into a
science industry to just collect data
you want to do something with that data
so that's what they did I know they're
looking to breed with that they're going
to use our research years and this is
what is kind of frustrating the
community we have spent years doing this
somebody in the chat earlier said that
they have done what a small family of
breeders would have done in several
years they've got all of that data to
themselves what the entire cannabis
community has done over years they've
got all of that data to themselves and
they charged us to get it they charge
you 250 to 300 dollars per submission to
enter a strain into their galaxy so they
charged us money they put our strains
into their galaxy now they're using that
data to their advantage that is what
it's kind of pissing off a lot of
growers and breeders and the industry as
a breeder I'm not worried they if and
when they do get to breeding and
creating their own strains that are
going to hire breeders who were people
just like us who have experience with
plants they're going to pay those people
to do projects that are charted out
they're gonna have instructions to
follow that's how breeding happens they
are going to be Budweiser or Walmart and
I'm always gonna be whoever I don't even
know the smaller one to compare to I'm
always gonna be mom-and-pop and people
are always gonna there's gonna be a
choice a lot of people go to Walmart a
lot of people by Budweiser but so many
people want that mom-and-pop stuff so
I'm not worried about it I think there's
integrity in good breeding I think what
they're doing in a way it helps the
movement it helps the industry it helps
the plant we're going to develop they
are going to develop plants that will be
they say more resistant to bugs more
resistant to pathogens more resistant to
mildew and molds and they claim that
they'll be able to dial in specific
strains to have very specific terpene
profiles to where if you want cheesecake
you can breed a strain that tastes like
cheesecake or you can breed one that
tastes like public knowledge that
another breeder could use their data and
do the same thing and choose the parents
that they want because there's that kind
of like a public thing it's not or do
they have grown like you think they
recommend if you explore their their
galaxy there are spaces where they
recommend breeding specific
strains together they say nobody has
done this yet and since these strains
are so far apart in our galaxy we
recommend a breeding them because it
would make unique phenotypes is
something that they actually send that
to you when you file strains with their
galaxy
they'll make those recommendations for
you and they actually suggested
something that I had already done they
recommended I crossed first they said
Girl Scout cookies to grateful dog and I
had already done it they also suggested
I crossed the space clean to my grateful
dog and I had already done that so they
were they were predicting things that I
was going to do they were predicting my
moves that I had been planning through
science they saw it before I did as a
breeder you know a lot of the
information they have is lineage breed
or living it's information besides a lot
of unknown cultivars you know where you
don't know the lineage most of the data
was out there um you know before you as
a breeder before you take upon any
project you do your research and do what
you're crossing you don't just go oh
this looks pretty and this looks pretty
and slap them together hopefully yeah
hopefully there's a long process behind
it and the information was out there and
is out there and you know you find your
lineages you see how those have been
grown out and what the result and you
make your best educated you know
decision based off of the data that you
you draw they've just drawn a ton of
data and brought it into one spot a ton
of data and here's the thing like
everybody forgets how many active
compounds of Canada this plant itself
has and every seed is a little different
than the other seed that you germinate
and they make me similar but they're
still different compounds are a little
bit higher in each one so for them to
really take that and say hey this is
what we're gonna create they still don't
know exactly what all compounds they're
gonna find they have an idea but they
don't know for sure and that's what
they're looking for 13:30 I like the
fact compared them to like wiser or like
you know like a miller or something you
know I mean like I
really big just broad industry and you
know me personally I'm not a drinker but
I would much rather go to a small
brewery I would much rather support a
small poem brewer versus like a big
corporation like Miller I mean dude
there's tons of people out there that
want that stuff that are perfectly happy
and fine with that hey what's going on
humidor through this hey guys the
embracing organics podcast is recorded
live on Google Hangouts which gives the
opportunity for guests to come and go at
different points of the show sometimes I
have to leave the show early sometimes I
show up for the show late at this point
in the show we were joined by another
friend I'll be politely greeted him we
said hello to him for a few minutes we
let him talk about where he was he was
at a new cannabis club we let him hype
that up for a few minutes
he politely said goodbye then we
continued on with our talk about Philo's
dirt man dan seem to remember exactly
where he was so let's just let him pick
up right where he left off ladies and
gentlemen here is dirt man Dan but yeah
like I was saying earlier I like the
fact that like Jeff was comparing these
guys to like a big corporation like a
Walmart or a Miller or something like
that
I guess they're their is their place for
it but me being the person I am I like
supporting the small mom-and-pop shops
even though there is that giant
corporation right down the street and
I'm gonna wind up spending more at the
mom-and-pop shop but I know at the end
of the day I'm probably getting a better
quality product and that makes me
happier well I think some of the issues
too were as people weren't getting
credit for some of these genetics that
people sold over the years and people
wanted to know what really was going on
and who really had what to begin with
and this kind of helps sort through some
of that oh yeah now we can see we can
trace it back through DNA we can see
well that came from this came from this
came from this or no we're we have more
opportunity to find out what
oh gee really is we're gonna find out
what oh gee cush really is where it came
from
we'll find out if all these different
different named oh geez the sfv the
original oh gee all the different ones
we'll find out if they're the same cut
or if they came from the same sea
stock we'll be able to narrow that down
and in that rumor which will be really
cool for the cannabis world yeah because
everybody swears they have a cut of the
OG or you know I got og this I got og
that dude it don't matter where you're
at somebody's got yo gee yeah but is it
that original og because there are so
many OGS back in the day there's the sfb
and then there's the Tahoe and they're
probably very similar yeah exactly
supposedly the one group like so many
different variances and Fino expressions
that came out of that plants being
handed down and down from generation
generation just also gets lost to yes
somebody will click somebody will you
know forget what it is and then make up
a name and we've been growing that for
forever it doesn't matter what the name
is people forgot I think that in your
neighborhood there's a guy over there
sellin OG Kush and everyone's buying OG
Kush but I need mine to be different so
I'm gonna call it Jeff's og now mine's a
little bit more expensive and you want
to buy Jeff's OG because it's that new
hot [ __ ] so we just got to rename it and
that's how a lot of that happens on your
channel change the name of them
something like we don't want people to
know what this is and where it came from
like oh okay like I was saying before
the show I see a lot of this stuff as
the inevitable and like I'm hoping for
federal legalization honestly I mean I
want to be able to grow these plants
like they're Tomatoes you know I want
everyone to be able to have access to it
though that needs or want access to it
as long as they're you know an adult and
responsible with their life whatever but
my whole point is like this is only the
inevitable of when legalization comes in
because you're gonna have companies like
bear you know big [ __ ] like FiOS is tiny
you're gonna have big [ __ ] boys
coming in and
thrown down you know intellectual
property rights all over [ __ ] trying to
you know patent these strains and stuff
and they're gonna have some real money
to throw at it and then people are
really gonna be [ __ ] it's like this that
people are freaking out over nothing
right now go over some some data because
that's all Philo's has data yeah but I
think it's gonna be too hard to patent
this plant itself there's too many
variables to it gonna do besides hurt
maybe they're trying to be legal you're
gonna put some sort of tracer in there
and they're gonna let their [ __ ] grow
and their pollens gonna [ __ ] fly or
something and then they're gonna come in
your field find you know seed and your
[ __ ] crop from with their genetic
yeah see you know that's what Monsanto
farms because of all this [ __ ] yeah so
at this point in the show we kind of
drifted off into a different
conversation there are about six people
in the Y feed at this point so it does
get a little bit hectic I chose to cut
out at this point you can hear the full
unedited version of that podcast on the
embracing organics youtube channel that
original episode aired on May the second
which was a Thursday so that should be
really easy to find on the YouTube
channel I do encourage you to go listen
to that full episode I also encourage
you to subscribe to the embracing
organics podcast YouTube channel then
next week you can join us for the next
live Thursday podcast alright there is
more to talk about here with the Philo's
galaxy controversy as stabby and med fit
touched on there are things to think
about like intellectual property a lot
of breeders a lot of creators of very
popular strains sent their information
to Philo's they have now got our data
they have got our intellectual property
they are going to use our intellectual
property to further their breeding
projects there are a lot of different
ways to think about this you can think
about this as your aren't being used you
can think about it as your business
being used there are a lot of different
approaches to come at this subject I'm
trying to come at it from all angles and
keep a clear head and a
in mind said I can relay the information
properly without being biased a recent
rumor or allegation that has been flying
through the cannabis community and
social media is that Philo's bioscience
may possibly be linked up with a company
in Israel who is actively working to
patent specific cannabis strains or
variety so that is something that would
be really shitty and shady of them to do
we gave them our plant data now they are
using that data to create their own
patents that is again an allegation and
a rumor that I will look more into and I
will report more information to you as
it does come to light there is a lot of
information coming out very quickly the
owner and spokesperson of Philo's
bioscience has been scheduled to appear
and speak on numerous podcasts this past
week but as expected he has backed out
at the last moment for every interview
he has scheduled so when I do find more
information I will update you with that
information and I will keep you guys in
the loop as to what is happening with
Philo's bioscience as I'm wrapping up
this recording I just received a message
from our friend medically fit who is
joining us on the embracing organics
podcast he has sent me a video that has
a lot of detailed information from the
spokesperson and owner of Philo's
bioscience this video can be found on
the soil Kings YouTube channel so go to
youtube search for the soil King he's
got 18,000 subscribers give him a
subscribe and the video you were looking
for is Philo's bioscience industry
leaders with Mowgli that's the video you
want to watch Mowgli speaks for almost
an hour about the things he said in that
controversial YouTube video that
controversial Instagram clip that
everybody saw that sparked all of this
controversy for his company so I
recommend you check out Philo's
bioscience industry leaders with Mowgli
on the soil Kings YouTube channel and of
course give him a subscribe since he's
got such a great video up ladies and
gentlemen I think that is all I have got
to cover for the Philo's bioscience
controversy if I do learn more I will do
my best to present that to you on this
podcast I think the conversation between
Mowgli and our friend soil King will
answer most of the remaining questions
once again I want to give a huge shout
out to all of my friends over there at
the embracing organics podcast big shout
out the dirt man Dan big shout out to
Tennessee Gardens big shout out to med
fit big shout out to bear and of course
is always a big ol shout out to my buddy
stabby mixed aderson I'm sure there's
somebody I missed a lot of people cycle
in and out of that chat room of course a
big shout-out to Pedro and of course a
big shout out to dizzy see if I keep
going I'm just gonna have to give a
shout-out to everybody so big shout out
to everybody on the embracing organics
live feed it is an honor and a pleasure
to be invited to join those folks for
such a great show ladies and gentlemen
that is all I've got for you for this
episode I want to thank you for
listening to my info about the Philo's
bioscience controversy in most episodes
I ask you to support me on patreon
instead I'm going to ask you to
subscribe to my friends podcasts make
sure you go check out embracing organics
give them a subscribe make sure you go
check out the soil King and give him up
subscribe and of course please subscribe
to my youtube channel to grow from your
heart podcast
I want to thank dirt man Dan for the
permission to repost the portion of his
podcast and I also want to give a huge
shout out to all of my friends at the
embracing organics podcast and until
next time take a phat dad and give your
mom a hug for me