[Music]
yeah what's up ladies and gentlemen it's
time for episode number 43 of the IG gr
culture podcast the podcast all about
Cannabis News education and culture if
you're a new grower a professional
grower a longtime cannabis consumer a
brand new smoker or even someone who's
just curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you thanks again for joining us guys
as promised at the table today is our
good friend King Cola how you doing
brother good man good thanks for having
me oh man thanks a lot for coming thanks
for time taking time out of your busy
schedule all these Growers are super
busy we're sitting here talking about
all the stuff we're doing how you doing
Jesse pretty good you looking better
this week yes my skin and complexion is
the right color and on both feet quit
making fun of Jesse he's he's back he's
onest we took lot of dabs today he
redeemed himself he's on his game Sean
brought some solventless uh it's
delicious and Jesse did not die no not
at all my my blood sugar is correct
today yeah I was worried about coming on
here with you guys I'm not a big BHO
smoker so I didn't even ask that I was
going to ask that as we were uh as the
show progressed I had a BHO question for
you so I was going to see if you're a
Dabber I am actually I I I grew up with
Spencer man like come on like but but in
the same sense I was pampered so when
you smoke his chatter you can't really
go to smoke smoking a
dispensaries so I was just like screw it
on make ice wax do you smoke live resin
um I've had the pleasure of trying it a
couple of times from his personal stash
and good gracious it is amazing um is it
it really is I'd like to steal some of
his Tech on that one tpy turpy slurpie
by the time this episode airs uh in my
mind I feel like Spencer will have won
The Secret Cup yeah I think that's a a
safe assumption he's there now the
competition actually happens uh Sunday
night think the judging happens so by
the time this episode comes out he will
be the champion of the secret cup and I
can reveal what was entered um it was
White Widow oh yeah grown by Rost yeah
it's this is like oh no no you can't you
looked at me like you can't say that but
this won't come out this is now that
everybody knows now it was White Widow
grown by rosta Jeff of iy genetics it
was the cut uh Spence gave me the cut a
while back I crossed that cut to
Grateful Dog and actually made Capleton
with it I love that white widow dude it
grows like a boss they KCK out multiple
donkey dicks like Monas of donkey dicks
it's so awesome yeah so I hope that does
well for you good luck brother I hope
you brought home a trophy either way if
he won or not I plan to get him here on
the show he might be the episode after
this his schedule pending it's up to him
he's invited he knows he's welcome
anytime hopefully we can get him shout
out Spence shout out to Big D shout out
to Jeremy shout out everyone involved
with the secret cup we'll do a wrap up
on that one in the next show uh let's do
an ad real quick we got to pay some
bills before we get too far this podcast
is brought to you by our good friends at
Natures green remedies.com check out
Natures green remedies.com for gag green
genetics llata Labs Sin City rare
dankness mile high can Adventure the
Cali Connection MTG iy genetics and of
course many more trusted Brands uh
Nature's green remedies has a coupon
code for you if you type in coupon code
Frosty you will get 15% off any order uh
and you get free priority shipping in
Nature's green remedies.com that coupon
code does expire on the 31st so take
advantage of that while you can this
podcast is also brought to you by my
good friend task Rock and highly
educated titanium if you're using high
quality concentrates if it's solventless
if it's B if it's live resin if you're
taking a dab you deserve a high quality
titanium nail don't use some cheap ass
Chinese knockoff or even some cheap
American knockoff made by some
competiting brand competing brand
they're not using the quality titanium
you need trust the industry leader trust
Highly Educated titanium check out
Highly Educated ti.com for more info if
you want to buy some Highly Educated
products go to Aqua lab technologies.com
big shout out to Giddy Up while we're at
it Jesse's pointing out the new email
that we got my buddy giddy up and
emotech sent me the sweetest brand new
gnail I love it it works like a boss if
you're in the market for a gnail an
enail that stays hot at the perfect temp
gives you fat rips all the time check
out the gnail also mad Lov to tree
Thugger dcom this episode is brought to
you in part by tree Thugger dcom music
and Festival no concert and Festival
news and reviews look out at the cookout
with tree Thugger dcom and and our last
commercial I promise this is from hygro
indoor growing supplies make sure you
check out hyro indoor growing supplies
they have two locations to serve
Colorado visit the Denver store 6271
Beach Street or of course the beautiful
PLO location featuring burn and Jesse on
618 East Fourth Street uh check out hyro
for competitive pricing and a great
selection of indoor grow supplies also
don't forget if you mention you listen
to the Agro culture podcast you will get
commercial pricing it's going to save
you a lot of money if you're buying a
nanolux light you're going to save quite
a few bucks Jesse just looked at me like
we didn't think of that no that's cool
we got them in uh in stock now too nice
yes we got and you know enough to get
going there in the store I just saw you
visualize the Shelf he looked up at my
wall as if the Shelf would be there and
he could see it and I think he counted
them um I I don't know if it's how
many's there or if we're going to get
the order by the time show show so
there's two different numbers going
through my head there either way they
will they will get your nanolux lighting
needs taken care of they look to be
quality lights uh much love to all the
sponsors I appreciate it you guys thanks
for helping us out if you're interested
in sponsoring the show email me it's
ulture hotmail.com and we'll get it
going so I've got a couple of things I
got to say uh big shout out to Angela
Adam and Mike dude you guys trimmed for
seven hours last night thank you uh I
would have gone nuts without it Sean
just looked over and saw the trimmed
pots and shook his head those are big
pots yeah I've been at it for like a
week trimming by
myself I know good trimmer if you need
them all I'll give you their numbers
they're yours they need money you just
got to pay them decently so big shout
out to those guys they helped me out
trim and I could not have got through it
also uh big huge shout out to hanky B uh
hanky B gave me some live resin to dab I
was hanging out his house and as I left
he goes here man take some of this and
just gave me like a grandma live res uh
make sure you follow him on in Instagram
that's hard to say he's hanky b11 he
told me to make sure I say that because
he gave me hash so big shout out to Hank
uh we'll skip some shout outs for now
that's enough let's get on to the meat
of the show here we got a guy that does
all kinds of Organics and we've been
talking about a lot of grow lessons so I
guess the first question to jump right
into it dude if we just want to get down
to it you want to tell me uh all about
organic as [ __ ] uh yeah well organic as
a [ __ ] is just a hashtag we started
using um it's created by J I'm going
move like a little closer to you no
worried oh good there you go I just want
to get your well oh you're good um
important [ __ ] to say Jesse actually
started the hashtag I stole it off of
his page um but no it's the idea is that
uh all organic um we don't like the idea
of any bottled fertilizers synthetic
nutrients uh specifically you know
pesticides anything with mineral salts
map and dap uh mono um monoammonium
phosphates uh you know preservatives
there you go um the idea is to create a
clean product um food grade everything I
probably buy half of the products I use
at our local natural groceries uh so so
really big emphasis on growing style um
that's most Growers tend to focus on
flour where we focus on the soil um I
feel a lot of stuff is lost when you're
just focusing on weight uh High
vegetative yields uh you know quick
flowering times you're just losing a lot
of I mean money time I mean you're just
losing so much in that process quality
exactly and then hurting the environment
and a lot of other people the way that
part is What's Really Got Me interested
I want to learn a lot from you to maybe
shift my grow toward this style and my
reasoning is the sustainability uh I've
got a kid and she's 11 now and I keep
thinking about the stuff that I hear I
read about what they're making my
nutrients out of and then I'm thinking
about uh I toured a large grow facility
that runs a lot of hydro and they have
lots of water that has to be flushed out
is waste and I thought where does that
go that's going back to our Municipal
Water Supply and being filled filtered
out and when you get water out of the
sink that's what we're drinking and that
really that stuff the past few years has
had me think and I want to get more
sustainable and no offense to the hydro
shops but I love them because they help
us out but we don't need to be paying
overmarking [ __ ] and seabird guano and
make something that we can one day the
end of the world is coming and you can't
go to the hydro shop then I totally
agree Sean's going to out us yeah Sean's
going to outgrow all of us when that day
comes feel hypocritical sometimes cuz I
use very few products from our store as
well so yeah but see your store it it
has the option I ours is a little
different than most I like to think so I
I was pretty blown away when I first
walked in there and that's coming from a
guy who just who absolutely hates hydro
stores yeah so you're doing it uh mostly
out of the Organics for the clean
product for the food grade I'm
interested more for the sustainability
uh I think that's both a great reason to
do it one thing that got my attention
right off bat you said you don't use any
pesticides or non-organic pesticides I'm
really curious and I bet the listeners
are too how do you keep bugs out of your
crop without some nuclear attack right
at the beginning of the Fall here
everybody I know got three types of bugs
at once three letters i p m can I guess
what that means ladies and gentlemen
integrated Pest Management please write
that down that's important we will talk
about that a lot that's going to be a
glossery term that you need to Mark IPM
integrated Pest Management ion is the
only guaranteed form of pest control uh
100% if you don't want to deal with pest
then you have to start a program um and
that starts with a nice organic base uh
you want to start out with you know
things high in chit uh insect frass crab
meal uh things neem cake uh all of that
into the soil mix then you want to start
off on a regiment of you know silica uh
what else uh aloe vera you want to build
you want to strengthen the plant help it
build its uh cell walls basically you
need to build its immune system so it
can take care of itself so throw away
the bottle of pottassium
silicates and use the aloe vera and the
uh what was the other one that you said
that I felt would really build the cell
walls uh the silica we yeah silica is
just such an
underutilized uh thing in growing and
I'm pretty sure both of you guys can
contest to that and synthetics or
hydroorganic whatever it's all the fiber
growth exactly and the your Leaf wall is
the stronger it's going to be able to
stand up to attack what what do you use
to get silica in Organics uh there's a
couple of different uh options on the
actually there's thousands of different
options on the market uh potassium silic
is probably the number one most common
um it's really you know that's a good
one to use uh most companies sell it
most organic companies sell it I
personally use uh silica derived from
diamite uh through the majority of my
growth uh potassium silicate though does
have its place uh from my clones uh
obviously late and flour I do prefer
potassium Sil little more stuff that's
like in desicant packs in your box of
shoes new shoes or guys what I'm talk
about it it sounds like they it looks
like a familiar familiar word now that
I'm thinking about that it looks like
the same word on there but I that's what
it says on the side of those little
packs I think so it says desicant pack
on there yeah well no I think it says
potassium silicate it wouldn't surprise
me it's all very common stuff I mean and
then the diatomite the silica derived
from diatomite is basically dious Earth
which you're probably more familiar with
got a rough texture kind of crushes up
the kind of cuts up the bugs if they try
to get through it's like walking on
glass for a bug okay um so your plants
never get sprayed uh well actually they
do I uh I fure spray every day I I
probably Overkill my fure spray um it's
you know every girl likes to spend time
in their Garden um and if you can find a
way to do it yeah go for man and in my
ways to spray uh so you know I do break
it down into regiments uh shout out to
dragonfly Earth medicine with their
natural Mystic te's of fer sprays they
soil inoculates and other herbal
inoculates but that's a big part of my
spray regiment um homemade compost teas
fpj's ffj so fermented fruit juices
fermented plant juices uh that I make
myself and you're actually spraying that
on your plants spraying that on the
plants how late into flower would you do
that I usually don't go past week four
or five just like a traditional spray
even though it's organic uh things just
tend to stick
around okay yeah you can cause problems
going past week four or five I assume
exactly especially everything that I use
is very sugary yeah you know fruit
juices and plant juices and everything's
got molasses he uh he brought some nugs
you guys I'm not going to say that I was
a hater of Organics but I feel he stood
up for himself before anybody even
mentioned it he said I brought this to
show you that it's dense and it's odorus
and it's covered in tricomes and it's
all of that the tricomes are actually
real they're not tall they don't stick
off the bud that he showed me real far
but they're compacted they're everywhere
all over that nugget even between where
the two little buds touch on that Branch
they're between there you got resin
everywhere on that thanks so the
Organics do work I can see the proof and
I'm doing you know I do some Consulting
on the side but I'm actually working
with a couple of uh concentrate
companies um shout uple of diamond
extracts they're really killing the game
right now with shout out your uh your
consulting company going yeah Rocky
Mount natural farming uh you can check
us out on Instagram but uh follow them
guys a lot of these guys you know
they're making BHO and it's funny you
have your little meme on the internet of
says he grows veganic and only smokes
BHO but uh I'm pretty sure there's
plenty of guys out there who will back
me on this one saying Organics produce
better hash um I feel the Tricom is more
fully developed you your membrane's more
intact you're not going to get that mus
I see it a lot especially when making
the ice wax uh as you can see this is
some stuff that's locally
grown um or actually here's the better I
think I smoked this the other night one
of your buddies had some of this yeah I
actually made it for him um this is uh I
believe it's organically grown um but in
the sense that you know you probably
went to the store and bought some
Organics organic soup exactly and then
you can look at this one it still has a
nice smell a lot of the solvent List It
kind of loses the odor in my opinion and
it's still got that dank smell
um but I believe that the that maybe the
it's degrading a little quicker so you
know check the quality of that one yeah
I like this I like this one a lot and
then check that one oh this I I hit this
one this one is
tasty uh who did you say made this uh
that was made by triome heavy extracts
shout out to jibs and grown by growing
kushan Maha shout out Rob who's just
killing the game right now um I walked
into the first Cannabis Cup nobody knew
who I genetics was I hadn't put my face
on Instagram yet and I had my shirt on
and growing Kush one mile high spotted
me right away and he goes dude your I
genetics come here and took a picture
with me and posted it to Instagram and
now my face was out that's what did it
that's what put my face on Instagram
that's when I was like well I'm the tall
guy with dreadlocks that's how it goes I
remember that yep yep he's uh he's very
humble dude um if you want to get your
genetics out there get him to grow it
tell you that much I like that kills it
cool at growing Kush won hi email me bro
you're getting a seed
pack some stuff should be ready couple
of them yeah some stuff should be ready
here in a couple of weeks if everything
goes well do you think that you were I'm
going to kind of back Loop here you said
that the tricomes have a better the
triome heads have a better casing from
Organics do you think that it's because
we're using what the plant actually
wants instead of feeding it junk food
out of a bottle exactly I I feel the
synthetic approaches like you said junk
food is just the such an appropriate
term um your bud are going to get denser
they're going to get bigger they're
going to get fatter does that
necessarily mean they're any better no I
mean it's only better for your wallet
exactly and um and we're fortunate
enough to be in an industry or at a
point in this industry where maybe that
doesn't matter as much anymore um so now
that people aren't all obsessed with
hitting you know seven pounds per light
uh we can focus a little bit more on
quality what strain was
that yeah you know was from BC uh I'm
pretty sure we were trimming last night
and uh there was one plant and that's a
perfect example one plant kicked out
donkey dicks a size of my arms and then
the Girl Scout cookies had little
popcorn but there was as much resin on
that little popcorn of Girl Scout
cookies as there was spread amongst that
entire other plant H yeah it was so dank
that little cookies plant is just coated
I'd rather grow more of those if I
didn't have picky patients if my
patients weren't demanding of the
Grateful Dog and other strains I'd grow
all cookies yeah just cuz the resin it
puts out it's so gorgeous cookies Yeti
and SF yeah there'd be some Grateful Dog
in there but I'd definitely have like a
36 Lightroom of just cookies cookies
cookies yeah yeah yeah little over I may
uh I kind of want to mention things but
I don't want to say too much I am in the
process of possibly uh taking on a
badass position running 227
lights do it I'm I if everything works
out within the next month I will be in
there growing
under
227 gavitas hell yeah I'm a little
stoked it's all Hydro tables it's going
to be fun all right so TR better triome
heads because of Organics does the aloe
vera have anything to do with that you
think same way it makes my skin more
Supple and doesn't burn Under the Sun or
under the grow light yeah and I mean you
know you can really go into the
properties of aloe and yucka and the
saponin and all of that stuff that's you
know 30 minutes worth of conversation
but bottom line is is it it increases
the health of your plant um silica aloe
coconut water those are the bases uh
outside of that um I'm glad you say that
cuz I preach those products other than
the uh the silica I'm always about aloe
and coconut water I teach a lot of
people that so yeah it's a necessity the
coconut water um extreme I drink coconut
water myself and I feel amazing when I
drink it yeah you know with the style of
gardening that I use I like the idea
that me and my plant sh the same food
you know the more I grow and the more I
evolve into this I think my plants I was
a vegetarian before I grew I took decent
care of myself but I think learning
about the plant biology has made me take
better care of myself and it's
influenced my shopping when I go to
Vitamin Cottage or whatever grocery
store I hit uh and Jesse has done it too
his organic practices have influenced my
shopping and my eating a little bit and
it's which in turn has affected my
growing because now you're here to teach
me how to be more healthy more
sustainable so I see it going full
circle it's there's a passion there I
like it yeah I I feel like people uh
maybe put a little bit too much emphasis
on the switch I mean if you're running
soiless and you're running Botanicare
you're you're almost there that's what
I'm saying yeah I'm just scared dude I
my patients love what I do and I've got
oh they love you even more promise I've
got Grateful Dog grown to Perfection you
know with with the way I do it and I'm
and I can get it that way with the few
strains but it's a big jump for me to
just go change but I may do it I'm going
to write down what you do and kind of
and I I can people are probably disag
agree with me on this but I don't think
you're going to lose yield um I swear up
and down that this whole Organics yields
less is just a a misconception in the
industry I mean it really is
unfortunately you do have people it's a
different approach than traditional
gardening um so you've got guys out
there who have been doing Hydro or soil
mixes for years switching to Super soils
and burning their plants and all
Organics doesn't yield anything but it
it reflects a lot on the grower also I
think somebody like you could definitely
just take off with it especially with
your experience with additives that's
the key okay um is with Organics you
start a base a lot of people like to
water never or water every time I'm
sorry they don't use anything but water
me personally I like to water never um
and that's kind of your style now where
you're giv
it I don't know all the product name but
you're giving them silica and you're
giving them yucka and you're giving them
everything that I am just just in a
liquid bottle I'm doing it the lazy way
and you know how most of that stuff is
made is it's a compost tea and then so
make like a compost tea and then they
basically they'll arrest fermentation um
so they stop and kill all the living
organisms in there run it through a
protein skimmer bottle it up and then
sell it to you um so just cut out the
middle man make it yourself there we go
by the summer guys we should all be
making our own NES when it's warm and
we're in Colorado I'm not going out in
the backyard and doing it this week but
I got a garage if I had some space by
the summer we'll get it going we'll all
be growing organic Let's Get Away we
have to support the hydro shops go buy
the Organics there get the stuff that's
in the Box the blood meal the bone meal
things if you're doing that uh get your
worm castings and stuff wherever you
locally yeah go go to hyro and make sure
that when you're mixing your soil talk
to Jesse about that CU he can fill you
in on the whole bone meal and blood meal
thing I'm pretty sure Jesse loves to
talk to people at hyro he loves to just
stand there and get paid to talk to yeah
you know so it's better than Advanced
but you know bone meal blood Mill can be
approved upon as well so exactly and
this goes back to the the veganics we
were kind of talking about before the
show uh by no means do I claim to be a
veganic grower we use a hashtag called
Beyond veganics to kind of poke fun at
it uh just for the simple fact vegan
growing is kind of funny just like
vegans are
right I love that how do you know
someone's a vegan don't worry they'll
tell you exactly and and that's really
how it is is you know these vegan these
veganic Growers are they're using just
bottled nutrients I mean you you know
that it's just plain and simple and if
they're not they're really depriving
their plants of you know certain things
they could be using uh earthworm
castings for example like I know people
hey there's a nice little shout out you
can give right there yeah Jay uh Rocky
Mount earthworm castings um I know Jesse
uses it uh I use it um they are super
high quality um he is killing the game
right now dedicated his life to making
uh castings for people like me and Jesse
I've heard a lot of good things if
you're a customer in my store
and you use uh earthworm castings ask me
for them yes do that yeah please do um
you know as a organic grower uh I've
been in Colorado for about two years now
um before then I grew is that all I've
known you bro it's two years it's only
been two years seems like it's been a
long I know right time flies man um but
no so uh you know I have a degree in
horiculture I'm from North Carolina
obviously uh but back there I grew also
uh it was organically um small scale but
you I've been doing te and soil mixes
for a while uh coming out
here really opened my eyes to the fact
that you know you think you're going to
come out to Colorado you think you're
going to grow Organics you think it's
this big popular thing but it's all
about money um yeah but you know Jay I
met Jay um and then he had the high qual
these high quality castings i' I've
never turned back met him probably
within a month to being here been using
his castings ever since uh he does all
testings on his stuff you know it's
super high quality and that's really I
posted some today actually yeah and
that's really the key to uh basically
what I do is my castings um and plain
and simple everybody wants to know how
do I do it it's jce castings without a
microbial inoculate not microbial Source
I couldn't do what I do um a lot of
people Source you know reggers then B
worm castings from stores you know you
can make your own compost it's probably
the best way to do it your own worm
casting thinks it's probably the best
way to do it but at the same time a lot
of people I call it greenwashing um they
go out and they buy something because it
looks organic or it looks like it's you
know going to be all natural exactly
like this this environmental friendly
product and these companies are preying
on the consumer just like they would in
any other you know organic companies
aren't any nicer than synthetic
companies uh there's a company right now
for example that loves to kick out this
they throw numbers to people and you
know your average grow doesn't really
understand uh how these work but for
example Like Jesse was saying uh Jay
actually posted something earlier
um about the worm castings I'm sorry I
wanted to bring this up check it out do
your research I like it um but you know
for example so you've got a company out
there who's throwing this number around
like
30,000 plus microb you know living
microbes in your tea and you can use use
it and multiply it and you know it
sounds amazing it really does and then
you read Jay's test and it's like uh 6.9
million uh protozoa in one gram of
material so in one pound that's over
three billion protozoa that's before you
multiply in your Brewer so to everybody
out there that's using these these
products you know these sales pitches uh
I'm sorry they're sing the shake you're
getting seeds and stems exactly you know
you're you think you're getting a leg up
but really you're paying for an overp
priced Brewer and somebody to put stuff
in a bag for you that's all you're
paying when the bottled new it's a lot
like clothes we're paying for the label
you're paying for that Nike symbol that
Botanicare symbol that advanced
nutrients logo you know so shout out to
Jay he's doing it big and not only worm
castings um he can Source a lot of
things that you know grow stores can't
get uh Jesse can probably attend to that
there's a lot of things that yeah that's
they're just not going to be able to
Source he approaches it a little
differently and you know that's that's
cool yeah and once you get to a certain
scale it's time to adjust from being a
garage basement addict grower to
actually being a horticulturalist and
setting up a grow and doing horiculture
that's kind of what it sounds like
that's what Jay is more aimed for yeah
yeah so you got KNE meal up there uh
yeah he can get whatever you want nice
nice cool yeah I'm going to put knee
meal in my here's a weird question I'm
going to feed Botanicare will it kill my
NE meal if I put it in my soil before I
mix no you you got to the only reason
you really have to be careful mixing
synthetics and Organics is you can
really throw off your micro herd um you
feed too much of something your fungus
is going to feed at a faster rate than
your bacteria which will kill your
bacteria out and your fungus will
actually start to pull things from the
plant if it's not in the soil so it's a
balancing act uh there's a couple of
people I've seen on Instagram who are
just absolutely killing the balancing
act with the synthetics and Organics I
would never recommend it to anybody
that's something we talked about in the
last shows don't mix Stay Away unless
you were just extremely well-versed in
what you do I would highly recommend
staying away from running synthetics and
Organics at the same time I know a guy
that amends his uh uh Coco soil and he's
running full-blown uh uh General
Hydroponics and all that yeah these
probiotic guys now I've a lot of them
running cocoa that probiotic Farmers
Alliance is getting crazy it's killing
me I think everybody at this table knows
there's one grower he runs Organics all
the way until about week six and then he
starts just pummeling with like
Hammerhead and all kinds of ridiculous
pgrs just to make him explode and he
said that gives it the flavor that's his
but you know I'm just to each his own
man yeah yeah that's his grow he can do
what he wants in there just don't sell
it to me I heard they didn't make that
stuff anymore you know they don't but I
know it's called it's called like Bush
master or something putting it out there
are two or three bottles on the Shelf at
H High gr indoor growing supplies if you
use Hammerhead dude I I don't use it any
I did use it in the past when I was a
new grower I tried every brand and I
tried Hammerhead that [ __ ] made my buds
larger I'll say it uh if you're an
advanced nutrience grower or a hydro
farmer and you want to clean that [ __ ]
off the shelf at Jesse's shop go get it
it's $107 a bottle please no it's not
that much I'm just for a whole bunch of
advanced nutrient stuff there we go
Advance is on really good sale right now
yeah igro indor growing supplies say you
listen to the igro culture show speaking
of advanced I had something written down
we've already gone a half hour guys with
this show may be a little longer than an
hour if nobody Minds
um why don't you guys I'm GNA take a dab
and I'm gonna this is I'm like I'm
starting a fight right now tell me a
little bit about pgrs and how you feel
about
them I'm gonna I'm going to jump in real
quickly pgr stands for plant growth
regulator you guys and now I'm going to
let sea tell us about those while I take
a dab uh there's H time in place for
everything man um not in my food crops
at least not
uh synthetically made pgrs there's
obviously plenty of ways to use natural
pgrs plant hormones uh gibc acid
triol uh gibc acid gibc acid you know it
goes on we need to talk after the show I
got a buttload of that stuff there you
know alphalpha I do raw alphalpha I was
to say barley Sprouts barley Sprouts
which great uh barley tea every two
weeks my veg plants yeah I actually
alternate uh Alfalfa and barley for veg
and then corn and barley for flour I
haven't used corn yet but that's just
cuz I haven't found uh I mean I know uh
95 oh really cool organic yeah really
really nice it's not that expensive oh
no no that's um I've been yeah learning
that you know a lot of cool little
additives you don't find at Girl stores
although I'm going start having some
ferments ferments fer ferments like cold
processed extractions that's how you're
going to get your natural pgrs um
fermented plant juices uh basically
you're going to collect growing nodes
you're can you teach us what a pgr
actually is kind of explain like what it
is and what it does let's say like what
uh Axiom are you familiar with that yeah
so explain that to people so basically
uh basically what a pgr is is uh it
controls the plant's growth um so it
contains either real or synthetic forms
of plant hormones uh and then it's going
to make the plant react in a certain way
usually by triggering like apical
dominance or stimulating the plants s
there's different ways that these pgrs
can affect the plants but for the most
part uh you're just applying it to the
plant at a certain stage in its growth
cycle to make it do what you want you're
just manipulating nature so the most
popular one I think that a lot of us
have used in the past would be snowstorm
snowstorm
Ultra uh it's basically they've taken I
think it's seelp and other plant
proteins and concentrated them uh why
don't I want to feed that to my plants
and I'm just being I'm just trying to so
that we can get the and the thing is is
a lot of those you I can't really tell
you without looking at at the bottle uh
what exactly is in it but if you're
telling me it's the kelp um me
personally my favorite flower hardener
uh back when I used to use bottled
Organics was uh what is it moo Avalanche
Menino lnch um which is basically two
different types of kelp and molasses uh
so I've actually kind of adapted that to
my so just replace the B crap and use K
exactly just make the real deal Natural
Healthy pgrs versus uh exactly and that
goes right back into uh the fermented
like plant juices extracts is the way to
go it's basically the same idea as if
you want to if a human wants to get
ripped you shouldn't go inject steroids
and sit on the couch you should go to
the gym eat protein eat vegetables get
all the things you need and work out uh
we're not giving our plants a workout
we're feeding them uh energy bars and
protein shakes and treating them like
[ __ ] and expecting them to be fully
healthy we need balanced healthy plants
not just you they use these steroid
boosted plants they use pgrs it's so
funny like axium is one of the best uh
I've used lots of it not on my personal
stuff but I've seen the result no just
the idea of it is you know you're using
this synthetic to stimulate the plant's
s
AR which what is it's uh is it
systematic automated response the the
first word might be off I'm not even
sure yeah it's some sort of automated
response basically it's the plant's
ability to protect itself um and it's
defense mode that's the reason you know
the plant produces resin is to protect
itself basically uh and that's kind of
what Axiom does is it stimulates that
Chain Reaction inside of the plant so
it's going into def defense mode so it's
exactly what it's doing is it's uh
stressing the plant you have to be
careful uh you know Jess can probably
contend to this when you're messing with
gibberelic acid and stuff I get a lot of
fox tailing yeah uh when I kind of use
it later into flower and that's usually
with any pgr um wasn't a tlic acid at
one point was a choice for people
creating femin seeds yeah before they it
makes them too stretchy really yeah I've
found uh uh silver tho sulfate that I
make myself is the best way for
reversing I was meeting some with some
old heads this morning they were talking
about clal silver yeah and
cloning
man if you're going to reverse seeds
definitely make your own silver thle
sufate at home it's really easy to do
make everything at home it's really easy
to do yeah and just I mean if we're not
if you guys I'm going to kind of
apologize also if you live in an
apartment if you're a new grower uh if
you're not if you're not striving for
what we are D don't don't feel bad use
your bottles do what you can if you're a
medical patient and you don't have the
physical ability AB ility to mix this
[ __ ] up we're not hating you we're just
recommending we're encouraging this is
no and reach out to us cuz we we
definitely have ways that we could help
you yeah you know if if you live in an
apartment if you are unable to mix your
soil or make your own teas there are
definitely options out there for you um
see that stuff community on the podcast
yep yeah everybody deserves the we'll
get Jess's awesome ass truck and we'll
drive up your mountain and we'll come
mix up soil in your yard for you and
we'll put it in pots and we'll carry it
in and hopefully you can get your
wheelchair the plants to water them yeah
I feel going yeah but I think people
kind of over complicate things with
Organics um basically if you if you want
to grow Organics or start growing
Organics I'd recommend going and finding
a nice and organic bottled line of
nutrients Roots organic General organic
age old or um you know the list goes on
and on and there bio bobiz biob stuff
pretty simple stuff too they're uh fish
Hydro slate is very good um yeah I used
to use it when I was back in the D but
uh anyways uh I'd recommend picking up a
nice bottled organic nutrient line uh
then outside of that go and get you some
nice Rocky Mount worm casting style worm
castings uh they the quality is
extremely important I cannot stress that
enough um find high quality worm
castings or find a high quality
microbial Source um and then molasses
there's your compost tea sea is pretty
much uh
uh describing the uh the way I grow yeah
we're supposed to call him something
different the whole time name
bro that's that's basically the way I
grow inside and uh I can promise you it
you get Stellar results and it's um you
know it's way better than Hydro thus for
damn sure I mean you're just replacing
uh you know synthetics have keates um
and that's kind of the idea of using the
tea with your organic bottled nutrient
is when you feed with your when you feed
with the nutrient you're putting it in
the soil when you're feeding with your
tea you're activating that soil to help
it eat those nutrients to give it back
into your plant that's a really good way
to put that it's a great way to yeah so
if you're if you're growing with bottled
organic nutrients and you're not using a
te of some some sort of microbial Source
you're just hurting yourself plain and
simple I have a couple of questions
written down for you and stuff will you
give us a quick run through um five
gallon bucket on how to make a nice
Jesse's done this for us but we tell us
how to make a nice microbial T4 just to
start off with that we can use almost
anytime okay so uh yeah without a doubt
uh worm castings and molasses if you
can't get anything else just those two
um and there's your microbial source and
there's a food for it uh depending on
your quality of castings a four A cup
per gallon uh molasses depending on how
often you're using it one teaspoon to
one tablespoon per gallon um outside of
that Kel meal is always always a good
one uh kelp meal I mean if you're not
familiar with the benefits of kelp you
should really look it up plenty of plant
hormones there's a decent mpk value in
there um and then really go crazy uh
just molasses earthworm castings then
you can go into kelp you can go into
Alfalfa depending on you know veg flower
that's how you're going to kind of
deliver more of an mpk value to your
plant um do you agree with the revs uh
the revs book uh true living Organics
you know I shout out to the Rev I I read
his book uh you know the Rev sub I grew
up learning Organics just like everybody
else did and I really don't agree okay
with his stuff unfort I mean it's but I
learned everything that I know now from
his book you know it's if it if I
wouldn't have went through that trial I
wouldn't be where I am today so I can't
be mad at him you just have to work
learn what works for you I know people
who have used his stuff with great
success okay so he's not saying to skip
it no definitely you you want to read
I've seen some people crush it and have
amazing buds with super soil and I've
seen other people have burnt up shitty
buds with super soil so it's kind of
it's how you grow both people you know
it's people are really funny about
Organics uh we even with my Rocky
Mountain Natural farming page we kind of
had to take a break with post for a
while um we like to put in informative
posts up trying to help the community
but uh we're me met with a lot of
defiance oh as soon as you put up I quit
posting a lot of stuff on Facebook is as
soon as you put up a helpful thing 10
people tell you why you're stupid for
doing exactly and you know to each his
own you you don't have to agree with the
way I grow um you know I even if I say
something wrong sure I mean it's a lot
easier for you to focus on one point I
got a lot of stuff I got to remember
I've actually made mistakes on this
podcast and I felt proud to come back
and say hey guys last week I I told you
the wrong way I'm sorry Like Jesse
called me he's like you just said this
oh [ __ ] I did say that but yeah I feel
like people are getting too caught up in
uh this growing style or that growing
style or he grows like this or they grow
like that and it just people need to
choose their own information it's
amateurish in my opinion exactly Bro
Science all three of us I like that all
three of us grow different ways and you
know see us fighting like children you
know we all but we all borrow something
from each other I'm sure you've learned
something you've learned something from
me and I've learned five things from you
and five from you CU we're all still
doing the same thing
I love talking to synthetic Growers um
I've I've never grown marijuana
synthetically uh my background is in
commercial agriculture I've grown grown
millions and millions of GMO horrible
horrible synthetic plants um I'm not
proud of it food crops food crops yeah
all edible food I mean you can look on
my Instagram and see them okay oh yeah
uh thousands we was 30 Acres of glass
green houses we would run um people got
to eat but you know there's a certain
point in time time that you've got to
kind of figure out what means more to
you is that your money or your morals
you I walked away from making $45,000 a
year which is you know it's a good bit
for me [ __ ] student loans man but uh
no you know I walked away from that and
got a part-time job here in town working
at a hydro store and just grew because
you know it's that's what I wanted to do
and I couldn't it's a lot easier to wake
up and look at yourself in the mirror
saying absolutely that's why I started a
seed company because I got tired of well
that's that's kind of what led to it but
that's how I ended up self-employed I
don't want to work for somebody all day
for something I don't support exactly
for a minimum wage and hate myself I'd
rather be kind of struggling and really
happy and have a cool job and have a
cool job and I've got everything I want
I got a cool ass girlfriend I can do
what I want I got a seed company if I
and I'm not rich I think if I were Rich
I'd just be depressed and confused on
all this money and I wouldn't know if
you guys were my friends cuz I'm rich or
CU you guys are cool as [ __ ] and we're
Bros I'd be like do these guys just want
to come smoke all my live resin cuz I've
got an ounce of it in my pocket you
know I think I've got we're we are rich
we're rich this way cuz we make we make
the we know that we're not poisoning
people we're happy people we're growing
a quality product we're contributing
we're moving it Forward we're making the
Cannabis a good thing instead of a scary
thing I walked away from a $25 an hour
job well they asked me to leave but so
you walked away I walked away stomped
your feet away they they actually told
me uh I had to quit smoking weed and I
said no so uh but yeah that's and a lot
of people will tell you that that's
ridiculous but you have to choose the
decisions that make you yeah happiness
over money is way important I don't
drink a fifth of whiskey every night now
oh man yeah yeah shout out to sobriety I
haven't had alcohol in a long time I It
Feels So a drinker either yeah I no I
still enjoy beer but I don't know if I'm
really really good at drinking or really
really bad at it I'm not sure which one
it is but either way I'm not a big
person as you can tell like I one beer
wasted wow the biggest lightweight
unless now I bet you two beers would
crush me now yeah be silly sitting in
the corner uh let's see I wanted uh you
kind of told me earlier what is your
average uh Harvest weight per thousand
watt light running your Organics um you
know it varies so last round we ran with
the kind of like the style Jesse was
talking about uh with the just a bottled
nutrient kind of or a bottled organic
you know supplemented with te's we were
hitting around I say 1.7 lbs per light
um this Organics guys this last grow um
which is what I brought you today was
grown with no bottled nutrients
absolutely none I mean this is all fruit
juices plant juices the calcium and I
think I you run a pretty mild soil too
compared to like T or super yeah I don't
I I I really uh go light on my soil mix
I think over mending is a big problem
really impressed me about that jar you
got there is that I know your your soil
mix is almost minimal so I'm holding the
butt up to the microphone but it's not
loud
enough but uh you so we hit uh I hit
probably 1.2 I'm not done pulling yet
I'll text you with a final weight and
you can throw it up on a later show but
yes right now I'm kind of looking at 1.2
but that's with no bottled nutrients um
and these are new strains that I'm
running this round so on that do you
have a favorite strain to grow um you
know I'm still so I still feel so like
new to the growing game um you know
growing back east and kind of growing
what you have to you get out here and
you know so I guess Flo would probably
be my favorite screen that's a great she
loves to take good pictures too yeah um
outside of the Flo citrex I think we
were talking about that earlier yeah
that one is definitely G to be in the
garden for a long long time uh yeah
outside of that I've grow I've had a
pleasure of growing some of year gear
I've growing The Grateful Dog the Heart
of Gold L and Jeffrey nice I think the
Heart of Gold was my personal favorite
cool um it was racy to say the least
yeah yeah I mean it's it's not like you
wake up in the middle of the night and
you accidentally grab that to put you
back to sleep you [ __ ] up do not go
back to sleep no not at all that one
that's the Golden Goat in there the
Golden Goat is definitely sativa heavy
um I wish I had have taken it like a
week longer than I how long did you let
it go uh I think I cut it at like N9
okay yeah that's good to know so yeah I
think about 10 weeks is usually what I
recommend for the hard toen it a little
longer I took one like 76 77 days once
nice that's uh I think probably 72s as
far as i' go so DJ Short's been
preaching this 1113 light cycle so I
tried it oh man Sean had a reaction
right away I'm glad I decided to go that
route I had a couple of things written
down a couple of ways to go so I'm glad
I went that way um I'll tell you my
experience but uh what did you think
about it confusion man I just a little
bit of information is a dangerous
[Music]
thing that's all I have to say about it
uh I see I was saying see more
expression the plants showed more color
um a sativa strain that has never really
Fox tailed on me kind of made fingery
buds um I got a lot of color I keep
saying that the color was tremendous on
this run but I feel like it lowered my
Harvest weight by somewhere between 10
and 20% I'm not I haven't cut everything
down yet I've got more to go but I could
tell it diminished my Harvest that may
have been from the cold but I really
think it was from that light cycle I
felt the same thing about it yeah yeah
we always preach it the most important
nutrient to our plants is the light yeah
and so we took a full hour and that's we
took 63 hours 65 hours away from our
plants honestly way to put it yeah and
one thing I did notice they finished
quickly uh I probably saved two weeks on
some of my 10 or 11 week strains they're
going to finish week nine and they'll be
done I I'm worried to let them go too
long one may Herm out I can see it kind
of getting it's pissy it's like you got
to cut me down yeah yeah which is cool
I'll cut her but I just wasn't ready
it's uh it's a a neat tool in a breeding
aspect um you know if we were testing AC
cross we had made if you're looking for
feno if you're feno hunting that is a
good point but that's probably the only
time I'll use it again but like you hear
that you've got Growers and and advanced
breeders and people talking about this
so just please don't try this at home
yeah it's I mean yeah there's no need
for
you US stick with 1212 you guys stick
with 1212 if you want to get adventurous
if you're uh if you're kind of advanced
do what you want to do I don't I don't I
don't want to hold anybody back but be
responsible cuz if you do go and Herm
out that crop you got to do something
with that hered out crop and don't go
try to you did not just make a seed
company you're not called calypso
seeds mids Ash Vigor lover smokes mids
but if if you hered your crop you did
just not make a seed company you made a
mistake you got to get those seeds out
of there grow them grow them yourself
give them to your friends give free
those are free seeds that [ __ ] is free
those are the seeds you give to your
friends you warn them these are
and then you'll understand hopefully
what we're you know all the Breeders are
bitching about yeah yeah Sean I'm just
picking on you no you're good no sorry
there's another guy named Sean figger
lover his name is Sean also oh yeah yeah
I didn't know that's what his I see I
don't know if I should even say yeah
whatever he posted a picture of himself
today did you I don't even know what he
looks like he's been apparently was it
like seven years or 15 years of GMOs or
something he posted the guys a nut shut
up big yo his cats yo that is that is
wild you it's not dude that is crazy you
know when you're somebody standing next
toop and you're scroll through your
Instagram feed and then you hit Vig Ros
page of a cat thicking a [ __ ] in the
toilet so our buddy Viger lover trained
Two Kitties adorable kitties if you're a
cat guy uh he trained these kitties to
full on take a [ __ ] in the toilet like a
human and they do it but the only thing
is he posts a video of it every day on
Instagram like I've seen more cat
butthole on his feed than I have plants
lately it's kind of weird shout out to
Viger lover dude hey start tagging that
iy
genetics yeah cats pooping hashir
genetics I like it thanks a lot I like
that uh guys we got about 10 minutes to
go I don't want to start we're going to
have Sean back because we got more stuff
to talk about I don't want to start
another long rant because we get him
going uh do you guys have any plugs or
shout outs or anything you want to do
people you want to say thanks to uh just
uh Rocky M worm company I can't give
enough thanks to J father do they have
an Instagram or anything they do Rocky
Mount worm company uh on Instagram check
them out they've got a Facebook page
cool kids are on these days Facebook
they've also got a website uh Rocky MW
worm company.com and then they ship all
over the country too high quality yeah I
know I happen to know a high quality
nutrient company that smuggles the stuff
into
[Laughter]
Canada you know just be thankful that
you if you live in Colorado going get
the damn castings because there's people
out there who just want them so bad and
just can't afford the shipping or they
don't have access to them uh it's just
such an underutilized thing here in town
and it doesn't sound like you need a
whole bunch you said like a quarter cup
yeah I mean most people are putting in a
cup per gallon these outrageous rates
and you can use a fourth a cup I mean
your 5 to 10% cutting into your soil mix
is just more than enough and I use like
80 lbs of it on my six outdoor plants
yeah you guys will notice a huge
difference
grow a clone grow two clones keep them
in cups for like 3 weeks you know until
they're starting to get root bound where
they're pissed off rootbound uh feed one
consistently with your microbial tea
with the worm castings in it don't add
that to your other one when you feed it
and pull them out of the cup and watch
you'll have thicker fingery dank happy
roots on one and the other one you'll
have these thin angel hair pasta wispy
shitty sad Roots if you mulch the one
that you're giv the Micro
mobile Jesus tripped on that word um if
you put some Mulch on there you'll see
some really cool [ __ ] happen so try it
nice yeah you see some fungus or or just
a plastic cover some fungus amongus uh
hey where do we find you on Instagram
bro sorry uh King Cola nice kingore Cola
follow him on there
guys Rocky Mount natural farming uh you
can link through that on my Instagram or
Jay's Instagram Rocky Mount worm company
do you have a store opening soon I hear
something about that well we have a shop
up in Colorado Springs for 11 a 411a
Tiana Street in Colorado Springs you can
come and check us out uh see the worm
operation check it out for yourself you
got any questions you know just come and
ask nice nice Jesse got any plugs any
shout outs uh Jesse grow Instagram
better say hi to your wife bro yeah yeah
hey baby BN I hope you're listening to
the Agro culture podcast I hope you're
playing it in the store play the show in
the store that'd be really cool I keep
telling her too she's like I've I
already heard it yeah I did
that oh God I could edit that out if you
it's okay uh when is the next Growers
meeting um I think we might be skipping
December uh Christmas and new yearas and
everything lack of a heater but uh oh it
is cold back there yeah okay but but
we're getting one sounds good yeah we'll
take December off want to make sure I
make it to this one for sure yeah yeah
no me and Sean have talked about some uh
cool demos that he might come and help
us with so tell tell Jesse you want to
learn some natural farming tip yeah hit
me up yeah let's uh let's get this going
I'd love to stock more of this stuff in
um if to get rid of uh one of those
things we talked about earlier I got a
whole bunch of shelf space so help him
help you make your
owns some synthetic grower in California
or wherever you are hit me up dude I'll
I'll s you all that advanced help us get
some organic stuff on the shelf that you
don't care about yeah he'll give you a
discount on it uh finish out your and
then I'll help you go Organics next
round there you
go can they get commercial pricing
they'll get way better than commercial
pricing if they buy it all all right I
guess uh I got to give one more shout
out I skipped one earlier I need to give
a big shout out to Robert and Vegas and
Craig from the spot also Angela what's
up from the spot also just Angela in
general but those kids from the spot all
those guys from the spot and the spot
dispensary and PUO West huge shout out
much respect
some things are coming up in the
future that's cool I got a a shop
opening soon too so I can't say any Nam
yet though lots of stuff going on yeah
uh see all the work that uh this
community has put in is starting to pay
off for all of us yeah finally some
quality meds hopefully down here in PUO
it's about time all right guys we're
going to wrap up the show make sure you
follow me on Instagram it's I genetics
on Instagram make sure you follow the
show it's IG gr culture so we'll read
this part now that the show is over
please go to iTunes or Stitcher go to
the iTunes or Stitcher main page search
for the igro culture podcast find that
review section give me a festar rating
honestly you can give me as many stars
as you feel I believe I just want that
five if you can helps me move up in the
ranks more people listen to the show the
more people that listen to the show more
people that grow Organics more people
that grow Organics the more Organics you
have to smoke the more people that are
smoking Organics more people want more
people to grow Organics more people
start growing weed the more people grow
organic weed the more we outgrow
overgrow the government the more we
legalize cannabis the more people listen
to my podcast repeat and grow your own
food in there too I want that on a shirt
all of that that I just said printed on
the front of a shirt and then repeat and
then write it on the back again and then
just spin around and just have somebody
keep spin around more trees less
[ __ ] someone really famous said that
but I I can't remember their name or
what they did I wonder why they they
have a cool hey I want to congratulate
Jesse for making it all the way through
this episode yeah I took like a whole
bunch of dabs too so yeah you did couple
of you guys didn't even hear he took a
little nap on the couch last time was
cute all right great nap guys don't
forget that the podcast is available on
iTunes Stitcher and every single episode
is archived on iy genetics
colorado.com make sure you follow us on
Twitter and Instagram and Facebook
search for igro culture if you're
interested in sponsoring the podcast I
do have a couple of openings uh if you
have a product you would like us to
review I would like to do that also send
me an emails ulture hotmail.com I'll get
you all the information you need uh we
do need our own theme song if you want
to make a cool ass ree theme song um on
the next episode I hope to have Spence
here I can't promise PR you anything but
I really hope to get Spence here Jess
may be here also man thank you guys for
taking time out of your day to come
we're all busy Growers it's great to get
all three of us met here everybody was
on
time freaking crazy dude you were on
time like that that that coffee stop
counts as you were still on time even
after that in our world it was awesome
all right so until next time guys shout
out to my ninja Spence thanks for
listening take a fat dab give your mom a
hug for
me waking up next to a topnotch female
roll out the bed and click the button
checking my Emil well friends and fans
from across the land from Japan extended
F both the Mystic root B and man I got
to thank the Lord up above alls that I'm
getting connect with your music it's
been years I've known you what's it like
to be from Roots up in Califor yeah
what's it like living my life rocking
mics every night smoking purple and
white is tight I can't lie I'm loving
how I'm living since birth I've been
giving aition plus the gift is spitting
hot now all over my be can't be stop now
see me your now got it lock