hey what's up everybody it is time for
episode 431 of the Grove from your heart
podcast this episode of the show is
brought to you by my friends at the
hella dank seed company if you need new
seeds in your garden I highly recommend
the hella dank seed company and you can
find them at www.sedar.com a tradition
that we start this podcast off by
talking about what I'm dabbing I think
you can still hear my last dab in my
voice it was highly effective and it was
delicious
I just took a dab of miracle alien
cookies full spectrum extract from our
friends at Green Dot labs yes that is
the Mac this concentrate is delicious
and it got me high as [ __ ] on the
package it says this is a blend of alien
cookies and Colombian Starfighter the
flavor is described as jelly biscuits
and lavender I don't know that I tasted
jelly biscuits but I absolutely did
taste and smell the lavender on the
exhale on the back of the package it
says that this product contains
seventy-three point eight eight percent
THC I've honestly been smoking another
concentrate that says it contains 98%
total cannabinoids and this miracle
alien cookies full spectrum extract
immediately put me in another place it
took me somewhere beyond where that 98%
concentrate has been putting me so don't
fall for the hype don't rely too much on
the numbers lab testing is great but it
should not be the main deciding factor
when it comes to choosing your medicine
I've got one concentrate in my hand that
says it contains 98% total cannabinoids
and then I've also got this miracle
alien cookies which says it has 73.8%
total cannabinoids
I would rather dab this 73.8%
concentrate over this 98% concentrate
almost anytime I think it tastes better
and I think the buzz is more desirable
so that tells me that it's not all about
the THC that it is a lot to do with the
other compounds that are in there the
terpenes the flavonoids whatever else is
in this product that other let's see
we've got 74 percent approximately that
other 26% of stuff is actually making me
enjoy the buzz a little bit better so
big shout out once again to our friends
at Green Dot labs for the delicious and
tremendous miracle alien cookies full
spectrum act
tract this [ __ ] has me high as giraffe
[ __ ] ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls smokers and growers in this
episode I am going to read a couple of
emails from some listeners those emails
will segue us into doing a couple of
strain descriptions before we get there
let's do a couple of shout outs to our
friends on patreon I want to give a
giant grow from your heart podcast shout
out to my friend farmer John how about a
big grow from your heart podcast shout
out to David OQ I always want to send a
big groove from your heart podcast fist
bump to my buddy Aldridge and last but
certainly not least a big giant grow
from your heart podcast shout out and a
fist bump to my buddy Sam if you would
like to learn how to become a patron you
can do so by going to patreon.com slash
grow from your heart all the information
you need will be right there on the
screen alright ladies and gentlemen at
the start of the show I said that I had
a couple of emails let's not waste any
more time let's jump right into this
first email let's see if I can say their
name right on the message it says no
names on the podcast if you read this so
I know not to say your name let's get
right into it it goes a lot like this
hey Jeff I've been listening for over a
year and I have bought seeds hey thank
you for buying seeds not only on my ipod
caster I am also a seed breeder some
people may not know that I am the the
only breeder the only proprietor of I
read genetics Colorado that is all me
and this person has bought seeds thank
you I appreciate that those seeds are
available at dank seed store that is the
hella dank seed company my seeds are
also available at Oregon elite seeds you
can also find my seeds at gringo beans
and the very near future I will be
announcing another vendor that I'm very
proud to be involved with let's keep
moving this email continues it says I
think you would sell even more seeds if
you made more strain info available I
shop heavily with Duke diamond mainly
because he has those growing tips on the
package and on seeds here now listings
he has great descriptions and grow notes
and tips hey I love the constructive
criticism I don't have a lot of details
on my packaging my packaging is very
minimalistic I kind of have one generic
package then I put a sticker on it to
identify the strains so my packaging yes
does not contain a lot of info however
my website has
overly detailed descriptions of every
strain that I have available plus stuff
that I released a long time ago and his
since been discontinued so on my website
you should be able to find information
on every strain available and I put a
lot of the older strains that are
discontinued up there also because they
were used as parents and current crosses
so if you see something like what's one
that I did a lot of work on if you see
something like space force you say well
what the heck is space force space
forces space [ __ ] cross to arise people
may not know what a rise or space
[ __ ] so you can click on space [ __ ]
and you can see that space [ __ ] is a
space Queen from sub cool pollinated by
my reversed grateful dog that made space
[ __ ] then you can also see that a rise
is golden go to day breaker and then you
can start breaking down the family tree
that way because a lot of people who are
buying seeds really want to know really
detailed lineage of what they are buying
so on my website I do have overly
detailed descriptions but I do
appreciate your recommendation and in
the future maybe I will be able to add
more descriptions to my packaging the
message goes on and it says I bought
your lemon jeffery after listening to
that strain review episode because it is
cool to hear the breeder give tips and a
little of what to expect well that means
a lot to me I'm glad that you are
appreciated and trusted my review and
I'm glad you got some seeds by being
inspired off of that episode so that
helps out man I hope they went crazy I
hope you grew the [ __ ] out of those I
hope it made you completely happy let's
continue with the message it says I
understand that you don't like to toot
your own horn on the show by doing
strain reviews for every offering and
who knows maybe I would get sick of a
month of strain reviews but how about an
episode or two where you give a shorter
presentation on each strain perhaps a
quick story a few fee knows to look for
a tip or two and then take a dab of it
and describe it to us
hey that is a wonderful idea and you're
right it does feel a little bit weird
sitting here and talking about my
favorite strains the strains that I've
created the strains that I've made
available it feels egotistical and it
feels kind of weird doing it but so many
people ask for it that I do feel like it
is time to put out a few more strain
episodes so look forward to those in
fact in this episode we are going to
jump into some strain descriptions
pretty soon here there's more to this
email and it goes like this you hit a
bunch of strains dished out a ton of
info on the dude
Grolsch oh and that was with Scottie
taking up time too I think a couple of
episodes would be enough to really push
your seed sales through the roof and
help all those customers get what they
are really looking for hey Thank You Man
I appreciate that it is great to hear
advice and guidance from consumers I am
on this end of the business you're on
that end I need to know what you're
thinking so I do appreciate this sort of
feedback thank you he wraps up the email
and it says you are the man thanks again
for all the info and the entertainment
and then he ends it by signing his name
and he asked me not to say that so I'm
going to keep your name private hey
thank you for the great message thank
you for the encouragement and thank you
for the constructive criticism I do
appreciate that people don't know where
they can improve where they're making
mistakes until sometimes somebody points
that out to them so thank you I know now
goodbye
doing a little better strain
descriptions on my packaging and having
a little bit better of a strain
description on the vendor website so
that maybe I may sell a few more seed
packages which would always be nice for
myself as a seed seller and always nice
for the people on the other end who are
getting seeds that they need so thank
you for the great advice I will take
that to heart in fact we are going to
use some of your advice on this episode
let's get right into the next email
because it goes a lot like this hey I'm
in prohibition land so please don't say
my name I just wanted to say that your
podcast has helped me immensely in my
growing efforts I work nine hours a day
as a janitor basically sweeping floors
and being bored all day and your podcast
helps so much to pass the time a man I'm
glad I'm making your day go by that has
got to get tedious just sweeping floors
I'm glad I'm there to entertain you at
least one or two days a week thanks for
listening
feels like we've got a great
relationship already he goes on to say I
love the show lessons or I love the grow
lessons and I also love the episodes
with white Mike hey white Mike you got a
shout-out bro it's time to come to
another episode he goes on to say I just
finished my first grow and I was
honestly feeling a little discouraged
and I had thoughts of giving up growing
because I did not get the yield I had
wanted but then I heard you talk on one
of the grow lessons about how to not be
discouraged by your first grow and to
instead use it as a learning opportunity
and that advice has stuck with me yeah
you can't give up on the first try of
anything remember the first time you
played Mario Kart you sucked it was
embarrassing it was no fun you couldn't
keep that damn car on the track you
couldn't go around the corners right
somebody threw a banana at you any
[ __ ] spun out you were angry but now
everybody kicks ass at Mario Kart so you
can't expect to be really good at
anything the first time you try it I was
a terrible drummer the first time I got
sticks people wanted to beat me to death
with my drumsticks now I can hold the
fat groove all day long don't feel
discouraged if you are not a pro at
something the very first time don't
expect to be a pro at growing the very
first time if you have a successful crop
that you can smoke out of your first
grow that is success and like this guy
says use it as a learning experience now
you've got a baseline to start from if
your next grow is worse you should
reconsider [ __ ] if your next girl is
better you were on the path you need to
be on so don't ever get discouraged from
anything you fail at the first time that
is a learning lesson you need to fail
the first time because if you're
successful if you're hugely successful
at anything the first time it gets to
your ego and you start teaching yourself
bad habits because you already know
everything so you got to [ __ ] up you got
to be humbled then you can improve so
let's continue with this email it says I
am now on my second grow and I'm growing
Michelangelo from I read genetics and a
five gallon pot with Fox Farms ocean
forest soil and I'm using a
horticultural lighting group 100 grow
light with a 2x2 grow tent he says I
live in a one-room cabin without much
space but I am feeling more confident
about this grow thanks to the help of
your podcast
he goes on to say if you have any tips
for that strain it would be awesome to
hear them I'm sorry for the rambling
email but I wanted to let you know that
your show is amazing and tell you to
keep up the good work man dude this is a
great email thank you so this guy
started off disappointed in his first
grow but listening to the podcast
encouraged him to give it a second try
so I'm proud of you for going in for a
second try even though the first time
kind of disappointed you
this time he has got a great setup he's
got some Michelangelo seeds that is a
platinum tangi pollinated by a reversed
blueberry cookies
so he's got some feminized seeds that
are very reliable I know what they were
gonna do these are going to be great in
that grow he's got a five gallon fabric
pot with Fox farms ocean forest soil
that is going to be great for this grow
he's using the appropriate light he's
got an HL G 100 and his two by two ten
so that is going to be perfect he's
probably got one five gallon pot under
this light in a two by two tent this
should provide perfect medicine for one
person now he says if you have any tips
for the Michelangelo it would be awesome
to hear them now this is the point in
the episode where that first email
talking about strain descriptions and
strain review episodes is going to
collide with this email where our new
friend is asking for advice and guidance
on the strain Michelangelo now let's
shift podcast gears and do a few strain
reviews I'm not going to start with the
Michelangelo today I want to start with
the strain that I call Leonardo Leonardo
is a very important strain to me
leonardo was made from a reversed
blueberry cookies plant which is a
platinum cookies cross to the blueberry
tahoe so you can already imagine the
smells and aromas coming from there I
had the blueberry cookies plant and I
reversed it which means I treated it
with a solution that solution made that
plant produce pollen sacks those pollen
sacks produced pollen that only contain
female chromosomes I have done complete
episodes on reversing plants I have done
full episodes on selfed and reversed
plants if you want more information on
that check out episode number 330 one
called selfing and reversals I go into
deep detail there today we're going to
focus on these few strains because I can
tell that this episode is going to get
quite long so I took the blueberry
cookies and I selfed it so that is a
blueberry cookies s 1 that is the
Leonardo let's talk briefly about
Leonardo Leonardo is the blueberry
cookies s1 being self that means it
doesn't have a lot of opportunity for
Fino typical variation you're going to
find very common phenotypes in there
blueberry cookies will grow tall and
fast in veg coming from the Tahoe og
parents and the Girl Scout cookies
parents she likes to get kind of tall
she will make long branches she also
makes giant colas most of the crosses
that came from the blueberry
cookies really take off in height but
they make up for it because they make
gigantic top colas so be prepared for
taller plants maybe flour just a little
bit early expect your plants to double
in size from the time you flip them to
the end of flour so the blueberry
cookies will get tall and it makes tall
offspring but they make gigantic buds so
it is worth it you will get heavy
harvests from almost all of the
blueberry cookies crosses almost every
phenotype will give you big fat harvests
so Leonardo is going to get kind of tall
and make gigantic buds I like to give
Leo about eight and a half to ten weeks
to finish it depends on your environment
it depends on your room it depends on
your feeding somewhere between eight and
a half to ten weeks will be perfect for
this plant somewhere between sixty and
seventy days everything that comes from
the Leonardo crosses can be fed very
heavily and they also like to drink a
lot I've noticed that most of them love
to suck up more water than the average
plant so don't be afraid to feed them
heavily and you're gonna have to water
them frequently so be on top of that now
all of the crosses that come from the
Leonardo the reversed blueberry cookies
they are all huge producers they make
gigantic buds they all make tremendous
resin production they are all super
potent they're all going to take
somewhere between eight and a half to
ten weeks to finish the thing that is
really going to make these crosses stand
out is all of the unique flavors and
aromas I used very carefully selected
females for these crosses and my goal
was to make ridiculous candy Terps and I
feel like I nailed that goal so let's
talk about the flavors and aromas from
the blueberry cookies the dominant smell
of course is the blueberry but it also
has a funk to it it is almost like blue
nerds or some sort of blue candy maybe
blue skittles it kind of reminds me of
when I was younger and I used to buy
those blue raspberry lollipops and I
would suck on those and it would turn my
whole face blue it kind of reminds me of
those kind of suckers with a Wang to it
it's got something sharper something
funky to it it's like blue nerds and
skittles with dirty feet in the bag or
something it is really enjoyable and I
really love that funky everybody that
smells it really loves that aroma that
is part of what inspired me to work with
this a very well-known grower
and breeder smokes some of the finished
product and when he smoked it he said
man this is amazing
are there any seeds available and I said
there aren't any seeds available and he
said can somebody reverse this and make
some seeds so that I could take this
back to her I live and grow it there and
everybody kind of looked at me and it
became my job to reverse the blueberry
cookies and make seeds of it for this
friend of ours who's a highly respected
member of the cannabis community I was
honored to accept that job but when I do
something like that I don't just make
one cross I had to think about it and I
chose a few of my favorite females to
put in the room along with the blueberry
cookies to pollinate them also and I
feel like I made very wise choices on
the girls that I selected but let's keep
focusing on the blueberry cookies for a
moment we're still talking about the
flavors here it is unique it is crazy it
is like blue raspberries and it is like
blue skittles and the flavor just hangs
out in your mouth for a long time you'll
have tremendous cottonmouth you'd be
like I really need a drink but you won't
want to drink anything because that
cottonmouth flavor from the blueberry
cookies is just so delicious so a lot of
the crosses are going to be dominated by
that blueberry cookies blue raspberry
funky chirp so keep that in mind as we
talk about all of the next crosses the
next cross I want to talk about that was
made from that reversed blueberry
cookies is a strain I call Donatello
Donatello was made by the reversed
blueberry cookies pollinating my
favorite lemon skunk female I talked
about that lemon skunk female a lot that
is the mother of the lemon Jeffrey she
is also the mother of Firefly that lemon
skunk has made a lot of great progeny
I've been working with her for several
years because I love that plant it
smells amazing it is gorgeous it puts
off beautiful colors beautiful bright
bright light green colors with beautiful
orange pistils it is such a gorgeous
plant it smells like lemon candy and
sort of a lemon sorbet sort of a thing
I've never smelled anything like it it
came from seed so I'm the only one that
has got that phenotype as far as I've
ever seen I think it's an amazing plant
I loved working with that lemon skunk I
loved it because of the aromas the
structure everything about it is
beautiful when I crossed it to the
blueberry cookies it put a lemon lime
blueberry sort of a Wang to it it is
really amazing it's
sort of like a key lime pie with
blueberries in the middle or a blue
raspberry key lime kind of a pie sort of
a thing going on I really like the
aromas and flavors of that one
Donatello does grow tall because of that
lemon skunk but it's got big thick fat
branches so it can get tall and it can
handle being cracked it can handle being
bent it can handle being worked into a
net it likes that sort of a stuff again
I think it should go about eight to ten
weeks for best results it is going to
vary depending on your environment based
on your humidity your temperature and
your nutrients a lot of things will
determine the factor of how long it
takes for these plants to finish in your
room but somewhere between 60 and 70
days should be perfect one thing I
should note about the Donatello most of
these strains I'm talking about get
quite tall Donatello is one of the more
branchy strains it will widen out it
wants a little bit more space than the
rest of its sisters in this line it
wants to spread its arms just a little
bit more and it does get a little bit
branch here so you may need to be
prepared with Stakes tomato cages or
some sort of scrog net because she may
need some training she's gonna try to
widen out on you also she will need some
supports later in Flour because those
long branches will need some support
again all of these strains love it when
you put them in a scrub they love it
when you crack them when you super crop
them when you twist them when you pop
them they like being topped all of these
plants can take pretty good abuse
because of the parents I selected now
let's talk about the strain that
inspired this episode let's talk about
Michelangelo Michelangelo is made from a
platinum tangi female that was of course
pollinated by that blueberry cookies
male the platinum tangi has its own
crazy unique aromas it is like dirty
greasy oranges it's like candy oranges
that you've got at the motor-oil shop or
something like that it is delicious and
funky I tend to like those really fruity
flavors with something nasty on top of
it it just seems to be one of my
favorite sort of varieties to find it's
something with a real familiar citrusy
fruit thing and then just dirty it up
with some funk I really like that what
I've noticed in most of the Michelangelo
seeds is that it is dominantly oranges
it comes out as just sweet gross oranges
almost orange rinds almost overpowering
orange cleaner oranges sometimes have a
overpowering a stringent aroma when you
get too close to the rind and I think
sometimes the mic
Angelou can carry bat and some of the
phenotypes it is overpoweringly orange
and it is amazing if you want to make
concentrates that taste like straight-up
tangerines and oranges Michelangelo is
the way to go for you our friend stabby
mixed adversan gruesome Michelangelo
that the jar still smells like oranges
and tangerines and it's been empty for
over a month now so the flavors from
Michelangelo is dominantly oranges with
a little bit of that skittle e funk on
top of it that candy funk sweetness
which I really enjoy Michelangelo is
another one that will branch out a
little bit for you coming from that
platinum tangi that one doesn't get
super tall it's kind of a short squat
plant that makes the Michelangelo do
kind of the same thing she stays a
little shorter than the rest don't get
me wrong she will get tall on you she'll
make big plants but she has a little
branch here she widens out a little bit
more but she makes really thick stalks
so she can support herself a little
better than the Donatello again like all
of these crosses Michelangelo will love
being scrubbed she'll love being trained
she'll love being topped these plants
can all take quite a bit of abuse
another thing I should note Michelangelo
may be the earliest finisher out of this
bunch I keep saying that some of them
should take 60 to 70 days Mikey may
finish as early as 56 or 55 days don't
be in a rush let it finish if it wants
to go longer let it but some of the
phenotypes
coming from that platinum tangi cross do
make it finish a little bit earlier so
that is Michelangelo let's talk next
about Raphael I'm sure by now you have
found the trend and the theme and these
strains that I made you can see where
these names came from let's talk about
Raphael Raphael is the Strawberry Fields
from Crockett farms pollinated by the
reversed blueberry cookies that
Strawberry Fields plant is great to grow
it makes giant colas and that definitely
came through in the cross raphael likes
to make giant huge top colas that are
just coated in trichomes and they smell
ridiculous it is like strawberries and
tangerines and there's a little bit of a
grapefruit thing going on in there and
then you get that blueberry skittles
that kind of backs it up it is really
hard to describe because it is just so
funky it's tropical its strawberries its
mangos its pineapples its bananas it's
got a little bit of all that tropical
fruit Plus that we
funk that I like it is really delicious
it almost tastes like in my opinion and
people think I'm crazy sometimes with my
strain descriptions but a lot of people
love it a lot of times when I smoke a
DAB my mouth gets really dry I feel like
when I smoked the Raphael my mouth gets
juicy it tastes like I just ate juicy
candy or juicy fruit and my mouth is
actually moist from it so I'm not
thirsty when I smoked the Raphael
concentrates and one thing I should add
to that is Raphael makes great
concentrates and it makes a lot of
concentrates everybody that presses it
that washes it that extracts it in any
way they always report back that they
got impressive returns and then later on
they always report that it tasted
amazing
so Raphael is great for concentrates it
is also great for production if you need
something with fat harvest and good bag
appeal and unique aromas Raphael is
perfect for you I've got two more
strains I want to talk about here in
this strain review episode the next one
I want to talk about is called bebop
bebop is my prized arise number four
female pollinated by the reversed
blueberry cookies so those are two of my
best tasting favorite to grow favorite
to smoke best lab testing easiest to
work with strains and I cross them and
the results were almost exactly what I
expected I turbocharged the good traits
from both of those plants I basically
made bigger badder blueberry cookies
with more potency and more trichomes and
it seems to grow with more vigor bebop
does tend to get a little bit tall
that's because it has got the Joseph og
the Kim D the Tahoe and the cookies all
in there that is going to result in
taller plants also this is one of the
longer finishing crosses in this line I
keep saying that most of these plants
are going to take about eight to ten
weeks I really recommend that you let
this one go closer to ten weeks if
you've got the opportunity in that last
week it's going to add potency and it is
going to give itself just another week
to just bulk up so it'll get even bigger
and fatter on you and it'll be well
worth that extra week if you can let it
go that full seventy days so bee bop
does get kind of tall she does take a
little bit longer to finish but she is
ridiculously potent arises one of my
highest lab testing strains the
blueberry cookies always test really
high in the lab when we grow it in a
commercial facility so when I
those I knew that the potency would be
off the charts the trichome development
on these plants will be ridiculous the
flavors and aromas are crazy it is kind
of the blueberry cookies really
dominates the flavor you get that blue
skittles blueberry cookies blue
raspberry sort of a flavor but then it's
got a wonderful disgusting skunky og
cushioning in the back end of it that
you don't notice until you exhale you
inhale and it's straight-up candy and
deliciousness and then you blow it out
and you're like oh that is dank it's two
different flavors in your mouth it is
really amazing so that is the be-bop the
main thing about her is that she is the
longest flowering one out of the line
and she's going to get tall but she
makes up for it with amazing potency and
tremendous flavor so if you've got the
space the height and the patience bebop
is a great one for you the last one in
this line that we were going to talk
about is what is left the one called
rock steady rock steady is a Durban
poison female pollinated by the reversed
blueberry cookies this one is one of my
favorites it is also a huge
crowd-pleaser
rock steady grows ridiculously fast and
makes ridiculously giant buds rock
steady is going to get tall like the
rest of these plants she will finish in
that eight to ten week time frame
something to think about with Rocksteady
is it does not like as much water as the
rest of these crosses coming from that
Durban poison female it wants a little
bit less water than the rest of the
plant so pay attention
also it likes to widen out real far you
will get a real Big Top Cola but then
you'll get some branches that want to
kind of stretch out and make some space
she is going to need cages or supports
or she works wonderfully in a screen of
green system she kind of programs
herself automatically to reach out she's
beautiful in a screen of green you can
really Weaver in their super nicely now
the flavors that come off of Rocksteady
are hard to describe of course it's got
that blueberry cookies flavor it's got
that blue raspberry thing going on to it
but then you put that Durban poison I
think Durban poison has a hint of mint
in the background of the aroma and then
everybody describes that other flavor as
anise oil which I'm not sure of it I've
ever smelled real anise but it's got
that Durban poison sort of a peppery
sort of a thing sort of a mint thing
going on with that blueberry cookies
thing and it also creates soar
of a raspberry kind of aroma I really
don't know where the raspberry comes
from but many of the phenotypes have a
raspberry aroma and flavor coming off of
them and I really enjoy it maybe some of
that flavor is blackberries as well it's
got that sort of a tart thing that a
fresh berries got but it also has that
fruity thing so it's really it's really
complex it's really unique it's kind of
hard to describe
other than that blue raspberry flavor
with that perfect Durban poison
combination to it it is exactly what you
thought it would taste like if you cross
those two together so I think that is
enough on the breakdown of leonardo
Donatello Michelangelo Raphael bebop and
rocksteady just to wrap it up all of
them are going to grow fairly tall the
ones that are going to push out a little
bit more for you are the Michelangelo
and the bebop the Rocksteady is going to
grow a little more sideways it's not
going to exactly push out it branches
out and those branches need supports it
kind of looks like most of the Durban
poison crosses want to stay lower to the
ground and push out a little bit and
then produce one big top so if we train
them if we give them some supports they
really work well they lift themselves up
and they work beautifully I love that
flavor and aroma and the potency can't
be beat so I'm going to keep working
with the Durban poison that is an
excellent strain Rocksteady may need a
little extra attention out of all of
those but if you're running a screen of
green that is the ideal strain for you
all of these strains are going to
produce crazy ridiculous candy
out-of-control fruity turps you're going
to need some sort of odor control and to
wrap it all up most of them are going to
finish in about eight to ten weeks of
course that is phenotype dependent that
is environment dependent that could be
nutrient light humidity dependent but
most of them will take about 56 to 70
days to be finished now I didn't go too
deep into specific phenotypes to look
for within each strain most of the time
honestly it is going to be about a 50/50
mix of each parent you're going to find
things that look a lot like the
blueberry cookies and then you're going
to find things that look a lot like the
female I crossed it too and then you'll
find things that kind of dominate or are
50/50 mixes you're going to find very
close representations to both parents
and beautiful combinations in every pack
so that is a quick breakdown on six of
my favorite feminized lines I do
more feminized seeds coming out in July
we will talk about one of those strains
on the show in the very near future if
you would like more information about
any of those strains or if you'd like to
see photos there are highly detailed
descriptions on my website my website is
Irie genetics Colorado calm click on the
genetics tab all of the information on
all of the strains will be available I
do know that the website isn't the most
advanced piece of technology on the
planet all the information you need is
currently there and we are updating the
website behind the scenes as we speak
if you are interested in acquiring eye
region that exceeds you can find them at
seeds here now calm my seeds are also
available at Oregon elite seeds calm
also you can find my stuff at dank seed
dot store every time I release feminized
seeds they sell out very quickly so if
they do not have what you're looking for
have no fear because I will make more of
all of these lines in the very near
future
all right podcast world it is time for
me to start wrapping up the show don't
forget to visit our friends at seeds
here now.com oregon elite seeds calm and
dank seed store also if you feel like
this podcast was educational informative
or entertaining and you would like to
make a financial contribution to the
show you can do so by going to
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
all of the information you need to
become a patron will be right there on
the screen I would also appreciate it if
you stalk me on social media on Facebook
simply search for the growth from your
heart podcast on Twitter it's @gf wih
podcast on Instagram I use Irie
underscore genetics and I cordially
invite you to join me on my new favorite
application called cannabis cannabis is
a cannabis friendly social media
application where we can post pictures
of our cannabis plants and nobody will
take them down
nobody will report them nobody will
delete our accounts so join myself join
my friends junior token and Q groves
over at cannabis I look forward to
seeing you give me a follow its Irie
underscore genetics on cannabis if
you've got something you'd like to say
and you're not in all of that social
media nonsense maybe you've got a
product you'd like me to review maybe
you'd like to sponsor the podcast or
maybe you just want to send me a grow
question I would love to hear from you
my email address is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com
send me an email let me know what's on
your mind don't forget to follow the
show on YouTube again simply search for
the girl from your heart podcast click
the subscribe button leave a few
comments let me know what you think
about the podcast right there on YouTube
all right podcast world that is all I've
got for you today I want to give a huge
shout out to my buddy - naw see and
until next time take a phat dab and give
your mom a hug for me