hey welcome back ladies and gentlemen
boys and girls smokers and growers it is
time for episode 433 of the growth from
your heart podcast this episode of the
show is brought to you by seeds here now
if you need new seeds in your garden I
highly recommend seeds here now and you
can find them at www.cdxzipstream.com
abba noids
star dog is one of my favorite strains
to grow and definitely one of my
favorite strains to smoke so big shout
out to our friends at apothecary farms
for the delicious star dog ambrosia
batter in this episode I'm going to go
over a really long listener email that
contains multiple questions I'm going to
briefly cover each of those questions
before we get there let's do a few
shoutouts to our friends on patreon how
about a big ladies first shout out to my
friend Miss Mel a big gigantic
grow from your heart a podcast shout out
to our friend Kenny you dig it a giant
girl from your heart podcast shout out
to Hogan farms of course a big Viking
handshake too my friend Grimble the
druid and last but certainly not least I
want to give a big high-elevation shout
out to our friend bag
seed Jesse I want to thank everybody for
all of the continued patreon support if
you would like to learn how to become a
patron you can do so by going to
www.mobileaustinnotary.com
I want to give a big shout out to James
bean and the entire seeds here-now crew
that is an honor and a pleasure to be a
part of the
seeds here now team so make sure you
guys check out seeds here now calm and
grab yourself some I read genetics the
golden goat BX sold out in just a couple
of hours they do have a lot of a rise
and they have a lot of other great
varieties available and I will be
restocking that golden goat
very soon so make sure you check out
seeds here now dot-com
all right podcast world at the start of
the show I said I was going to read a
long email with multiple questions let's
get into that portion of the show if
you've got a cannabis culture or a
cannabis cultivation question and you
would like me to read that question on
the show you can send me an email my
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com and you know i would love to
hear from you this message for today's
episode goes just like this dear Rasta
Jeff this is my second email to you my
first message was read on episode 350 so
cheers dude you are welcome to read my
name out loud so this message comes from
our friend John and it goes a lot like
this a couple of things I heard you call
up for music on podcast 400 and I will
see what I can do for you
I checked out fish to get an idea of
what you like and I will see what I can
come up with hey that's pretty cool of
you man don't try to make too much of a
fishy sound for an intro I would prefer
something kind of reggae kind of
up-tempo reggae kind of kicks in the
door remember how we used to start it
with that beat that would just kick off
right away something that Kicks down the
door and says hey it's time for a
podcast that's what I would love
something kind of reggae like if you
made a fish type song I will certainly
play it that sounds great so yes I did
ask for music on episode 400 I did not
get a new theme song if anybody out
there would like to make a theme song
like I said something reggae something
that kicks in the door something that
has not been posted to YouTube before
because if you have already posted it to
YouTube YouTube will flag me when I post
it and say that I am stealing your
content so it's got to be fresh original
material if you'd like me to play it on
the show so so far John you are off to a
great start you are making me an intro
that probably sounds like fish and I
appreciate that I will play it on the
show it will make a great vibe there is
more to the message it says a few grow
questions and this is where it gets fun
question number a budget grows how do I
control humidity when the lights go out
when it is time for the girls to go to
bed
there is always a huge humidity spike
which is difficult to control on a
budget I have a cheap 100 pound not the
weight but the price 100 pound
dehumidifier which removes moisture from
the air and is fine whilst the lights
are on but fails to control the humidity
during darkness humidity spikes it would
be worse without the dehumidifier but it
struggles to get the RH down to desired
levels during darkness is this a fact of
life for all gardeners unless you have
access to serious equipment I can't
afford a better dehumidifier or the
power to run it any tips for a novice
grower on a brutal budget so this
listener has a very common problem when
the lights go out in their grow
environment the humidity spikes
drastically and this person is getting
concerned that it may cause a problem
and their grow and they need a way to
control that humidity without spending a
ton of money perhaps without spending
any money they said that the budget is
low they cannot afford a better
dehumidifier or even the power to run it
so let's talk about things that we could
do things that need to be done the first
thing I would suggest is maybe turn on
the dehumidifier earlier I don't know
when you were starting that dehumidifier
so I don't know when it is starting to
remove the moisture from the air your
problem is happening right when the
lights go off maybe if we start turning
on the dehumidifier an hour before the
lights go off we can start prepping the
environment and removing some of the air
beforehand now what's gonna happen is
the lights are gonna go off and that
plants are gonna start respiring and
transpiring and they're gonna let out
moisture but maybe we can remove enough
moisture from the air before the lights
go off to where when the lights do go
off it is not such a drastic swing so
maybe when the lights are on you're
running about 50% humidity maybe 40%
humidity when the lights go off you're
probably peaking up to 60 70 maybe 80%
humidity I don't know your environment
maybe if we start turning on that
dehumidifier one maybe two hours before
lights go off we can reduce the amount
of moisture in that air low enough to
compensate for that giant swing when it
does happen when the lights go off that
is going to be my first plan of attack
try to get ahead of the humidity problem
before it happens we know it's going to
happen we know when it's going to happen
maybe we can remove moisture from the
air before that time comes and give
ourselves a head start
now I don't know how larger gross space
is I don't have a lot of details on your
grow environment I don't know how many
plants are in there I don't know what
size containers those plants are in I
don't know how much moisture you are
adding to the room or how frequently
that is happening so with the small
amount of information I have got I don't
have a lot to work with no matter what
size that environment is I think you
need to install some sort of extraction
fan to remove the humidity from that
environment and send it somewhere else
if you've got a small grow tent
something like maybe a four inch
extraction fan maybe a computer fan up
in the top corner would work that may be
efficient anything to help pull some of
that stale humid air out of that
environment would be beneficial now if
you have something larger you may need a
larger extraction fan I don't know your
environment I don't know the size of
your space I don't know how much
moisture is in there but your best bet
next to another dehumidifier would be
some way of extracting that humid air
from that room something like a squirrel
cage blower or something like a vortex
fan or something like a can fan
something to move that old air out of
the room I keep saying I don't know how
large your environment is the size of
your gross space is going to determine
how much air you need to move out of
that room now when you go sucking air
out of the room you start thinking about
odor that's when you start thinking
about a carbon filter which is when this
starts to get expensive I don't know if
you've got neighbors or people that you
need to conceal the aroma from but if
you were extracting your odor outside of
your home or just somewhere other people
may come in contact with that air you
need to clean the aroma out of that air
so you will need a carbon filter I've
done a full Episode on carbon filters
episode number 430 is all about a carbon
filter and where to place that filter
that lesson would apply greatly to your
question here now I know you were on a
budget but this is what I would do if
this were possible I would get the
appropriate size extraction fan for your
grow environment I would try to hang
that extraction fan in the top center of
my flowering room if you can get it as
high as possible and in the dead center
that is your best bet I understand that
ceiling space is limited I understand
that height is limited and I understand
that things are heavy so we can't always
mount things to the ceiling but that is
the best place for this extraction fan
so I would hang that fan from the
ceiling then I would run ducting from
that ceiling to the wall then I would
cut the appropriate size hole in the
wall and I would run that ducting
through the wall now I don't know where
it needs to go once it gets out of that
room do you need to run it even further
down another hallway is that going
outside at that point that's a whole
another thing to think about but now you
were sucking air through that blower
you're blowing it down the ducting and
it is going out of your grow environment
you're going to remove heat and you are
going to remove humidity by doing so at
the same time you are going to be
blasting odoriferous cannabis scented
air straight through that ducting
wherever that air ends up so that is
when I recommend a carbon filter I would
recommend you hang a carbon filter then
your blower vineyard ducting out of the
grow environment now I do understand
that earlier you said you don't have a
budget to work with you said you cannot
afford a better dehumidifier and you
said you cannot afford the power to run
it if you can't afford a big expensive
blower and a carbon filter maybe
something like a small computer fan
anything that will just blow some air
out of that room from the top would be
helpful now I understand that buying a
blower and buying a carbon filter and
buying ducting does cost money and I
really don't have a more affordable
solution that humid air either needs to
be sucked out or blown out of that room
or treated by the dehumidifier those are
basically your two options other things
we can't think about are where is excess
water coming from do you have any
standing water in that room after you
water is there water left in your catch
tray or your runoff saucer or whatever
you're using is there water left in the
room maybe you can use a shot back and
suck that up and get that out of the
room another thing that will help in
this may sound crazy is a little bit of
defoliation if those leaves aren't there
they can't let out water so that may be
another way to help combat your humidity
issue so hopefully one of those options
work maybe a combination of those things
will help you out I'm sorry I don't have
a really easy solution that will fix
this that could be free it sounds like
you may have to spend a few bucks on
this and if you do go with the blower
route I highly recommend that carbon
filter because a carbon filter a blower
and some ducting is much more affordable
than a court case for an illegal grow
all right there are a lot of questions
in this email so let's keep moving
question number B says
low stress training when should it start
is there a method to the madness are
scrog nets worth the hassle if LST has
been done properly and is there anything
you should not do when low stress
training that's a lot to think about you
can start LST as soon as those plants
are thick enough and robust enough to
handle being cracked and being twisted
being manipulated if you feel like the
plant can take it go for it
usually I would wait for them to get
about the thickness of a big pen or a
pencil before I start cracking on them
but you can start as soon as you feel
like they can take a little bit of abuse
and that is going to be strain and maybe
phenotype specific so be careful with
that now there is a method to the
madness I'm not sure what type of low
stress training you were doing there are
very many different options that you can
do I like to grab the plant and give it
a little twist and pop it I like to do
that a lot the method to that is to grab
it kind of close to the stalk put your
other hand above it and twist and just
pop you'll hear it pop and then I do
like that thing we used to do in school
and we tried to decide who goes first in
baseball where you put your hand on the
bat and the next guy puts his hand above
yours the next guy puts his hand above
yours that's how I measure my crack
distance I go crack and I put my hand
above it crack put my hand above it
crack and I just work my way up the stem
that is my method to that madness I
start at the main stalk of the plant and
I go all the way up until it gets kind
of skinny until I'm up to the top then I
do that to every single branch starting
at the lowest branch and work my way up
that branch then to the next branch will
work my way up I popped the [ __ ] out of
those plants that is the method to my
madness again there are several
different methods and approaches to low
stress training I'm not sure what you're
doing as long as you have a goal in mind
and you were observing what is happening
there is a method to your madness don't
just go in there and do a bunch of
different [ __ ] and don't pay attention
if you're gonna do something to plant a
and something to plant B have a reason
make a note of what you did why you did
it in which plant you did it to and then
there is a method to your madness
the next question is our scrog nets
worth it if the LST is done correctly
yes I really like a sprog net I feel
like when the top buds start getting
kind of heavy and floppy if you've got
one two maybe even three layers of scrog
Nets you don't need to get in there with
a bunch of sticks hopefully your buds
are going to get so big
fat that your branches can't support
them even after all of that low stress
training you're still gonna get big fat
giant buds that those sticks are not
ready for in any commercial environment
which I am responsible for I always run
a screen of green system I usually set
up one screen to kind of spread the
plants apart a little bit the second
screen is to kind of guide them to get
them going straight up to put them in
the position where I want the branches
the third one is to support those big
gigantic floppy buds that will happen
around week five six seven and then
continue all the way through week nine
or ten whenever we harvest they're just
gonna get bigger they're gonna get
floppier you don't want to get in there
with a bunch of sticks and bamboo sticks
and tomato cages and [ __ ] I think those
screens really are worth their weight in
gold and they're definitely worth the
hassle once you get good at hanging them
up they're not that hard it almost
becomes as easy as making a bed once you
learn how to do it in a commercial
environment I like to find another guy
that's as tall as myself I'm six five if
I can find another guy that's like six
foot or six too we can hang up trellis
all day no problem it is super fast and
super easy then to wrap up question B he
asks is there anything you would not do
when low stress training really the only
way to learn what not to do is to do
some [ __ ] and see it go wrong that is
the best way to learn anything in a
garden so try some [ __ ] experiment when
you try three or four things and one or
two of them absolutely fail those are
the things not to do again I really
don't know what else to tell you not to
do because I don't know what you're
planning I don't see your devious little
mind applauding what's gonna happen in
that grow so I don't know what to tell
you not to do what I can tell you is to
think twice before you do anything you
can always cut later but you can't put
[ __ ] back so think about it if you're
gonna do something crazy look at the
plants think about what you're gonna do
think to yourself why am I going to do
that what is my desired outcome what is
it going to look like immediately after
I do that what is it gonna look like in
12 hours after I do that what's it gonna
look like in three days what will it be
like in two weeks after I do this how is
this going to affect my final outcome of
my finished product then before you do
that crazy [ __ ] you're thinking about go
smoke a joint go for a walk go play on
the internet then come back and rethink
your [ __ ] and see if it is something you
really want to do because
like I said a moment ago you can always
cut more off but you can't glue leaves
or plant parts back on so think about
everything twice before you're gonna do
it smoke a joint think about it again
maybe ask a friend maybe send me an
email maybe go look on a forum get an
educated decision before you do anything
crazy so that is what I would say not to
do don't do anything ridiculous without
thoroughly thoroughly thinking it
through all right we are ripping right
through this message let's work on
question numbers see question number C
says best seed company in the UK or
Europe for reliable genetics any
recommendations I would like to try your
lemon Jeffrey and golden goat but I have
a difficulty sourcing them in the UK or
Europe I understand that frustration I
get messages like this every day that
people overseas would like to get their
hands on some I read genetics seeds the
best advice I have got for you there is
to try seeds here now.com Oregon elite
seeds calm or dank seed dot store they
may be able to help you out I do not
know they're shipping policies I do not
know where they are willing to ship
seeds but if you're interested in
strictly I read genetics those are the
three top vendors that I would recommend
again that is seeds here now calm Oregon
elite seeds calm and dank seed dot store
those are my three top vendors right now
that may be able to get products to you
in the UK or Europe now even if you do
contact a vendor that can get seeds to
you in the UK or in Europe you will not
be able to get any lemon Jeffrey or
feminized golden goat seeds until at
least the middle of July those seeds are
not ready yet they are currently sold
out and almost every outlet that I know
of I am making more right now they are
almost done but they will not be
available anywhere until July all right
let's work our way into question number
D question D on this email goes like
this upgrade so if you start with a one
meter square budget tent a 400 watt
light a small dehumidifier and a 4-inch
extractor fan at some point you will
want to upgrade now you've just given me
a really good idea of your grow I wish
you would have started with that I would
have had more accurate better more clear
advice but this is where we are now so
let's keep going the question is
can you give me any advice on upgrading
as many upgrades I suspect will only
give you tiny gains and maybe rather
pointless unless you are upping your
game altogether to a much larger grow
with commercial aspirations are there
any big gains for small grows then he
says by the way I appreciate that the
best gains are achieved by knowing and
loving your plants yes absolutely
understanding the plants developing a
relationship with each cultivar is the
best way to improve and grow top notch
product but let's look at the equipment
you've already got you've got a decent
light you have got a small dehumidifier
it sounds like you need a larger
dehumidifier already is the thing you
need to step up you've got a 4-inch
extractor fan maybe you need a better
extractor fan those are the two things
for you to focus on right now it says at
some point you're gonna want to upgrade
to a better light and a better
dehumidifier and a better tint not
necessarily a larger tint but you like
advice on that I generally start with
lighting I like to buy the highest
quality light I can afford and the most
efficient light for my space in today's
modern market grow lights are constantly
changing so I would try to find the most
efficient most effective light that I
can afford for that space that's where I
would start
then I would work on cooling that area
and controlling the environment I would
work on dehumidification and removing
stale hot air out of there so you're
going to need that extractor fan and a
carbon filter that's the next thing I
would work on then I would work on
cooling the environment in which that
tent is in I wouldn't necessarily cool
the inside of the tent I would cool the
room which the tent is living in and
that air would then cycle into that tent
so I would start with lighting then I
would work on air flow then I would
focus on cooling the tent now that we've
got our light and our environment dialed
in it is time to work on automation
the first step to automation is knowing
what is going on in the grow room so
you'll need something that can monitor
your environment something that can pay
attention to temperature and humidity at
all times then I like to have some sort
of a device that can react to those
inputs maybe I've got some sort of a
device that tells me hey Rasta Jeff it
is now too humid in your grow room at
that point I want something to trigger
on to reduce that humidity a good
example would be a smart be unit you can
plug a smart be stinger into any wall
outlet then you can plug your
dehumidifier into that smart B you plug
it into spot number one you assign
number one to dehumidification then you
tell your smart B sensor hey I want it
to be fifty percent humidity in this
room if it gets higher than that turn on
that dehumidifier and it will do that
for you the monitor will pay attention
as soon as it hits 52 percent humidity
in that room it'll say hey guess what
rhasta Jeff wants it fifty percent I
need to turn on slot number a on that
stinger your dehumidifier will fire up
you will suck out the humidity in that
room you can also put an extraction fan
on that same stinger throw it on slot
number two put it on dehumidification
that way when it gets too humid your
dehumidifier comes on and your
extraction fan comes on and now you are
dehumidifier that room so once you've
got good equipment I like to add
monitors followed by automation
I think monitors and automation make
things very easy cannabis plants love
consistency and if you automate simple
things like watering and dehumidifier
that saves you a lot of time for doing
other things in the grow like the low
stress training like the popping and
twisting like defoliating like scouting
for bugs like all of the other things
they get pushed aside because we're too
busy doing things we could have and
should have automated so I would start
with the lights then I would work on
climate control and air conditioning
then I would go to monitoring then I
would work on automation then if you
really want to step it up it is time to
start adding co2 to your grow room you
want to supplement co2 ambient co2 in
most environments on earth is around 400
ppm our cannabis plants can thrive in
much higher levels of co2 they will grow
more rapidly it will grow with more
vigor it will become larger with less
time so supplementing augmenting co2 in
your grow environment is a great way to
improve your grow room you will increase
the harvest way you will decrease grow
time and you will increase overall
quality of your finished product now
that is the equipment you also need to
make sure that you are feeding the best
nutrients you can feed you need to make
sure that each feed is dialed in also I
suggest good pH pins and ec meters and I
also recommend you calibrate those
vices regularly those devices don't do
you any good if they are not calibrated
properly so that is a list of options
and things you can do to upgrade your
grow room keep in mind that grow room
equipment is constantly changing and
evolving especially with legalization
people are able to research more people
are able to advertise their product as a
cannabis specific product so things are
developing and changing rapidly so doing
a lot of research and buy quality
products that you think will have
longitude e don't fall for gimmicky [ __ ]
in the grow world try to find a company
that will answer you when you send them
an email try to find a company that will
respond to you if you've got a problem
customer service is huge in this
industry now I keep saying it no matter
how much great [ __ ] you buy nothing ever
will make up for building a relationship
with the plant and understanding the
plants we are growing something that
will probably improve your garden more
than anything is a solid grow book go
buy a cannabis specific grow book that
was written by a reputable cannabis
grower and a reputable author then once
you've got that book the next step is to
read the book those books do you know
good if you buy them and set them on
that bookshelf by the toilet I've seen
it I've been to your house I picked up
that grow Bible that is right by your
toilet the spine of that book has never
been cracked [ __ ] open it and read it
it's not going to do you any good
sitting there on the Shelf that
knowledge isn't gonna fly out of the
book into your head you have to open it
and read it then once you are done
reading that grow book the next step is
to buy another grow book from a
different author and read that one then
combine the knowledge you got from both
books and develop your own understanding
for these plants understanding the
plants we are growing and having a solid
goal will be more useful than any piece
of equipment you could buy at any gross
store on Amazon or any sort of wizardry
you could ever find learn the plants
develop a relationship with each
cultivar touch it feel it smell it pay
attention to it
take notes all of that is free and that
is probably the best way to improve your
garden alright that was a good rant that
was a great question thank you for that
that wraps up the portion
question of this email but there is more
it goes on section 3 says please give a
big shout out for white Mike hey white
Mike you're getting another shout out on
the show it is time for you to come be
on the podcast the message continues it
says I heard that a few listeners did
not relish Mike's wider industry view I
do not agree at all I love white Mike's
contribution to the podcast people like
Mike and yourself remove the stigma of a
bunch of potheads justifying their own
habits by presenting a mature thoughtful
and well reasoned approach to the
industry and the culture and that is a
great sense I love that thank you man
that means a lot to me I kind of wanted
to start the show to break some of the
myths dispel some of the rumors about
cannabis kind of take some of the fear
away from cannabis and so I'm glad that
you see they were trying to do it in a
professional manner I appreciate that
the message continues it says this helps
to break down the bigoted views and any
lingering stigma from a hundred plus
years of prohibition I particularly
loved episode 400 in which you Mike and
another guest discussed the things that
you do not like about the business
regulations and the culture your guest
was not a fan of dab rigs because they
looked like drugs that was our friend
Clint big shout out to Clint I hope
you're listening to the podcast bro I
thought that was such a good discussion
to have I have no issue with dab rigs
but I totally get that look like drugs
view that those opposed or without much
knowledge will fastly well fasten upon
to justify their agenda yes sometimes a
dab rig can kind of look like you're
doing other drugs I've got this big
glass bowl on here I'm heating with the
torch and then I'm dropping [ __ ] into it
it does look a little suspect if you
don't know what I'm doing
so I understand your view and I do
understand Clint's view on it make sure
you listen to episode 400 if you want to
hear more about that we're gonna keep
moving where was I it says it says this
sort of grown-up warts-and-all approach
is what the industry needs more of then
he wraps it up by saying if necessary I
will set up a GoFundMe page to save
white Mike that's pretty funny don't
worry why Mike isn't going anywhere he's
always invited on the show white Mike is
consumed by his family life he just
loves being a dad he loves being a good
husband
he is always there doing that I'm sure
we'll break him free pretty soon and get
him over here on the podcast no need to
save white Mike however I'm not gonna
stop you if you want to make a go fund
me page for white Mike I would not be a
good friend if I tried to stop you from
doing that so let's get white Mike a
GoFundMe page going you hear that Mike
you got some money coming bro Mike is
doing fine you guys Mike's not going
anywhere
Mike will be on the show pretty soon
here this message continues part 4 says
if either you and/or white Mike ever
venture over the pond to the UK then you
both have a place to stay and then he
says where he says just drop me a line
then he says I have had 400 free
training lessons from you and you are
both welcome to stay at my expense hey
that sounds fun hey Mike
let's go overseas and have a good time
Mike was just over there recently I did
not get to join him but Mike went to
France for his birthday we talked a
little bit about that on the show part
number five says if you ever want a
foreign contributor to your shows I
would be more than happy to contribute
you just did and I appreciate it he goes
on to say that it would be interesting
to get a non-us Canadian attitude as to
what's happening all over our continent
which I do agree with that it would be
neat to get a little over the pond kind
of a report so if you've got some
recording equipment maybe we could work
out a little brief segment maybe
occasionally just drop in a little
pre-recorded part if you're able to do
that keep in touch with me I would love
to hear your ideas on that now he does
wrap up the email with cheers guys
keep up the good work looking to another
400 shows then he wraps it up with kind
regards from John hey John thank you for
the great message thank you for
listening to the podcast and I look
forward to bringing you another 400
episodes all right podcast world my
voice is burning out I want to thank
everybody for hanging out for the Monday
episode if you feel like this episode
was educational informative or
entertaining and you would like to make
a financial contribution to the show you
can support the show by going to
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
all of the information you need to
become a patron will be right there on
the screen if you would like to support
the show and you're not able to
contribute financially I would
appreciate your support on social media
you can find me on Facebook simply
search for the growth from your heart
podcast on Twitter search for @g
YH podcast on Instagram I use my other
company name it's Irene underscore
genetics and I would really love it if
you find me on cannabis cannabis as a
new cannabis friendly social media
application be encouraged promote and
support cannabis posts and cannabis
related posts so if you'd like to share
a picture of your garden if you'd like
to show off some of your buds or if
you've got a cannabis question
join us on cannabis and feel free to
safely post all of your cannabis content
if you've got something you'd like to
say and you're not into all of that
social media nonsense you can send me an
email my email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com
you know that I would love to hear from
you don't forget about the YouTube
channel simply search for the growth
from your heart podcast on YouTube click
Subscribe leave some comments on the
videos let me know what you think about
the show I do love that type of
interaction ladies and gentlemen that is
all I've got for this episode I'll be
back in just a couple of days with fresh
new content I want to give a huge grow
from your heart podcast shout out to my
buddy stabby Mick stab dude and until
next time take a phat dad and give your
mom a hug for me