hey what's up podcast world it is time
for episode 436 of the Grove from your
heart podcast this episode of the show
is brought to you by seeds here now if
you need new seeds in your garden I
highly recommend seeds here now and you
can find them at www.cpa.psu.edu or
[Applause]
friends at apothecary farms for the
Malibu pier cush Ambrosia ladies and
gentlemen in this episode I'm going to
read a listen or email and I am also
going to read some comments from YouTube
before we do that let's give a shout out
to a few of our friends from patreon
let's start off with a big ol shout out
to miss Mel how about a big gigantic
grow from your heart a podcast shot to
matthew KW of course a giant grow from
your heart a podcast shout out to Steve
F as always a shout out to basta only
give a big giant shout out to Isaac
Green of course a big grow from your
heart podcast shout out to squirrel
tactics and of course a big fist bump
and grow from your heart podcast shout
out to my new friend kill and kind I
want to thank all of you for the
continued patreon support and if you
would like to learn how to become a
patron you can do so by going to
www.hsn.com or lemon jeffery seeds a lot
of people ask me when i will have more
feminized golden goat seeds
the answer is July 10th those seeds will
drop on July 10th make sure you check
out my vendors on July 10th they should
be available at seeds here now calm
they should be available at Oregon elite
seeds and they should be available at
dank seed dot store they will also be
available at the dude grows 7/10
concentration celebration on July 13th
at cultivated synergy at the IRA
genetics booth I'm not trying to sound
like too much of a sales guy but these
seeds will go quickly so don't sleep on
the new drop of feminized seeds these
will drop on 7/10 on the websites and
they will be available on 7:13 at the
dude grows concentration celebration
7/10 event in Denver at cultivated
synergy in very limited quantities I
will have the lemon Jeffrey feminized
seeds I will have golden goat feminized
seeds and I will have the brand-new
never before released orange gasm seeds
in very limited quantities so come see
me at the dude grows concentration
celebration on 713 a cultivated synergy
or check out those websites I mentioned
before seeds here now calm Oregon elite
seeds and dank seed dot store on 710 for
the fresh feminized seed drop I've also
been getting a lot of requests for
detailed information about my feeding
mix and my nutrient recipes I mentioned
before that I use veg bloom as a base
I've mentioned that I add in some new
millennium products since I went on the
dude grow show and mentioned my mix
since I mentioned some of my mix on my
podcast I get at least two or three
emails every single day asking about my
mix so in the future I will do a fully
detailed episode on what I'm using for
veg bloom and new millennium and a
couple of other things I'll give you
some very good ideas some very thorough
information on my nutrient mix and
options for your setup when I do
episodes that are really in-depth like
that and I feel like a lot of people are
going to cling to every word and follow
my advice very closely I do my best to
make sure to give accurate information
so this episode will take me a little
bit of time to put together but it will
be worth your wait so in the near future
you will get a nutrient recipe episode
that is mainly focused on what I mix in
a home grow and in a commercial
environment now please keep in mind I
said it's going to take me a little bit
to create those episodes they are going
to be very detailed I want them to be
very accurate so please be patient but I
will make it worth your wait all right
now let's move into this email that I've
got sitting here in front of me recently
I did an episode about carbon filters
and carbon filter placement we got a
great email from a listener who wanted
to add on some advice to that
information and I definitely encourage
and welcome updated information if I say
something on the show and you agree or
disagree or if you've got something to
add on to it please do reach out to me
if you'd like to correct me if you'd
like to expand on my knowledge please
help me out don't be afraid I am not
afraid to be corrected I'm not afraid to
learn more I want to expand my brain so
fill me up with knowledge my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com this listener sent the email
that goes like this hey Rasta Jeff I
listen to the carbon filter episode and
I thought I would chime in with a couple
of things I am any location that
requires absolutely zero smell and they
put zero in all capitals so they mean
zero smell which in my experience is
pretty difficult to achieve yes if
you're growing dank herb zero smell is
difficult to achieve even veg plants put
off a very distinct aroma
it smells like growing vegetation as
soon as you flip the flower you start
putting off that dank aroma so sometimes
it is pretty difficult to achieve zero
smell with a carbon filter we can
minimise aromas with careful duct tape
and careful caulking we can absolutely
minimize aromas this person has some
great contributions it says even with a
24 inch carbon filter for a six-inch fan
I was catching a whiff of sweet dankness
outside of my discharge point which
happens to be outside for me which now
that means a lot of people have access
to that smell maybe you've got it near a
part of the house where you think no
one's gonna go there but you never know
what happens sometimes the kid hits a
baseball it bounces three times it lands
right there by that duct or that vent
that little kid runs over there to get
the baseball and he goes damn it smells
dank over here little kids nowadays know
what dank weed smells like you're busted
it only takes something simple and
stupid like that so zero aroma is the
goal for this listener and here is some
of the advice that they sent us it says
one of the ways I corrected the issue
was to use rope caulk easily found in
Home Improvement Center to seal all of
the joints in my ductwork this is super
important and then I added another
carbon filter at the discharge point
just in case so this guy's got air going
in through a carbon filter and also out
through a carbon filter at the other end
so he is double scrubbing the air and is
also using rope caulk on every joint so
you're typically going to have your
carbon filter and then your blower you
need to caulk between there then you
will have your blower and probably some
duct work you will need to caulk between
the blower and the ducting wherever that
ducting attaches you need to caulk that
as well if you have more parts caulk all
of that if you've got a grow light with
glass between the bulb and the canopy so
that that grow light is sealed too you
can move air over and cool those lights
you probably need to seal all of that up
with caulking as well if zero aroma is
your goal you cannot be too careful I
would put some type of sealant on every
joint VIN I would wrap that again with
duct tape just to make sure if zero
aroma is the goal we want to go extreme
and make sure that zero aroma escapes
this grow space now when I was talking
about sealing up the light we need to be
careful if we have got a ducted light
hood we need to carefully seal that
glass think about it this way you've got
plants directly under that light and you
were blowing air over that light if
there is a gap where air can get in or
out that is a spot for aroma to
essentially get sucked right into that
and blown right out of your grow space
that did not get filtered we want any
air that enters that tube that exit path
to run through that filter at the
beginning and have no chance of entering
the grow room or collecting more air
through gaps on the way down that tube
then this listener also places another
carbon filter which I'm sure he's using
more sealant on that joint as well at
the very end at his exit point now if
you don't have another carbon filter at
that end I highly recommend some sort of
a screen at least a pantyhose or some
type of thin cover just to prevent
anything from coming in your ductwork I
don't know how high off the ground your
ductwork is I don't know how low your
ductwork is but I have seen weird [ __ ]
happened with duct work that was not
covered I have seen birds fly into duct
work
it was up high I've seen snakes and
reptiles climb into ductwork that was
down low I've walked into a grow room
before that's got sealed lights and
there was a snake just chilling in the
grow hood because it was warm as [ __ ]
and that snake was a loving life right
there he just climbed right down the
ducting climbed into the light hood and
just chilled out like hey this is
beautiful here and it was a pain in the
ass to get him out because we had to
undo all the ducting just to get to him
then some [ __ ] had to reach in there
and get a snake out don't put yourself
in that position you don't want a snake
in your grow room you don't want a
reptile in your grow room make sure you
seal the end of that ducting also
insects like to come up there it's nice
and warm they feel that warm air coming
out they think it's warm it's got to be
nice in there it's probably the Sun
setting it's getting colder outside they
look there's still Sun in there and they
want to go in there and find some food
or maybe find something to mate with
they want to go where the warm is don't
invite them cover that [ __ ] up also if
you were using one of those portable air
conditioners that has the ducting in and
the ducting out cover the ducting on
that with something but make sure you
use something that does not restrict the
air flow because you will ruin that air
conditioner it needs to be covered with
something that allows air flow but will
not allow pets to come in or out a very
thin screen something with a very fine
micron mesh I like to use those HIPPA
filters they saw them in many different
sizes you can cut them to size and then
you can just use a staple gun to staple
them right wherever you need them put a
little duct tape over the edge so it
stops fraying but make sure you cover
all your ins and outs we don't need bugs
coming in we don't need bugs climbing on
our plants and we certainly don't want
some sort of reptiles in our grow room I
don't know maybe you do but if you do
want a reptile in there you probably
brought it in there already you don't
want to just showing up on [ __ ]
surprise that's gonna freak you out so
cover up your [ __ ] be careful but the
point is make sure to not let any aroma
escape that grow room so on all of the
stuff I talked about on the previous
episode replace all of those seals with
some type of sealant or some type of
caulking this person recommends rope
caulk and he says you can get it at any
hardware store I would put a nice solid
layer of rope caulk then I would also
cover it with duct tape just because
I've got some solid OCD now there is a
little bit more to this message it says
personally I like this setup because if
one filter starts to fail the other will
help to minimize the odor until I can
fix the problem hey man I like the
mindful
and I like the fourth thought great
thinkin it goes on to say I have not
experienced any negatives to running two
filters no I don't think you will as
long as your blower is able to handle it
there will be that will be a [ __ ]
good idea
then it says safe discrete and odorless
has no price tag that is the truth that
extra carbon filter that stronger blower
is way more affordable than a lawyer way
more affordable than bail and way more
affordable than having a felony on your
record for the rest of your life so buy
that extra carbon filter and do the
extra work he wraps up the message with
made sure to hug my mom on mom's day and
then he signed it with the milkman hey
milkman thank you for the great message
and thank you for the great contribution
to the podcast I do appreciate updates
and information like that and again if
anybody out there would like to send me
an email my email address is grow from
your heart at hotmail.com I would love
any sort of corrections updates or
contributions all right I've got one
more email in front of me then we're
going to get to the YouTube comments
I've never read YouTube comments before
on the show we're gonna start that on
this episode this email goes like this
it says hey I can't thank you enough for
the incredible content and knowledge
that you share that's a great way to
start a message it goes on to say I
learned something each and every time
that I listen to one of your shows and
that is the point that's what I'm trying
to do so that makes me feel good knowing
that I'm reaching my goal it goes on to
say I've recently started my first grow
it's turned into a slightly controlled
disaster that's oftentimes how first
grows go he says but finding your show
and documenting my grow gave me a lot of
great knowledge that I can take forward
to make the next one more successful
that is the perfect attitude you learned
how to [ __ ] up a grow now you can learn
how not to [ __ ] up a girl you got to
start somewhere man so you've got the
great attitude you were on the right
path it goes on to say I recently signed
up for the four dollar and twenty cent
level on patreon if you're going to
shout me out use darren w that would be
appreciated i'm in a legal country but
my work would likely frown upon micro
interest whether it's legal or not all
right Darren I will keep you safe real
big shout out to my buddy Darren Debbie
you
thanks for the patreon contribution also
thanks for the great email I do
appreciate hearing that I am helping
people out and that I improved your grow
just by hearing my show
taking some of the stuff that I rambled
into a microphone you were able to
improve your garden which means your
life is better which means if you're
smoking or recreationally or medicinally
you were improving the quality of your
life so that makes me feel good to be
here so thank you for the great message
you wraps it up it says keep up the
great work I always look forward to
listening and learning from you thanks
Darren
Debbie you a man thank you for the great
message once again and thanks again for
the patreon contribution I really
appreciate that
all right podcast world I'm going to
press pause for a moment I'm gonna take
a drink I'm gonna take way too many way
too big way too hot dabs and right after
that I'll come back and read a couple of
comments from my YouTube channel take a
dad with me boys and girls all right
podcast world I am back I am well
hydrated I am heavily medicated and it
is time to read some comments from the
YouTube channel I'm click in that
direction right now I want to give a big
thanks to everybody who has subscribed
to my youtube channel if you go to
youtube type in the grow from your heart
podcast you will find my youtube channel
please click Subscribe leave some
comments maybe I will read your comments
on a future episode the first comment on
today's episode comes from somebody who
calls themselves killer bees garden they
left this comment six days ago the comic
goes a lot like this you're the man RJ
and RJ stands for Rasta Jeff
he says you help so many I was the same
way in school but the way you teach is
super engaging and what he's referring
to is in an episode I said that I hated
school but I love to learn so I had to
find a way to entertain myself while I
was learning so he agrees he was the
same way but the way that I teach is
super engaging that means a lot to me
thank you he goes on to say thank you
for all of your efforts and a huge thank
you for all the awesome genetics sudhir
so welcome those compliments mean a lot
to me so that makes it all worth it all
the hard work all the late nights
podcasting all the frustration all the
research all the writing all the time
all the energy that this makes it worth
it right here it goes on to say I've
popped mini beans but all have been
bagged seeds so I finally got my hands
on some legit beans and man everyone is
right when they say genetics are the
most important part and yeah I
definitely can't agree with that after
this grow I'm on at the moment keep it
up and I'm
glad you finally got some quality
genetics and I'm sure you're going to
see a huge difference in vigor and
performance and also just knowing what
you've got what you're working with will
make the grow so much easier and so much
more enjoyable so I hope you enjoyed the
new genetics and I hope those come out
beautifully for you and I also hope to
see photos send me some pictures of the
grow and if you've got any questions let
me know hey killer bees thank you for
the great comment we're gonna move on to
the next comment this one was left by
somebody who called themselves smoke why
maybe they want to be called smokey
because I know why to smoke their
comment goes a lot like this amazing
show once again I've been listening to
your podcast on stitcher since 2015
maybe 2014 hey that's a long time you've
been there since the beginning Thank You
Man I appreciate that the message goes I
don't remember what year you started but
I've been listening forever thanks for
all of the help you have been a big help
a thank you for the great comment thank
you for listening and if you ever have
any questions please send them to my
email it's grow from your heart at
hotmail.com we're gonna keep going
because there are some great comments in
here our friend you grow says love the
show man I always get my seeds from
seeds here now thanks for listening to
the show and of course thanks for
supporting our sponsor seeds here now
Jesse James said I'd love to hear what
genetics you bring back from Europe that
is referring to one of our friends who
invited me to Europe to go hang out on a
vacation dude I would love to see what
kind of genetics I brought back from
Europe also if that happens you'll be
the second one to know I've got another
comment from Bill parks it says great
podcast dude very informative thank you
hey Bill parks you're very welcome
thanks for the great comment it keeps
going that one just says arise arise
arise that's a great comment this one
from Stony scholar what's up to our
friend Stoney scholar Stoney scholar
says another great listen in the garden
I appreciate that I think a lot of
people listen while they're growing I
know that I listen to the dude grow show
while I'm in the garden it just feels
right to be around the plants and
listening to a show focused on plants so
thanks for listening in the garden yo
Stoney scholar I look forward to seeing
you at the DGC event bring some diamonds
I'll take a DAB we've got an
a great comment from our friend Tristan
Hawke this one was left a week ago when
it says I wanted to drop in and say
hello and thanks from a fellow new
listener Youtube subscriber and say I
have been producing my own medicinal
cannabis for 12 years I decided to take
it a step further by getting my plant
science degree hey congratulations dude
to have the paperwork to jump on the
legalization train for micro cultivation
here in Canada man I hopes that that's
working out for you it says one more
year to go one more year bro good luck
he says great stuff well informed and
also well balanced between botanical
knowledge yeah making it simpler for new
growers to comprehend keep it up this
guy's been growing for 12 years and he
is getting a plant science degree and he
is learning from this little podcast
that means a lot to me I am teaching
people who were going to school for
plant science degrees that makes me
proud that lets me know that I'm really
doing a good service so thank you that
is a great message and good luck in
school man keep going I know school can
be a struggle I did not enjoy school
like I said earlier I love learning
school is just not the environment for
me there are more great comments this
one says hey Rasta Jeff just curious
about your thoughts on using a sorbic
acid to neutralize chloramine in tap
water that may be effective in a small
grow but now you've got a sorbic acid in
your water I think your pH is gonna be a
little bit out of whack I think our O
filtration may be the best if not the
only way to effectively get that out for
commercial production our next comment
was left by our friend craft cannabis it
says another fantastic show Rasta Jeff
thanks my friend stay lifted I promise
you I will thanks for the great
compliments miss Mel says thank you for
the shout-out you were very welcome Mel
it's always great to hang out talk to
you our next one says yo Rossi o best
stay away from my mom I love that
comment that is [ __ ] hilarious to me
and then it says just kidding she wants
a hug directly from you that was left by
her friend Mike Jones who Mike Jones it
Mike Jones when I see your mom I got a
big ol hug for her don't worry bro we've
got more great comments this one says
I've bought I read genetics from Oregon
elite and hella dank both have good
service but Oregon elite has freebies
now hella dank has freebies also have no
fear get your gear I've never said that
before that's catchy I'm gonna keep
saying that the next comment is
somebody who calls themselves the Lynx
grows and shows that's a cool name it
says is bebop the same cross as blue
raspberry truffle no it is the exact
opposite bebop is a rise cross the
blueberry cookies the male was the
reverse blueberry cookies and the seeds
are feminized the blue raspberry truffle
the male was the arize and those seeds
are regular so it is the exact opposite
I hope I said that correctly because I
don't have any notes in front of me and
I tried to keep all that [ __ ] straight
but I think you guys know what I mean
they are opposites the comments keep
coming ladies and gentlemen this one
says thanks for sharing have a beautiful
day hey thank you for listening
take a phat dab this one says great
content I love how you lay it all out
there thank you I'm glad you notice that
I try to put as much out there as I can
without overwhelming you I want to make
it clear but I don't want it to be too
much so I try to try to find that line
the next one says always the best advice
from Ross to Jeff that means a lot to me
thank you there are more let's find a
couple more than we're gonna get out of
here
love the podcast brother keep them
coming OnPoint as always with love from
Canada a big shout out to all my friends
in Canada I've noticed that recently
I've gotten a large following of people
from Canada thank you I appreciate that
thanks for following me up there if you
guys have any questions send them on to
me I love helping out my friends to the
north the next comment is a compliment
about the hella dank seed company it
says just receive some of your genetics
from HDS see in two days very fast very
friendly can't wait to get these in the
ground and as awesome it's always good
to hear that my sponsors and my vendors
are working correctly and they're doing
things properly so that's a great
complement to them then there's a
comment here on the episode I did about
mushrooms in Denver it says you can take
too many I ate about an ounce one night
well that yeah that is too many that may
be too many for a lot of people went
into seizures and started vomiting
profusely obviously lived and was fine
but the rest of that night sucked dick
yeah that sounds like a miserable
experience that comes from our friend a
be my advice there don't eat a goddamn
ounce of mushrooms I'm a soldier I like
a spiritual experience I like to go
heroic and ounce of mushrooms just
sounds like a bad idea the next comment
says good show
thank you a good comment
I see Stony scholars name pop up in here
a lot shot at the Sony scholar the next
comment says I love your show and all of
your shows big thank you for that one
that means a lot it looks like I need to
give a big shout-out to my buddy CJ
what's up CJ I hope you're listening to
the podcast I see you pop up in the
YouTube comments a lot he just leaves a
couple emojis some flowers some smiley
faces some thumbs up what's up buddy I
see you out there CJ CJ is a great guy I
met him at the Indo Expo we've been
talking a little bit online oh we're
gonna hang out buddy don't worry we'll
take some dabs sometime soon we are two
like-minded to not become good friends
also I see James but ursin on here a lot
what's up James you were always the
first one to comment on all of the
videos Bigg love much respect to James
but ursin we got a comment from buzz bro
it says thank you very much for taking
the time to answer my question I had to
drop a line and let you know how the
dark period worked out for me the buds
plumped up and the trichomes multiplied
so that means a lot to me that my advice
is working the next comment is in
reference to an episode I did right
around the time when we lost my friend
Brody Stephens it says this one was a
trip to listen to I'm a big comedy fan
what a lineup so much has gone down with
all these folks rest in peace Brody
Stephens yes big love to Brody and big
shout-out to Blackbird for the great
comment and then we're gonna start
wrapping it up we've got a couple more
this one says big Grover's love to Rasta
Jeff and all my fellow COUNTA heads big
shout-out to Kraft cannabis for the
great comment big shots all of my fellow
canna heads and big growers love to
craft cannabis our last one for this
episode comes from tea bean and it says
what is your cannabis channel name
that's a great question on cannabis I
use ireon ders core genetics please go
to cannabis cannabis is a social media
application that encourages promotes and
endorses cannabis you cannot buy sell or
exchange goods on cannabis but you can
absolutely post cannabis content you can
post your photos you can post your
videos you can post your grow you can
post your grow questions you can post
grow advice you can post your rosin your
diamonds you can do your fancy dad
videos there now the fine stony folks at
cannabis encourage promote condone and
support your cannabis based content so
find us over at cannabis it's an
application that is available on your
iPhone or Android device it is free
download download create an account log
in post your cannabis content join me
I'm I read genetics I'd love to see you
there I want to give a big shout-out to
our friend T bean for the great comment
that gave me the opportunity to pitch my
new favorite social media application
called cannabis you guys that looks like
that is all of the comments I'm going to
read for today this one actually says
[ __ ] dig it super accessible
knowledge and really helped me rethink
my newts that kind of stuff means a lot
to me that one comes from our friend el
pinche that is all of the YouTube
comments I am going to read for today if
you would like a chance to have your
comment read in the future simply
subscribe to the growth from your heart
podcast YouTube channel and leave a
comment on your favorite video let me
know what you think of the show and I
may read your comment in the future all
right podcast world that is all I've got
for you for this Thursday episode I want
to thank you again for listening to
another episode of the growth from your
heart podcast make sure you support my
friends again on cannabis also make sure
you support seeds here now calm don't be
afraid to contribute to the patreon
campaign you can do so by going to
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
all the information you need to sign up
will be right there on the screen i want
to thank everybody once again for
listening I'll be back Monday with fresh
new content I wanna give a huge
shout-out to my friend Pedro's grow room
and until next time take a phat dad and
give your mom a hug for me