hey welcome to the show everybody it is
time for episode 437 of the Grove from
your heart podcast this episode of the
show is brought to you by seeds here now
if you need new seeds in your garden I
highly recommend seeds here now and you
can find them at www.cdxzipstream.com
ohe Ambrosia this stuff tastes
ridiculous it smells like grapefruits
it smells like dish soap and it smells
like smarty candies the dabs are
tremendous big shout outs my friends at
apothecary farms for the buffet of
delicious concentrates ladies and
gentlemen boys and girls smokers and
growers in this episode I'm going to
read a couple of listen or emails before
we get to the emails let's give some
shoutouts to our friends on patreon I
want to give a big shout out to my
friend Mike H I want to give a gigantic
grow from your heart podcast shout out
to my good friend Aldrich how about a
great big shout out to David OQ a big
shout out to farmer Jon I want to give a
giant grow from your heart podcast shot
at 210 or M Iowa giant girl from your
heart podcast handshake and a shout out
to Richard memo and of course a giant
shout out to our friend Glenn Jeron if
you would like to learn how to support
the show on patreon you can do so by
going to www.hsn.com the patreon
campaign oke italy dokely podcast world
at the start of the show I said that I
was going to read some listen or emails
the first email in this episode goes
just like this what's up Rasta Jeff I'm
living in prohibition land and I haven't
grown in 15 years I absolutely love the
podcast and how informative and
entertaining it is hey Thank You Man
I like the messages that start with
compliments so thanks a lot
recently I've had some traumatic
experiences that have given me extreme
general anxiety and have given me PTSD
honestly though I'm not concerned about
me I have a five year old son that we
see starting to have many many problems
with being on the spectrum with very
high-functioning autism and extreme ADHD
I want to avoid him being prescribed
harsh narcotics so I want to get him
into CBD I have recently been reading
about how CBD and how it could help my
son so I purchased some CBD tinctures
legally here in New York this has been a
miracle for my anxiety and my PTSD more
importantly it turns my son into a new
kid that is great to hear sometimes when
you're purchasing CBD you're not exactly
sure what you're getting so I'm glad
you're getting a CBD ilegal CBD product
and I'm delighted to hear that it's
helping your son when it fixes the kids
that always feels a little better when
you heal an adult an adult feels better
that feels great but when you see a
little kid just better that just makes
everybody feel better movies with little
kids those are always more
heart-wrenching anything with a child
just feels better so I'm glad that your
son is able to be himself and you're
able to enjoy your son that's gonna
build a better relationship for both you
that'll make both your lives better so
we see CBD helping already this is a
great message it goes on to say my son's
teachers have asked me if he is on
adderall and I say nope just CBD I am
amazed and I now need to grow my own
medicine for myself and my son because I
can't afford these very expensive CBD
oils so my question is what strains
would you recommend I would like some
CBD only and then some one-to-one ratio
and I'm sure he means a 1 to 1 THC 1 to
1 CBD and then a very high THC strain
for myself and my fiance especially
since I'm risking it for my son anyway
but seriously if you know of any high
THC strains that will help with PTSD
please let me know I know you aren't an
expert on making extract so I'll get
that info elsewhere unless you have some
input I follow you want all social
medias since I haven't been able to
become a patron hey that's alright
thanks for the great message thanks for
following me on the social media you
don't have to become
patron for me to support you and help
you out I goes on to say but I will soon
and I look forward to it I thank you for
bringing this community together people
like you are what's making this industry
legitimate and then he signs his message
and then it says PS been listening since
before I started growing again and
before your dude grows episode a true
fan of your kindness and voice I
seriously love the podcast a that's a
great message there is a lot of stuff to
cover let's back up a few steps and talk
about a couple of things I love and
respect the fact that you are stepping
up to produce medicine to make your son
and your entire family's life better but
you said earlier that you are in
prohibition land so one thing we need to
weigh here is the cost of your safety
you are producing medicine to make
yourself and your son's life better is
that worth the risk if you get caught
you may be removed from your son's life
for quite a long time there's another
personal part in this message I did not
read out loud imagine what would happen
if you were removed from your son it
would be in the hands of that other
person you mentioned that I did not read
about that may not be the best outcome
that may not be what you want so think
about that you need to weigh those
options yes I always say grow cannabis
do that you're an adult but in this case
your son needs you you may want to
consider your options here you do have
the option to get that teacher it is
expensive growing is expensive equipment
is expensive the processing is going to
take a lot of effort and a lot of
equipment and you could really screw it
up and waste an entire crop which means
you just risked your freedom and your
son's well-being for a crop that you
accidentally destroyed I'm not trying to
say you're gonna do this I'm just trying
to put some thought into your head so
you know very clearly what you're
risking and you know your options I just
want to make that clear for you it
sounds like you're gonna grow it sounds
like I probably can't sway you but I
want you to know that that teacher is
available at a cost there's money money
is expensive but freedom is priceless
and if you are not around to help your
son you are not around to help your son
at all so it really sounds like you've
got your heart set on growing cannabis
it sounds like you've already
some equivalent and you're gonna do it
so I will talk about some genetics that
would help you out but keep in mind if
there is tincture available that is
already processed and you can buy it and
it works and it did what you need done
and it is already showing positive
results I may stick to that if it is
illegal to grow in your area just that's
that's something that I would stick with
if it were me for the child safety
that's what I would do that's what I
should recommend I'm a cannabis grower
I'm a SI breeder I'm a cannabis advocate
I'm a cannabis activists on the cannabis
spokesperson but before all of that I'm
a father and if you made me choose one
you wouldn't see me do any more cannabis
stuff you'd just see me focused on that
kid she's 16 she needs a good father I
understand how important it is for us to
be there so that may be something to
think about I'm just coming from my
fatherly side today is her birthday so
maybe it's weighing a little extra heavy
on me today but that is what I thought
of first of all now it sounds like
you're gonna grow so if you're gonna
grow if your heart is set on it or if
there's somebody else out there who may
want this information let's talk about
some CBD rich strains I'll try to touch
on some things that are known to be one
at one-to-one and then I will give some
recommendations for strains that I
believe are high THC and have worked
well in PTSD applications one thing that
pops into my head when I start thinking
about Fino hunting for CBD rich
phenotypes from a pack of seeds is lab
testing do you have lab testing
available you're going to hypothetically
acquire seeds and you will grow those
seeds the plants that come from those
seeds will have different traits the
buds that come from those plants will
have different medicinal qualities they
will have different cannabinoid profiles
they will have different terpene
profiles depending on the breeding
selections and the filial generation you
could have vastly different cannabinoid
profiles without lab testing there is no
way of knowing how much CBD or THC is in
each finished plant the only way you are
going to know which of those plants
works effectively for your son's
condition is to make a tincture out of
each one of them and let him try it then
you have to observe him after trying
each one and make sure that what you're
giving him is working for him now you
could in theory administer
each plant is a separate dose or you
could mix all the finished product
together and make one large batch of
teacher that way and see how it all
works that is up to you there are a
couple of ups and downs to this the
downside is some of those phenotypes may
contain THC if that medicine is working
for your son that is wonderful but if
anything should come up and your child
is tested for THC and he has tested
positive maybe they want to put him on
another medicine maybe something comes
up in the family maybe he gets hurt
somehow maybe something comes up you
said he shows signs of autism maybe they
want to test him to put him on an autism
medicine and they want to test to see if
he's on THC just because anything could
happen and if they test your child and
he does test for THC that could become a
problem the positive is you are now
making custom-tailored medicine for your
son if you find one phenotype out of a
pack of seeds that makes the perfect
medicine for your son you have solved a
problem and you've got him healthy and
happy for a long term you can produce
that medicine you can make the tincture
out of it you can administer that
teacher at the proper dose whenever he
needs it you can keep him in a good
condition that is the advantage to doing
a phenol hunt from seed and finding the
perfect phenotype for the medicinal
application which you are seeking like I
mentioned before the risk there is
getting the THC
into the child and having something go
wrong legally because there is THC in
your child's bloodstream maybe one of
those teachers that asked are you giving
him adderall and you said no it's CBD
maybe one of them is all uppity and they
want to throw a fit one day maybe
something happens maybe your child has
an outburst I'm not just saying your
kids a bad kid I'm saying I'm just
giving you options ideas of [ __ ] that
could go wrong maybe somebody throws
something at your kid and he throws
something back and now they're gonna
blame it on your kid because you give
him CBD and they're gonna drug test your
kid he's got THC in there and now it's a
whole new ballgame just try to keep I
just tried to look way ahead in the
future and see options so we can prevent
that kind of [ __ ] from happening but
that could be the only downfall to this
if you do a Fino hunt you find that
perfectly custom-tailored phenotype that
works for your child then it's got THC
in it if it works I hope that is the
case I hope it works beautifully but I
don't want
trouble to come from it so keep that in
mind without a lab test you don't know
exactly what you are giving your kid
we know that it's cannabis we know that
you drew it we know what it's in it but
we don't know the finished cannabinoid
or terpene profile so without a
qualified lab I don't know how you would
determine how much THC or CBD is in your
product but I can make recommendations
on seeds that are very well known to be
very high in CBD and very low in THC in
Colorado the strain I am about to
recommend is grown in many hemp fields
in Colorado finished products are
allowed to have 0.3 percent THC which is
very little THC if a product tests any
higher than 0.3 percent THC it is either
considered cannabis or if it is supposed
to be a hemp plant it is then destroyed
if a hemp farmer produces too much hemp
that test what we call hot if it tests
higher than 0.3% THC
he can face legal ramifications in the
state of Colorado just by growing a
plant that accidentally tested too high
for a certain cannabinoid so people in
Colorado are very picky about the plants
that they are planting in their CBD
fields a very popular CBD varietal that
has been going around Colorado is known
as the cherry wine and if you do a
google search you should be able to find
the cherry wine seeds and you should be
able to get your hands on them very
easily cherry wine it is a high CBD hemp
variety one thing I need to suggest if
you choose to grow the cherry wine is
make sure you cut it down a little bit
early if it goes too late it will
develop some THC and it will become hot
most oftentimes a little bit of THC will
help with the effects of the CBD but
also we need to pay attention to how we
are medicating your Sun and we may need
to be careful for legal reasons like we
mentioned earlier so if you do let the
cherry wine go too long and it develops
THC it may be helpful but I would
recommend cutting it down early the
first few times and see how it works for
you once you've found a phenotype that
you really like then start playing with
that one grow multiple clones of the
same phenotype in the same environment
maybe grow four of them
know how much space you'll have I'm
gonna say grill for maybe cut one down a
week early maybe cut one down right on
time cut one down a week late and then
you've got another one that you can cut
down whenever you feel like it just cuz
we picked four for some stupid reason so
maybe do some experiments and find out
what cannabinoid profile you get by
letting them grow a little sooner a
little later
see what happens there so that is the
hemp variety that I would recommend that
is the cherry wine cherry wine has
become really popular in Colorado and
across the entire United States since
the farm bill allowed us to grow more
hemp so the cherry wine is really
popular it has been bred to many things
one thing I can recommend if you can't
find cherry wine seeds by itself I can
recommend the cherry Torino from llama
bean seeds you should find some very CBD
dominant phenotypes in the cherry Torino
as well alright let's talk more about
things that do have the potential to
produce one to one ratio phenotypes
again when you're growing from seed
you're going to see
fino typical variation you're going to
have different cannabinoid profiles
different terpene profiles possibly
completely different growth shapes and
structures you're going to see
differences in my opinion that is the
fun and the beauty of growing from seed
I get to pick the phenotype that works
perfectly for me in this case you get to
pick the phenotype that works perfectly
for your son so let's talk about some
one-to-one ratio strains a strain that I
see commonly testing with one-to-one
ratios is something called penny wise
penny wise should put out some
phenotypes it will give you a one-to-one
CBD to THC ratio some of course will
lean heavier to the CBD side and some
will lean heavier to the THC but you
will find that one to one ratio
phenotype in there if you run a few
seeds another one I can suggest is the
Harlequin I'm not sure that Harlequin is
available in seeds by itself it should
be available in feminized seeds
somewhere by now if not it has been
crossed to many other things you will
find many CBD heavy and one to one type
phenotypes in many Harlequin crosses
another strain I should mention that is
known for making high CBD and
potentially 1 to 1 ratio phenotypes is a
plant known as ac/dc I've seen some
breeding done to ac/dc and everything
that comes out seems to come out CBD
rich so if you can find seeds of ac/dc
or a cross of ac/dc you should find some
potentially CBD rich and possibly one to
one type phenotypes again this is going
to be phenotype dependent and you don't
have a lab to test for THC and CBD so
you're going to have to find a phenotype
that works for your son or yourself now
if you really want a better opportunity
to get a true one to one ratio something
you could do would be to grow something
like the cherry wine or another CBD rich
variety like the wife you could grow
some of that and then you could extract
that then you could grow something that
is high in THC like we're going to talk
about in just a moment and you could
extract that you can make your tincture
out of that then you've got a batch of
high THC tincture for yourself and for
your fiancee and then you've got a vat
of high CBD tincture for your son then
you could mix them at will you can have
a 50/50 ratio you could have a one two
three you could have a twenty two one
you can make whatever kind of blend you
wanted out of that you could customize
your cannabinoid ratios that would work
best for you for your son for your
fiancee however you wanted to do it for
the morning for the afternoon you can
make your perfect dose if you wanted to
do something like that again without lab
testing you're going to have to
experiment on yourself and see which
plant works best for you see which
ratios and which mixes work best for you
in my opinion that is part of the fun of
medicating with cannabis your condition
is a little more serious than some
people's so it's a little more critical
that we get it correct and also we're
working with a small person here so we
really need to make sure to get the
ratio dialed in so we don't create any
discomfort that may scare the child away
from using it as medicine again so we
really want to work on getting it right
but just a little trial and error it
won't take too long to get everything
dialed in but let's talk about some THC
rich strains also you said strains that
work well for PTSD I've got a traumatic
brain injury that comes with a little
bit of weird PTSD so I have experience
in that department I have noticed
through myself and talking with other
people that there are a few strains that
really do help with things like PTSD so
let's jump right into that one of my
favorites and
maybe just because I bread it and it is
named after me but one of my favorites
that works for my brain injury and my
PTSD is a little strain called lemon
Jeffrey lemon Jeffrey is a female lemon
skunk pollinated by a reversed golden
goat so that is a feminized seed line
lemon Jeffrey seems to work very well
for anxiety and PTSD type of situations
it really so I described that my brain
injury kind of makes it feel like my
record skips a little bit like my brain
will be going just fine but then
sometimes it'll just it'll just it'll
just and then it will keep going right
after that but then as it comes back
around to that part of the wreck wreck
wreck record and then so it'll just skip
a couple of times nobody else really
notices it but me but I feel like if I
smoke enough lemon Jeffrey or a couple
of the other strains that we're gonna
talk about that little skip on my record
just gets wiped right off
it's like record cleaner they just
polish up my CD cleans up my record
cleans my hard drive or whatever puts
all the files back in the correct drawer
so that my brain can access them
properly
I feel like strains that have limonene
really work well for my brain for my
PTSD for my traumatic brain injury so
lemon Jeffrey works beautifully for the
PTSD another strain I can recommend for
anxiety and PTSD is Jillybean there's
something in the Jilly bean that just
puts a smile on your face it makes the
PTSD kind of chill out any sort of bad
thoughts bad vibes bad moods it all just
kind of just it goes away the bad vibes
are washed away when you smoke the lemon
Jeffrey and the Jilly bean it just kind
of it just makes you feel better you're
in a better mood and I don't know if
it's the high from it I don't know if
it's the Terps I don't know if it's the
specific cannabinoids in either one of
those I think the limonene and the lemon
Jeffrey really has something to do with
it just from as much attention as I've
paid to that limonene Terp I noticed
thatone helps my brain a lot but the
Jillybean kind of does the same thing
it's not as potent it doesn't last as
long but it'll get me there and another
strain that works really well for the
PTSD and anxiety type of stuff is a
strain called Clementine Clementine
smells a lot like Jillybean Clementine
is very similar to the lemon Jeffrey
Clementine has lemon skunk in it
lemon Jeffrey also has
lemon skunk in it so that makes me think
there's something about that lemon skunk
Terp or that lemon skunk strain that is
doing something good for the PTSD for
the anxiety type of conditions now I
just thought of one more that I should
mention that fits right into this
category and when I say the name of the
strain you're gonna go oh yeah that
makes sense but one that really works
well for PTSD and anxiety and social
anxiety sort of stuff is a little strain
called tangi a few people have heard of
tangi it's getting kind of popular you
probably have heard of that one a couple
times but that orange citrusy chirp
seems to really do something really nice
for the traumatic brain injury PTSD type
of stuff now those strains will be high
in THC but they're not going to be the
highest they will be in the high 20s
have grown properly the mid to high 20s
some of them may hit 30 that lemon
Jeffrey has hit 30 before but not all of
them are going to be super high in THC
but it's more about the effect I think
you need those Terps to get what you
need
I think the THC if it were fireworks the
THC
tells you how high the firework is gonna
climb then the Terps are kind of what
color's the firework is gonna put off so
the Terps decide the display the THC
decides how high it's gonna go so I
think the terpenes are going to have a
lot to do with it don't focus too much
on that THC number THC is definitely
important but the Terps are what we need
if we're aiming for a specific condition
and you ask for something for the PTSD
so I think that's gonna help you out now
again without lab testing we don't know
exactly what type of ratios you're
getting I know that the cherry wine will
be rich in CBD I know that the few I
mentioned will have the opportunity and
the potential to produce high CBD
phenotypes and also one-to-one ratios
also other types of specific ratios I'm
not sure what you're going to get but
they do have the potential without a lab
test you'll find something in there that
works for you it's sort of a kind of a
placebo effect if I gave you a bunch of
lab numbers you would believe that that
one with that good number works without
those numbers the one that works will
work for you just let rely on your body
rely on what you observe in your son and
you will know exactly which plant to
keep using alright so those are a bunch
of different options for strains the you
asked information on you've got
something CBD something 1/2
something THC with all of that
information I hope you have made a
decision on if you want to grow or if
you want to stick to getting those
tinctures you're going to have to grow a
good amount to produce enough tincture
to keep the entire family medicated I
think I'm the only podcast online right
now without a CBD teacher sponsorship or
some sort of CBD teacher advertising but
there are many options available for
quality CBD teachers make sure you go at
the reputable company if the place you
are shopping has become too expensive
shop around look for more options like I
said don't be fooled by gimmicky [ __ ]
don't fall for snake oil read a lot of
reviews shop around if you're gonna buy
a product type in the name of that
product and then type in customer
reviews and go read a lot of reviews see
what people think fish out the [ __ ]
reviews some of those reviews are gonna
be fake they were left by the company
learn how to find that [ __ ] and then
read the reviews and see what you think
about the products you don't have to get
it from that one source there are many
options available but I hope you're able
to grow I want everybody to be able to
grow and produce a quality product but
it is going to be a lot of work I just
want you to know there are options
available alright my friend out there in
prohibition land I want to thank you for
this great email I wish you luck I hope
everything goes well for you either way
you decide to approach this problem I
wish you your family and your son the
best of luck if I can do anything else
to help you please send me another email
you have got my email address if anybody
else out there would like to send me an
email my email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com and you know that I
would love to hear from you
all right podcast world that email got
away from me it took longer than
anticipated so I'm going to save my next
message for the next episode I want to
thank you for listening to another
episode of the grow from your heart
podcast if you feel like this episode of
the show is educational informative or
entertaining and you would like to make
a financial contribution to the show you
can do so by going to www.hsn.com that
is okay I would appreciate it if you
find me on social media
on Facebook simply search for the drove
from your heart podcast on Twitter it's
@gf wih podcast and you can find me on
my new favorite social media application
called cannabis cannabis is a cannabis
friendly social media application is it
is available for free on your iPhone or
your Android device cannabis allows you
to post your cannabis photography your
cannabis videos you could post your
fancy dab videos up there you can post a
picture of your plant that is sick or
has problems and you can say yo what's
wrong with my plant and people like
myself and other experienced growers and
breeders may chime in and say hey it's a
cow mag issue or maybe you should do
something different I don't know what
could be wrong with your plant but will
tell you we'll say hey this is what's
wrong we'll try to help you out and your
posts will not get deleted your post
will not get censored unless you're an
[ __ ] on a troll we'll take your [ __ ]
down but your cannabis activity is
encouraged and promoted so come join us
on cannabis my new favorite social media
application also don't forget to visit
our sponsors seeds here now check out
their fresh restock of I read genetic
seeds I think that's all I've got for
you for this episode I'll be back in a
couple of days with fresh new content I
want to give a huge shout out to my
buddy Scottie real and until next time
take a phat dab and give your mom a hug
for me