hey welcome back podcast world it is
time for episode 438 of the grow from
your heart podcast this episode of the
show is brought to you by seeds here now
if you need new seeds in your garden I
highly recommend seeds here now and you
can find them at www.ctvn.org feel able
on this product says it contains 71% THC
and eighty-two point nine percent total
cannabinoids this four gram jar smells
ridiculous it smells like rotten mangoes
it smells like raspberry syrup
it smells deliciously disgusting and
overwhelming all at once when you take a
DAB the raspberry flavor just coats your
face then there's a sweet sugary
aftertaste that sticks around for quite
a while and the buzz goes straight to
your brain it makes you a little bit
silly it makes you kind of forget where
you put your car keys it'll make you
lose your phone while you're scrolling
on Instagram so once again I want to
give a huge shout out to our friends at
apothecary farms for the delicious
Tropicana likey Fambrough Jie in this
episode I'm going to read an email about
over-watering in cocoa before we do that
let's give a few shoutouts to my friends
on patreon how about a big shout out to
my friend Jacob W how about a giant grow
from your heart podcast shout out to
Tyler R I want to send a giant shout out
to john milk and of course a giant girl
from your heart podcast shout out to my
friend sour tea once again big giant
thanks to all of my friends who support
the podcast on patreon if you would like
to support the show you can do so by
going to www.whitehouse.gov/champions
anna de i love that that is a great way
to start an email i love the enthusiasm
big shout out to my new friend Brett up
in Canada the message goes on it says
aside from dabbing a little as a team
I am new to cannabis use just prior to
full Canadian legalization following a
brain injury with the host of
side-effects I will not get into I
started using cannabis medicinally hey I
used cannabis long before I had a
traumatic brain injury then I had a life
disrupting traumatic brain injury and I
have continued to use cannabis and I see
the effects from what I am able to
medicate properly from what I am not
able to medicate properly I can tell
that cannabis does help with the effects
and/or side effects of my traumatic
brain injury and the recovery so I do
understand that it works for you and I
am a believer and I hope things are
going well let's keep going with this
message because it's not about me it
says without question cannabis has been
the single best medicine I have used for
my issues with no side effects from its
use I have become a firm believer and
advocate of this plant and its value as
medicine and as a recreational herb
let's be honest when you don't feel good
most of the time it feels amazing to get
some relief even if for a few hours
I completely understand and agree with
everything that you just said when you
don't feel good it's hard to enjoy a
life it's hard to be around people it's
hard to do the things that you would
normally enjoy so it makes normal life a
struggle just not feeling good so
finding relief through cannabis can put
you back into your normal daily routine
put you back on our rhythm and put you
back in the position to enjoy your life
now something I really like that our new
friend Brett said is that he believes in
the medicinal and recreational powers of
cannabis I think that almost all
cannabis in a way can be labeled as some
sort of medical or therapeutic use of
cannabis it makes you feel better I
can't speak for everybody but in most
cases cannabis makes you feel better and
there is a point that if you consume too
much cannabis it will make you feel
worse or like [ __ ] so it works as any
other medicine would but I think that
any use of cannabis can be considered
recreational if we're just sitting here
at the table and I decide hey you want
to smoke a joint with me and we smoke a
joint
we feel better we might have felt just
fine before we smoked but we feel even
better after so that is medicinal that
is therapeutic that makes you feel
better why would you not want to do
something that makes you feel better
even if you felt just fine before you
improved upon feeling just fine now you
feel [ __ ] excellent why wouldn't you
want to do that so I think that is
medicinal that is therapeutic now think
about if you start in pain you normally
start at zero right feeling just fine as
a zero feeling pretty cool as a 1
feeling great is like a five feeling
[ __ ] stoned his [ __ ] is like a 10
right now you got the other way to go
maybe when you wake up your back hurts
your neck hurts maybe you got some sort
of debilitating condition where
everything hurts and you're already
starting off at negative 7 you've
already got a happiness and a comfort
and a level of enjoyment deficit you can
only enjoy life so much if you already
started off at negative 7 so it's time
to consume something smoke a couple of
dabs eat an edible maybe rub some cream
on there maybe take some t-shirt however
you get your CBD and or THC into your
body when you do that maybe you can take
that negative 7 to a negative 5 maybe we
can get that down to a negative 2
hopefully we can dial in your treatment
along with your diet and your medical
cannabis intake maybe a few other things
to hone in your health and hopefully we
can get you to a zero and then
eventually start turning you the other
way and get you on the positive side
again so anyway that cannabis is
improving the quality of your life or
allowing you to enjoy life a little more
I find that to be medicinal or
therapeutic we can see physical pain we
can see a lot of diseases and ailments
but mental health you can't see being in
pain all day not being able to live your
normal life because you were slowed down
by pain or a condition will wear on you
mentally that will wear you out being
able to smoke down and first of all
relieve that physical pain will allow
your brain to enjoy life a little bit
you don't have to think about how bad it
hurts you don't have to think about
protecting that sore spot you can kind
of chill out and enjoy so first of all
the pain will melt away a little bit
second you'll forget about it third
you'll be able to just relax and enjoy
yourself you've now escaped that trap
that was pain or that ailment that was
bothering you it's a little bit freeing
and that's the part a lot of people may
overlook or may not see we can see when
someone's walking funny or grabbing
their hip or making a funny face because
their back hurts but we can't see what
you're going through from being in pain
all day so
a little smoke a little relief goes a
long way we can call all of that
consumption medical or therapeutic all
right I am rambly today I'm gonna blame
it on those dabs there is more to this
email let's get back into it
it goes a lot like this I have decided
to grow my own after spending more than
I can afford from licensed producers I'm
now working on my second grow after
harvesting a decent yield and quality
legal product and making my own oil
infusions I am using Auto flours and I
admit this knowing how you feel about
them a lot of times I have talked trash
about Auto flowers but I have found that
they work for people and if they have
their application use them that's why
they are there use them to the best of
your advantage if that is what you want
to do I am going to be more diplomatic
toward my auto flower growing friends if
you're gonna buy Auto flower seeds big
shout out to my friend it Mephisto
genetics let's keep going with a message
he says I thought this was a good idea
at the time
remember I've got brain damage and he
goes on to say but after listening to
your podcast I am very interested in
running regular photoperiod seeds as
much as I would like to run your
genetics for this I'm afraid ordering
from the USA may cause more grief than
I'd like in the long run potentially
getting me banned from your country is
there a chance that your genetics will
make it to a distributor in Canada that
I could then order you know I do not
have any plans for a Canadian
distributor any time in the near future
but I can suggest you check with seeds
here now calm and see if they are able
to help you out in any way shape or form
now this is the part of the email where
we get to the question it says also I am
growing in Coco I've listened and
understand your level of watering but
what I can't find information on is when
to begin watering to run off I get
concerned about nutrient buildup in the
Coco but I also don't want to over water
a plant without a root mask that can
handle that much water I want to get the
most out of my plant genetics but I feel
that I'm holding them back by waiting
too long to be sure they can handle a
runoff watering any tips would be
appreciated okay I do have some great
tips for you before we get there let's
talk about the comment where you said
you have listened and understand my
levels of watering I think what this
person
referring to is episode 337 which is
titled one through five watering tech so
if you guys would like to catch up with
that I highly suggest you listen to
episode 337 and understand one through
five watering tech now let's get into
the suggestion portion when I am
watering plants in Cocoa I like to
achieve about ten to twenty percent
runoff with each watering so what that
means is I need to water that plant
until that Coco is saturated and
continue to water until I get twenty
percent excess water coming out of the
bottom of my container there are a
couple of reasons
to water your Coco this way but the main
reason is to make sure that you don't
have any salts or nutrients from
previous waterings built up in your
medium in most cases we are feeding the
plants more salt than they can take up
there's going to be a buildup in the
root zone if we just keep adding more
salts in and nothing runs off out the
bottom we will get a heavy saturation of
salt based minerals in our medium that
heavy saturation of salt based minerals
will disrupt the pH of our root zone it
will disrupt the uptake of our plants we
will see nutrient lock out we will see
nutrient problems we will see plants
that start changing colors we will see
plants to start slowing down we will not
reach our harvest goals and we will not
reach our potency expectations so that
is one of the main reasons why we like
to water our plants to runoff when using
Coco as a medium now something I should
touch on before we go too far is if you
are going to saturate your Coco that
heavily it is a good idea to amend it
with some sort of aeration product I
like to put perlite and personal light
both in my cocoa mix in most commercial
environments I prefer to run a three
gallon fabric pot I fill those fabric
pots with a perlite Percel light and
coco coir mix in most situations I use
20% perlite 20% personal light and 60%
cocoa in some situations I will adjust
that mix depending on the environment
depending on the growers in that
facility depending on the genetics in
that facility but in some situations I
will do fifteen percent perlite fifteen
percent perlite
and 70% cocoa some of those decisions
are based on genetics again some of
those are based on the facility and some
are based on the growers and also those
are based on schedules if I use a little
bit less perlite and personal light I do
get a little longer wet and dry time so
the plants don't need to be watered as
frequently but if you were using cocoa
and you're going to water it's a full
saturation to get runoff I do recommend
some sort of aeration product in there
perlite and personal light are always my
go-to I like the way they fluff up that
cocoa and they don't add anything to my
mix and if we're gonna talk about cocoa
one more thing I should mention I don't
know what brand of cocoa you're
purchasing I don't know where it comes
from
no matter what it is I do recommend
giving it a rinse when you buy bags of
cocoa it can be very salty I have seen
people use bagged cocoa straight out of
the bag into the pot put a plan in it
feed it throw it in the grow room and
watch that plant turn to [ __ ] because
they did not rinse the excess salt out
of that bag - cocoa I don't know where
your cocoa is coming from I don't know
how it was shipped i don't know how it
was stored but i do know that a lot of
times there is a large buildup of salt
in a lot of store-bought cocoa so rinse
that out if you've got the opportunity
if you've got an EC meter fill up a
large container with water test the EC
of that water test the pH of that water
if you have the ability mark those two
things down fill a small container with
cocoa then water that container until
you get run off gather some of that
runoff water in a clean container and
test it what is the pH what is the TDS
what is the EC of that runoff water if
it is really high you need to clean that
cocoa before you put your plants in it
because it will fry your plants now it
doesn't sound like our friend Brett is
having a salt issue I just wanted to
make sure to mention that let's get back
on track let's have faith in Brett that
he rinsed out his medium so we know he's
got some nice clean cocoa let's also
trust that he put plenty of perlite or
personal light in there so we know he
has got plenty of aeration we also know
that he listened to episode 337 so he
understands one through five water tech
he seems to understand that he wants a
little bit of runoff but he is afraid to
water his small plants because he is not
sure that their small root system is
ready to handle such a massive
muttering that's a really good concern
because watering Coco can be confusing
it can be deceiving the first few times
Coco does hold a lot of water and the
wet and dry time is vastly different
than that of working with a soil or
soilless mix over watering your plants
in Coco will slow them down also under
watering them will allow them to get too
dry which prevents them from eating
which will give us nutrient deficiencies
so we do need to dial in our wet and dry
cycles and our watering times and also
dial in our amount of runoff so let's
talk about watering our small plants to
runoff the first part that really gets
my attention is if you are too concerned
about giving that plant that much water
in that container size that maybe you
have probably possibly up potted too
early now you may have a small plant you
may have a clone I would put that clone
into a small pot I would go something in
like a 4x4 cube maybe a six-inch net pot
something really small where we can
contain all of that medium where we
don't have to water a whole bunch that
way you're not wasting a lot of water
you're not wasting a lot of nutrients
just watering medium that doesn't have
any roots in it so start off with a
smaller pot then gradually increase pot
size until you reach your finished
container size my clones generally go
into a four inch square pot or a 6-inch
round net pot then I let them grow until
that pot is filled with roots I like to
get it almost rootbound in that
container then I will transplant it into
a three gallon pot when I go from that
four inch square pot or that round a six
inch net pot I usually have to use my
fingers to break up some of those roots
to encourage them to grow outward
because I leave it in that first pot
until it gets fairly tight that first
container is only temporary I just have
it in there to get it develop just to
get it started and I don't want to water
a whole bunch of medium and a whole
bunch of space with no roots so that
smaller containers advantageous plus I
can fit more of them in my space so I
can pack way more small veg plants under
some t fives or veg lights in a small
pot than I could if I had them already
in their three gallon pots and they're
only six inches tall and have a few
nodes and they haven't branched out yet
there's no need to give them that much
space so I keep them in the small pot
and I let them grow until they're almost
rootbound
they really need to be transplanted by
the time I pot them sometimes I almost
have to cut the pot off because the
roots have grown so massively inside the
container so my first thought is that
you may be transplanting too soon I
would go from that clone to a small
container let it grow until it's busting
out then go to a big container and then
if you want to uh pot one more time I
would wait once again until it is
busting out until that first container
is almost full of roots where when you
take the container off you can see those
roots just spiraling around the outside
of the container wait until then to
transplant and that will absolutely
reduce the risk of drowning your plant
when you do water to full saturation to
achieve a little bit of runoff so my
first concern is you may be
transplanting too soon and if you're not
transplanting too soon maybe you are
transplanting into too large of a pot
maybe you need to make more gradual of a
pot size increase and that may reduce
the risk of creating a giant pool for
that small plant to drown in so maybe
wait a little bit longer and possibly
reduce the transplant pot size that may
help you out right off the bat so let's
say Brent has done everything correctly
he's got his small container plant it is
busting out the roots are starting to
hang out of the bottom of the pot a
little bit you can see it creeping up
through the drainage holes we got some
roots coming out there they look like
nice spaghetti so that plant is in a
four inch square pot or perhaps a six
inch net pot let's up pot that plant
into a three gallon pot of cocoa so
let's say we just gently remove that six
inch net pot right off the root ball
there it should pop out if it's not
super wet if it's not super dry it
should just slide off nice and easily
all of the mediums should stay in one
nice clump there you'll see roots
wrapped around the bottom of it at this
point I would hold the plant in my palms
to where the plant is facing straight up
just like it naturally should I'm kind
of cradling the plant in my palms I
would stick my fingers in the middle of
the bottom of that root ball and I would
just separate it and break it up a
little bit with my fingers you're gonna
hear it it sounds like you're pulling
someone's dreadlocks apart it sounds bad
you were encouraging proper root growth
at this time if that plant is tied up in
that container you want to break those
roots up so that it will spread out
those roots are now used to growing in a
circle we want to tell them hey you're
free grow that way grow out grow down go
fill this nuke
so I would separate them then I would
set that in the new container that is
probably about halfway 3/4 of the way
filled with cocoa set that new plant
right inside that pot fill that
container up with cocoa packets
semi-tight in there you don't want it
super tight you don't want it super
loose you don't let the water fall in
right through but you don't want it so
tight that the roots can't dig through
it so pack it semi tight when you're
filling containers I always suggest
leaving an inch or two so that you can
water the plant don't forget you need
room for water in that container so
you've got it filled up appropriately
you've now got your plan essentially
successfully transplanted at this time I
would saturate that cocoa I would water
until run off at that first transplant
time I really love to soak the [ __ ] out
of the cocoa I may go more than 20
percent runoff at this time because I
want to ensure that I saturate all of
that medium with water with nutrients
and I want to kind of settle everything
in I don't want there to be any dry
spots if there's a dry spot in the
middle that will slow down plant
production so I want to saturate my new
medium and that'll really help the cocoa
settle into the container and let me
know if I need to add more onto the top
so now you're probably thinking holy
[ __ ] Rasta Jeff we just drowned the
plants there's so much water in this
container it is super heavy yes it
should be but we've got an aeration
product in there we've got 20 percent
perlite we've got 20 percent perlite or
a similar mix in our container so we
don't have to worry about drowning the
plants we've also got a healthy plant
with an established root zone they can
take this type of a watering so we
shouldn't have to worry about drowning
that plan now the next step is to watch
this plant as the medium dries a lot of
people are gonna want to stick a
moisture content meter inside that cocoa
and they can pay attention to that
digitally they can look at it on their
phone and they can see what's going on I
think the best way to do it is to pay
attention watch the plant stick your
finger in the medium pick up the pot
when you pick up the pot does it feel
nearly as heavy as it did when you first
water does it feel half as heavy as it
did when you first watered or does it
feel super light like you might throw it
across the room that comes from one
through five water tank feel that you'll
know if it needs water when you put your
finger in there does it feel wet does it
feel dusty you'll learn does the plant
need water the most important thing to
pay attention to is the plant watch the
plant is it telling you that it needs a
drink
when cannabis plants get thirsty the
leaves start to droop when they get
really thirsty the top of the plant
starts to tip over pay attention to that
plant the minute you see those leaves
start to droop it needed water just a
few minutes ago
write down how long ago it was or
remember what that medium feels like put
your finger in there now pick it up now
remember that don't let it get to that
point
next time water at 15 minutes before it
gets to that point and you have found
the ideal watering cycle for a plant in
a cocoa container your wet &amp; dry times
are going to vary depending on plant
size container size light size and VPD
of the room but as long as your plant is
large enough and established enough to
be in the size pot in which you have put
it you should not over water your plant
if you give it enough time to dry
between waterings so my main suggestions
would be to make sure that your plant
has a well-established root zone before
you try to uh pot it my next suggestion
is make sure you're not going into too
large of a container then when you do
water get that saturation get that
runoff then the next step is patience
and learning the plant to see when it
wants water again that part is going to
be room environment
plant and strain and also watering type
dependent that is part of the
relationship that you will have to build
with each plant now sometimes you're
going to be worried because the bottom
part of your container will have more
moisture than the top part hopefully
your roots have grown down to that
bottom part and they are drinking from
that bottom part that slight dryness
will encourage the roots to go seeking
moisture and finding water and nutrients
but there is a fine line between
encouraging growth and completely
starving and dehydrating a plant so pay
attention to the plants learn when they
start showing you that they're a little
bit thirsty and then learn to water
right before that time you will develop
a relationship it will become very
comfortable you'll know you'll be able
to look and you'll go they're gonna want
water pretty soon so that will become
natural to you and once your roots are
developed in that pot is full of roots
you'll notice that they really they will
tolerate being too wet more than they
will to dry so that would be something
that you'll start to notice again a lot
of this stuff just comes from developing
relationship with the plant a lot of it
comes from developing a relationship
with one specific cultivar so I would
say dial it in grow one plant over and
over again learn your cocoa learn your
plant learn your watering system then
expand from there whatever you do
whatever I say whatever you learn
wherever you read it just keep in mind
the plants are the boss all the monitors
all of the equipment all that stuff it
won't make a difference if you've got a
moisture content sensor in there and it
says there's plenty of water and that
plant says [ __ ] the plant is right
that monitor doesn't know what that
plant likes so dial it in pay attention
to the plants pick up your plants keep
an eye on them and you will learn
exactly when to water your plants and
again if you are worried about over
watering you were probably in too large
of a container and the roots weren't
ready to go so big all right Brett I
want to thank you for a great email
thanks for listening up there in Canada
big shout out to all of my friends up
north I do appreciate all of the
Canadians support speaking of support if
you feel like this podcast was
educational informative or entertaining
and you would like to support the show
financially you can do so by joining our
patreon campaign for more information on
becoming a patron simply go to
www.petland.com
slash grow from your heart all the
information that you need will be right
there on the screen I would also
appreciate it if you support me on
social media on Facebook simply search
for the girl from your heart podcast on
Twitter it's @gf wih podcast and on
Instagram I use my other company name
it's Irie underscore genetics give me a
follow on Instagram join me for my
Instagram live feeds maybe I'll answer
one of your grow questions in my
Instagram live feed I look forward to
seeing you there also don't forget about
my new favorite cannabis friendly
application called cannabis cannabis is
available on your iPhone or your Android
device and it is free join me I'm Irene
underscore genetics on cannabis
also don't forget about the YouTube
channel again simply search for the girl
from your heart podcast click Subscribe
leave some comments on the videos I
would love your support ladies and
gentlemen that is all I've got for you
for a Thursday episode I wanna thank you
again for listening I'll be back Monday
with fresh new content I wanna give a
huge shout out to my friend Kevin
Hartman and until next time take a phat
dad and give your mom a hug for me