hey welcome to the show podcast world it
is time for episode 439 of the Grove
from your heart podcast this episode of
the show is brought to you by our
friends at seeds here now if you need
new seeds in your garden I highly
recommend seeds here now and you can
find them at www.ctvn.org ambrosia
from our friends at apothecary farms the
label says this product contains sixty
four point seven percent THC and seventy
six point four percent total
cannabinoids star dog is one of my
favorite strains to smoke it is also one
of my favorite strains to grow and I
absolutely love the concentrate it's a
big shout-out to my friends at
apothecary Farms for the star dog
ambrosia
all right podcast world in this episode
I'm going to read a listener email about
white flies before we get there let's
give some shoutouts to our friends on
patreon only give a giant grow from your
heart podcast shout out to my friend
jacob w-iowa giant shout out to just baz
how about a big girl from your heart
podcast shot it's my friend Kenny you
dig it and of course a giant shout out
to my friend Sam
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who supports the show on
patreon and if you'd like to learn how
to become a patron you can do so by
going to www.petland.com
slash grow from your heart all the
information you need will be right there
on the screen alright in this episode I
am going to read an email about white
flies before we get there I would like
to talk about something I saw in the
news recently recently I saw a report of
a young lady dying from cannabis use I
want to come on this podcast and call
complete [ __ ] that young lady did
not die because of cannabis use
I do not know that lady's medical
history I don't know anything about that
person the only thing I know is that
this person died and the coroner found
THC and her system so he then decided
that cannabis is what killed this lady I
call complete [ __ ] I think that this
medical examiner is blaming cannabis
because he can't find the true cause of
death I also think he may be blaming
cannabis so that he can catch a little
spotlight time for a minute
if he finds the very first
cannabis-related death that will put him
in some sort of medical book that will
put some news on him I'm talking about
the doctor right now even though I won't
say his name he is getting a little bit
of spotlight time because of this
situation he may be taking that
opportunity to get a little attention
and he may be on the other team he may
be against cannabis so this would be a
good way to kind of throw cannabis under
the bus is to find the very first death
caused by cannabis so he would be able
to fight for the other team you'd be
able to get a little bit of notoriety
and he would also have a cause an
explanation for this young lady's death
from everything else I read there is not
a reasonable cause of death so he simply
states that he believes cannabis is what
did it I am NOT a doctor I'm not going
to try to explain why you cannot OD from
cannabis it does not work on the parts
of your body that make you shut down and
make you die those are different drugs
if you could die from cannabis it would
have happened a long time ago myself and
many of my friends would have been
victims several years ago I do not know
anything about this young lady's medical
history I don't know anything about her
health history I don't know anything
about her life or her habits she was not
an old person she was not a sick person
that is really all that any of the
articles listed would mention about her
the only real details we got was that
she was dead and that she had THC in her
system and that the coroner was blaming
it on the THC I know it's tragic and
terrible and anybody dies but sometimes
people just die without explanation
there doesn't have to be a reason
sometimes part of your body just goes in
done sometimes your car breaks down
sometimes your computer gives up
sometimes a light bulb burns out our
bodies are made of a bunch of different
connecting parts and one one decides to
shut down it can shut down the whole
system so I don't know what killed this
young lady
honestly I don't believe the coroner
knows what killed this young lady one
thing I am certain of this lady did not
die because she had THC in her system so
no matter what the news tells you no
matter what this report tells you there
are still zero deaths linked to cannabis
consumption I want to send my love and
my condolences to this
young ladies family it's terrible that
she's been brought into the news and
into the spotlight in such a terrible
way but I send my love I send my heart
out to her her family
I send a big middle finger to this
coroner ah he is wrong he's a liar I
really think he's just trying to get
some spotlight I am not sure if this is
the end of this story I'm not sure if he
can just say cannabis caused this and
then somewhere in some record book it
now says that there is an official
cannabis death I hope that there is more
investigation more to be proven before
that can be marked down I will do my
best to stay updated on that situation
all right let's jump into this email
about white flies this email goes a lot
like this hello Rasta Jeff I need some
help and you are the best resource I
know for all things cannabis feel free
to read this on the show if you want
well here we go buddy we're gonna read
this on the show right now it says I've
been bested by white flies let me give
you a little background on my grow I
grow in a reasonably sized cabinet six
foot by two foot divided into two by two
and four by two spaces and a two by two
grow tent I keep my mothers in the two
by two cabinet I grow out clones in the
two by two flower in the four by two all
in soil with LED lighting all of this is
in my basement all right so we got a
nice little compact Perpetual grow it
says about two or two-and-a-half months
ago I found white flies in my flower
I picked off every affected leaf and put
out a bunch of sticky traps here on the
right start I shook the plants three to
four times a day and vacuumed up what
flew off which got me through flower so
far that is an effective strategy let's
talk about white flies really quickly
white flies are really easy to identify
they are little white flies they look
like flying pieces of ash in your grow
room if you pull off the leaf and turn
it upside down it looks like a piece of
rice or probably bunches of pieces of
rice on the bottom of your leaves those
are white flies when you shake the
plants when you tap the pots if white
things come flying out those are white
flies this guy said he shook the plants
three to four times a day and vacuumed
up what flew off that is a very
effective strategy those white flies
want to fly up toward the light when you
shake the plant you just
RUP them they're nice and comfortable
they're hanging out in the leaves you
shake it they go what the [ __ ] was that
they go flying up toward the light they
just want to go fly and tell that all
the disruption stops and they'll go land
back on their home while they're flying
get the shot back and just shot back the
[ __ ] out of them I use the long
attachment on the shopvac and I would
just point that right at the light and
just kind of move back and forth as
those bugs fly up at the light and just
get them if you want to get in there and
kind of tap the buds with the shopvac
and just smack it you're using that long
wand attachment just smack some of the
buds with that and then the bugs will go
flying out and you just suck them up
right as they come flying out there you
can do that multiple times a day if you
remove a lot of the excess foliage the
white flies have less places to hang out
less places for breeding make it less
desirable in there there is more to this
email let's keep going it says now with
everything in veg I went to the gross
store and got the recommendations of my
local guy and treated with a rosemary
extract pesticide I also did a soil
soaked and foliar spray on all three
spaces and I sprayed down all surfaces
as well all right so you got a pesticide
that was recommended by a grouse store
person then you did a soil soak and a
foliar spray on all of your spaces so
you treated all the plants that were in
veg then you also sprayed down all
surfaces that is a good plan of attack
that is a good strategy but I honestly
don't think that the rosemary extract
pesticide is going to be strong enough
to eradicate white flies at the level
which you have got that you have got a
serious infestation and something like a
rosemary extract works better as a
preventative it just makes it kind of
undesirable for the for the pests and
they're already there they don't give a
[ __ ] they have made themselves
comfortable I don't think you're gonna
get enough coverage with this rosemary
extract to run them off there's more to
the message let's keep going it says it
seemed to work he recommended holding
off on moving anything into flower and
treat a few times a week for a few weeks
to make sure the white flies are gone
everything seemed to be going well I
treated for three weeks I cut new clones
I moved my current clones to flower and
after a week under twelve twelve I found
more white flies something to address
right there
first off you started with a pesticide
application that was not strong enough
for the infestation you were battling so
you did not really have a chance it
looks like you knocked him down but
there were still eggs you need to break
the life cycle of the pest you need to
disrupt multiple generations then you
can guarantee that the paths are gone
but you were using something that didn't
knock out all stages then you made a
crucial mistake you applied the same
pesticide multiple times a week for
multiple weeks by the third week those
white flies were laughing at that
pesticide they were gone
haha we drink that [ __ ] now and the bugs
that are now in your room have built up
a resistance to that rosemary extract
pesticide so your main crucial mistake
was using one pesticide over and over
again you need to rotate products you
need multiple different products so that
you can prevent that resistance and you
also need the appropriate pesticide you
were basically just given them a bubble
bath after a while and they were just
laughing at you let's keep going there
is more to this message at this point
the plants are in flower they're under
12 12 and we have discovered more white
flies one week into flower so it says
they are in all three spaces yes those
white flies get around quite quickly
they breed rapidly white flies are a
pain in the ass they get out of control
really quickly but we are going to help
you get rid of them he says I trashed
all of my clones and flowering plants I
trimmed up my mother plants i vacuumed
the spaces out and I tried insecticidal
soap on the mothers and empty Gro spaces
again it seemed to help I thought they
were gone I cut new clones and this week
they're back again yeah that
insecticidal soap and that rosemary oil
are not gonna cut it we're gonna have to
step up our game we're gonna have to go
nuclear pretty soon we're gonna have to
talk about that let's keep going there
is more to this message I grabbed a bag
of diatomaceous earth and I've dusted
everything I checked today and the
bottoms of my leaves are loaded with
white fly larvae once again I need a
nuclear solution to this I'm not sure
what else to try other than bug bombs in
each grow space and I hope the mothers
survive to cut clones from can you
recommend anything that would be a
surefire way to wipe out my white flies
and
advice would be greatly appreciated
thanks again from Dan hey Dan thank you
for the great email it's too bad you got
white flies but let's talk about getting
rid of those bad [ __ ] for you
white flies can be a pain in the ass
like I said earlier they come on quickly
they breed quickly they spread from room
to room rapidly unless you know how to
get rid of them they can be a complete
pain in the ass let's talk about
eradicating white flies in your grow one
thing that I like is you only have
mother plants that is going to be very
beneficial we don't have to think about
treating plants that are in flower we
will talk about treating flowering
plants but it's going to help you out a
lot that you can apply just about
anything at this point because you have
got veg plants you don't have any buds
to worry about that is truly
advantageous I think a lot of growers a
lot of facilities are doing it a little
bit backwards when it comes to pest
management they focus on treating the
flowering plants for a pass they're the
priority for pest management then they
go to the large veg then they go to the
small veg then they go to the tiny stuff
then they go to the moms and they worry
about the moms dead last when it comes
to pest management I like to go to the
complete opposite direction I like to
worry about pest pathogen problem-free
mother plants and work my way forward
through the grow with a good healthy
start so in my opinion IPM starts in the
mother room then it works all the way
through the grow it's a process it
starts in the mother room just like all
the other plants so I love that you've
got nothing but mother plants to work
with that puts you ahead of the game one
of the first things I would do is work
on sealing up my grow space where are
those bugs coming in they're tiny but
they're finding a way in and they are
breeding so figure out where they're
coming from seal up the grow space a
little bit more securely that will help
you out the next step is to D foliate
heavily take off any leaf you don't
think you need we need to get rid of all
of the breeding space all the hangout
spots we need to remove all the space
for these [ __ ] white flies to hang
out let's take away all the free parking
just chop it out of there clean it up
get that out of the grow space get that
out of the house you said this is in
your basement get it out of the house
get it as far away from your house as
you can get rid of all these white flies
just evict them get out we don't want
here so defoliate heavily be fully to
the point that you're worried about
those plants they'll grow more leaves
they'll come back as long as those
plants are mostly healthy they will
recover from the defoliation they will
like being d foliated more than they
like being a host for white flies so
strip off any extra leaves strip off all
the giant fan leaves we don't need all
that [ __ ] right now
these aren't high-performance plants
these are mother plants that we're just
trying to make survive at this point in
time so defoliate heavily your next
thing to think about is stepping up your
spray regimen the things you're spraying
right now have basically become kool-aid
for the white flies I would suggest a
stronger pesticide application here is
where you have a few moral decisions to
make how strong of a pesticide do you
want to use I try to stay on the
Colorado Department of Agriculture
approved pesticide list for commercial
cannabis production I try to maintain
that standard in any grow I work in
whether it be a home grow whether it be
a commercial grow I still try to adhere
to those standards just to make it a
habit some people don't want to use any
pesticides that are not Omri certified
organic what you spray on your plants is
ultimately your decision but also you
have to live with what you've done to
those plants and what you are giving to
other people to consume so as long as
you can live with yourself and you feel
okay with what you've done you can apply
whatever you're comfortable with to
these plants in this message you said
you're ready to go nuclear carefully
scheduled sprayed pesticide applications
will be the quickest and simplest way to
eradicate these bugs but we can't just
keep spraying forever so we need to
eradicate them and figure out how they
got in there and make sure they don't
come back so let's talk about a few
products we can apply to our plants to
make sure we get rid of these white
flies one thing we can start with is as
a max as a max has multiple modes of
attack to make sure these bugs don't
want to be around hopefully when you're
working with as a max you're wearing a
glove but if you've ever touched it
you'll notice that it is quite oily we
apply that oily consistency to the
bottom of the leaves the bugs don't want
to be on that oily consistency so it
makes it undesirable for them to live
there then as an added bonus there is a
in the a Xamax that works as a stomach
poison so any pest that does eat your
leafy foliage they will get a tummy ache
it will stop eating and they will die
another product I can recommend for you
is evergreen pyrethrum there's also a
very similar product called pi Ganic
there are very similar products but they
do have different application rates so
if you are used to using one or the
other make sure you read the bottle and
adjust your application rates both of
those products are very oily and very
sticky so again we're going to apply
those to the bottom the underside of the
leaves where do we see all those eggs if
we apply a nice coat of oily surface
those bugs don't want to go there they
don't want to hang out they don't want
to breed and will also suffocate the
bugs and we can also suffocate their
eggs
so if we use evergreen or pie ganic our
first mode of attack is to create an
undesirable environment by making it
sticky we're also suffocating them then
there's also the added bonus of the
pyrethrum in there so anything that does
take a bite out of the leaf it is going
to get a tummy ache
and it is going to die those are both
very affordable products another very
affordable and readily available product
is something called monterey garden
spray with spinosad i'm not sure if you
call it spinosad or spinosad either way
that [ __ ] works to get rid of white
flies spinosad is a fungus that is
created in the bottom of whiskey or rum
barrels I believe it is the bottom of a
whiskey barrel it is naturally occurring
and for some reason it kills the [ __ ]
out of white flies so there's a product
called monterey garden spray and it will
say spinosad right on the bottle it is
very affordable it is very easy to find
another product I can recommend for you
we're starting to get a little more
expensive also we're starting to get a
little more dangerous a little less
gentle another product I'll recommend is
something called venerate venerate we'll
wipe the [ __ ] out of almost every pest
in your garden another product I can
recommend for white flies is botanic
guard
EAS and I also like a product called bio
seer WP both of those products contain a
beneficial fungus I'm trying to remember
the name it is actually called Bavaria
basi onna which is very good at
destroying white flies now if you really
want to step up your game a really
expensive product that will work to help
you get rid of your why
flies is a product called my Cotrell es
o be forewarned that one is not cheap I
don't know your budget I don't know what
you're working with
I don't know how nuclear you want to go
but that is a nice list of products
they'll will work to eradicate your
white flies know whatever you choose to
use to get rid of these bugs make sure
you have a rotation don't spray the same
product every three days Spray one
product on day one apply a different
product on day four apply a different
product on day seven if you can then
start the rotation over but don't do the
same product more than two times in a
row no matter what you do that is how
you start giving these pests a
resistance to the products you're buying
your bugs are gonna get stronger and
stronger you're gonna create super bugs
in there another thing you can do is you
can tank mix multiple pesticides in an
applicator at one time as long as those
products are compatible so before you go
mixing a large batch of pesticide if
you're going to do a tank mix of
multiple pesticides you've never ran
together before I suggest mixing a very
small batch of them together mix it up
see what happens see if you get any
weird chemical reactions out of it if
you don't get any weird reactions mix up
the desired amount which you want to
apply to your plants then pick one
sacrificial plant and spray the [ __ ] out
of it see if that one plant does any
weird [ __ ] if it doesn't harm that plant
you've got a great mix that is your new
pesticide application write down exactly
what went in there write down how much
water you started with write down how
much whatever product you put in there
write down how much of the other product
you put in there write it down write
down when you sprayed write down what
you saw from that take a lot of notes we
consume cannabis so we forget a lot of
[ __ ] make sure you write things down if
you want a great lesson on mixing
multiple pesticides in one spray
applicator for one good application I
highly recommend an episode I did call
tank mix it is episode number 289 of the
growth from your heart podcast make sure
you check that one out I talked a lot
about mixing pesticides and proper
pesticide application so we've got a lot
of spray pesticide application options
another thing I would recommend is a
root drench many of the products I
recommended
are also usable as a drench I feel that
maybe some of the larvae from your white
flies has ended up in your medium that's
why you're having a hard time getting
rid of them
you've got eggs just chilling down there
in the soil so I would recommend a root
drench I would probably use the
Evergreen or the a Xamax or the Bataan
Agard and I would just mix that into
some water and I would soak the roots
thoroughly just water it in let it soak
out through the bottom that way you've
got pesticide in your medium we need to
go nuclear like you said we don't need
to leave any open space let's get the
leaves coated and nasty stickiness let's
get the root zone
let's get that medium coated and nasty
stickiness let's not make it a desirable
environment for these white flies now
when you do a root drench you do need to
make sure not to suffocate the roots so
whatever your recommended dosage is for
your foliar spray
I would probably reduce the root drench
application to about half of whatever
you were spraying so if you're spraying
10 milliliters of a product I would root
drench with five you can always route
drench again with the increased dosage
but you can't under inch so once those
roots are coated in oil and you've got a
problem you're already pretty [ __ ]
so go light then if that doesn't do it
go harder next time
pay close attention to the plants like I
said write everything down another thing
we need to do is continue with the
yellow sticky traps those yellow sticky
traps are going to let us know how the
population is sustaining we'll know if
there are less if there are more white
flies than there were before one
important thing is to change those
sticky traps if you leave the same trap
up for too long how do you know how many
flies were gathered at one point in time
so make sure you rotate them on a
frequent basis once a week is probably
enough so we have heavily d foliated
we've taken all that foliage out of the
grow it's out of the house it's as far
away as we can get it we have burned it
it is gone then we have applied
ridiculous amounts of pesticides on a
routine schedule we're spraying every
three days and we are rotating we're
possibly doing a tank mix with multiple
pesticides this is going to knock down
the populations then we are going to do
a route drench this is going to make
sure that none of the larvae none of the
eggs are chilling in the medium now
we've in theory destroyed all of the
bugs we were trying to get rid of what
are we going to do to
make sure they don't come back it sounds
like the first step is to seal the room
the next step is to think of an
integrated pest management strategy that
will make sure we don't get these bugs
back when we are late in Flour it is
really easy to get rid of these bugs
with our mother plants with our veg
plants because we can just go spraying
every three days
once we've got buds we can't spray
anymore so what are we going to do to
make sure we don't get bugs later in
Flour this is where I like to introduce
predator insects spider mites thrips
fungus gnats white flies I don't care
what kind of bug you are you cannot
build a resistance to being eaten by a
predator so once you have eradicated
your infestation and you're sure that
99.9% of these white flies are gone I
would switch my strategy and invest
heavily in predator bugs if you are at a
point where you have only got mother
plants and/or veg plants you were at a
huge advantage to start with predator
bugs it is a great time to start
building colonies you can purchase
enough predator bugs to build a large
enough colony to overtake any sort of
invaders that may try to come in if you
start with your moms and your veg plants
the idea would be to get enough predator
insects on those veg plants or when you
take clones you move some predators
right along with the clones then those
veg plants start to grow and those
predator insects will colonize on your
veg plants their party and their
breeding there to live in life so
they're just colonizing and they are
expanding with the grow they become a
part of the girl you create a symbiosis
that's what happens outside that's what
happens in nature if you get bug a bug
bee will come along and say hey look a
bunch of these and it'll eat it then
they'll either move along or they'll try
to colonize if they get too much if they
get too comfortable they get too fancy
bug seal come along it's eight now bro
this is our territory and they'll eat
bug bee and they'll run them off and
then those bugs will either move along
to the next guard and they keep playing
security that way or they'll repeat the
process they'll try to hang out they'll
run out of bugs to eat and they'll die
or they'll leave or something will come
and eat them that's how it happens in
nature we can replicate that in our grow
rooms if we use a well-thought-out
integrated pest management strategy now
something you're going to have to be
careful with is our
pesticides you are using going to
endanger your predators that you're
paying money for in a lot of commercial
environments I will start the mother
rooms and the bedrooms by using
pesticide applications as we move into
the later bedrooms in the flower areas
and will begin releasing large amounts
of predator bugs my budget may be a
little bit different than most people's
because I'm working on a commercial
scale also the value of my crop is more
critical than some folks because I am
working on a large commercial scale I'm
not downplaying the size of your garden
I'm just saying that we have to be a
little more careful we're going to lose
hundreds of pounds compared to somebody
losing one or two pounds in a home girl
yes you're out of medicine but if I lose
hundreds of pounds people are out of
jobs businesses fail it is a very huge
loss so my strategy is to go very hard
on the moms go very hard in the veg
phase make sure I do not get any pests
any pathogens any problems throughout
that cycle late in veg or right at the
start of flower I start adjusting my
pesticide application schedule to make
sure I'm not applying anything that will
be harmful or detrimental to my predator
bugs then I like to switch to releasing
large ridiculous amounts of predatory
mites so I've got that residual
pesticide hanging out for a couple of
weeks then that starts to degrade then
by the time all that pesticide breaks
down is no longer active on my plants my
predatory mites have had time to
colonize I've got a big army in there
and I've still got protection I know
that I don't have any chance for spider
mites or anything like that to come take
a hold in my garden so you've got a
couple of options for this strategy you
can either start by letting the
predatory mites go in the mom room get
them in the veg room get them started
early
get them colonizing or you can start
with pesticides early then when you move
to the flowering phase when it's no
longer a good idea to spray you can
start releasing your predatory mites and
start working things that way you've got
a few things to think about but I think
with all the information I've given you
we should be able to get rid of those
white flies let's talk more specifically
about some of the predatory bugs that
you could use and then we were gonna get
out of here for this episode I really
appreciate lace wings in a garden
I feel like lace wings are hungry and
aggressive I am most familiar with the
lace wings that come in the eggs that
are on the black sheet that you hang in
there
locations throughout the grow those are
what I'm most familiar with I like to
watch them come alive they turn into a
little crocodile looking thing and then
eventually they turn into a green
lacewing those things are hungry
they're so hungry that I believe they
become carnivorous they will eat every
pest in your garden then they will turn
on their friends and family so green
lace wings are awesome in any garden
then the next predatory mite that I
would recommend their works on a
plethora of garden pests is the sworsky
predatory mite I release sworsky mites
on a regular basis in any commercial
grow environment that I am responsible
for I can also recommend hookah Marys
and my new pirate bugs now predatory
mites can get a little bit expensive but
if all you've got our mother plants you
have a great opportunity to start
colonies in a small garden so now all
you've got to do is hang up some yellow
sticky traps defoliate like a
[ __ ]
do some research on several pesticides
select the few that work for you create
a nice rotation of pesticides start
applying them diligently until you knock
down that population then decide how you
want to proceed are you going to keep
going with the pesticides or are you
going to start using some sort of
predators you also need to seal up that
room and figure out where those bugs are
coming from you've got a very small
crack somewhere they have found that
crack and they are making their way in
so we've got to figure out how to seal
that up but I think we can get rid of
these white flies white flies aren't as
big of a problem as they seem like
they're more of a pain in the ass
they're more ugly they're more annoying
than anything else but if we stay on top
of it we will get them out of your
garden hey I want to thank you for a
great email if anybody else out there
has a grow question I would love to help
you out my email address is grow from
your heart at hotmail.com and i look
forward to hearing from you if you have
sent me an email and I haven't read it
on the show don't feel discouraged I
have got a stack of emails about eight
feet tall I am working my way through
them be patient and I will read your
message on a future episode ladies and
gentlemen that is all I've got for you
for episode 439 I want to thank you
again for listening I'll be back in a
couple of days with fresh new content if
you feel like this episode is
educational informative or entertaining
and you would like to make a financial
contribution to the show you can do so
by going to patreon.com slash
from your heart all of the information
you need will be right there on the
screen
once again big thanks and big shout out
to everybody who is helped out on the
patreon campaign in the past and the
present and in the future
I would also appreciate it if you
support the show on social media you can
find us on Facebook simply search for
the growth from your heart podcast on
Twitter it's @gf wih podcast on
instagram i use my other company i use i
re underscore genetics and please give
me a follow on cannabis cannabis is a
new cannabis friendly social media
application if you post about cannabis
your post will not get censored or
deleted if you've got cannabis questions
or cannabis photography you would like
to share come find us over on cannabis
join the community we would love to see
you over there if you've got something
you'd like to say you're not into all
that social media nonsense you can send
me an email my email address is grow
from your heart at hotmail.com ladies
and gentleman that is all I've got for
you for this episode I want to give a
huge shout out to my friend few Madore
and until next time take a phat dad and
give your mom a hug for me