welcome back podcast world it is time
for episode 440 of the Grove from your
heart podcast this episode of the show
is brought to you by our friends at
seeds here now if you need new seeds in
your garden I highly recommend seeds
here now and you can find them at seeds
here now dot-com ladies and gentlemen
white Mike is back on the show welcome
to the show buddy
thanks man what's up everybody thanks
for joining us dude I know you were a
busy guy but we get a lot of requests to
have you on the show I've been here in
the shadow it's keep centered on people
I'll keep coming back there you go keep
requesting them he will keep coming back
on the show we don't have him for a long
time so we're gonna get in a minute
let's dive right in
yeah it's been a little while dude
thanks for coming thanks for hanging out
we've been chatting for a few so we got
to jump into this where are we let's
talk about what we're smoking on usually
we talk about what we're smoking
we just took a couple of dabs of Gigi
number four batter the potency label
says it is 65 percent THC with seventy
five point one percent total
cannabinoids but I topped that off with
some pre 98 bubba kush high cannabinoid
full-spectrum extract the potent season
label says this is eighty four point
five percent THC and ninety six point
seven percent total cannabinoids
basically the batter looks would you
agree that that kind of looks like
cheesecake or cake batter the lids are
wrong looks like packages so that one
right there let's say cake batter or
cheesecake and then this one put the
lids on the right containers as they go
back yeah that's this one over here
would you say it looks like diamonds
with hints of yellow yep so I've got
some some batter with some diamonds in
it basically and those dabs were
delicious mmm the GG for we're not
supposed to say she did other words with
the GG for taste yeah it tastes so good
it's got that that earthy cushy sort of
a thing going on and then that the
flavor on that combo dad was really nice
yeah the pre 98 just punches you right
in the face so big shout out to our
friends both of those of course are from
apothecary farm so big shout out to our
friends and apothecary Farms boo boo or
it take good care of me over there I've
been shopping at the Pueblo location a
lot since it is pretty close to our area
here and they see me on a regular basis
we have become quite friendly so a big
shout out to all my friends go take care
of your bud tenders at apothecary farms
all right Mike what is next Oh patreon
shoutouts that's what we usually do next
I've got to do some shoutouts to our
friends on patreon I'm gonna give you
huge shout out to my friend miss Mel of
course a big girl from your heart
podcast shout out to our friends at
Hogan's farms a big girl from your heart
podcast shot to our buddy Brian s of
course a shout out to Aldridge and as
always a big giant grill from your heart
a podcast hug and a shout out to my
buddy
stabby make stabber said I want to thank
everybody for all of the continued
patreon support if you'd like to learn
how to become a patron you can do so by
going to www.petland.com
slash grow from your heart all of the
information you need will be right there
on the screen all right we do have a
couple of things to talk about on the
podcast before we get to the main topic
of the show I do need to make a
correction there is a Corrections
Department big shout out to the person
who sent me the message reminding me
that I [ __ ] up I said something wrong
on the podcast and uh I'm all about
being corrected that's how I learn
sometimes people are gonna make mistakes
I did 440 episodes and I think this is
like the second or third correction I've
received right if this is the fourth I'm
gonna say that's still good percentage
oh yeah yeah so and I'm gonna make some
mistakes and things are gonna change and
I apologize when that happens I do my
best to stay on top of it but
occasionally I talk fast my brain goes
really fast sometimes they don't connect
properly sometimes the wrong numbers and
lighters will fly out but I said
something that was inaccurate and our
Corrections Department sent me a message
and if I do that again please feel free
to send me messages I like learning I
like being corrected that's how we stay
smart on top so the correction I need to
make is on the last episode I said that
I only use products in aggro that are on
the Colorado Department of Agriculture
approved pesticide list for cannabis use
then I listed as a max as a max has been
banned in the use of cannabis and
Colorado medical and recreational
production so when I said that I was
absolutely wrong I'm correcting myself
now do not use as a MACT you will get
yourself in some trouble with the
Department of Ag so I stand corrected
I apologize for that
information I will do my best not to do
that again and I promise you I'm not
spraying as a max anywhere I've got
another product I can't think of it off
the top of my head I should have looked
that up but that's not what I was here
for today I just wanted to make sure
that I did correct you that as a max or
correct myself that as a max is no
longer allowed in cannabis production
all right so we've made that correction
let's move forward Mike you ready to
jump into the main topic of today's
podcast indeed indeed so the big news
today Illinois no Illinois has gun
recreational legal reason now in
Illinois you can possess I don't know
all the rules but you can have your
cannabis they have recreation so January
1st
okay well yeah you gotta wait till the
rules come into play that's always the
fun part up bill was signed into law
today at Atlantan on the governor's desk
a couple of weeks ago and has been in
that fun limbo while the governor
decides or decides not to or waits for
the time they feel like signing to occur
so today was that day got signed this
morning awesome well thanks for signing
it sir whose name I am not aware of
governor hard to say his name
there you go governor hard to say thank
you I don't know what his name is but uh
it feels like when you say that the bill
has been that we've basically been
waiting for him to sign it I get the
feeling of like when there's a movie
coming out or a toy coming out when you
were a kid and you wanted to go to that
movie or you wanted that toy and you
were to ask your mom Friday when the
story comes out can i get it and i get
it and i get it and all week she's like
i don't know because she really didn't
know no she could make that [ __ ] happen
Friday when payday came she's gonna pay
up all the bills and if there were six
bucks left to go to that movie you could
but do you want to tell you yes does
she'd break your [ __ ] heart she don't
want to say no now because she might
break your [ __ ] heart so she like I
don't know it all we hear is waiting so
it's it's a bizarre political thing like
this is something that the governor in
question the governor Illinois said he
wanted it was part of his campaign for
reelection I'm getting it done this year
was a big platform of his something he
talked about wanting to accomplish
legalization efforts especially in the
Legislature's this year took a weird
turn where instead of just getting
cannabis legal we're trying to write
like a whole bunch of the wrongs that
have occurred over the Prohibition years
at the same time and it's just too much
at once yeah like we want one-stop
shopping here where we get weed legal
and we get funding for communities that
were way over policed for drug crimes
and have suffered systemic problems
because of that over policing and we're
gonna get them some funding and we're
gonna make sure that there's a fund for
minority business owners to become
marijuana business owners to help them
out with credit and stuff and we're
gonna if you sent that to me in an email
you know what I would reply with too
long I didn't read it's yeah it's it's
four or five different ideas on Bush
together they also got fixing past
convictions if you were convicted of
possession or less than I want to say
it's thirty grams
I remember thinking it was an ounce and
change if you had less than an ounce to
change and you were busted in Illinois
you can now apply to have that
conviction sealed or removed from your
record I'm not sure how they worded it
like that they gave me was 130 grams in
case you got it from me and I gave you a
fat ounce you know you can act for 30 31
troubles cuz I never gave you twenty
eight point three five also I've
mentioned that before twenty eight point
three five announces not twenty eight
grams and ounces twenty eight point
three five that only that doesn't sound
big that point registers are a little
surprised the rest of the world is like
[ __ ] America right yeah well that
point three five doesn't sound like much
but add it up to four times if you're
buying a quarter pound now you're at
point seven that's one point for right
do the sixteen times what if you're
buying ten pounds like I was gonna say
we've got a legal medical marijuana
market now if I say I sold them ten
pounds and you only ring up that ten
pounds by twenty eight grams and you
actually gave I gave them twenty eight
point three five there's gonna be a
shortage somewhere on our system and in
our money as I got halfway on a [ __ ]
crazy rant there that's gonna three
grams thing and don't get me wrong I
like all of the parts that they kind of
squeezed into this law but
we watched New York and New Jersey fail
in their attempts to get legalization
done this year not because like a whole
bunch of people there were like maybe
it's a bad idea let's hold off and see
how it goes and the other place there's
none of that [ __ ] they were all like
well I want money for this pet project
and you know I think it's important that
we address this particular wrong with
this bill and they could never hatch out
the the taxes and the other stuff they
wanted to attach to legalization so they
left it illegal for another eight months
or in Texas for two more years because
the legislature only meets every other
year but illinois' managed to squeak it
out it just barely to that I think when
this bill went through the Senate and
the House of Representatives it only had
a couple of days left in their official
session so it made it through just one
of the wire and then governors do this
weird thing where they campaign on
something the House passes it the Senate
passes it it goes to the governor's desk
and then there's just three weeks so
wondering what the [ __ ] going on why
why do they play with us like that
there's not any rhyme or reason to it
because all the governors do it and it
happens pretty much any time there's a
bill signing the bill heads to the
governor's desk in uux you would expect
like hey this is a big thing you've been
[ __ ] talking about for a year there
was a big fight over at the press and
you won like you official one on Friday
why is Monday night like that everybody
get together in my office and we'll sign
this yeah there's always a couple of
weeks down the road and he's like
golfing and then they don't announce it
abies so I've been waiting for the
official like hey Illinois got signed to
call you and say hey we have to do a
show we should talk about Illinois
perfect timing and I've been watching
there's been no one now it's been saying
hey we're gonna sign that sucker on
Wednesday nothing it's just I got up
today and I was to my phone it was like
oh hey he signed it yesterday was the
day it's weird we don't pay attention to
much of their stuff going on in Illinois
because we are in Colorado so not no
offense to Illinois I just pay more
attention to Colorado stuff I wonder if
he's just been going through a list
signing [ __ ] or if today was just the
days like Oh actually does its
he was working on a to-do list and this
was just item 25 and he couldn't get to
it until he got item 24 done is there's
nothing like that strange yes
either way shout out to our friends out
there in Illinois for joining the
recreational cannabis game it uh January
first
everything really kicks off if you're in
Illinois or want to start a marijuana
business in Illinois now's the time to
get on that [ __ ] brings us to eleven
recreational cannabis states here in the
great states eleven yeah if you're from
Pueblo that's eleven but most of the
world says eleven so how Colorado gets
to claim to be first Washington gets to
claim to that they went at the same time
as us their polls just closed two hours
after ours and then every state census
tried to come up with their own little
claim to fame like Vermont got to say
like we legalized adult possession but
through the legislature we're the first
state to do it through the legislature
but they haven't gotten around to
creating a commercial industry system
and so Illinois's went through the
legislature they were the second to do
through the legislature but they the
first to do it through the legislature
and include a retail system like
framework for that so they're like hey
we're first and it's like 11th [ __ ]
people are gonna jump up and say that
Colorado was not first he said
recreational when it comes to medical
there are other states that were first
happy yeah big shout-out to our friends
McCallie and that's that is a good segue
33 medical marijuana states here if you
guys can do math 33 now yeah that only
leaves out six states without some
cannabis friendly laws Mike and I were
trying to do some research honestly at
the start of the show and we kept
finding conflicting information on which
states do not support medical or some
sort of cannabis so many states at this
point I think I really think it's under
five that don't have any sort of
marijuana law but now there's at least
four or five on top of that original
five
that are CBD only where you can get
basically help extract that up until the
farm bill passed in November would have
been considered totally illegal part of
the marijuana plant no different in a
court of law from high THC hash but you
can get CBD extract I think it's like
Utah on a couple of others that are
really minimal CBD only we looked at a
map and it had different shades of green
would indicate recreational legal or
decriminalized and then little black
states on the map would indicate don't
go here and most of those work down in
the southeastern part of our great
nation here so that's where we need to
kind of shift our focus on the cannabis
legalization efforts most of us seem to
be catching on here it's in it's coming
in quick Wisconsin is one of the states
that has no medical marijuana laws no
recreational marijuana laws and today
their elected officials several of them
were in the press talking about like
well you know now we're kind of boxed in
with Illinois goes awesome um so is is
illinois' another big state there's a
[ __ ] ton of people who live in Illinois
I was gonna Google exactly what their
population is but that seems like extra
effort for tonight's show
do you thanks Mike do you think that
state officials people that
decision-makers on that level think like
I do when they see so I'm just gonna say
they were asked where and the states to
the north the South the east and the
west of us have all hypothetically just
legalized some sort of cannabis use do
you think that that makes us go well
from an economic standpoint we need to
do this too because all of our people
are just driving 30 miles that way 30
miles that way or 30 miles that way or
110 miles that way and they're buying
product they're bringing it back maybe
we need to just start there's some of
that that works I know for a fact there
are sections of Colorado that were
thrilled that a couple of our
neighboring states failed that their
legalization attempts because areas like
Trinidad in southern Colorado
have been
um really energized by legal cannabis
taxes and revenue investment in the
community it's a Trinidad's a weird city
that's gone through several boom and
bust cycles even like their Sheriff is
like hey ride the boom wall it's booming
these guys aren't hurting anybody
they're investing a ton of taxes more
little area too late for us we have
friends down there we used to go to
gatherings down there and we've seen
that place go from a dusty kind of a
fall in a part of town it was almost a
ghost town it was now it's yeah
beautiful like it's strange to say but
it was five or ten years from ghost town
yeah I'm and now it's a hustling little
city and Trinidad is basically the first
city in Colorado when you come from New
Mexico if you're coming north from New
Mexico which is a good segue to talk
about this part I see a lot on top of
what's happening in New Mexico I'm
involved in the New Mexico medical
marijuana movement is also and also what
is going to become the recreational
medical marijuana movement I do some
consulting and things like that I help
people down there do some teaching and
other things but I pay attention to
what's going on down there a big part of
why they are pushing toward the
legalization of recreational cannabis is
because they see if many people post
openly about it on Facebook in the in
anywhere in the groups on the where
wherever we talk on social media like I
don't even shop in New Mexico I go to
Colorado because it's half the price and
so they're showing pictures of all this
Colorado product in New Mexico and so
New Mexico saying well [ __ ] they're just
driving two hours that's all they have
to do and it's half the price and double
the quality because we have silly rules
here let's change that and that's
actually part of why they're changing
their rules that small influence I can't
say it's a big deal but it does affect
them they've noticed it there was a huge
influx of they caught tourism traffic
through Colorado
starting in January 2014 as soon as our
rec stores opened there was no reason to
come visit us with med stores really I
mean you could but you weren't you
couldn't get in who wants to go stand in
the parking lot at Disneyland yeah or
Walley world or whatever but
with wreck people from all around the
u.s. I mean all over the planet really I
when I was but tending it one of the
more touristy spots in town like we
would get people from all over the
planet regularly you can remember a
couple of guys from Ireland who just
spent spent like an hour walking around
and taking pictures of I mean everything
in the dispenser is just blown away
because there's nothing like this where
they're from he's not gonna be for
another 30 years that's a great ok keep
just watching us exactly
Canada saw some of our state's going
legal and that really pushed that
government I mean really really pushed
they've been more adult about their
marijuana discussion I'd say for the
last 20 years yeah but watching States
in in the u.s. go legal and then having
Canadians report like we just jumped the
border to Washington grab what we want
and bring it back no one checks our cars
like who smoke will ship from the u.s.
into Canada so um Canada jumped on it
Mexico is talking about it right now
when Mexico goes legal that's huge um
that's gonna change the game completely
if the feds here haven't made a move on
legalization when Mexico goes they'll
have to yeah absolutely yep yeah that'll
cause okay that'll cause all kinds of
weird probably all kinds of
international rule stuff not really
um there's all kinds of [ __ ] that's
legal in Mexico in Canada today illegal
here like cigars for one thing anyway I
think those may if I heard correctly we
we lifted that I don't know what's
happening there I don't pay enough
attention to that you did give me a good
opportunity for a good segue I want to
throw it out before I forget it we've
talked about the 11 wreck states the 33
medical marijuana States we kind of talk
some trash about those punk-ass states
that haven't caught on yet get it
together boys and girls let's get some
some cannabis friendly happenin in your
states what do you do you know of any
places where would be in your opinion
the worst cannabis laws and they don't
have to be in the United States where
would you not want to be caught with
cannabis there's a bunch of places in
like Asia where government story dude
had
a little bit of a nug like that fell off
his lap he was rolling a joint like
something fell to the end of the joint
and got stuck in his shoe and was doing
time in like Egypt for it or some [ __ ]
at the airport u.s. Texas has always had
particularly horrible marijuana laws
especially in regards to concentrates so
if you're caught with hash they would
charge you as though it was heroin like
went away I have an acquaintance who was
caught with one of these containers in
Texas so this container I'm picking up
system is in container and inside is a
gram container what do you that Abel I'm
gonna turn the mic for the table and
then I'm gonna drop this on the table so
you can hear how much this container
weighs it's a heavy glass that's heavy
yeah that's a lot of weight today blast
joy so when they busted him in Texas you
know what they did they charged in and
for the weight of the container yet so
however much you just heard they hit the
table they think he had that much
concentrate on him when he had less than
a gram because honestly had been
consuming it was probably three-quarters
maybe a half no and this dude by the
time he got to Texas so yeah they've
charged him with that full weight of
that container there was a case that I'm
pretty sure I mentioned it on the on the
show at the time where a dude I bought
two grams of shatter so just two grams
of hash and baked each gram into a tray
of brownies so he had two trays of
brownies they weighed the tray that the
brownies were in and the brownies oh and
then charged this kid in court as though
he had that way worth of heroin and so
this kid was looking at like forty years
in prison for making two trays of
brownies because he used hash to make
them and then they way everything is
they could have they could have charged
him with two grams of marijuana
concentrate right but under Texas law
they get to weigh the [ __ ] brownies
they get to weigh the container the
brownies are in and then they get to
call it heroin at your trial
you had a hard narcotic a Schedule one
narcotic miserable Utah
I hate on like a number of principles so
sorry if you your Utah lever notice I
haven't thrown at any hatred for any
places trying to travel
Utah's marijuana laws have always been
exceptionally harsh so is Oklahoma's I
remember Macaulay Culkin got lost
killing Oklahoma with like a quarter and
they were talking about sin and Macaulay
Culkin to jail for like yes several
years ago they've got a nice medical
program going now on now Oklahoma is
kind of like the new Colorado if you are
trying to start a cannabis business if
you're got something going on if you got
commercial grow experience you're hot in
Oklahoma right now that is a slice to be
yet there are stories from I'm from I've
got some background in the music
industry I don't want to try to sound
like some [ __ ] music guru or
something but I've done some stuff in
the music industry excuse that throat
stuff there I'll fix that I've done some
stuff in the music industry and when you
travel out of the states one of the
things that comes in this little
pamphlet that a lot of the record
companies and touring companies will
give you says that they recommend you
buy new shoes and new clothing before
you travel to places like Dubai and
Egypt and like anywhere in Asia or the
Middle East because they scan you and if
they find they say not to wear they say
to go to the airport in one pair of
shoes and carry another pair of shoes in
the box and never wear them and ditch
those before you get on the plane and
then put on your new or ditch the old
ones as you get on the plane and put on
your new shoes and fly in those and
travel into the country in your new
shoes because they'll scan your shoes
and if you've got if you've walked
through something with drugs on it they
will detect and I'm doing air quotes
there's there's at least one Asian
country where there regularly executing
like beheading yeah like Kuwait well
they basically drug traffickers but it's
anybody caught with more than a tiny
amount of drugs I'm they're doing the
same [ __ ] they used to do here where if
you go by a quarter ounce of weed if
your guy throws you two bags that are
three point five grams each you don't
you didn't just buy a quarter
to law enforcement right you have 7
grams ready for distribution I've got a
gram of pre 98 bubba kush I've got a
gram of gg4 I've got a grandma star
cookies I'm not trying to listen here
I'm just saying that I've got multiple
grams but since I chose to buy multiple
flavors exist it's not all mushed
together in the bottom of the jar or a
baggie it's ready for distribution yep
no sir these are different flavors yeah
it's uh I heard a cop say they think
that all these different plants do
different things to him but I'll just
make some stupid like I've heard the
cops say that and I was like jeez all
right good support officer it's uh the
level of ignorance around cannabis and
why it's so effective on so many
different things it's just astounding
hey we're fixing that we're doing our
part to fix that way little by little
and all that [ __ ] one one episode at
a time it thanks for helping us do that
dude I'm trying man you know what you're
doing your part out there we haven't
given you a shout-out on your social
media would you like people to follow
your face you can check me out on
Twitter at at Nemo Punk 15 or on
Facebook at Pueblo for sensible cannabis
laws there you go give Mike a follow
because he is a cannabis advocate a
spokesperson and a warrior we need to
give him some support so give him some
clicks and follows let him know you
found him on the podcast you it always
it's nice to know where your clicks and
falls are coming from
you haven't been inspired to write much
lately hit me up send me some social
media love and maybe I'll get writing
again trigger him get him going I
started to felt less like arguing and it
kind of felt like I was the dude
clubbing baby seals to death for a
minute the needed the average
intelligence on the Internet is not
impressive so when you go in if you've
done two minutes of research you already
look smarter than 99.9% percent of the
people in opposition of your idea and
it's mostly an echo chamber so if you go
in and you break up the echo chamber you
already look like you're [ __ ] some
sort of elite something already I it
there's the anti pot rats [ __ ] bad at
everything and when I the first three
paragraphs my response are correcting
words they've used majorly incorrectly
and it's like no you didn't mean school
bus dude you meant sneakers oh man well
there are only six states left so
it just feels like to watch him down
when you got to start off like that so I
took a little break I've slowed down on
my social media and my social media
trolling and it does make a difference
in your life guys put down the computer
and that's coming from a guy who is
constantly yeah but we're running a show
here this one's got show notes bro that
one's for you so that you know where the
hell work going this one's making the
show happen so without these man it's
it's dark yeah I'm gonna use that word
more often hey Mike thanks for joining
us let's start wrapping up this podcast
I think we should it feels like the
right time to do that it does it does it
feels good make sure your installations
Illinois before we uh yeah before we
move to the the outro big shout out to
governor hard to say and all of our
friends out there in Illinois yeah I
could google his name for a minute but
it's got some weird letters mashed
together in the front and I'm bad at
that I bet only the people from Illinois
care what his name is
and yeah that's 80% of them are going
yeah hard to say it's good enough for us
governor hard to say but we really
appreciate the marijuana legalization
effort this month there this year
Illinois's we needed that way and so
good on you yes yes good on you yeah I
look forward to seeing everybody at the
dude grows
710 concentration celebration on 713 at
cultivated synergy it'll be an
educational event we will talk a lot
about concentrations it'll be a good
time the dude grows crew will be there
the dude probably will not be there he's
got another event I think it's his
wife's birthday so he's got to attended
back but Scottie real will be there guru
will be there I myself will be there I
am also bringing my side piece Deb and
granny will be there she's also bringing
grumpy grandpa they will be there they
will be hanging out at the eye region
etics booth make sure you come by the
booth say hi come check out some of the
new packaging on some of the I read
genetics gear grab it before it's gone I
look forward to seeing you there I would
also appreciate it if you support the
show on patreon if you feel like this
podcast was educational informative
and/or entertaining and you'd like to
support the show financially you can do
so by going to patreon.com slash grow
from your heart all the information you
need to become a patron will be right
there on the screen once again big shout
out to everybody who supports the show I
would also appreciate it if you stock me
on all of the social media on Facebook
simply search for the girl from your
heart pod
asked on Twitter its @gf wih podcast and
of course make sure you give me a follow
on cannabis cannabis as a new cannabis
friendly social media application they
will not delete your cannabis related
posts you can post your cannabis
pictures there you can go talk about
cannabis you could do your fancy dab
videos and make your duck face there
come hang out on cannabis it is a free
cannabis friendly social media
application I want to see I want to see
what did I say it like that I want to
see you there on cannabis also follow my
youtube channel I talk about that way
too much grow from your heart on YouTube
give it a search give it a follow leave
comments I like that and if you were not
into all of that social media nonsense
and you would like to reach out maybe
you've got a question maybe you've got
something you'd like to say maybe you've
got a correction to make maybe you like
to sponsor the podcast perhaps you've
got a product you like Mike and I to
review you can send me an old-fashioned
email my email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com you know that I
would love to hear from you might
remember when old fashioned meant you
wrote a letter and folded it up and put
in an envelope and put a stamp on it I
just said old-fashioned email yeah so he
told me my gray hair looks like I paid
someone to highlight it that way and it
was the complement of last week so it's
a little grayer every episode but it's a
little grayer every episode kids man
that both of them alright ladies and
gentlemen own him think Mike once again
for coming and hanging out for a good
podcast this is a great show buddy yeah
good to be back I want to thank
everybody for listening to another
episode of the girl from your heart
podcast I'll be back Monday with fresh
new content I want to give a huge shout
out to Deb and granny and it's all next
time
take a phat dab and give your mom a hug
for me