hey welcome back everyone it is time for
episode 441 of the Grove from your heart
podcast this episode of the show is
brought to you by our friends at the
hell a dank seed company if you need new
seeds in your garden I highly recommend
the hella dank seed company and you can
find them at dank seed dot store it has
become a tradition that we start this
podcast off by talking about what I'm
smoking today I've been taking dad's of
Blue lemon ty ambrosia from our friends
at apothecary farms the package says
this product contains 67.7% THC and
78.5% total cannabinoids I really love
the flavor and aroma of the blue lemon
ty ambrosia it's got that blue lemon
flavor I know that sounds ridiculous but
if I broke it open and gave you a smell
you would absolutely agree that that
smells like blue lemons so big shout out
to our friends at apothecary farms for
the delicious and extremely potent blue
lemon ty ambrosia in this episode of the
podcast I would like to introduce you to
a new strain called orange gasm but
before we get there let's do some
shoutouts to some friends on patreon I'm
gonna give a huge grow from your heart
podcast shout out to my buddy Jacob W a
giant podcast shout out to stabby mixed
a person as always a giant Viking
handshake to my friend Grimbold a druid
Oh a big giant shoutout to my friend
Justin and of course a big grill from
your heart podcast shout out to my
friend Eric Ross once again big shout
out and big thanks to everybody who
supports the show on patreon if you
would like to learn how to become a
patron you can do so by going to
www.petland.com
slash grow from your heart all of the
information you need to become a patron
will be right there on the screen
all right podcast world at the start of
the show I said I was going to introduce
you to a new strain let's talk about one
of my newest creations let's talk about
orange gasm orange gasm is a cross of
platinum tangi from our friends at the
garden of Weeden pollinated by a
reversed golden goat so I took a female
golden goat plant I treated it with a
solution that solution caused that plant
to create pollen sacks those pollen
sacks contained pollen which only
contain female chromosomes I applied
that female pollen on to the platinum
tangi plant and we have made or
Yasim feminized seeds my goal when I was
creating orange gasm was to create a
really orange and tangerine flavoured
feminized seed lion I really think I
nailed it
what I got was that sweet orange
tangerine creamsicle sort of a flavor I
brought that Platinum tangi flowering
time and platinum tangi growth pattern
and structure into the cross and then it
also added that golden goat potency a
little bit of sweetness and some of the
phenotypes even bring out a grapefruit
sort of flavor and aroma which comes
from the golden goat side of things so
my main goal was to create a feminized
seed they carried that delicious orange
Terp flavor it looks like in the process
I created a great structured plant that
has a great flavor and tremendous
potency so let's talk more about the
orange gasm let's start by talking about
the parents of orange gasm orange gasm
is a cross of the Platinum tangi and
golden go platinum tangi is of course a
tangi male named Julius Julius was
selected by our friends at the garden of
Weeden big shout out to Maddy and Spence
so they used Julius to pollinate a
Platinum cookies female so they had the
Platinum Girl Scout cookies pollinated
by Julius that made platinum tangi
platinum tangi has a delicious greasy
orange smell with a hint of that girl
scout cookies background there's
something funky there's something
slightly spicy there's something dirty
to it so it's like a greasy funky orange
with a hint of armpits maybe a little
bit of skunk going on I really
appreciate the platinum tangi it grows
beautifully it's got the greatest growth
structure that's one of my favorite
things about it the way that it grows as
a grower as a commercial grower platinum
tangi always did a great job in the
production rooms it always helped me get
bonuses and the flavors and aromas are
unbeatable it makes amazing concentrates
so then I paired that up with the golden
go let's talk about golden go for a
moment golden goat is a Hawaiian Romulan
mail that pollinated an island sweet
skunk female so we've got a lot of great
genetics in there I see that Island
sweet skunk come out a lot in the orange
gasm phenotypes that is what will bring
out that pink grapefruit sort of aroma
that comes from the island sweet skunk
golden goat was bred by a guy who's
known as mr. dank and he is from Topeka
Kansas
I've done a full Episode on golden goat
so if you would like to learn a lot
about golden goat I suggest checking out
episode 418 of the growth from your
heart podcast that entire episode is
heavily focused on golden goat golden
goat brings a really delightful tropical
smell it has some citrus to it it has
hints of pineapple to it it has a
beautiful growth structure golden goat
always puts out huge harvest and also I
love the potency of golden goat I have
seen golden don't reach impressive lab
test numbers but also sometimes I have
smoked a golden goat that didn't show
impressive lab tests but it blew me away
when I smoked it so there's something
special about that golden goat I have
always been a big fan of golden goat
I've obviously fallen in love with it
because you see it in a lot of my
breeding so I used a female golden goat
clone it was treated with the solution
which made it create pollen sacks which
only contained female pollen I applied
that female pollen to the platinum tangi
we have now got the orange gasm seeds
let's talk more specifically about the
orange Gaza as a consumer the first
thing you are going to notice about
orange gasm is the insanely intense
pungent orange aroma it is orange II it
is tangerines there are hints of
grapefruit it almost smells like
somebody sprayed orange ozium in the
room or directly into your face it's
like you were in a small compact car and
somebody has got that orange ozium and
they just won't keep spraying it it
smells like you cleaned the entire world
with citrus cleaner it carries a
tremendous orange smell it also kind of
smells like tang powder if you used to
make Tang back in the day it's got that
strong overpowering fake orange flavor
in some phenotypes also some phenotypes
will have a really sweet smooth
creamsicle sort of aroma and flavor I
really like the array of tangerine and
sweet orange flavors that come from the
orange Gaza one of the best things about
orange gasm is the concentrates if you
were a concentrate maker of any type you
will find a beautiful phenotype of
orange gasm for your concentrate
production there's a phenotype it works
beautifully for ice water extraction
there is a phenotype that works
beautifully to be pressed and almost any
of the phenotype
we'll make wonderful pho extraction all
of them are going to smell like
disgusting delicious potent pungent
sweet oranges I can't talk enough about
the orange flavor that comes from orange
gasm you guys I'm gonna say oranges in
this episode 3,000 times because that is
the only thing I can think of
when I smell these flowers so now we
know that it tastes and smells like
oranges I've said that enough let's talk
about growing orange gasm orange gasm is
very easy to grow it has a very nice
growth structure and shape one good
thing about the orange gasm in
comparison to most of the crosses i make
is it does not get ridiculously tall it
will get tall but it will not be a
gigantic stretchy plant like most of my
other crosses so this one stays a little
bit shorter it takes on a very nice
Christmas tree type of a shape but then
it creates what I call a menorah it
makes a lot of even length branches you
don't have one big tall top glory bud
you get a nice even canopy out of the
orange gasm I really enjoy that it makes
it great for sea of green type of
growing it makes it great for large
commercial production and it is a
wonderful plant for outdoor growing so I
really love the structure and the shape
it also it is really stout it makes
thick stalks and branches I like to do a
lot of popping and twisting and super
cropping and this one really takes it
well because the branches start off very
thick and very stout if you're growing
in windy conditions or if you need to
put some plants at the end of a row
where a fan kind of beats them up a
little bit orange gasm may be a perfect
candidate for that type of environment
the stalks are so big the branches are
so stout that I don't worry about the
wind whipping the [ __ ] out of this plant
and if it does whip the [ __ ] out of it
if it does get beat up a little bit
orange gasm can take a lot of abuse she
is a very Hardy plant the platinum tangi
that I used is a very Hardy plant we
have beat the [ __ ] out of it in many
different ways in commercial
environments and it never shows me any
stress it's always just like hey I'm
over here growing I'm doing exactly what
she need me to do and then golden goat
is the same it is very vigorous it has a
lot of energy so crossing these two
created a very energetic plant so it
grows quite quickly in veg and in flower
you'll see a lot of growth it'll get
very robust fat
stocks you may want to transplant more
early than you were used to if you were
growing the orange Gaza it does like I
said before it likes being popped and
twisted and it enjoys being topped
however you may not need to top it too
much because it does grow that menorah
type of a shape or it's got a bunch of
arms that all reach up to the same level
it may get one kind of one dominant bud
but it's not gonna get a big giant glory
Cola
in many phenotypes the golden goat
dominate phenotype will show you that
glory Cola but more of your platinum
tangi dominate phenotypes aren't going
to have that giant stretch on the top
but that perfect growth structure makes
orange gasm really easy to trellis if
you're going to throw her in a large
commercial facility or if you're going
to put her in a tent she likes to be
worked into a net a lot of times people
like to really work the branches into
the net and spread them out
orange gasm doesn't need a lot of help
to spread it kind of spreads wide on its
own what you will need is a little bit
of support both of these parents are
heavy producers so the offspring are
obviously going to be large producing
plants you're going to get big buds
throughout the entire grow room so be
ready have some supports have some
tomato cages have some sort of
trellising going on but these plants
really do appreciate some trellising and
some scrubbing and some sort of supports
they also take very well to defoliating
the Platinum tangi dominant phenotypes
won't require heavy defoliation but the
golden goat phenotypes will take very
well to semi heavy defoliation that
brings us to another good point the
calyx to leaf ratio many phenotypes of
the orange gasm are not very leafy a lot
of them will have a very long PDL with a
very big fan leaf coming off of it and
not a lot of small leaves that is known
as a good calyx to leaf ratio that makes
it easy to trim it makes it easy to
defoliate and while the plant is growing
that gives less opportunity and
potential for pests and mildew there are
less places for bugs to hide and less
places for powdery mildew to cling on so
it gives us less potential for problems
that does make orange gasm a great
strain for beginners if you were a new
grower I highly recommend orange gasm
the Platinum tangi is really easy to
grow the golden goat is very easy to
grow
and the orange gasm is even simpler to
grow in my opinion orange gasm is only
available in female seeds so that saves
one more step you don't have to search
out the males making it even easier for
beginner growers orange gasm is also a
great strain for outdoor growers in some
locations some phenotypes of orange gasm
will finish as early as 56 to 60 days
some phenotypes will take as long as 70
days if you've got one of those earlier
finishing phenotypes they do beautifully
outside they don't have a lot of
problems because of that wonderful calyx
to leaf ratio and I've noticed that the
orange gasm does very well in high heat
conditions so if you're growing in a hot
outdoor environment orange gasm will do
very well for you it tolerates high heat
another great thing about the orange
gasm as it takes errors very well if you
make a mistake
orange gasm is not going to show you
immediately that it is completely pissed
off if you were growing some Sour Diesel
type stuff if you're growing an OG Kush
plant and you mess up with one feeding
you were going to pay for that in the
end your harvest will not be what you
expected the quality may not be what you
expected when you were growing orange
gasm you have a lot of room for mistakes
she is a very forgiving plant now that
is a good way to segue into talking
about feeding orange gasm she is very
easy to feed and get dialed in she likes
a lot of nutrients she will go macro
nutrient deficient early in flower if
you don't boost up the NPK most of our
cannabis plants do absorb 90% of their
nitrogen through their veg phase make
sure you do not let these plants get
nitrogen deficient you will not catch up
so the main thing to look for when you
were growing orange gasm is to watch for
nutrient deficiencies or nutrient burns
and get that dialed in the thinner
leaved golden goat phenotypes are going
to show you that they are experiencing
nutrient burn before you see it pop up
and the larger leaved
platinum tangi dominant phenotypes so
pay attention to that skinny leaf and if
you see it starting to get its nails
done you can tell that you're probably
giving it a little bit too much nutrient
if that skinny leaf phenotype is
starting to get a little bit pale it
probably needs more
nutrients pay attention to the skinny
leaved phenotypes they are going to give
you hints before the larger leaved
phenotypes I've mentioned it briefly
before but most phenotypes of orange
gasm are going to flower from somewhere
between 60 and 70 days some of them may
finish earlier some of them may finish
closer to the 56 day mark I would rather
not set that expectation I would rather
say 60 to 70 days to be honest with you
you may get some outliers that go 2 to 4
days longer each direction but you can
generally rely on that 60 to 70 day time
line it may be easier to tell early and
flower with the orange gasm which
phenotypes will go longer because of the
two parents I used the skinnier leaved
phenotypes are going to take closer to
70 days that is a golden goat dominant
phenotype it is more sativa dominant
that will need to go a little bit longer
the wider platinum tangi dominant leaves
that phenotype will probably finish
closer to the 60-day mark so pay
attention to the leaf size the leaf
shape that will indicate to you how long
to go the first time you run these I
suggest going 70 full days and flower if
you've got the opportunity now that
feels like a good way to segue into
talking about expected phenotypes I have
seen several different phenotypes pop up
from the orange gasm most of them very
closely resemble the Platinum tangi and
the golden goat but I do feel like I
have seen some Island sweet skunk
dominant phenotypes pop up in the mix
some of the common phenotypes you can
expect to see are the golden goat
dominant phenotype this one grows very
much like golden goat it has got very
long skinny and pointy leaves and it
makes very pine cone shaped top buds
it's got a very tropical kind of a
pineapple II and citrus sort of aroma to
it sometimes that one will bring out a
little bit of a grapefruit smell that
does come from the island sweet skunk
which we'll talk about in a minute there
is another phenotype that obviously is
platinum tangi dominant that is the one
with big wide fat leaves
sometimes the platinum tangi dominant
phenotype will produce purple stems it
does not make a lot of purple leaf and
purple by
but it will make purple stems that is a
great way to see the Platinum tangi
dominant phenotype early in your growth
a really great phenotype that you are
going to find in packs of orange gasm is
a phenotype that I have named the mean
girl or the jagged girl a long time ago
I made another cross called heart of
gold
and it had a phenotype that I called the
mean girl it was another golden go
across I see this same trait coming up
in the orange Gazza some of these
phenotypes produce a bud that just looks
mean the buds are really jagged the
leaves are really serrated it's got a
really tight structure to it and it just
looks like it would be really mean or it
looks like it could be weaponized I just
call it the mean girl phenotype it looks
like it's probably got a switchblade
that phenotype grows a little bit more
like the golden goat but it carries that
delicious sweet platinum tangi aroma so
I really love the mean girl phenotype it
is a little bit airier
the buds aren't as tight and compact and
dense as some of the platinum tangi
dominant phenotypes but if you've
listened to the podcast for a while I'm
sure you've heard me say that I think
Airy buds are going to be the future for
concentrate production I feel like you
have more surface area for trichomes I
feel like it's a little bit easier to
extract something off of a fluffier area
bud than it is a tighter more dense bud
so I feel like this one is great for
concentrate production sometimes you
will see that the mean girl phenotype
creates what I call a taco leaf the leaf
will curl up kind of looks like a canoe
kind of looks like a taco shell it is
folds in half a lot of times people will
think that that is a result of excessive
heat sometimes that is the issue but
that is just a common trait that you
will see happen in the mean girl
phenotype of orange gasm that phenotype
is going to extract very well that
phenotype is going to have one of the
most intense orange flavors and aromas
that I have ever bred so that is the
mean girl phenotype that is probably the
one I would look for if you're making
concentrates if you are going for
potency you may go for more of the
golden goat dominant leaning phenotypes
if you're going for that orange flavor
of course go for those wider leave
platinum tangi dominant phenotypes
now there is one phenotype that I call
the outlier
she is ugly it is really tall it is
really thin it's a little bit wispy it's
kind of stretchy she produces fairly
well but not as well as the other
phenotypes but what she does do is she
is encrusted in trichomes there is no
room for more resin on those tiny buds
and when you dry it and cure it and
smoke it the flavor is like disgusting
sour tart grapefruit and it is so
pungent and weird then it made my mouth
pucker just thinking about it right now
if you were into pink grapefruit or pink
lemonade and grapefruit sort of aromas
that phenotype may be the one for you I
feel like that phenotype came from the
island sweet skunk parent from the
golden goat so we are seeing things way
down the line pop out in this cross when
this phenotype pops up if you've paid
attention you won't know it it is
immediately the tallest phenotype it is
the one with the branches that are
trying to all keep up with each other
and they are all stretching in
competition a lot of people may want to
call this phenotype immediately if you
were into grapefruits this is the one
for you it will produce okay but the
potency and the flavors are going to be
off the charts so if you're growing just
for yourself and you're into that sweet
grapefruit sort of a flavor I really
hope that you are the one defines this
semi rare ugly phenotype of the orange
gasm now let's talk about the one that
everybody is going to want I call it the
50/50 as probably obvious why I call it
that it is 50% golden goat and it is 50%
platinum tangi and we got the best half
of each one for this phenotype it
carries a tremendous sweet orange flavor
it has got that perfect the golden goat
stretch but then it's also got that
platinum tangi menorah shape and then it
carries the potency of the golden goat
that phenotype tends to finish up right
around 63 days if you were growing this
strain in a commercial facility that is
the phenotype that you want that is
perfect it puts out great weight it puts
out great flavors and aromas and the bag
appeal on the finished dried and cured
buds is beautiful the buds are bright
green the pistils dry up and they stay
bright orange and it creates great bag
appeal so that 50/50 phenotype is per
if you were growing for commercial
production all right another thing I
should mention about the orange gasm is
temperature many growers like to lower
the temperature of their flowering room
lay in flower to bring out the colors of
their flowers this is not necessary with
orange gasm I have not seen any benefits
to reducing the temperatures of the grow
room late in flower when growing orange
gasm orange gasm seems to prefer higher
temperatures and I have not seen any
advantage to reducing the temperature
late in flower I have not seen any
improved color I haven't seen any
speed-up in flowering time I really
think that it is best just to leave the
room just like it is and continue
flowering until the end with orange gasm
don't make it cooler don't reduce the
lights don't do any tricks just keep it
just like it is it tends to like it
fairly warm so keep it warm all the way
through flower don't worry about
reducing the temps don't try to get it
cold late in the cycle that is not
necessary now that may be really
advantageous for people who are growing
large facilities or running perpetual
cycles sometimes you might want to
reduce the temperature in your grow room
so that you can get that one strain to
finish earlier sometimes reducing the
temperature late and flower will bring
out some great colors sometimes it makes
the plants dance up a little bit I have
noticed that that does not work for the
orange gasm she likes it warm all the
way through all right so I think that
covers all of the grow details of orange
gasm let's talk a little bit about
smoking orange gasm orange gasm is a
delight to smoke of course because those
tremendous orange and tangerine and
sweet candied orange flavors but what I
really like about it is the really good
mood and great vibe that I get from
smoking orange gasm it doesn't
completely obliterate my brain to where
I can't think and can't focus but it
does put me in a really good mood it
just puts a smile on your face if you're
having a rough morning if you've had a
shitty day smoke a little orange gasm
you will be smiling I call it the Oh
face you'll smoke a little and you go oh
you just blow out your smoke your mouth
tastes like oranges and your stress goes
away your shoulders relax you feel
better
another thing that I have noticed is
that it works great for people with
anxiety if you are experiencing anxiety
or if you want to keep the anxiety away
smoking the orange gasm will chill you
the [ __ ] out it let's see in a good mood
it makes you forget that you are anxious
it makes you forget that you were
worried about something and it just puts
a little pep in your step and puts you
in a good vibe
I really think orange gasm would make
great morning medicine if you're a
person who likes to medicate in the
morning but you still want to be able to
function you don't want your brain to
get too blown away you don't want to get
too lazy but you want to put a little
pep in your step and lively if the vibe
that is where orange gasm fits in
perfectly alright podcasts world that is
all of the information I have got for
you on orange gasm if you have any more
questions I do encourage you to ask me
my email address is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com don't be shy I look
forward to hearing from you if you are
interested in acquiring orange gasm
seeds they will be available on 710 at
seeds here now dot-com they will be
available at dank seed dot store and he
will also be able to find them at Oregon
elite seeds dot-com if you're not into
shopping on the internet I will be at
the dude grows concentration celebration
on July 13th that cultivated synergy in
Denver Colorado and I will have orange
gasm lemon Jeffrey and golden goat
feminized seeds on-hand and available
for my friends for more information on
the dude grows concentration celebration
check out dude grows calm there's a 710
cup tab right on the page all the
information you need will be right there
so don't miss the 710 drop at seeds here
now organ elite seeds and the hell a
dank seed company and if you're able to
make it to Denver for 713 I look forward
to meeting you and shaking your hand at
the dude grows concentration celebration
ladies and gentlemen that is all I've
got for this episode I want to thank you
for hanging out and learning all about
my new strain orange gasm I look forward
to seeing your pictures I look forward
to hearing your reviews I cannot wait to
get this new strain in your hands if you
feel like this podcast was educational
informative or entertaining and you'd
like to make a financial contribution to
the show you can do so by visiting
patreon.com slash growth from your heart
all of the information you need will be
right there on the screen I would also
appreciate it if you support me on
social media you can find the show on
Facebook simply search for the growth
from your heart podcast
Twitter the show is at G fyh podcast my
personal Twitter account is a trusted
Jeff 420 I would love it if you'd give
me a follow also give me a follow on
cannabis cannabis is a new cannabis
friendly social media application other
social media platforms like to censor
and delete our posts we are not able to
post cannabis related content freely on
many other social media applications but
cannabis encourages and promotes your
cannabis post so come join us on
cannabis post your cannabis pictures if
you've got a plant that has given you
problems snap a picture post the picture
to cannabis and say what's wrong with my
plant folks like myself and other
experienced growers will chime in and
give you helpful advice and we will help
correct the issues you are having with
your plants so join us on cannabis I
look forward to seeing you over there it
is a free application it is available on
your iPhone and it is available on your
Android device so join us on cannabis if
you've got something you'd like to say
perhaps you've got a product you'd like
me to review maybe you'd like to sponsor
the podcast maybe you've just got a grow
question if you're not into all that
social media nonsense you can send me an
email my email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com and I do look
forward to hearing from you if you have
sent me an email and I haven't gotten to
it yet please do not feel discouraged
I've got a mountain of emails in front
of me I can only get through so many in
so many episodes but your email is
coming up just be patient
do not get discouraged I will get your
advice to you very soon ladies and
gentlemen that is all I've got for you
for this episode don't forget to check
out that new drop on 710 I look forward
to seeing all of my friends at the dude
grows concentration celebration on 7:13
and I think that is all I've got for you
for this episode ladies and gentlemen
I'll be back in just a few days with
fresh new content I want to give you a
huge shout out to my friend AZ Cushman
and until next time take a phat dad and
give your mom a hug for me