hey welcome to the show ganja smokers
and ganja growers it it's time for
episode 442 of the Grove from your heart
podcast this episode of the show is
brought to you by my friends at seeds
here now if you need new seeds in your
garden I highly recommend seeds here now
and you can find them at www.ctvn.org
batter from apothecary farms the label
says this product contains 68.4% THC and
79.9% total cannabinoids i've been
scooping up big chunks of the star dog
batter and then i'm dunking that in the
leftover turps from a jar of gg4
ambrosia
I bought a big jar of the gg4 it had a
lot of saucy turps in the bottom of it
so I am using the star dog batter as a
sponge to soak up the gg4 turps
and these dabs are delicious and
tremendous I'm always a fan of star dog
I am always a fan of the gg4 and when
you mix the two it is really delicious I
want to call this some guerrilla dog or
something like that this is a great
combination so big shout out to my
friends at apothecary Farms for the
delicious concentrates all right podcast
world I am recording on the 3rd of July
we are going to talk briefly about the
4th of July
then we're going to talk more about 7:10
before we get there
let's do a few shot outs to some of our
friends on patreon I want to give a huge
grow from your heart podcast shout out
to my friend Jacob W I wanna give a
giant shout out to Keith Kay of course a
giant grow from your heart podcast shout
out to Tommy Debbie you of course a girl
from your heart podcast shout out and
fist bump to Bret G as always a giant
fist bump to my friend dick goals how
about a big shout out to Stephen F and
as always a giant grow from your heart
podcast shout out to our friend BAFTA
I want to send a big thank-you shout out
to everybody who supports the show on
patreon if you would like to learn how
to become a patron you can do so by
going to patreon.com slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
all right podcast world I said we were
going to talk briefly about the 4th of
July if you hear a bunch of noise
outside a bunch of explosions in the
background of this recording that is
because
I am recording at the start of July and
where I live we'd like to get started a
little bit early everybody is blowing
[ __ ] up
everybody's had their fireworks going
since about the 1st of July in my
neighborhood the Sun just went down
about an hour ago so they are really
getting going it is going to be a party
in my neighborhood so if you hear some
noise please excuse that we're just
having a good time I hope everybody out
there has a safe and joyous 4th of July
be careful you guys don't get yourselves
blown up don't get yourselves in any
trouble don't get a DUI be safe out
there and if you do throw a barbecue
don't forget about your vegetarian
friends have something available for
those folks who don't want to eat a
burger don't make fun of us invite us
over we want to have a good time too
that's all I've got for the 4th of July
let's segue into talking about 7:10 7:10
is the next big holiday we are going to
celebrate what is 7:10 some people may
not be up to speed on what 7:10 is as my
buddy Adam Hill puts it 7:10 is the new
for 27:10 upside down says oil so if you
right 7:10 flip it upside down that says
oil my friend task rock wanted something
new everybody's been talking about 420
for a long time tasks needed something
to help represent the oil movement so
him and a few other folks coined the
phrase 7:10 and the 7:10 movement became
the new concentrate movement 7:10 is
when you're supposed to take a fat dab
7/10 represents the oil movement so
that's where a 7/10 came from
that's what 7:10 is all about that's
where the 7:10 culture erupted from so
7:10 is all about smoking oil smoking
concentrates taking a DAB however you
want to do it it has evolved so far
since those days I remember just a few
years ago we would get concentrate that
we thought was the most amazing [ __ ] on
the planet we would smoke it we would be
completely impressed it started off as
this kind of dark colored kind of look
like glass it kind of look like candy we
called it shatter it started off like
that then it got a little better then
people started making it more clear it
started getting more shattering you got
a little tastier we started learning
more it got better then people started
making live resin we started seeing a
whole bunch of new consistencies a bunch
of new textures then a lot of us started
think it ourselves because something we
were smoking six months ago we would not
even touch at this new point in time and
it seems like the concentrate world
keeps evolving it seems like about every
six months there's a brand new tech or a
brand new product out that blows the
concentrate market away and then I laugh
because I'm thinking weren't we smoking
the best [ __ ] on the planet just six
months ago and now we have vastly
improved that to where the things I was
smoking in 2010 I probably would just
pass and laugh at now I would not even
consume that so we went from that
shatter II stuff and we had live resin
and people started making better
consistencies of live resin and then we
started seeing sauce and Terps come out
and then we started seeing big crystals
and now you can go to the dispensary and
you can get just about any consistency
you want on my table
I don't really [ __ ] with shatter no
offense to the people that still smoke
shatter
I don't smoke shatter anymore I've moved
forward from that no offense if that's
still what you're doing be in your time
do what you're doing but we went from
you can have shatter I've got some
batter here on the table that kind of
looks like cheesecake batter I have got
some HC FSE who just looks like diamonds
and little rocks I've got some turps
that is just saucy it looks like golden
water I've got some ambrosia it kind of
looks like a like a glass of tea with
ice cubes in it it's so beautiful
I have got some we've got all kinds of
different textures and consistencies we
have come so far in this oil industry
since we started this movement and now
people are learning how to squish buds
and they're making rosin I've seen
people making diamonds solid diamonds
out of rosin that they're making at home
so the 710 movement has come a long way
I really give a lot of credit of the
coining of the phrase 7 10 to my buddy
task rock from highly-educated titanium
also now highly-educated quartz they
make great gavels and bangers so make
sure you check them out but it has come
a long way so when we talk about 7/10 we
are generally talking about dabbing
we're talking about oil we're talking
about the concentrate movement that sort
of spawned from the cannabis revolution
there is the cannabis crowd but then the
dab crowd is a completely different
level and you can spot the dab crowd
when you go to the cannabis events so I
feel like that is a great way to segue
into talking about 7
events what is coming up four seven ten
what are you doing for the 710 holiday
710 falls in the middle of the week this
year so there will be events on the
weekend before and the weekend after 710
and that also means that when 710
happens in the middle of the week
wherever you are whatever you're doing
it is time to get yourself a big fat dab
and join the world and take a DAB at 710
for the 710 movement I will be spending
the weekend before 710 getting ready for
an event the weekend after 7:10 I will
be at the dude grows concentration
celebration it cultivated synergy
cultivated synergy is in Denver Colorado
and the Rhino district and that is on
the Saturday night after 7:10 so if you
can be there I look forward to seeing
you at the dude grows concentration
celebration for tickets and information
on that event I would recommend you
visit dude gross dot-com there's a 710
cup tab right on the front of their
website click right there all the
information you need for the event
should be easily accessible so I look
forward to seeing you at the dude grows
concentration celebration I will be
there with my brand-new booth set up I
will also have dab and Granny at my
booth come say hi take a DAB get a hug
from dad and granny get a hug from
myself take some photos I will also have
a very limited supply of the brand-new
eye region etics drop so stop by the
booth and say hi I look forward to
seeing you at the event I am also doing
a special drop for 7:10 on 710 I will be
releasing three feminized seed lines
through my vendors the things that will
be available on 710 are golden goat
feminized seeds orange gasm feminized
seeds and the return of lemon Jeffrey
feminized seeds those will all be
available on 710 at seeds here now.com
it will be available at dank seed dot
store and you will be able to find them
at oregon elite seeds dot-com so check
those three websites make sure you grab
them before they run out also I will
have very limited supplies of these new
lines at the dude grows concentration
celebration so if you're able to attend
the event
by the booth and grab some before they
run out the golden goat is a golden goat
s1 that is a female golden goat
pollinated by a reversed golden NGO
female that made pollen so that is a
golden goat feminized seed the orange
gasm is a platinum tangi female
pollinated by the reversed golden goat
and the lemon jeffery is a lemon skunk
all three of those have been quite
sought-after and they all three make
amazing concentrates so make sure you
catch these before they are gone the
feminized seeds will also be available
at org antica in new mexico so if you
are a New Mexico medical marijuana
patient org antica and Albuquerque will
have the feminized seeds on 710 that is
only available to New Mexico medical
marijuana patients you have to have all
of your New Mexico medical marijuana
paperwork up to work and valid and you
have to have your ID if you've got all
the proper paperwork stop by Oregon
teeka grab yourself some feminized seeds
tell them Rasta Jeff sent you if you
would like email updates about where my
seeds are available if you like email
updates about sales I'm having or events
I may be attending or perhaps maybe I
will send out coupon codes when I'm
dropping fresh strains you can get
inside information by joining my mailing
list if you would like to join the
mailing list simply send an email to
Irie genetics
mailing list at gmail.com and that will
instantly add you to the mailing list
that way I can keep you updated if I add
a new vendor if I put something on sale
if I drop a new strain or if I put out a
coupon code for the new feminized seeds
that are coming out so join the mailing
list that way I can keep in touch and
keep everybody updated on all the great
new stuff that is happening in the world
of ira genetics all right podcast world
i'm going to wrap up this 4th of july
episode thanks for hanging out for a
short episode i know it was short and
sweet it is a holiday put down your
phone put down your ipad get off the
computer go out there hang out with some
people join the barbecue go blow some
[ __ ] up and enjoy a holiday ladies and
gentlemen I'll be back Monday with fresh
new content and a full-length episode I
want to thank you again for listening to
this quickie episode I want to give a
huge shout out to Benny's in the veg and
until next time take a phat dab and give
your mom a hug
me