hey what's up podcast world it is time
for episode 443 of the growth from your
heart podcast this episode of the show
is brought to you by my friends at seeds
here now if you need new seeds in your
garden I highly recommend seeds here now
and you can find them at
www.cdxzipstream.com farms for the
delicious
gg4 ambrosia ladies and gentlemen boys
and girls smokers and growers in this
episode I am going to talk about some of
the mistakes I have made in a grow room
but before we get there I'd like to give
a shout out to a few of our friends from
patreon let's start off at the big shout
out to my friend miss Mel how about a
giant grow from your heart podcast
shoutout to jacob w i want to give a big
grow from your heart fist bump to tommy
w also a big girl from your heart a
shout-out to Tyler I owe a big shout out
to Paul T how about a shout out to Mike
F how about a big giant shout out to
canna you dig it and how about a big
giant grow from your heart podcast shout
out to my buddy
farmer John big shout out to all my
friends and thank you for all the
continued patreon support if you would
like to learn how to become a patron you
can do so by going to www.petland.com
slash grow from your heart all of the
information you need to support the show
will be right there on the screen once
again big shout out and big thank you to
everybody who has helped the show in the
past in the present and in the future
all right podcast world I said that in
this episode we were going to talk about
some of the biggest mistakes that I have
made in a grow room before we get there
I would like to ask you for your email
submissions what are some of the biggest
mistakes or what is the biggest mistake
you have made in your grow
don't be shy I would love to hear from
you send me an email my email address is
grow from your heart at hotmail.com
let's talk about some of the biggest
mistakes you have made in your grow room
I think by sharing our mistakes we will
do a couple of things first we will
humble ourselves we will remind
ourselves that we are human and we do
[ __ ] no matter how much you practice
no matter how good you think you are no
matter how prepared you are sometimes
[ __ ] goes wrong and we do make mistakes
I also feel like me coming on here and
talking about some of the major mistakes
I've made
as a beginner grower as an experienced
grower and I've even made mistakes in
giant commercial facilities I feel like
coming on here and talking about my
mistakes and admitting those mistakes
will build a better bond between you and
I it will give you a better trust with
me it will say hey that guy was a noob
Mac I made mistakes and it will show you
that even though you were making
mistakes as a newer grower you still do
have the potential to become a great
grower you do have the potential to
become a commercial level grower so this
episode will build a better bond between
us this episode will help us build
confidence and this episode will also
humble many growers so let's talk about
some of the mistakes I have made in a
grow environment when I first started
growing I was really into using grow
tents it was a great setup for my
environment it was better than modifying
the house in which I lived so I started
with grow tents I started with one tent
then I expanded to two before you knew
it I had a tent with mother plants I had
a tent for vegging then I had two tents
for a perpetual flowering cycle most of
the time I did very well taking care of
my tents but those tents led to one of
my biggest mistakes I am not blaming the
grow tent in any way this was all my
fault let me tell you a little bit about
what happened all of my grow tents were
in one big room I liked starting the day
by opening all of the tents then I would
let the air from the fans blow around
the entire room and they would all get a
lot of airflow I felt like the plants
were really happy they were getting a
lot of fresh air there was no stagnant
air the humidity was just right the
temperature was just right in that
entire room my normal routine for that
room was to open all of the tents water
all of the plants leave the tents open
throughout the day so that they could
have a lot of nice airflow and
just before the plants went off for the
night I would go in the room and I would
seal up all of the tents that way my
flowering plants wouldn't get any light
in and by sealing the other tents I
would make sure that the light wouldn't
get out and do another preventive
measure to make sure my flowering plants
don't receive any light during their
night cycle most of the time that plan
worked perfectly
I had an alarm set if the plants were to
turn off at nine o'clock I would set an
alarm for 8:30 so that I could go to the
gross space I could make sure nothing's
wrong if anything needed water I could
water if anything needed adjustments I
could adjust it if any equipment was
failing I could see that it was messed
up and I could repair it then I could
close up those tents the plants would go
to sleep and I could continue with my
evening go to sleep wake up the next
morning open the tent and reset the
process one night I made a huge mistake
I'm sure a lot of you can already tell
what I did I don't remember exactly what
happened because it was a long time ago
but I fell asleep with every tent in
that girl room open I woke up several
hours after my flowering lights had gone
off I woke up in a panic I knew
immediately that I had [ __ ] up I ran
to the grow room and just as I had
suspected my flowering lights were off
but the grow tents were all wide open
and all of my veg lights were still on
so my flowering plants were now
experiencing an interrupted dark cycle
now just in case we have some new
growers listening what I did is a
serious mistake interrupting the dark
cycle and all will create problems in
the grow I interrupted the dark cycle
for at least four to six hours so my
plants thought that it was daytime for
an extra six hours that day this is the
exact type of mistake that will cause
our plants to hermaphrodite this is the
exact type of mistake that will generate
unwanted seeds in our cannabis crop one
of the most important things to a
successful seedless cannabis crop is an
uninterrupted dark cycle and I
completely [ __ ] that up by falling
asleep with my grow tents open I was
still a fairly new and experienced
grower I wasn't exactly sure what to do
the only thing I could think of doing
was immediately closing up my flowering
rooms closing up those bedrooms and
making sure those plants
it back on their regularly scheduled
program I think that I got really lucky
that that mistake happened later in
Flour
because I got a few seeds but I did not
ruin the entire crop if that mistake had
happened earlier in Flour I would have
ruined an entire crop of cannabis that
entire grow tent that 5x5 grow tent
would have been filled with seeded
cannabis I would have wasted all of
those plants I would have wasted all of
that soil I would have wasted all of the
nutrients I would have wasted all of the
time that I had put into those plants
and I would have wasted all of the
electricity from the lights that I was
pumping into those plants I would have
had useless buds at the end and I would
have had a bunch of shitty seeds that
nobody wants so I got really lucky that
I made my mistake late enough in Flour
to not seed my entire crop but had I
made that mistake 10 or 14 days earlier
I could have potentially seeded that
entire crop so as a beginner that is one
of the first major mistakes I do
remember making I fell asleep with my
grow tents open and my veg lights
contaminated my flowering cycle and I
got a few seeds in my crop now a lot of
people may ask what happened to those
seeds what did you do with those seeds
those seeds in my opinion were
undesirable they were probably thrown
away I really don't like to give away or
share seeds that are made on accident
they come from a light contamination I
don't think that is good karma that is
not good practice don't give those seeds
out those are probably trash if you want
to do anything with them grow them
yourself don't spread those seeds and at
the time I was a medical marijuana
provider so I had a couple of people
that relied on me for quality products
we had a couple of friends that were a
little bit frustrated with me because
their medical marijuana supply for the
month had seeds in it they would put
their buds in a grinder they'd grind it
up and they're here ting ting ting ting
ting and they would just look at me like
you [ __ ] up but I learned I did make a
mistake and I know now to not fall
asleep with my grow room open so let's
talk about another mistake I have made
in the grow room one time I mixed up a
large batch of nutrients that were meant
for a flowering room this flowering room
had just been flipped to the flowering
phase in that nutrient mix I added a
product that is used to encourage and
promote
rapid onset of the flowering phase that
would have been perfect for my freshly
flowering plants it would have sped them
up we would have seen bud set a little
bit sooner that product also slows down
the stretch so I thought I was doing a
really good thing it worked out
beautifully
I fed those flowering plants that mix
went about my business
everything was I read when I was done
watering that flowering room I mixed up
nutrients to water my veg room I don't
know how it happened but I got mixed up
and I used the wrong bucket to water my
veg plants so I accidentally poured that
product that is used to initiate flour
onto my vegetative plants which
triggered them to flower so at that
point I had plants underneath a
vegetative light in a veg room on a veg
schedule that were showing full pre
flower these plants were starting to
show the little dandelion bud sets while
they were in veg and that was all caused
by one incorrect feed with one incorrect
product it doesn't sound like a big deal
that maybe some plants flowered 10 maybe
14 days maybe 21 days early but think
about this where are they gonna go
my flowering room is filled I can't turn
my bedroom into a flowering room to
accommodate these plants because that is
where I keep my mother plants so now
I've got plants that are going into
flower and I don't have room for them
for it at least 10 maybe 20 more days
depending on when that crop in front of
them finishes so I was in scramble mode
I had to figure out what to do with my
next crop was I going to sacrifice that
crop because I ruined it was I just
gonna scrap it and throw all those
plants away and cut fresh clones and
then wait the two weeks for the clones
to root and then wait two or three weeks
for them to veg to catch up to the size
they were at that rate I'll fall behind
on my perpetual schedule and I won't
have plants in the room and I'll have a
room empty for two weeks then the crop
that is supposed to come up right behind
that that is probably already in the
cloner is going to be behind it's going
to throw everything off rhythm so by
accidentally feeding my veg plants the
wrong nutrients I [ __ ] everything up
in my grow for at least two full cycles
I had to rethink everything had to
reschedule everything I had to regroup
and start fresh and get a whole new plan
for the rest of the year for my
and yes I do have my grow spaces planned
out for at least the next six to twelve
maybe 18 months if you are growing on a
production schedule you should know what
is happening for at least the next two
or three maybe four or five crops in
your grow when you think about it a
flowering cycle eats up two full months
so you can plan an entire years worth of
growing just by thinking about three to
six full cycles if you are going to run
a nine week flowering cycle in your
flowering room you can pull five point
seven harvests per year but that is only
going to work if you were on a very
tight schedule if you run a sixty day
cycle you will be able to pull off six
full crops but only if you do not miss
one single day in that flowering room so
in my world scheduling is very important
when it comes to commercial growing
scheduling is extremely important so
that was a huge mistake that I made I
fed my vegetative plants flowering
nutrients and it sent those little
[ __ ] into flower way too early which
caused chaos in my grow room for at
least two more full cycles so be very
careful when you're mixing your
nutrients for your plants and pay very
close attention to each product you pour
into your solution you guys this is
starting to feel kind of like a
confession or something like I am over
here admitting all of my grow room sins
or something let's keep going I do have
quite a few more mistakes that we can
talk about let's talk about a mistake
that I have made once or twice and I
will never make again I have made the
mistake of getting a clone from either a
friend or a dispensary and I brought
that clone into my grow room without
treating it for every pests and pathogen
imaginable that is a huge mistake if you
ever get a clone from a dispensary or a
friend
be sure to treat that clone for every
pests and pathogen that you can imagine
before introducing that clone to the
general population in your grow
environment I strongly recommend
treating any incoming plants for pests
and pathogens before they are introduced
to general population I suggest keeping
any new plants in quarantine for at
least a week until you can be sure they
are
problem-free so whenever you get a new
plant treat it for pests and pathogens I
don't know your integrated pest
management program
I don't know how organic you want to be
I don't know how nuclear you want to go
but when you bring in a new clone I
suggest blasting the [ __ ] out of it for
every problem you can imagine treat it
like it does have bugs and powdery
mildew keep that clone away from your
mother plants keep that clone away from
your veg plants try to wash your hands
and change your clothes before you
interact with the rest of your garden
until you are certain that that new
incoming clone is pests and pathogens
free I like to call that setting
yourself up for success the minute you
get that clone is when your success can
begin or when your failure can begin you
do have the option to get super excited
and race home with your new plant and
put it in a new pot so it matches all of
your other plants put a nice fancy label
on it so it's got a cute name on it and
then put it right in the grow room right
next to all of the other plants so that
it can look just like the rest of your
garden now you're super excited look I
just got a brand new cut of this plant
it looks gorgeous
then about three to five maybe seven
days later you start noticing that
there's some weird [ __ ] happening in the
grow why are these leaves yellow why is
this plant drooping what's going on over
here you know what's going on over here
you just brought in russet mites and
they came from that clone but you did
not quarantine that clone that you did
not spray that clone that you are not
responsible with so my advice my
guidance to you is to treat every single
plant coming into your grow as if it
were infested with every bug imaginable
and every sort of pathogen imaginable it
is really easy to treat one plant but it
is a pain in the ass to treat the entire
garden so get that one plant spray the
[ __ ] out of it quarantine it inspect it
for four or five maybe seven to ten days
and once you are absolutely sure that
that plan is clean put it in general
population let it be a part of the grow
all right those were some mistakes I
made as a rookie grower let's move into
some things that I have [ __ ] up in a
commercial facility yes I am responsible
for large commercial facilities a lot of
the facilities I work with have around
100 flowering lights some of the
facilities I work with have as many as 5
to 700
flowering lights that gives me a lot of
opportunity to make a lot of mistakes I
do my best to minimize mistakes I keep a
lot of notes and I try to pay a lot of
attention and I try to follow a lot of
standard operating procedures but
sometimes [ __ ] does go wrong so let's
talk about some of the things I have
[ __ ] up any commercial grow facility
it seems to be a tradition that when I
take over a new facility that the way I
Chris in that facility is by flooding
the [ __ ] out of that facility I like to
see how much water a building can hold I
like to test the floor drains in a
building as soon as I take over I don't
know why but it seems like as soon as I
take over a grow within the first two or
three weeks I always tend to flood the
damn facility we usually have something
like a usually at least a 100 gallon
reservoir maybe a 250 maybe a 500 gallon
sometimes when were working with a
thousand or a 2500 gallon reservoir and
it takes a really long time to fill
those reservoirs I've got this really
good habit of turning on the water and
deciding I'm gonna go do some other [ __ ]
while this fills up and then it feels
like it's usually two three minutes
right after that thing is filled I
realize hey I left water on and I've got
a thing filling up and I go running back
and guess what there is a [ __ ] flood
in the hallway that is like my gift that
is one of my super moves I don't mean to
do it it's usually not that big a deal
you just get a couple of squeegees and a
mop and you open the doors get some fans
just get everything dried it's just a
setback but it seems to be a tradition
and it's sort of like a way of me I
don't know maybe I'm making my mark
maybe I'm hazing the new facility but
whatever it is it feels like whenever I
get comfortable about that two-month
mark I really enjoy just overflowing the
reservoir and flooding the [ __ ] out of a
new facility now it may not sound like
overflowing or reservoir is a huge deal
to a lot of people but keep in mind when
I work in a commercial facility some of
my water supplies can put out
approximately 30 to 50 gallons of water
per minute so I've got the opportunity
to put 30 to 50 gallons of water on the
floor in as little as one minute so that
can cause a huge problem really quickly
also I'm Way too experienced and I've
been doing this way too long to make
mistakes like overflowing a reservoir
that is day one [ __ ] but for some reason
I am still doing it so that is a major
mistake that I have made and it seems
like I will continue to make any
commercial environment let's talk about
one more mistake that I made and then I
should wrap this up so that I don't get
myself banned from working in the
commercial facilities people are gonna
be afraid to hire me because they know
that I [ __ ] up but at least I'm not
afraid to admit my mistakes so let's
talk about a mistake that I have made on
multiple occasions in multiple grow
environments I have done this in home
grows I have done this in small-scale
commercial environments and I have done
this in a large commercial environment
let's talk about something we like to
mess up quite often in a commercial
environment I suggest using cloning
machines an aeroponic type of cloner the
kind that sprays water up from the
bottom onto the plants to where it
creates nice aerated bubbles the plants
grow nice roots that dangle down into
the water that is the type of cloner I
prefer something like an EZ cloner or
the botanic air power cloner those are
my favorites they're all basically the
same but that is what I recommend in a
commercial environment the mistake I
often make with those easy cloner
machines is every day at the beginning
and the end of the shift I like to turn
the cloner off by unplugging it then I
lift up the lid and I put a pH meter and
an EC meter inside the water I like to
see what my pH is if my pH is off I
adjust it I also check and see what the
EC of that solution is if the EC is
incorrect I adjust it I also check and
see that the water level is just to the
base of the halo and that the sprayers
are not clogged after I have done my
full cloner inspection I've checked my
pH I've checked my EC I've made the
proper adjustments at that point I put
the lid back on the cloner and I plug
the machine back in and I go about my
business one big mistake that I used to
make way too often when doing my cloner
inspection was I would check everything
I would do all of my adjustments I would
write everything down I would put the
lid back on the cloner and then I would
walk away without plugging the machine
back in that can be a huge costly
mistake if I catch that mistake in one
hour I should be okay if I catch it in
two hours we'll be all right
three hours you're kind of pushing your
luck
you don't check on that cloner for four
hours you're gonna cause problems if you
don't check on it in five and six hours
shits gonna go wrong if you don't check
on it before you leave the facility for
the end of the day and you wait until
tomorrow to come back to start the shift
all of your clones are [ __ ] dead in a
commercial environment we don't cut a
couple of clones in a commercial
environment we generally cut a hundred
and twenty-eight clones and a minimum my
small corner is a hundred and
twenty-eight sites I like to fill that
I'm not going to cut half of it I'm
gonna fill it up so if I killed clones I
am probably killing at least a hundred
clones at a time now what can make this
even worse is a lot of times I've had
all of my cloning machines plugged into
one power strip and I used the on/off
switch on that power strip to turn them
all off and on during my inspection yes
I have plugged in five easy cloners into
one power strip I have gone and done my
end of the shift cloner inspection
everything was legit I put the lid back
on I wrote down that the pH was correct
I wrote down that the EC was correct I
wrote down that I just added a little
bit of clear res because we do that
every three to five days to prevent any
sort of algae buildup then I walked away
from all of those cloning machines I
clocked out and I went home for the
evening when I showed up for work the
next day I had five cloning machines
full of dead clones every single one of
them died because I did not turn that
power strip back on after I did my clone
or inspection that is a huge and costly
mistake luckily those clones were new so
they hadn't started routing it only sent
me back two or three days it also set me
back the amount of time that it took me
to recut all of those cloners worth of
clones I basically paid my staff an
entire day to cut a bunch of clones so
that I could kill them three days later
and repay them to recut all of those
clones all over again I'm very lucky
that in a commercial environment I had a
lot of very large mother plants to pull
those clones from in a smaller grow
environment your mother plants may not
be able to provide enough clones you may
have been [ __ ] out of luck in that
situation so be very careful with your
cloners if you were using an easy cloner
if you're using a turbo cloner an auto
clone or any
sort of arrow cloner be sure to turn
that thing back on after you make any
adjustments and if you were using the
old-fashioned trays and plugs and domes
make sure you put that dome back on
correctly if it's got a little gap at
the edge all of your water will escape
your clones will dry out so that's
another mistake we can talk about I have
made several times in my grow career
let's talk about leaving the dome off of
our clones for way too long
say you've got a clone dome and it is
time to start burping your clones they
are just now developing roots we want to
give them 15 to 30 minutes of fresh air
every day we take that dome off we let
the air blow around then at about 30
minutes you go and you put that dome
right back on and then hopefully your
plants start to develop stronger roots
you increase that open interval a little
bit over time then eventually those
plants can survive without the dome one
mistake that a lot of people like to
make is you take that dome off and you
go get stoned and you forget to put the
dome back on you come back like two
hours later and your plants are all
crispy dead and dry that is a very
simple mistake to make in a grow
environment if you are going to take the
dome off of your clones set a timer
everybody is addicted to their iPhone
set a timer on your iPhone your phone
will set a timer without you pressing
any buttons you can ask your phone to
remind you when 15 minutes have passed
you can say hey Siri in 15 minutes
remind me to put the lid back on the
clones and she will say okay in 15
minutes I will remind you to put the lid
back on the clones and you won't forget
we're all addicted to our phones use it
to your advantage so those are a couple
of other common mistakes that I am
admitting to having done way too often I
have killed clones by not plugging in
the clone machine again and I have
killed plenty of clones by not putting
the dome back on after their burping
period so don't forget about your clones
set a timer learn from my mistakes and
hopefully you don't have to suffer the
same traumatic experiences that I have
suffered in my garden
all right podcast world I think that is
enough grow room mistake confessions for
one episode I look forward to hearing
about your biggest grow room mistakes
once again send me an email my email
address is grow from your heart at hot
Elcom I look forward to all of the
submissions and I will keep you
anonymous don't worry I'm not gonna say
bill from st. Louis ruined every girl he
ever worked in by doing this I'm not
gonna do that to you I will keep your
identity secret I will keep you
anonymous I'm not trying to embarrass
anybody by doing an episode about
people's mistakes my goal here is to
help other growers to not make these
same mistakes that other people have
made and maybe if we tell them the
mistakes that we've ran into the
problems we've experienced we can give
them a little bit of warning and they'll
look out and not make the same mistakes
that we are making my ultimate goal here
in this episode and in this entire
podcast is to make everybody's grow
experience more enjoyable and to improve
the quality of everybody's overall
finished product
all right podcast world I'm going to
start wrapping up this podcast while I'm
still employable if you feel like this
episode was educational informative or
entertaining and you would like to make
a financial contribution to the show you
can do so by visiting www.hp.com slash
grow from your heart all of the
information you need to contribute to
the show will be right there on the
screen once again I want to send a huge
thank you to everybody who has
contributed to the podcast in the past
in the present and in the future I would
also appreciate it if you support the
show on social media give us a follow on
Facebook simply search for the growth
from your heart podcast on Twitter it's
@gf wih podcast if you would like to
follow my personal Twitter account it is
at Ross to Jeff 420 on Instagram I
suggest you follow my seed company on
Instagram I use Irie underscore genetics
give me a follow on Instagram check out
my fine cannabis photography join me
every Monday around 710 mountain time
for my Instagram live feed I go live I
talk about growing cannabis I take a few
dabs and I do my best to answer grow
questions on the fly so I invite you to
follow me on Instagram and join me for
my Instagram lives every Monday if
you've got something you'd like to say
and you're not into all of the social
media nonsense you can send me an email
my email address once again is grow from
your heart at hotmail.com you know that
I would love to hear from you don't
forget to visit our sponsor seeds here
now it's seeds here now calm make sure
you check out their fresh
drop on 710 they will have lemon Jeffrey
golden goat and orange gasm feminized
seeds get those before they run out I
think that is all I've got for you for
this episode ladies and gentlemen I want
to give a huge shout out to my friend
Troy Thomas and until next time take a
phat dab and give your mom a hug for me