welcome back podcast world it is time
for episode 445 of the growth from your
heart podcast this episode of the show
is brought to you by my friends at seeds
here now if you need new seeds in your
garden I highly recommend seeds here now
and you can find them at
www.pmtasetup.com
and seventy six point seven percent
total cannabinoids i'm cracking open the
jar right now so i can give it a fresh
smell the first smell that hits my face
is exactly watermelons it is like
watermelon candies it is delicious then
there is sort of a funky gassy thing in
the background it is amazing when you
dab it it tastes like fresh watermelon
candies with a hint of green apples I
really loved the watermelon gelato so
big shout out to my friends at
apothecary farms for the delicious
concentrates ladies and gentlemen in
this episode I'm going to address a
couple of questions that people asked me
about correcting powdery mildew and
handling bugs in a grow room but before
we get there I'd like to do a shout out
to a few of my friends on patreon how
about a big giant grow from your heart
podcast shout out to my friend Todd Kay
I want to send a huge shout out to my
friend John em I wanna give a giant grow
from your heart podcast fist bump to my
buddy Justin how about a big growth from
your heart podcast shout out and a thank
you to my friend David OQ also a big
podcast shout out to my friend Glenn G
of course a girl from your heart podcast
shout out and a fist bump to our buddy
sour D and of course last but certainly
not least a giant girl from your heart
podcast shout out and a thank you to my
buddy squirrel tactics I want to thank
each and every one of you for your
continued patreon support if anybody out
there would like to learn how to become
a patron and support the show
financially you can do so by going to
www.whitehouse.gov/champions
to address a question about spray
applications to take care of powdery
mildew and pests let's jump into that I
was in an Instagram live feed today and
somebody kept asking questions about
what they can spray to take care of
powdery mildew then they asked what they
can spray to take care of their bugs now
spraying is a good way to minimize a
pest population spraying is a good way
to minimize potential powdery mildew
problems but spraying products is not a
long-term solution to cure problems in a
grow environment so let's talk about
that for a little bit here the plants in
this person's garden are obviously
displaying but they are infected with
powdery mildew you can see it is visible
it is present now it's going to be
really easy to grab a product and spray
it all over those plants and wash that
powdery mildew off and act like we have
just solved the problem it's not visible
it's out of sight it's out of mind we
think it may be cured the problem is
solved let's move forward it is not that
simple depending on the product you
applied depending on the environment
depending on the conditions that powdery
mildew has a very good potential of
coming back all you did was give that
plant a little bath you did not destroy
you did not kill that powdery mildew you
just rinsed it off you probably just
spread it out to tell you the truth so
your powdery mildew is going to come
back all we have done is a temporary fix
it looks like it's gone but it is going
to come back and it is going to be worse
then what are you going to do when it
comes back with a vengeance you had a
little powdery mildew you sprayed it
with a product that kind of knocked it
down for a little bit but then when it
came back it was even stronger now what
are you going to do you're gonna spray
again so that it can come back even
stronger and then as the plants get
older as the cycle progresses you're
going to get big fat juicy buds are you
going to spray those I don't want to
consume your buds they were sprayed with
any sort of product that is used to
treat powdery mildew once your plants
get big fat buds if you continue to
spray them you're going to destroy the
flavor you're going to destroy the aroma
they're gonna burn funky your buds are
gonna taste funny and a lot of
commercial grow environments I see
people attempt to use a sulphur burner
to minimize the risk of powdery mildew
that works to get rid of powdery mildew
but it also puts a terrible shitty
sulfur flavor in the finished product
also if you turn that finish prod
into a concentrate it makes the
concentrate tastes like burnt fish it is
disgusting so do not use a sulfur burner
in your grow that is my advice that is
my opinion
many people will argue with that I do
not like it I do not approve you will be
able to taste it and it will ruin your
concentrates so I highly advise against
the sulfur burner now let's talk more
about spraying what are you gonna do are
you just gonna keep spraying forever
spraying will not last forever spring is
like a temporary band-aid for whatever
problem you have got if you've got a
giant gash on your arm you need some
stitches are you just gonna keep putting
little band-aids over it every day and
hope that [ __ ] closes are you just gonna
suck it up and go to the ER and get
seven stitches and get that [ __ ] fixed
sometimes you need to just bite the
bullet and fix the grow room you need to
figure out the problem and you need to
correct the issue and quit spraying
every day spraying will get expensive if
you have a small garden it may not add
up as quickly if you are in a commercial
environment spraying a large room will
become very expensive very quickly first
you have to buy whatever product you
were going to apply if you have a large
room a large facility you're buying a
lot of product then you need an
applicator that is going to get
expensive depending on the size of your
grow the size of your environment you
need something that can effectively and
efficiently cover all of your plants
with the pesticide product you choose to
use then once you've got the products
you need to pay somebody to apply that
product to your grow they're using
manpower that you're using time also
they're damaging the plants they're
decreasing the overall quality of your
finished product by applying that
pesticide also you are cutting that room
off for work for the rest of the day in
most cases a pesticide application will
have a re-entry interval in which you
are not allowed to enter that room until
that time period has passed most
pesticides have a minimum of a four hour
re-entry interval in most cases that is
half of a work shift so that will
eliminate access to that room for the
rest of the staff for probably half the
day so if there was more work to be done
in there you're [ __ ] out of luck you
can't be foliate you can't do any of the
extra ketchup work you can't put up
trellising you can't do any popping and
twisting because that room is off-limits
now
it is shut down it is under a re-entry
interval and the door is marked do not
enter until this time so applying
pesticides will become costly and in the
long run correcting the issue that is
causing the problem will be more
efficient than reapplying pesticides
every three days I didn't even think
about the cost of training an employee
to spray that room that employee has to
be trained they have to have Department
of Agriculture pesticide safety training
if they want to apply a pesticide they
have to have a OSHA and OSHA respirator
fit certification which means they have
to go to a doctor and they have to put
on the respirator that they intend to
use when they apply pesticides and they
have to show that they know how to put
on that respirator correctly they have
to show that it fits them correctly
around their face and there are no air
leaks and they have to show that they
can remove it correctly without getting
pesticides on their face and they also
have to show that they can clean it and
keep it up to date
that is an expensive class that is an
expensive doctor appointment so that is
another thing that you have to pay for
when it comes to a pesticide applicator
also you have to pay for all of the
personal protective equipment every time
somebody applies a pesticide they need
to suit up in a commercial environment
anybody that I am responsible for wears
a full tiebacks suit when they are
applying a pesticide they are suited up
from head to toe they've got the hood up
they've got the appropriate goggles some
of my dudes wear that big full face mask
respirator that covers your whole face
you look like the [ __ ] SWAT team I
like that one really well we were at
least six millimeter thick gloves
depending on the pesticides we are
applying most of the time it's a six
millimeter sometimes a little bit
thicker of a glove we've got the
appropriate gloves based on the
pesticides we're using we are suited up
all of that [ __ ] is very expensive
those Tyvek suits are one-time use you
go in the room you spray you get coated
and pesticide you got to take that suit
off and throw it away you basically do
your best to step out of it without
touching it too much those respirator
cartridges those are expensive to
replace the respirators are quite
expensive to replace all of the gloves
we go through are extremely expensive
when you go through them and the volumes
that we do in a commercial grow
environment all of those little costs
will add up and in the long run whatever
was causing your powdery mildew issue
would probably have been cheaper just
to correct that in one big bite that is
a good way to segue into some of the
things that are probably causing the
powdery mildew in my opinion the most
common cause of powdery mildew is an
incorrect
VPD that's right vapor pressure deficit
I've done a full Episode on VPD if you
were interested in learning a lot about
vapor pressure deficit I recommend
episode 314 of the growth from your
heart podcast it is actually titled
vapor pressure deficit that episode will
teach you a lot but I think VPD is the
most common cause of powdery mildew and
that includes excessive heat and high
humidity another thing that I think
really contributes to powdery mildew is
temperature swings diurnal temperature
swing when your day and night
temperature change if your day is 80
degrees and your night is 60 degrees you
are giving yourself a really good
opportunity for powdery mildew
development try not to have more than a
five to seven degrees swing and your
diurnal temperatures 10 degrees max may
be 12 degrees I'd like to see you stay
within 5 to 7 degrees temperature swing
from day to night 10 degrees is cool 12
degrees is pushing it 15 to 20
you're gonna start causing yourself
problems another thing that I think
often contributes to powdery mildew is
excessive water left in the grow room
sometimes I see small puddles in a
commercial environment just because [ __ ]
happens in the grow we're busy sometimes
we're cleaning things sometimes we're
watering things sometimes we just spill
some [ __ ] and there is water left in the
grow sometimes there's a bucket left
somewhere with water in it sometimes the
tables the flood to drain tables will
get clogged with debris at the drain and
you don't clean that out and then the
table will get a little layer of water
in there then you start seeing that
little green algae buildup on your table
that will also contribute to powdery
mildew another thing I think contributes
to powdery mildew is improper airflow I
talked about in a previous episode
people squish their plants too close
together that will contribute to powdery
mildew also you need some fans in the
room move some air around also another
critical thing you can't just move air
around we need air exchange you have to
get that old stagnant air out and put
some fresh air in the room you need a
dehumidifier
fire you may need a humidifier and you
need air exchange some folks may be
working a sealed environment they are
advanced growers they understand how to
control the environment and keep things
safe if they're running a sealed
environment I'm pretty confident in
their skills they're running co2 to
augment the co2 to keep the co2 high in
there they don't need much advice on
keeping the powdery mildew under control
hopefully at this point another thing I
see that people commonly overlooked when
they are starting to have powdery mildew
issues is defoliation if you've got
powdery mildew on a leaf why not pull
the damn leaf off take it off of there
that is less opportunity for a bug or a
piece of mildew to attach itself to your
plant less places to hang out less
things to hang out that is just good
logic in my opinion also you will reduce
the amount of water that those plants
release into the air because there are
not as many leaves basically there
aren't as many mouth breathers in there
spitting out a bunch of hot air so d
foliate and that will help you out
another thing that will help you
tremendously is to just basically clean
up the grow space I talk a lot about
cleaning up I find it really important
to clean up the gross space also clean
your tools if you're going from one
plant to another plant or from one table
to another table why not just dip your
scissors and do some rubbing alcohol and
dry them off with a paper towel and keep
moving sterilize your [ __ ] that way if
one plant infected with something you
don't move it right along through the
entire garden which is another great way
to segue into this next bullet point I
don't have any of this [ __ ] written down
you guys this is all flying out at the
top of my head just so that you know
that today the next thing I was going to
talk about is infected clones another
way that I see people bring powdery
mildew into a grow is by bringing a
clone from a friend or a dispensary or
wherever that had powdery mildew on that
clone already quite often clones travel
around our country allegedly clones may
happen to go across the country in a
sealed baggie and then also inside of a
box and they are moved from one point to
another and they are left in that
packaging for quite some time
often when those clones are opened up
they have developed powdery mildew
inside that packaging the person who
received that package is so excited to
get that new clone that they don't give
a [ __ ] about the
powdery mildew they forget to look they
pop that clone into a little bit of dirt
they put it right into the general
population of their grow room they put
it right next to the fan and then in
three or four days the entire room has
got a nice little sprinkle a powdery
mildew that is a very very common way
for folks to get PM you get a clone from
a friend you get a clone from a
dispensary maybe you get a clone from a
friend online or something like that and
it ends up in your grow and you have now
contaminated your entire grow that is a
big mistake if you ever get a new plant
from anybody I don't care if it's your
best friend I don't care if it's your
mama I don't care if it's your mentor if
you get a new clone from anybody
quarantine that clone and make sure that
it is pests and pathogens for you
introduce that plant into your general
population as a responsible gardener you
cannot blame your friends your fellow
growers whoever gave you that clone for
giving you powdery mildew spider mites
thrips whatever comes with that plant is
not their fault it is your fault for not
being responsible and treating that
clone as if it had every bug and
pathogen on the planet when it was
brought to your grow it is your
responsibility to make sure that plant
is clean everybody thinks their garden
is clean everybody thinks their plants
are pests and pathogens free most of
those people are wrong what I found is
the people who boast the most about
having a clean and pests and pathogens
free garden are the ones with the most
problems they just haven't discovered
the problems yet so be very careful all
right so I have talked about how we get
powdery mildew I've talked about how
sprays are only temporarily effective
and how they will not solve the problem
for a long term so let's talk about
things we can do to correct the room and
make sure we do not get powdery mildew
ever again first off let's start
treating any incoming plants with proper
pesticides and proper fungicide sprays
now yes I have been ranting that sprays
are not the solution to everything but
if you're bringing something in you want
to spray it you want to treat it so that
you don't introduce a problem to the
rest of your grow you don't want
somebody else's problems we can't
correct their room so let's correct the
plant that they brought us that's where
we have to start now let's make sure
that the room we are going to put that
new plant into is prop
let's make sure we have got the proper
VPD I'm going to leave it up to you to
understand and study
VPD once again I did a podcast all about
it it is episode 314 check that out
get your VPD dialed in get your
temperature and humidity dialed in get
your air flow dialed in make sure you
don't have any microclimates in your
gross space what that means is is it 80
degrees over here is it 72 degrees over
here is it 68 degrees down here under
this canopy you need enough airflow to
keep a homogeneous environment you want
it eighty degrees over here eighty
degrees over here 60% humidity over here
60% humidity over here you don't want
big swings and jumps throughout the room
so maybe another thing that you may need
is a proper grow room monitor something
that can actually monitor the VPD of
your room you need to pay attention to
those things if we don't know what's
going on in there we don't know what is
causing problems so dial in the VPD
dial in the temperature and the humidity
get your air flow up to speed clean up
the room remove any excess water that
does not need to be in the room maybe
you're over watering the plants perhaps
you were trying to saturate your medium
a little too heavily maybe you need to
saturate a little less and let the
medium dry and then water again instead
of one big fat watering through the day
may be due to medium waterings that way
you have less water in the air less
water in the room that will help you out
another thing I highly suggest to help
you minimize the potential of powdery
mildew is to defoliate the less leaf in
the room the less potential for problems
I also suggest that you dial in your
diurnal temperature swings you don't
want drastic swings from your day and
night temperatures make sure things
aren't going crazy there also make sure
your humidity swings aren't crazy when
your lights go off so you've got the
lights on all day that is putting heat
in the air that is making the water rise
then the lights go off all that moisture
is in the air it doesn't know what to do
the humidity spikes it goes crazy in the
room for a few minutes if you've got the
proper monitoring gear you can see what
is happening if the lights on and lights
off in your room and in a lot of cases
that is where we start develop
being powdery mildew problems so make
sure you're not getting temperature
swings make sure you're not getting
humidity spikes then another thing we
can think about is to make sure that
none of the air being drawn into the
room is extremely cool some growers like
to pull air from outside during the
winter because they think that helps
cool the room that is actually giving
you a huge potential for powdery mildew
you're bringing that cool air into the
warm grow room it is going to create
moisture and that will begin to create
perfect conditions for powdery mildew so
if you take some time to correct your
vapor pressure deficit get your
temperature and your humidity dialed in
make sure that your air flow is proper
clean up that grow room maybe add a few
fans maybe add an extraction fan so that
you can suck that humidity out maybe add
an intake fan so that you can suck some
fresh air into the room maybe some small
adjustments will help you minimize the
risks of getting powdery mildew now
here's something that just came to my
mind when I was talking about moving air
around this is something funny that I
see in a lot of commercial environments
so you've got multiple flowering rooms
and multiple bedrooms in one big
building so a lot of times there's a
hallway in most facilities there's one
long hallway with flowering rooms all
along one side and flowering rooms all
along another side just separated by
walls and doors so basically like an
apartment building you got a long haul
when you got apartment a apartment B
apartment C and then on the other side
you got D en F right except I do in my
letters in numbers just cuz I'm weird so
weird ugh a lot of facilities I see
their ducting the heat straight out of
room a into that hallway their ducting
that heat straight out of room B into
the hallway their ducting the heat from
room C into the hallway also their air
conditioner take intake is in the
hallway so you're just dumping hot air
into the hallway and then trying to suck
that right back up through the air
conditioner in take all that humid air
all that stagnant air is just going
right back into the grow you're fighting
yourself think about your ducting think
about efficiency that way are you
heating up a room where you're pulling
your air conditioning air through are
you humidifying a room that you're
trying to be humidify are you dumping
the hot air into a room where you're
fighting yourself just think about air
efficiency when it comes to designing
your HVAC system and where the heat and
humidity end up I can think of one clear
or there's a growth facility or they've
got their heat duct shooting the heat
right are there extractions shooting the
heat right into the hallway but then
right across that hallway is an intake
fan sucking what should be fresh cool
air into that flowering room it's
actually sucking all of that heat
straight out of the other room into that
room and it heats up that room
perpetually and that room never gets
cooled down so that room has been
designated as a veg space because they
can't figure out how to cool it I told
them spend a few bucks redirect your air
and that problem will be solved
unfortunately that is not how all owners
see things they would rather just make
the grow team struggle and make it hard
on them and then yell at everybody
because they can't reach production
goals unfortunately all too often that
is how a commercial grow environment
will work but my point of this 20 minute
rant you guys is that sprays are not a
long-term solution sprays are temporary
quick fixes it will not solve the
problem you can't just keep spraying
forever what are you gonna do are you
gonna spray every three days you're
going to be buying personal protective
equipment every week you're gonna be
buying more pesticide a more fungicide
every week solve the problem fix the air
conditioner fix all those air
conditioner gaps fix all the ducting
gaps to solve the [ __ ] and your
whole grow will be more enjoyable now
let's shift gears and talk about the
same thing but we're gonna focus more on
pest this time most often pests come in
on clones or you bring them in the grow
yourself or they find the most minut
crack in the walls and they sneak their
way in but I believe that most commonly
they come in with a clone or they come
in on your clothes on your shoes or you
bring them in from your home grow or
from your commercial grow maybe you've
got a friend that grows at home or
you've got multiple friends that grow at
other places you guys all go hang out at
the same place you sit on the same couch
his thrips crawl onto your shorts your
spider mites crawl into his shorts you
guys go home now you both have thrips
and spider mites I just think that since
everybody is growing cannabis we are all
just constantly trading bugs so we've
got to think about pest management
before you go into your grow change into
your dedicated grow room clothes you
should have grow room shoes you should
have some grow room pants you should
have grow room shirts you should have a
separate grow room
you can't just wear your normal hat
that's not gonna work you want separate
clothes for your grow space so when you
come in and out of that grow you're
basically wearing your uniform this will
help you out in so many ways you're only
going to get pesticides on those clothes
because when you're in the grow if
you've applied a pesticide every time
you rub up against that plant and that
wall you're now getting pesticides on
your clothes so I have some dead it
designated clothes also have designated
shoes you don't want to be I'm a hippie
I'm out hiking on the trails I'm running
in the mountains I don't want to go take
my mountain shoes into my grow room or
into a commercial grow and think about
whatever kind of bugs I may have picked
up out near Red Rocks or out of the
canyon trail and take that [ __ ] into a
commercial environment the next day I
walked in and there [ __ ] Athens
everywhere I would be so mad at myself
so get yourself some dedicated grow room
shoes some dedicated grow room clothes
all the way up to the Hat if you're in a
commercial facility I almost recommend
changing if you've got a lab coat or if
you've got the opportunity to change
clothes between big rooms I would
definitely suggest that if you've got a
room in a commercial facility that is
contaminated with bugs make that the
last room you work on every day so that
you don't start in that room get
yourself coated in spider mites and then
drag them through the rest of the growth
throughout the day start in the cleanest
room then work your way to the dirty
room and then go home that way you don't
take those bugs through the rest of the
grow that way you're probably going to
take them home but as soon as you get
home
drop those clothes in the dirty clothes
pile take a quick shower put on some
fresh clothes or put on your grow room
clothes then head to your grow room and
handle your [ __ ] but you need to switch
clothes before grow spaces
I also recommend switching clothes
between your indoor and outdoor grow
space if you've got the opportunity I
understand
switching clothes can be quite
time-consuming if you need to do it
multiple times in a day maybe if you've
got a couple of lab coats or something
you can switch in and out of that would
be helpful but do anything you can to
minimize the opportunity of bringing a
stowaway pests from grow to grow so I
think some of the most efficient ways to
prevent yourself from getting spider
mites is to treat any clones they come
into your grow act like that any plant
that comes into your grow has got all of
the bugs and all of the problems act
like that thing is a trap you've got to
treat that plant for spider mites for
thrips for aphids and for powdery mildew
before you even
think about bringing it into the grow
then also change clothes and keep
yourself clean from grow to grow if you
go to the growth store if you go to some
grow meeting if you go to a grow class I
would definitely change clothes before
you enter your grow environment and then
you also need to think about long-term
pest management we are not going to
apply pesticide sprays forever
we're gonna get big fat buds eventually
any pesticide will die off it will not
be effective most of them have a very
short shelf life unless you're going
with something pretty extreme so you
will need to find a better solution I
highly suggest predator mites I like
predator bugs in the grow one of the
most popular pest management instructors
has coined the phrase no bug can build a
resistance to being eaten which is a
great statement if we keep applying
pesticides to our pests they're going to
build a resistance to it if you keep
spraying as a max on your spider mites
you are going to create a Naza max
resistant spider mite
they will start drinking it and spitting
it back in your face and laughing at you
you need to rotate your pesticides once
you get into flower you release those
predator mites and guess what
nothing has a resistance to being eaten
if you are a little tiny spider mite and
a great big hungry predator mite comes
by your food you're gonna die that's how
it goes so I would suggest switching to
predator bugs early in Flour if not late
in veg and here's a little note that
I've been talking about just randomly
when I'm teaching classes and talking
about pest management I think many
people are prioritizing their plants
backwards when it comes to pest
management many people focus on the
plants that have the big fat buds that
are almost ready for harvest that are
really photogenic that are beautiful the
management is gonna come in and look at
many people focus on keeping those
plants pest free I recommend starting
the other direction I think that the
mother plants and the small clones are
the most important plants to keep pest
free because that is where everything
starts if you've got a grow that is
contaminated I would start working on
the mother plants and the veg plants
first those plants that are in flower
their numbers are up their time is
counting down they're gonna be cut down
and removed from your facility in just a
few weeks those mother plants they're
there for a much longer time
you've got to deal with them much longer
we need to correct their problems get
them happy get them healthy because the
mother plants are the start of
everything the mother plants are where
it all comes from you need a happy
healthy mother plant so that you can get
a happy healthy clone so that you can
have happy healthy veggie
so that we can have happy healthy
flowering plants so that we can have big
fat juicy beautiful healthy buds so that
in turn we can have happy healthy
patients so you need happy healthy
mother plants to make that happen and to
make all of that happen you need a happy
healthy clean dialed-in grow environment
ladies and gentlemen I think this was a
great podcast episode I had a lot of fun
doing this with very minimal notes I'm
kind of proud about that I want to thank
you guys for listening to this episode
of The Grove from your heart podcast if
you feel that this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
and you'd like to make a financial
contribution to the show I encourage you
to do so all you have to do is go to
patreon.com/scishow I would also
appreciate it if you support the show on
social media you can find me on Twitter
it's at G fyh podcast also I would like
it if you find me on a new cannabis
friendly social media application called
cannabis cannabis is a very cannabis
friendly social media application where
you can post your cannabis photography
your cannabis questions if you need some
advice if you need some help or if you
just want to show off your buds and your
plants I encourage you to post your
pictures at cannabis recently the
Android App Store has removed cannabis
from their applications store but
cannabis is in the process of adding an
android download link to their website
so you will be able to directly download
the app from their website it will work
just like it did before it's just not
available in the Android store they're
kind of being haters on the cannabis
focused application so they shut us down
there don't worry the application will
be available on the cannabis website
very soon I encourage you to join us on
cannabis if you've got an Apple device
all you have to do is go to the Apple
App Store type in cannabis download it
it is free join me come check out my
fine cannabis photography on cannabis
I would also appreciate it if you
subscribe to my youtube channel simply
search for the growth from your heart
podcast click subscribe leave some
comments on the videos let me know what
you think about the show if you'd like
to reach out and you're not into all of
that social media nonsense maybe you'd
like to sponsor the podcast perhaps
you've got a product you'd like me to
review you can send me an email my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com you know that i would love
to hear from you ladies and gentlemen
that is all I've got for you for episode
4 or 45 of the girl from your heart
podcast thanks again for listening I'm
gonna give a huge shout out to my friend
James but erson and until next time take
a phat dab and give your mom a hug for
me