all right what's up podcast world it is
time for episode 448 of the grow from in
heart podcast this episode of the show
is brought to you by our friends at
seeds here now if you need new seeds in
your garden I highly recommend seeds
here now and you can find them at
www.ctvn.org e and jam-band
the aroma is really funky I'm cracking
it open right now to get a fresh smell
it's got a immediately a gassy dirty
aroma right off the crack of the jar as
soon as I open it there is a gassy smell
then there is a rotten fruit sort of a
thing on the background I think it is
delicious the flavor is gassy and gross
all at the same time it coats your mouth
so deliciously the potency label says
this product contains seventy two point
nine percent THC and eighty four point
four percent total cannabinoids I really
like the Tahoe Jam Fambrough juh from
our friends at apothecary farms so big
shout out to all of my friends over at
apothecary ladies and gentlemen this is
going to be a quick Thursday episode
I've got an email from a friend that I
want to read so let's not waste a lot of
time let's jump right into this email
this message goes just like this it says
hey Rasta Jeff I found you through the
embracing organics show just to keep
people up to speed I am part of another
podcast called embracing organics that
show is on YouTube it happens live every
Thursday at 7 p.m. mountain time it is
hosted by my good friend dirt man Dan he
invites me as a panelists that show is
mainly based on organically growing
cannabis I know I'm not much of an
organic farmer but I do have plenty of
opportunities to give a lot of good
insight in that episode we talk about
the cannabis industry we talk about
breeding we talk about smoking we talk
about cultivation we talk a lot about
cannabis anyway I invite you to join us
on the embracing organics show Thursdays
on YouTube at 7 p.m. mountain time I'm
not sure your time zone I know that I've
got to be there at 7 so find out what
time 7 p.m. mountain time is in your
time zone
join us on Thursdays for the embracing
organics live
also if you miss the show all of the
episodes are still available on YouTube
just go to youtube type in embracing
organics you'll find an episode I'm sure
you will enjoy so I am a guest on the
embracing organic show every Thursday
and that is where our friend found me he
goes on to say I found you
via stabby mixed a person who spoke
highly of your work and made me curious
I meant big shout out to my friend
stabby stabby is a great person a great
dude he is also a panelist on the
embracing organic show we have become
quite good friends lately and it's good
to hear that stabby is speaking well of
me so the message goes on it says I
don't have money to support you on
patreon or buy your seeds but I would
like to support by giving some grow tips
of my own which I have picked up and I
felt could help you out if you have not
heard them yet so my new friend here
wants to support the show he is not in a
position to financially contribute to
the show he is not in a situation where
he needs seeds so he is doing his giving
back by sending us some useful advice I
thought I would share this advice with
you guys and here are some tips sent in
by our friend tip number one is sworsky
predator mites can get expensive and
need to be reapplied I talk quite often
about using sworsky predator mice as
part of my integrated pest management
yes they do need to be reapplied it does
take some time to establish colonies
this email comes with some great advice
it says if you grow banker plants or
companion plants such as poinsettias and
place a few between each plant in the
veg and flower room thus worse Keys will
feed on the pollen from the pepper
plants and tell your bad bugs arrive or
return so if you have released
Swarovski's in your grow eventually they
are going to eat all of the bad mites
hopefully in theory they're going to get
in there and they are going to eradicate
all of the intrusive spider mites at
that point in time those Swarovski's
will go hey there's nothing here for me
I'm gonna take off and just like you
they're gonna want to eat and they're
gonna want to get laid so they're gonna
leave they're gonna go find a better
opportunity to eat and get laid if you
have some point set ax or pepper plants
in your grow those Swarovski's can feed
off of the pollen so they will have
something to survive off of and you
don't need bad bugs in your situation in
your environment to continue to keep the
popular
Asians of Swarovski's colonized in your
facility or in your outdoor grow so that
is a very useful tip if you are trying
to establish and keep colonies of
Swarovski's around in your facility or
in your outdoor grow some points Etta's
or some pepper plants will help them
stick around because they can simply
feed off of that pollen now this email
continues he said I learned this from
psyche angel on Instagram now psyche
angel is an IPM specialist and an
entomologist and he says I've seen my
buddy's garden effectively maintaining
his sworsky population and he also says
females were skis produce three times
more when on a pollen diet so you'll be
able to increase your population quite
quickly if you are feeding them the
proper pollen it goes on to say the
point setters make copious amounts of
pollen which you probably already know
peppers won't pollinate cannabis plants
and keep the good bugs around sort of
like a barracks of soldiers waiting to
deploy when the bad bugs come around yes
that is absolutely correct the pollen
from the poinsettias cannot pollinate
your cannabis plant so that's not
anything to worry about I'm sure
somebody was thinking that I'm glad you
corrected that then yes you were correct
then we've got a barracks of soldiers
waiting to deploy for when the bad bugs
if the bad bugs do decide to come back
around then we don't need to worry about
building our population it is already
there ready to go
you've got the troops all lined up
they're just waiting for the signal
they're just waiting for the little
bells and they could slide down the pole
like firemen and just get out there and
start destroying [ __ ]
keeps on going it says swore skis are an
excellent generalist and will actually
eat nearly all cannabis pests yes that's
absolutely correct that is why I like
the swore skis in almost all commercial
grows I use them outside in some
environments and I even use them in
small caregiver personal private grow
situations so big thank you for grow tip
number one if you guys out there would
like to keep your sworsky populations up
this person recommends adding a
poinsettia plant to the room and letting
it pollinate and those Swarovski's can
live off of that pollen while the bad
bugs are sparse now let's move on to
grow tip number two this is a good one
it says if seeds don't crack after 48
hours in a paper towel you can use a
seed cracker okay let's talk about that
when I germinate seeds I recommend
folding a paper towel you fold it once
you fold it twice maybe once more then
you soak it with water that's the way I
do it then I unfold it I put the seeds
about in the center of that and I fold
it all back up and then I will either
set that on a plate and a room or I can
pay attention to it or if I'm leaving I
will put it in a baggie and seal the
baggie the purpose for putting in the
baggie and sealing it is now I have kept
the moisture in there that moisture
can't disappear if I'm gone for longer
than expected those seeds will not dry
up and die we've talked on a previous
episode about how my stoned-ass
germinated a bunch of expensive seeds
went to work came home went to bed woke
up in the middle of the night and
realized I just killed a bunch of seeds
and I put them in a baggie that probably
would not have happened so I like to
fold a paper towel soak the paper towel
either put it in a baggie or put it on a
plate then you wait I like to unfold
that paper towel every 12 8 hours or so
and check on it see if I've got any
tails coming out of my seeds most of the
time those seeds will sprout within 24
hours they'll start making little tails
they look like a little sperm or a
little worm and they'll start growing
sometimes that doesn't happen sometimes
you get a dud and it just doesn't crack
this guy says that you can use a seed
cracker or you can also use scissors or
a pair of mechanical hemostats to
squeeze the seed until it pops the shell
but no further now to be completely
honest with you I do not have any
experience using a seed cracker
anytime a seed is not germinated for me
I've thrown it away and called a dud and
sprouted a new seed in hopes that that
one worked seeds can be very delicate
but if you've already tried to soak it
for 48 hours and it did not germinate
you don't have much to lose by giving it
another shot by using some sort of a
cracking method so he says once the
shells cracked I've had 100 percent
germination rate since trying the seed
cracker he also says I saw a member of
coastal seeds pops some 40 year old
seeds with the seed cracker may not need
to throw under seeds out and start over
if they don't pop right away yes that is
absolutely correct this could be like a
second chance if you do your method for
germinating seeds however you do it if
you soak them if you put them in a paper
towel if you put them in a rapid Rooter
if you just bury them straight in the
dirt
and it doesn't work you can dig it up
you can take it out of the paper towel
and this is another last-ditch attempt
to getting that seed to pop now I
wouldn't personally do this or recommend
this until it's been at least 48 or 52
or 60-something hours and you're sure
that that seed isn't going to pop under
your normal method I would make sure
that that seed has been properly
moistened I would make sure that it's
not too cold cold seeds won't sprout so
if it's a little a little bit too cold
it won't do anything if you make it warm
enough it should sprout right now it's
the middle of the summer so it's not
real cold so I would just germinate my
seeds here on the table I would fold the
paper towel up I would soak it put the
seeds in there maybe put it in the
baggie maybe not depending on my
schedule and I would just germinate
those seeds right here at the table
right where I hang out so I could check
on them I would see him I wouldn't
forget about him and they'd be just
right here part of my normal day if it
were the colder season and I couldn't
keep the house warm like it is now I
would put that baggie with those seeds
on top of my refrigerator I think that
heat from the top of the refrigerator is
just enough heat to germinate seeds any
warmer than that and you run the risk of
burning those seeds I've seen more
people just roast seeds I've seen more
people make popcorn out of seeds I've
seen more people just kill seeds with
the heat mat with some sort of a heat
source then I have seen success with a
heat mat so I don't recommend that they
will ruin your seeds unless it is really
cold in your environment I also don't
like to pop seeds in a humidity dome I
don't like the dome on there I think
that makes them a little bit weak I like
to have them exposed as soon as they're
growing out that way they can get some
wind on them that way they're not
expecting a bunch of humidity if you
germinate a seed in a dome it's
expecting that domed condition then you
have to slowly acclimate that clone you
have to let it realize oh I'm not gonna
have a dome for 15 minutes and the next
day you give it 30 minutes and you let
it go for a couple days and then you
give it an hour and then you give it two
hours and then finally it's used to not
having a dome but I don't like starting
a seed under a dome because then it
expects it why not just start it in your
normal grow environment where you've got
the proper VPD you've got a little bit
of airflow going on there's a little bit
of wind in there that airflow that wind
happening will give that plant some
strength just imagine when I push you if
I just gently walk by you and shoved you
by your shoulder just as a buddy not as
an [ __ ] just know
two on your shoulder just jokingly
what's up bro a little shoulder nudge
the first thing you do you spread your
feet so that you can get better better
balance I feel like when we blow on a
small plant just a little bit of wind it
tips over a little bit and it goes oh
[ __ ] I better get my footing and I think
it tries to reach out and it spreads its
roots a little bit further and it makes
it a little bit stronger I think a
little bit of a struggle makes
everything stronger if it's a plant if
it's a person anything a little bit of
adversity a little struggle what happens
when you lift weights when you do some
work you come back stronger I think the
plants respond the same way so I don't
like starting my plants in a dome and I
certainly do not like starting my plants
with a heat mat I prefer the paper towel
I prefer the baggie and I prefer the top
of the refrigerator if I'm going to use
any heat at all so do your best to set
yourself up for success when you were
germinating new or old seeds if you find
that your method does not work you've
got a back-up plan we can crack them
over some of the ways that our friend
mentioned we could crack them there is a
product called a seed cracker you can
buy he also said we can use a small pair
of medical hemostats to gently squeeze
the seed until it pops but no further he
also said you can use scissors if you
use scissors it is probably easier to
use the part of the scissors closer to
the handle then closer to the tip of the
blade there's just a thing about
leverage closer to the handle you're
gonna have a little more control it'll
be easier to pop it so get open the
scissors will real wide put your seed
down in there close to the handle then
gently squeeze
you'll feel a little crack it won't take
much pressure at all at that point
you'll feel a little pop now that seed
has another chance go back try to
rejuvenate it it should sprout and if
not that seed did not stand a chance in
the beginning so we've got another
option all right so I want to thank you
for that great tip there is more to this
email it says that is it for now
you may have posted these in an update
so I apologize if you have covered
either topic no I have not these were
great topics so thank you for the great
tips he says I am about halfway through
part 3 of the grow tip compilation
episodes and I wanted to write the email
before I forgot hey thank you for
listening to I bat long grow series and
thank you for sending the email I hope
that by the time this podcast comes up
you were all caught up so you get to
hear this right
comes out there is just a little bit
more to this message we'll wrap it up it
says love what you do and really enjoy
the podcast also I've been cultivating
for over a decade I like listening to
your grow tips as I can always learn
something new even when reviewing basics
sometimes I'll always be pointing many
new growers to this playlist as well
since it answers a lot of questions I
get asked on Instagram on a daily basis
so he's saying thanks for the podcast
man thank you for listening he's been
growing for over a decade and still
learns things from this podcast you know
what I was listening to somebody the
other day they were paying me to do
consulting they were paying me to give
them advice and they said something that
I said holy [ __ ] I've never thought of
that
and I pulled out my notebook and I just
casually wrote it down just in my little
notebook that I have for consultations
it looks like I was making a note on the
facility or something but I was making a
note on something profound that that
person had said that I had never said
out loud or never thought over never
heard before and I was like hole that's
really good information and they were
paying me to be there so never think
that you can't learn something from
anybody there's a brand new grower out
there that read a book that you didn't
read in one sentence it was really
important stood out to him and you
didn't read that book and he's gonna say
that sentence one day and you're gonna
go holy [ __ ] that person that I thought
was stupid know some [ __ ] and I'm
impressed so always keep an open mind
our friend here has been growing for
over a decade and still finds nuggets of
useful information in my little podcast
many mentions reviewing basics yes
sometimes reviewing the basics is very
important like I've mentioned in a
previous episode we had somebody with
the grow room issue they thought they
needed a giant consultation when all
they really needed was to take some time
and maybe buy a small piece of equipment
and find out what was happening in the
grow so yes remember the basics you
can't build anything without a solid
foundation so don't forget the basics
then he says he's going to share the
playlist with his friends and people on
Instagram because he has asked questions
on a daily basis I appreciate that I
hope I get a lot of new listeners from
you and I hope I am able to help you and
a lot of your grow friends he wraps up
the message by saying thanks for all
that you do keep up the great work I've
taken many fat dabs and given my mom
lots of hugs for you I appreciate
that is super cool of you he signs it
with Jack green stock so hey Jack green
stock thank you for the great message it
sounds like Jack has got a podcast also
make sure you guys look for that I'm
gonna give that one a listen as soon as
I am done with this show I'm circling
that right here on this paper and
putting it right in front of me so I
remember to do so once again big
shout-out to my friend Jack green stock
thank you for the great email thank you
for the great tips thank you for sharing
the show with your friends and of course
thank you for listening to the girl from
your heart podcast all right podcast
world I've got one more email right here
in front of me for this episode this one
comes from they've said their name
multiple times in the message we're just
gonna call them see because it doesn't
say if they want their name said or not
it says what's up my name is C and I'm
from yeah we're not gonna say your name
and your location both that's a little
too much but our friend is from a place
and he says I recently started growing
with my dad we have a few plants right
now that looked great and it turned out
pretty well so far I've worked at a
plant nursery for the past few years and
have always had a fascination with
plants specifically cannabis I've been
listening to your podcast for some time
now and I have a few questions that
hopefully you can answer well here we go
it says I am currently studying business
and I would like to change my major to
agriculture and/or agronomy what field
of study would best fit someone who is
looking to pursue a career in
cultivating cannabis secondly what steps
did you take when you first started
breeding and cultivating they'd have
brought you to the point where you are
right now I'd love to hear back from you
keep up the bomb ass podcast Thanks see
so our friend C is currently studying
business and would like to change their
major to agriculture or agronomy and
they are seeking advice on what field of
study I think would best fit for
somebody who is looking to pursue a
career in cultivating cannabis that's a
great question I don't have a clear-cut
answer because there are so many
different aspects to the cannabis
industry that I think having your
business education will be more useful
than any type of other education I could
recommend you have a passion for plants
you've already got nursery experience
unless you plan to enter
a facility as an owner or a lead grower
you were already on the right path
you've got just enough experience in a
plant nursery and you've got a
fascination for plants specifically
cannabis where as a candidate for me to
hire that makes you a great starting
grower you're the kind of person I want
to put on watering plants and I pay
attention to if you can follow
directions for a couple of weeks and
then I give you a few more tasks you
sound like a smart person you sound like
you can handle that stuff so trying to
aim you or point you toward the
direction of an agriculture or an
agronomy type of a school or an
education doesn't seem necessary you're
going to learn that and pick that up
along the way by being there what the
industry is lacking is business minded
people and it sounds like you probably
want to get into the grow you probably
want to play with some dirt you probably
want to cut some plants and pull some
leaves there are a lot of those people
available and unfortunately the pay rate
for those types of jobs is rapidly
declining as the cost and price and
value of cannabis declines as cannabis
becomes more regulated and more
available and you can just go to the
store and get it anywhere around here
it's getting much cheaper it is much
more affordable for the consumer but
that means on the business end there's
no profit which means the growers are
getting paid less the people who are
making the money are on the management
end the consultants the lead grower the
I hate the term master grower but that
is just a name for the person in the
building who is in charge of the grow
there are growers and then there is a
master grower it's the lead grower the
cultivation manager that guy he's the
one making the money the other people
are grow techs that are paid as hourly
employees but it's the management is
where the money is so if you want to
make money in the cannabis industry you
either need to own your facility or you
need to be in the business end of it so
unless you are completely set on being
in the cultivation side I recommend you
stick to the management aspect of the
legal part of cannabis there are many
things we need administration type
people for everybody needs a compliance
officer the compliance officer is the
person who reads all of the rules and
walks through the retail establishment
the cultivation establishment the
extraction establishment and makes
that that company is following all of
the rules in case any of the inspecting
departments may pop up because they can
show up at any time
the marijuana Enforcement Division can
show up any time they don't need any
announcements they can walk in knock on
the door and say hey we want to inspect
everything right now
they inspect everything if the
Department of Agriculture decides they
want to come do a surprise inspection
today at your cultivation facility guess
what Department of Agriculture
inspection happens to day they don't
care how busy you are they don't care
what's happening they need somebody so a
compliance officer is a great person to
have in every single facility it sounds
like you would make if you were talking
about agronomy it sounds like you were
already ahead of the game you understand
agronomics you already are thinking
about where to be it sounds like you
were a forward-thinking person we should
have you in some sort of a management
position making strategies thinking long
term moves we need to get you out of the
cultivation and get you up in the ivory
towers with all the other people weren't
suits thinking about the direction of
the company we need you helping to drive
the ship so I do appreciate that you
want to better yourself for the
agriculture aspect I think you're going
to develop that if you've got the
passion and you're already working with
plants it's going to come naturally
listen to my podcast expose yourself to
the garden be in there you will develop
all of the skills you need rapidly I can
tell by the way you wrote this email the
way your punctuation is perfect
everything is spelled right you're a
smart person now if you really insist on
being in the grow I think you are at
just the right level to get started
unless you're going to own your own
facility I think you were right at the
right area for me to hire you people
that know too much are a pain in the ass
to hire I wouldn't want to hire somebody
that was his experienced of a grower as
myself had to find the correct words to
say that in my head did not sound
egotistical but it would be hard to
retrain me to grow the way I need me to
grow in another facility if that makes
any sense you don't have any bad habits
that I have to break you can come in
just knowing just enough to be dangerous
and I can mold you into the grower that
I need you to be so that we can all be
successful in the facility now if you do
intend to be the lead grower or if you
want to own your own large scale
cultivation facility there are probably
large scale commercial cultivation
schools it will teach you about farming
and about agriculture all of that stuff
will apply to your cannabis cultivation
facility learn about Department of
Agriculture rules and laws learn about
pesticide rules and laws learn about
basic greenhouse growing all of that
stuff will apply to cannabis and as
cannabis becomes a big industry you will
be ahead of the game when you've got
college degrees for that type of stuff
when it comes time to pay people and
decide who gets the bigger jobs that's
when you get those opportunities if
that's what you want to do I apologize
that I don't know which classes to tell
you to take or which schools to go to I
did not do that stuff that is a great
way to segue into the second half of the
question you asked the second part of
the question is what steps did you take
when you first started breeding and
cultivating to have brought you to the
point where you are now you know I don't
think I saw this path ahead of me when I
started cultivating and breeding it all
happened in small steps just like it was
supposed to I don't talk about this a
lot and I'm not sure if I've ever said
this on the show but when I was a very
small child I had family members
illegally growing cannabis in our
backyard in California I its way long
ago nobody can get in trouble for that
[ __ ] now but I might have been seven or
eight years old
when I remember growing these plants and
I remember one of my uncles
telling my other uncle hey tonight
before it gets dark make sure you do
this to these plants and then he left my
uncle was like sure dude and the day
went on later on that evening it was
gonna get dark and my family was having
a conversation and my uncle said [ __ ] I
got to go out there and do these two the
weed plants and he said it wrong and I
said no dude he said to do this and
everybody looked at me and they said
[ __ ] he's right that's what they said to
do and so I kind of saved the crop is a
little kid I remember that kind of
vividly in my head and I wasn't allowed
to touch the plants then but I was out
there every time if they were out there
watering or doing something I was out
there with those ganja plants I was a
little tiny kid they probably tried to
keep me out of it but that was my house
that was my yard you know the little
kids just run [ __ ] you think that the
little kids are not running [ __ ] they
are they've got the ability and the
freedom to be all over the yard the
front yard the backyard the top of the
the back of a house because it doesn't
look weird if he was an adult go play in
that weird corner in the back of the
yard people notice you're their kids
nobody thinks it's weird so that yard
was mine but I remember they're like
seven I was like seven they were growing
weed way back then so that was like my
first step into cultivating and then I
was in another state where cannabis is
still illegal and I found out that a
friend was growing I accidentally
discovered his grow and I was like hey
bro I can see your grow and he was like
oh [ __ ] and then he was like well since
you saw it can you help me
he was like since you saw it you
obviously know what's going on because
it was pretty well hidden I spotted it
on accident he had a light leak I saw
the light leak it hit me in the eye and
I was like brothers a light leak right
there and he's like well should I need
help with these plants and so I helped
him then we harvested that together and
I used that experience that I had had
from my previous family members they
grew for quite a while I watched them
then I helped my buddy
then I was helping some friends with the
dispensary I'd been dabbling and growing
and I was talking about how I felt like
I had some better ideas than the grower
for that dispensary so they made me the
grower they're like okay then guess what
you grow now we fired him you take over
and I was like oh [ __ ] pressures on they
also gave me a bunch of equipment so I
set up some personal grows then that
compounded and expanded rapidly I became
known around my local town as the guy
that could solve the problems in your
grow if there was something wrong they
would call me they would come to the
dispensary where I worked they would say
after work I need you to come look at my
grower they would bring me pictures and
I would just politely help everybody
solve the problems in their gardens so I
got a very good reputation as being a
knowledgeable grower eventually that
dispensary was closed because of some
basically zoning reasons there are
dispensaries all around that bad [ __ ]
now but that was the very first
dispensary in my town it was myself and
some other friends they shut us down for
zoning white Mike was a big part of that
that is gone let's not dwell on that
place but that gave me a lot of exposure
and a lot of experience so I started off
as a young kid helping the family um I
evolved into helping and kind of taking
over a friend's grow in another state he
had an emergency he left I actually
finished his crop for him he came home
harvested a to cut it down we dried it
and cured it he split it with me that
was one of my first crops that I felt
like I kind of had a lot of control over
then I got my own grows going then I was
helping my friends with the dispensary
they kind of funded me with more gear I
got more grows going so at that point
I've had a few grows under my belt now
that I've got a dispensary grow to work
with and multiple personal growth of my
own to work with I'm getting a lot of
exposure to these plants to their
problems to their cycles I've got a lot
of rooms to play with now I'm getting
friends having me come over and look at
crops I made quite a reputation and had
quite a nice little following around
here when one of the larger dispensaries
was rebuilding their facility and they
called me and asked me to partner with
them I got to work with an architect and
an HVAC person and a whole bunch of
different people involved with the city
and building codes and I learned a
tremendous amount about building a
cultivation facility and working with
all of those contractors and licensing
people there was a lot to think about in
a lot to work with in that process
I learned a tremendous amount there and
got paid in that process so that was a
gift
eventually I parted ways with that
facility there were just some personal
issues I didn't get along with the owner
we are different kinds of people that is
all I need to say about that we were
completely different types of people I
have no problem with who he is he has no
problem with Who I am we just see things
differently so we don't work together so
I moved on I took over another grow in
another location and in that grow
I pulled 314 pounds out of 100 lights so
I was pulling 3.14 pounds per light I
was really gaining momentum there I got
really good at commercial cultivation
there I trained another staff at that
facility and then I moved on to another
place where I had a nice staff I had a
really large facility we built another
facility next door in the build of that
next facility I got to see and
participate in a lot of the work and a
lot of the meetings I got to learn a lot
again about HVAC installation about
sizing HVAC I got to learn a lot about
electricity I got to learn about
commercial cultivation construction the
planning I've seen all aspects of it
from the idea in somebody's head to
finding investors how to get the money
to do it to getting people to simply
believe in you to get it done - getting
the lawyers the
towns the city people the state people
the marijuana Enforcement Division the
Department of Ag the people who need to
put more electricity on that pole you
get to get all of them in the same room
I've been there for all of that silly
[ __ ] it is a struggle it's a challenge
but I am so blessed that I've been
involved in all of that because every
one of those little things is a step
that has gotten me to where I am now so
I saw that small facility expand to
become a larger facility I got to lead
that team I got to learn about
commercial drying and curing
I all of it I've seen all aspects of it
before I was even in the commercial
growing part I was a budtender doing the
over-the-counter part so I got to see
that aspect as well then I started doing
consulting for many other commercial
facilities so I have walked into many
facilities and seen how many places are
built I can walk in and tell you what's
wrong with the facility I can improve
your cultivation by 30 percent within a
certain amount of time guaranteed that's
what I do
so it's been many steps to get to where
I am today it hasn't just been like a
hey this happened it took a lot of steps
so that is kind of how the commercial
grow part of my career developed the
breeding was just passion you said that
you had a passion for the plants earlier
I simply have a fascination and a
passion for breeding cannabis I was
growing these plants for a long time I
started buying seeds like most of us do
we trade clones with our friends we get
plants from here and there and then you
start seeing that they're all seventh
out of ten and you want an 11 as a
passionate grower I don't want to grow
sevens I don't want to grow eight so I
want to grow [ __ ] out leavens all day
so I thought the only way I'm gonna get
anything better is if I order new seeds
and get new [ __ ] in so I got seeds I was
getting eights and nines didn't find any
tins or 11s I was like ah there's
something close here I'm just not where
I want to be and then a couple of my
friends were like bro it's not too far
before you start breeding and I was like
it's not happening I like growing I'm
focused on this then I was like you know
what I like this plant I like this plan
a lot it's really time to start doing
some pollen chuckit and I started
breeding my intention was to make seeds
for myself I made a bunch of seeds for
myself I started growing them some of my
friends were like bro that is awesome
can I have some and so I was giving
seeds away I went to a couple of
cannabis cups in Denver and I gave away
probably 5000 seeds over
two events just passing out packs of
five and ten seeds to friends and random
people and strangers and smokers anyone
who I saw with nutrients if they had a
bag of nutrients like they bought
nutrients or were given a nutrient
package at the show I gave them seeds
now you've got seeds to grow with those
nutrients it was a sign that they're a
grower I spread a bunch of seeds
um you can't expect to just start a seed
company it takes a lot of time to
develop a brand you have to develop
seeds those seeds have to grow people
have to see that it is something worth
growing you have to create demand mostly
it has to just be a quality product and
that comes from me being passionate I
keep going back to that passion the
cultivation part the knowledge the
experience that commercial aspect of my
career that all came from experience
from slow baby steps and exposure and
also doing a good [ __ ] job I talked
about the way to get into the industry
is to go be a trimmer or just show up
showing up is the first step show up so
I started off and show that I could do
it I was like man I can help you
transplant and I transplant like a
champion and then one day they needed
help bud tinning and I bud tendon
they're like dude you're good at that
and then eventually I ended up with the
keys to the whole facility it was
basically mine so baby steps get you
going showing that you give a [ __ ]
that'll get you there and it's like
going to martial arts or playing an
instrument or something you got to start
off learning your rudiments and then one
day you're doing paradiddles with your
feet or if you're doing karate you start
off they start you off in karate just
throw on the left punch Right punch left
punch right punch
ten years later you're [ __ ] doing
back flips and spin kicks it all starts
off in baby steps so that's how the
career aspect of my life got going then
the breeding the seed part that is all
passion that is just my love for growing
for breeding when you breed some seeds
and then you've got a handful of seeds
the real excitement isn't growing those
you get to see what you just created
that I just make the next chem dog did I
just make a bunch of duds did I make
something that tastes magical did I make
really amazing medicine for my friends
that are sick that I make something that
is totally a piece of [ __ ] I got to
throw it away that is so much fun to
find out it's a very similar feeling to
opening Christmas presents or even
better it's like opening up a pakka
a package of baseball cards or I guess
it's 2020 so they're [ __ ] pokemon
cards are Magic the Gathering car
now and you're looking to see what you
got but in cannabis plants you've got to
wait a little while so you got to make
the seeds and then you got to grow them
out and you get to watch and while
they're vegging you're paying attention
that one's a little taller that one's
kind of stretchy er that one's got some
crazy leaves and then when you start
flowering them it gets exciting you pull
out all the boys you're like Tim and I
was hoping that one was a girl cuz it
was pretty and then about week five
you're like oh look at the buds on this
one a week six it started stinking week
seven and eight you're like holy [ __ ]
look what I did I made amazing buds or
you're like look what I did there's a
bunch of duds but it's so much fun and
that's that all that passion that you
can hear in my voice when it comes to
talking about a Fino hunt of seeds that
I have bred that is what got me here
always staying passionate always loving
that plant and always breeding for what
I felt was right and not just doing it
for something that I thought would be
some kind of hype yes I was asked one
time to make a strain by another
professional breeder and his idea was
[ __ ] a hit it went very well for me
so I'm glad that he kind of recommended
or asked me to do that favor cuz in my
career that did help me quite well so
he's doing things that I thought were
right just following my heart following
my head try not to screw anybody over
try not to do anything from my ego or
from my wallet or anything like that or
for Hyper for fame just doing it because
I love it that seems to be what kept me
moving forward and kept me in this game
for so long and honestly right now I
feel like I'm at a high point and I'm
just going up I've never felt like my
company like I read genetics has had so
much momentum before it has until this
exact moment and I feel like it just
gets stronger and stronger every day and
then where that commercial side and that
breeding site meet is I get the ability
to run large batches of plants large
populations in other people's facilities
and see what they do that also gives me
access to many plants so that's where
the commercial and the breeder and the
passion side kind of combine and I also
believe in that phrase that people say
if you love your job you don't work a
day in your life or something like that
I love what I'm doing and it shows how
business owners grow owners dispensary
owners they can tell when I show up that
I'm excited and eager to get there grow
going top notch and they see it in just
a few days just a couple of weeks I
start turning the grill around so that
passion that
Ariane's has gotten me a long way so let
me recap cuz it you did ask a question I
just got off on a long rant I am not
sure what to recommend for schooling I
would say stay in business school that's
going to get you the farthest in my
opinion then you ask what steps did I
take I didn't know it at the time but
the steps were presented to me I don't
know what you believe in I don't talk
about that sort of stuff on the show
I follow Rastafari I think that job put
those steps in front of me and I was
wise enough to take the opportunities
that were presented and by doing what I
thought was right I ended up right where
I feel like I am supposed to be all
right let me get back on track because I
got really rambling here he raps this up
with I would love to hear back from you
keep up the bomb ass podcast hey I hope
you just listen to that long-winded rant
and I'm glad that you think the podcast
is bomb-ass I want to thank you for the
great email if anybody else out there
would like to send me an email I would
love to hear from you my email address
is grow from your heart at hotmail.com
don't be shy send me an email ladies and
gentlemen this podcast got long pretty
quickly so it's time to wrap it up I
want to thank you for listening I would
appreciate it if you find me on social
media simply find me on cannabis
cannabis is a new cannabis friendly
social media application
you cannot buy or sell cannabis there
but you can definitely post your
cannabis photography find me on cannabis
it's Irie underscore genetics I look
forward to seeing you there also check
out my youtube channel go to YouTube and
simply search for the growth from your
heart podcast click Subscribe leave some
comments on the videos let me know what
you think about the podcast maybe just
maybe I will read your comments on a
future episode ladies and gentlemen that
is all I've got for you for this episode
I look forward to joining you again
Monday with a brand new episode I want
to give a huge shout out to my buddy
aquaponics Steve and until next time
take a phat dad and give your mom a hug
for me