[Music]
yeah what's up ladies and gentlemen
welcome to episode number 45 of the IG
gr culture podcast the podcast all about
Cannabis News education and conversation
if you're a new grower a pro grower a
longtime cannabis consumer a brand new
smoker or just someone who's curious
about the current state of cannabis this
my friends is the podc for you I'm your
host rosta Jeff thanks for joining me
hanging out over to my left here is our
good buddy King Cola how you doing buddy
good man thanks for having me man I
started to choke right as I tried to
introduce you I apologize I stumbled
there I just took a big giant dab and
it's it's a it took about a minute to
kick in and it happened to be right at
the start of the
show wow turn down the music then I
won't have to yell wow across the tables
Adam how you doing bro good man tired
tired you're all
[Music]
redeyedeluxe decisions whatever religion
race Creed you are I hope you have a
great winter holiday hope you get a lot
of gifts if you're into the gift giving
thing I hope you give a lot of gifts I
hope you give twice as many gifts as you
receive B hug you're not into the
holiday thing bro no what if what if we
try to change that for you what we give
you gifts it give your kids some gifts
I've gotten I've gotten gifts that blow
my mind in the past couple years but
it's it's always like now I feel
obligated because I'm an adult and
that's the proper thing to do and I
understand that that's not what it was
about but um
yeah what if we just hold you down what
if we Bender is a great example Bender's
a great and kind person I see what
you're saying Bender hooked you up with
a fat gift and now you feels [ __ ] you
feel [ __ ] uh the people that uh are
able to give out kind gifts like that to
our friends that we know can't give a
gift like that we do it because we know
that you want that [ __ ] and that you
deserve it and we don't expect anything
in return you're going to [ __ ] play
with that you're going to throw that
thing he gave you he our buddy Bender
gave adam can I say he gave you a a
video card a graphics card for your
computer and you're going to love it
dude that's what it's about he's going
to see you smile sming and all [ __ ]
and giggled when you're playing with it
and that's what it's about it ain't
about you giving him back a gift yeah
absolutely and thank you you know yeah
so cheer up and [ __ ] enjoy the
holidays with us or we'll hold you down
and tickle you you know I I try with the
kids but it's hard how's it going to
make you feel when two grown men hold
you down and tickle you have you been
tickled as a grown man not since I left
Florida this just took an awkward turn
I'm going to try to put it back on track
um I want to mention something I
mentioned it's the holiday season iTunes
sent me me an email and they say that
there will be a delay in podcast posting
between December 22nd and January 5th
which will affect this episode and
possibly another episode I will post
them early I'll try to get them we're
recording on a Thursday the show comes
out on a Monday I'll try to put it up
like Saturday night and hopefully
that'll give iTunes time to do whatever
it is they're doing I'm not sure why
they choose to do that around Christmas
time people love it early they can love
it early yeah if it makes it it may not
I don't know what it's going to do also
I want to remind you guys we're going to
change the name of the podcast
eventually I said December 1st but I was
high I meant January 1st uh we're going
to start calling it The Grow from your
heart podcast because iow is actually a
horiculture agricultural educational uh
institution that does not want me
associating their name with our beloved
sacred plant so before they send me a
ceas and assis letter I'm just going to
go ahead and switch it up it's a
responsible thing to do it's kind I
don't want to rip off anybody else's
name you know if somebody else El was
called igro culture uh I'd be pissed off
about that you know and or if they were
called I genetics I'd be double pissed
so I got to be fair it's very Noble yeah
it's yeah you know just step down uh I
want to move your mic closer to you but
you've got yeah you've got that
beautiful Hitman rig in front of you
that you grabbed did you get that at the
emerald cup yeah dude that is sexy thank
you uh I didn't write down any space for
you to ramble about the emerald cup but
do you want to tell us about how your
experience for a second uh yeah the
emerald cup it was a let's get that way
that there you go yeah the emerald cup
was a great time um I'd highly recommend
uh All Growers to try to make it out to
that one uh best cup I've ever seen nice
that's a huge thing to say yeah it's way
different it's not as tongue and cheek
as the Cannabis Cup there's it's not as
stereotypical yeah so less of a less of
an RV Show and more of a Growers kind of
thing and it's in Santa Rosa California
right yes awesome so you flew out there
did you hang out with Baka a lot yeah
yeah me and him went out there together
shout out to Baka he's never gotten a
shout out on the podcast what's up James
sending some love bro hope we get to dab
sometime soon we keep talking about it
it just doesn't happen all those Growers
yeah all the Growers are hard to get in
one room together yeah I know and it's
like we went to Cali and it's like for
four days and you know it sounds great
but four days for a grower an eternity
I'm still trying to recover from that
[ __ ] and that third day you're like
going I wonder if everything's alive I
wonder you on the flight you're like I
just want to can you just fly over my
house I just want come on I want to see
if it burned down or something you know
you always got the worst ideas in your
head um Adam you've been working a lot
bro what you working on man uh just some
grow up buildings it's uh is it the one
that we talked about last yeah so for
the whole Denver Bud Company Denver Bud
company you guys are still putting that
together yep yep do you know how many
lights are going in
there more a lot a lot more than a lot a
lot and uh I would say 55 to 75 per unit
okay uh I don't want to give exact units
but it's still single digit units
so sounds like you're a busy man yeah
putting in the house there was nothing
there and the guy that was there doing
it um was there all alone and I mean I
don't know if you've ever tried to do
construction all alone but it's hard you
can't really do a lot of construction by
yourself you're just slow cutting and
doing and cutting and doing measure
twice cut once nail it up measure twice
cut once and then you need someone to
help it's easier if you got someone to
help you hold the [ __ ] right when he
told me I literally laughed at him I was
like
that's great uh but we you know that's
it's good job I can't I can't [ __ ] and
hopefully it holds out through the end
of the month cuz I really needed the
stuff for the kids in Christmas oh it's
good timing right good Christmas check I
I was kind of busy today myself dude
today I want to give a big shout out to
my homie Spence uh Spence and I have
been talking about me learning how to
make dabs because I smoke a lot of hash
and I grow my own herb I am sufficient
all the way from I can create my own
seed seeds I can germinate I can grow
the seeds I can Harvest it I can trim it
then I've got the product that is done
is flowers and trim and then I like to
smoke Dabs so I had to learn how to turn
that into the dabs I want today SP
Spence spent about four or five hours
teaching me how to do that we ran a
couple of batches I got to run some
tubes myself uh I've got all the way up
to uh the point when we put it in the v
oven I understand all of that and I
understand the back oven I just don't
know the controls on the oven very well
myself once I get that comfortable I
think I can make pretty good shatter
there's a batch of my shatter that I
blasted sitting in the v of and right
now waiting for me to uh check it out in
about 48 Hours Spence is going to flip
it because it's in his uh his facility
but I'm kind of proud I'm kind of
excited that's awesome yeah so we'll go
from seed to shatter it'll go all the
way from the germination all the way to
my Dabber now congrats all in housee
yeah thanks thanks well I don't know
about congrats yet I uh I've watched and
tried once experimental process yeah I
mean just trying to learn something yeah
uh getting out of the comfort zone I've
been really I I was comfortable I
realized I was comfortable for a year
like I I had IE genetics going I haven't
done anything for a year I've got I've
expanded and learned and grown but now I
got this new grow facility with 227
lights now I'm learning how to make hash
I'm definitely getting out of the
comfort zone yeah nothing's more
comfortable than just blast in a QP like
yeah see what happens see if I can make
Ash yeah throw down three ounces of your
favorite lemon Jeffree and just run it
and see what happens yeah my forearms
are a little uh there's a lot of work
involved yeah it's not as easy as you
might think uh speaking of me making
dabs uh this podcast is brought to you
by our good friends at Highly Educated
titanium if you're using high quality
concentrates made by rosta Jeff or
garden of Weeden or even this water hash
uh solvent list what do you call it Sean
uh full melt full melt hash that Shawn
made and brought over that stuff is
tasty and dank you deserve a high
quality titanium nail that's made right
here in America they're made in Provo
Utah by our good friend task Rock don't
trust a cheap Chinese nail don't trust
an American knockoff made of cheap
crappy metals trust the industry leader
the innovator the Kings trust our good
friends Highly Educated titanium make
sure you check out Highly Educated
ti.com for more information if you want
to buy yourself a highly educated
product or if you want to buy somebody
else a highly educated titanium gift you
should head to aqualab technologies.com
right now and place your order and get
that Christmas gift in for your favorite
Dabber I think every Dabber would like a
brand new titanium nail uh they've got a
nailed little fiter 14 and your 18 mimet
rig they've got one fit your 10 uh
you're 11 and you're 12 you can get a
carb cap to go with that I think that
would make anybody at this table pretty
happy if you got a nail and a carb cap
in the mail yeah yeah see everybody
looked at me like absolutely I don't
have one for you they've got cool colors
now they do have cool colors Sean's is
kind of is that purple or would you call
that pink purple this one right here is
a purple so yours is pink yeah well it's
pink though thank you got a pink one and
then I got a blue one too sorry I'm
spoiled guys I got multiple colors go by
your lady a pink dude there's nothing
you're manly as [ __ ] for carrying that
pink one around with pride and a pink
torch jeez this guy's dick must be huge
[Music]
yeah speaking of big dicks make sure you
check out Highly Educated
titanium. I also want to give a big
thanks to Adams right in front of me
dude thank you you helped me out a whole
[ __ ] Bunch you helped me transplant a
large number of plants and it took us
hours and I appreciate that also shout
out to Mike Mike helped a lot we got our
fingernails real dirty we got sweaty I
made these guys listen to Ree and then
we got tired uh and something really
weird happened the grow uh I blasted
panta as loud as it would freaking go
for a good album worth and that's really
out of character for me but it got us
pumped up we were a little bit getting
burned out and that panta really got the
mosh pit in the room going the point
where there's like where's the rest of
the work and there was no more work so
yeah it worked it went pretty quickly
you guys knocked it out so huge thanks
dude I could have done it took the three
of us most of the night so imagine
watching me try to do that myself as
I've said it's a learning process for me
so I'm going to do a couple quick ads
and then we'll keep this going I'm
trying to keep the momentum going in the
conversation this podcast is brought to
you by our friends at Natures green
remedies.com visit naturegreen
remedies.com for gag green genetics L
Plata Labs rare dankness mile high can
Adventure uh the Cali Connection and a
whole bunch of other sweet sweet
breeders uh Nature's green remedies is
running a special for our loyal podcast
listeners type in coupon code Frosty for
15% off any order and you always get
free priority shipping at Nature's green
remedies.com that coupon code is good
for any brand in stock but it does
expire at the end of this month so take
ADV manage this offer before the 31st uh
if you get some Christmas money or if
your girlfriend Andor boyfriend is a pot
grower or if you're trying to get your
boyfriend to grow pot uh go to
naturegreen remedies.com and order them
some seeds and give them seeds for
Christmas and that's like inspiration to
get somebody to grow weed I know that a
few of my friends are getting packs of
seeds so that they'll start growing the
weed they keep talking [ __ ] that they're
going to grow I'm going to grow weed one
day we here are some seeds now you got
to get on that [ __ ] and these are good
seeds don't let them sit around cu I'm
your friend and I know I gave them to
you I'm going to ask about them every
month how are they how are they speaking
of seeds I've given people huge shout
out to Maddie she's growing an
experimental strain I think I saw that
did you see that it's the uh the Girl
Scout cookies cross to the king Kim
grape stomper OG and she killed it bro
uh MD got her own little grow space over
at the Garden of Weeden and she put some
of my seeds in there and they look
freaking marvelous so good job Maddie
I'm proud of you they look great I got
to meet them uh the other weekend and
like I said it was a pleasure to meet
them there I got smell finally some of
the stuff that I've been looking at
Instagram for the past three months so
you want give Jesse a shout out for
absolutely Jesse you know thank you for
letting me and my wife get out of the
house for a change and you know putting
putting me to work so I can pay some
bills for sure and Thanksgiving though
he invited you to dinner yeah he he did
you guys got everybody blazed medicated
food yeah you have no idea you should
have came it's all right by the time I
was able to go it was wrapping up I was
like like ready to go thanksging was
what the phrase was by the time I wanted
to go they weren't giving anymore
speaking of Jesse this podcast is
brought to you by high gr indoor growing
supplies high gr indoor growing supplies
has two locations to serve Colorado
check out the Denver store 6271 Beach
Street or go to the Pueblo location on
618 East 4th Street in Pueblo Colorado
check out Hy gr for competitive pricing
and a great selection of indoor grow
supplies you guys hyro is small they
might not have everything you need when
you go there but they will get it
they're still building their inventory
they don't want to order a bunch of [ __ ]
they don't need and then try to sell you
that they'd rather wait until you go in
there and say you guys don't have this
and they'll go we didn't know you wanted
it we'll order it for you and we will
have it all the time now I can rely on
them once I say order this I said hyerim
and now they always have hyerim uh we
have kind of ran out the ogt company
it's taken a minute to get ogt in stock
but once they get it they'll have it
back uh what was I going to say when you
check out at hro indoor growing supplies
make sure you tell them you listen to
the igro culture podcast and you will
get commercial pricing that's good for
everybody just say that all you got to
do is talk who doesn't talk all day just
say some [ __ ] and you'll get a discount
I'm going to do one more ad cuz I got a
lot of cool stuff to say to Sean and
he's sitting here patiently twiddling
his carb cap like he wants to hear the
questions I've got do a do that there
you go uh Adam do a dab well he does a
dab I'll give you a little dab right
here and I can just ramble can I try the
live resum yeah that one's live right
there uh hook Adam up with one after
that yeah you got it all taken care of
go for that uh this podcast is brought
to you by our friends at tree Thugger
tree thug.com live music lifestyle
magazine check out tree Thugger dcom for
concert and Festival news and reviews
www. tree Thugger
docomo there will be some [ __ ] about
that on tree Thugger tocom I won't write
it but I know that that [ __ ] will be up
there because a lot of the hippies will
like it bro you can put the rig by the
by the mic nobody Minds hearing makes
them feel like they're there with us
listening to your
torch um also I'm going to read part of
an email I want to give a shout out so
that's all the commercials guys if
you're fast forwarding through
commercials you could stop right now and
just listen to this part I got to find
my
phone um I have a couple of notes on my
phone that I want to make sure I read go
ahead Adam you got something for me I um
I went on the forms the other day and I
was just looking through there it seems
like you're getting more response on the
forums as well uh it's not like a a
dramatic but when I logged in there was
only like x amount of users and now
there's you know a little bit more than
double I think I've done pulled and you
can't say just a little because every
one of those people I'm [ __ ] grateful
for I don't say there only 63 I say
there are [ __ ] 63 yay and I don't I'm
making up a number but I'm excited for
each one of them like I and he's talking
about the iy genetics Colorado website
Forum so that's I post a lot of stuff
there I haven't been there for like a
week because I got this new job and I've
been kind of scrambling to get a whole
bunch of [ __ ] done before I start there
but trust me I'll be back I live on that
website sometimes I want to give a shout
out to our good friend Jake Jake sent me
an email uh I kind of can't read the
whole thing because of some of the stuff
that he says he kind of asked me not to
say some stuff that he wrote but he ends
this with uh congrats on the new job and
keep up the good work you're doing your
part in making my 12-hour shift bearable
and for that I am grateful so big up
dude thanks for uh the compliments that
kind of stuff right there makes the
hours that I put into this show worth it
it makes these guys come in John puts
part of his day aside to come here and
hang out Adam has to break away from his
family Jesse's got a construction
company a grow business a hydro shop
these guys have to break away from their
lives so hearing these compliments
really lets us know that you're loving
it makes it worth it honestly makes it
to me and I'd do it even if you didn't
but it really it's like Yay someone's
listening so big shout out to Jake I
appreciate it bro that's pretty awesome
that you did that and I won't say the
rest of your message because you said
some cool stuff that I don't need to
say um I've got more stuff written down
let's get into the news you guys want to
talk some news real quick or do you want
me to ask Sean questions there's a lot
of stuff there's a lot of cool stuff
Sean will have an opinion on this I just
want to give Sean some room to talk he's
patient and quiet over there nice and
polite uh in local news I hope you guys
have an opinion on this it's not really
cannabis related but the Westboro
Baptist Church is coming to our town to
pick it at our cour house and at two
local dispensaries they're coming here
because our town uh supports gay rights
we have a uh a gay woman who is one of
our uh representatives and she's a cool
ass lady and I support her in every way
and the we uh Westboro Baptist Church
wants to come here and protest us
because we have gay rights here and then
once they're done protesting at our
Courthouse they're going to go to two
dispensaries and protest over there in
pbla West um I'm flattered you guys are
coming but [ __ ] off we don't need you we
are our own town we're adults uh what
are you going to do go worry about your
own damn town do that over there yeah
it's just hate I mean yeah it's hate
there people they're [ __ ] crazy yeah
and in my opinion no matter what
religion you are no matter what you
believe in I think be kind and love
everybody is what you're supposed to do
and they're being very hypocritical
they're not being kind they're not
loving anybody they're preaching hate
they're driving from another they're
driving from Kansas to come to Colorado
to show how angry they are at us I
didn't realize they were that close get
a life that's how I feel about that
absolutely like don't you have some [ __ ]
to do at home I bet that while oh I
can't be
presumptuous that's all right but I'm
gonna I'm going to play Devil's Advocate
do you think that while Mom and Dad are
here protesting that little Jimmy
smoking a joint in Kansas and little
Sarah's getting butt [ __ ] by Jimmy's
older brother definitely if not much
weirder [ __ ] going on because it's
Kansas right ex the brother and sister
are just getting it in the living room
while the parents are here protesting
I've seen their children that they have
hope their kids are getting gay and
smoking weed while they're here
protesting watching Duck Dynasty
watching Duck Dynasty watching porn
getting gay smoking weed drinking 4S MH
uh wearing camo saying the nword but but
not in a racial word call calling each
other the N word yeah it's cool yep like
it's cool I hope that's what your kids
are doing while you're here protesting
soon as you get home it's back to the
the polo shirts and yes Mama but I truly
am flattered there are a lot of places
for them to go and they chose here
because we have gay rights in cannabis I
just figured they'd running out they're
running out of places to go I don't want
to be offensive to a lot of people just
just the West I can't even say the name
of them they bother me so much but just
this one group they just piss me off I
know I've said a lot of R sh I kind of
wanted to know the name of the
dispensary so I'd be
like uh they're going to Marisol is the
first one they listed you know what I
think I uh took a screenshot of the
article here um because that's how I was
just saving news on my phone no I didn't
take a screenshot of the article but I
know they're going to marasol and one
other one uh and if you said the name of
it it may be pbl West Organics actually
but it was not the spot shout out to the
spot that's the spot that I would
represent they should go there that's
where the good weed's going to be so
that's our local news in bigger news
Colorado is being sued by I'm looking
for the article on my phone Colorado is
being sued by the state states of
Nebraska and Oklahoma have you heard
about this yet no not yet cool Sean's
lighton to join over there he looks like
he's ready for this story uh today the
states of Nebraska and Oklahoma
announced that they have filed lawsuits
against Colorado alleging that
Colorado's amendment 64 is
unconstitutional Colorado's Attorney
General John suthers issued the
following statement in response because
neighboring states have expressed
concern about Colorado grown marijuana
coming into their states we are not
entirely surprised by this action
however it appears the plain if's
primary grievance stems from a
non-enforcement of federal laws
regarding marijuana
as opposed to choices made by the others
of Colorado we believe this suit is
without Merit and we will vigorously
defend it against it in the US Supreme
Court so Nebraska and Oklahoma are
trying to sue Colorado because we are
not following Federal rule they're going
to try to force the feds to come in here
and clean up the weed scene that we've
created they're jelly all that money you
think they're jelly no I don't think
that but those aren't states that those
place they're not very popular in the
first place place I don't think they're
really worried about that yeah those are
places that pretty much lock you up
forever for having herb they don't like
it at all there no and I know it's
happening because I know people we read
about them getting busted all the time
people are definitely driving pounds
pounds and pounds out of this state
because we're able to produce it yeah
but do you really think it was any more
than before you know what I mean um
there there is more cannabis smaller
amounts uh well when more personal were
you here for the wild wild West
Revolution that I talk about when
everybody got a red card and there was
nobody to care to regulate it everybody
just grew yeah when I first got here or
at least when I first got here there
wasn't the whole badge system or
anything like anybody could I worked at
a dispensary and and you could grow I
could walk into your shop with a
backpack full of quarter pounds and sell
them to you right yeah so imagine if you
were getting here it was seven to eight
maybe nine if you could really Hustle
the shop for a quarter pound but I know
friends that will maybe send [ __ ] to the
east coast and they can get for that
same quar pound to their cousin that
live or their brother that lives out
there and they just don't give a [ __ ]
they're like why not and they'll just
send it or drive it out there and what's
to if you're a 20-some year old kid with
no kids what's guess my point of view is
just the the weeds it's either going to
come from California it's going to come
from Washington or it's going to come
from Colorado so I feel like the weed's
just going to be moving across those
States anyways regardless of whether
they sue us it'll just go right back to
wherever they were getting the uh the
solution would just be uh Nationwide
legalization you know medicine Without
Borders oh did we just start a new uh
new program medicine Without Borders
yeah just make it known that we'll just
drive around your [ __ ]
state they're talking about giving it to
uh convicts and stuff too spin your mic
a little towards your face please
they're talking about giving it to
convicts as well how rich you sound Rich
yeah you sound like you're up in there
get it I like it so anyways they're
talking about giving it to con we might
have taken a lot of dabs before this
show and I think that would help
yeah yeah convicts uh just in jail bro
just I think that what you saw was on
the onion and I don't think that that
was real I don't know Christy pointed it
out to me oh then yeah um oh yeah
consider your Source bro all right cool
I didn't read a source I [ __ ]
internet yeah he could be right but I'm
pretty sure well all I know is that I've
you know spent a little bit of time and
weed makes it all right it makes it not
so annoying the loudness and the why
weed cures depr helps with depression it
makes things that suck not as oh yeah
absolutely that's why people get that
have to work at Taco Bell all day get
[ __ ] blazed right before they go to
Taco Bell all day then when you try to
order your food I don't even want to go
off on that rant the guy at Subway the
other day was way higher than we were
and that's saying
something yeah there's a time in place
for that I've got an
article um I hope I saved it oh look
it's refreshing we might not have
internet service come on on
computer if that happens then we're
making a 45 minute video on how bad it
sucks I bet the internet sucks oh look
there's not another internet company is
there no oh no yeah we don't get an
option in our area we get one provider
so uh little less anxiety for medical
marijuana states on on a federal level
is the next article here it's from the
Cannabis and it's published December
12th and it's from Kyle Potter of the
Associated Press and it says buried deep
inside the 1,600 page funding bill
Congress is scrambling to pass to avert
a shutdown a few lines can for come
sorry let me try that again a few lines
comforted Minnesota officials worried
about the federal government cracking
down on the State's new medal medical
marijuana program I'm going to kind of
skim a little bit here because I want to
get to more of this stuff I just wanted
to read this one uh in its current form
the $ 1.1 trillion spending Bill
includes a section that bans the
Department of Justice from using federal
funds to intervene with states with
medical marijuana laws that that's the
best part right there I can almost stop
the whole article right there so what
that says is I'm going to read it again
in its current form the $1.1 trillion
spending Bill wrap your money name wrap
your head around that [ __ ] number
real quick $1.1 trillion but then it
says bans the Department of Justice from
using federal funds to intervene in
states with medical marijuana laws which
means they can't [ __ ] with us now I mean
they can because they'll find a way but
they're not going to mess with the
States they're not going to try to come
and make us switch our laws back they're
not going to I don't think they're going
to continue with raids there's still
going to be illegal growups there's
still going to be illegal stuff going on
that they're going to have
to it says 23 states have legalized
medical marijuana but those measures
still conflict with federal law and
though the Obama Administration has
generally been friendlier to marijuana
than administration's past mson Regala
wondered what if that changes or a new
president changes cour uh changes course
US House narrowly passed the funding
bill with the medical marijuana section
Thursday this Senate was is expected to
take it up
Friday so uh he doubts the bill will
marketly change the government's
handling of the issue uh most attorneys
have indicated they won't go after
medical marijuana business as so as
they're as long as they're following
state laws so the point is I think it
gives them a little more comfort and I
wouldn't say it gives very much more
Comfort but you never know he continued
the bottom line is it's still illegal
under federal law so anything could
happen but they don't have funding so
what are they going to do these cops
aren't going to go and raid [ __ ] on
their own time are they there was cop
California that did but I
mean then you're also if a cop's going
to go off and do that on his own time
without support he may be looking for
that lucrative income yeah that's not
going to fly in Colorado though no but
I'm just saying yeah it it sounds like
to me it's going to lead to bad to cops
all right so we've gone like 25 minutes
let's get into some talk about this
organic stuff I want to make sure that I
got through all the important part paid
all the bills yeah I'm good I'm caught
up I'm paying attention I got notes and
[ __ ] you guys this is like almost a real
show you wouldn't even believe it
episode 50 is coming up and I'm getting
excited starting to think about what we
can give away hey Jesse if you're
listening dude remember you guys kind of
volunteered to give some [ __ ] away on
number 50 we got to talk about that uh
so you're gonna say something go for it
we've been kind of like trying to figure
out what to give away nice so he's been
bouncing things off me and I've been
bouncing things off him and he's like no
tweet us let let us know what you want
uh if you guys are listening tweet me at
AGR culture or email me ulture
hotmail.com let us know what you want
for giveaway prizes and we'll see if we
can accommodate you so Sean's here the
guy that talked a whole bunch about cool
organic [ __ ] King Cola you guys loved
that show uh drying and curing and that
Organics episode have been my two most
popular episodes out of 44 episodes
awesome yeah people learned a lot um
people asked a lot of questions I can't
shout out everybody that emailed me
texted me uh tweeted me because I would
spend a whole show doing it but we got a
lot of response on that I want to talk
more about worm casting mostly because
that's kind of what seemed to be the
base of a lot of your stuff and a lot of
what got the conversation going um I'm
going to jump back we were talking about
worm castings we've got uh for basic te
you said worm castings in molasses and
you mentioned multiplying the protozoa
is something that you really stressed uh
so first of all I guess my main question
I should ask is what are protozoa uh
protozoa are just other
microorganisms uh in the Pro it's not
just the protozoa it's everything it's
all of the microbes in
there so you've got fungi and bacteria
and all of these beneficial things so
you're just going to give them a food
source and really give them a chance to
thrive and grow so all of those things
actually fall under the category of
protozoa uh no the protozoa are a a
specific uh I don't know what I can't
think the term right off of my head but
yeah it's just a certain microbe that
lives in the soil all right that's one
that I'd never really I'd seen the word
but I never paid attention until you
opened my mind to it actually I had a
wor so uh since we're on the subject uh
we have been feeding our worms we've
been substituting Alfalfa with cannabis
um nice yeah we were donated a little
over 3,000 pounds of what we call Canam
which is finely ground material from a
local o or actually I can open Vape are
you familiar with the company they sell
vapor pins um and organ labs they
donated the material uh by law by law
all dispensaries have to dispose of
their waste and unfortunately a lot of
people are just mixing it with old dirt
and throwing in a dumpster and then it's
going to a landfill uh we have been
feeding it to our worms kind of is a
test trial worms loved it uh they really
did we just sent or we just got our test
results back uh today actually and the
it was off the chart I mean it it really
was let's see what we have on here he's
searching you guys give him a second
bear with him he's digging through the
iPhone always takes a minute I mean the
Rocky Mountain worm company's definitely
been the conversation at work for the
most of the week anyways well that's
good to hear yeah he he really takes
pride in what he does and he feeds his
worms the highest quality everything and
that seems to be the important part it
really is you know he he he makes them
produce what you want you know
everybody's so focused on cost everybody
wants the cheapest casting out there and
they don't really understand that you're
only hurting yourself you know if you
want I keep saying if you're going to
cut cost on the grow then cut the cost
in the sale too ex and they don't want
to do that they want to cut cost in one
end and it's not fair yeah and with
these castings um you can take a compost
and cut you know 10 to 15% of the
compost and then make your own Verma
compost and then cut that in one part
Pete Moss one part Iration one part
vermac compost there's your base soil
you can add in your amendments like your
crab meal and your asite and kelp and
alala whatever you're going to add you
know there's your mix soil and it's
really that simple but uh Jay's been
feeding his worms uh cannabis plant
matter and they have been freaking
loving it uh test results were
astronomical uh comparably to running
the alphalpha the biological life was
off the chart I mean we gained hundreds
of
protozoa fungi bacteria um the active
fungi which means basically the things
that are working in the soil um before
we had a higher fungal content but that
doesn't really mean much if they're not
active we have a lower fungal content
but more activity if that makes more
sense oh you want more BioLife yeah this
stuff is so freaking biodiverse it's
amazing we're so excited about it so
feeding at cannabis made it better and
now you're going to feed that to your
cannabis feed those leaves back to those
worms Loop Growing System yeah I like
that a closed loop self-sustainable
system and we all got to get away from
the bottles um I've been reading more
about it since Sean kind of talked about
it and we're paying for shipping and
water that's what we're paying a lot of
yeah I was looking at the general
Organics label today just kind of going
over what was in it and it's it's pretty
amazing I mean there's just so much
stuff in the label for and there's
really not that much in the bottle it's
pretty amazing they got to preserve it
and they got to make it stable and it's
got to be chated or buffered or yeah
then it's got to be shipped and it's got
to be able to stay in different
temperatures and it's got to have a
shelf life you could just make it
yourself 24 hours before you yeah and
then it's use it you can smell it and
it's so much richer it really is and
then you're not throwing away plastic
for all the neighbors to see your
freaking botanic air bottles in the
trash can they don't need that um so you
talked about multiplying the protozoa
what's the best way to go about that uh
so basically you just need to give them
a food source so when you um when you
give like mix your tea up so you
basically what you're going to do is
you're going to add in your worm
castings and then you're going to put in
your food source and that's going be
using I'm going to back up just for a
second using a five gallon bucket yeah
so a five gallon bucket like a nylon or
something to keep all the stuff in uh I
preach free suspension te's especially
on a smaller scale I mean if you're not
doing anything over 15 or 20 gallons
anything throw all the [ __ ] right in
there you just throw it right in there
um and then Stir It Up and it's like top
dressing goes on kind of th you need to
Bubble it put a bubble yeah you're going
to want a bubble it 5 gallon bucket get
your hopefully reverse osmosis water uh
or at least uh let it bubble for a
couple of days get the air out and then
put all your your worm castings your
molasses and whatever else you decide to
put in there exactly we can you can
expand on it as you please we've talked
about a lot of cool [ __ ] to put in there
I hope you're paying attention yeah
basically yeah so you get your bucket
you get your airstones uh castings of
molasses you're going to throw that in
there and you're going to just want to
brew it from 12 to 24 hours I really
really wouldn't recommend taking it
anything over that if you're not
familiar with Brewing set it on
something you guys it's going to Bubble
Up and hopefully it's going to Bubble Up
huge and make a huge bub you do have a
big problem with the foam it's as simple
as dropping a little bit of the coconut
oil in there and then it's just gone
nice s did not know that yeah I've made
plenty of mess I used to grow in like
carpet and stuff like that I've seen
some of your pictures yeah yeah so all
right so we're we just want to feed them
and put them in a bucket and give them
some oxygen and they will multiply uh do
you know the ratio they multiply are we
going to get like 10,000 times or a
thousand times more you're going to get
thousands and thousands of times more
yeah it's pretty amazing uh check out
anybody who's listening that's
interested in this like Google micro man
and he's got amazing articles about Brew
times and how you can you know take them
longer for for more fungal dominant teas
shorter times for more bacterial
dominant te's how you can
actually uh kind
of cook your or inoculate your
ingredients for your compost tea to make
them more fungal dominant so you can
take uh your earthworm castings and
sprinkle in a little bit of oatmeal like
so let's say that you're going to use
three cups so I made for example I mixed
a 15 gallon tea earlier I use three and
3/4 cups of worm castings all right and
I knew I was going to use that much so
what I did is I took that three and 3/4
cup of worm castings and put it in a
mason jar uh added some oat brand
sprayed it with a water bottle and
sealed it up about two days ago and then
today I went down into my base B and
cracked it open and it smell sweet it
was covered in whiteo bacteria and I use
that for my tea and that's a way to
fungal charge the [ __ ] out of your tea
yeah it sounds like it wow that's pretty
sweet yeah and cannabis plants love
fungal dominance and so that's going to
make instead of those little scraggly
shitty Roots you see it's going to make
big thick white spaghetti for roots
right exactly I like to you know with
the when you do the free suspension teas
and you kind of get messy your your drip
trays will fill up with dirt you know
how it gets it at the end of the and
I've seen my root will grow right into
that dirt in the bottom of the pot me
they just can't get enough of it uh I'm
definitely I need to go so the storees
in Colorado Springs I live about 45
minutes away from there I'm going to
plan a trip up there quite soon uh here
within the next week I've got some
freshly transplanted stuff that I want
to feed some Rocky Mountain worm tea um
you keep talking about azomite do I want
I've always thought of azomite as
something I wanted to add during flour
do I want that in my veg phase as well
uh you know really it's just more for
flour if you're going to mix it in with
your soil um which most people will do
or they'll have some sort of amendment
similar uh in their soil that makes
sense yeah so I really wouldn't
recommend it until you're flowering
especially if you're you know not
transplanting really yeah okay all right
yeah these these plants I'm doing now
are going to finish in their little pots
yeah the asite I know a lot of people
who will do uh worm castings grow Kashi
and asite every two weeks as a top dress
I need to learn more about the Kashi
everybody's all Gro Kashi happy yeah I
think I don't know the grok Kashi is
really cool but I feel like a lot of
people are using it just to use it I
don't know if they really understand
what they're using it for the idea is
that uh it's lactic acid bacteria it's
photosynthetic bacteria it's yeast it's
a lot of other things going on in there
and you're going to introduce that into
your root Zone into your plant and the
grow Kashi will actually help digest old
root parts and
and things that are sitting in your soil
kind of stagnant
en exactly like enzymes W yeah I mean I
can show you how to kick that bottle of
hyro it's as simple as sprouting some
seeds Okay see there's something else
I'm going to learn it's going to take me
a little bit of time but eventually I'm
going to get away from all the bottled
nutrients it's a little overwhelming
it's funny cuz I taught Adam how to grow
mostly with full bottled stuff and he's
over there shaking his head like I have
to I saw the seed process the other day
and I it just clicked I compare it to
like cooking you know like when you when
you first start cooking and you look at
recipes online and stuff they're
freaking overwhelming because there's so
many things that go into it but once you
acquire once your you know your
cabinet's filled with all those spices
it's nothing it takes five minutes to
you know whip up a meal and it's the
same thing with the tea is it's
overwhelming at first but once you have
castings of molasses and kelp and hydro
slate and everything that you use it's
really nothing and then you're buying
all this things in bulk so you're
getting them at a fraction of the cost
without water weight for shipping too
yeah and you can buy everything locally
between Jesse at hyro and then Jay up
Rocky Mount worm company there's yeah
there's absolutely no reason to buy
anything online when's a good time for
me to drop in man uh Monday through
Friday okay yeah he's always up there
midday I like it that's about my style
Monday through Friday midday I don't do
things too damn
early but yeah he's always 11 to 11 to
one yeah lunchtime is when I do business
yeah you need to stop up there and check
out these Cana castings they're pretty
freaking sweet man I'm excited about
them yeah I'm going to I'll be up there
really soon I want to go get some stuff
oh man you sparked so many questions so
many questions I'm not sure which one to
pick I have uh I'll choose one from a
listener I got to grab my phone again I
feel like I'm the wrong person in this
damn chair I feel like if Jesse was here
right now he would have been all in this
conversation and I'm just sitting over
here like with my mouth open like a so
that's great man I I'm love hearing
about this because I see it around in
all the the growing footage and [ __ ]
part of my show is to bring the Growers
on your level and The Growers on his
level into one together because we're
not different uh I started first you
were playing guitar or being a
skateboarder or you probably play Xbox
way better than me you might MMA fight I
was growing weed while you're doing that
I'll help you grow some weed hopefully
when I want to learn how to MMA fight or
some [ __ ] you're down to teach me I live
back East there was nobody that was
willing to teach you and you know it's I
watched all the YouTube videos for many
many years so now being able to see it
firsthand and being able to have
different styles when I let you trim the
first time I thought you had a boner it
was It was kind of weird yeah I did
until the dog and then it was like it
got really weird yeah yeah when I gave
him that Grateful Dog he went nuts it
was stuff stunk so good wow what
happened oh I know what's happening I
hope that doesn't really affect the
podcast here cuz I'm get phone call and
it's popping up on my computer because
the new iOS no it's working the new iOS
8 likes to do that but anyway let's get
back on track here no dude I like having
you on because you don't have to be a
pro to be here you you might ask the one
question that the listeners are
wondering because we're Sean and I kind
of know what we're saying and we just we
get I've been told that we're snobs and
we just talk right over some points
because we expect everyone to know it
happens I mean we that wears off really
well too like it it's it's just I go
home and she'll have like oh this so so
and so gave gave us some bud and I'm
like I don't I don't want that yeah I'm
good now that you've seen some things
yeah we've kind of opened Adam's eyes
when Adam first moved here he would have
smoked anything I have smoked
anything yeah you know that guy that
cleans out your ashtray yeah and smokes
the stuff out of your ashtray it totally
be Adam Adam will do that yep all right
so we got an email uh actually this is a
Facebook comment from our good buddy
Fred uh Fred Garvin Fred likes to
comment and I appreciate it dude so this
one says haha shout out Jeff hey episode
44 was rocking dude I caught that tease
about the next episode and map and dap
I'm really interested in that I know
nothing about it except kushman
yammering on about it uh being bad on a
couple other podcasts but that's it so I
would like to know what it is is it bad
is it in my Cana A and B Coco and if it
is bad what synthetic new line should I
should I slwe be looking at anyway keep
the shows coming and stay frosty bro and
thanks for what you do so first of all I
want to say dude thanks for freaking
sending us messages uh partic ipating
and thank and Thanking us for what we do
like I said earlier that means a lot
yeah that was awesome that was a really
weird Echo did you catch that yeah
something went digital on me that's cool
it's back though yeah thanks for the
question and so that's a question for
Sean you were talking about map and dap
yeah so map and dap is uh let's see if I
can say this right it's mono ammonium
phosphate and Dio potassium phosphate or
something similar to that I'll give it
to you yeah um but basically yeah
they
they chemicals that are used in
basically every single Hydro product or
synthetic nutrient product on the Shelf
uh they're synthetic salts
uh the big problem with them uh in my
opinion is they don't flush out of
plants I I you know I don't think that
you can get them out uh heavy metals and
things like that are stored in the
triome so once you kind of get them in
there there's no way to get them out and
if you're blasting you're blasting those
heavy metals into your mix exactly and
that's you know I kind of mentioned
azomite a couple of times and asite is
one of the things that's filled with
heavy metals so you really want to be Li
you know you don't want to use too much
of that stuff uh glacial Rock Dust
filled with heavy metals so it's not
just or synthetics you know that are
filled with these things but mono uh map
and dap are probably the worst of all uh
just in the simple fact that they're the
most common and it's easy it's something
easy to look out for I'm not telling you
to like run away from the map and D but
it's if you're somebody who's interested
in a cleaner product something that's a
little bit more
organic uh you know you need to become
familiar with the terms that you need to
look out for and those are some of them
you know if you're looking for a nice
organic Pro product look for something
with like uh soybean meal or kelp or
alala Brewers East or Soul synthetics
offers stuff like that yeah soul
synthetics is a killer line so good yeah
biob Biz is especially if he's running
Cana I mean if you're running Cana then
you know biob Biz is an organic nutrient
line that's very similar style of
growing uh really high quality stuff uh
or grown on Instagram I don't know if
everybody probably follows that guy he
straight crushes it all bi aiz um I
don't know if he really talks about what
he uses but a lot of us don't talk about
it on on the Instagram Fe I'm going to
call him out because he's got amazing
[ __ ] and he's using Organics and he
deserves to be called out on it yeah if
you're using Organics and getting good
progress that's deserve to be noted
congratulations on that one but yeah the
biob biz is a really good one to use uh
General Organics that's you know that's
another one to use that's really good
but you know to each his own I don't
use things like that there's what's the
big one on the market right now Moab
yeah you know the mother of all blooms
yeah you know you know what Moab is is
just MTH
if you look in the ingredients it's like
99.9% map so I'm not going to sit here
and tell you that it's like going to
kill you or it's bad for you but it's
one of the things you want to look out
for if you're an organic grower so it's
just printed on the bottle as
monoammonium phosphate yes okay so if
you're looking for it that's map and dap
is the Dio ammonium phosphate it's very
similar the D so if you're trying to
avoid that that those are the two to to
stray from and uh I know I'm just paring
what kushman says but kushman says that
that's often what gives you when you
smoke good weed and for some reason you
get a headache and you're like that was
good herb why did it give me a headache
it had map and dap residuals in it I
can't prove that but that's what kushman
has led me to believe from everything he
has said and I mostly trust kushman
there's no reason not to trust kushman
in my opinion he smokes a lot no he's
he's the he's kicking ass and taking
names with his veganics right now he's
won a couple of cups
um so he really knows what the plant
wants yeah I'll take his word for it
yeah
uh do you recycle your soil yes did I
ask you that in the last episode uh yeah
I don't I don't like to recycle my soil
okay I really don't I do it because it's
cheap um I really don't if I recycle my
soil I like to use it as a in my veggie
garden
but I just I haven't mastered that yet
okay um I always see a loss in yield no
matter what I do I've blamed it on other
things and haven't attributed it to that
I'm thinking that these worm castings
are going to help me out that problem
yeah and I and I'm having better luck uh
starting with sterile Medias you I used
to run like Happy Frog and roots and
stuff like that uh switched it up to
more of like a promix base got a lot
better results out of that now I'm
running my own like Verma compost Pete
Moss and buckweat hole with amendments
and stuff but the promix and stuff I'm
getting better results with reusing the
soil it's a lot easier to amend it at
the beginning it being a sterile media
okay um I can write down how much of
what I put into it and basically if my
plant doesn't show a deficiency
throughout that cycle I just REM
everything like I would you know a brand
new soil mix and grow right back into it
whereas you know Ren the fox farm and
The Roots organic I feel like with the
guos and the blood meals and everything
that's already in there plus me amending
it by the end of the cycle sure that
might not have been of any deficiencies
but I really don't know where that
soil's at yeah so that's kind of where
I'm at with reusing soil uh using mix so
this is kind of what I found to do with
I've been doing with my soil lately so I
take it and mix it with the stuff out of
my Bashi bucket uh like all of the slimy
leftover pickled trash that ends up in
your Bashi bucket so I just mix it in
with my soil in a tu looks like you're
making him
hungry you do that [ __ ] I'm not doing
that I'm not doing that is so you just
dump it out into your uh you know into
like a Rubbermaid container fill it up
with dirt and then just let it sit and
then basically you know in a couple of
weeks or a month or two or whenever I
get around to going back to those
buckets um it'll be compost and then
I'll mix that with worm castings and use
that as a vermac compost for my soil so
you're using up a lot of space aren't
you uh not really I just pictured a lot
of space when I'm think about Gage I
have I have a garage and I don't park my
car in it yeah so that's where I'm
storing everything nice yeah I do crazy
[ __ ] so other people don't have to if
you have any like weird experiments you
want to try and you don't have the space
just email Jeff and he'll let me know
yeah there we go and I also have a
friend in California who wants your bugs
yeah uh yeah if you've got a plant with
bugs he wants you to clip off a leaf of
that or a branch of that plant and send
it to him so that he can play with the
bugs that's his specialty that's cool
yeah Treet town what's up bro I hope
you're listening Treet toown farmer yeah
I met a guy at the cup who uh does
something similar with microscopes he's
been through a couple of elain Ingram
courses and uh he's like yeah send me
your soil send me your tea we'll get him
looked at [ __ ] yeah some people are
hardcore man you got to find your Niche
yeah yeah that's the truth Adam's a good
little uh transplanter and grunt worker
he does some [ __ ] in the gardens I just
worked to get it done I walked in the
room and him and this other dude had
dirt flying three feet in the air and
all of it was Landing into pots I don't
know how it was working that's how you
learn I don't know if Mike knew what to
think about that that's all right no you
definitely work at a different pace than
what Mike us doing it's fine he picked
up he picked up he was fine yeah uh what
should I not use in my Organics that's
going to be my last question for the day
uh you know it's depends on your level
of like you know your dedication to
Organics but the first thing that I
would kick out would be blood meal and
bone meal okay uh if you really care
about Organics chances are you don't eat
GMOs and you don't eat I'm not going to
say you're a vegetarian if you're you
know if you're into Organics and stuff
but those things are byproducts of like
the you know slaughterhouse industry
feather meal is a byproduct of the
poultry industry all of and they have
their place don't get me wrong because
I'd rather them be recycled into
agricultural byproducts for farm and
other agricultural uses but when it
comes to Growing medicine for people I
don't believe that feather Meal made
from chickens that were fed you know
antibiotics and hormones should be used
to grow it same thing with the blood
that scraped off the slaughterhouse
floor to make the blood meal it's just
this gelatinous goo filled with
everything that there was in that cow uh
bone meal same gig so if you're going to
use things like that I would just
recommend there's other Alternatives you
can use things like fish blood meal
alala kelp I mean there's a lot of plant
baits um if you really want to get into
it cfree and berock root and nettle and
dandes and you know go out in the woods
and pick a bunch of [ __ ] am I going to
come back from the Rocky Mountain worm
company with a whole back seat full of
brand new [ __ ] and rethink my whole
growing method the first time I go in
here you probably will and and the cool
thing is is you're going to you'll
probably see a couple of things that
you've seen at Jesse's shop too okay and
when you see those you know might click
with you like well maybe I should pick
those up next time okay you know shout
out to if you're going to be going up to
Jay's check out the C crop uh that's a
little secret product that I use in my
garden I was gifted by Jay a long time
ago I think you're the second one to
tell me about that [ __ ] is awesome yeah
it really is I think our buddy Spence
had some of that does he really maybe he
might have picked it or Jay might have
given him some of it or I don't know but
I use it to basically replace my full
power or if you're if anybody out there
is familiar with full power or fulvic
acid or humic acid I use it yeah and
replace in place of that okay there's
scientific studies I hope you'll be
there when I go yeah the fungal oh yeah
just give me a call I'll be up there
I'll meet you cool I'm I'm not sure when
I'm going yet but you know I'm always
looking for an excuse to get up to I'm
going to go find one more gift for the
girlfriend so I got to sneak away while
she's at work and sneak up there and get
some worm castings one more gift for her
speaking of gifts if you guys want to
get a cool gift for somebody come and
get the like a bkash bucket uh worm you
know home worm farm guys I need one of
those can I ship it to
Australia help be your grower be more
self-sufficient come by Rocky Mountain
worm company H you up uh Rocky Mountain
worm company they listen to the podcast
cuz they said they liked it hey guys uh
I'm going to come get some warm castings
and we should talk about some
sponsorship sort of stuff because people
seem to be responding to you and I want
to support semilocal [ __ ] you're
Colorado you're Colorado Springs that's
not Pueblo but I still love it i' like
to support that let's see if we can do
something uh I'll brag about worm
castings and you uh Supply me with worm
castings I think they might be more than
happy to work with you man yeah they're
big fans they love sh cool I appreciate
that well they're doing a great thing
I'm excited to get in there and learn
about it um man we've gotone 55 53
minutes let's uh start closing up the
show dude I got to have you back on more
I like what you we get sidetracked cuz
we're heads but I like having you on and
you have a lot of useful [ __ ] to share
with us yeah yeah and then send anybody
who has any questions uh send them to
Jeff and get them to send them to me
we'll have him ready next time and we'll
just we'll just slam through them but
yeah I'm [ __ ] high yeah we we took
solventless dabs we took live resin dabs
we took shatter dabs uh Adam looks
dabbed yeah I feel like I'm just tired
as [ __ ] man this delicious year bam mate
is keeping me up yeah shout out the the
mate Factor also big shout out to sweet
Angela for getting me addicted to the
yba mate I love you babe but jeez that's
mate I don't know what you've done to me
you've created a
monster Monte is so great the best idea
we had though was buying bags to bring
it home and make it so now we don't have
to drive to our favorite mate spot in
Colorado or in manat Springs every time
we want mate because we would do so yeah
but it's a great excuse to get up there
the place is freaking awesome uh I hate
to say it I'm more comfortable in manit
2 Springs than than I am here in PUO
when it's starting to get bad here man
it is kind of yeah it's a little
gangster here but I have I feel like I
have more friends that are more open to
go do [ __ ] in manitu nobody wants to go
out of their house here because it's
it's weird here there's nothing to
really go have fun at you can't go walk
in man you can just go walk and enjoy
the day shout out to manitu Springs it's
a fun time yeah it is um anybody got any
shoutouts anybody you want to say you
love to you love them anybody anything
like that you guys it's the boy's
birthday it's the boy's birthday happy
birthday little little miniature Adam y
I've seen pictures of him on Facebook
riding his skateboard and [ __ ] bro he's
going to be just like you when he grows
up yeah give we got him a Genesis I want
to give a shout out to my girl Kelly for
holding it down while I was in
California she took care of the grow
kept the plants healthy and I know she
was pissed that I left so I love you
baby sorry about that I'm constantly
trying to talk my wife into just
learning that like the ability to take
care of something if you walk in there
and go why is everything all
droopy they they they take they take in
a lot more than they let on like I never
thought that my girl could do it but you
you know given the chance you could
probably make a tea better than most
what's up Queen Cola it's been a long
time since I've seen you hope you're
doing well we used to take dabs together
over at MD's that was fun hope you're
all right hope you're doing well hope
you're smiling good job on holding down
the plants I got to give a shout out to
my chick if we're talking about that my
chick knows her way around to Garden bro
uh if I need anything done she can
definitely do it oh here goes my phone
again dude I just mentioned her and she
started calling te Rumple still again
yeah yeah all right Adam uh you shouted
out the boy anybody else uh just Bender
man running the servers yeah running the
servers Jessie Jessie Jessie dude you
paid my bills brother like but you work
too so you know it work no I'm I'm there
busting my butt but it's just yeah all
right thank
you wow phone ringing oh nice got off
work early we might have some food cool
let's wrap up the show uh now the show
is over please go to iTunes or Stitcher
go to the iTunes store or the stitcher
main page search for igro culture find
the review section give us a a festar
rating you can give me as many stars as
you feel like honestly but what I want
you to do is type in a comment and let
me know what you think of the podcast
and I will read your comments on the
show don't forget that the show is
available on iTunes Stitcher and every
single episode is archived on iry
gentics colorado.com make sure you
follow us on Twitter Instagram and
Facebook just search for igro culture
follow iy genetics on Instagram I had
10,000 uh followers but then they went
and did some cleaning up now I got 9,500
so give me back up to 10,000 followers
that'd be cool uh if you're interested
in sponsoring the podcast or if you have
a product you'd like us to review send
me an email at ulture hotmail.com and
I'll get you all the information you
need uh we are going to change the name
it's going to be the grow from your
heart podcast you'll still be able to
find it I'll advertise we won't go away
it'll just be a different title uh we do
need a theme song and a new logo if
anybody started working on that
one um big shout out to everybody that
keeps listening be prepared for episode
50 because we're going to do some
giveaways there'll be some at least
stickers Jesse mentioned some things
from the hydro shop m um there'll be an
iy genetics t-shirt in there maybe a hat
pin we'll see what we've got available
maybe some uh Jenny Kush prizes that
I've had around for a while that nobody
claimed back in the day I've got a Jenny
Kush pin that needs a home anyway guys
keep listening to the show I really
appreciate you for hanging out big shout
out to my ninja Spence he taught me how
to make hash today you teach a man to
fish bro oh man yeah it's on now game on
big shout out to you guys for coming out
these guys will be back on the show yeah
thanks for having me thanks again for
listening you guys until next time take
a fat dab give your mom a hug for me