hey what's up podcast world welcome to a
very special episode of the grow from
your heart podcast I don't know what
episode number this will be or if it
will even have an episode number if
you've been listening to my show for a
while you know that I am friends with
another podcast known as the dude grows
show I was recently invited by Scotty
real of the dude grow show to go to his
studio known as the bakery to record a
podcast I feel like the podcast came out
very well we had a very good
conversation we had a very good time and
it was a very good episode
so with Scotty's permission I'm going to
repost the episode of the dude grow show
right here on the Grove from your heart
podcast feed so that all of my friends
and listeners can hear the podcast
interview that I did with Scotty real if
you're not already following the dude
gross show please give them a subscribe
on YouTube or iTunes I highly recommend
their YouTube channel because they put
out very high quality video content
ladies and gentlemen boys and girls
smokers and growers with no further ado
let's jump right into the dude gross
show featuring Rasta jeff of high region
etics what is up DGC scotty real hanging
out with one of my good friends Rasta
Jeff I read genetics came to visit for
our trip you're a badass brother thank
you brother thank you for having me
thank you thanks a bunch man everything
we do you support and I called you up
for the concentration celebration the
seven ten and he said I'm in there
brother who's my honor to to help get it
going I was involved behind the scenes
that was an honor when you say you're
gonna do something I want it to be a
success I feel no competition in
podcasting it's one community we're
going to do the same thing for everybody
we want everybody to grow the dank
absolutely want to legalize and we want
everyone out there smoking the best so I
think we're a team we're on the same
team I know that I love and respect for
the DDC crew and the show so thank you
thank I can't even imagine that somebody
would just listen do you know how burnt
out they would get of just listening to
me they would hate me or just me variety
is the spice of life
oh it's truth yeah man go from your
heart podcast for get an awesome show I
do dig it
but dude let's talk about breathe and
let's just stop this is hangman anything
at everything you want to talk about bro
we've been telling a pretty good friends
lately man so we're getting to know each
other a bit more with definitely kindred
spirits so I agree yeah but we got
different skill sets brothers from other
mothers I love it I love it
but way different skill sets like
remember I said I want your nose cuz you
you can actually smell absolutely
terpenes yeah a lot of people tell me
that lately they want like Turk nodes
that's awesome
that's awesome alright so I want to ask
you first off I did want to start off
with breeding because I have a feeling
it relates to your sensor ease your
sensory perception yes yeah what me
first off if I'm just looking at
breeders so what makes a legit breeder
what what makes a legit breeder yeah I
may frustrate some people here I call
myself Apollo just cuz I'm humble you
can excuse that um a legit reader
somebody with a goal so I'm gonna do
when you start off breeding you have a
goal which not is which is not money
right a goal which is to create a line
that is improving something or maybe
you're growing strain a and strain B and
you want the flavor of strain a and the
vigor of strain B right you've got a
goal not just put a bunch of elite cuts
in a room and a mail and sprinkle some
pollen and then sell those seeds sure
that's a pollen chucker that's an
[ __ ] that's somebody up for profits a
breeder is somebody with a goal then
once those seeds are made you have to
test them you can't just make seeds and
put them out sorry about the throat
clearing we got dabbed out we did by the
way
right as well I was asking you about
he's got the rig and the torch and
everything I'm like come on man just hit
a knee now it's so [ __ ] easy and we
all hit a dab and each one of us one dab
and we're stoned yeah the whole room is
a little lit it's nice but yeah it is
different I you know even smoking out of
a pen or even those little cartridge
pens you just don't get it stoned just
waiting to just take a [ __ ] full-on
torch Devin and I agree that's why I've
got that rig with me almost all the time
yeah and now that's travel piece and
that's cold starters that we can insert
damn I call it an insert I've heard it
called a few other things but right I
put the dab in a basically a glass
thimble and then heat the banger and
then drop the thimble into the banger
and cap it right it works kind of like a
double boiler instead of my dad hitting
hot glass it gets to heat up slowly
it's like as it comes to temperature and
sure scolding hot dabs dry
to the lungs they're still warm I like
I'm kind of hot but right just come it
bubbles up you can watch the dab bubble
and it comes to temperature instead of
just instantly yeah I seen it was
awesome it works better you get a lot of
drawers off one good dab yeah really
nice - love it everybody in the room is
baked yeah got me going so we're just
gonna [ __ ] a little bit man really
good at that since we've declared we're
all baked we're just gonna [ __ ] a
little bit we're good at that
so dude first off I want to know I read
genetics ever since I've been you know
in the DGC I've always known you guys
existed but you guys are when you go pro
I'm gonna ask I didn't know we did it
just seemed to kind of I took I just
followed the steps and I seemed we're
supposed to happen in life as well
whereas a breeder at all just kept
coming to me naturally and I would see
opportunities and some I had to decline
and some I knew were right and one day I
was here doing this I don't know that
this was the exact intention you can
tell what I obviously believe in the
colors I wear hair style that had a lot
to do with it I just listen to the steps
from above and followed the path it was
light in front of me and I think I'm
right where I'm supposed to be and just
you'll say where did you get the skills
most of that I think comes from passion
I love cannabis I've got crazy
ATD and when I smoke that seems to stop
there are seven thousand thoughts
happening in this crazy brain of my
shirt so when I smoke I can hear five of
them really clearly I'm so advantageous
for my life it just makes all that
background chatter stop and then I can
function mmm excuse me again so then I
started smoking a lot right in I think
like most of us I got tired of paying
for it so I wanted to grow my own and
then I wasn't satisfied with the clones
and the seeds I was getting so I started
making my own stuff and then how long
ago is this probably before I should
admit there weren't legal cannabis when
I first got into it but as soon as we
were able to get more rooms and more
space I was up in breeding and doing it
nice 2008-2009 okay blow
yeah and for that in other state and you
were breathing though you had the
foresight to brow is just super psyched
to be able to find a cut in two thousand
eight thousand nine I was lucky to be I
had some good friends who are ahead of
the game I had some friends who came
from Calif
four new ranked in North Carolina who
were growing out in the Hills for years
the rise I had friends with Oaksterdam
University teachings who brought cuts
from Oaksterdam but I got a hold of so I
just fell into the right circles I feel
like I was really blessed that's why I
say I just followed the steps that were
laid in front of me and write whatever I
believe in put me right where I needed
to be yeah that's interesting okay so
that's how that makes you pearl
it makes you pro because you've been
doing it first off for so long and then
you've got such a good reputation now I
appreciate that oh yeah yeah I mean it's
a fact but so what are you saying oh I
see all these people I get people
handing me packs of seeds all the time
and I don't know what to say I don't
know what to think about them and you
know what he wouldn't I mean I don't
know what do you think about when who
would call you when you would call
yourself professional if you're a young
breeder oh that's so I guess that's up
to you when you're when your seeds when
you know that everybody growing your
seeds is not having a problem right he's
a big sign people are reporting
hermaphrodites if they're complaining
right not professional yeah I just see
it's such a trendy business and I see
people always trying to just throw
something and throw something out there
and that's that's hype that's instant
success but also you don't see those
people around I'm here for a little
while when when I was trying to get on
seeds here now he said one of the things
that brought him me to his attention
right I've been around for a while and
he said I've seen you you haven't been
here for just two weeks you're out of
these new pollen chuckers yeah that
makes a difference those guys just
throwing pollen on hype strains they
won't be here for two or three harvest
you'll see a bunch of homes come from
them people complain they'll disappear
but you do here I mean there's guys I
think who was the bubble guy there's an
alien guy rather shoot we just gave away
some of these seeds last week I know his
name and it's killing me it's a it's a
funny name but anyway so he's known for
something specific right right known for
that alien yeah yeah so you're known for
a rise is that what you're saying you
rise would be my high potency regular
line that's right not available in fence
oh game line that's popular would be the
lemon Jeffrey that's so I've got a
regular and a feminized line arisal
image out for me yeah so we're ok so
we're talking first off I want to get
into feminized the little guy so we'll
hold that for one second because I'm
just thinking about being a breeder
and I'm on [ __ ] I was I'm laughing
because it seems like it's a license to
print money you're like they're just you
know put calling on there you come back
and you got hundreds of seeds and you
sell them for five packs for a hundred
bucks or whatever but it's not like I
was talking to James being our friend
James bean seeds here now huge supporter
go get your seeds over there please do
yeah but I was talking about just so
many obstacles just about trying to do
business how discrimination there is out
there right oh you've even it's CBD you
say the word CBD and he gets a scrim
native customs book shut down your
Instagram yeah it causes problems
quickly yeah man what would you say man
if we're looking at obstacles obstacles
about being in this business some
unforeseen things your social media is
gonna be a struggle a lot of people
think they're gonna advertise on social
media my social media gets taken away
all of my friends social media if you
post pictures of plants if you say the
wrong stuff social media goes the
YouTube channels our friend Colin his
video has gone from your feed yeah and
what does that someone hater one hater
says something yeah that's all it takes
I think it is all a case man so just
simple things like that then social
media we take that for granted I come
from an era where we didn't really have
that right like when I started doing
this we weren't supposed to be doing
this so for me just to be able to post
my pictures feels kind of it feels like
it's a special thing so I feel yeah I
understand when people say they're
lurkers like I've been lurking for a
while that was me yeah here's my weed
I'm proud yeah this guy's in my IP
address before I should have overgrow
yeah I've got my face and like giant
bugs yeah that's where you can buy it
and we don't at all I love it that I
feel like we're really taking that for
granted now we feel it's really a huge
privilege I didn't have that back when I
was starting this obstacles as a seed
breeder there's a lot of work to it
you've got to become relevant you said
people it's a license to print money
sure but that money is a lottery or
monopoly money until you've established
that your seeds are worth something oh
that's true no offense do you or the
guys in this room but if we made
warehouse Kyle seeds they're not gonna
go anywhere what if we put his picture
on the back maybe if that picture with
no shirt
rose-cut baby but the ladies will buy a
few packs and then real stop moving of
it I understand it is there's a lot of
work a lot of regulations you have to be
vetted by the community a lot of people
have to grow it Brian if somebody
doesn't like you in the canvas industry
or community that spreads more quickly
than a good reputation kid you've got a
thousand likes and one thumbs down and
everyone goes what's with the thumbs
down why that pisses me off I do that
myself there's a hundred nice comments
about something and one person being
like ooh you know whatever negative and
I'm like why did he think that I'm
sitting there at the you know the
baseball game I'm like why do you think
that I wonder why doesn't everybody like
what I say everybody likes you it's one
person has to not like you then right
because if somebody doesn't like it
you're you're pissing someone off and
that's you should be everybody likes it
you're fake it's kind of like one of
those I tell my kid a product for
everyone is a product for know yeah I
guess
absolutely dial it in get your target
and if you don't like me that's okay yes
I do you do like it absolutely is
absolutely yes all right so getting back
to breeding if I'm because I'm just
thinking about how I've talked to like a
bunch of breeders and everybody wants to
get into the game house thinking about
how long we just how long it takes to
figure out even if something's working
okay you got a cross you did arise by
Mac maybe okay which seems to be on your
mind that's happening geez you're a
psychic or did I blow it I know I'm
gonna make myself summarize to maxi's
and we'll see what happens right now
that's exactly what you'll see what
happens see what has it take to see what
happens what kind of investment is got
to veg but we've got to cut clothes you
have to cut and a rise male King Solomon
you got to get a Mac clone so you're
cutting those you got what 14 days in
your cloning machine 1014 days then
you've got to put those in small pots
you got probably two or three weeks
there right can I go into a three gallon
pot for four maybe six weeks there we're
already at about 10 weeks right
we've got soil we've got lights we share
water already I know I'm gonna flower
about round 8 18 to 25 all pollinate
then I've got another 40 or 50 days
before those seeds are done then we
harvest is that like a plants dry it's
like the halfway out now
got seeds and now I've got to grow the
seeds to find out if what I've created
is worth a [ __ ] because it could be it
could be amazing it could be a total dud
I don't know because I've never played
with the Mac before sure I know what
Solomon does he's reliable
but I don't know what that Mac girl how
she's gonna react to that pollen and
what those genes are gonna do together
it could make a bunch of lopsided
handicap planets for all I know and okay
and what's the deal you were talking
about reputation earlier firms are the
worst thing you know for the reputation
yes if I were to release hermaphrodite
seeds I would destroy all of this that
I've built um right stop all of
everything he's done so when you're
crossing with things you don't really
know we're kind of we're just kind of
looking for the best here the way that I
do my best to prevent that is to not use
some Afra Didache parent plants it so
that's what it is science that you're
using have a tendency to her do not
breed with them because that will come
out down the line yeah maybe not a whole
bunch but it will show up and if it
shows up then it's a problem it has to
happen so I've got to grow those seeds
that I make your right myself or send
them out so I've got a lot of good
friends who are reliable testers they
get them and they know hey this is brand
new you try this you take pictures look
out for problems right could be it could
be a ticking time bomb in your grow so
just pay attention for this it could be
a hermaphrodite it could be totally
weird or it could be the new Mac you
never know god yeah you have to give
them a warning but they grow that for me
or I grow them and then we make sure
then if it's successful then I give it
to James bean she lets it out as a
tester or as a freebie to other people
and then they grow it also and say I got
free stuff then we see that it works
well in a lot of garden feedback hydro
coco soilless organics LEDs whatever
kind of lighting you could think of I
want all the results and then we'll put
it out for the public sure yeah all
right that makes sense it makes okay now
here's one I'm trying to I've had this
explain to me before you're you're a
good good you're actually a podcaster
you could probably explain this to me in
a very simple way
MCS feminized seeds there's all sorts of
you know the Internet's full of [ __ ]
Oh FEM seeds will harm on you you know
that kind of stuff would you explain
feminized seed I think it's fairly
simple if MA like I said a minute ago if
you use hermaphroditic parents you get
hermaphroditic offsprings okay if the
fem seeds are made with
hermaphrodite girls they will be
hermaphrodites the way that I make them
is I carefully select my girls I stress
test the females that I use so if I'm
gonna use a Strawberry Fields girl and
I'm right golden bill the stakes I'm
popular for using the golden go and
reversing it sure I put those in a row
and I'll run them on 1212 like we
normally do but about two weeks in I'll
go and change the light cycle you know I
all want to see it right they do under
stress and if they hermaphrodite they
don't get to breed they get taken out of
the breeding schedule they're gone awry
eaters if they show me that they're
worthy then I'll work with them and
that's where we'll get to the feminized
talk so I'll take the golden goat plant
and I make a product called silver
thiosulfate it's really easy to figure
out how to make that I don't teach a lot
about how to make that I don't want to
get too detail I just want to get a
product I spray that product on the
plant right turns the plant it's makes
pollen sacks that contain pollen that
only have female chromosomes there's no
male chromosomes in that plant but I
have just tricked that planter or
something basically yeah it's the silver
stops the copper movement which creates
other things so it's a blocker yes step
at a time all right so we stop the
copper movement we create other hormones
from moving then we create pollen sacks
with female pollen then I put that
female pollen on a female plant now
there's no opportunity for male it's all
female chromosomes happening right if I
have chosen my parents correctly and I'm
quite careful to do it I don't get any
reports of hermaphrodites in my seeds
that's huge
yes that's why you got a good reputation
thank you that's why they're breathless
and there are a lot of them out there
now a lot of lemon Jeffrey's a lot of
golden right they're out right and first
up what do you do I'm gonna guess you
haven't have you ever had it because I
mean what the hell do you do that's like
a fire right there well I get rid of
them I chop them down right yeah if I've
had it in the room and I see a
hermaphrodite I remember what the
parents are I take good notes right line
it goes I don't continue that anymore
there's no need for that we've got so
many opportunities for good genetics
yeah I'll play with anything that isn't
a tent we've got 11s now we used to
scale things on a one to ten we found a
Levin
why do you want to mess with a 7/32 I've
seen that Mac and I was like oh yeah and
so let's play with the nines and tens
and 11s and leave the hermaphroditic
sixes and fives out of it couldn't agree
with ya okay so just as we're gonna
leave this subject feminized seed has
nothing to do with hermaphrodites
correct AB some Aphrodite's have to do
with hermaphroditic plant parents FEM
seeds are just blocking what's blocking
some kind of male hormone or something
like that
allowing female seeds to grow that's the
best explanation I've heard you give a
FEM so far you've got it alright I maybe
I'm getting it man go hmm excellent man
how long you been doing FEM seeds I have
been do I released Femmes at one of the
first cannabis cups we had here in
Colorado I think it was 2010 bouquet
very wrong all right I've got a brain
injury that makes dates really fuzzy for
me no yeah I was giving away yeah I was
giving away grateful dog and heart of
gold seeds I gave away probably ten
thousand seeds at a couple of cannabis
cups just walking around giving them
away five seeds at a time
oh if you were carrying like if you had
a bag with those nutrients right my saws
like he's gonna grow here a free see
that's so cool that way you could go
home anyhow to everything that's so cool
it up yeah okay dude so if I like to
take your drink but uh so what's going
on
tell me what's first off we're
bullshitting about following the trends
I mean my buddy Jan comes over he gave
me them and I can't say Darren didn't do
anything
gave me the wedding cake gave me some
beautiful cuts the mat came from jera
and that's proper because you're
supposed to give it to people that we
trust and respect Maggie came from Jared
to you that is a worthy gift Wow
specs you and he knows you're gonna do
well with it so that means a lot like
you should brag that means a lot all
right and I change it Thank You Jeremy I
appreciate you brother but [ __ ] now you
got me thinking the host about the Matt
cut hang on what are we thinking about
Trent's waer back are you pretty good
man podcaster brain but trans man so you
know the Matt cut super trendy ok Jaron
comes over to give me that and he goes
oh cheating the wedding cake smell it
because you really get to vanilla
frosting don't you and I'm like mmm
smells like weed and butter and he's
telling me goes oh you
are out now sweets are in yeah how much
[ __ ] do you keep up with that [ __ ] man I
love to smoke that high P stuff but I
don't follow it in my growing or
breeding I avoid it that's not uh I
don't look like the most trendy guy I'm
pretty sure well nowadays yeah but these
were way before most people's if I let
him down you'll see I was first not
really yeah you wait long enough yeah
yeah but I stay away from a lot of the
trends a lot of the hype stuff I do my
thing what feels right to me when I see
a girl plant and a male plant right it's
like when you see a girl at the bar in
your friend like hey dude you and her
should talk you guys would all right you
know who should and I'm like that with
plants I'm like this the plant
matchmaker the plant porn producer ah
that's funny who would make a good scene
I do think of that frequently I think of
the Mack cut as like this beautiful girl
with just a whole shitload of baggage
with her you know every should grow slow
she blah blah you know what I mean but
I'll still probably hang out there for a
little bit yeah yeah Oh baby I stay away
from the hype I just I dodge the trends
right I'm obviously I'm pollinating the
Mack so that's that just sounds fun I
want to see what it does sure but I
don't have wedding cake and all that
other stuff right on you don't see a lot
of that stuff in my grow I do what I
like
so tell me come on let's show off what
you got man maybe Geoffrey's a legend
day I brought some lemon Geoffrey
which camera am I gonna bet I got laid
feminized seeds this is uh the lemon
skunk and golden goat so give me come on
you're the best guy to describe this
[ __ ] paint me a picture man so if you
took a box of lemon head candies okay
poured those on the table and smelled
the box it's not real overwhelmingly
powerful all right but like soft lemon
kind of a dryer sheet and lemon sort of
a thing that's the wrong I think comes
from here to sort of a a dish soap great
flavor
real big giant buds on this one it's not
super tight on some phenotypes some of
them are a little airier that comes from
the lemon scum right I think that makes
amazing concentrates so there's gonna be
a Hobson's how many people just trichome
farmers these days cuz then the
parameters totally change everyone's if
ting and squishing right I sing now
so they care about pretty buds and they
care about yields well you got to post
those pretty buds come on that's what
social media is all about until they
shut us down and
you go to cannabis that's what you're
supposed to do respect respect to our
friends over there yeah so it's a
cannabis but yeah they're all about the
giant but still that's that's gonna be a
thing for a while and most people you're
right are squishing and press in and
running it somehow it's either diamonds
or squish right then bro I was at a show
yesterday that should have come smelled
completely like weed it was back you
know yes I mean any you know you could
smell it every now and again everybody
was smoking but they're hitting on pens
and you know I mean it was so low
pronoun most of the market is pens yeah
generaiiy been so discreet I mean you
don't smell yeah and if there are kids
around they don't know if you're smoking
nicotine or if that's a DAB pens yeah
regards that got that and they let you
in so they thought that was your
nicotine yeah I handed it to a security
guard yeah yeah here you go have fun
yeah actually I brought two because it
you know it was like a three hour
concert well yeah and if they took one
then he had another you took both you
blew my plan and you gotta have one in
this pocket one in this pocket no there
you go that's my pin I'm sorry and then
he just walked right it is all one here
twirl man there's places I go and
they're like no you have to bring a
clear backpack if you want to come in
and I'm just like that's the future that
hell's happening here I have some
dreadlocks that look like me go to the
concert they get the gloves alla vodka
products the potent tonic Stephan seems
like it's weird I get searched at the
airport is weird
he's fun to hang out with eyes another
friend I made through the shows I'm
actually super pretty a friend that I
made through your show so I'm gonna be
[ __ ] over the DD secret I've also got
the orange gasm orange gasm is kind of
new I talked about the lemon Jeffrey
being super lemon Terps right guess what
orange Terps we got straight-up oranges
tangerine's you know I was reading the
turf book I'm trying to study up on
terms I can't smell them but at least I
can [ __ ] about you know carafa lean
I thank you you know her awfully funny I
tried to send it in a text that's not no
you did it was good what is it
I don't remember how I typed it I see
really type it out thinking beta
rock those are yeah me and Steve are
sitting there trying to correct each
other right two starters I'm probably
saying also it's cool though but what I
was gonna say is there's one that's a
Valencia or something like that and
there's avalanche
the orange yeah so there is an orange
terpene I remember out drive by the
citrus squeeze plants in Florida and
they would have big barrels of orange
juice and then it would have a little
tiny barrel of something like a 25 25
gallon barrel there's always so
different a hundred hundred bucks says
those are the terpenes right oh yeah man
they got a little bit of Turkey you
probably made cleaner and all kinds of
crazy stuff out of that I want or I
wonder if they sell it for stuff rose
ium yeah you're right yeah I think this
smells like the orange ozium if you get
the orange one right and smells like the
orange Ozio that's what I think we shout
out to that was one of the best I mean
they saved my ass oh and look at joint
in the car smell go ball in the car will
go crazy and spray a little hit the O's
iam just one yeah cuz two dashes of that
that's too powerful good one and yeah of
course Mel's like oranges for a week
platinum tangi so you got platinum
cookies right Angie cross to the golden
goat feminize as well recognized as well
it's so [ __ ] important people give me
seeds all the time and I was looking
through and being like I need some stuff
to plant I was gonna actually for the
greenhouse and I was like I don't go on
a phenol hunt yeah and not only you know
on I don't want to lose half my crop to
males and you don't want to accidentally
pollinate the neighbors for the next
three miles if you forget a male and the
wind comes yeah people forget about that
I think that's one of the things we need
to pay more attention to so yeah FEM
seeds for lots of new Instagram breeders
online now they all come from here and
welcome that's it so you know what
everybody's crosses right yeah alright
and then I've got the the staple the
golden goat s1 some of those labels get
confusing it's a golden goat
reversed so I made golden goat to create
pollen and put that on another golden
goat so it's just a self golden goat you
know I heard you say golden goat and I
was already thinking of my next question
and I just have to stop and cuz that's a
really special strain I agree when I
first got here amazing flavor to it a
great plant you know just a big just a
beautiful plant yeah and I mean who was
it that made that shatter was it was it
a darkness gross gross and that
beautiful orange shadow
that slab this smell hit my face and
came back down and I went oh that's the
most delicious golden goat and he smiled
golden goat its absolutely butyl is so
delicious yeah yeah wonderful job with
that you can't lose with that plant you
can't you can crack it you could twist
it you can kick it over
yeah it just grows it goes okay now
that's why the dude gave it to me when I
first got here that was the one he's
like Scotty I set you up for success
well that's partly why I love reading
with her you can't do her wrong right if
the pH is too high or too low she'll go
then that'll be all right she likes a
lot of nutrients so you can't really
over feed her it's real simple to work
with
I'm good potency good flavor good
harvest and she breeds really well now
you said as long as you're good at
explaining stuff so I'm gonna take a
little lesson I'll be listening in this
back and I keep on glossing over stuff
how'd you get the golden goat again
because I want to learn this you
reversed did you say reverse with the
seeds come from making getting a golden
goat clone right and I treat it with a
silver thiosulfate garnishing and it
turns it into it's basically a male it
looks like a male but it's still a
female it's just got male pollen sacks
with female pollen got it and I put that
on a female plant so it's just golden go
to golden coat okay wait I got the plant
I didn't create it a lot of people think
I made golden goat I didn't I got it as
a gift from my friend who I call
pineapple Express all right he's
actually from Hawaii
the golden girl has nothing to do with
Hawaii but my friend pineapple Express
is from Hawaii that's what I named him
that's just his nickname he doesn't his
real name out there sure if he got that
clone from another person it actually
came from mr. dank in Topeka Kansas he
bred yes
Topeka Kansas there's a recycling center
in Topeka known as the golden go
recycling plant and it's a hundred
degrees out here imagine if I had a
bunch of soda bottles out there and how
sweet and sticky and good that would
smell right it smells like a golden goat
plant and that's why he named it golden
goat after the golden goat recycling
center yeah that's a lot a lot of people
probably I get credit for it quite often
and it was not me I didn't create that
huh
so okay yeah mr. dank from Topeka Kansas
it's Island sweets go kauai incentive ah
and Romulan I remember the Romulan back
in their grills and that's what keeps it
short and squat that's what is the other
two or a tall monster right what keeps
it short and keeps the finishing time
down is that
I'm beautiful did a great job with the
Romulan excellent lineage service and I
will just go back and touch on do em and
icg yeah I pack I know I got five female
yes man yes that's big for me you know I
pull those boys down you'll find one
that looks just like what you're looking
for
yeah and easy yeah I love it those are
yours so I hope you find a keeper in
there oh I will I brought some for the
DGC crew also thank you so much door
prizes yes sir
gotta share the love we'll do it take
good care of me I appreciate it man yeah
you right back action reciprocation
that's what makes the world go around
respectful for us let's go respect
respect I love being in Jamaica so
minded me have we got to get Stephen go
god the weed there it's just outdoor
weed but it got me so high what do they
say I think I learned in sixth grade
help set and setting you know you're
hanging out with ya and where you're at
I'm like just going down a river and
Jamaica smoking a freaking fat one here
yes yes all the Irie that feeling I'm
serious insurance I love it I love it
hey do me a favor man tell me a little
bit about your grow and give me a little
bit of you gave me up we were working
and we've been collaborating lately yes
we have yeah so sometimes I don't know I
please concentrate companies I don't
really know exactly some of the specific
questions to ask so I was getting with
Jeff and one of the questions he said to
me was hey man how would these guys are
sure that they're delivering a really
high-quality a really clean medical
product you know IPM you know nutrients
leach and that kind of stuff even going
as far as having mold on there you know
even when you're curing processes man
I'm asking you this you know ask you the
same thing you're not in a commercial
production like that but what what kind
of advice could you give as far as IPM
as far as keeping a good making a good
safe product even I do consulting for
commercial growers so I know and I'm
also certified by the Colorado
Department of Agriculture everything I
do in any grow I follow Colorado
Colorado Department of Agriculture and
marijuana Enforcement Division pesticide
guidelines right so nothing I play in
any grow that I consult for my personal
grows none of my breeding grows if the
Colorado Department
bag won't let us use it I don't use it
sure I'm not restricted by those
guidelines in my private grow but I
still choose to follow that sort of a
restriction yeah I mean that
concentrates are exactly what they say
your cause you're taking it yeah think
about somebody yields from these things
you take a whole plant and get three
grams out of it or something you're
taking that all the essence of that
whole plant or at least all the
trichomes and and concentrating it down
dig up there's even that tiny fraction
of pesticide on there oh yeah know
enough that you smell the little flower
and it'd be okay now you're
concentrating it down to where you're
smoking right right on that plant you
just basically broke that back down into
a little ball dangerous I've smelled
sulphur I've tasted sulphur before the
concentrate tastes like fish or like
burnt fish or something rice they use
sulfur too late in their flowering
process and really what that's from
and I mean Iggy I could see that
happened you know you know I could put
it this way I can see somebody making
that mistake if I had a big pot of soup
or chili how much pesticide can I put in
there that you still want to eat it you
know and then I might you like the
people you're serving absolutely right
come on guys it's right come on we've
all gotten I had thrips before I used
the a mammoth IPM and knocked them out
for me what do you do when you have bugs
are you preventing it with with other
bugs give me some advice in veg I am a
spray guy I like to use a reliable
sprays and veg later on to the veg phase
I like to give to be the predator bugs
going I like to use Swarovski's I
depends on what kind of pest I think I'm
gonna get right these are always the
go-to nice swear skis and green lace
wings they're definitely aggressive and
they'll keep anything away so if you get
them colonized and get them started I
liked it so I do the sprays it's easier
to spray smaller plants and control them
keep the moms all sprayed up it's
reliable and as I move toward the
flowering phase I'll start releasing
massive amounts of predator bugs my god
and to always filled with predators and
I like to keep perpetual flowering areas
so there's always predators over here
let's move to the next spot as they come
in and they're coming from the late veg
plants so I like to start with sprays
and then move to the predator bugs I
also do a lot of defoliation a few
defoliate that's less opportunity for a
pathogen all right look if you don't
have a leaf that wears that bug gonna go
come on give us give us your advice on
day what day what do you do Foley aid
you got specific days when three when I
go into flower ID foliate hard I put on
the trellis I pop all the sticks I
dressed all the stems and work
everything into the net and I take off
quite a bit of loose a twist on stem
super crop and basically for crop them
put one hand here one hand here and give
it a twist yep Google that if you all
don't know that's an interesting
technique it sounds just like a knuckle
pops now you know you did it right yeah
go up a few inches and do it again let
that heel about two or three weeks and
go back and do it all over again right
yeah like did you and that will prevent
your stretch and early flower so I'll do
that on day one I'll do defoliation in
about week three do some defoliation
then again about week five or six okay
and then as they mature and harvest I'll
just strip them is there getting close
to the end week eight week nine really
Katy yeah well a lot of times I'm in a
large commercial cultivation facility
where hundreds of lights right and so
I'll just send a crew of dudes in there
and just say make them naked boys and
that way when it comes time for harvest
you don't have all that leaf to take off
you chop them hang them upside down you
don't have that mess of chlorophyll
basically to deal with yeah I used to do
that Easter I think it was in the 90s
that people I guess strip off all the
leaves boys you know you only want buds
yeah and yeah I wasn't sure the
technology science behind that so I
stopped doing it you're saying you don't
if you do it late enough you're not
seeing any negatives you do it late
enough you don't see any negatives we've
already done what they're gonna do
you're just work it and I don't strip
them completely naked naked but right at
the end right we'll go naked but we've
up to week six there I'm keeping some of
the bigger leaves but I take if it's got
a purple pea do that comes off like a
purple or something that'll stay there
yeah okay yeah I want as much light
penetration as I can get I want as much
air flow as I can get right in a big it
changes when you're in a big facility
that one little spot of powdery mildew
can multiply you know and you know eight
pounds and pounds I'm not risking one
pound like in a home gram
risking 500 pounds sure so I've got to
be a little more aggressive with my
prevention as far as P n goes you got
any time you need loves there correct
the rooms it's all about money P D we
talked about VP deal or I out the bar
shows all about proper yeah no
microclimates people forget that you
need a fan here and share not just way
over there that used to be my I was like
I never got powdery mildew but I'll be
damned to fight him he'd go crazy with
the fans he would be like dude what's up
with you and these fans and
make floor fans and I put a fan on the
floor and pointed up a fan over there
and point it down yep and don't have all
your fans I've seen rooms where all the
fans oscillate together you're just
moving you want to stir the air yeah he
was moving that heat over here and move
the heat over here we want to mix it so
the heat and the cool and the humid and
the yeah well combines yeah since we're
talking grow VPD is basically vapor
pressure deficit we talk about it all
the time it's the first time you tuned
in here it's basically the pressure
that's keeping the water onto the leaf
if you're able to get it correctly the
leaves actually able to respire and
breathe basically yes yeah it's almost
like if we were in a rubber suit man
yeah gonna work so good yeah you're
getting good at this cutting Oh a man
where's my mister analogy coffee cut man
another gold star for you I appreciate I
love bullshitting with you about grow I
also like bullshitting with you you know
if you listen to the show I'm more about
the culture I'm more about what sit
we're interested in what's happening now
we listen to all the same podcasts
weren't all the same [ __ ] yeah it's an
absolute revolution what's happening I
love it I got my mother-in-law using
started off with CBD now she hits the
pen every now and again you know but I
never would have I don't say I never
would have thought I don't know it would
have been hard to imagine this I think
the the easy way that we got in here is
because it is really good medicine it is
super easy to convince people that this
is really good medicine usually it just
takes one hit off one of those price if
you were running thanks man
all right if you had a minute to talk I
would tell you my father-in-law holy
[ __ ] he don't believe it man you don't
believe you just you stayed the course
actually it was weird cuz I knew I was a
grower and never admitted it and then
after it became legal and I came here
and he goes up good I'm glad I just
don't want you breaking the law like he
had a problem in a breaking the law not
really
cannabis is medicine or anything like
that but if you were trying to convince
somebody like him that cannabis is real
medicine what would you say who I got a
minute I had a traumatic brain injury in
2015 I'm easily a pretty upbeat guy you
could say I like life right I'm not dark
in session is he absolutely my brain
injury had me thinking it was tricking
me into thinking I wanted to
you hurt myself and do bad things to my
life and I knew that wasn't right
right but my head hurts so bad and my
thoughts are so twisted from a brain
injury like my brain just my waters were
[ __ ] on for watches and I get I was
doing purple orange I thought that
purple was orange now and I thought that
a burrito was called a banana holy [ __ ]
but yeah that's where my brain was it
took a while for it to come back and
then amazing how it works and like you
have something like that me like I can't
believe it worked in the first place my
computer was scrambled yeah messy maybe
go to the doctor and he you're like no
we could watch it work we kind of we
don't really know how it works though
they tried were scary one of my friends
was entering a cannabis cup for a CBD
concentrate and he said hit this and I
said okay right when I was smoking dabs
or flowers it would make my head throb
from the injury I hit I dabbed that CBD
and it felt like I had a belt around my
head and when I hit that CBD it felt
like he just went back there and turned
a little knob that loose into that belt
two or three notches really oh and as
soon as I hit it and exhaled his
girlfriend goes give him another one
just like they could see my puzzle
pieces just coming I was like whoa like
hey hey guys like I'm back and they're
like keep hitting this Wow so they gave
me a few days supply I can't give you a
lot right cannabis cup entry but here's
you know it's work and hit this and so I
smoked CBD first so I don't like CBD now
right but I smoked CBD for several days
and then it kind of put me back on the
tread sped up my healing whatever was
happening in my brain that put it back
together in this mm lens you saw us 2015
holy crap yeah that's not long no not
long ago and I'm pretty much back -
there are still things that happen -
sure sure
well do you ever have the thoughts and
you're going hey wait whoa how did I end
up in this room like only when I'm super
duper stone not at the end of the joint
of the a what room I didn't see when I
smoked my brain doesn't I see that
there's like a skip on my record
wherever I hit right my record was spin
and I dinged it right there and so and
so and so sometimes skip you know I mean
right when I smoked that little they
wipe off the skips on my record when I
dab like the lemon Jeffrey's you're
holding goats right the right strain so
I'll just clean my my skips right on up
so that's that's amazin want to kill
myself anymore from consuming CBD
sounds really weird to say but rising it
wasn't like me being crazy it was a
brain injury an injury that does things
so I mean CBD really does have
anti-inflammatory properties I mean if
any if you think about what inflammation
is shoving everything to get it it don't
need to be together you don't need our
space man wait my three brain cells that
get along we're fighting in their you
know a luster together yeah do we you're
in business then right you've been
trying yeah
imma [ __ ] keep motivated when you got
something like that how do you mean
motivated in general man you just get up
every day to mansion do the passion I
love cannabis
I loved it before my brain injury it
sure made my smile you can tell I talk
too much and it talked to me just right
just right I would talk too much then if
I didn't consume right ah but so the
brain injury the just the passion and
then I became a caregiver and I was
involved in the medical marijuana from
the beginning very cool ah people would
come to our dispensary and we would I
had time then at dispensaries to sit
just like this and write what's wrong
and they would say it hurts I would say
where and they would tell me how and
where and I'd say oh you want this
strain and we'd actually get to develop
that so I would see young guys like you
and I and little ladies and everybody
all walks of life would come in and
after a week of talking to me and
consuming a product I recommend they
would I would see improvement in their
quality of life
just a better smile yeah maybe a little
more pep in their step and do that put
something in you that is irreplaceable
I'm a father and that that's a magical
feeling that thing when you see other
people healed from a product you may so
true is the next best thing maybe the
next best it's funny we were talking
about this book that I read and it talks
about the joy of being able to actually
produce something and then say that see
something that he produced like be
enjoyed it gives you like a fulfillment
the book was about a lot of people don't
get that anymore cuz we stopped
producing most stuff just talk about it
yeah well I get to make seeds I get to
teach people how to grow or I see people
grow those seeds I see people grow for
other people share I see my best friend
Mike heap smokes a product I grow he
shows up to my house going [ __ ] back
hurts dude takes two dabs and goes oh
thank you buddy yeah it's the dab and
the social interaction those are
medicinal and therapeutic so we're
making people feel better
and then to keep me motivated dude I've
got the DGC I've got the Irie army any
time I wake up and I'm like oh it's a
bummer day I open up the social media
there's and then awesome people saying
killer podcast thanks for teaching me
how to grow you look great and you can't
be down when you have support like that
no so it's that's part of what does it
and we talked about checking out the
one- hundred people that say nice things
and all our friends it does round it out
bracing it definitely does yeah it's
just weird how your brain works oh oh
yeah you don't want that bad you want to
make everybody happy you know what I
think it is I think it's primal I think
it's like when you would see a fire back
in the day you know from been thousands
of years ago based about that fire you
know there's a potential problem there
when somebody Falls you want to pick
them up yeah I think it's really bright
like you you want to pick them up make
money too sometimes they're just gonna
say it's not me this one's you Bubba
yeah I train hard on that podcast I'm
sorry you didn't learn anything all
right we'll wrap this up I've enjoyed
the hell out of Tommy this is great are
we gonna start the podcast yeah we turn
the cameras on Kyle
actually recording this warehouse Kyle
is doing it today did a good job brother
doing a good job yeah there is a guru's
on vacation warehouse kyle is one thing
excited to our friend guru hope you
enjoy this vacation
absolutely catch up that dog catch a
trout for me sir I give up a little
parting words of wisdom there's probably
someone that's younger than us I'm sure
most people are younger than than me
anyhow that are sitting here being like
man Rasta Jeff awesome I'd love to have
a career like that I'd love that uh
wants a life like that that's creepy but
they just think of you as a role model
give you some people some advice on the
business and on the anything you want
and it just do what is right for you
you can't follow you can't judge
yourself by anybody else I can't look at
you and say well Scotty is doing this I
need to do this I know what I need right
wha I know what works for me do what is
for you don't judge yourself on anybody
else's success or Riley yours I don't
judge yourself on your success or
failures you can fix all that right now
you're done I do do what's right don't
follow the hype don't follow the money
follow your heart grow from your heart
that's the name of my pocket or reason
so do it all from the way it should be
done do what's right and just listen to
yourself listen to your heart listen to
whatever you believe in and I think
you'll get where you need to be
don't don't listen to social media don't
listen to the YouTube haters I don't
listen to your whoever well how do you
get information though I get a lot of
information through saying okay
information and encouragement and things
but right don't get don't take too much
life direction
yeah because everyone's gonna say you
should don't let me more [ __ ] on you
like yeah don't let people [ __ ] on you
got a bumper severed love to see that as
a sticker do what you feel you should
know you they don't know your goal you
may see that I want a seed company and I
want to be a breeder you'll say you
should do this before I leave it also I
want to be a podcaster and a dead your
idea may not work so I've got to do
what's right for me I wish I could give
somebody better advice and say like you
need to do these steps but do the steps
and you'll know what the steps are right
or whatever your path is the steps will
come and avoid the [ __ ] you'll know
you know when there's [ __ ] you know
oh yeah whatever you're doing even when
you're driving like I'm gonna go to fat
you feel you know Drive it too fast all
right now I'm gonna get a ticket for
this all right like don't do that and
stay on the highway and get to Fort
Collins on time and do the show yeah I
will say positive attitude is huge being
when you have a positive attitude I love
being around he always had a smile I
same about you so I think that's big I
think you really have to associate you
have to find people that want to help
you that want to teach you things and
man people don't want to teach you
things if you got a a big sourpuss right
right yeah yeah why am I gonna teach you
something just gonna be negative about
it right or positive energy someone
that's gonna share what they learned
that's what we got it what thing I try
to do I give credit to the people who
taught me a lot of times I say I learned
this from this person right and that's
just giving credit to my source so that
I don't feel like I'm the Wizard of Oz
no we almost from other sources a lot of
them I was reading another book is
called steal like an artist and it was
Tanya that good luck trying to have a
completely original thought you've got
it from somewhere oh you know so you're
motivated by things just take it and I
mean breathing is the same way typical
expression is that what we were doing
expressing yeah I can invent the genetic
code though right right I love it good
[ __ ] when your brother every summer
is vacation week man you came up and I
keep it Irie I love her brother when's
the next event you tell me man you tell
me the 420 event it cultivated synergy
we're definitely doing that so that
could be could be I've got a couple
plans I'll talk about it I'm excited
take it easy all y'all well there you go
podcast world that was Scottie real and
Rasta Jeff on the dude grow show make
sure you give my friends that the dude
gross show some support make sure you
subscribe to their YouTube channel go to
youtube search in the dude grows podcast
they will pop up right away click
Subscribe leave some comments let them
know that you found their podcast
through the growth from your heart
podcast that way they know that I'm
givin them a little bit of support
ladies and gentlemen that is it for this
episode I want to thank you for
listening follow me on social media be
good to one another and until next time
take a phat dad and give your mom a hug
for me