all right take 17 somewhere around there
welcome to episode 452 of the girl from
your heart podcast this episode of the
show is dedicated to the life and memory
of my friend Jason Jason was battling
cancer for a really long time and I got
the news that unfortunately last night
he has lost his battle with cancer I
have a lot of great things written down
that I want to talk about things I want
to say about my friend but I'm not sure
how much of that I can get through here
on this podcast so please bear with me
and join me while we honor my friend
Jason now it is a tradition that we
start this podcast off by talking about
what I'm smoking my friend Jason was
super important to everybody at the
Green Dot labs team he was what my
friend just called a what did he call a
a coal and the fire for Green Dot labs
if you needed a motivator if you needed
somebody to cheer you up and get you
[ __ ] started Jason was the dude so
today I got myself some Green Dot labs
concentrates I may have gone a little
bit overboard if Green Dot has it
available right now I am probably
smoking some of it in honor of our boy
Jay so big [ __ ] stupid sighs
ridiculous Green Dot dabs for our buddy
Jason that is a great way to start this
dedication I'm smoking green dot for you
bro I hope you're catching the clouds
I'm blowing your way now let's move
forward we know what we're dabbing on
let's talk about this kid Jason was a
great guy he was a couple years older
than me and I call him a kid because he
was a [ __ ] kid at heart he knew how
to do business he knew how to take care
of [ __ ] but he wasn't burdened by
adulthood he didn't let all that
business [ __ ] he didn't let all the work
stuff it didn't slow him down it didn't
make a smile go away he was gonna make
sure that we had a positive attitude
that we had fun that everybody had what
they needed the work got done and then
everybody got a hug and a high-five at
the end of the day so he was a great
[ __ ] kid even though he was older
than me he was a good [ __ ] dude
one thing that I've mentioned about Jay
is positive attitude that dude you never
see him there are so many pictures of
him on Facebook that's another thing
that as a testament of how awesome this
kid was if you look at all of the
pictures on Facebook and everybody today
has posted ten pictures of this guy
everybody's got photos of him every
picture he has got a smile from
to ear the dude doesn't stop smiling he
beams love he beams kindness ah as a
grown adult sometimes we need advice
from friends and sometimes you're kind
of shy on who you're gonna ask advice
from from friends because most of my
friends are in the same industry as
myself this industry can be competitive
a lot of my friends including myself
have big [ __ ] man egos and we don't
want to ask other men for advice I never
felt shy or ashamed to just ask Jay for
some guidance like hey bro here's what's
happening what would Jason do and he'd
be like bro I would [ __ ] quit being a
[ __ ] and I would do it like this and
he's like you're right I knew that
that's what somebody needed to say to me
I just needed you to say it so he would
motivate you he would be positive with
you he would give you advice he was
filled with kindness and even if you
didn't see him for a while we lived it
quite a ways away from each other no
excuse sometimes we wouldn't see each
other for a while when we did see each
other it was one of those you know you
do the handshake
it's a handshake it's a fist bump and
then it turns into a man hug and then
you back up and he kind of high-five and
you just talk uh it was that the moment
we saw each other
his friendship was everlasting his
friendship was unconditional and that
unconditional love that unconditional
friendship shows through his social
media everybody on social media is
posting about how much they love this
guy about how much he helped them
everybody's got a story about how Jay
helped them so when he got sick
everybody did their best to help him and
we've all contributed to auctions and
given donations and things to help our
friend out he was an amazing friend he
was a great person it he was just he was
a cool kid he [ __ ] showed up with his
oversized grass roots hat he was always
[ __ ] stylish bro he had the coolest
clothes I don't dress all stylish like
that but that kid dressed a mad [ __ ]
style I always had the coolest hats just
always positive does coolest [ __ ] always
beamed at this cool energy this cool
vibe it was just love and kindness
strangers would walk up to and be like
hey you've got cool vibes we need to be
friends so I wanted to share his vibe
share his love make sure we continue his
spirit continue his energy I wanted to
express my love for the dude here on a
show also I wanted to take this as a
time to say thank you to my friend Jason
I didn't say thank you
face to face enough I
have many things to thank him for just
basically for the friendship that is the
first thing I would thank him for he was
a good friend we had business talks we
had friend talks we had relationship
talks we had all kinds of fun
conversations so I owe him a big
thank-you for all the inspiration the
advice and for the friendship and I wish
I would have told him in person
several many more times I wish I had the
opportunity to smoke a DAB with that
dude right now he would love all these
concentrates I got on my table he would
tell me which one I had to smoke first
it would be fun gonna miss my boy big
shout-out to Jason the entire cannabis
community is at a loss everybody feels
it social media is in tears today
everybody misses you Jay we wish you
were all here now I don't have a smooth
segue into the next portion of my show
there's really no smooth segue out of
that last part so I'm just going to tell
you what I want to talk about this
brought me to thinking that medical
patients are basically pioneers and
cannabis community leaders my buddy
Jason was very well-spoken for the
cannabis community has been involved in
medical cannabis since I knew him that's
how I met him he was a huge part of the
Colorado cannabis medical and
recreational cannabis community he was a
big part of the concentrate community we
found that a lot of the people who were
using cannabis for medical purposes
concentrates work very well you could
take one dab and you can find great
relief where before he may have had to
smoke two or three bowls to get the same
relief so our boy Jay was a medical
patient and I believe he was partially a
pioneer he's been making concentrates in
Colorado since we were just coming since
the market was getting huge he was there
he was part of it he was one of the
pioneers he has earned that title and by
being such a good dude having such a
good heart being so outgoing he also
became a community leader everybody in
the Colorado cannabis community knows
who Jason is and I feel like every state
that has legalized or will legalize
medical cannabis will have a person like
Jason in their area in their demographic
we're all gonna have that like outgoing
charismatic super friendly business
minded family oriented
of a businessperson who is also a
patient and an activist and an advocate
and a lot of times those are the people
who help us get the medical marijuana
laws started and get things put in place
they're the ones who stand up for us at
City Council they're the people who do
their best to hold the city and counties
accountable when things go wrong and the
rules and regulations are backfired and
citizens rights and patients rights are
infringed upon those are the people who
do that type of work those people are
crucial to our team those people are
critical for our cause without those
people helping create the rules without
the people doing all of the petitioning
without the people doing all the City
Council work the growers the
dispensaries the trimmers all of that
stuff is useless so those people are
critical to our team the reason many of
those people are fighting so strongly to
legalize medical cannabis and to uphold
the rules and regulations the medical
cannabis gives patients those rights
that we are afforded by those laws the
reason they fight so strongly is because
cannabis is what they have found to help
keep them alive or comfortable or to
improve the quality of their lives in a
significant way
and that is why they are out there
fighting to legalize cannabis and to
uphold patient rights because they are
patients themselves they know firsthand
how well cannabis works to cure ailments
in their lives who knows what their
ailments are who cares as long as
cannabis is making it better we should
allow them to use it so that's why many
people become activists become advocates
they want to heal themselves and they
want to see that healing and that
improvement in life amongst other people
so many cannabis advocates and activists
are pioneers in their area is what I'm
discovering and that is because those
people have passion and a purpose they
are passionate about medical cannabis
because it is improving the overall
quality of their daily life maybe they
don't have as much pain maybe they are
able to eat maybe it makes the PTSD go
away maybe it makes this seizure stop
they are improving the quality of their
life they have got passion and with that
passion comes purpose
animus is not legal but it makes my
ailments go away I need to do everything
I can to make cannabis available to
myself and other people with this
ailment and so now you have added some
purpose to that passion you have got
passion and you've got purpose you were
on the right track to actually do
something that's what makes somebody do
something real passion and purpose so
ladies and gentleman my advice to you is
find your passion and find your purpose
because your time is limited do what you
love to do and figure out how doing what
you love to do can be a purpose for the
world what are you contributing figure
out a way to make your passion
contribute positively to the world if
you don't worry about money you will
make your income you will pay your rent
you will eat you will not starve you
will not be homeless if you follow your
passion and your purpose now there is
one more important lesson that I've
learned today when you do find your
passion and your purpose no matter how
committed and how dedicated you are take
a couple of minutes tell a couple of
your friends that you love them and that
you're grateful that they're there
because at any minute they may not be
there so find your passion find your
purpose but still make a few minutes out
of every day to love the people who are
important to you ladies and gentlemen
I'm gonna wrap up this quick episode I
apologize for a short episode I've got
some grieving to do on my own I want to
turn off this microphone I'm gonna take
a couple of fat dabs for our boy Jason
I'm gonna sit here in the quiet by
myself and just think about my friends
think about things I'm grateful for I'll
be back Monday with the full length
episode I want to thank you guys for
listening to this I wanna give you huge
shout out to my friend Jason I love you
brother and until next time take the fat
dab and give your mom a hug for me