welcome back podcast world it is time
for episode 453 of the growth from your
heart podcast sitting across the table
from me is white Mike welcome to the
show bro
thanks man what's up everybody what's up
everybody hope everybody's having a
wonderful evening daytime nighttime
afternoon whatever time it is wherever
the [ __ ] you are hope you're having a
great one hope you're smoking something
delicious hope you're hanging out with
somebody beautiful hope you got a nice
buzz on if you're in your cubicle and
you can't smoke if you're working you
can't smoke don't worry Mike and I have
got you covered we are plenty medicated
here today for you bro did a DAB for you
bro as always this podcast is brought to
you by our friends at seeds here now if
you need new regular feminized or auto
flower seeds Auto is the one I almost
forgot they even got Auto flowers bro if
you need new seeds in your garden I
highly recommend seeds here now and you
can find them at seeds here now dot-com
we do like to start the podcast off by
talking about what we are smoking Mike
and I said we took a DAB for you just in
case you're curious that dab was banana
Rama ambrosia from our friends at
apothecary farms the potency label says
70.1% THC which is not a high number but
I got lit from smoking it was going
total cannabinoids 81% total
cannabinoids so there's got to be some
CBD or some THC V or some something
different in there something something I
lost the thread Mike lost his train of
thought it's working so it is that's
with the Bananarama it's got a really
interesting aroma it does have to be
more more you dude you were you jumping
right on it it's got a I said it tastes
like jell-o shots and I haven't had a
jello shot in a hundred years but it's
got that uh the green jello not the band
but the snack it's got the green jello
sort of a flavor to it aroma a little
bit I think so that lemon lime jello is
sort of a thing big shout out to our
friends at apothecary farms for the
Bananarama ambrosia
all right podcast world I recently
discovered a new website that provides a
lot of information for me I'm not gonna
tell you the name of the website might
include to me is if I may do my
advertising voice we're joking about it
earlier not gonna happen not gonna do it
I did find a website where I can find a
lot of podcast review
a lot of statistics they want me to give
them money for some more stuff but the
free stuff is very useful there are a
lot of useful stats on there I can see
my rankings on stitcher and iTunes I can
see my favorite part what I'm getting at
is all of the iTunes customer reviews
all of the stitcher reviews they are all
compiled into one place one I did not
realize I think I knew it but I don't
think I ever thought about it that
iTunes is broken down by country and
there are folks in other countries that
have been leaving reviews on the podcast
which we are not able to discover
through we don't see through the
platform we access exactly because
they've got a different library and a
different matter just a different
algorithm and they're probably different
things
yeah differents different stuff I don't
need to worry about what all the
technical stuff is but my point is there
are other reviews which we have been
missing when you do that it's really
creepy by the way your mic is so low
that it comes weird yeah that is creepy
that we've found so there are more
reviews and I think that we need to take
a minute and read some of the reviews
from some of our friends from other
places we should it may be
discriminatory if we didn't do so I'm
going to leave out speaking of
discriminatory I'm going to leave out
the u.s. iTunes customer reviews because
they're easily accessible on the iTunes
which I normally find we're going to
focus on our foreign friends for these
next couple of reviews internationally
and then after we do a couple of reviews
we are going to jump into some listener
emails
couple of them all right let's jump
right into it alright this review was
left on May 9th and it goes a lot like
this they gave us a 5-star rating it
says it is the best I should mention
that this one was left by big bass on
Apple podcasts from Great Britain so the
comment goes I would highly recommend
listening to this podcast even if you
are just remotely interested about
cannabis that is the best source of
convocation and then he said comedy and
education this is my review I can write
like that if I want and I appreciate
that I like your creative writing he
goes on to say for cannabis I could
easily sit and listen to Rasta Geoff and
the and of course white Mike for hours
which
have done they should be proud of what
they have achieved here that Mike we
should be a proud of what we have
achieved and if this listener could only
help with the progression of cannabis as
much as we have he would be a happy man
hey that's cool man thank you I
appreciate hearing that and it says I
think you need to take a tour to the UK
and spread your love around here thank
for all of your help from just bass
whatup just bads thanks for all the love
and support they helped us out on
patreon also I appreciate that so that
is a great review from our friends in
Great Britain and appreciated you so far
so good dude all right this next one I
believe comes from our friends in Canada
big shot at or friends up north they
gave us 5 out of 5 this one is from
Presley Presley boo from Apple podcasts
in Canada this was left on August 6 it
says one of my favorite podcasts top
tier sound quality and information that
is a great review I can stop there they
like the top tier sound quality and they
like the information they go on to say
they've been listening to all the grow
lessons and they are extremely helpful
so I appreciate that they wrap it up
with Irie Gang Gang Gang Gang buzz buzz
thanks for the great review I appreciate
it that people appreciate the top tier
sound quality coz I put a little effort
into that I was an audio kind of a guy
before I really got into the podcast
thing so I'm glad people notice I'm glad
they like the top tier information and
those grow lessons took a lot of work so
I'm glad they found those helpful and
big shout out for the Gang Gang it's
good to know my friends are listening to
the same podcast that I'm listening to
all right this next review comes from
our friends up north big shout out to
our friends in Canada
this one says Rasta Jeff my dude they
gave us 5 stars and it says Rasta Jeff
is the most effective cannabis
cultivation educator around these parts
that's a huge compliment dude the most
effective that means a lot like that
means the effort we're putting in is
doing the most work results you or
comment on those parts around those well
there you go maybe I'm the only well
Jesse you go to just go out of control
folks every now and then we got a little
that's the truth maybe I'm the only one
round those parts which still
means on the best damn it then they said
the Willie Nelson Snoop Dogg over here
so I guess that's another huge
compliment
I started this podcast on a two to three
hour commute to a job I hated the
podcast inspired me to become a novice
home grower so we got him growing yeah
that's the goal minute says I have
perfected my craft I've entered the
Canadian cannabis industry worked my way
from the trimmer room into the room to a
grow lead manager how many of those
co-workers did you introduce to the
podcast yeah Congrats bro no I'm proud
of you first went from listening to the
show being inspired thinking hey I want
to grow a little bit and then became a
home grower perfected the craft got the
travel want to do good enough Yeah right
get out of the rat race and into
something we'd like to do injured the
industry bow away from the trim room I
always talk about the first step is go
trim you got it in the trim room yep
went from the trim room now they are
lead grow lead manager and then they say
much respect my dude and then it says
when these I don't know if there's more
to this review that this application cut
off but uh dude that is a great review
even without the win these if that's how
it ends then when these bro when these
much respect my dude so big respect back
at you that's from our friend loud music
2:01 for an apple podcasting Canada it's
a big shout-out to our friends from
Canada or big friends up north hope you
guys are having a great grow season up
there hope everything's going well for
you hope you're staying
I read all right Mike I'm gonna scroll
down we've got a couple of more reviews
this website keeps refreshing itself
because there is an ad so it's hard for
me to keep track of my place on this
page but we're gonna get through it
together technology shall not defeat me
you look like you doubt me bro no I
don't know it might just also looks like
you're playing tic-tac-toe yourself on
your list I'm just making sure to cross
out the ones we do so that I don't read
them all over again because nobody wants
to hear these twice in fact we'll get to
another review in a minute this one
comes from our friend
he says Wales UK and they gave us five
stars they are called Zootopia and
they're listening on Apple podcasts from
Great Britain apparently they're from
Wales UK they say let's hear about out
gorillas grow Otto flower tips um that's
not my wheelhouse I would fail at that I
did a decent outdoor grow lesson it was
a little bit but Otto flower is not my
wheelhouse I don't know much about Otto
flowers and anything I did I would have
to just fake it for you so that wouldn't
be a quality podcast in my opinion we
could do a little show on like gorillas
growing general tips or house [ __ ] used
to be back here in the struggle but days
struggle but I've heard that worked a
minute when I first heard of flowers
that was the first the first place my
brain went was like those be perfect for
a struggle but crap yeah struggle bud
was a term for planting seeds it kind of
in the wilderness in a location that was
likely to produce some sort of growth
without any intervention from you from
the the state like when you put the seed
in the ground until you come back six
months later and rip it out of the
ground and run away real quick in the
dark that was struggle blood grown [ __ ]
half of the people I knew with home
grows outside had some struggle but
going on and [ __ ] look like yeah
where were we Mike did we start reading
this review yet no I knocked out the the
Otto flower review and now we're on to
you slimy cross that one off the list
let me go for the next one here alright
this one is going to be the last one for
this episode then Mike and I are going
to press pause and take a DAB and then
we're going to read a couple of emails
this one is a good one they say 50/50
they call themselves a long time
listener they're listening on a podcast
from Canada once again big shout out to
all of our friends up north that looks
like we have a nice Canadian
listenership that makes me happy yeah I
enjoy it I appreciate it they've got a
nice Canadian grow industry up there a
nice cannabis industry so big shout outs
all of our friends oh man I'm gonna keep
moving forward the review goes like this
please stop wasting episodes by reading
iTunes reviews if I wanted to hear
reviews I'd read them aloud to myself
I'd do more episodes with your strain
info answering emails grow tips and
white mic with other potential guests I
love the show I look forward to each and
every episode
but the ones when you read reviews feel
like a waste of my time and yours I
appreciate the fact that you read the
reviews and please take this as a
constructive critique and not a dig five
out of five stars for most episodes 0
out of 5 for the ones when you use most
of the episode up by reading reviews
keep up the work
I appreciate the review I appreciate the
feedback
my voice did a weird thing there I kind
of like to edit that gonna keep moving
um what really helps a podcast to get
exposure is when somebody leaves a
review that helps us get noticed on the
front page of iTunes that makes you more
popular in their algorithm requests
that's the truth I request reviews I'm
asking people to do that as a favor as a
return to that favor I read their
reviews on the podcast I know I'm not
maybe not your favorite grow person
maybe I'm not any sort of important
person to you I know that every time
Joey Diaz says my name on the podcast I
know that every time the dude grows crew
says my name on the podcast I still feel
a little smile inside I get a little
goofy in my heart I'm like ah they're
talking about me on my favorite podcast
right now so when I read people's
reviews and I'm reading their [ __ ] they
feel like they're connected I've done
them a favor they've done me a favor
it's a communal effort so that's why I
read the reviews I say I will read your
review on a future episode and so people
leave a review they want to hear it they
want to hear me say it I think it's a
great thing to do it's an exchange I
thought we both get something out of it
so I appreciate that you find it to be a
waste of time there's a little skip
button on your iPad on your iPhone it's
15 or 30 seconds for just mash on that a
couple we do make some G this words
we're brought to you by on it not really
manscaped com
don't cut your dick off [ __ ] oh but yeah
just use that 15-second skip forward
button you'll get right through the
reviews you be all right I still want
you to listen I still want to be your
friend I do appreciate your constructive
criticism I don't take it as a dig oh
you're not gonna hurt my feelings
somebody has to not like my voice keeps
doing weird should I'd like to edit but
we're not gonna do it
somebody has to not like
you you're not gonna make everybody
happy so and he said fifty-fifty he
likes the girl episode so he'll be cool
he probably has already checked out of
this and doesn't know we even read his
review that's funny if you got this far
send me an update send me an email girl
from your heart at hotmail.com and be
like hey listen bro I just made it
through this alright I think that is a
good spot to stop with the listener
reviews I want to thank everybody for
the listener reviews we really really
appreciate every single review even the
ones that are negative or focused on
something that the reviewer would like
us to do different every review is
helpful and appreciate it thank you I
may take some of the constructive
criticism and I may use it I'm pretty
set it the way that this show goes I'm
comfortable I look how many notes we've
got okay feel like four notes here for
this whole show it's all I need we could
just turn on a mic we could start
talking I'm not going to change a lot
but if something really pisses somebody
off or something we would consider it
and I'm I will listen to opinions but
this is the way the show is gonna go bro
we're good at this by now yeah we've got
a nice little rhythm down I think we're
both real comfortable with it and enjoy
doing it and I think we've found a fan
base that enjoys listening to us do it
so far like and if you don't agree with
that please hit me up on Twitter it's at
15 or public acceptable cannabis laws on
Facebook hit up Mike I was gonna say
when you're in a room and like one
person says hey you're an [ __ ]
that one person may have had a bad
experience with you two people go you're
an [ __ ] that could be that other
person's friend but if three or four
people start going you're an [ __ ]
you're probably the [ __ ] so far like
one out of every 50 reviews say we suck
so we're doing okay in my opinion yeah
we're not an [ __ ] yet you're not
succeeding unless somebody's dating
that's right
Michael Franti said if I don't have any
enemies I'm not doing my job life might
throw me a curve but I'll never be
throwing a lob shut up to Mike Franti
alright I said we're gonna take a dad
and then we're gonna read some emails so
I'm not gonna do that pavlok [ __ ] make
you drool over there
let's press pause for a moment and let's
take it down because they don't want to
listen to you choke while we dab so
we're gonna press pause we're gonna take
a couple of quick dabs I need a drink
obviously my voice sounds like [ __ ]
we'll be back in just a couple of
seconds through the magic of editing
we'll be back right now watch here we go
alright we are back we are well
medicated we are well hydrated I should
speak for myself medicated yeah yeah
we're doing well over here we took some
dabs we smoke some GG for ambrosia the
label says 59 point something percent
THC it's smeared slyguy concentrates on
it
66 point four percent total cannabinoids
I feel like I got stoned er than 66
percent you know me too a STONER a word
because I just said it like a [ __ ]
answer's no all right podcast world
before we took a little dab break we
said that we were going to read some
emails let's read some emails if you'd
like to send me a grow question or
something like that my email address is
grow from your heart at hotmail.com you
know that I'd like to hear from you here
is a great email it goes like this what
up Rasta Jeff what's up bro how you
doing I says good day from Down Under
hey thanks for the good email mate then
he goes on to say I'll try to keep it
short and sweet
then he said that's what she said is
that what she said but uh that's not
what you said I don't think that's what
she said bro he goes on to say I came
across your podcast about a month or so
ago by the way of episode 138 breeding
and harvesting seeds I was hooked after
hearing how informative and in-depth you
were in explaining genetics and
feminization Ruby's gonna motya awesome
thank you for listening yeah glad you're
listening to the breeding episodes then
he says I started listening to all of
your grow lessons which have really
brought together everything else that I
have read through my research about
growing and made it simple and easy to
understand that means a lot to me
because that is kind of my goal I want
it simple for everybody to understand
people learn with different brain types
people learn by looking by hearing by
doing so people are just hands-on
learners I try to make it easy for
everybody even those hands-on people I'm
thinking about it like Mike sees me
right now I'm like looking
telepathically up into the sky and I'm
putting my hands in shapes so that I can
do those things while I'm thinking about
it so I can explain it to you as
thoroughly as possible so I'm glad that
somebody's learning I'm glad you're
appreciating that this has been a great
message there is still more he goes on
to say I have some bubblegum some ak-47
some purple haze and
Widow seeds and was wondering what your
opinions are on these varieties and if
any of them would make good or decent
hybrids they sign it with thanks from
big tea then they say you and white Mike
should come to Australia as consultants
to our government on legalization
I'd love to I'm not sure I want to go
there because everything there is trying
to [ __ ] kill me not in the city not
in the city all right we'll be cool yeah
taken I've ascent just 90 percent of the
stuff trying 90 percent of the rest of
the city stuff so if we go out of that
little wine we're gonna get murdered by
some crazy animal and I'm just playing
Australia's got a reputation for having
some crazy [ __ ] wildlife out there
I'm interested let's go to a grow some
Australian cannabis let's do it oh that
may be a thing so let's see where do we
start he wants to know if he's got
bubblegum ak-47 Purple Haze and white
widow seeds and he's wondering my
opinions on these varieties and if any
of them would make good or decent
hybrids I can't see your plants I can
see your a list of strains which you
have got and I can hope that those are
truly the genetics that that seed
package claims they are I don't know
where the Bubblegum came from I don't
know where the ak-47 came from I don't
know where the Purple Haze or the white
widow seeds came from I knew who
originally bred those yeah what makes me
nervous about those that strain list is
it sounds oddly familiar from our kind
of distant past you know I was I thought
the same but also there in Australia so
they may
culture takes a little time to travel
maybe that's where they are maybe
they're still in their time capsule is
still there with those genetics so I was
gonna let that slide and not judge too
harshly on that but yes that is like
that's like having a bunch of Mickey
Mantle rookie cards back in the day
you've got some pretty good stuff there
if that's real you've got some great
[ __ ] I don't want to question or doubt
the legitimacy of these seeds I know who
bred most of those things I know who I
would like to see on the packaging for
most of those but I don't know what
you've got so without seeing the
packaging without seeing the seeds I
don't know if what those are all
so I can't see the plants I don't see
your phenotypes I don't know what you've
got to work with that is kind of how on
paper I could look at the genetics and I
know that white widow is great to breed
with I know that I would like to breed
with the white widow I've grown
bubblegum and a K I could probably think
of some creative ways to breed around
there are some cubes some triangles some
open pollination x' I could think of
great things to do but without seeing
the plants I don't know what would work
best I need to see each plant that is I
think as a breeder I'm kind of like a
plant matchmaker I've got to find two
plants that I'm gonna look at him and
grow them and some and smell them and
experience that picking from a list like
this is sort of like trying to pick two
people who are gonna hit it off from
names in a phone book I was gonna make
that analogy pretty soon I was gonna be
like so do you think Bill and Karen will
get along we don't know anything about
film or care just two white people
probably bill and Karen we have no input
on them so I don't know how these are
going to breed I wish that I had more
input so if you do choose to breed with
them I would pick one or two packs of
seeds and I would get those started I
would select a couple of males a couple
of females that really stand out for
whatever reasons you believe you're the
breeder now you get to make those
decisions and then I would work projects
as desired from there as Mike said a
second ago it sounds like you've got
you've got four different packs of seeds
to choose from so you've definitely got
enough stuff to start a breeding project
the thing is that you have to do it by
looking at the plants you can't just do
it these all look good on paper yeah
until you see him for any it's hard to
tell yeah you've got they all look good
on paper but you don't know which males
are gonna look good which females are
gonna look good you'll have something to
do some sort of a breeding project if
you pop two packs of seeds if you pop
three packs of seeds you'll find
something find a solid male out of there
that looks like it'll work perfectly for
you and then find a girl from all three
packs of seeds so that you've got maybe
a bubblegum female an ak47 female and a
white widow female and then perhaps a
white widow male and pollinate all three
of the girls with the one male you can
make white widow f2s and then you can
make white bubblegum and you can make
aka bubblegum for tea
RAK white widow 47 it's just that way
you can do a little bit of breeding and
then you get to grow all those seeds
you'll have a lot of seeds to play with
but that's probably the way that I would
do it I would grow them you gotta grow
them you gotta be I can't be a
matchmaker without knowing some
personalities it doesn't work out that
way um and if you want to make some
feminized stuff then you just got to
find a solid female and then reverse it
then pollinate the same cultivar a
different clone of the same cultivar and
you can make your feminized seeds I wish
I had better input for you my friend
without seeing the plants I really don't
know what to tell you I on paper I know
what would look good of course I like
the white widow as a male just because
there are a lot of traits I would stay
personally I wouldn't breed with the
purple haze that's going to put a lot of
extended time flowering time into
everything and it's just not one of my
favorites but that clue strawberries got
a long silver grouse season well this
could all the purple haze could also be
this person's favorite [ __ ] strain
and it doesn't get my attention at all
kind of a lot of Hayes's and watching
them sort of slowly disappear because
they take more than nine weeks has been
hard for me to deal with
yeah the market has definitely changed
well this one comes from our friend Big
T so thanks to Big T for sending us a
great message and they also say PS white
might come down and be consultants for
they don't want us to go consult on the
grow or anything like that want us to
fix the Gov they want us to go help them
legalize cannabis I think what we got to
go do is go down there and set up the
podcast setup just like we've got this
we got to take a rig we got to take some
flowers I'll be your ambassador or a
weed and then we've got to go smoke down
and while we're smoking we need to be
interviewed by people so that they can
see that we can medicate properly and we
could still produce and actually and act
like border wasn't called responsible
productive citizens what do you want to
call us responsible productive citizens
is pretty much exactly what I like to be
called pretty much exactly you sound
like one of my old bosses and throwing
handsome in there and I'm right don't
make me edit this [ __ ] yep alright Mike
let's keep moving with this I've got
another email if you've been listening
to this show regularly that was harder
to say than it should have been while if
you have been listening regularly you
may remember that in a recent episode we
read an email from a friend of ours
who
grew and smoked some lemon Geoffrey that
he flowered for 11 weeks if I remember
correctly
it blew his mind I asked for more
information he was listening we've got
more information magic at the Internet
baby he magic it says it was a trip to
hear you and Mike read and react to my
email I'm glad you like that that's why
I read read your reaction our words bro
it's a trip to read your reaction to our
reaction man I goes on to say I bought
the pack of lemon Jeffery from dank seed
I think I only popped one seed because
it was all I had room for at the time so
an old vendor when he don't work with
yeah I was gonna say an old vendor that
we're no longer working with but there
are plenty of other good opportunities I
check out seeds here now or the hell a
dank seed company I'm pretty sure he
means the old dank seed so that is not
hella dank seed company we do still do
business with them support them let's
keep moving before it gets confusing he
says I wanted to make sure I had room to
trellis so he only had one one plant he
wanted room the plant filled up about a
2 by 3 foot canopy and he let a lot of
smaller nodes go full term to avoid
getting any really thick buds he said
airflow is never good enough for a
closet tent in our state I'll leave his
state out of there we don't need to
narrow down his location so he got one
lemon Jeffries seed he grew it in a 2 by
3 area a lot of smaller nugs he says
even at 11 weeks I wasn't seeing much
amber except at the very top of the
plant I was thinking I'd probably
stalled or slowed them along the way
with a misstep I wish there were more
details on there because I would assume
that that is what messed them up a
misstep something slowed them down I
don't see that plant taking 11 weeks so
there yeah I wish I knew more about what
you're suppose it our possible misstep
was because I assume that's gonna be
what slowed him down but man whatever
you did it sounds like you made some
amazing mistakes it goes on to say I
pressed rosin pretty early after harvest
and it had a slightly darker look
leading me to believe that the trikes
were mature so maybe he wasn't looking
didn't see that they were actually amber
but the rosin did come out
we are can with yellow cantaloupe are
you looking with how how good your scope
do you need to clean your lens he keeps
going I didn't push her much at all
meaning he didn't feed her a lot is what
I'm gonna assume that means I had a nice
organic amended soil and I supplemented
with 1/4 strength organic bottled newts
and some top dressing and microbes that
that makes it taste really good if you
don't overfeed the lemon Jeffrey she
comes out nice and sweet that goes on to
say I did not keep a clone of this one
is I had to break off the Grove for a
couple of months that's understandable
this is I'm back on it now yeah welcome
back bro I bet it feels great to be back
growing again it always sucks that to
tear down the grove for a minute we
don't know where you are I do know where
you are sometimes [ __ ] goes on
especially there so be careful where are
we it says my wife and I polished off
our last lemon Jeffrey this morning and
we will be on dispensary for a while man
I'm sorry about that he says it's
heartbreaking and expensive if you can
find some quality dispensary buds around
there yeah it's rough to go from your
personal back to the store shelf why'd
you give me that look Mike it's just
that's that's just life yeah I get it
I get it there is more to this great
message it says the next run of lemon
Jeffrey will be at least two plants so I
can harvest one a little earlier and
taste her as intended by the breeder and
another so I can revisit this late
harvest again and compare now I'm
curious if I that misstep will show in
this next trial runs down with the same
spot again in the same way or don't and
see if that 11 week flower is really
what that plant needs if it works twice
then it's not an accident there's
something cool about that right but
maybe it might have been that misstep we
don't know unless we try again and don't
do that
and then we have to keep trying under
different conditions I like running
experiments they can go forever there is
more it says thanks again Mike and
thanks again Rasta Jeff you guys are the
shiz and then they signed it with no
name excellent assignment yeah
especially from the state they revealed
that they are from hey thank you no
names for the great email thanks for the
update on the lemon Jeffrey I look
forward to
hearing how the next grow goes and I
really look forward to photos of the
next grow I know you're down there in a
dangerous location but if you can sneak
a few shots in you don't have to post
them to social media I do have an email
account you can easily shoot them to the
email
Mike's giving me that sour face what's
that mean buddy I just three bad jokes
went through my head instead of making
them I just cringe I appreciate that
so city an email I think we want to
follow this little grill where we dig it
yeah I like the small sets they're fun
to see you don't produce that and there
could go big to have a blast growing at
home one plant to plant pop in one seed
at a time that's there's absolutely
nothing wrong with that grow your heart
out one seed at a time somebody made a
joke today in another podcast I
participate in I'm also on the embracing
organics live podcast on YouTube every
Thursday at 7 mountain time um but I was
on there and somebody said something
about I know I'm just a basement grower
so excuse me Jeff and I was like oh bro
not to interrupt you but I was like I I
am a basement grower yes I have a lot of
commercial experience yes I have been a
lot of places through and for growing
but like almost all of us I started with
a light in the basement and I still
remember those days I still honor those
days I still appreciate and respect
those days I've got as much love and
respect for a basement grower as I do
a guy with 20 lights as I do for a guy
with fifty to a hundred to five hundred
lights
we're all growers we're all doing the
same [ __ ] it's all a passion we're all
in it because we love growing we love
cannabis we love the effects of cannabis
so don't don't think that I think I'm
hot [ __ ] because I'm a commercial grower
I got nothing but love for the basement
grower that's where I started that's
where I came from
never forget your roots I'm a basement
grower kind of guy I know I talk about
get out of the basement mentality in the
commercial grower mindset if that's
where you are if did I still got a drum
set in the basement I've played huge
[ __ ] places and I have just as much
fun and just as much passion and when
I'm playing in the basement on Thursday
night before I have to do a podcast
after dinner just killing an hour I have
the greatest time so whatever you're
doing if you do it with your heart any
I got mad respect for it so don't ever
think that just cuz I've gotten real far
that I got any sort of not belittling
any basement Grover at all
you don't gotta go baby us you know they
have a more of a struggle than us
I can call I'm not gonna say the name of
our vendors or anybody I can call people
in another state or in another County
couple miles north and go hey I need a
pallet of this two pallets of this five
bottles of this and this they put it on
a company credit card they show up with
a semi we get a forklift and pull a
[ __ ] pallet of stuff out into a
warehouse high-five the driver and sign
for it you can't do that at your home
grow you got to go in some places know
to do a throwback earlier when they're
asking about guerilla growing a lot of
those tips are the same for for home
growing somewhere were you ain't
supposed to be homegrown or where it's
brand-new um if I was on an East Coast
if I was in an East Coast state right as
they were going legal I'd still be just
as nervous as I was here when we were
just going legal
with growing at home and stuff because
it's still worth several thousand a
pound and that's though your ass if the
wrong people hear about it yep yep see
and you have to be careful not because
of just the thieves but because of the
law you have to use the law the hassle
the headache you got to drive one car at
the gross store drive to your friend's
house park in the garage
get all the [ __ ] out of that car put it
in your car drive your car to your house
to the garage unload for a while my
hustle was buying supplies for growers
like that was the thing I did for side
money was I would call up my growers I
knew gave my shopping list for the day
go fill their shopping lists go home
repackage it and then later that and
that that day or the next day go deliver
it all like that was a major side hustle
for a minute when things were just
started to turn the corner things are so
different now so yet my point is no
disrespect to however big your grow is
if you're trying you are on Team
cannabis and I am on your team I want to
support you you're one of us that was
what I'm trying to say
he might we've been going for a 30
something minutes you ready to wrap up
this podcast we should all right let's
uh five five go fist bump and do this
part of the show
happy podcast yo first off Mike thanks
for coming dude I know you take time
away from your family and away from your
life
it uh I love being on the show it's uh
it's rewarding I absolutely love getting
over here and doing it it's just finding
the time can be a [ __ ] so I'm trying to
do it more yeah hope you appreciate it
we've had internet love that's it keep
sending in the encouragement we've had a
mere couple of times this week so dude
thanks yeah all right podcast world if
you feel like this episode of the
podcast was educational informative or
entertaining and you'd like to make a
financial contribution to the show you
can do so by visiting patreon.com slash
grow from your heart all the information
you need will be right there on the
screen big shout out to all of our
friends who have supported the show
through patreon I would also appreciate
it if you support me on cannabis
cannabis is a free cannabis friendly
social media application you cannot buy
or sell cannabis there but you can talk
about it you can brag about it you could
post your picks you can post your dab
pictures you can post your duck face
smoking pictures anything you want to do
over there come join us on cannabis give
me a follow i'm irene underscore
genetics on cannabis i look forward to
seeing you over there if you've got
something you'd like to say you're not
into all that social media nonsense you
can send me an email my email address is
grow from your heart at hotmail.com you
know that I do love the interaction
ladies and gentlemen my voice is burnt
out here at the end of the show so I
want to thank you guys for listening
I'll be back in just a few days with a
fresh new episode I'm gonna give a huge
shout out to pierce Hester and until
next time take a phat dad and give your
mom a hug for me