here we go welcome to the show podcast
world it is time for episode 455 of the
growth from your heart podcast this
episode of the show is brought to you by
our friends at seeds here now if you
need new seeds in your garden I highly
recommend seeds here now and you can
find them at www.cdxzipstream.com farms
the label says that this product
contains seventy-three point two percent
THC and eighty five point five percent
total cannabinoids apothecary has
recently started releasing the premium
rosin the sh o rosin I was reluctant to
buy it because it is at a higher price
point and I did not want to fall in love
with it but I think I might be in love
the aroma is ridiculous I always say
that there is a strong aroma coming from
these concentrates there's something
different about the rosin concentrate
the aroma is more like the plant it is
more similar to the essence of the way
that plants smelled while it was growing
and it's got a hint of that dried and
cured plant smell as well the Ambrosia's
and the batter's get the essence of the
Terps of what the plant smells like when
it was alive when it was growing when it
was fresh I think the rosin gets a
fuller more of a cannabis flavored
profile something that a cannabis smoker
is more familiar with if you've never
smoked pho and you smoked the rosin you
may say what is the flavor coming out of
that BHO you may think it's fake because
it is Souter P the Terps are so
prevalent in a different way this rosin
has a cannabis based flavor to it
and unless you've smoked a lot of
concentrates that may sound weird but
there is much more of a cannabis
dominant familiar flavor to this rosin I
really like it of course it's got me
[ __ ] rambley it's got my eyes nice
and heavy
something about a BHO or a diamond or a
sauce or an ambrosia or a shatter dab
even when I smoked that it makes me feel
like I'm kind of bug eyed like almost
caffeinated off of the amount of THC
that has entered my body so quickly when
I smoked there the SH o the rosin it
makes my eyes go droopy my eyes are
heavy my eyes feel
I feel like I get really high from the
BHO and I got really stoned from the Sh
oh so I'm not sure if that's a good
description for people that don't get to
smoke every day but the buzz is
different the feeling in my lungs are
absolutely noticeably different it feels
a little bit thicker a little bit
heavier which that makes sense because I
can see the consistency of these
products this is almost like a heavier
thicker version of the batter that I
smoked on a regular basis but it is just
thicker and it feels like I get just I
just need a little bit smaller of a dab
of this and I get as much smoke and it
really punches me so big shout out to
our friends at apothecary I didn't mean
to talk about the new concentrate for
two minutes but I really appreciate the
flavor the aroma the buzz the flavor is
crazy
it's intense it just lingers on your
mouth it leaves that weed flavor that's
what I miss from the BHO so it leaves
that that cannabis that when used to
smoke a joint there was a flavor to it
that is back with the rosin so shout out
to our friends at apothecary farms for
the start of Ambrosia sh o premium rosin
alright in this episode I'm going to
answer a couple of grow questions but
before we get there I would like to give
some shout outs to some friends from
patreon let's start out with the big
growth from your heart podcast shout out
to miss Mel I need to send a big
thank-you shoutout to todd kay i also
want to send a big thank-you grow from
your heart podcast shout out to richard
m i also want to send a giant shout out
to our buddy steve f also a big giant
girl from your heart podcast shout out
and a thank you to my buddy basta as
always a shout out to our buddy Brian B
and last but certainly not least I want
to send a giant grow from your heart
podcast shout out and a thank you to my
good friend Aldridge I want to thank all
of you for your continued patreon
support if you're not already supporting
the show and you would like to learn how
to become a patron all you have to do is
go to patreon.com
all the information that you need will
be right there on the screen
all right podcast world at the start of
the show I said that I was going to
answer a few grow questions recently I
was asked a question by a friend he sent
me a picture of via email I did not
print out the message because I can
cover it without printing that paper so
let's talk about his question he sent me
a picture he is
using a root pot he's got a fabric pot
his plants look beautiful and healthy
the room looks nice and clean everything
looks stellar he's got his plants worked
into a nice trellis so he's developing a
nice canopy everything looks real sexy
in there my friends one major concern
was hey Rasta Jeff why do I have roots
growing out of the bottom of my pots so
my friend is using a root pot like a
fabric pot is a there are many different
types of them available now just a giant
fabric bag basically into the shape of a
root pot so it's got a lot of breathing
room for your root zone it's basically a
big potato sack that you fill with soil
or soilless mix and you put your plant
in there and it grows really happily
because the plastic doesn't allow as
much airflow if you're using a plastic
pot you restrict a lot of air flow to
your root zone so your roots are growing
through the medium they're like hey
there's oxygen this way they go that way
they get to the edge of that root pot
and they say ooh there's more air out
there and they grow through right
through that root pot those roots are
looking for oxygen while they're doing
that they are also looking for more food
hopefully they find water and food at
the end of their voyage
those plants that have got the roots
growing out of that bag are simply so
happy that the roots have just grown
right out of the bottom of that bag you
do have the possibility of those plants
becoming root bound in the near future
but with the size of the plants that I
saw and the size of the container that I
saw I don't think that is going to be a
problem until late in Flour if not all
the way to the end I think you've chosen
the right size pot for the length of
what you are growing that plant but what
is happening is some of your roots are
so happy and so excited that they're
just outgrowing their space they want to
see what's on the other side of that
wall and that wall is just a little thin
fabric line so they were able to wiggle
the way right through there
and now the roots are simply on the
other side now the roots that I saw
sticking out of the bottom of the pot
were at the very bottom corner of the
pot where I would assume when you water
that plant a little bit of water stands
in that area you get some runoff out of
the bottom of the pot you probably have
an inch maybe a half-inch deep worth of
water just chill in there for a short
duration of time until you either suck
it up with a shop vac or it drains
somehow or maybe you just let it
evaporate whatever works in your
environment works but I'm thinking that
those
nutrients that little puddle of water
that moisture and then that dries up
you've got that very thin boundary for
the roots the roots just say hey this is
a really cool direction for us to go and
made it start going that way from the
pictures I saw it looked like these
plants are very healthy they're very
happy and it looks like that grow room
is very well taken care of so I don't
think you're going to see any problems
because of that root growing out of the
bottom of that pot it is actually a sign
that you were doing a very good job now
if you were still in veg and the pot was
smaller and the plant were larger and we
knew that you had much more time to go
in that container that could be a
concern but since you were as far along
as you are and those roots are that size
I think you were timing it just
perfectly when you were growing cannabis
part of your goal is to select the
appropriate size container to be
completely efficient too small of a
container you'll get root bound you'll
have to water way too frequently it
becomes difficult if you're running like
a 1 gallon pot and your plant gets big
you may have to water multiple times a
day if you've got an auto watering
system that's awesome if you're a home
grower and you got a water by hand and
you've got multiple plants that can be a
pain in the ass so selecting the
appropriate sized pot is very important
when you're growing in a home grow
without an auto watering system and
you're running in a soilless mix or even
in cocoa
the idea is to choose the size of
container to where when those plants are
getting harvested you want them to just
achieve rootbound status like you got to
go oh man they're rootbound now oh it's
okay they're harvesting tomorrow that's
how you want that to time out you want
to fill that bottom container at the
same time that the top part finishes
I feel like too many people overlook the
importance of the root zone the roots
are where it all starts healthy roots
healthy fruits fat roots fat fruits it
all translates it all makes sense the
root zone is where it's all happening if
you have a healthy active root zone that
you're probably hopefully inoculating
with some sort of beneficial funguses
some sort of root inoculant that will
help you reduce the risk of pathogens
and pests those things want to go to
weaker plants and healthy plants start
at a healthy root zone that moves up
through the plant and those plants don't
get diseases and pests and plants with a
big fat healthy root system are much
more forgiving if you make a mistake
a grower and your plants have little
shitty roots they may die from a very
simple mistake if you've got plants with
big fat lush healthy roots you might be
able to abuse them a little bit and they
can still recover because they've got
enough life source to survive no I do
have a little bit of a follow-up to this
question somebody else said are these
mushrooms in my soilless mix a problem
now I'm sure there are a lot of growers
out there who have grown with sunshine
mix number four or Fox farms ocean
forest or maybe some of that 7:07 stuff
or that roots organic stuff and you have
all seen those gold cap mushrooms pop up
either on the top of the soil or they
come out of the bottom of the pots where
you got the little drainage holes you
just get a couple of smurfy looking
mushrooms growing out of there in my
experience those mushrooms usually pop
up late in veg it seems like they like
the late veg environment something about
the temperature something about the
humidity maybe it's something to do with
the nutrients but that is usually when I
discover those little golden mushrooms
popping up in the soilless mix in my
experience those mushrooms have never
been a problem those mushrooms have
always appeared when my garden was at
its peak optimal state so if you are
getting those mushrooms you were
probably doing something right you have
probably got a nice healthy root zone
you are probably watering properly
you're probably getting enough drainage
you've probably got enough oxygen your
VPD is probably just right I have always
taken those golden mushrooms as a sign
that I am doing a good job I also like
to let those mushrooms fall back into
that soil and decompose I feel like they
give life back to that soil and now that
I'm watching that cycle happen in my
head that is probably where the
mushrooms came from there were probably
just spores in that soil we gave them
the perfect environment they decided to
develop into mushrooms then they are
going to decompose and fall back into
the soil and give our plants life there
is no competition between our cannabis
plant and the mushroom that is growing
on that soilless mix they are using
completely different things to survive
that mushroom will not cause any harm to
your plant in fact that mushroom may
actually help speed up the breakdown of
some of the things that are in that
soilless mix and make those elements
more bioavailable to our
so they work sort of similarly to our
little wiggler worms in a very different
way so if you've got those golden
mushrooms there is not a problem in your
container it is probably a good sign it
means that you were doing a good job and
those spores probably came free in your
bag of soil they're nothing to worry
about
let them keep growing until they fall
over and die let them decompose then
they will provide even more nutrition to
your plants while they're alive they
break down things then once they die
they fall back into your soil they
decompose and they continue the cycle of
life so if you've got some roots
sticking out of the bottom you're
probably doing a good job if you've got
some golden mushrooms growing out of the
top or growing out of your drainage
holes you are probably doing a good job
with your soil keep it up now here's
another thing I should talk about while
I'm on this subject this was not on my
notes this is just something that popped
into my head while I was ranting about
this a lot of people have begun making
super soil or some sort of a living soil
or a premix soil that doesn't require
nutrients at every watering something
that you just give it water and an
occasional tea and it keeps the plant
sustain through most of its life you may
have to top dress at some point it may
be beneficial to give it specific teas
to support specific phases of growth but
the main idea that a lot of people are
heading for is a super soil mix that you
premix and then the idea is that you put
a bunch of amendments and a base soil
together you mix it up and you put some
water in there and you store it in a
warm place and that water the air all of
those amendments and that warmth create
life inside of that container where all
of your stuff is mixed up and it becomes
alive that is called the cooking process
so when you make a super soil basically
you throw a big tarp on the floor you'll
put down a few bags of your base
soilless mix and then you will mix in
various amendments based on what you
want to do with your super soil
so whatever amendments you have chosen
we mix them up in the appropriate ratios
along with that base soilless mix then
you may sprinkle a little bit of water
on it now or you may scoop it into
containers depending on how much mix you
have made some people will scoop it
right into a large trash can some people
scoop it into some of those like
Rubbermaid shipping or storage
containers whatever container you put it
in that's up to you you may need to add
a little bit of water in there just to
get it activated just to get it moving
then you want to seal it up
then you want to put it in a warm place
the combination of the water those live
amendments that warmth the air in there
they all start creating life that soil
all of those amendments start doing a
process that we call cooking all of your
organic amendments start breaking down
naturally and making themselves more
bioavailable to our plants so that when
we put a plant in this soil we've got
organic soil that is ready to go it is
enriched it is well balanced and the
plants will love it so you've got your
stuff all mixed up you throw it in your
containers you've got just enough
moisture in there to get everything
alive you put a lid on it you throw it
in a warm place and you just leave it
for a few days depending on your goal
depending on your mix some people will
let it sit for seven some will go
fourteen some people like to go thirty
some people like as much as a 60 day
cook on their super soil that is all
about your preference that is all about
your goal that is all about your
amendments there are many ways to do it
there is no wrong way unless your plants
die do what works for your plants do
what works for you that is not the point
here my point is during that cooking
process you need to check on your super
soil occasionally to see the progress
some people like to stir it some people
prefer not to disturb it I am NOT a
super soil expert or a maker so I don't
have a preference on that for you you
have to learn that yourself read the
recipe that you're working with maybe
start at build a soil calm and work your
way from there or check out sub cool
super soil recipe and work your way from
there see what you want to do with it
add subtract as you feel necessary but
whip up your super soil then check on it
in a few days here is where people make
a crucial [ __ ] mistake you're super
soil should begin to grow a nice fuzzy
white layer a funky weird [ __ ] across
the top of it it should start off
looking like maybe a little bit of a
spider web then it should look like you
almost have maybe powdery mildew or
almost trichomes or powdered Donuts
growing across the top of your soil a
lot of people will freak the [ __ ] out
when they see that they'll say oh god
it's all moldy what do I do
you [ __ ] celebrate that was the goal
that is mycelium that is the life source
that we have been trying to create in
that container you did it good job the
problem is a lot of people see that and
they think the
they have created a problem they don't
realize that that was the exact goal we
were trying to achieve so if you were
making a super soil please do not freak
out when you get that fuzzy white stuff
that is the magic we were trying to make
happen tada
you did it good job and I know it sounds
silly that I should even be talking
about this but you would be surprised
how many people I've heard say it in
person how many times I've read it in
forums and how many stories I've heard
about people dumping out large
containers of soil mix that they have
made that they had intended on using for
the next four or five runs in their
garden they spent an entire day mixing
it up they spent 30 days letting it cook
then they opened it up and went oh I
ruined it and they simply threw it all
away or they just dumped it in the yard
because they wanted to mix it out with
yard dirt they did not realize they just
created super soil which was the goal so
don't be that guy don't freak out if you
see the mycelium that is what you were
trying to do boy that really took longer
than it was supposed to let's move
forward with more grow questions
another question somebody asked me about
growing was when I cut clones why do I
cut the tips of the leaves off of my
freshly cut clones so when I'm taking
clones to make fresh plants I usually
cut I'll probably cut a six to eight
inch section off I'll get a bunch of
those in a cup with some water in it
then I will carry those to my cloning
station and I will take one cutting out
of the water and I give that cutting
what I call a haircut I will take the
leaves and I will trim them down so the
leaves are kind of shaped they're shaped
like they get skinnier and then they get
fatter and they get skinnier again right
at the very thickest point is where I
like to cut them before they get fat and
then I cut them right there to where
they don't have a chance to taper back
to skinny so it tapers really wide I cut
it at the widest point now the leaves
are only about half the length that they
were when we start it then I will cut
the base of my stem at a 90 degree angle
I will trim that up a little bit kind of
shave it just a little bit with my
scissors my point is to open up that
outside flesh anything that is going to
get dipped in the cloning solution if
you're using if you're trying to stay
all organic and you want to use aloe or
if you're gonna use olivia's or if
you're gonna use clone x whatever you
choose however far you are going to dip
that color
into your cloning solution I like to
take my knife blade and just kind of
scrape that edge of that clone up just a
little bit and what I'm trying to do is
open up that outside layer open up that
fiber so the roots can grow out of that
more easily they're gonna grow from the
inside
I just want to lightly scrape that
outside skin off just a little bit I
don't want to go [ __ ] it up and make
it real rough and messy that's gonna
give it an opportunity for problems but
I do want to scrape it and rub it just a
little bit with my blade just to take
that outside fleshy layer off so I like
to give them that haircut cut them at
the fattest part of the leaf flip them
upside down give them a nice 90 degree
angle give them a little scraping then I
put it in my clone solution I use clone
X most of the time in most facilities
and most applications that works for me
you do what works for you somebody's
gonna send me an email and tell me I
prefer this good job you use the product
that is working for you I love it that
people have different options and that
different things work for different
people you use whatever works you dip
your clone into that then you put that
clone into in this situation we're going
to go into a rapid Rooter and that rapid
Rooter or a root riot or whatever type
of plug you're gonna use they're all
very similar they will all work in my
opinion whatever works for you again you
do that I've got 50 rapid rooters in a
tray and that tray has an insert that
keeps the rapid rooters in place there
in ten rows of five
I like that amount of clones per tray
because I can fill up two trays I know
that's 100 clones
that's a really efficient amount of
space it works really well the problem
is those trays are designed to have
those plugs really closely so they can
fit 50 of them into one tray the roots
the cubes work really well that closely
together the leaves up top kind of make
a mess when you have too many of them
that leafy that closely together you get
humidity issues you get transpiration
and respiration issues plants that are
on top of each other that are resting on
top of each other really have a lot of
potential to cause problems imagine if
all day
I just put my sweaty arm right across
your sweaty chess just all day in the
middle of the summer in a clone dome
just sweaty sticky stagnant you're gonna
get pissed off at my arm at about five
minutes but you're a plant you can't
move it you just got to sit there and
deal with it
that's what it is like if you've got
them too close together if they're all
crushed together the first thing is they
don't like being crammed together like
that and it will lead to problems down
the road these clones are going to be in
this dome for probably 14 ish days maybe
10 maybe 20 depending on your experience
depending on your cultivar you've got a
lot of options there but they're going
to be in there for a long enough time to
where we need to put some care into this
before we set ourselves up for failure
you've got the option to set yourself up
for success from the beginning let's
take all of the appropriate steps so I
like to cut the tips of the leaves off
because first it prevents the leaves
from resting on each other too
ridiculously there's enough foliage in
there even after I do the trim all that
excess foliage would just cause me
problems so I'm getting that out of
there
I am eliminating potential problems now
there is another reason why I cut the
tips off of those leaves I feel like the
less leaf there is on that plant is the
less that there is to try for that plant
to support that plant doesn't have a
root system it was living off of the
root system now it's only way to live is
through the leaves now I said that I
want to cut a bunch of that leaf off so
you're like wait how is it gonna live
imagine if you had 12-foot arms and you
had to hold the other six foot of your
arm up all the time
your arms gonna get exhausted you're
gonna use all of your energy just trying
to hold your arms out all day long now
that you've only got like probably two
something foot my arms are long so I'm
six five
you probably got two foot long arms
right it doesn't take a lot of energy to
hold those out you can do that you're
not gonna spend all of your calories all
of your life source trying to keep your
arms up so if you've got less plant it's
just less to sustain it is less stress
on the plant that plant only has so much
energy so let's not make it spin so much
energy keeping those leaves upright so
it can survive let's just cut it to
where they're short and then you notice
when they're shorter they kind of want
to stick up anyway so let's trim them
down a little bit and help them survive
we want to set ourselves up for a
success and by trimming those leaves we
kind of minimize transpiration that
gives us an advantage in the clone dome
I also think that when we cut those
leaves that the plant goes into sort of
a panic mode and it sort of knows it's
like hey I better route
because I'm getting all beat up up here
I better start doing something down here
so that I can survive now there is a
very fine line when cutting clones we
need enough leaf to keep a plant alive
but we don't want too much leaf to try
to sustain while we don't have a root
system we need just enough leaf to keep
the plant functioning to where it can
survive without a root system until it
develops roots but we also don't need so
many leaves that that plant can't
sustain those leaves without a root
system it's a very fine line we also
need to think about hormones each of
those leaves and shoots contain hormones
that contribute to the function of the
plant if we leave some of the shoots and
take off the leaves we will preserve
hormones and that will increase overall
success rate of our clones and our domes
so it is a good idea to remove as much
leaf as possible but be mindful that you
are also taking out hormones there is a
fine balance just like everything we do
in cannabis there is a balance there is
a pro and a con there's always some kind
of a balance and you always have to find
the fine line most of the time it is
phenotype specific so you just have to
develop a relationship with your plants
some plants are really challenging to
clone some plants will clone just by
looking at them you can knock a cutting
off and set it in a cup of water and
come back in the next day you got a
whole [ __ ] rooted plant some are not
that easy some plants really like to be
cloned in a rapid Rooter and dome type
of a setup some plants really prefer a
turbo cloner or easy cloner a narrow
clone or type of environment sometimes
it is very clone specific very strange
specific you may need to work on each
specific cultivar and get them figured
out sometimes in a commercial
environment I know which strains work
well together they go in this dome
sometimes I'll have a dome that is only
half full because it's a very specific
strain that is just that I need 25 of
these I'm gonna do them by theirselves
so that they have a better chance of
surviving I know they need to stay
sealed up for a few more days or they
need to be opened sooner or whatever I
know that those need special attention
so I will fill one dome with just that
one strain and treat it special on its
own that may be what you have to do to
get your clones to root that puts me off
on another side tangent our friend mr.
soll has recently reminded us too
start taking the domes off of our clones
sooner mr. soll and I see eye to eye on
many things this is one of them in
commercial facilities I quite often see
clones in domes that the dome has been
on there for far too long we can get
that dome off of there we can get those
clones active acclimated to the
environment get them out of that clone
situation and into some dirt much more
quickly if we start burping the clones
sooner and start gradually getting them
used to that open environment then just
remove the dome and let them live in
that tray for a couple of days with no
dome and they will be okay so let's work
on getting the clones off of the domes
earlier and we will see healthier
starting baby plants what is happening
is they're trapped in that environment
they can't thrive they can't expand
their roots are stuck they're pissed off
they're not getting the appropriate
nutrients they want to grow they start
getting nutrient deficiencies because
they're just angry for being trapped in
a little tiny dome in a little cube so
let's try to speed that process up get
them out of there and once again let's
do what we can to set ourselves up for a
success every day of every phase counts
in this new cannabis industry now since
we're talking about cologne domes I've
got one more great thing to add to that
if you were using an auto cloner an easy
clone or a turbo cloner whatever kind of
cloner you were using that is an aero
clone or type machine you do not need a
dome on that clone machine I find it
really silly to put a cloner on that
machine I find it really detrimental it
kind of slows you down it does more harm
then it does good if you were using a
turbo cloner an easy cloner whatever
brand it is I don't care if it's spring
from the bottom and you're getting your
roots missed in from the bottom you do
not need a dome on that clone or if you
take healthy cuts and you you can either
cut the base of that cut at a 45 degree
angle or for an easy cloner what I like
to do is cut that clone right up the
center of the stick I don't go too far
maybe a quarter of an inch is all you
need right in the middle boom now it
looks like you just took your your
forefinger and your middle finger that
are together now you just go and just
put a little slit right between them now
I think that when the water from that ez
cloner sprays up there it will start to
roll those tips up and the roots will
grow out of that little slit that you
just made
it is beautiful when you see it you'll
say holy [ __ ] that worked really well so
I like to cut a little slit right in the
middle of it
then dip it in my I use clone axe we
talked about this earlier use whatever
solution you like I use clone axe I dip
it in there then I put it in a perma
clone reusable clone caller from a clone
doesn't pay me I just think they are
great because they're reusable and I can
fit two cuts in one collar so quite
often you will find two clones per clone
collar when I'm using a perma clone so
you put it in the clone Ex gel you put
it in your permalink clone collar you
set it in the turbo cloner and you
forget it
if you have got the nutrients and your
turbo cloner dialed in correctly and
you've got your pH and your turbo cloner
dialed in correctly you will not have to
put a dome over those plants ever that
arrow cloner should be spraying
constantly if you do run into heat
issues you can do a cycle where the pump
is off and on for certain durations just
give it time to cool so that the water
doesn't heat up to it too ridiculously
hot because those pumps will heat up
your water depending on the size of your
cloner and your environment you may need
to give it a break I have had great
success running at 24 hours a day I have
had great success running it for
different intervals maybe like 45
seconds on in 15 seconds off maybe 30
minutes on and 10 minutes off a lot of
different cycles have worked for me if
you've got to experiment to keep your
water cool do the experiments that are
necessary let's get back on track here
you've got the water spraying up from
the bottom if you've got the pH dialed
in you've got your nutrient solution
correct you do not need to put a dome
over those plants they are going to be
so happy about that water spraying up
their little butt that they're just
gonna start dancing and they're going to
develop roots in seven to ten days and
these plants will be vigorous and
healthy but keep in mind I keep saying
this will only work if your pH and your
EC or ppm s are dialed in in your
cloning machine you have got to have the
proper numbers in there you have also
got to maintain the proper numbers in
your cloning machine you have got water
creating a bubbly mist all day long and
spraying at the roots of these plants
all day long in that machine you can
hear it from across the room
all day long that thing is moving that
water hasn't stopped you are going to
get evaporation you are going to get
slight leak sout of that machine anybody
there's ran that machine knows that
there's going to be a drip from
somewhere all the time you're going to
lose water also your plants are going to
be drinking some of that water you are
going to need to check on the water
level of that machine on a regular basis
if you're in a commercial facility the
first thing you should do when you get
there is check on the cloner is the pump
on is it making a funny noise does it
sound like it's spraying correctly if
it's spraying correctly you got a risk
just a couple of seconds of your life
and lift it up and look in there and see
if any of the sprayers are clogged I
know it's a real [ __ ] you're gonna get
sprayed first thing in the morning
you're awake now let's get it on just
lift that lid up and look and see where
all the clones getting sprayed if they
are you're good now you got to unplug it
now you get your EC meter or your ppm
meter whichever one you're using and
your pH meter and just stick them right
in that nutrient solution the machine is
off at this point you take the lid off
carefully don't break the bottoms any of
those clones but then you put your ppm
or your EC meter in there and your pH
meter in there and just test that
solution what are your numbers is your
pH in the acceptable range are your
PPM's in the acceptable range if not
adjust that [ __ ] is the water at the
correct height if not correct that [ __ ]
write it down I have a sticker on the
front of my cloner that shows when Mike
Lohner was last checked and who checked
it you just we have little stickers you
just write your name rhasta Jeff at 4:20
on Monday put that little sticker on
there now I'm accountable for that I
know that on 4/20 on Monday I checked it
the PPM's were cool the EC was cool the
water was cool all the plants looked
happy everything was fine also I have
another sticker on there that says res
clear I like to put res clear in my ez
cloners that makes sure that I don't get
any funky algae or anything happening in
there it keeps my plants nice and
healthy I put that in there every 5 days
so I will write a little note res clear
on Monday January 1st so I know that on
January 6th I know I need to put some
res clear in there but my main point
here is you don't need a dome on your
cloning machine that
Spray that comes from the bottom if your
nutrients and your pH and your EC and
your ppm and your water is not too hot
if everything is dialed in they are
going to love getting sprayed from the
bottom and they do not need a dome you
are only slowing yourself down by
putting a dome on plants that are in an
easy cloner then you have to adjust them
to the non domed environment if you
don't ever give them a dome they don't
know what that life was like they don't
ever need it again the reason we put a
dome on the clones that are in the rapid
rooters is because they're not getting
sprayed and there are little bombs with
constant fresh nutrient water they've
got to kind of learn to develop roots to
get the water they've got to eat from
the air they've got to eat from that
humidity that is kept in that domed
environment that is their only life
source they don't have roots they're not
getting a little bit de spray to get
tickled and kept alive so that is why I
feel it is silly and almost detrimental
to your garden to put a dome on your
clones that are in an easy cloning type
machine now I've got one more thing to
talk about we are going to start
wrapping up this podcast the last part
of this episode is I do not find it
necessary to put a dome on seedlings I
feel the same thing about clones in a
clone machine as I do
ceilings with a dome over them I believe
that putting a dome over a seedling will
make that seedling a little [ __ ]
I want that seedling to grow in the
environment with the rest of the plants
it doesn't need a dome I think putting a
dome on it is like wrapping it up in
bubble wrap
it's like nerfing my seedling I want it
to survive I want to put a fan on my
ceiling so where it gets really strong
and gets abused from the very beginning
I want my seedlings to grow and to know
that they are not going to be babied I
want them to come out and go ah [ __ ] I
better be strong or I just might not
make it in this world now that may be
different for me because I've got
experience and I have access to a lot of
seeds and I understand that seeds are
quite expensive so people really want to
baby them and not destroy them but I
feel like by putting them in a dome or
putting a bag over the cup with the
sealing in it you were kind of slowing
it down you're kind of giving it a
participation trophy and making it a
little [ __ ] so I think it would be
better if we did not put domes over the
seedlings I also do not like to use heat
that's when germinating seeds I feel
like that sometimes will make them too
hot and you do have the opportunity to
rose to your seeds if you've got them in
a paper towel in the baggie then you put
them on a heat mat you're gonna cook
them I think that if you put them in a
baggie in a paper towel on a plate and
on top of the refrigerator that is more
than enough heat and you should have
great success there if you've got one of
those old-school TVs a big box TV who
still has that [ __ ] but if you've got
one of those old Sony Trinitron 's the
back of that bad [ __ ] is the perfect
heat to germinate your new seedlings all
right podcast world this was a great
episode I feel like this rosin had me
[ __ ] super rambley once again I want
to give a big shout out to my friends
over at apothecary Farms for always
taking great care of me big shout out to
the entire Pueblo crew big shot up to
the spring screw and big shout out to my
friends up in Denver hope everybody's
feeling high Ryu guys get to hear this
big fist bump to the entire Apothecary
family ladies and gentlemen I want to
thank you for listening to this episode
if you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
and you'd like to make a financial
contribution to the show you can do so
by going to patreon.com slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
once again big thank you big shout out
big fist bump and big grow from your
heart hugs to everybody who's
contributed to the patreon campaign in
the past and the present and in the
future ladies and gentlemen make sure
you follow me on cannabis I talk about
cannabis on almost every episode now
cannabis is a cannabis friendly social
media application you cannot buy sell or
trade cannabis but you can post your
cannabis related content other popular
social media platforms have been
removing cannabis related accounts so if
you are a cannabis related photographer
a cannabis enthusiast if you were part
of the cannabis community and you would
like to find more like-minded friends
join us on cannabis we were posting our
flower photos we're posting our dab
videos we're posting our concentrate
pictures we are hanging out and creating
a brand new community on cannabis
cannabis is free it's available on your
Android and your Apple device give it a
download create a screen name join us
give me a follow join cannabis and catch
a buzz with us I just made that up catch
a buzz with us say you guys should use
that cannabis if you heard that
you better use that [ __ ] alright also
please subscribe to my YouTube channel
go to the YouTube co2 value to buy sound
like an old guy go to the YouTube there
and pull up the old grow from your heart
podcast click subscribe on my channel
leave some comments on my videos let me
know what you think of the show
I do appreciate all of the YouTube
interaction if you've got something
you'd like to say maybe you've got a
product you'd like me to review maybe
you'd like to sponsor the podcast or
maybe you've just got a cannabis
cultivation question send me an email my
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com you know that i would love
to hear from you ladies and gentlemen
that is all i've got for this episode of
the girl from your heart podcast i want
to thank you once again for joining me
be good to yourselves be good to one
another I want to give a big shout out
to my friend sun-grown bagsied and until
next time take a phat dad and give your
mom a hug for me