all right welcome to the show podcast
world it is time for episode 456 of the
growth from your heart podcast a quick
Thursday episode for you this episode of
the show is brought to you by our
friends at seeds here now if you need
new regular feminized or Auto flower
seeds in your garden I highly recommend
seeds here now and you can find them at
www.cms.gov double og full spectrum
extract from our friends at green dot
labs this is a blend of legend oh gee
and sour double on the package the
flavor is described as pine sour and
lemon I would absolutely agree with all
of those flavors there is certainly a
pie ninis on the inhale there's a
sourness on the exhale and the lemon
kind of lingers on the tongue there's
also a very gassy aroma the lingers in
the room when you smoke the sour double
the potency label says that this product
contains 74 0.73 percent THC I really
love this concentrate I picked up a four
gram jar and it lasted two and a half
days so big shout out to our friends at
green dot labs for the delicious double
og full spectrum extract ladies and
gentlemen boys and girls smokers and
growers in this episode I'm going to
read a couple of emails but before we
get there I would like to do a shout out
to a few of our friends from patreon
let's send a giant grow from your heart
podcast shout out and a thank you to my
friend baked pwn I want to send a giant
shout out and a thank you to my friend
Tyler how about a big giant girl from
your heart podcast shout out and a thank
you to Mike F of course another giant
shout out to our buddy Mike how about a
big giant shout out to Dustin P of
course a giant girl from your heart
podcast shout out and a thank you to
Darren W of course a shout out to Baz
and last but certainly not least holding
it down out there I want to give a giant
grow from your heart podcast shout out
and a fist bump to our buddy farmer John
I want to thank each and every one of
you for the continued patreon support if
you would like to learn how to support
the show on patreon you can do so by
going to www.hsn.com
buddy who is supported the show in the
past in the present and in the future
your continued support does mean a lot
to me that support keeps this podcast
free for everybody I've put out over 450
episodes I've never charged a penny for
any of my content the patreon is what
allows me to produce free content that
patreon covers the cost of my computer
that patreon covers the cost of my
internet connection every month my
internet connection is expensive here
that patreon covers things like
microphone covers so that when Mike
comes over him and whatever guest has
been over before they don't have to
share the same microphone cover because
that's a little bit funky it goes for
things like that so big shout out to
everybody who supports the show on
patreon thank you I appreciate it and it
makes the show possible I feel like I
just did an NPR sales drive or something
ladies and gentlemen without your
donations NPR wouldn't be here it's not
like that you guys without the patreon I
would still do the podcast I just want
to make sure that the people who
contribute know that I appreciate it so
big thanks to everybody now let's talk
about the next order of business have
you joined the new cannabis friendly
social media app known as cannabis
cannabis is a free app that is available
on your Apple or Android device all you
have to do is go to your App Store and
download it and it is a lot like some of
our favorite social media applications
but it is very cannabis friendly we
cannot buy sell or trade cannabis on
cannabis but we do encourage and promote
you to post your cannabis related
content
post your ganja photos post your weed
plant photos post your bud photos post
your concentrate photos post your dab
videos post any cannabis related content
you have got on cannabis join us come
catch a buzz with me on cannabis it is
free and it is a good time we're
building a great community over there
we've got a lot of friends I have got a
lot of people following my feed I think
you would enjoy cannabis if you like
this podcast you're gonna love cannabis
so come join us it is free download it
create an account
give me a follow I am Irie underscore
genetics on cannabis come check out my
fine cannabis photography also get a
chance to win a free I read genetics
t-shirt or other prize packages I do a
lot of Giveaways and
test on cannabis so don't miss out join
me on cannabis it is free and it is a
great community another thing I should
mention about cannabis is we recently
added an IR e genetics group that's
right if you were growing or interested
in growing or interested in learning
about
I read genetics there is a group
dedicated to I read genetics on the
cannabis application the app is new it
may be hard for some people to navigate
I'm going to walk us right through it
all you've got to do is open the
cannabis app then on the bottom there is
a little magnifying glass type icon
you're probably familiar with that click
on that one then there is a I know this
is a lot of steps already at the top
there's a search bar if you click on
that search bar it will bring up the
group's when you click on that group
scroll down when you click on the group
tab scroll down and you will see I read
genetics they're in alphabetical order
click on their join the group at this
time it has got 47 members it is a brand
new group there are a lot of great
photos in here I encourage you to join
the group and post some photos if you've
got any questions about I read genetics
that is a great place to ask them
there's a great community there ready to
help you I am there quite frequently and
the irie army is there all the time to
have your back so join us on cannabis
and join the IRA genetics group alright
that's enough talking about cannabis you
guys let's get into an email a lot of
people send me great emails they've got
a lot of wonderful grow questions they
need help in their garden I've got a
stack of emails two feet tall so let's
not waste too much time
let's help some folks out I know I said
I've got a stack of emails in front of
me but if anybody out there has a grow
question and you would like some help on
the show maybe you've just got something
you'd like to say you can send me an
email my email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com I would love to
hear from you let's jump right into this
first email this is from someone who
calls themselves st. Stephen hey brother
good to hear from you the email from our
friends st. Stephen goes just like this
hey Rasta Jeff first off I have
purchased two humidity and temperature
monitors they are both giving me wildly
different readings
I would like my information about
temperature and humidity to be as
accurate as possible both inside and
outside my tents are there any
temperature and humidity monitors
which you would recommend there are a
couple I will recommend but before we
get there I am kind of curious about
your experiment that you have done here
you bought to temperature and humidity
monitors those are hygrometers I think
we call those and they were giving you
wildly different readings I want to know
if you bought two of the same kind are
they the same thing did you buy two
different hygrometers did you buy one at
one time and wanted another is one
battery operated as one I don't know
what the other one works is the battery
dead on one is what I'm getting at so
are they the same kind are they the same
quality then my next question is are
they in the same place how far apart are
they in your area it is very common in a
gross space to have wildly different
readings just a few feet apart from each
other in a grow environment imagine if
I'm up here by the light six or eight
feet up high in the room and I come down
just directly straight down go three
feet down it's going to be drastically
cooler just a few feet down if we don't
have appropriate air flow then imagine
if you move off three feet to the left
it's gonna get much cooler so you're
going to get drastically different
readings throughout the room possibly
you may have microclimates based on the
size of the room you may have 90 degrees
sections and 78 degree sections based on
the size of the room and the efficiency
of your air flow equipment so my first
investigation is what kind of
hygrometers are we using are they the
same thing are they the same quality
because if we're using different
monitors and we're getting different
results that experiment is a little bit
invalid we need three of the same or at
least two of the same tools to do the
same experiment to expect similar
results if you're using the same kind
this may sound crazy but I would suggest
buying a third and compare that third to
those to maybe get a more expensive
model that's what you came to me for
you're asking if there is something that
I would recommend of course I would
recommend APO grow unit they are very
great monitors they monitor your
temperature your humidity you can water
the temperature of your nutrient
solution if you have got a reservoir
with water in there there's a little
probe that just measures that
temperature at all times it will do the
calculations on your VPD for you so you
know what your vapor pressure deficit is
in the room
or the monitor is hung at all times they
are quite affordable they are not
expensive units at all they're very easy
to get a hold of what I really like
about the pol grow unit is I can look at
it on my phone all I have to do is open
my phone go to a website I've already
got the tab saving my favorites says pol
grow click on there once I man it just
takes a couple of seconds to refresh the
dashboard and that shows me the
temperature and the humidity in my room
I know immediately what is going on I
can tell if the lights are on I can tell
if the lights are off I can tell if the
air conditioner did or did not cycle on
as needed I can tell if the extraction
fan to get rid of the humidity cycled
off and on as needed also I can set
parameters in the pol grow unit it will
send me an email if something gets out
of the parameters which I set so if I
tell it hey when it's 87 degrees in here
send me an email and when it hits 87
degrees I get an email and it says hey
Rasta Jeff your pol grow unit has
detected that you are above desired
temperatures and then I can go oh [ __ ] I
need to go to the grow if I'm not where
that grow is I could drive to the grow
which ever grow it is I've got these in
multiple locations that I can log into
and look so I could say how's the grow
in Pueblo West that one's doing good
how's the grow in Colorado Springs
that's doing good and I can look at all
of those grows while I'm chilling at
lunch I don't have to go anywhere I can
monitor those conditions so the first
monitor I would recommend for your grow
environment would be a pl grow systems
minder unit you can find a pl grow
systems minder unit at pl grow dot
systems then while you're there use
coupon code Z fyh 25 and you will get 25
percent off at checkout what 25 percent
off that's a quarter of the price
offering to pay 75 percent of the price
for a minder unit because you have got
it grow from your heart podcast coupon
once again that is PL grow dot systems
the coupon code is gfy H 25 they gets
you 25% off at checkout my friends at PL
Gro were kind enough to send me a couple
of minder units to give to my listeners
so I am going to do something super kind
here st. Stephen it sounds like you need
so as a gift from myself and PL Gro
systems I would like to send you a
minder unit to put in your grow and find
out what is happening in your grow room
we need to get that room dialed in and
this is a perfect opportunity to help
somebody out so this podcast will come
out on August 22nd I'm going to give you
until August 31st to send me an email
and claim your prize' I know who sent me
this original email so don't try to pull
a fast one on me reply from the same
email address and I will set you up with
a brand new free Pio Gro minder unit to
put in your grow room once again my
friend Saint Stephen who sent me this
email yes this is real you have got
until August 31st to send me an email
and claim your prize' and I will be
happy to send you a pl grow minder unit
to play with in this grow room it is
yours to keep I would just like some
updates and some info on how well it
works for you how about that ladies and
gentlemen a random giveaway in the
middle of a podcast now there is more to
this email we should cover
they also say I would like my
information about temperature and
humidity to be as accurate as possible
both inside and outside of my tents I
agree so I'm wondering now if you are
putting your two individual hygrometers
and thermometers inside and one outside
the tent and checking those readings and
getting two wildly different readings or
if those two thermometers are actually
sitting next to each other and showing
you wildly different readings that's
alright we're gonna figure it out
because you've got a minder unit coming
your way pretty soon we'll get your room
all dialed in once you get that minder
unit you can find out what actually
works which thermometer hygrometer is
working for you you can place that one
outside of the tent you can put the peel
grow system inside of the tent you
should be all set up if you like the pl
grow enough you can get another one
and put that outside of the tent you can
have it all dialed in and pay a lot of
good attention you're really gonna have
a lot of fun with this there is more to
this email question number two I am
lucky to have central air conditioning
coming through a vent into my grow room
that is very beneficial it goes on to
say I have been struggling with heat
problems due to the 2000 watt and 3000
watt LEDs that I am using on top of that
plants are in flower and are transpiring
tons of moisture into the air it's like
gardening and a rain forest in here I
just added a duck fan to boost the
airflow from the air-conditioning vent
and it's helping to cool the room down
but I still need to do more my question
is should I have the cooler air blow
directly into the tent via one of the
lower openings in the tent or should I
cool the room outside of the tent all
right we've got some great questions in
here we've got a lot of great
information to work with we've got a
tent it has got a lot of lighting in it
and it is in a small room that has
central air we're trying to cool the
tent it is getting hot because it is a
super hot summer this year let's think
about some of our options the main
question is do I want to blow air
directly into the tent via one of those
lower openings or should I cool the room
that when which the tent is in ideally
we would cool the room in which the tent
is in but that is going to be a struggle
because you're probably venting the hot
air out from the tent directly into that
room then I don't know where it goes
from there if that hot air is trapped in
that room it's going to be hard to cool
that entire room if you're able to maybe
open the door and get some air exchange
where that hot air can get out of that
room travel through the rest of the
house that would be helpful I understand
if that is not an option sometimes we do
need to keep the grow rooms contained
when you go opening that door you expose
odor you expose noise you expose the
option of discovery which may not be
something you can open yourself up to so
you may need to run that ducting
directly to that lower passive vent near
the bottom of the tent now depending on
how cold that incoming air is that's how
I would judge how closely to the plants
I put that incoming air if it's really
cold I would back it off a little bit if
it's just nice if it's like 78 degrees
you may allow that to blow directly
right onto the plants think about any
temperature of air blowing directly on
you for too long will become annoying I
don't care if it is the perfect
temperature any air blowing constantly
on you for a long duration of time
eventually will become annoying if
you're a plant it will happen more
quickly the plant can't move
the plant can't reach over and turn the
fan off that plant is stuck there so if
you've got a duct blowing on one section
of plant pay very close attention to
that one plant you're VPD in that
section your vapor pressure deficit is
going to be highly disrupted because of
that constant airflow and you're
introducing that cool air right to that
one area now if you do that you do need
more than one mix fan in that grow you
need to stir that fresh air in there and
get that environment mixed up so we
don't create like I said earlier
microclimates so if you do duct that
duct right to the bottom there feel how
cold it is could you stand having that
blowing on you 24 hours a day at that
temperature if not the plants don't want
it either if it's a good temperature
allow that to blow in the plants you may
be blowing this across the roots of the
plants they might be hitting right
across the pot area that won't be bad as
long as it is not super cold the lower
area can tolerate a little cooler
conditions that's expected it's shady
down there the plants should tolerate
that quite well now if you were blowing
Arctic chill air if it's [ __ ] 68
degrees or lower in there those plants
may not be super happy about that so pay
attention temperature of the air being
delivered through that ducting that is
going to make all of the decisions for
you if it's super cold you've got to
back it off and cool the room which is
ideal anyway in a large commercial
horticulture environment that is known
as a lung room it's more common to treat
the room get the temperature the
humidity the co2 levels correct in that
room then pipe that air into the actual
gross space it's easier that way that's
how it's done in other countries that's
how it's done in large flower production
that's how it's done in the Dutch
production where they do all the flower
production most of the flowers that we
have come from Dutch production
facilities they're shipped all around
the world in those facilities they use a
long room type environment in those
facilities they are also ridiculously
clean and it is very impressive
I wish American grow facilities would
take some lessons from that but I'm
getting way off track now ideally you
would cool that entire room and pump
that air into the tent that era would
just move in through the bottom vents
hopefully you have got an extraction fan
at the top pulling out
the heat and humidity that will create
just a normal airflow the air will come
in through the bottom it'll pass up over
the plants and go right out through the
top naturally heat rises so that will
help encourage the heat rise up to the
top your humidity is gonna go up to the
top hopefully you've got a carbon filter
in there so you're sucking out the heat
and humidity now the key is that all of
that stuff that heat the humidity all of
that air is going to be stuck in that
room unless you've got somewhere for it
to go I don't know your exit strategy
for that air I don't know your plan to
replenish that air you need to get rid
of that stale stagnant co2 depleted air
and replace it with some fresh co2
enriched oxygen that is the appropriate
temperature and the appropriate humidity
the most common ways to do that are
ducts in and ducts out most commonly
you've got a power ducked out sucking
air out and that naturally draws air in
it's all about displacement it works on
its own that may not be an option for
you I understand that what you may have
to do you said that it is very humid in
your environment you may need to add a
dehumidifier that will help you get the
humidity down in that room that'll make
it feel much more comfortable for the
plants so if you're unable to add some
sort of an extraction fan or a blower to
remove that stale stagnant air from the
room or possibly open the door you may
want to consider adding a dehumidifier
to your room and again with the
dehumidifier you've got the option of
putting that directly in the tent or you
can put that in the room in which the
tent is in if it sucks up a lot of space
a lot of square footage in your tent I
would consider putting it in the room if
you are growing on tables or trays and
you've got plenty of floor space why not
throw that the humidifier down there on
the floor where you've got some open
real estate again I don't have all of
the details about your grow I don't know
what you've got going on so I can only
give you options based on the idea the
blueprint that I've built in my head
based on the information you have sent
me but it sounds like the dehumidifier
may be the next thing you need to get
for this grow another thing I would
consider I don't know if this is an
option you say that you are watering a
lot and the plants are transpiring tons
of moisture into the air an idea is how
about watering less water a little bit
more frequently so that way you don't
have all that water in the room all of
that water in the pot all the water from
transpiration it is all
in the air maybe don't put so much water
in there let it cycle let it do its
thing then water twice a day instead of
one big fat watering once a day again I
don't know the size of pot you're
working with I don't know if you're in
Cocoa I don't know if you're in hydro I
don't know if you were in soilless mix I
don't know your options that is simply a
suggestion that may help you out less
water more frequently may be a benefit
for this type of environment now one
thing that comes to mind you may simply
be over watering if you have got that
much air in the room you may have put
too much air into the plants they can
only let out as much as we give them and
if we are giving them too much they may
try to let out too much now that could
be environmental that could be watering
that could be a lot of things we are
going to figure that out because you're
gonna get a PL minder unit you'll be
able to dial in the VPD then we can
decide how to set up the ducting we can
decide how to pipe that cool air into
there then we can decide if we need to
add a dehumidifier I would absolutely
work on cooling the room and circulating
that air as much as possible I would
absolutely consider getting some ducting
going some sort of extraction you need
to evacuate that old air if possible if
you cannot evacuate that old air I would
recommend putting a dehumidifier in the
room to reduce the relative humidity in
the room then another thing you may want
to consider is co2 enrichment you may
want to augment the co2 levels in that
room since it is all sealed up and your
air is not going anywhere anyway pump
that [ __ ] with co2 and your plants will
go cutbank Kapow again I don't know if
you've got an extraction fan I don't
know your ducting setup it says you just
added a duct fan to boost air flow but I
don't know where that is coming or going
from I don't know if that is just a stir
fan but I hope I gave you some useful
guidance and advice I know you're gonna
make great use of the PIO grow minder
unit that will be coming your way so big
thank you for the great email if you
have got any follow-up questions based
on the information that I have given you
today I would love to hear back from you
I'm already expecting one message from
you so let me know if you need more
information get back to me so we can get
you that pol minder unit and then let me
know how it all goes once you've got the
ducting set up and the minder unit in
place
once those are added in we will know if
you need to add the dehumidifier then
from there we can decide if you want to
add some co2 then we will make
additional adjustments and we will get
that room going Kabang
Kapow all right st. Stephen I want to
thank you for a great email I look
forward to getting this Piell grow
minder unit to you so we can get your
grow room dialed in once again I want to
give a giant shout out to our friends at
PL grow dot systems make sure you check
them out give them support show them
some love follow them on social media
and let them know that you learned about
them through the grow from your heart
podcast alright ladies and gentlemen it
is Thursday so this is going to be a
short episode I am going to start
wrapping it up I want to thank you guys
for hanging out for this episode don't
forget to support the show on patreon at
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
don't forget about the pl grow minder
coupon code it is g FY h 25 @ PL Gro dot
systems make sure you support my friends
also don't forget to join us on cannabis
and don't forget to join the IRA
genetics group ladies and gentlemen boys
and girls pimps and hoes smokers and
growers I want to thank you again for
hanging out for a short episode I'll be
back Monday with brand new content I
want to give a giant shout out to my
friend Q grows and until next time take
a phat dab and give your mom a hug for
me