[Music]
yeah what's up everybody it's time for
another episode of the AG gr culture
podcast your source for Cannabis News
education and conversation welcome to
episode number 46 I'm your host rosta
Jeff and I'm coming to you this week
with a solo episode it's the day after
Christmas and all my friends are hanging
out with their family so I put together
a quick show this week and I'll probably
do a short episode next week also I hope
everybody had a wonderful holiday
holiday whichever holiday you choose to
celebrate I hope it was wonderful for
you I owe a huge thank you to my mom for
an amazing Christmas gift I cannot
believe what my mom put together for me
uh big thanks Mom and also a big thanks
to my Queen uh thanks a lot Angela you
made Christmas awesome I'm glad you
spent that with my family and I your
family now also I owe big Christmas
shout out to the Garden of Weeden uh
thanks for letting me be a part of your
Secret Santa that was really cool I felt
blessed to be there that was a good time
I think I'm still dabbed out from the
dab Gauntlet we did and I'm wearing the
socks that uh I scored at the secret
santa um exchange right now I got my
Huff socks on and my feet are nice and
warm so and it's a cold ass night here
in Colorado holy [ __ ] it's snowing out
it's windy as [ __ ] so these sucks came
in perfectly thank you guys if you're in
Colorado I hope you're
warm uh next week is a uh it's New
Year's Eve actually so I will be at the
String Cheese Incident concerts in
Broomfield Colorado with my lady uh
we're taking a little mini vacation so
next week and this week will'll be kind
of easy shows without a ton of info but
I do promise you guys that I'll get back
to the original format with tons of info
and great guests at the start of the
year uh the holiday's got everybody in
chaos everybody is We're All Growers and
we all have jobs and families so most of
the guys just decided to hang out and
not do a show with me this week which is
cool I don't I don't blame him I hope
you guys are having fun big shout out to
everybody who has been on the show who's
taken some time out of their life to
come put in an hour an hour and a half
with Agro culture podcast that's pretty
cool I appreciate it the listeners love
you guys so I got a few people to thank
and a few things to remind you guys of
but before we get into too much of that
part let's pay the bills let's start
with Nature's green remedies this
podcast is brought to you by our good
friends at Nature's green remedies.com
visit Nature's green remedies.com for
gag green genetics llata Labs s City
rare dankness mile high can Aventure the
Cali Connection IE genetics and many
more trusted Brands Nature's green
remedies is running a special for all of
our loyal podcast listeners if you type
in coupon code Frosty you'll get 15% off
your whole order and you'll get free
priority shipping at naturegreen
remedies.com but this coupon code does
expire on the 1 so you have until
December 31st to get this coupon code in
I will have a new coupon code for you
around the start of the the year so a
big thanks and much respect to Nature is
green remedies.com
this podcast is also brought to you by
our friends at hyro indoor growing
supplies hyro indoor growing supplies
has two locations to serve Colorado
check out the Denver store at 6271 Beach
Street or the peblo location on 618 East
4th Street in Pueblo Colorado guys if
you go to the Fourth Street location in
Pueblo and there's no parking take a
right uh right at the corner there's a
taco place right there and then turn
into the kind of area and that first
door is actually hyro there's parking in
the back go park back there it's a lot
easier to carry your stuff out of the
back also so check out hyro for
competitive pricing and a great
selection of indoor grow supplies don't
forget that hyro runs a special for the
podcast listeners when you check out at
hyro tell them you listen to the igro
culture podcast and they will give you
commercial pricing on your entire
purchase because they had a whole bunch
of advanced nutrients stuff at the PUO
location and they're dying to get rid of
it if you went in there and made them an
offer on a bunch of advanced nutrients
products
I bet burn and Jesse would hook you up
tell them I listen to the Agro culture
podcast Jeff said to come in here and
get these nutrients and they'll give you
a deal so this podcast is also brought
to you by our good friends at tree
Thugger dcom tree Thugger dcom live
music lifestyle magazine check out tree
Thugger doccom for concert and Festival
news and reviews
www.re Thugger
tocom all right much respect to all the
sponsors for making the show possible
big shout out to the Mystic Roots band
that song that just played was from the
Mystic Roots band They let me play all
of their music on the show so every
episode I try to give them a shout out
Mystic Roots band they are awesome
they're SoCal ree kind of funk re they
got a lot of cool stuff going on they're
probably going to play in your
neighborhood sometime soon those kids
travel around actually they are in uh
Europe right now the last pictures I saw
they were in Italy um man it's good to
see the Mystic Roots man in Italy I
think they're just out having fun I
don't know if they're playing but all
the pictures I've seen is just them on
vacation and that is welld deserved guys
I hope you guys are having a great
vacation shout out to cat and cot in the
Mystic Roots band check them out they're
great uh let's see got a bunch of
comments and stuff to read what do I
want to do first oh I just smacked the
microphone with the papers I'm sorry
guys I might have taken a bunch of dabs
tonight so I want to remind you guys
that we're going to change the name of
the podcast the show is not going to be
the IG gr culture podcast for much
longer it will be called The Grow from
your heart podcast uh like I've said
before there's an agricultural
educational entity that has the moniker
Igo taken and also I was told that
iTunes doesn't appreciate people ripping
off the eye so we're just going to be
respectful we're going to change it to
grow from your heart cuz that's what
this is all about I've always said grow
from your heart uh if you grow your herb
your cannabis your medicine from your
heart uh you will produce better
cannabis if you don't grow your cannabis
from your wallet or your ego or your
camera I know I take a lot of pictures
but I grow dank herb because I grow from
my heart that's why I'm able to take the
Dank pictures I'm not thinking about my
wallet I'm not thinking about the
Harvest weight I pay attention to that
stuff but when I'm in the grow room I'm
thinking about what's going to happen
after I grow this herb properly after I
flush it after I chop it down after I
trim it after I cure it after I give it
to my patients that smoke this cannabis
I've got an older friend uh his initials
are DC I don't really want to call him
out on the show but he's who I think of
when I think of medical cannabis he's a
good friend of mine and I'm his
caregiver when I see him consume the
herb that I put my love into I can see
him get something inside of him feels
better and it's not just a physical
thing it's not just him getting high
there's an emotional thing that happens
to that guy when my medicine makes him
feel better and that emotional thing
happens back to me and it fulfills my
heart so I grow from my heart and you
should grow from your heart as well and
I think it'll improve your outlook on
your weed it'll improve your cannabis
overall it'll improve your relationship
with your patience uh it'll just make
things a lot better grow from your heart
quit growing from your wallet quit
growing from the scale quit growing from
your camera quit growing from your ego
and grow from your heart so the grow
from your heart podcast that's our new
motto grow from your
heart um coming with a new name requires
a new logo um I can't change the name
until I have a sweet ass new logo so if
any of you artists out there would like
to uh throw me down a grow from your
heart podcast hosted by rosta Jeff logo
I would appreciate it I don't have a lot
of money to tell you the truth but I
would compensate you in some way that
made you happy it may take time it may
take payments it may take multiple gifts
over time
we will work something out because uh I
like to pay back my community that helps
me out and you like to help your
community out so do me a favor make me a
logo I have this Vision uh Jesse said it
actually it's a seed like if you've ever
grown pot when you germinate seeds they
crack open and the Tap Root comes out of
there when that cracks open it kind of
makes the shape of a heart so if you
could kind of make that into a heart
with the the little thing coming out of
it but then make that tap rout actually
turning into maybe I don't know you can
get creative but I want to see that
heart coming out or just whatever with a
heart in it or grow from your heart of
course I like red yellow and green I'm a
Rastafarian if you do that I've never
said this on a podcast if you're going
to make a
Rastafarian themed logo the red goes on
the bottom you guys it's red gold and
green Yes red yellow green but the red
is on the bottom so it's actually green
yellow red so do that properly if you're
going to make me a logo because I'm a
rosta and I want it right because it's
almost disrespectful to put your logo
with the colors upside down if you're
bringing it in a Rasta way I'm not going
to [ __ ] about it I'm just saying do it
the right way if you're a real rosta
you'll understand why you want it the
right way it's like if I put the
American flag upside down it would piss
a lot of Americans off so just imagine
you people getting the roster flag
backwards it kind of frustrates some
people I don't give too much of a [ __ ]
about it I'm just letting you know that
you're doing it wrong um yeah also um we
need a new theme song I've been playing
The Mystic Roots band it sounds awesome
but wouldn't it be a lot cooler if I had
a customized theme song that was like
something about grow from your heart I
don't even know how it would go but
maybe some danceall Reggae or something
grow from your heartom I don't know
that's your job not mine if somebody's
got a song for me I got the same deal
for you as I do the logo some kind of
kick down if you're in Colorado I'll
hand you packs of seeds you'll get iy
genetic seeds uh feminized or regular or
both we'll work something out uh I'll
give you a t-shirt I'm going to get more
hoodies made more of the iy genetics
hoodies are being planned out shout out
to handmade apparel they're uh we're
negotiating had to kind of hesitate a
little bit I'm going to do it at the
start of the year just for tax purposes
and then we'll get some more hoodies
maybe you'll get a hoodie out of the
deal so I'm begging I'm just asking for
a new logo and a new theme song for the
grow from your heart podcast because I'm
too busy putting together shows and
growing gardens and teaching people how
to grow herb to uh actually be able to
make a new logo and I don't really have
good art skills so if you do that i'
appreciate
it uh let's see what's the next part
I've been getting a ton of emails dude
holy crap I've been getting so many
emails tweets and Facebook messages
about the podcast it's overwhelming in
such a good way I want to thank
everybody for messaging me uh the huge
response I've gotten in the last few
episodes has really inspired me to push
the show to the next level I've been
putting more time into the shows and
doing more research because I want to
keep bringing the best show that I can
uh every time you guys message me that
makes me want to try a little bit harder
you know I just want to step it up uh
let's see I've got a couple of tweets
that I saved here I've got them in my
phone so I got to search through the
phone I know I just said I want to bring
you guys better shows as I bring you a
half-ass New Year's Eve show I don't
have any guests or anything I thought
I'd have people here so I don't have a
lot planned but I'm goingon to make it
dope for you let's see big shout out to
party McFly he says rosta Jeff bro oh
yeah you can tweet me at the Agro
culture or igro it's igro culture or you
can also tweet me it's rosta Jeff 420 if
you just want to hit me directly I check
them both quite frequently like once a
day probably this dude says bro I love
the podcast it's the first podcast I've
been into I'm going to have to start
from the beginning and catch up um okay
I'm embarrassed that you're going to do
that because honestly well let me not
say I'm embarrassed I guess I'm proud
now the first uh 25 episodes or so I
didn't know what I was doing
I turned on the microphone and just
blurted out a bunch of [ __ ] and whatever
came out of my face is how the show went
and then I started making too many notes
and it got a little weird but I feel
like I'm kind of comfortable with the
microphone now I just turn it on I start
I make a few bullet points and start
going and it all comes out I'm not so uh
so hypercritical of it now but dude uh
party McFly and the way you wrote your
Twitter handle is pretty cool I can't
even uh I don't know what how you did
that but it's @ frivolous f r i v o l if
you want to follow party McFly dude
thanks for a tweet that uh I hope you
listen to every single episode if you
want to listen to them all they're on
iTunes um I think the last 10 are on
Stitcher but every single episode all
the way from the beginning all the way
up to whatever episode you're on will
always be on the iy genetics
colorado.com website I'm going to have
to change the tab on there we're going
to do a lot of changing you guys don't
get lost uh it's still going to be in
the same feed so if you're listening on
iTunes or Stitcher or whatever the feed
will still be the same if you're coming
to the website it'll still be easy to
find don't lose me when I change my name
I just have to do it it's going to be
super easy I hope so party I'm rambling
I took a bunch of dabs a lot of dabs I
made these dabs even uh party McFly
thanks for messaging me on Twitter my
next tweet came from Roadrunner it's _
Runner 420 he said listening from the UK
still underground here but great to see
you guys leading the way for us great
show keep it up dude thanks a lot uh
those words of encouragement mean a lot
to me like I was saying everybody wants
to hear that they're doing right
sometimes you just put in a bunch of
work and nobody says anything and you're
like ah but you guys have been making me
feel like I'm killing it so awesome
thank you we've gotten uh 6,500 listens
on some episodes uh the episode with
King Cola is probably going to hit
10,000 episodes eventually that will be
the first one to do it which is
remarkable because it's a newer episode
and there's been a lot of time on other
shows and they haven't been listened to
nearly as much as the episodes with King
Cola so shout out to King Cola and
episode 35 with drying and curing also
has been a huge success if you guys
haven't listened to that one it's time
go back and listen to number 35 if I had
a recommendation for you 35 and then uh
the ones with King Cola I don't remember
the numbers I could pause and look hold
on all right I went back and checked um
I honestly think that from 35 on is
where if 35 through 45 are some of our
best episodes ever there are a couple in
there uh 44 is random chatter because uh
we got chatty and then 41 is chatty
stoners but for the most part the 35
through 45 are some of my favorite most
proud episodes um 45 more about Organics
with King Cola 43 intro to Organics with
King Cola those are some great episodes
number 42 intro to NPK that got a lot of
response uh the episodes about building
your grow 39 and 40 those really crushed
it 37 was planning your grow space that
did a lot and 35 drying and curing
definitely has been listened to a whole
bunch so thanks a lot guys for listen
into those it's good to know that you're
paying attention and liking it I'm so
rambly today I'm glad I turned on the
microphone guys take a dab I'm going to
take a dab right quick I've got some
dabs sitting here this is a a mix of
stuff that I recently grew uh my homie
Spence taught me how to make this hash I
usually wasn't making it was letting
other people do it but why not be
self-sufficient right this is a white
widow uh Girl Scout cookies no there's
no cookies in here it's white widow
Golden Goat Flo ghost OG G there's
Gorilla Glue number four in
here um there's some lemon Jeffrey in
here there's Lemon Skunk so this is
quite a nice mix I'm going to take a big
fat dab you guys take a dab with me
please I want to give a big shout out to
Giddy Up in emotech I'm hitting this
gnail I've had it turned on for about a
month now I haven't turned it off I
don't
think oh that was a big dab wow and this
Gil has not not giving me any trouble
it's been awesome I love it it's got a
USB port on the front that'll charge up
your phone so you can plug in if you've
only got a limited spot of plugs you can
plug in your email or the gnail and then
you can plug in your iPhone into that
and charge your phone while you're
taking hot dabs it's amazing I like it
so shout out to Giddy up thanks a lot
bro that was a good gift came right
before
Christmas all right let's see I did the
tweets I want to thank uh Jake and Emily
wow I just yelled into the microphone
I'm sorry I hope the software fixes that
I want to thankk Jake and em for the
emails they sent I will be in touch very
soon you guys I haven't responded to a
bunch of emails it's been the
holidays been a little overwhelmed I'll
get back to you I promise but uh I'm
interested you guys said some things and
I'm interested I'm paying attention also
I want to give a big thanks to
G35 don't even ask guys that's his name
he can be G35 if he wants uh Brent M and
also Fred Garvin want to thank you guys
for all your interaction messages uh
tweets emails Facebooks all of the above
I appreciate the emails guys so keep
them coming uh send them to ulture
hotmail.com [ __ ] I'm going to have to
change that too we're going to make
another email address since we're
changing everything I can just keep that
and I'll forward it but we'll make up
another one uh episode 50 is coming up
guys and I'm planning a small
celebration episode I'm going to try to
get uh as many microphones as I have I'm
going to try to get that many people my
software or my setup here I could
probably put in 20 microphones with all
the inputs and other in lines I've got
but I don't really you know we'll try to
get we'll get Adam and Jesse and maybe
Spence hey Maddie you're invited I'd
like to have Maddie on the show it'd be
great to have the first chick on the
show be you I'm sorry the first woman I
won't say chick that's sexist we'll have
the first woman on the show will be
Maddie try to correct myself there uh
I'd like your guys' input about episode
number 50 I've got a few questions for
you so if you want to email me or tweet
me now's a good time I want to know what
were some of your favorite moments on
the podcast so far what stood out to you
if there's an episode or a moment that
stood out tweet me and tell me what it
was I want to celebrate that on episode
50 uh what did you guys learn is there
something that you learned that really
stood out that really like if you ever
heard somebody say one thing and you're
like oh my god I've been listening to
this guy ramble for a whole hour and
that's the one thing that made it worth
it if you got one thing that you learned
uh or something that really stood out
let me know I want to know what you guys
learned from me or us uh also who's your
favorite guest on my podcast I've had a
lot of people on Spence uh Jesse Mike
Adam King Cole
Addison deor was on the show via
interview that was one of my most proud
because that was my second episode and I
called up Addison like I had a podcast
going on I didn't know what the hell I
was doing it was kind of funny of me to
do should try that again and see how it
goes uh also I want to know what would
you guys like to hear next I talk a lot
and why not make it be about something
that you guys actually want to hear you
know cuz if I'm just going to talk you
could tell me what you want me to say
instead of me just rambling and rambling
and
rambling all right so send me some input
you guys it's I ulture hotmail.com you
can tweet me at ulture or you can find
me on Facebook um send me a message
there just search for igro culture I've
got a personal Facebook if you guys find
that uh I don't accept every friend
request right away I kind of I'll troll
you a little bit and see who you are
before I approve your stuff CU I'm
getting if Facebook's getting weird I'm
sorry uh I don't I don't want to be that
open anymore if you want to see I'm
completely open with the iy genetics
stuff and the iGo culture stuff all of
that is fair game I tweet uh I Instagram
dude my iy genetics Instagram blows up
and I'm going to brag a little bit my
mom spoiled the [ __ ] out of me for
Christmas she knows that I've been
looking at this Nikon camera and so on
Christmas uh the gifts were all done and
then she slid this other box toward me
and just smiled and had a tear in her
eye and when I opened it I kind of got a
tear in my eye also cuz she hooked me up
with the Nikon d32 uh the D3200 the
package with the extra lens in the bag
and [ __ ] and uh I've been eyeballing
that thing for quite a while so thanks
Mom again that's why I shouted her out
at the start of the show but holy [ __ ]
dude that's the one of the best gifts
I've ever gotten uh not to discredit any
other gifts but I mean holy crap that's
the camera I've been eyeballing for
months and Mom's bought it for me so
thanks again mom uh that means that my
Instagram is going to improve uh you're
going to see better pictures you're
going to see more angles you're going to
see more zoom you're going to see better
better better just cuz I've got better
gear I've been shooting those Instagram
shots you see if you follow me on IG
those shots come from a Panasonic Lumix
point and shoot camera that was $199 at
Best Buy and that's what I'm pulling off
so if now that I've upgraded to this
freaking badass camera I think you'll
see some improvement all right I've been
rambling about that holy crap but follow
me on Instagram if you want to it's iGo
culture or iy genetics I've got them
both I post a lot of stuff on I genetics
I post about every three hours I try
just to keep it moving holy crap guys
I'm dabbed out and I feel like I'm
talking really really quickly let's take
a Big Yoga breath together and slow down
a little bit
[Music]
yeah that's a sound to me calming down I
do that [ __ ] sometimes I need to calm
down for this part uh this is important
uh I've got a friend whose name is
Deacon gray Deacon gray is a comedian um
he's from Oklahoma but he currently
resides in the great city of Denver
Colorado if you've gone to a show at
Comedy Works there's a good chance
you've seen Deacon gray as an opening
act he's a little white-haired dude that
tells weed jokes uh he talks about being
from Oklahoma he's hilarious in my
opinion um Deacon gray has made me laugh
my ass off multiple times and uh
recently I'm going to go to this website
that I've got here I got to search
through it real quick sorry I'm
stumbling because I was trying to be
somber about this let's see I got to
back up one
tab so Deacon gray uh this page is
called Help Deacon gray grab cancer by
the throat um help Deacon gray grab
cancer by the throat Deacon was living
his life and slinging his jokes and
doing his duties as a new Talent
coordinator Comedy Works everything was
hunky dory except that his friend say
hunky dory when he noticed he had a lump
on his neck hm Better have that looked
at well he had it looked at and they
wanted to look at it a little closer
like take a tonsil out closer which they
did the bad news it's cancer you guys
the good news it's a highly curable kind
of cancer the same kind the Nuggets
Coach George Carl beat recently his
prognosis is excellent his spirits are
good but he's got several weeks of
chemotherapy and radiation treatments to
get through so it says click more I'm
not going to read all this to you guys
you get the point what I'm headed for is
Deacon gray has made me laugh my ass off
several times he's funny as [ __ ] dude he
tells weed jokes his delivery is amazing
and in return for making me laugh I want
to shout out his website so that we can
raise this guy a little bit of money
he's got throat cancer we got to get him
through it he can't smoke cannabis right
now cuz he's got throat cancer but he
can definitely eat Edibles he can do
stuff like that so if you live near
Deacon gray and you see him lay an
edible on him a good edible don't give
him some [ __ ] give him a good clean
quality edible and then after that go to
giveforward.com and search for Deacon
gray I'm looking for the my it just
wants to show me here we go it's GE
forward.com
fundraiser uh there's a whole bunch of
stuff so just go to giveforward.com and
search for Deacon gray it's DEA n then
his last name is Gray g r a y I truly
appreciate it uh you can donate as
little as $5 somebody on here donated
one of the last donations that I saw was
$1,000 and I thought that was really
generous I wish I could give somebody
$1,000 for their cancer treatment and
help but man I would contribute a little
bit to this I won't disclose how much
that's my personal donation but I will
donate to this cause uh as soon as I'm
leaving the tab open so that I can do it
right after the show here but I'd
appreciate if you guys just went through
a couple bucks to deakon gray I'm not
trying to beg for him the dude's got
throat cancer he made me laugh uh
laughter his medicine that [ __ ] means a
lot to me so I want to give forward and
help out Deacon gray so once again I'll
read out his website it's
giveforward.com and just search for
Deacon
Gray he's really close to his goal he's
trying to raise $10,000 he's already got
$
4,120 he's almost 50% of the way through
39 donations so he's getting there
that's freaking awesome uh Deacon gray
shout out brother I hope you get to hear
this somehow I hope somebody relays this
to you much respect you made me laugh a
lot this is the least I can do for you
so I want to go and read a news article
that kind of hit home for
me because uh well you'll understand why
I'm a seed breeder I am I am rosta Jeff
I do the agriculture podcast but I'm
also the guy that owns iy genetics I I
am iy genetics I do the breeding I do
the selection um Jesse is actually part
of the team now none of his stuff is
available through me yet but it will be
very soon so Jesse is part of the team
big shout out to Jesse Jesse grows
follow him um you'll see his projects
coming through but you'll understand why
this hits home now this is from the
Cannabis the article was written by
Jason bevens it was from The Denver Post
originally it was published December
mber 24th uh at 50:5 p.m. it says pot
Grover's new Quest US Patent protection
for cannabis seeds Ben Holmes gently
loaders the turntable needle onto the
album and traffic's medicated goo begins
to play Steve Winwood's wistful tener
sweeps through the Centennial seeds
laboratory my own homegrown recipe will
see you through everyone stole from
Steve Winwood Holm says his foot tapping
as he injects a syringe of dark syrupy
liquid into his gas
chromatograph no one is stealing from
Holmes a self-taught scientist engineer
farmer and cannabis seed geek who next
month will take a rare step to apply for
a patent on a laborous created cannabis
super strain if it is awarded the US
patent on Holmes medical grade auto2
strain will be the first to protect a
cannabis plant and a first step in
establishing plant breeder rights for
Growers who only a few years ago were
considered criminals now I said the The
Strain is called Auto 2 uh it's spelled
OT t o and then the Roman numeral 2 it's
not Auto like autof flow so I just want
to clear that up it's the same word
essentially I'm saying Auto and I would
say Auto if it were spelled the other
way so if you guys are haters of
autoflowers uh that's not what it is
it's just Auto like uh the dude from The
Simpsons it's probably got uh some
Canadian influence I would assume right
anyway uh this industry came up in
stealth born in basements and crawl
spaces holes said but now with companies
forming and making larger Investments
the desire to protect intellectual
property is becoming Paramount bleeding
edge stuff right here and I this is kind
of hits home to me because I breed seeds
and I create strains and I see people um
I don't want to say ripping them off
because I don't know if they thought of
it before me if they just happen to post
it to Instagram after me but people we
like to borrow names in this industry
for strains we uh we think we're coming
up with something original you guys are
going to hear a thumping noise I'm
moving this microphone it's sliding
sorry here we go got to tighten this up
tighten up now here we go sorry if that
sounds like [ __ ] in the recording I'm
not going to censor that or edit that
out at all so making stuff my strains
get stolen often and I can't complain
about it because I'm actually using
other people's strains to make mine
somebody had to make the seeds for me to
breed with but just give credit I guess
but now people are going to be able to
patent stuff so what I'm worried about
mainly are people with more money going
to punk me and patent my [ __ ] and
squeeze me right out are you going to
see other people claiming that they own
Capleton that's what I'm worried about
and I don't I don't know the legal parts
of this enough to know but I do know
that I don't have any money compared to
a lot of these people I am small time
compared to a lot of these people
compared to Greenhouse compared to the
Cali Connection compared to DNA I am
nobody and those guys could squeeze me
out tomorrow if they wanted to but
luckily we're a friendly industry big
business doesn't give a [ __ ] about
friendly industry they'll squeeze us all
out by doing this kind of stuff because
they've got the money that's what I fear
but I'm a paranoid hippie uh I've been
on too many fish parking lots to have a
clear head about that kind of [ __ ] I
just always think the the paranoid part
so let me read more more of the article
it says indeed gone are the days when
pie-eyed long hairs haphazardly hurled
pollen into jungles of pot plants hoping
to meld two strains damn that's such a
great cliche in one [ __ ] sentence I
love that let's see what we got we got
pie-eyed long hairs so you can see those
guys pie eyed long hairs all I'm high
and I got big eyes right I long hair so
halfhazard Le hurling pollen they're
just got this male plant and they're
just beating it into the room into
jungles of pot plants so no strain
selection here let's just put a bunch of
females in here and yeah sorry I'm just
talking [ __ ] out about this sentence it
was great hoping to meld two strains uh
today's top readers are geneticists
taking years uh to weed through
carefully engineered generations of
cannabis to elevate the most desired
traits now that's a pretty accurate
statement I will agree with that uh some
of the new super strains are high in
canabidol or CBD one of several dozen
canabo chemical compounds in cannabis
and the plant's major non- psychoactive
ingredient a man I was proud cuz he said
chemical compound but then he said
ingredient and then that ruined him I'm
so critical of these guys' articles and
I bet I say some really dumb [ __ ] on the
podcast cuz I'm high but these guys have
editors and proof readers and [ __ ] I'm
just here spouting it out I've taken
dabs and drank mate and can't be held
accountable for anything I say after
that all right CBD has been credited
with relieving some epil epileptic
seizures prompting widespread calls for
additional research uh other more
utilitarian super strains are resistant
to mites or the crop killing powdery
mildew that plagues grow operations
across
Colorado um crop killing powdery milw
that plagues grow operations across
Colorado it sounds like we only have
that here they have powdery milw all
over the place bro I don't know why
you're singling out Colorado it does
happen
here all right I'll quit ranting about
that part let's get more into the
article here uh where was I some super
strands are simply super Stony with sky
high levels of tetra hydr canol or THC
the psychoactive compound in
cannabis uh you got to scroll way down
there's like seven ads here here we go
the gas chromatograph is home's key in
shaping Auto 2 a high CBD low THC strain
he hopes can fuel medical therapies the
50-year-old Gizmo separates molecules
and converts them into an electrical
impulse a green line tracking across
screen reveals the THC level in the
substance that line will be the Baseline
for a measurement of Auto 2 Holmes
produces a well-worn label tablet Laden
with acronyms and molt values from the
gas chromatograph those figures reveal
his painstaking progress toward breeding
the THC out and the CBD into his
treasured varietal it is in many ways
the result of a lifelong career
dedicated to breeding growing cloning
engineering and charting the most useful
cannabis plants as Winwood sings the off
covered Dear Mr Fantasy Holmes shares
his plans to protect Auto 2 which ranks
among the most valuable of his
collection of 400 varieties of cannabis
seeds both marijuana and hemp most of
which are stored in additional freezer
in his lafa lab in addition to the
patent he hopes to be the first cannabis
breeder to secure protection under the
plant variety protection act uh the
seminal plant breeders rights
legislation from
1970 uh the value of the seed the value
of that seed longterm could be very very
valuable an annuity said Holmes a father
of two who serves on the state's
Industrial Hemp advisory committee and
is collaborate collaborating on the
University of Colorado's groundbreaking
cannabis genomic research initiative and
if you guys haven't checked that out you
should uh I'll say it again it's the
Cannabis genomic research initiative
there's a link to it in this article on
the Cannabis so if you can find this
article on the Cannabis it's the article
about pot growers new Quest US Patent
patent protection uh this link is in
that article so everyone who does this
wants to produce something with
durability he said a seed with good
utility that produces well uh can have
longetivity for Generations which is
very true uh I've read a few strains
that uh I can keep those seeds around
and that Capleton the Bounty Killer will
be good forever I'm going to get back
into the article here that was kind of a
random rant it says Holmes is sort of a
modern-day Luther Luther Burbank who you
should read about guys the P pioneering
American botanist in horticulturist who
developed more than 800 varieties and
strains of plants in the late 1800s and
early 1900s his name is Luther Burbank
if you want to Google him uh Wikipedia
that guy Burbank faced intellectual
property challenges in his career as he
created still Herald peaches plums
daisies and the world dominant Burbank
Russet potato Holmes follows burbank's
lead offering a few types of seeds to a
single large distributor who can flood
the market in the first year before
anyone can take it as their own by
cloning the young seedlings uh so this
guy's idea and that's a good idea uh
he's going to put out so many seeds so
quickly that everybody will know it's
his because it'll be flooded but nobody
will uh be able to claim it before they
can cut a clone because he'll be so well
known for putting it out that's pretty
smart he just puts out so many that
they're like oh it's got to be him cuz
everyone's got the seeds yeah that makes
sense to me I like that it's a good idea
I might start hoarding certain strains
when I make seeds now just make a whole
bunch of them until I can do that no I
wouldn't do that I'm just joking sorry
guys by the time copycats have cloned
holmes' strains he's already uh he
already has made his money he also
licenses the use of his Heirloom Seeds
but not the extra special seeds he
doesn't want copied uh really the focus
minus any patent protection is non-
licensing and careful selection of
Distributors Holmes said State trademark
protection can Safeguard the name of an
innovation within a state's borders but
protecting intellectual property through
state law is a bandage patents are
exclusively federal marijuana is illegal
under federal law and federal law
Trump's state law so this guy could get
completely denied for his attempt at
patenting his cannabis strain but if he
does he's going to open the floodgates
for a lot of [ __ ] and people will start
patenting their own strains I bet you
and that's that means I'm going to have
to get on the game uh get lawyered up a
little bit harder for a lawyer that
knows about patent laws too God this
game is getting so vast you have to have
your hands in everything now to be able
to keep up in this kind of a business if
you guys want to move to Colorado and
get in the Cannabis industry I recommend
you do like a year of research before
you get into it maybe come here and talk
to somebody who's in the industry uh I
could help you out a little bit I don't
know a lot about getting into the
industry I don't like into if you want a
dispensary or something it I don't know
how to get you into there that's going
to be hard so be careful let's see what
else do I want to talk about in this
episode I wanted to talk about the new
year is coming up and the new year is
always a good time everybody says they
want to do New Year's resolutions and
stuff I think it's a good time to start
a new grow calendar or a schedule to
kind of make a game plan clean up your
grow room get everything started fresh
again and then instead of just cutting a
bunch of clones and having a bunch of
plants and veg and having some [ __ ] over
here and some more [ __ ] over here think
about what you're going to do
think about how many lights you have in
each space how many flowering lights do
you have how many plants fit under each
of those lights how long do they take to
flower okay so you got about 65 days
underneath this light right well in
about 65 days you need more plants to go
under there but you need a couple days
to clean that you got to trim you got to
sweep up you got to wipe the walls down
you got to clean all the dirt out you
got to repot you got to get [ __ ] back in
there so remember that in like 9 weeks
you need more plants in there so you got
to cut clones about 3 to four maybe 5
weeks before that depending on how much
space you have you got to get your [ __ ]
ready so start planning I think it's a
good time for you guys to start working
on an advanced grow
calendar I don't know how you want to do
it there are a lot of ways to go about
it do it your way is what I recommend
maybe we'll make an episode out of that
but it's the start of the year coming up
and just make a calendar because if you
pop a bunch of seeds you cut a bunch of
clones and you got a vetro full and a
flowering room full and you don't have a
full plan of where those plants are
going you're going to run into some
problems overcrowding causes problems
overcrowding promotes problems you can't
see that plan on the bottom you can't
tell there was a spidermite infestation
there you got spidermites everywhere you
got way too many plants the shit's out
of control just be diligent think in
advance think ahead of yourself be like
five steps ahead that's how you be a
good grower kind of try to predict
what's going to happen in your plants
don't just watch and see what happens be
like oh this is going to happen because
I've grown weed a million times and I've
paid attention at least 10 of them all
right I'm ranting again but that's
really important I think and it's the
start of the year so it's time for that
to happen it would be a good time for
all of that and clean up all your [ __ ]
right at the start of the year if it's
if your carbon filters are all mie buy
some new carbon filters if your bulbs
are all shitty get some new bulbs it's
the start of the Year spoil your Gardens
they spoil you back that's my advice
that's my personal advice from the from
the heart of rosta Jeff God I must be
dabbed out I'm saying from the heart of
rosta Jeff grow from your heart right
that's what I
say all right I'm going to wrap up this
episode you guys I hope you join me next
week it's going to be be another quick
episode I'm going to go see the string
cheese on uh the 29th 30th and 31st The
String Cheese Incident at the Broomfield
it's the First Bank Center in Broomfield
if you happen to run into me say what's
up don't be shy I'm the tall white guy
with dreadlocks I'm probably wearing an
iy genetics hoodie uh that if I'm a tall
white guy with dreadlocks and there's a
little short chick with dreadlocks next
to me and she's sweet looking uh that's
probably me there's going to be a lot of
people that match that description but
I'm probably wearing the ivory hoodie
and she's probably got the ivory hoodie
I might have uh I'll try to remember to
take some stickers or something with me
and throw them in my back pocket so that
if you say what's up shake my hand give
me a hug I'll give you a sticker um
it'll be really funny when you hug the
wrong hippie cuz there's going to be a
bunch of tall white guys with dreadlocks
there so say what's up to me at the
String Cheese Incident if you see me I
hope to see you there maybe we'll smoke
down or something I'll have some dabs
with me if we're not in the show I don't
know how I'm going to sneak my rig into
the show but I'll definitely have a
spliff all right let's wrap this up um
man happy New Year you guys you guys
might be when are you listening to this
you might hear this on New Year's huh
let me look at the when does this come
out when does this come out
bro go to the calendar I'm not even
going to press pause in the recording
I'm just going to do it we're going to
try not to do any editing anymore what
do you think do you like it when I just
talk a lot and don't uh you like it when
I talk about my life and my stuff and I
don't just keep talking about weed and
have it all scripted or do you do you
want me to keep it tight I want to know
what you think so this episode will come
out on the
29th oh [ __ ] you guys will probably I
hope you're listening to this on your
way driving to the cheese show wherever
you are so if you see me at string
cheese give me a hug uh the next happy
New Year also because Wednesday is the
new year so happy New Year I hope you
guys are safe dude don't drink and drive
um be safe take care of one another keep
an eye out for each other I don't I want
everybody to be able to see all your
friends again tomorrow so have a happy
New Year you guys I love you guys thanks
for listening to the show there's
nothing cooler than having people that
email you and tweet you until you're
listen they're listening so now the show
is over please go to iTunes or Stitcher
and find the iTunes or Stitcher main
page search for igro culture find the
review section give me a festar rating
type in a comment let me know what you
think of the show and I will read your
comments on the show don't forget that
the show is available on iTunes Stitcher
and every single episode will always be
archived on iry
genetics.com
um find us on Twitter Instagram and
Facebook search for IG gr culture I'm
going to have to change all of that
stuff to grow from your heart podcast I
hope all of those services will let me
change my name at least once not sure
how it's going to work but I'll do it uh
I'm more focused on the string cheese
concerts I'll be gone for 3 days I'll be
gone for like 4 days so I'm more worried
about that right now though I am um
getting the show stuff done because I
don't have a logo yet and all that but
once I get the logo going we'll get it
happening at the start of the Year you
guys it'll all be rocking stay with me
please don't don't abandon me right
around episode 50 that'd be weird uh
also follow iy genetics on Instagram
that's not going anywhere well unless I
reg unless Instagram [ __ ] me like
Facebook did if you guys are interested
in sponsoring the podcast or if you have
a product You' like me to review send me
an email at AGR culture hotmail.com and
I'll give you all of the info you need
uh we do need a theme song and and a
logo uh big super huge shout out to my
ninja Spence also big shout out to
Maddie big shout out to my moms for the
super cool camera and other cool gifts
big shout out to Angela love you babe uh
thanks again for listening you guys
until next time take a fat dab give your
mom a hug for me