hey what's up ladies and gentlemen boys
and girls pimps and hoes chicks and bros
smokers and growers friends and foes
welcome to episode 465 of the Grove from
your heart podcast this episode of the
show is brought to you by my friends at
seeds here now if you need new regular
feminized or Auto flower seeds in your
garden I highly recommend seeds here now
and you can find them at www.ctvn.org
axe tract which means it is saucy and
has chunks of diamonds and crystals in
it the cross is a blend of ruby red and
to peel your face on the package they
describe the flavor as hops fuel and
grapefruit rind I honestly did not get
any hops I am NOT a fan of hops so it is
just fine that I do not catch the hops
aroma I do get a hint of fuel the
grapefruit rind is there but honestly
this tastes more to me like strawberries
and hints of watermelon I really enjoy
that fruity flavor it's a big switch
from what I normally go for when it
comes to concentrates lately I've been
buying the more savory flavors so it was
a nice change of pace a nice change of
aroma and flavor and definitely a
different buzz ah this went straight to
my head made me forgetful made me kind
of have a hard time paying attention
the potency label says 68% THC something
about this concentrate makes it hard to
focus so big shout out to our friends at
Green Dot labs for the delicious India
Pale Ale full spectrum extract I highly
recommend this concentrate this is going
to be a quick Thursday episode I do have
a couple of questions from some friends
before we get there let's do some
shoutouts to our friends on patreon I'd
like to send a giant grow from your
heart podcast shout out and a thank you
to our friend willies armpit I'll a
giant thank you to our friend Mike f as
always a giant grow from your heart
podcast shout out and a thank you to
David OQ also another giant shout out to
Mike H I also want to send a giant grove
from your heart podcast shout out thank
you and a fist bump to our friend farmer
John and last but certainly not least I
want to
a big thank you and a fist bump to our
friend darren w big thank you and big
shout out to all of the people who have
been supporting the show through the
patreon campaign if you would like to
learn how to support the show you can do
so by visiting www.disabilitydenials.com
for a new cannabis breeder I probably
have a lot of other titles cannabis
advocate
cannabis activist cannabis photographer
there's a lot of other things that I
could probably be labeled as but I am a
grower I am a breeder those are the
things I find the most passion for
followed by photography so that is where
my heart lies I do not find much
interest in making concentrates I have
done it I know how to do it I understand
the process concentrate making is just
not where my passion lies
we've got great friends like Spence
we've got great friends like keV we've
got all the people that work at
apothecary
all the people that work at green dot of
the wonderful highly trained highly
skilled concentrate makers across the
country I am letting them do that work
for me it is a dangerous process it can
be a dangerous process making
concentrates that concentrates I enjoy
the concentrates I prefer are made with
butane if you are not familiar with a
butane extraction process it sounds like
it can be very dangerous yes you are
correct it can be very dangerous we are
working with a very flammable
hydrocarbon and any small mistake could
result in an explosion so I am leaving
to concentrate making up to the people
with the proper labs the proper
equipment and the proper training so
when it comes to acquiring safe reliable
koala
he concentrates I tend to shop at some
of my favorite dispensaries I always
mention apothecary I like the apothecary
concentrates they're a great concentrate
they have a great price point and
they're great folks I also really enjoy
Green Dot labs they make great products
they are a little higher in price point
compared to some concentrate companies
but you get what you pay for
I like their concentrates I like the
full-spectrum extracts I like the
batter's and I like their cartridges so
apothecary farms and Green Dot labs are
probably my two favorites there are
several companies competing for third
place
unfortunately I live in a smaller market
so the availability isn't as broad for
myself as some folks in other markets if
you're in Denver or Boulder you've got
many more options I'm down here in
Pueblo I've only got a few stores to
choose from that is not true I've got a
lot of stores to choose from many of
them are a waste of time so I've
narrowed it down to two or three stores
most of those stores they're top-shelf
product is either an apothecary extract
or a green dot labs concentrate so that
is why I buy my concentrates from the
dispensary now why am I not buying my
own strains because in Colorado we've
got some ridiculous rules
anything sold in a Colorado dispensary
must be grown and produced in a Colorado
marijuana Enforcement Division regulated
facility all of that makes sense we have
a program called seed to sale tracking
and it is exactly what it sounds like
from the inception of a seed from the
planting and germination of that seed
all the way through growth all the way
through harvest all the way through
trimming then whatever type of
processing is done to that flower if it
is turned into an extract if it is
turned into an edible if it is thrown
away at this point it is tracked all the
way to the point of retail at the
consumer level so it will be tracked
from the flour from the plant to the
flour dried and cured then one it is
sent once it is sent to an extraction
facility or an edible maker it is
tracked then they process it then it is
tracked that batch number of your flour
now becomes the batch number of that
edible or that concentrate that number
is now attached to that so if there's a
problem in the future with your
edible or with your concentrate we can
trace back which flower batch that came
from we can tell which grow that came
from or the opposite if we detect a
problem in the flower or in the
concentrate because every flower is lab
tested and every batch of concentrate is
lab tested if a problem is detected we
were able to recall the products that
were made from that by following that
batch number down the line so there is a
seed to sale tracking system there was a
time period where we were allowed to
bring plants into that seed to sale
tracking system the governing body who
regulates the plants coming into that
system sort of turned a blind eye and
allowed us to enter plants into that
system for a limited amount of time the
plants had to come from somewhere so for
a short period of time the marijuana
enforcement division played dumb and
acted like all of these plants were just
part of some immaculate conception these
plants were just manifested and ended up
in our growth facilities and entered
into the computer they did not know what
else to do there's not another way for
plants to enter a market to come from a
non-legal market to a legal market there
had to be a way to get plants in so that
was the opportunity they gave us a short
time we were able to enter our genetics
if you had seeds there was a way to get
those seeds in the system if you had
clones there was a way to get your
clones into the system those became your
plants for the future so now there has
kind of been a door closed on the
opportunity to enter new genetics into a
medical or recreational recreational
that's a new word recreational cannabis
facility in Colorado now if you want to
introduce new genetics into your grow
they have to come from seeds which were
produced within your marijuana
Enforcement Division regulated facility
so you have to grow a plant and you have
to find seeds within that plant then
those seeds need to be entered into the
system as new seeds then you can
germinate the seeds then they become veg
plants there is a procedure that they
follow in the computer system to
document that process so in theory the
entry time for new genetics in the
facilities has been cut off unless those
genetics are produced within a facility
so
theory the only way to introduce new
genetics would be to breed inside of a
facility which is very costly and very
ineffective we need every gram of
profitable flour to come out of that
facility as possible so we are
struggling to produce all of the flour
we can we can't spend time making seeds
in one of our rooms
what oftentimes happens is during
harvest we may discover a handful of
seeds in one plant we may be chopping it
up and a bunch of seeds will go tink
tink tink and will go hey this whatever
plant over here plant number seven six
five three three just dropped out a
bunch of seeds and then you go to the
computer and you say plant number seven
six five three three dropped a bunch of
seeds you actually wave the seeds so you
can subtract that weight from your
harvest total you document how many
seeds there were which plant they come
from I already forgot the number seven
six five something [ __ ] whatever we
[ __ ] forgot what plant that came from
that happens a lot make up a number
that's what we do in the meed system I'm
just kidding you guys that never happens
we always do it by the book anyway find
out where those plants came from
document the number write it down
subtract the weight now you've got seeds
in the computer with a parent plant that
they came from the meed would like to
know the male and female oftentimes in a
grow environment who knows where they
came from if it's a commercial
environment it was probably a herm it is
not illegal I don't know if I want to
share this advice it is not illegal to
enter pollen into a commercial facility
if you own a facility if you're the
manager and you have got pollen you can
take your pollen and pollinate your grow
at your own disposal if that's what you
want to do that is not illegal the
pollen is not regulated by the marijuana
Enforcement Division so if you do want
to breed that is an option in a
commercial facility but that is where
the new genetics need to come from so
unless this facility acquired some of my
genetics a long time ago during that
window of opportunity they do not have I
region attic strains to work with now
before these rules were put in place
some facilities and some people were
able to acquire my seeds or my clones
and enter them into their system so at
some facilities there are I read
genetics plants in there grow I have
seen lemon Jeffrey in several facilities
I've seen the Kalonji I've seen the
Kabletown and I've seen the Grateful dog
and a couple of
but I really don't know where the plants
have gone we are able to transfer plant
from facility to facility once they are
in the system but I don't know who has
what and where they go what I do know is
that apothecary farms and Green Dot labs
do not have any I read genetics in their
stable at this time now one good thing
about the extract market in Colorado is
something known as a 50/50 deal this is
a little bit of a business talk here for
the Colorado concentrate market there
are a lot of different business
strategies available for a concentrate
company but a very common practice is
this hypothetically let's say you are an
extract company you are big dick gems
extract company you are making
concentrates your job is to make the
best concentrates for the dispensary
you've got to grow you grow your own
flowers and you process those you put
them on the shelf and you [ __ ] you've
got a vertical line you're growing
you're extracting you're putting it on
the shelf and you're making money
there's nobody else involved maybe
you've got your own store maybe it goes
to a different retail location either
way as long as you're growing extracting
and then selling the extract you were
making plenty of profits now at some
point your grow will slow down or you
will be between harvests and you won't
have anything to process now you're not
making any money you are only relying on
that retail product that has been
stocked on the Shelf that may run out a
great way for a concentrate company to
make extra income and broaden their menu
is what is known as a 50/50 deal let's
say that there is another grow
who wants concentrates but is not
attached to a concentrate company they
will take their flowers or their trim
material and give that material to the
extraction company that extraction
company will do their job of processing
your material into top-shelf
concentrates and they also package it
into individual grams that are properly
labeled for retail sale now once the
flowers are processed you have got a
bulk batch of processed concentrates in
retail
ready containers this is where a 50/50
deal quite often comes into play the
concentrate company needs to be paid
for their extraction work they did a lot
of work they did the processing they
trained employees to do it they used
equipment to do it they packaged it they
probably paid for the packaging so now
there is a fee owed to that extraction
company many times the grower will let
the extraction company keep 50% of the
finished product as their payment so if
that commercial facility gives big dick
Jim's extraction company so many grams
of cannabis they extract it and they
turn it into 100 finished prepackaged
grams of cannabis and they have reached
a 50/50 deal that means that the grow
and the extraction company each leave
with 50 grams of concentrate now that
grow gets to put that concentrate on
whatever retail shelf they want they've
got money to be made they've got a
product they can sell that the
concentrate company in turn puts those
concentrates on their shelves they have
just doubled their inventory and
hopefully in that process they've added
some new flavors and added some variety
to their menu so that is a 50-50 deal
they run the product then they split it
50/50 with the grower the grower sells
it however they want if they're
retailing it's got to stay legal this
all stays in the legal market then the
extraction company puts it on better
shelf and they sell it at their store
that is how they get paid on their end
another thing that can happen sometimes
is the original grower will buy back the
product if they run it they've got a
hundred grands at the end they sell it
back to them at a premium price which is
pre agreed upon before the extraction is
run so they run the material then the
grower actually buys it all back from
them then they send it to their retail
location and they can put it on their
retail store or they can spread it out
to other retail locations maybe they've
got multiple stores they want to spread
it out to different stores maybe they've
got a wholesale deal lined up to where
they already have a customer that wants
to buy a bunch of it and then they can
put that on their shelves but in most
cases it is either a 50/50 deal where
the extraction company ends up with half
of the final product and the grower or
the facility ends up with the other half
of the final product and that gets
transferred to a retail store or it is a
buyback deal where the grow sends the
material and then they run it and they
say there's a hundred grams we'll sell
it back to you with this much they buy
it back then they put it on the retail
shelf and they mark it up
quite liberally that is where the money
is made in the concentrates so that is
the long explanation of why when you
hear me talking about what I am dabbing
on the podcast it is rarely an eye
region attic strain because most of my
stuff is not in the Colorado marijuana
Enforcement Division system a few
facilities do have it but you have to
find a facility that has got the plant
who is also ran the extraction who also
has it on the Shelf available in my area
for a desirable price those are a lot of
variables to hit sometimes elevations in
Colorado Springs will have some
wonderful lemon Jeffrey concentrates but
they also let different concentrate
makers make the product they let
different companies run the material so
the product comes out differently
through each processor some of those
processors I approve of some of them I
will not buy their product so sometimes
they may have lemon Jeffrey concentrates
on the shelf and I still might pass on
it so that is part of why I'm not
smoking my own concentrates there is
another little branch to this question
you see me growing a lot of flowers on
social media I post a lot of pictures of
quality flowers I am a breeder most of
what I am growing is loaded with seeds
most of the seeded plants do not make
quality hash material that is so beat up
by the time I take the seeds out of it
that it is a waste of time for a
concentrate maker a concentrate maker
could have ran quality product and had
much better results they don't want to
waste their time on my beat up seeded
material so I don't have that made into
concentrates that is usually given to
friends and they turn it into edibles
because they do it with their own small
personal time their personal kitchen
we're not using a lot of big space we're
not wasting a lot of time not wasting
anybody's energy so I give it away to
people and they make edibles out of it
that is what happens to the material
from the seeded plants now when you do
see me doing phenyl hunts of my new seed
runs because once I breed seeds the next
step is to grow them and see what I have
created that's part of the fun that's
one of my favorite parts those buds are
finished they are not seated most of the
time I take those buds with me to events
like the Indo Expo or the dude grow show
or whatever
vending event or community event or
social event may be happening this week
I took a bunch of
to the Phish concerts I did not bring
any of the cannabis I took with me back
we smoked every single bud so that is
what happens to most of the flower I
grow I take it to events I take it to
concerts I smoke and share it with my
friends if you show up in my house and
you're like I haven't had weed in a
couple of days we'll make sure you leave
here with a couple of buds and stoned as
[ __ ] so that's what happens to my flower
you see all those pictures of seeded
plants all that finger-banged material
gets given away people make edibles out
of it then those buds you see from the
pheno hunt runs those nice photogenic
buds I smoked those with all of my
friends at the events I had multiple
jars on the table at the dude grows cup
I had multiple jars on the table at the
concentration celebration
I had several jars on the table at the
endo Expo I smoked all of that cannabis
with all of my friends so that's what
happens to all of that material
all right podcast rule that got really
carried away that took much longer than
I had anticipated so we're going to jump
right to the next bullet point really
quickly no more testers is my next
bullet point recently on the podcast I
mentioned that I need some people to
test a few new seeds for me um thank you
my email inbox exploded I have never
gotten more emails and please stop I
found enough testers I may have read
your email and not replied yet because I
got so many that I'm kind of filtering
through them and looking for my
favorites don't be offended if I did not
select you as a tester this time you
were still in my potential testers
folder that I will go back to in the
future when I'm looking for more people
to test new strains so big thank you to
everybody who responded and replied to
my request for people to apply to be a
tester of my genetics I got so many
responses that it was overwhelming and
it was tremendous thank you I'm still
going through the emails that has been
quite a while I get more messages every
day if you were listening to this
episode now please stop I've got enough
my inbox is going crazy you guys I
appreciate it and I love it
it is just overwhelming and I'm never
going to catch up on all of the emails
so if you've sent me an email and I
haven't replied I apologize I am digging
through all of those emails and I will
get to it it may take a minute but I
will answer every single message that
has come to that inbox again thank you
for the
Wehling response I do appreciate it
again I'm going to add on to that if you
have sent me a grow question a cannabis
question a cannabis culture question and
I have not replied to you please do not
get offended or frustrated I took a four
day vacation and I ended up being about
six days behind on emails I don't know
how the [ __ ] that worked but it did so I
am catching up I am always going to be
about a day and a half behind emails
that feels like until we get a holiday
and you guys all take a day off and I
don't that's the only way I'm gonna
catch up so if you have not gotten a
reply I apologize it is nothing personal
there are thousands of you and one of me
I'm doing my best to catch up I
appreciate all of the interaction and
all of the support this podcast has
gotten very popular in the past few
months
my listens have doubled in the past
couple of months I want to send a big
thank you to all of my friends who have
shared the show and helped to expand my
audience it means a lot to me it also
means a lot more emails so with the
growth I may slow down a little bit on
the personal replies that's just how it
goes I apologize
also my seed company I read genetics has
been taking off so I've been getting
even more emails for that company the
growth from your heart podcast and I
read genetics is all a one-man show it
is all me the growing the breeding the
writing the podcast the producing the
editing the podcast all of that stuff
the packaging of the seeds is all done
by myself so please be patient with me I
love and respect and I'm very thankful
and grateful for each and every person
who supports I read genetics and the
growth from your heart podcast it does
mean the world to me please do not feel
like I'm ignoring you or forgetting
about you
there are just a lot of you to try to
keep up with so big thanks and much
respect for making my dreams come true
without you as an audience without you
as my supporters my dreams would not be
happening I know that so thank you I'm
not going to forget about the people who
made this happen so again please do not
ever feel like I am skipping your email
like I'm ignoring your email I want to
answer every message that is in my inbox
but it is going to take me a little bit
of
to catch up so please continue to listen
to the show keep sending messages don't
stop and I will catch up and I will get
to your message in due time all right
I've got one more thing I'd like to talk
about and then we're going to wrap up
this episode I recently did an episode
talking about dab pens and smoking
concentrates we got into that
conversation again on the embracing
organics podcast live on YouTube where I
was asked the question how do you
politely decline
somebody's dab pen or questionable
concentrate being in my position in the
cannabis community many people want to
smoke with me many people want to dab me
out a lot of people want to find me at
an event and come to my booth and give
me a DAB
just to show that they love me that
they're my friend they want to share
their concentrate with me they want to
show some respect and they also just
want to say I dabbed with Rasta Jeff I
understand that I respect that and I
appreciate it but sometimes those people
show up with the scariest questionable
concentrates that I do not want to
consume I also want to be polite I also
want to remain friends with everybody I
also don't want to belittle anybody's
product maybe they made that concentrate
themselves maybe they grew the flower
maybe they're extremely proud of it and
I don't want to be the person who tells
them that is doodoo and I do not approve
so somebody politely said what is the
best way around that situation and I'll
tell you how I handle it if you approach
me and you have got some dabs then I'm
not really sure I want a dab I'm going
to keep talking you're gonna say hey
Ross - Jeff I brought you a dab but I'm
gonna go oh man let me check that out
I'm gonna look at it and I'm gonna keep
talking until you forgot that you
offered me a DAB that looks pretty good
bro what strain is that cool man how'd
you make that cool bro how long did you
let the flowers grow how long did you
flush it what's your process tell me
about it now you forgot about the
concentrate a little bit and you're so
focused on your garden you're getting
excited while you're getting excited I'm
gonna reach back and I'm gonna grab some
of my Green Dot labs what do I got here
I got some soul cleanser from Green Dot
labs I got some India pail from Green
Dot labs I'm gonna grab one of these and
I'm gonna let you tell me about your
girl
I'm gonna open the lid I'm gonna scoop
up a pretty good dad and while you're
talking I'm gonna heat up the dab nail
and then when the dab nail is the
appropriate he I'm gonna hand you the
dabber and give you the day break and go
hey man take a dab of this green dot and
you're gonna take a dab and you're gonna
go I'm [ __ ] stoned and then you're
gonna forget you even offered me a dab
of your questionable concentrates and
I'm out of it don't have to worry about
it you're stoned
I'm already stoned if you keep pressing
I may go oh man I'm gonna try some of
this and then I'm just gonna take a dab
of mine and then act like I forgot to
dab yours so the best way to kind of
switch it up and get out of dabbing a
questionable concentrate is to pull out
yours and politely offer that person
some of your concentrate and flip the
script switch it up be a Salesman
keep talking don't stop keep moving
overwhelming their thoughts reprogram
them that they want a dab of your [ __ ]
and they'll forget so that is how I get
around it I am kind of afraid to take
concentrates from other people
I am absolutely afraid to hit a vape pen
or a dab pen from a company I am not
familiar with so in the future if you
offer me a concentrate or a vape or
maybe even flowers and I politely
decline it has nothing to do with you it
has everything to do with popcorn lung
and me not trusting other companies and
other makers I have to be careful we all
have to be careful at this time protect
yourself protect your lungs protect your
health
all right podcast world this was a fun
episode thank you for letting me ramble
at you for 26 minutes if you feel like
this episode of the show is educational
informative or entertaining and you
would like to make a financial
contribution to the show you can do so
by visiting patreon.com slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen I
would also appreciate it if you find me
on cannabis cannabis is a new cannabis
friendly social media application we
cannot buy sell or trade cannabis but we
can have a great friendly cannabis
community you can post your cannabis bud
shots you can post your indoor/outdoor
Gro photos you can post pictures of your
plants with problems and folks like
myself and other qualified growers will
chime in and help you diagnose your
problem and correct your garden issues
you can also post your concentrate
pictures you can post your fancy
rip videos and your dad videos join us
on cannabis it is a free application
available on your Android or iPhone or
Apple mobile device go to the App Store
type in cannabis you'll find it it's
free give it a download create an
account give yourself a fancy username
login and give me a follow I am Irie
underscore genetics also if you are
interested in growing I read genetics or
if you are growing or have grown I read
genetics I encourage you to join the IRA
genetics breeders group on cannabis go
to the search tab tap in groups scroll
down to where it says breeders - I read
genetics and follow that group I am
doing many great giveaways for the
members of my group so join us on
cannabis and get your opportunity to get
some dank IRA prizes I think it would
also be cool if you subscribe to my
youtube channel go to youtube search for
the Grove from your heart podcast click
subscribe type some comments and some
videos and let me know what you think of
the show if you've got something you'd
like to say and you're not into all of
that social media nonsense or maybe
you've got a product you'd like me to
review or perhaps you'd like to sponsor
the show you can send me an email my
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
and you know I would love to hear from
you ladies and gentlemen that is all
I've got free for this Thursday episode
of the grill from your heart podcast I
want to give a giant shout out to my
friend Jack green stock and until next
time take a phat dab and give your mom a
hug for me