what's a podcast world it is time for
episode 465 of the Grove from your heart
podcast yes in the last episode I said
465 it was 464 stop sending me emails
this episode of the show is brought to
you by our friends at seeds here now if
you need new regular feminized or auto
flower seeds in your garden I do highly
recommend seeds here now and you can
find them at www.cpa.psu.edu or mout
there it is beautiful gotta love it
right now we just took some dads and
then Mike had to go have a cigarette we
were watching the clouds I took so many
dads I saw a dragon in the clouds
yeah we were starting to see stuff in
the clouds and thought you know what
we're in the right space to hit record
that is a good day we like to start the
show off by talking about what we're
smoking we took some dabs of copper Kim
full spectrum extract from our friends
piston dot labs it is tremendously tasty
it is a blend this is actually a cross
of chem 4 and star dog the aroma and
flavors are described as described I'm
having a hard time with words lately
the flavors are described as guava juice
and watermelon I would give the
watermelon absolutely a thumbs up I
don't know if I know what guava juice
smells like and there's also a hint of
gassy stuff going on in there I got the
gassy in the watermelon yeah gassy
watermelons it's a great cross I like
the flavor the label says sixty seven
point nine percent THC I do approve of
the buzz like I said I saw a [ __ ]
dragon in the clouds it's a good
concentrate dude it's tasty thank you
brood of boys yes big shout out to our
friends at ladies and gentlemen at Green
Dot labs um I do have some fun stuff to
talk about but we have to stick to the
script let's not get carried away let's
do a shout out to some of our friends
from patreon let's start off the big
giant shadow and a thank you to our
friends at Hogan Hogan's farms how about
a big giant grow from your heart podcast
shout out and a thank you to know me by
my guacamole you will know him by his
guacamole don't worry maybe her by her
guacamole we don't want to single
anybody out big shout - Ryan Hess how
about a big giant girl from your heart
podcast shot
squirrel tactics and of course a big
giant girl from your heart podcast shout
out thank you and a fist bump to my
friend basta I want to send his big girl
from your heart podcast thank you to
each and everybody each and everybody
what's up with my words probably three
dot anyway big thank you to everybody
who supports the show on patreon and if
you would like to learn how to support
the show you can do so by visiting
www.hp.com slash grow from your heart
and all of the information that you need
will be right there on the screen man
I'm glad we're through the business I am
stumbling with my face today got through
the required um today what is the date I
need to look at my phone and see the
actual real date today is Friday
September 20th when I woke up today I
was oddly excited to check my newsfeed
and to see what was going on in the
world because today is the start of the
raid on area 51 um there's a lot we
could talk about here I don't wanna go
too long on this because this is just a
beautiful story and it's fun it's
entertaining so there is a raid on area
51 let's talk briefly about area 51 a
long time ago I don't know the year I
didn't do any research maybe possibly
some aliens crashed in Roswell New
Mexico maybe I don't know allegedly I
I'm not even gonna [ __ ] go down that
path we asked Eddie Bravo about that
[ __ ] so maybe some aliens crashed there
was a museum and also a base made based
on this discovery or this findings of
these alien parts area 51 is where the
spacecraft and all the [ __ ] was taken
the crime scene was moved to area 51
capital allegedly yeah yeah yeah but if
they didn't it that isn't the story that
none of the other part adds up so a lot
of people think there are aliens there
they've moved all the aliens stuff the
crafts the bodies all that [ __ ] is there
the iPhone was made there I'm just
joking with that part so a alien UFO
crash all the stuff gets moved to area
51 area 51 is a real US military base
for a hundred percent for sure it's a
real military installation and
research facility that absolutely is
there it exists it's on the map so much
that people are their offenses guards
gates guns and dogs so dogs one day not
so long ago a guy who I won't say his
name went to the barn had just the right
amount of drinks the exact right number
of drinks and she's already kind of made
history
he went home yeah just the right amount
of [ __ ] drinks he went home and he
posted to a social media platform that
we should raid area 51 and clap some
alien butt cheeks if we all show up at
once they can't stop us all right yes
it's the same theory behind like amp
fest so alright alright maybe slightly
different but yes okay if a hundred
thousand people show up to do one do
something together like there's almost
nothing that authorities can do to stop
that thing from happening right except
this is a military base I bet their [ __ ]
they can do so they have ways of
stopping that this guy goes online and
he decides that he wants to collapse an
alien butt cheeks and like mike said if
i think he said a million people if we
can get a million people they can't stop
us and so he started what was known as
the raid on area 51 and it was meant to
be a joke
i get started it's just a funny little
internet joke dude that a funny drunk
thought on his way to passing out and
decided to actually share it two more
beers he would have got to pornhub four
more beers he wouldn't've made it home
from the bar three less beers and he
probably would have tried to watch TV
instead of Facebook that night and none
of this [ __ ] would have just the right
amount of its beer and burritos and yeah
it all came out just right so this dude
post this post and it actually caught on
people like [ __ ] yeah the social media
network era that we live in if you don't
know what we're talking about get off
and under that [ __ ] rock you've been
under yes has been everywhere for months
so today is the day he said let's all
gather days the day area 51 and raid
area 51 so eventually he said eventually
the government said hey [ __ ] it
happened pretty quick this blew up fast
and the government came out right away
and said by the way folks this is a real
government installation with real rules
and if you try to rush it past the gates
we really will use lethal force to stop
you they went so far in their statement
as to saying we don't have rubber
bullets here we shoot you with live ammo
and you die they don't use crowd control
toys to keep people from rushing under
military installations yeah it's
military this is not a civilian control
thing this is an attack and you have
said raid and attack we will defend and
they don't [ __ ] around they got the [ __ ]
around it oh yeah they will put holes in
you who knows what they've got there if
this is really the alien storage
whatever what what the [ __ ] do they have
there to protect that they might have a
button let it go
oink at minimum they've got lots of big
guns in a whole lot of like medium sized
guns what I've seen in the press the
dogs that I've seen are enough to keep
me the dog throws to the people that are
there the one dog that they showed in
the video the popular one weighs as much
as me that dog weighs as much as I do
that dog can run your teeth tackle
destroy yeah I told Mike I'd rather get
shot eight or six times by that [ __ ]
gun than take one good lashing from that
dog like at least she shoot me with that
gun I'm dawn that dogs just gonna chew
me up and I'm gonna cry for a few
minutes and I'm gonna need stitches I'm
gonna bleed and I'm gonna be [ __ ]
mangled just [ __ ] shoot me please
anyway let's trigger my high ass a
little bit back on track here today is
the day they're all gathered up the
government knew we were coming
there's like 1500 people is what I was
reading in the two little towns closest
the area 51 and like 150 or 200 people
have made their way down a little dirt
ass back row so that's another side
thing we should touch on this guy
finally realized after the government
came out said well [ __ ] kill you he
went oh yeah maybe maybe we shouldn't do
that and so he decided to be a
capitalist in a modern-day world and
turn his prank into a profitable
business and he tried to create a
festival out of it he actually tried to
turn it into a music festival
unfortunately ah he was just a drunk
dude that posted some [ __ ] so you had no
ability to throw her fast if you build
it sometimes they don't come yeah he
didn't want it he did not want to fire
everybody uh I haven't
my fire pun he didn't want to fire
everybody up so he did not do his fire
festival I know I know but some other
people took it upon themselves to do
small local things this is a 5% of
Burning Man yeah it's a bunch of yeah
but basically it looks like a bunch of
small fish concerts parking lots
happening little mini burning man's and
everybody's got all their alien gear on
everyone's got blow-up alien dolls
they're dancing with it's just all alien
to the [ __ ] out at all these places so
they're having a good time nobody knows
what the plan is all these people are
yeah we're here to raid area 51 and like
so what are you gonna do like I don't
know I don't want to cross that gate I'm
gonna get shot if the original Internet
joke was they were gonna rush the
buildings at like 3:00 in the morning so
we'll wake up tomorrow to either mass
casualties is morons rush area 51 or
yeah they didn't do anything other than
get a tan right bunch of trip and
hippies get tickets for illegal
possession I saw one guy has already
been arrested for peeing near the gate
so so far at this point don't pee
towards soldiers it will get you
arrested and about 3 o'clock in the
morning people started showing up and
gathering around the gate and they were
greeted by armed guards who are like
yeah we know you're coming just don't
cross this line you'll be ok one guy
started recording and politely asked one
of the guards with the dog I'm watching
on a youtube live video like 3 in the
morning goes sir I'm not gonna do it I
just want to know what happens if I
cross the line and the guys weren't like
a ninja mask cuz he's a federal agent
he's all covered up
he removed the mask just far enough to
see his mouth clearly and he smiled they
said I get to release my dog and he put
his mask up and it wasn't like a sir I
will be forced to release my animal sir
I'll be forced to detain iou's I get to
let my dog eat you I think he was kind
of excited about it he's like cross the
line [ __ ] I would really like to
let this dog go we don't train those
guys to handout hugs
oh no no they're not there to be gentle
like there's one dude in every group
that's trying to give first aid but the
rest of them were trying to test pieces
yeah yeah well if I told if I told just
about any adult male your job now is to
protect the perimeter of this with your
life most guys take that as like a fun
assignment there's something in you that
is like I'm
if now I'm primal this is my property
that's the thing about guard duty is its
99.9% wishing [ __ ] what happened cuz
your skull-fuck bored these guards that
I saw the guards which I saw in the
video were very polite they were
actually friendly and interacting some
of them there were different you can
tell you can tell there were different
levels well I'm sure there's a whole
bunch of extra people on duty as oh yeah
there's gotta be a percentage of them
that are just livid their appalling
[ __ ] middle of the night guard duty
to morons funny you said that the one
kid in the the interviewee said sir what
would you rather be doing right now and
he goes I would have gotten off work
about 15 minutes ago so I'd be getting
home to eat dinner and go to bed man and
he's like oh sorry to keep you up
neither sorry it's our job and so there
was like four or five agents whatever in
this group
two of them are talkative the other two
stood there like we don't talk we're
like we're just looking you guys talking
like the reality is that people are
idiots and there's a perfectly
reasonable chance that tonight a bunch
of people get drunk and like six of them
roll and go [ __ ] tequila running at
the gate
the dude who is charming and talking to
people this morning might have to kill
like eight idiots tonight so you never
[ __ ] know when you're that guy I
think when he goes for eight I think
once he crosses like the four to five
maybe six threshold I think it's just
happy fire after that dude I think he
just turned it into the end of [ __ ]
true romance at that point you don't you
don't have an assault rifle and you
didn't just cross the line I think there
might be something in that man's head
that might just accidentally go they
were all coming at me they everybody
looks like they're coming at you once
you start firing it's like once you got
a hammer everything looks like a nail I
think that guy may just enjoy it so so
far nothing has happened but yeah like I
hope nothing happens tonight I have no
faith and ninety to me the night no you
tonight could be the night that a bunch
of stupid people scratch themselves a
bunch of people from all across the
country possibly the world who have
never been to the desert where it was
[ __ ] like thirty degrees last night
and it's gonna be a hundred and four
today and they're partying and they're
not prepared they're gonna be not in
their right [ __ ] minds they're gonna
be bored and restless by the end of
tonight some shakin go down by Sunrise
the sick part of me is excited the good
wholesome part of me is like oh nothing
goes wrong I could go either way dude I
like to report good news and I like to
see [ __ ] happen so yeah my kid ain't
there if nothing else we have some
wonderful news because of it that is the
truth through the past few months of
just alien memes giving lab some alien
butt cheeks have been some funny [ __ ]
memes I don't even drink and I laugh my
ass off at them yeah all good [ __ ] so uh
there is one good time in my life that
alcohol did some good [ __ ] and so he
gave some stupid people run in a gunfire
not in my life but this guy nailed it
dude
shout out to all the people that made
the trek to area 51 next make a plan
before you drive it's funny to see
everybody just showed up and like so
while we're here um know why do we check
it yeah exactly like is there a leader
do we have like a leader and there's no
internet service out there so nobody can
they don't know what to do it's a bunch
of millennial it's good honestly whew
when I went out there we didn't have
service who do I want now what like
what's the next step like my phone
doesn't work usually I go to my phone to
find my next move and it's not available
yeah it's gonna be plenty of funny
coming down the pipe from this as long
as a bunch of people don't rush the
gates and then an entirely different
sort of funny happens yeah I was the
part of the sick twisted part of me was
gonna say I don't know Mike that's when
the funny really begins you just nodded
in silence all right let's move on from
the butt cheeks let's talk about some
real cannabis related stuff this that
has to be a cannabis related story at
least tangentially yeah they're people
out there smoking weed smoking some
alien OG half those memes were inspired
by cannabis the aliens brought us the
weed but no I'm just kidding so here's
something that has been popping up in
the news again I've been avoiding
talking about this subject because I am
NOT a doctor I'm not a scientist but
I've done some reading Mike brought this
up and said we should talk about this on
the show there is a syndrome a thing
that is happening it is known and I'm
going to pronounce it incorrectly but
that's okay because if you've never
heard the word before
it doesn't matter from saying it wrong
or not and it only matters that we're
talking about this
I'm giving you the information I've
heard it said a couple of different ways
we're gonna talk about a syndrome called
cannabis hyperemesis syndrome I've also
heard it pronounced cannabis hyperemesis
syndrome however you want to say it
we're gonna call it CHS for this episode
it's much much easier we'll get much
less criticism there is a syndrome that
is being labeled CHS it is popping up
all over the country but most commonly
in places where we have done some sort
of cannabis decriminalization and made
cannabis available to people I believe
part of that we're gonna get into that
it's not so much localized around
legalization it's just that's where you
read about it right because the people
there can say they consume cannabis well
in any place that's legalized it's in
vogue to blame every problem you stumble
across on legal weed and lazy Doc's is
my third note so that's yeah but yeah
it's also we can say yeah we do smoke a
lot of weed here is you can't say that
if you live in some other place and so
and then also doctors are lazy they go
you got dreadlocks and smoke a lot of
weed you've got CHS that's your problem
so the symptoms a lot of times the
symptoms include a very crappy stomach
and nausea and vomiting and muscle
tension and a headache and a burning
sensation in your skin or in your body
and there are other random symptoms that
some patients do report and some
patients do not report some people feel
itchy some people feel like their skin
is crawly but the main complaints are
stomach problems and a stomach cramps
nausea repeated bouts of vomiting and
the the kicker that the doctors are
looking for is if the symptoms are
relieved or baited with hot showers
right for some reason it gives you the
urge to take a hot shower and the hot
showers will help it which is really
weird because one of my favorite things
I just go randomly take a hot shower
I've done the kids on my own this is
strange they came across that because
like when you're riding in agony or
whatever your mind starts going through
the rolodex - oh [ __ ] how do we get this
to stop yeah and one of the things that
people have reported that works is hot
chow
and so they're they're doing a couple of
different things to treat it they're
doing something with capsaicin and
mainly it's just hydrate you and tell
you to lay off whatever you've been
smoking until the symptoms of bay is all
anybody's doing right there's not like a
drug that they found that makes it
better or or anything like that that
they can give you it's just you have to
stop consuming cannabis and in hydrate
and just give it time and as whatever's
in your system passes they they're
blaming THC right now but it's I really
highly doubt that that's my next note so
so pause um [ __ ] I forgot I was gonna
say because I told you to pause well
that's like that's what's up with the
syndrome if you're not familiar with it
you can look CHS up I we're talking
about it right now because just what do
you want to do a show about today and I
said before I was CHS has any news um so
you'll be able to find out more specific
information about it if you'd like so
it's popping up people are getting CHS
people that have smoked for a long time
are suddenly developing CHS like they've
been like folks like myself who have
smoked for years and years it's not like
sixteen-year-old sneaks out of house
smokes first joint with friends comes
home it has CHS right well it could be
that could occur as well but that's not
as common
no one's reporting that yet right
because they're probably just thinking
if that does happen they also just think
I'm just too [ __ ] high for my first
time it's probably what they attribute
that to so yeah it is popping up in
folks that smoke like myself and Mike's
level like a daily or a frequent or a
like a regular consumer somebody that
smokes a lot so it's popping up in
random places and the only way to stop
it for a short time as these hot showers
and then quit smoking and kind of clean
out your system some people report that
it comes back immediately some people
say that it doesn't come back some
people say that it will come back later
on so it's kind of strange and kind of
random at that sort of a thing now the
next thing that we should be that's part
of the reason this has been so hard to
to nail down and describe as a this
cific illness or something that's being
caused by whatever is because it's it's
characterized by the symptoms we've said
but the to get a diagnosis the people
have to go back to the ER over and over
and over again with they showed up
because it kind of presents like extreme
food poisoning and stomach cramps which
is typically those symptoms are
alleviated with hot showers - it's not
until you've come back to the ER three
or four times and they start asking
about your cannabis use that they
decided to diagnose it as CHS and
recommends stopping all cannabis
consumption - see what that does occur
for several weeks and I think excuse
that that was terrible I'm sorry I think
that a lot of that is a doctor getting
lazy and getting tired of seeing you and
being like we don't have a real
diagnosis for you it would be easy just
to slap this CHS label on there so there
you go you say you smoke that's probably
what's doing it so I think part of that
is laziness what I really think is
excuse my throat you guys I apologize
that's rude podcaster throat what I
really think is the root cause of CHS is
honestly a pesticide exposure I really
think I've got worker protection safety
training from the department the
Colorado Department of Agriculture and
the Colorado State University of Pueblo
I am train-the-trainer certified I am
certified and going to anywhere that
uses pesticides any sort of agricultural
facility I can train the staff on
pesticide handling and pesticide
application and pesticide safety on a
professional commercial horticulture
level I understand pesticides I
understand pesticide application I think
I made my point I've read a lot about
pesticides in what happens when you were
exposed to them I think that the
symptoms of CHS directly match the
symptoms of as a direct and poisoning
and has interact and exposure they're
very much the same symptoms they're
parallel and I think people common is
this product use in cannabis
it is one of the most common pesticides
and that's when I first started reading
about these cases I thought well it's
not the THC because humans have been
using THC in concentrated forms look if
you don't know the history of cannabis
and hash you can look this [ __ ] up but
before the 1920s eating hash was wildly
popular there's a book called the hash
eaters it's even in the Count of Monte
Cristo they eating hash is one of the
subplots and so it's the the odds that
there's an illness with symptoms this
severe that's caused directly by THC or
CBD or one of the other cannabinoids is
highly unlikely
what is extremely likely is that there's
something that's in common use like neem
oil or something else that [ __ ]
everybody uses at least for a while neem
oil is not super popular now but for a
minute everyone and their brother had
neem in their [ __ ] garage a lot of
other folks are attributing neem oil to
this syndrome I'm I think they're
attached I think neem and has a direct
and are the same if not similar I should
read that before I say that but they're
attached somehow but that's a lot of
people suspect a lot of people in the
cannabis communities prime suspects is
something that we're adding to cannabis
for one reason or another and it's this
ties in with the the vaping story that's
going on right now too
there's a concerted effort by people in
the media and people in the anti
marijuana world to to pin the vaping
stuff on THC or vaping period and that's
clearly nonsense it's clearly an
additive that's causing us
the two main not focusing on that's
going to cause us problems so everyone
in the community needs to be aware that
we're talking about stuff that's being
added to our cannabis not cannabis I
don't want to say added that's going to
sound like it's being added sprayed a
plant live fed - it's being sprayed as
an intention as a
pest preventative or a pest deterrent
and it's being applied too late or too
heavily and it's being applied
improperly is basically what's happening
I did a quick google search the two main
active ingredients derived from the neem
tree seeds are as interacting and
clarified hydrophobic extract of neem
oil also referred to simply as neem oil
so yes Niemann has interact and are one
in the same just an extract of the other
one so it's that's what the symptoms are
coming from when I typed in the word as
interacting the first thing that came up
were poisoning symptoms and if you look
it is very similar to what we're looking
at with CH s and then you asked if that
is a product that is used in Sue's
[ __ ] everywhere everything with a za
at the start of it and I don't
I feel bad mentioning the products but
as whatever is made with hazard Arango
yeah and but one of them two of them I'm
thinking quickly I can think of at least
three as interact and derived products
that are allowed by the Colorado
marijuana Enforcement Division and the
Colorado Department of Agriculture so
I'm gonna Lou back to something I was
talking about a minute ago about
improper pesticide application there is
what is known as the re-entry interval
when you apply a pesticide if I spray
most products have a four or an eight
hour most of things that I would use
have got a four or an eight hour
re-entry interval if I spray that
product in my garden I have to leave and
unless you are in the proper protective
equipment you should not enter that grow
room for four to eight hours because
that pesticide is active in there if you
touch the plants you risk getting a
pesticide contamination on your skin if
it is still in their field was sprayed
and micronized bubbles you can still
inhale that into your lungs you can get
exposure that re-entry interval needs to
be lengthened in our indoor grow
environments because we don't have wind
and we don't have Sun those pesticides
are not getting broken down by the
natural response yeah they're just
hanging out on the plants so people are
spraying too often when there's no
absorbs like when you're spraying
outside [ __ ] drips out of the soil it's
gonna absorb and diffuse into the
topsoil other sun's gonna break it down
the Sun
is gonna destroy most of what we're
putting out there it's gonna break it
down there just like it is written to do
inside the drips gather like in the
little rain gutters and they just yeah
like there's there's no absorption
there's nothing that just sits and
there's no wind they just gathered ups
and then we apply again and we apply
again and we apply again and that is
where there is too much pesticide
gathered up on our flower or I've talked
about this also in a previous episode
we're taking plants that have been
sprayed a little bit too late and we're
like [ __ ] man this this this crops got
bugs on it and I've been spraying it I
can't get rid of the bugs and then you
make an executive decision around week 8
man this can't go 10 weeks these bugs
are gonna eat this [ __ ] how to bring it
down early got it but then you know what
else we got to do with it because it
came down early no no no no turn it into
oil but also we just sprayed it four
weeks ago three weeks ago so now what
are you gonna do we're also gonna make
concentrated as interacting in my oil
yeah yeah sometimes I can see it and
some in some concentrates I can identify
the floaties pesticide but so you apply
that pesticide you take down the crop a
little bit early because it wasn't a
plan you've got bugs it's got to come
down you've got early flowers nobody
wants to buy premature flowers you
turned it into concentrate you've just
made concentrate with contaminated
flowers now you're going to get cannabis
hyperemesis syndrome from consuming that
as interact and latent concentrate I
think that is what's making people sick
to tell you the truth the part of the
this whole topic that drives me just up
the wall is like when it's cantaloupe
that's making people say like seven
eight people get sick and we're like
it's Billy's cantaloupe farm in like
Billy Carolina that produced it and sold
it and they [ __ ] up step 7 and these
people got sick and those families sue
the company and life goes on like
because it's a legal regulated product
that goes through standard testing and
inspections when stuff sold like that
they can track it back right away like
when they had scares in the 80s and the
90s where people [ __ ] with tylenol
bottles and [ __ ] on the shelf when
somebody would buy a
a time all that had been tampered with
they were immediately able to say that
bottle of Tylenol came from Billy's
drugstore
Billy's drugstore got their shipment of
time off from Timmy's warehouse yeah
Timmy's warehouse got their [ __ ] from
the tylenol Factory 17 that's right here
they go to town on Factory 17 they
talked to the 15 guys that were working
the day that bottle went through the
line
that's what legal and regulated means
and as cannabis moves all the way into
that market we're finally gonna get the
protections that should have [ __ ]
been there our whole lives right on the
I've grabbed this concentrate container
here on the back of this one I've got
I'm not gonna read the numbers exactly
but I've got an RM CF &amp; RM IP and then a
couple of other numbers one of these
numbers was the cultivation facility the
RM CF is the RM the recreational
marijuana cultivation facility I've got
a number there so I know where this was
cultivated I know what which grow these
flowers came from then I've got an RM IP
a recreational marijuana infused product
facility Wow proud of myself for that
one I've got a number there so I know
who grew this and I knew who extracted
it with this RM CF number if I wanted to
I could request their pesticide
application logs which they're required
to keep for a minimum of 2 years so if a
problem occurred from this batch of
concentrate I could tell you what was
applied to their garden for the past two
years if they were honest they're
supposed to write all of that [ __ ] down
the trick there is just apply some [ __ ]
and don't write it down how do we defeat
that mic morose inspections more regs
lab testing and inspections now the
Colorado marijuana Enforcement Division
has a couple of new machines that
they're just loving to [ __ ] use they
show up to your grow and they dress up
like their goddamn CSI and they go in
the grow and they cut off a leaf from
one or two plants and they denote plant
number six there the numbers are where
the other plants are all tagged with a
specific number already so they just
write that number down plant number six
that bottom third main branch of the
plant we took this leaf they put in a
little evidence bag it says evidence it
looks
[ __ ] crime back they take a few
samples throughout the entire grow bill
just pick random places and they'll take
samples and they'll write it down they
get all of the grower information the
owner information they check so much
stuff then they take those samples back
to a lab and they test them for a
pesticide contamination and if those
plants are tested for improper pesticide
application there are repercussions for
that garden it could be destroyed the
entire garden can be taken down yep yeah
and though they'll send people down to
watch you shred your [ __ ] or they'll
help you do it [ __ ] help you shred
those plants the the two people I know
that have been through that process um
the guys they sent to watch everything
get shredded we're just asking stupid
questions fault I'm making it worse on
the part that shred it I bet oh man meb
is a fun group of people I love you guys
okay I mean like this is what happens
like this is what we mean when we say
legal cannabis like legal beer don't
make people say if you know the history
of prohibition one of the really [ __ ]
up things that happened was a lot of the
alcohol people were drinking during
Prohibition was [ __ ] poison and why is
it poisoned because the black market
cares about profit yep in like I get it
I was I [ __ ] it I was part of the black
market like tangentially fundamentally
it's where I came from that's why
sometimes I try to stand up for the
black market I understand that I've got
compassion for the black market without
the black market in some places there is
no market that's 100% true and for the
cannabis community for so long we we had
no other option and so we made the best
black market we could like everybody
trusts and respects their dealer for the
most part when it comes to cannabis like
I don't think that's necessarily true
for a lot of other harder drugs but a
lot of those smokers I know especially
in the black market days like had a fun
relationship with whoever their guy was
and always went back to that one spot
and we've really carried some of that
through into the legal market where we
pick a dispensary and we stay with that
chain or or that outfit for as long as
we can before
changing it up and I think some of
that's making somebody's life a demyx
worse like the CHS thing if you're
buying product that's tainted with the
pesticide from shop a like odds are
strong that their whole grow is treated
with whatever is making you sick right
so as you move from flower to flower
concentrate to concentrate as long as
you're going back and buying from that
specific store whatever's in their
supply chain that's [ __ ] with you is
gonna keep [ __ ] with you and right
now odds are pretty good that it's
something that the whole industry is
using legal and illegal but I believe
strongly but the whole industry is using
as a direct and based on mean based
products dude I can be as such a strong
testament to your loyalty as what you're
talking about
once you do find a shop or a weed guy
you keep going there and if you look at
my table there are two brands all over
the table that's why they've never done
me wrong there's shit's always proper
and I don't feel sick from it so I mean
like right now I've never felt and we're
gonna make it [ __ ] paranoid from this
podcast I've got this syndrome now sorry
we did that to you guys know how Haley
really rough on my lungs like I smoked
tobacco
I'm bong hits or my favorite method or
you send a recommendation for coughing
like a [ __ ] savage on the show right
so I had like I haven't even converted
over to concentrates which like if you
haven't figured out that vaping
concentrates is a lot less wear and tear
on your lungs than smoking a joint for
the same amount of stone like you just
haven't been thinking about it and still
I prefer bong hits I don't know why it's
just it's too perfect to give up but
I've had vape pens where I take a couple
of puffs on it and I just feel like my
lungs feel soggy or squishy for the next
hour day and a half and like I didn't
mind losing those cards I'm [ __ ]
terrible with carts that's why I don't
do oh the Fate pen cartridges you lose
those too I know a couple other people
that are like that I can I can keep on
to him I got seven batteries at home no
carts I haven't finished a cart in like
four years man um but immediately I knew
that that was a product where
in industry on the margins or an
industry that squeezed as hard as the
legal cannabis industry is a lot of the
carts are where they're they're d- and
failed product ends up in the black
market who the [ __ ] knows what's in
those things they're finding carts with
k2 and spice in it and these are like
they found that [ __ ] in CBD carts in
[ __ ] Texas they found k2 in the carts
they found that [ __ ] Massa to mask too I
think
just know if you're buying black market
stick the flour yep you can look at
flour you can smell flour you can see
problems with the flour through the bag
in a quick transaction there are ways
that we've all learned to protect
ourselves buying flour in the black
market
right um concentrates if you're buying
legit hash you can you can look and see
quality versus not quality once it's in
a cart
ya know that could be that could be piss
in there now with the dispensaries they
are now before I get to the dispensary
part they are now doing concentrate
tests until recently I think it may have
been September first they did not have
to test the concentrate this is just the
flour so now they're also testing a
sample of the concentrate so if the
concentrate does happen to get an
abundance of pesticide concentrated they
don't get notice now so they're testing
for that as well another thing that is
happening to keep us safer they are
doing random dispensary tests they're
going to dispensaries a little spot
check bus and spot rings and [ __ ]
doing that wise they're going in like
Health Department and checking the
flower they're pulling flour out of the
jar and testing it for microbes and cuz
decides yeah they're doing checks on the
actual flower that is in the jar on the
shelf now who's I've singing because
[ __ ] can happen you and I know what can
happen from zero because it gets sealed
up depends on how your grow is it
probably goes in a [ __ ] turkey bag
and it gets sealed up in a turkey bag
and driven in the back of Mike's car
from the growth facility to the
dispensary and then somebody at the
dispensary checks it in and puts it into
a different container and then I don't
know if they get sealed airtight if it
gets left open to the Container you wash
from
last batch somebody sneezed matches
before did we wash their hands after
using the [ __ ] before they did da
bagon like all of that if this [ __ ]
we've seen we're talking about in the
legal market has your ears perked up or
your your gag reflex kicking in just
imagine the [ __ ] we've seen in the
purely legal market some destroyed trees
have a dry and cure it in the jar sort
of a theory so I've been asked to take
my shoes off and grind the plant
material that was stuck to the bottom of
them over a plate 2-0 rags for quality
control um like everybody I know that's
been involved in the black market long
enough to do with brick weed has stories
about insane [ __ ] they found in their
brick nuts bolts a [ __ ] bird
pinecones
anything to make you weigh anything to
make you look right and like stuff had
soda dumped out over it and then dried
in the Sun to give it more sticky that's
how they used to pour sugar water over
and put in a trash compactor it's not
they used to compress like a brick weed
there's endless nasty that we've just
been like [ __ ] but it's that or no herb
you know like in is legalization takes
hold we can finally get away from some
of this [ __ ] but it's it's always a
struggle it's always a struggle this
vape things really gonna [ __ ]
everybody's gonna take three steps back
hopefully there are some people that
will not there are a lot of people
pushing hard that have just been
salivating for their next opportunity
the the people who are just livid that
we can't arrest anybody who's a minority
for smelling like weed right now our
[ __ ] thrilled that wants this
flavored vape thing past they could be
like I [ __ ] smelled cupcakes from the
sidewalk so we kicked the door in and
arrested everybody yeah that's a little
wacky like we just need to I don't I
don't know the solution but just got to
be careful we have to educate consumers
you can't bust people for doing
something aunt joy well it's it's
rethinking a lot of stuff is how we fix
that like everything about arresting
people for consuming substances that
makes them happiest
just [ __ ] if it's not how cops were
designed to work
cops protect you for me they can't
protect you from you absolutely I agree
with that I just passed Mike a greendot
labs bait pen I'm not sure what the
flavour is of that but it'll be
delicious
so I do preach that we don't need to pay
attention to the numbers on the lab
tests because your nose nose your nose
knows what turps and flavors you like
and how you're gonna get affected by
that properly your nose knows which
product to buy what I do like about the
lab tests is that assures me that that
product has been through a lab it has
been produced in a quality facility
hopefully by an educated grower somebody
that cares and knows but most of all
it's been tested I know it has been
through the market hopefully it's not
super contaminated if it's in a vape pen
you know that you're getting probably a
quality product if it came from the
dispensary on the black come in there
and of course dude there are going to be
bad products that come from the
dispensary there's honestly right now
because we're still operating in a
federal gray area and we don't have
access to the resources that every other
industry has like jewel knows for a
[ __ ] fact that their heating element
isn't causing the vaping crisis Oh pen
is pretty sure I doubt the people at
Green Dot have had that tested that's
just straight up my guess I could be
wrong but that's my girl the smaller the
company is the lower the odds are that
they have access to the the resources to
run the testing to be sure now that
doesn't mean that that shit's all that
much safer than anything else is just
means they've run more are we gonna get
sued because of this type testing before
[ __ ] hits the market
I've watched vape pens evolve since they
first hit the market here and there
exist
now makes me more comfortable than their
previous iterations right
I knew they were putting the crap in him
before the first couple did like the
original vaporizers the table tops the
volcanoes those have been around since
the late 90s if they were making people
sick we'd [ __ ] know it
some of the medical studies have been
done on volcano vaporizers with people
sitting in hospital rooms vaping
specific amounts of product through
volcanoes like we would be [ __ ] sure
if the act of heating cannabis to the
vaporization point cause lung problems
but as soon as we went to the car it's
battery started exploding what's going
into the car was a big question
carts melting and leaking everywhere the
guy enough to cook what's in them we
used to work with a good friend who
smoked the called it the robot dick it
was just a nicotine vape I'll turn you
down a little bit go ahead and choke to
that I would watch him and I'm not
against your vape if that's what you
want to do vape away bra or lady bra he
would get his vaping and he had this
Lake looked like a piece of [ __ ] a
cut-up sock and he would just pour this
liquid [ __ ] syrupy [ __ ] into there
and then close it up and he would push
the battery on it he would [ __ ]
Sparkle and crackle and fireworks have
come out of it and he'd go just right
bro and he would hit it and he would
take these big old cloudy rips out of it
and he'd make this face like it was
heaven and he would blow out I hate it
how good it smelled bro I hate it smell
like megatons a hell of a drug but it
also smelled like cupcakes and [ __ ]
cotton candy and [ __ ] heavy I was
like God how did you just smoke that but
it worried I was thinking like bro
you're pouring like some liquid juice
from China that just says like fizzy
cupcake juice how do we know what's in
there and then he would just rip it and
it would smell so strong and I'm like
how many chemicals did it take to smell
right if it smells over here five
minutes later what went through that
lung the bottle said strawberry
cheesecake and when he hit it I went
runs that strawberry cheesecake and he
goes exactly I'm like what kind of
chemicals are in there like what kind of
science [ __ ] like your
diaphragm it was the it was toast with
butter and jam was the one that was I
was like dude it's got multiple flavors
there's no the [ __ ] is in all that yes
yep but I don't think it's that [ __ ]
that's making people say it's something
that it looks like it's specifically
something they're using I agree to cut
down on cannabis oil because in its pure
form like if you get 90% 95% pure THC
oil that's just like cold honey it just
doesn't doesn't work improvement some of
those work done this some of the damage
in the harm and the problems the
hospitalizations were caused by a
vitamin E cut they think that they're
still not sure there's because this is
all one of the first things they
realized was the people that are getting
sick aren't buying regulated [ __ ]
because if it was like I say Jule cuz
they're the most popular one but if it
was like Jules blackberry flavor like
that would have come to light a long
[ __ ] time ago just like it does with
the cantaloupe you never see a food
outbreak with hundreds and hundreds and
hundreds of sick people even though
they're recalling tons of food like
you'll see a million pounds of hamburger
got recalled one guy got sick three guys
got sick they got a recall 200 million
pounds of [ __ ] cantaloupe like
cantaloupe from an entire region because
the factory they went through it failed
the test if well we were what was
causing these products was coming from
the legal market it would have been
traced back already
right and so it's something that people
are buying online to cut in their garage
before they sell black-market cars
that's [ __ ] cheap and nasty and I'm
glad we don't have to deal with that
[ __ ] yeah I wouldn't even if I didn't
have these pins there's one other brand
I would probably trust but if I didn't
have these I wouldn't even be smoking
them dude and I mainly bought these for
a concert so yep and big shout-out to
the concerts were just not even giving a
[ __ ] I set multiple vape pins in that
little basket you gotta walk through a
metal detector and they give you a
little basket like you're going on a
plane and you put your your wallet and
your keys and your phone in some basket
to set him right in there the guys look
to make three of them ah yeah it's gonna
be a long night he's like
okay [ __ ] one of the things that always
makes me laugh when I see people ranting
and raving about how marijuana causes
violence it's like well security guards
in the cops if I can be aware by now
like yeah when they see a bunch of
joints or of a pen they just kind of non
smile I'm a big dude you're a big dude
we both tell each other stories of when
I used to drink like some of our
favorite stories to tell the reason I
don't drink and I'm I have shame in this
but I'm an adult now so I could talk
about it I like to [ __ ] beat people
up when I drink I don't know why there's
something about alcohol that I can drink
a few beers but then there's one and I
don't know if it's gonna be the seventh
or the thirty-first of beer but one of
them I'll take a drink of it and I'll
just decide let's go fight somebody I
don't know who I don't know why but
something in my brain decides you're
definitely not alone punching stuff yeah
yeah no alcohol for me I do I'm six five
and 200 pounds and you're [ __ ] six
four and a lot of pounds really hurts um
yeah yeah and us together drinking and
causing problems would be [ __ ] chaos
I'm not trying to say I'm tough or
anything I'm just I know that I could
cause a problem for myself and others
with alcohol in my life when I smoke
cannabis I produce a quality podcast the
teaches others how to improve their
lives better than cannabis and [ __ ]
my friends all like me I don't wake up
in the morning wondering Oh where's my
car how did I get home where's my wallet
how much money is left in my wallet
right I don't have to go through my
phone and see what kind of stupid-ass
text messages I sent to anybody last
night
yes woken up the next morning and
discovered I spent all the money for the
rest of the week on weed yeah like I
knew that the day I bought the weed
going into the the transaction it wasn't
something that surprised the [ __ ] out of
me the next morning when I was trying to
buy breakfast I like waking up from the
bar the next morning on where the [ __ ]
is my everything
oh she's yeah I really know I didn't I
didn't like that feeling at all it's
just kind of being a smartass they're
like I've never seen a security guard
freak out over Erb like unless they came
up to you were like quit smoking it in
here like two or three times in a row
like during one set there's a B there
were some kids
Red Rocks one year some younger security
guards that were younger than me it told
me you gotta put your weed out and I was
like brats Red Rocks and this was before
they got all their Red Rocks is
different I know you got to put your
weed out those with you now back in the
day I was like bro this is Red Rocks and
he goes he's got to put it out man or
put it in the bag and he had like a
trash bag he was taking [ __ ] from people
and I go here bro and I just gave him a
joint I go leave me alone he goes ok and
he let me smoke after that he just
wanted some weed from people he didn't
give a [ __ ] like he was just trying to
be it's tough ass tell me to put it out
or take it from me so that he could get
some weed I gave him a joint he let us
smoke all night didn't say [ __ ] like
they know what they aren't worried we're
peaceful folk most of us there's an
[ __ ] in every group don't get me
wrong no just be smart when you're
buying [ __ ] people in as is this stuff
develops follow the follow the stories
and watch cannabis CHS cannabis
hyperemesis syndrome is going to get
tracked back to some more spraying and
the vaping issue and the CHS issue our
Julie those are two different stories by
the way both of them two different
things it's the same cause it's like
[ __ ] it's the cause it's improper
cannabis market shake procedures but
yeah it lazy stupid reporters the CHS
and the vape pens are not related those
are two separate stories that we may
have blended together here at the end of
the high part of the talk and they have
a lot to do they also big giant shout
out and thank you for all of the
feedback on the vape episode I got a lot
of great recipients in that yeah you
gave me positive feedback you're like I
wish you to send more of this but good
job which there's a lot of stuff I wish
I would have said might you could see
how many notes I take I ran down like
four words four notes on this pot I like
to just you know feel like we're just
talking I don't I used to type it out
and [ __ ] today in the podcast we will
talk about growing cannabis the basics
of growing cannabis come from that's so
boring if there's a couple people doing
it I'm sure
yeah I want to have a conversation with
you sometimes I've missed some things
sometimes I talk way too long on other
things
but I got a lot of great feedback a lot
of people said that I missed a couple
things a lot of people said I got great
[ __ ] the main thing people wanted me to
make sure that I mentioned was that it
is all black market [ __ ] and they don't
think that any of it is
Pam or ejuice it's all black market
concentrate pins is what most of the
information that I got back was they
wanted me to make sure to stand up for
the nicotine side of it is what I think
most people are saying well I got a lot
of great feedback the YouTube comments
were great the emails were great thank
you guys the support the feedback just
know you guys are listening is [ __ ]
because yeah yeah we're growing bro the
podcast is getting huge our listens on
YouTube or multiplying if social media
it's nicer to us cannabis folks we could
really blow it up a little more social
media zeal evil I've got mixed feelings
on that see a lot of people think we
should be able to post whatever we want
I understand that social media platforms
are owned by other people who have a lot
of [ __ ] lawyers and they can say oh
you like the rules here
don't play here like it's that simple
like if I went to the UFC
and I was like hey I'm pretty and skinny
so no punches to the face for this fight
do you know why we look at me and punch
me straight in the face and go bruh
that's the UFC smack oh yeah I don't get
to make the rules here that's how it is
that's how social media platforms are
you signed a little thing you don't sign
it you clicked a little thing when you
signed up they said I won't post dumb
[ __ ] and they get to decide what dumb
[ __ ] is and if they decide that your
picture of your puppy is dumb [ __ ] or
your picture your weed is dumb [ __ ]
that's up to them you can't do [ __ ]
about it
so I understand that aspect also I come
from the black market we spoke of
earlier I'm not even supposed to be able
to post [ __ ] pictures of my weed I'm
supposed to hide in the shadows and
nobody should know who I am nobody
should know yeah we're posting pictures
of weed shut the [ __ ] up e be happy
about it like and if you really want to
post your cannabis and you're afraid of
your account getting taken down by any
sort of sort of social media police join
me on cannabis cannabis can get away
with that yeah we encourage you we
promote your cannabis photos you can't
buy or sell or trade cannabis there but
if you post the photos we definitely
like to click like on your photos there
are a lot of great giveaways a lot of
good community happening on cannabis
it's a free social media application
available on your Android or Apple
device that was a smooth segue for a
great commercial big shot us my buddy Q
grows support cannabis it's fun I'm on
there a lot
find us cannabis Minister that old weird
direction just don't assume when social
media is the same as news oh thank you
Mike if social media is not news there
is
and I say social media is evil it's not
because it won't let you post weed
photos it's because it's making society
[ __ ] dumber it is it's uh it's making
us that our world we're not supposed to
[ __ ] say it is retarding us from
actually learning the truth because we
are so distracted by memes and just
[ __ ] x' headlines that we don't read
any articles anymore or when we little
there was a bright clear line between
news and opinion like the news is
Yankees for Red Sox six the opinion is
Yankees suck Red Sox suck and both that
those are fun and interesting and
important and both have a place but when
you confuse a for B and B for a bad [ __ ]
happens really bad [ __ ] even when we're
just talking baseball in like we brought
[ __ ] smallpox in the plague back
people we're like five years from
[ __ ] in our own drinking water again
we don't turn this [ __ ] around you heard
it here first
do you feel better I do is this the
section that we called what really
grinds my gears sure I love social media
but [ __ ] people are still I've got a
huge love/hate I can't stay there for
too long it's something to do when
you're pooping it is get in there and if
I can release some [ __ ] and fill right
back up with more [ __ ] from the social
media then you know it's just a trade
yep if I like to posting trading actual
[ __ ] for digital [ __ ] and if I don't
reply to all your social media nonsense
it's because I'm living we've given the
people a good solid hour of podcasting
you're welcome thanks for coming and
hanging out in the afternoon oh yeah
this was random we did not get
interrupted by the UPS guy we made it we
dodged both are possible distract and
now let's put that out there UPS guy or
and or gal please deliver my new stuff
that I ordered
thank you world thanks for having me but
hey dude
come and do more shows the world likes
having you or if they not if they don't
like it we're gonna hear from them
pretty soon because I'm going to request
that they leave us comments on the
YouTube channel that's right go to the
YouTube channel search for the girl from
your
podcast on YouTube click Subscribe leave
some comments on this episode let me
know if you liked loved hated the
episode just type some stuff let me know
what you think I'm needy and wot
comments how's that feel alright ladies
and gentlemen if you feel like this
episode is educational informative
and/or entertaining and you'd like to
make a financial contribution to the
show you can do so by visiting
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
all the information you need will be
right there on the screen once again big
shout out big thank you to everybody who
has supported the show on patreon
Channel I've got a bunch of brand new
microphone covers and I use those with
the patreon funds and it's a good thing
I have new ones because a moment ago I
spit something into this microphone that
was pretty [ __ ] disgusted by so as
soon as we're done with this episode
it's coming off and it's getting a new
cover that was gross I'm glad I shared
that with the listeners um also if you
would like to support the show it does
not cost money to be our friend I want
you to listen if you cannot contribute
if you can't follow me on social media
if you've got earbuds in and you enjoy
the show and you were smiling and
feeling better about hearing it that's
my reward enjoy it I like it it doesn't
cost anything to hang out but I would
appreciate it if you follow us on
cannabis cannabis is a free social media
application you're already scrolling
around you're already clicking on some
[ __ ] why not look at some quality
cannabis photography download cannabis
that helps out myself that helps out my
friend cue grows that helps out our
buddy jr. token helps out the cannabis
community join us up here on cannabis it
is free give me a follow I'm Irie
underscore genetics I would appreciate
the support over there also I mentioned
the YouTube channel grow from your heart
podcast click subscribe give me a follow
once again type in comments cuz I'm
[ __ ] needy if you're not in all that
social media nonsense and you've got
something you'd like to say maybe you've
got a cool product you'd like me to
review maybe you'd like to sponsor the
podcast you can send me an email my
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I would love to hear from
you also Mike really quickly how can the
people find you on social media you can
find me on Facebook at Puebla for
sensible cannabis laws or you can hit me
up on Twitter at at new mo bum fifteen
there you go you guys Pueblo for city's
Mia cannabis laws and Nimmo Punk 15 on
the Twitter he does not do much on the
Instagram I wouldn't even give him a
fall
17 people gonna do it ever happens every
channel on the show well thanks for
following Mike big following me also if
you'd like to follow me on other social
media on the Twitter it is at Rasta Jeff
420 you can follow the show at gfy each
podcast of course there is the Instagram
it's Irie underscore genetics I'm
currently under what they call a shadow
ban I don't worry too much about it but
if I use hashtag I read genetics my
photos get blocked nobody sees them you
have to type in the full name of my
account including its Irie underscore
genetics all the way to the S to get me
to pop up in the search bar we are
shadow band because they don't like
cannabis that's all right we've got
plenty of friends on cannabis we'll be
okay either way
give me a follow on some kind of social
media be my friend like I said I'm
[ __ ] needy I want you to click on all
that stuff why don't you guys obviously
my voice is burning out I'm done talking
I want to thank Michael once again for
hanging out I want to thank you guys for
listening I'll be back in just a couple
of days with fresh new content I want to
give a huge shout out to my buddy
Willie's armpit and until next time take
a phat dad and give your mom a hug for
me
[Music]
long wide searching for sweet aspiration
my brother
yeah
[Music]
you got to check your step the day turns
to night know that you're never alone
lion guide why does every where you roll
that you got the tools you forget we got
to build this bar tonight
we gotta learn to work together or do it
right
[Music]
my brother
my brother tried on yeah
[Music]
my brother right on we gotta help one
another buses
my sister
right on
[Music]
we got a hell
another my sister my brother ride
[Music]