welcome back ladies and jelly spoons we
are gathered here today for episode 466
of The Grove from your heart podcast
this episode of the show is brought to
you by seeds here now if you need new
regular feminized or Auto flower seeds
in your garden I highly recommend seeds
here now and you can find them at
www.cdxzipstream.com --scent rate the
potency label says that this product
contains 67 point nine four percent THC
and zero CBD I really enjoy and
appreciate the copper chem the flavor is
perfect and the buzz is tremendous so
big shout out to our friends at Green
Dot labs for the amazing copper chem
full spectrum extract alright ladies and
gentlemen boys and girls pimps and hos
friends and foes I'm going to read a
couple of emails in this episode but
before we get there let's do a couple of
shoutouts to our friends from patreon
let's start off with the giant grow from
your heart a podcast shout out and a
thank you to our friend Melvin eight one
eight I want to send a big thank-you
shout out to Meredith also a giant grow
from your heart a podcast shout out and
a thank you to ethan g and of course a
big grow from your heart podcast fist
bump and a thank you to Gregory s I want
to thank everybody for all the continued
patreon support if you would like to
learn how to support the show you can do
so by visiting www.hp.com slash
grow from your heart all of the
information you need to support the show
will be right there on the screen all
right boys and girls I did say that I
was going to read some emails this
episode actually came to me from social
media I do not know that this person
wants their identity revealed so we're
just going to jump right into this
message it goes like this I just wanted
to reach out and let you know that I
really appreciate the info and insights
that you provide on the podcast a that
is a great way to start you were very
welcome thank you for the great
compliments it goes on to say I just
listen to episode 465 and you hit the
nail on the head with the CHS topic you
guys I got so many responses and so many
emails on the CHS topic I am going to do
a recap and a revision on that soon I
will have to because my YouTube channel
is just exploding with comments but this
is the first one that I printed before
they all flooded in so this is the one
we were going to focus on really quickly
it goes like this I found out that
without a patient diagnosis our doctors
cannot get paid from the insurance
companies for your visit so what he's
saying is when you go to the doctor and
they examine you if they can't write
down a word of something that is wrong
with you and have a title for it
they're not going to get paid so because
there is no test or even any studies to
back the CHS theory it is often used as
an easy diagnosis that is hard to argue
against as the patient yes
we're patients most of us are not
doctors we go to the doctor they say
that's probably what you've got and they
write it down now that you can get paid
you've got a diagnosis and they can move
on to the next patient unfortunately
many doctors are forced to see too many
patients in too little time I'm sure
that it's not the doctors goal and idea
to do it that way it is just a practice
of business and that is how the hospital
and how any sort of medical place is run
it is now a business you are a patient
but you are mainly a customer so you're
absolutely correct they do need a
diagnosis they need to get you out of
there and it is very hard to argue that
as a patient so there is more to this
email it says I ended up finding out
that I get migraines after two years of
studies and tests with most doctors
trying to blame my medical cannabis use
as soon as I mentioned it I am one of
the very few people that suffer from
migraines with nausea and vomiting
issues then they wrap up the message by
saying sorry for the rant take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug then they sign
it with great work as always I
appreciate the great compliments I am
for sure going to take a fat dab I will
give my mom a hug for you now let's
touch on this a little bit this person
gets migraines and also gets nausea and
vomiting and the doctors were
immediately attributing it to his
cannabis use or their cannabis use they
did not mention their gender
I should stop assigning genders to
people I could be wrong and I could be
offensive however
this person went to the doctor and they
kept getting told that they have CH s
this person believes that since the
doctor could not find a reasonable
explanation for their symptoms they
simply wrote it off as CH s and that can
be really dangerous and really
frustrating because after more tests and
more research and of course more money
being spent this person found out that
they actually have migraines that cause
nausea and vomiting it probably does not
have anything to do with CH s or
cannabis hyperemesis syndrome there's
something that happens when anybody is
trying to diagnose a problem or do some
sort of investigation or maybe a repair
and you're on a path and you're just
thinking what could the problem be and
you've got these doctors have very
limited time they need to focus on you
for 10 or 12 minutes and get out of the
room and get on to the next patient so
they can just keep writing receipts and
I should do a disclaimer there are many
great doctors who do great service
unfortunately many of the emergency room
doctors many of the affordable doctors
are forced to work under less than
desirable conditions but they'd like to
have a job they've got to pay for
medical school
they've got [ __ ] needs they need
groceries and rent so they're forced to
work in whatever type of environment
they can find employment and so they do
that that is what they're doing it
probably isn't their choice they're
seeing too many patients a day they're
seeing patients for too short of a time
they've got a very short timeframe to
come up with the diagnosis and when you
say well I also smoke cannabis that
little bell goes off possibly CHS they
look at all the other things on the map
and they go yeah nothing makes sense I'm
just gonna write down CHS next it's like
the all all of the above on the test it
just works
it's an answer you can get away with it
move forward and in this case for the
doctor unfortunately there is no
repercussion there's no circumstance
there's no consequence
you just write that down and move
forward unfortunately the patient has to
deal with that for their life or until
they do get it figured out now
fortunately or I guess unfortunately
either way fortunately this person was
able to find a doctor that could figure
out what really was wrong with them and
they've been diagnosed with nausea and
vomiting associated with migraines so
until they found the right doctor they
were just going to be getting told the
wrong diagnosis
just to be blown off and just to get
that insurance money so that was a great
message that came in right after the
episode came out so I wanted to grab
that one print it out and read that here
on the show thank you for sharing your
experience I hope you have found
something to alleviate the pain the
nausea and the vomiting from those
migraines migraines are terrible I have
a traumatic brain injury for a little
while I was very light sensitive and
very noise sensitive and very everything
sensitive due to a brain injury so I
know what it is like to have a migraine
I understand those symptoms and I
definitely hope you've got that under
control hey thank you for the great
message and thank you for supporting my
theory a little bit with the CHS that it
is kind of just a label for lazy doctors
to write down so they could say they
found a diagnosis alright I spent more
time on that one then I wanted to so I'm
going to quickly move to the next email
this one did directly come through the
email if anybody out there would like to
send me an email my email address is
grow from your heart at hotmail.com I
would love to hear from you I'm not sure
if they want their name set on the show
I'm trying to scan really quickly to
hear if they want their name oh wait you
can use my name if you read this on the
show so big shout out to our friend
Brian B here is an email from Brian B it
goes a lot like this Russ to Jeff your
podcast is awesome thank you so much for
taking time to deliver such a
high-quality growing podcast man I
really like the way this is starting
thank you bro I always look forward to
listening to your podcast because the
sound quality is superb and you have the
perfect radio voice and that is a huge
compliment I do put a lot of effort into
making sure that the sound of the show
is top-notch I was kind of an audio nerd
I was a musician I am a musician I was
into that way before I became a
podcaster or got into podcasting
so I appreciate knowing and hearing that
it sounds good and then hearing that I
have a radio voice really is
embarrassing because I don't like my
voice at all it took me 50 episodes to
get comfortable hearing myself now it is
just normal but I appreciate that
because I don't like it so I'm glad
people do and it is funny when people
like you've got that smooth radio voice
especially when dude said it's really
awkward but thank you I do appreciate
that we're gonna keep moving it goes
like this I've learned so much from your
podcast and I have applied as much as I
could to my second ever grow
I think the bud turned out really good
with your help
and your genetics and he says I was
growing Rocksteady so I'm glad the rock
said he worked well for you
that was a huge contributing factor to
the quality of your outcome goes on to
say however I wanted to ask you a
question regarding curing because I have
read many forums online with conflicting
information and it says PS I know you
don't recommend reading forums
I just wanted some quick info related to
the issue I will explain below now Brian
is very accurate most of the time I
don't recommend getting your information
from the online forums there is a ton of
[ __ ] and false information on the
internet but there is also a ton of
quality information if you are smart
enough to sift through it if you were
smart enough to do some comparisons if
you can read five articles and say this
one sounds like [ __ ] these two makes
sense this is the one I should probably
go with and then just disregard one of
them probably you should be able to
figure out which articles are [ __ ]
and which makes some sense once you get
a little bit of experience and you have
a basic understanding but until then
those forums can be really confusing and
really misleading and they can really
cause you more problems than they can do
you good so quite often I say to avoid
the forum's unless you are able to sift
through the [ __ ] on your own those
forums that were feeding people [ __ ]
are a big part of why I do this podcast
I just saw a group in Facebook where a
person was telling somebody to harvest
their plants based on the ripeness or
the brownness of the hairs on their
plants the pistils that were saying now
that the pistils are brown it is time to
harvest and we're not smoking pistols
the pistols don't have [ __ ] to do with
it we want ripe trichomes so let's not
pay any attention to the pistols so
you're right sometimes the forums and
the Internet can be [ __ ] but also
who's to say that I know what I'm
talking about I'm sure I've come on here
and said at least three wrong things
before so who knows we just got to be
very careful to filter out the
information try to get your information
from a qualified source I would like to
believe that is me I'm going to continue
with this email because this copper Kim
from Green Dot labs has got me rambling
let's get back into it it says does the
curing process stop at 54% when you were
curing in jars the blood that I grew
started at 70% and he's talking about
70% moisture content humidity in the
jars and I was
gradually trying to bring it down to 55%
through burping but it got away from me
one day and as a result the humidity in
the various jars ranged from 52 to 55
percent relative humidity so he was
burping the jar slowly his intention was
to start off at 70 and then you seal the
jar and while the jar is in there the
moisture kind of gathers into the jet
comes out of the buds and it sweats out
of the buds the moisture and the air
ends up in the jar there's a process to
that that we'll talk about in a moment
you open the jar the moisture is able to
release the jar the air and the moisture
come out of the jar that will also bring
out chlorophyll in that process that
chlorophyll has now been turned into a
gas and it is releasing that from that
jar then you seal the jar back up now
there's a little less moisture in the
jar because we've just let a portion of
it out we seal it up and now we give the
opportunity for more of that moisture
within the bud to kind of escape it
sweats out of the bud and becomes
atmospheric into the jar we open the jar
and it escapes along with that process
we're turning chlorophyll from a
chlorophyll pigment into a gas that is
basically what is happening that gas
allows that chlorophyll to leave the
plant then we open the jar it leaves the
jar we're gonna do that multiple times
each time we want to reduce the humidity
in that jar very little 1/3 maybe 5% so
we can do it over a period of time now
it sounds like Bryan got carried away
and maybe possibly left the jar open for
too long or something went wrong and he
has got some cannabis in the jars or the
relative humidity are ranging from 52 to
55 percent now we'll get back into the
email it says I have since brought the
bud back up to 58 to 59 percent relative
humidity by using cannabis leaves and
you guys if you get your herb to dry it
is okay to pull a couple of leaves out
of the garden and drop those right into
your tearing jar and seal it up but be
very careful because you will be amazed
at how much moisture is in that bud or
in that leaf and how quickly it goes
into that bud and just pay attention so
you don't mold it up please it will
happen very quickly check on that jar
very often very soon more frequently
than you think you need to the reason I
recommend to use a cannabis leaf is
because it is the same Brix level it's
the same
plant it's the same flavor it's not
going to make any funky aromas or
flavors in your finished product it is
the same thing you're putting the same
kind of plant in the same kind of plant
many people will recommend other things
people recommend fruit people recommend
maybe like a q-tip with moisture on it
many people will use a humidity pack
from different brands I don't recommend
any of that cannabis leaf is probably
free and probably available so let's use
that and not [ __ ] up the flavors and
aromas of our product let's keep going
Bryan has put leaves into the jar he's
got the humidity back up where he wants
it and now here's where the question
comes in it says I have read in many
forums that the cure is over once the
humidity drops below 54% and you cannot
reinitiate the curing process you can
remoisturize the bud obviously but as
the curing state entirely over once the
relative humidity drops lower than 54%
that is a really good question
I am NOT able to give you a solid
scientific answer I'm going to be
completely honest and transparent that
that is a science question that is a
little bit past what I am qualified for
I can speak from experience and I can
give you bro science so here's what I
know when we are curing our plants our
goal is to seal the buds in a container
and that will create a gas inside of
that container the light the oxygen and
the moisture work together to create a
gas that gas will begin to eat the
chlorophyll and turn that chlorophyll
into a gas itself then once we open the
jar like I talked about earlier that gas
is released from the jar now that will
continue like you said until we get to
about 54 percent relative humidity seems
to be correct now this is the part where
I lack scientific education I and my
experience have noticed that once I let
the buds get past that dry point the
chlorophyll does not it is not able to
be removed any further once that amount
of moisture is gone I feel like that
moisture is required to create the
chemical reaction that creates the
breakdown
of the chlorophyll that allows it to
become a gas to allow it to remove
itself from the plant into the jar into
the atmosphere so once it gets too dry
you will not be able to remove more
chlorophyll and more pigments in my
experience and opinion the buds may
still taste a little grassy they may
have a little bit of harshness to them
depending on how long you let them stay
moist if this took long enough you may
have gotten all of that chlorophyll out
of there you may have a nice sweet cure
I don't know the timeframe in which you
let it slip once it got too low it
sounds like you did a good job so you
should have at least a decent product
now there is another aspect of drying
and curing to think about first we want
to hear to remove chlorophyll that is
that cat that natural reaction that I
was talking about a moment ago when we
seal the product in a jar the gases and
the moisture all start working together
it creates an environment that breaks
down the chlorophyll it allows the
chlorophyll to become a gas that green
pigment that doesn't taste good has now
become air it is in the air when we open
the jar we let that out now you don't
have to smoke it it is floating around
in the room and such minut particles we
don't notice it but we don't have to
smoke it that is the good part that is
part of our goal the other part is
trichome ripeness and trichome
preservation and terpene preservation
depending on other environmental factors
and when the product was harvested you
may still be ripening your trichomes
during that curing process also so your
main question was is the curing state
entirely over once the relative humidity
has dropped lower than 54% you may not
be pulling the chlorophyll out but you
are still slow drying that bud it is
getting drier just naturally it is
losing a little bit of moisture content
it still may be breaking down and you
are absolutely getting trichome ripeness
and cannabinoid conversions are still
happening so something is happening
inside of that jar still I would take
some buds out now and smoke them I would
leave some in there for a week and smoke
those maybe just one just a bowl maybe a
joint I don't know how you consume maybe
a vaporizer bucket I don't know what
you're putting in the vaporizer
but just consume have one sesh of a bowl
today and then a bowl in a week and then
a bowl in two weeks and then if you can
conserve it a bowl in a month and then
if you're [ __ ] crazy a bowl in two
months and try to compare see what the
differences are try to notice all the
subtleties many people don't have the
palate or don't care to develop the
palate to taste all of the subtleties in
a cannabis plant many people won't clean
the pipe and even give it an effort like
it all tastes like weed to me I am NOT
one of those people I can taste
subtleties and many different flavors in
cannabis so I like a nice clean pipe I
would appreciate smoking a bowl of the
same herb that has been kind of dried
and cured and then pretty dried and
cured and then really driving true to
them this one's been going for a while I
would appreciate hitting a bowl of all
of those and being like here that no one
tastes pretty good and makes some notes
and then try to remember a week later be
like oh man that it does taste better I
would write down like gassy gray P
smooth burns my throat I would breathe
some of it through my nose just to see
what it feels like through the nose I
would just breathe different ways they
serve beer in different shaped beer
glasses like if you buy certain kinds of
beer they serve it in different glasses
at the bar because the air creates a
different flavor for those beers when
you're smoking cannabis or concentrates
make your mouth in different funny
shapes and blow the air around blow the
smoke around in different shapes in your
mouth and you'll taste different flavors
and aromas pack a bowl of weed and don't
light it and just draw through the pipe
and taste it dry no flame to see what it
tastes like you get that fresh herb
grassy dank flavor tastes pretty nice
then light it up breathe it in get that
smoke all in your lungs and then blow it
out like you normally do pay attention
to the flavor going in as soon as it
goes in stop breathing not for no like
die hold it right there when that air
stops your tongue will catch the flavor
then blow it out you'll taste it going
out also so you got an in flavor you got
a stopped flavor you got out flavor it's
gonna taste like something as soon as it
gets out then if you're patient just
wait just let your tongue relax
a couple seconds later you're gonna get
bunch of different subtle flavors those
are the flavors I really look for that
right after that exhale and then relax
your face whoo and
I'll breathe in through my nose and then
out through my mouth and then maybe in
through my mouth and I'm just getting
different flavors I'm activating
different flavors different parts of my
tongue different parts of my palate
different Terps are working together and
I am noticing many subtle different
flavors that probably many people didn't
take the time or didn't know they had
the ability to even detect so that's a
good way to kind of hone your palate and
that is something I would appreciate so
I'm gonna wrap back around the question
I just did get off on her weird rant
about how to smoke and smell and taste
correctly but not all is lost you can
smoothen up the flavor of that smoke you
can increase the potency there are still
cannabinoid conversions and things are
still happening inside of that jar so
the short answer is no not all is lost
the process is not done pull some out
smoke it pull some out later smoke it
and take notes and then let me know how
it goes
you wrap this one up to say sorry for
the lengthy email I just wanted to make
sure I showed you some love but also
give you enough details to answer my
question so keep up the good work thanks
Brian be and then he says you can use my
name if you read this on the show so big
thanks big shout out to Brian B I do
appreciate the great email and ladies
and gentleman I have done a full length
podcast all about drying and curing your
cannabis make sure you check out episode
326 of the growth from your heart
podcast that is a full-length full
detailed episode on drying and curing
your cannabis all right boys and girls
ladies and gentlemen pimps and hoes
smokers and growers friends and foes
ladies and jelly spoons I think that is
all I've got for you for this great
flying episode of the girl from your
heart podcast I want to think you begin
for listening if you feel like this
episode of the show is educational
informative or entertaining and you
would like to make a financial
contribution to the show you can do so
by visiting www.hp.com slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need to help out the show will be right
there on the screen
big thanks to everybody who's
contributed to the patreon campaign I
would also appreciate it if you
subscribe to my youtube channel simply
go to youtube search for the grow from
your heart podcast click subscribe maybe
leave some comments on the videos let me
know what you think about the show I do
appreciate all of the listener
interaction also make sure you find me
on cannabis cannabis is a free
Cannabis friendly social media
application we cannot buy sell or trade
cannabis but we can post cannabis photos
and cannabis news and cannabis updates
and dab videos without any worry of your
account getting deleted many of the
other social media platforms are
removing cannabis related content
cannabis welcomes our cannabis related
content so join me on cannabis I look
forward to seeing you there it is a free
application available for your Android
or iPhone device join us catch a buzz
ladies and gentlemen I think that is all
I've got for you for this episode
aunty give a giant shout out to our
friend mason pin and until next time
take a phat dab and give your mom a hug
for me
[Music]
what I said
please
[Music]
like a steam locomotive attract these
guys
[Music]
bring it back he's gone
let my skin
[Music]
cool inside
ghetto dogs
[Music]
the track
scum
[Music]
baby
in the back and more of the same
Oh God
you
[Music]
don't you
what I say
still
[Music]
like a steam locomotive
check these man
[Music]
see
the track
he's gone
he's gotta break it back
[Music]