hey everybody welcome to episode 468 of
the growth from your heart podcast this
episode of the show is brought to you by
our friends at seeds here now if you
need new regular feminized our Auto
flower seeds in your garden I highly
recommend seeds here now and you can
find them at www.cdxzipstream.com oh I'm
gonna give it a fresh smell right now
just so I can give you an accurate
updated description yeah it has
definitely got the watermelon strawberry
notes to begin with it ends with the
hops then the grapefruit rind kind of
takes over at the end there and then
there is a lingering hint of fuel at the
end but honestly I would have put
watermelon and strawberry in the
description it does pack a nice punch
the potency label says that this product
contains 68 point zero nine percent THC
non detectable amounts of CBD it does
pack a nice punch it gives me a nice
buzz but the part that really stands out
is that delicious sweet strawberry candy
flavor so big shout out to our friends
at Green Dot labs for the delicious
India pale
full spectrum extract in this episode
I'm going to read a couple of listener
emails before we get there I would like
to do a couple of shout outs to our
friends from patreon
let's start off with the big giant grow
from your heart podcast shadow and thank
you to our friend Gabriel I also want to
send a giant girl from your heart
podcast
fist bump and a thank you to our new
friend JM also a big girl from your
heart podcast thank you - jacob w of
course a big thank you to keith k also i
want to send a big THANK YOU to Willy's
armpit of course I always want to send a
big giant grow from your heart podcast
thank you to Tommy and last but
certainly not least I will a big
high-five a fist bump a girl from your
heart podcast
shout out a hug and a thank you to our
buddy stab
makes tabloid big shout out big thank
you to everybody who supports the show
on patreon and if you would like to
learn how to support the show you can do
so by visiting www.azcleanelections.gov
the growth from your heart podcast this
email comes from a friend who calls
themselves the King of Prussia and the
message goes a lot like this it says
what's up Rasta Jeff after listening to
the podcast for the last few months and
learning an insane amount of info I
figured it was time to join patreon hey
thank you for joining patreon I
appreciate that I'm glad you were able
to learn a bunch of stuff it says you
can use King of Prussia for the shoutout
what's up Wilson good to meet you it
goes on to say been listening to your
podcast a whole lot lately
and I've been loving the show and all of
the info it is truly appreciated a thank
you for the big shout out thanks for
listening and thanks for the words of
encouragement and for noticing that I'm
trying hard I'm for appreciating it so
that means a lot
it says I'm listening to the episode
from Friday and the vapin through
security topic gave me a good laugh so
if you've been listening to the podcast
you've heard me talk about taking my
bait pins through security getting them
into some concerts having a good time
with my Green Dot labs full-spectrum
extract
bait pens here I was able to heavily
medicated some Phish concerts I was able
to well medicate at a Tom Segura comedy
show recently but without those bait
pens I would have been uh not very well
medicated so let's continue with this
message because it says I am in New York
I went to my local courthouse to pick up
my pistol permit and had to go through a
metal detector yes when you go into most
courthouses you are forced to walk
through the metal detectors this person
says I emptied my pockets and completely
forgot I had my cartridge pen in my
pocket
while on vacation in Portland so this
person walked into the court they
thought sure I'll throw my car keys and
my cellphone or whatever else in the
little basket here and I'll walk right
through the metal detector and this dude
realizes I have got my cartridge he
picked up a cart when he was in Portland
probably came back all the travel woes
took over completely forgot that
cartridge was there this dude pulls it
out in the courthouse he says nearly
[ __ ] myself as the cop took the bin and
I walked through the metal detector yeah
I could imagine that feeling being in
New York it is much more secure than a
lot of other places I am certain of it
is not cannabis friendly so here in
Colorado if they catch you with your
pants I go what can take that back to
the car you can't bring that in here I'm
sure if they catch you with that in New
York they go oh you're already in the
court let's just put you in a cage and
they just skip a bunch of steps anyway
this person says not a word was said and
I was on my way so this person got lucky
luckily that law enforcement officer
that had to inspect the handful of crap
that they pass through they just thought
that's probably just a nicotine pen and
they didn't give a [ __ ] part of the
thing was that you just slid it right
through and didn't act like it was
anything so they didn't think it was
anything you wouldn't hand them drugs he
wouldn't be like here's my drugs so they
thought these aren't drugs they said
yeah it's probably your nicotine pen and
they just let it slide right through so
congratulations I'm really happy that
you did not get yourself in trouble
be more careful bro anybody out there if
you were going to any sort of
environment where you feel like you may
need to empty your pockets do a double
check make sure you don't have anything
illegal in your pocket so you don't get
yourself in trouble there's a really
funny meme that goes around on social
media it shows that a waitress in
Colorado
went to leave her pen along with the
check at the restaurant so the diner
could sign their check but they
accidentally left their dad pen now if
that were the wrong environment that
person could have gotten in a lot of
trouble fortunately it is a Colorado
restaurant everybody probably laughed
pretty hard at that but we've got to be
more careful I do catch myself getting
too relaxed too comfortable I want to go
to other places I do travel out-of-state
a little bit and I catch myself just
smoking places that I shouldn't be
smoking and I have to say oh yeah you're
not in Colorado you gotta chill the [ __ ]
out also I was talking about hitting my
pin at a Tom Segura comedy show I would
never smoke and comedy works that was at
a different venue a much larger venue
and I caught myself I had my pen in my
hand just cuz I have it and I click the
button a couple times and I put it my
mouth and I just ripped it and as I had
a lung full of dab smoke I realized
you've got a lung full of dab smoke in a
comedy club you should not be doing this
I was like now what am I gonna do I got
a bunch of smoke in my lungs had to hold
that [ __ ] in until I almost died you
guys so I did catch myself getting a
little too comfortable a little too at
home just pulled out my pen and ripped
it right there in the Belko theater like
I was supposed to be smoking it there
you're not supposed to be smoking it
there they would have kicked me out if
somebody had spotted me so we need to
learn to be a little more careful if
you're in a legal state still be a
little bit paranoid if you were in an
illegal state please be extra paranoid
let's not get ourselves in trouble
luckily our friend walked through and
not a word was said because he acted
like nothing was wrong anyway there is
one more sentence left in this message
it says anyway thanks for spreading the
knowledge and keep up the amazing work
hey our friend King of Prussia I want to
call you Wilson if you get that joke
you're a lot cooler than some people
Wilson thank you for the great email I
do appreciate it I'm glad you did not
get in any trouble if anybody else out
there wants to send me an email my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I would love to hear from
you all right let's just keep the show
moving right into the next email this
one goes like this jefe Jeff I've got
four outdoor container-grown sunkissed
plants where the top surface trichomes
are about 20% amber so this person has
four sunkissed plants outdoors in
containers and the top surface trichomes
are 20% amber that is a great place to
start that is good information Sun
kisses across that I bread that is of
course the Platinum tangi from our
friends at the garden of Weeden cross to
Maya rise wonderful strain to work with
a great outdoor strain we should have
good success let's continue it says
normally I would think these plants
would be ready for harvest
but looking at the undersides of the
leaves through a high-quality botanical
microscope showing trichomes are still
clear and cloudy with a little bit of
amber coloration
so this person has acquired a scope they
probably magnified similar to sixty to a
hundred acts and they're looking at the
undersides of the leaves through their
microscope and the trichomes are still
clear on the undersides of the leaves
more of the message says I'm a beginner
grower this is my third grow and I
previously would have cut these plants
at this point but given that they're at
day 48 of flower and the suggested
harvest age from Ira genetics Colorado
comm is 56 days I'm wondering if I
should wait another week these plants
have had a lot of TLC and full sunlight
all summer long maybe they're just ready
to go and he ends it with appreciate any
feedback you can provide thank you from
our friend we're just gonna call him
caffeine is what he signed it as here so
let's talk about a couple of things that
our buddy caffeine had to say and just
to make you feel better I do intend on
doing a full episode on the strain
Sunkiss I think that's about four or
five episodes out it is in the notebook
it is mostly written so we will get a
full episode on that strain but for now
let's focus on some of the questions in
this email you start off right on track
with trichomes or 20% amber and normally
I would think these plants are ready for
harvest if you've got 20% amber
trichomes you are absolutely ready for
harvest I almost would have taken that
plant down sooner but you're still going
to be alright we have a nice harvest
window here we'll talk a little bit
about that in a moment I would take
those down they are probably done you're
saying but looking at the underside of
the leaves through a high-quality
microscope shows clear with little amber
coloration in the trichomes now the
undersides of the leaves don't really
matter what we are going for is ripe
trichomes on the buds how many of those
leaves are you going to smoke hopefully
not too many hopefully you're going to
turn that into concentrates or something
hopefully you're not smoking the leaves
we want to focus mostly on the buds I
would look at a bud up at top I would
look at a bud halfway down the plant and
then I would look at a lower bud and I
would do a few checks with my microscope
and I would see what percentage of the
trichomes are amber in each section of
the plant and then I would use my best
judgment to harvest based on the overall
appearance of the trichomes the
trichomes you're finding on the
undersides of the leaves would
very little to do with my
decision-making when thinking about
harvest times that would not matter to
me at all I want to look at the buds so
it sounds like you've got 20% amber
trichomes on your buds your plants are
probably ready for harvest now you did
bring up a very good topic in here it
says I previously would have cut these
but they're at day 48 and on the website
from the breeder which is myself
we recommend 56 days so you're wondering
if you should wait if the plants are
showing you that they're done they are
done don't worry about what the website
says don't worry about what I told you
don't worry about what I said in a live
feed don't worry about what anybody on
social media tells you if the trichomes
are amber the plant is done that is what
we use to gauge the ripeness of a plant
is amber trichomes that is our goal is a
right track
the plant is ripe nobody on Facebook
knows if that trichome is ripe nobody on
any social media knows I don't even know
if it's ripe there are variations in
plants that come from seed ideally most
phenotypes of that plant overall will
end around the 56 day mark you've got an
anomaly you may have gotten a little
extra sunshine you maybe you've gotten a
little less sunshine and some grows
maybe you've fed it something different
maybe you've fed it more maybe you've
had it less maybe it is just a
phenotypic expression maybe you got one
that finishes around what are you at
forty eight maybe you got one they've
finished a week early that is a really
good thing and it is very possible
because the Sunkiss strain does have
phenotypes that end a little bit earlier
but if I would have written on that
package or on my website that those
plants end at 48 days if those plants
took 52 days the world would have been
pissed off at me
so saying that they end at 56 days and
you've got one that went a week early
that is kind of a good thing it still
sucks because I gave you poor timing but
that is an anomaly that is a phenotypic
'el variance something that is kind of
expected when it comes to growing so we
have to pay attention to that and
honestly I listed 56 days because that
is my experience indoors you've grown
this outdoors so you're finding
different results because you've got
different conditions so that is to be
expected let's talk about that briefly
when we were talking about the time that
it should take two
our on a pack of seeds that is a guess
that is an estimate depending on the
breeder of those plants that estimate is
based on different things unfortunately
we can type whatever we want on our
websites we can type whatever we want on
our packaging and there are very few
people that will hold us accountable to
that until growers start buying the
seeds and discovering that we told a lie
that is the only thing holding us
accountable but by then you've bought
the seeds and you've grown them
somebody's got your money and they're on
vacation already the proper way to do it
is to create the seeds then grow them
and take a lot of notes and that is how
I determine how long I suggest those
seeds are grown is by growing out large
populations I like to grow at least a
hundred seeds before anybody else gets
to see them so I know what to look for
when you grow a hundred it is really
easy to create percentages if one
doesn't it's 1% if 50 plants do it that
is 50% it's really easy to identify
traits and keep statistics with
populations of 100 so I grew out 100 of
those and the average of those plants
were done at day 56 we may have had
outliers go a week each direction I may
have had outliers go two weeks either
direction but what I determined overall
was that 56 days would be the average
completion time for that strain Sunkiss
where most people would have the best
success now we do have to keep in mind
that these are plants there is going to
be genetic variation in these seeds
their seeds made from plants I'm just
taking pollen and putting it on another
plant nature is making these seeds the
seeds come out we need to expect some
variation Sunkiss is an f1 hybrid it is
not F tude it has not been worked to
create more homogeneous phenotypes
I like the variation that come from f1
hybrids I like the bigger that comes
from an f1 hybrid so we need to learn to
understand and accept the variation that
comes from seeds I like it I think that
growing from seed gives me the option to
find something that nobody else will
ever have if the entire neighborhood is
sharing clones everybody is growing the
same [ __ ] strain and in a couple of
weeks everybody is going to be tired of
the same [ __ ] strain so if you buy a
pack of seeds and you find two or three
different phenotypes you've already got
two or three different things that set
you apart from the market from the other
people that are growing that same clone
that everybody in the hood is spreading
around so now you were separating
yourself from the market if you were
growing for profitability that is a
great way to set yourself apart then you
select that best phenotype that works
the best for you you've got the one that
sells the best the one that works the
best for your gross style the one that
does what needs to be done in your
neighborhood and you can find that by
growing from seeds if you buy seeds and
nobody else in the hood bottom you're
the only one with that now you get to
grow that pack of seeds you get to find
a keeper phenotype then you get to
dominate the market because you've got
something that sets you apart from
everybody else so I really enjoy growing
from seed and I really enjoy the
variation that I get when it comes to
growing from seed it's kind of like
buying a pack of baseball cards or I
guess today you would say Magic the
Gathering or [ __ ] pokemon cards or
something like that you get this pack of
cards you get a pack of seeds and you go
home and instead of just opening it up
and going through and seeing how many
lands and how many rare cards you've got
or how many [ __ ] Mickey Mantle cards
you got you got to grow the seeds out
you got ten seeds you put them in some
water you put them in some dirt and then
we nurture them for several weeks a
couple of months probably and then at
the end of that we get to find out what
cards came in that package of cards
because we just get a rare card that's
gonna help us win the game do we just
get Mickey Mantle or do we just get a
bunch of LANs and a bunch of shortstops
that is the fun of growing from seed you
get to find out what you get I really
find magic in that it makes me excited
to grow from a pack of seeds it's like
whoo I wonder what's in there and then I
am blessed I've got a lot of seeds so I
get to find many variations many
anomalies I get to see things from
populations that most people will never
get to see so growing from seed really
excites me I really love the variation
so let me try to get myself back on
track here you were correct those plants
are finished I would focus on the
trichomes on the but it's not as much as
the trichomes on the leaves we aren't
too worried about the leaves those are
kind of bonus trichomes those are
secondary trichomes you're probably
gonna cut those off and throw them away
if they are not used for extraction so
focus on those trichomes on the buds you
said there are 20% amber it is probably
time to harvest that plant hope you've
been flushing cuz it is time to cut down
now I hope you took a close
because you've got a phenotype that ends
a little bit early and endures that
plant would be a dream it is very hard
to find a plant that finishes around the
48 day marker you can increase
productivity by one full crop per year
indoors if you have that phenotype and
it is reliable and it creates a potent
product that people want most of the
time we are running eight or nine week
plants which will give us about five
point seven harvests per year if we keep
a perpetual cycle going in one room if
you cut off those extra few days you
give us the potential for one extra
harvest in our room now based on the
amount of white-sand square footage in
that room that can be as much as one
pound per year extra or in some
facilities where I work that could be as
much as two hundred and fifty pounds
extra product in one year so I think
you're really lucky really blessed to
have found a phenotype of Sunkist that
ends at forty eight possibly fifty days
I hope it is a winner I hope it's a
keeper I hope it is highly potent for
you I hope it tastes amazing most of all
I really want to see some photos if you
haven't cut it down by the time you hear
this go outside take a nice photo and
send that [ __ ] to me you can send it to
me it grow from your heart at
hotmail.com or you can send it to my
breeder email
I read genetics at hotmail.com either
way I would love to see your work
alright he wraps up the message by
saying appreciate any feedback you can
provide I hope I was able to help you
out those plants are done I hope you've
got clones I hope you're able to run
that indoors again I hope it works very
well for you he wraps it up and he calls
himself caffeine so big shout out to our
buddy caffeine thank you for the great
email all right podcast world this is a
Thursday episode so I'm going to cut it
short you can tell my voice is burning
out I do have an important meeting
tomorrow so I do need to have a voice to
talk for that so I'm going to wrap up
this episode I want to thank you guys
for hanging out for another episode of
The Grove from your heart podcast if you
feel like this episode was educational
informative or entertaining and you
would like to make a financial
contribution to the show you can do so
by visiting www.disabilitydenials.com
for
for the girl from your heart podcast
click on the subscribe button also type
in some comments on the videos and let
me know what you think of the show I
would also appreciate it if you find me
on cannabis cannabis is a free cannabis
friendly social media application you
can post your cannabis photography you
can post your dab videos you can post
your fancy pictures of your plants join
the cannabis community it is free the
application is available on your Android
or your iPhone device or your Apple
device give it a download create a
username login follow ireon der score
genetics don't miss your opportunity to
win some cool prizes quite often I give
away very cool prizes to random people
on cannabis so join cannabis you may win
a cool Irie gift pack ladies and
gentlemen that is all I've got for you
for this episode my voice is done my
throat is burning out I want to thank
you again for listening if you would
like to reach out to me my email address
once again is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com you know that I would love
to hear from you ladies and gentlemen
boys and girls pimps and hoes smokers
and growers that is all I've got for you
for this episode I want to give a huge
shout out to my friend Tara Lee and
until next time take a phat dab and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]