all right here we go a little Monday
show for you what's a podcast world it
is time for episode 469 of the growth
from your heart podcast this episode of
the show is brought to you by seeds here
now if you need new regular feminized or
Auto flower seeds in your garden I
highly recommend seeds here now and you
can find them at www.cdxzipstream.com -
a concentrate so it's got that delicious
aroma it's got a delicious flavor then
the appearance of this concentrate is
perfect I've got a big 4 gram jar it
looks like a nice jar of iced tea or
Terp tea if you will I've got some nice
icebergs floating around in here some
nice diamonds a perfect ratio of
diamonds to Terp sauce I really enjoy
the appearance again the aroma and
flavor are tremendous and if you can't
tell the high from this concentrate is
[ __ ] excellent it went straight to my
head it lifted me up it made me
energetic it made me want to come to a
podcast it made me just want to talk my
face off let's flip the jar over here
and check out the potency label on the
back of the jar it says that this
product contains 66 point 3 1% THC it
does not contain any CBD and I do
imagine that if we had a Terp test on
this product the terpene numbers would
be ridiculous because as soon as you
open this jar you can smell it from
across the room so big shout out to my
friends at Green Dot labs for the
delicious and ridiculous headbanger
full-spectrum extract all right podcast
world in this episode I'm going to read
a couple of emails before I get there I
would like to do some shoutouts to our
friends who support the show on patreon
let's start off with the big giant grow
from your heart podcast shout out and a
thank you to my buddy stabby make stab
wood
a big shot at or buddy Gabriel I want to
send a big THANK YOU to JM how about a
big thank-you shoutout to todd kay of
course i want to send a big grow from
your heart podcast shout out to our
buddy Brett gee as always a big thank
you shout out to Jacob w I want to give
a big thank you shout out to Keith K and
of course last but certainly not least I
want to send a big grow from your heart
podcast shout out thank you and a fist
bump to our friend Oh G
purple thumb big shout out and big thank
you to everybody who's continued to
support the show on patreon
I do appreciate all of the support if
anybody out there would like to learn
how to support the show on patreon you
can do so by visiting www.hp.com slash
grow from your heart all of the
information you need will be right there
on the screen
all right podcast world before we get to
the email portion of the show I want to
talk about some fun but I got to have
recently if you listen to the last
episode I'm sure you heard me mention
that I was accidentally hitting my vape
pen in a comedy show so I'm gonna talk
about those comedy shows for a few
minutes here over the weekend
my buddy Clint came over and we headed
up to Denver together we got some food
and then we went to a couple of
wonderful comedy shows we started the
evening off as I said before we got some
good food we had dinner at the mellow
mushroom big shout out to the Mellow
Mushroom a shout out to Clint for buying
me dinner had a great dinner then we
headed over to the comedy works to see
Brendan Schaub if you don't know about
comedy works Comedy Works is one of the
top three maybe top two best comedy
clubs in the country if not on the
entire planet I am a giant comedy nerd I
love comedy shows
I love comedians I love going to comedy
shows and laughing my ass off I go to
comedy works quite frequently so I am
treated like royalty at comedy works so
we headed to Comedy Works to see one of
my favorite comedians I listened to a
podcast called
the fighter and the kid I also listened
to another podcast called the King and
the sting there is a guy who was on both
of those podcasts his name is Brendan
Schaub he is a pretty funny comedian he
is a retired UFC fighter he is a fashion
model he is an all-around funny dude I
think he is hilarious so as soon as I
heard that Brendan Schaub is coming to
his hometown of Denver Colorado to
perform at one of the best comedy clubs
on the planet I knew I had to grab a
couple of tickets to go show some
fighter in the kid loved to go show some
King and the sting loved to go see one
of my favorite comedians Brendan Schaub
in his hometown and I'm glad I decided
to go because it was a great show when
we got in they treated us like royalty
from the very beginning we got VIP
wristbands we got parking passes we got
beautiful seats usually I'm right in the
front at Comedy Works we got there a
little bit later they didn't put me
right in the front it had a little VIP
meet-and-greet thing going on so some
people paid extra for fancy tickets so
they put me about three rows back and I
really enjoyed that third row spot my
neck wasn't as cranked as it usually is
trying to look at the front row I was
kind of nice to be right in the third
row so that was [ __ ] awesome really
great seats they brought us a couple of
snacks got us some non-alcoholic drinks
coz Clint and I do not consume alcohol
so we got settled in the show began and
the host and emcee of the evening was a
great comedian whose name was Assange
Ahmad if you guys are comedy fans pay
attention to Assange Ahmad he is coming
up he is hilarious
you will hear of him in the future pay
attention to that guy he is crushing it
so he came out he hosted the show he
basically walks out and he says hey this
is my name welcome to the show he tells
you a couple rules about the comedy club
basically shut the [ __ ] up and listen
don't heckle fire exits through that way
have a good time
buy a shirt buy drinks tip the waitress
here's the rest of the show then he
brings out another comedian and I got
really excited because he said you know
him as the voice of the King and the
sting and I knew it wasn't Theo because
he's the other member of the King and
the sting and I knew he was in another
city doing a show so I got excited I
said is it and he said ladies and
gentlemen I want to bring to the stage
mr. Derrick Poston and Derrick Poston is
the producer of a podcast called the
King and the sting which also features
Brendan Schaub I was really excited to
put a face on Derek posting because I
hear him weekly it was good to finally
see the dude and honestly his comedy
blew the [ __ ] room apart that dude
was hilarious I was not prepared to be
blown away by Derek Poston the way I was
he did maybe 50
or twenty minutes but it felt like 30
minutes of laughter it is hard for a
comedian to take the entire room with a
very short amount of time it takes a few
minutes to suck people in he walked out
on stage and he's like what's up
[ __ ] I'm funny you're gonna
laugh and then I got a go and that's how
it went
we [ __ ] laughed I almost pissed my
pants and then he's like now are you
ready for Brennan shop then shop came
out and he did a lot of material I did
not know that shop had that much
material he just put out a special on
show time recently and most of the time
once a comedian puts out a special they
don't do that material anymore it's like
you've heard those jokes we don't want
to [ __ ] tell those jokes anymore
it's called burning the material you put
it out and you move on you write a whole
new hour then you go through that
material in clubs for a year maybe do
that material and theatres for a year
then you go back and record another
special at that point that material is
burnt you don't get to do it anymore
yes there are some bits that people will
do over and over again like the machine
story with Bert Kreischer and then
anything Andrew Dice Clay but those are
comedic anomalies those don't [ __ ]
count most of the time people don't want
to hear your [ __ ] twice once you know
the punchline the joke isn't funny
anymore so I was blown away and
impressed with the amount of material
that shop brought to the stage one thing
I really enjoy is when I hear somebody
from a podcast on a stage telling a
story or doing a bit about stuff that
developed on the podcast recently I
really like watching that comedic mind
and watching that comedic snowball
happened like two guys are on a podcast
talking and something funny about I
don't know a white guy with dreadlocks
and a vape pen comes up just in the
funny conversation and then you'd hear
him tell a joke about it for two minutes
and then you hear it kind of taper off
and then you heard it on the next
episode they kind of make another stupid
joke about it that's called a callback
when you bring that up and you talk
about it again and then it fades and
then you go see him in a podcast or on a
comedy show two weeks later and he's got
30 minutes about it and you almost piss
your pants cuz you saw it develop and
you know that that's organic that joke
came from just a normal conversation
between two dudes and it is now a
polished and honed bit been made I think
comedy works holds about 250 maybe 320
people so it made 300 people piss their
pants with laughter from a little joke
they developed on the
cat so I think that that is great to see
also I like seeing the influences and
comedians I said earlier I'm a huge
comedy nerd you guys this is just gonna
be a quick rant about comedy will move
on to cannabis I know I've gone way too
long about this but I like seeing the
roots I like looking at a comedian and
saying oh you sound like this guy on
this guy and this guy so it's really fun
watching the influences in shop there
were a couple of moments when I said
that was completely Bryan Callen that
was completely Joe Rogan that was
completely Chris D'Elia
but that's okay because it's you're just
absorbing your influences so that was
fun to see it was fun to see shop shop
crushed it he did a really good job big
shout out to all three of the comedians
at that show big shot at the Brin and
shop big shout out to Derrick Poston and
big shout out to assange Ahmad I got to
meet everybody after the show like I
said there was a little meet-and-greet I
got to have a very brief conversation
with Brendan Schaub he said hey I love
the dreads and I looked him straight in
the face and said no you don't bro and
he gave me a bewildered look and I said
I listened to your podcast I know how
you feel about stupid white guys with
dreadlocks and he made a face like oh
[ __ ] I've offended people and then there
was a guy taking pictures and he just
goes picture so we both looked at the
camera and we do our pose the photo
happens and I looked back at him I go
bro I'm just joking I love that you make
fun of white people with dreadlocks on
the podcast you're a comedian don't ever
stop doing comedy and he laughed amigos
okay man he like felt better like I set
him up to like I was like man I know
what you said about white people and
then why people dreadlocks and then I
let him feel relief like man I think
it's funny that you say that I can't be
offended because I'm a white guy with
dreadlocks I expect jokes about white
people with dreadlocks that's how it
goes being this guy so when I when I
said that he felt relief I could see it
in his face and then I just shook his
hand I told thank you and I was walking
away and I got a few feet away and goes
hey bro and I was like what's up man I
turned around and goes how long you been
growing them things and I said 15 years
and he goes you sure have so that was
really fun and entertaining then I
walked outside and got to spend a minute
with the two other comedians
Derek Poston is [ __ ] hilarious very
friendly very approachable also assange
Ahmad very friendly very approachable at
a short conversation with both of them
VIN I got to meet a young man who goes
by the name of shark eyes doll smile
also known as Jay Shaab kind of a
popular guy if you listen to any of the
T fat K or King on the sting type of
podcast so
to shake his hand got to tell him that
he does great artwork I just got to hang
out with all those dudes for a couple of
minutes that is always a good time so
big shout out to that entire gang the
comedians and Jay Schwab big shot at the
Brennan shop for bringing a show here
this was his home town so it was kind of
funny his mom was heckling him he would
tell jokes and you could just hear his
mom giggle with pride that was [ __ ]
funny just to hear everybody laugh and
then his mom laughs a couple of extra
times and then he would do the thing
where you kind of put your hand it's not
the thumb across the throat like you're
killing somebody
it's the fingers across the neck like
cut it out cut it out Katie you're done
he was giving his mom that the look of
disapproval The Skeptical Hippo eyebrows
and then giving her that the cut it out
mom but it was just cute it was funny I
was like uh come on mom
but it was funny because the crowd was
in on it we all know it's his hometown
we know that that was his mom in the
back it was [ __ ] funny so big ol
shout out to that whole gang gang gang
buzz buzz culture culture that [ __ ] is
awesome if you know what that means then
you're in the gang with us that was a
great time I also need to send a special
shout out to everybody at Comedy Works
everybody at that club treats myself and
whoever I bring like [ __ ] royalty like
rock stars I love it go to comedy works
if you want to see a comedy show if you
want to get some laughter if you want to
take somebody on a date if you've got
somebody to take a business meeting or
something like that you need to take
them somewhere go to comedy works go
catch a comedy show the only thing is
you got to kind of shut up for a little
bit but you can share that laughter and
then on the car ride on the way home you
have a lot of things to talk about
because the comedian's are gonna bring
up points and you get to look at each
other like do I agree or do I disagree
with this person and you can talk about
that in the car so go get some laughter
go have a show then it will create
conversation with your date with your
business partner it is a great [ __ ]
time tell him Rasta Jeff sent you shout
at all my friends at Comedy Works also
big shout out to tall Clint from being a
cool comedy bro he's not my date he's
just my bro you guys we have a good time
he's much easier than taking a [ __ ]
date so after the Brendan Schaub show we
were not done we got to meet everybody
then we walked about 15 minutes to the
Belko theater where we got to see what
another comedy show I know it's kind of
crazy
I was a little spent my laughter muscles
were done my cheeks hurt my tummy was a
little bit sore from laughing so hard
but it was
to get more comedy going so we went to
the Belko theater I've talked about the
Belko theater before on this show big
beautiful theater inside of the Denver
Convention Center a nice comfortable
place we got a bottle of water we got
our seats chilled out for a couple of
minutes they made the announcement that
no phones if you get your phone out you
were to leaving basically is what they
said then the lights went out and this
young man by the name of Jeff Tate came
out and did a few minutes Jeff Tate is a
very good comedian I'm sure you've heard
me speak of him before I'm not the Jeff
Tate from Queens right a different Jeff
Tate the funny Jeff Tate the funny Oh
Jeff Tate at least he came out he did a
few minutes I told a couple of jokes he
was mostly funny then after that the man
the myth the legend the [ __ ]
offensive one mr. Tom Segura came out
and blew the roof off of the Belko
theater it's hard to say he blew the
roof off of the place because he's
mellow he doesn't get real fired up like
when you see Rogan Rogan yells at you
when you see Joey Diaz Diaz yells at you
Tom Segura has more of a mellow slower
delivery with kind of a condescending
tone to it it just hits in a different
way it's darker so instead of being
yelled some crazy [ __ ] that makes you
laugh after the idea is pounded into
your head
he'll say something and then just he
could say a normal sentence and then
think of a normal sense it would be fine
I don't have an example and then just
add two words to it with my dick and
then that makes every sentence creepy
anything you say if you add the words
with my dick to the end of it it's
[ __ ] subtle and it's gross and
everybody gets that it's a joke he'll
just say something and that's not a Tom
Segura joke I'm killing his ideas of
jokes but he'll tell you a story and
then end it with my dick and that's when
everybody gets a huge laugh and his
stories are [ __ ] great
he is offensive if you want to be
offended please check out some Tom
Segura comedy he will piss you off in
the best way that's my favorite kind
kind of comedy so check that out so that
was a great night I got to see Brennan
shop
Derek Poston Assange Ahmad I got to see
Jeff Tate and I got to see Tom Segura I
was honestly blown away by Derek post
and I can't give him enough credit and
enough props pay attention for Derek
Poston he is gonna blow you away in the
near future of course Tom Segura was the
highlight of the evening that was
[ __ ] awesome then we headed back to
the car bumped into a friend
on the way to the car got to give a good
friend to hug just randomly walking down
the street in Denver and there's a
beautiful friend said hey what's up give
her a hug kept walking got to the car we
headed back uh normal evening great safe
drive home so that was a fun time big
shot at the Clint for being a great
comedy buddy I've given him a shout-out
on the show for that before ah dude
let's go to more comedy shows
Joey Coco Diaz is coming up if you're at
the Joey show I look forward to seeing
you at the Paramount Theater give me a
high five all right so that is wrapping
up the comedy adventure what else did I
do just because it's on my mind and I
went there and it was [ __ ] awesome
let's talk about this quick road trip I
took just a couple of days ago I drove
to Evergreen Colorado the only place I
really mentioned that is because holy
[ __ ] it was beautiful and I cannot stop
thinking of the way the place felt and
smelled and just the vibe and the energy
there it was really calming it was
really peaceful and it was so beautiful
it was just the right temperature it was
the first kind of cool day in Colorado
so I didn't have my hoodie on but I kind
of wish I did but I enjoyed that brisk
cool mountain the air there's no traffic
up there lots of beautiful animals lots
of beautiful scenery and everybody I
spoke to an evergreen was like hey buddy
how you doing are you having as
beautiful of a day as I am it was just
[ __ ] excellent up there so it's a
great place big shot it's the Evergreen
Colorado
don't move there it's overcrowded they
don't need more people stay away let's
just keep it [ __ ] beautiful alright
now I'm gonna press pause I'm gonna take
a drink I'm gonna take like 47 dabs then
we're actually going to get into the
cannabis portion of this podcast take a
DAB with me boys and girls all right
boys and girls ladies and gentlemen
pimps and hoes smokers and growers
friends and foes friends and fam I am
back I am well medicated I am well
hydrated it is time to get into the
email portion of the show let's jump
right into it the first email for this
episode goes just like this it says hey
Rasta Jeff I hope everything is going i
read for you on this lovely tuesday i'm
reading this on a Friday you are
probably listening on a Monday
everything still I read the message goes
on to say my name is oh let's skip that
I don't know if you want your name said
it says my name is blank and I am 22 and
I've been growing for about four years
total and I started at my parents house
I rolling outside
the time I got to having ten three-foot
tall plants in one area was when I
realized that I have a passion for
growing cannabis and I want to go about
this legally that is a very common story
a lot of people start growing they
realize that it is very fulfilling in
many ways first off you have your own
cannabis that you grew that is
absolutely instantly gratifying and
rewarding but there is something that
comes with growing your own cannabis
that is just fulfilling and a lot of
people have a passion for producing
their own product so our friend here
quickly realized that they have a
passion for growing cannabis and they
wanted to go about it legally so they
the message continues it says I attended
a hands-on certified cannabis college
and shortly after I applied for a grow
position at and I'm not gonna say the
name of the company but they applied for
a position and got hired on the spot
that is awesome you went to a certified
cannabis college to give yourself some
credentials there and then you went and
applied and you were hired immediately
let's find where I was in the email it
says so I moved from one location to
another I'm going to leave out your
locations because I want to keep you
safe I don't know who may hear this down
the road we don't want to put you in any
jeopardy so we're gonna keep all your
locations and names kind of secret but
it says I've moved location since then
and that's where this new business is
located and I've been here for two years
I am now leading a building with
multiple rooms that are this size I'm
not gonna say that because that is those
are too many clues other people who hear
this they'll know that this is you I
says I've got a hundred or so plant in
each room I have rich 80 to 90 pounds
dry weight per 18 HPS lights per room so
you're saying you get 80 to 90 pounds
out of 18 HPS lamps per room I'm really
curious how long your vegging I'm really
curious how you're doing that deep water
culture hydro soilless mix are you on
tables I want to know about your
genetics I'm trying to do the math in my
head quickly while I'm talking that's
over 3 pounds per light that's 3.6
pounds per light I'm actually gonna pull
out a calculator here and do that let's
see what this says we were going to
divide 90 pounds divided by 18 lights
it's 5 pounds okay I did poor math in my
head there but we got 5 pounds per light
that's [ __ ] impressive I would like
to believe you doesn't sound
very likely let's keep reading to be
completely honest man I only know what
this company has taught me and from of
Sun and from some of the old heads with
that being said I don't know if it's
good decent or super bad if you were
genuinely pulling four to five maybe six
pounds per light that's impressive you
need to keep doing that again I can't
see the quality of the product I don't
know if you're even trimming it it could
be fluffy and larva [ __ ] I could pull
you five pounds perlite if I don't trim
it but I don't know if anybody wants
that I'm gonna do math again just to
make sure I did that right on 90 pounds
divided by 18 lights one's [ __ ] five
pounds of light bro that's very unlikely
very uncommon ah you should be getting
bonuses and a lot of money if you were
doing that for the company that is
unheard of I'm not gonna say it's
unheard of that's [ __ ] unheard of
dude we like to push for two maybe three
pounds per light five pounds is a little
bit ridiculous Congrats if you're really
pulling that but I want to see the
product I want to see how its trim don't
want to see how many sticks and stems
are left in there I'm not doubting you
I'm just questioning you there's a
slight difference not much though I'm
gonna continue where am I it says he
doesn't know if he's doing good decent
or super bad your harvest weight is
great I can't tell you anything else
about the quality of the product I'm
gonna go on it says with that being said
I know now that legalization in Florida
is coming up and I have two investors
which believe in me and they want to
open a shop once the laws allow so
Florida is about to legalize it sounds
like and he's got some people behind him
and this guy wants to open up shop he's
working for somebody now he's pulling
good weight but he's got some investors
that want to pull him away and give him
his own building it sounds like this is
a common thing this happens a lot it's
called recruiting here's what I call it
it says am i approaching the industry
the right way should I get any specific
degrees am i at a disadvantage for only
knowing how to grow commercially I
really don't think any specific degree
would help you out maybe some kind of
business degree because you're going to
need to learn how to manage business and
stuff just if you're involved in the
business you want to learn maybe go to
school just for the basics of business
and understand that so you don't get
ripped off once you get in business
people with degrees they can rip you off
just on purpose and there's not [ __ ] you
can do about it they could do it in a
contract right in front of you and
they'll say this is where I [ __ ] you and
you'll sign the pay
because you don't know that that's where
they wrote this is where I [ __ ] you so
learn a little bit about business learn
that stuff then are you screwing
yourself by only knowing how to grow a
commercial you know that's your goal you
are meant to be a commercial grower if
that's what this new business is going
to be so focused on commercial growing
dial it in learn as much as you can
every aspect of commercial growing it
sounds like if you're really pulling the
weight that you have typed here in these
numbers
it sounds like you've got commercial
growing figured out again you can pull
90 pounds out of the room but if you
don't trim it right your it and package
it and get it to the store and doesn't
sell by the gram at 80 to 90 or 80 90
pounds if that cash doesn't come into
the cash right sure it doesn't count so
being able to produce that much it's got
to be quality as well I want to see the
product I'm really curious about that
but learn how to function in a business
you're gonna have to go from a STONER
from a grower from a cultivator you're
gonna have to step up your mindset and
start learning a little bit more
business thought not just managing your
own but also working with other business
owners and working with the investors
you're gonna be playing with a lot of
money learn how to not take the money
and the pressure as stress just think
about think about it as this is what I'm
doing and I know how to do it I'm
confident so we will be successful but
at the same time know how to make wise
decisions you're gonna have to do a lot
of thinking and a lot of planning so I
don't recommend any specific degrees
just think about a lot of things and
open your mind step out of the the
closet grower or the small mind
cultivator and start thinking a million
dollar cultivation and everything you're
doing
you just have to dial in every detail a
little better don't let it stress you
that much more just step up your game
that much more go the opposite don't let
it scare you make it make you better
I'm gonna continue with the email
because obviously these dad's gonna be
[ __ ] rambly today so let me find my
spot where am i he said am i approaching
the industry the right way it sounds
like you're learning commercial
cultivation if you're pulling 80 to 90
dry pounds out of 18 lights you were
definitely figuring out commercial
cultivation specific degrees just keep
learning how to grow learn how to
conduct yourself as a businessperson I
learned about HVAC learn about all the
electrical ins and outs learn about the
entire business from the ground up from
seed to sale learn every aspect of it
don't be afraid don't be shy
to be involved in every business meeting
that happens with a business that you're
involved in just because you're the
cultivator doesn't mean that you don't
need to go to the packaging meeting that
you shouldn't be at some sort of a CEO
meeting go to all that [ __ ] that you're
allowed to go to you should be welcome
to all of that stuff be involved in your
company see where the money's going
there may be decisions that you're not
even involved in that you should have
input in you should have some
involvement in involve yourself that's
the bottom line involve yourself in all
aspects of the business that's what I'm
gonna try to say where am I now some
[ __ ] way rambley again am i at a
disadvantage by only knowing how to grow
commercial you know that's what your
goal is I just honestly want to know
where I'm at
should I write it out with this company
or should I not venture it out with them
and have them as my competition don't
ever worry about competition in business
there are always going to be other
businesses that is how business works
without competition you will fail you'll
be the only one your ego will get too
big you'll run out of product something
will go wrong if you're the only one
have a little competition that's healthy
but I can't tell you where to stay I
can't tell you if you want to stay in
the facility in which you're working
with now or if you want to step out to
another facility and take the reins and
have that much more control also that
much more responsibility you're gonna
have to learn how to juggle that in your
own life where that fits in for you but
don't go in thinking that anybody is
your competition don't make an enemy
mindset don't make a battlefield mindset
we're the cannabis community you may be
different businesses you may be doing
things differently but we all have the
same goal so even if you do end up on
the other team we are all headed to the
top of Mount Everest mountain climbers
aren't competing against anybody but
themselves even though there are other
climbers out there they don't give a
[ __ ] what the other climbers are doing
they just want to get to the top if
another climber Falls they're gonna help
but they're not worried about oh that
climber is going up the mountain more
quickly than me they just say I'm gonna
get to the top when I get there so you
do that for you don't worry about the
other climbers you do your [ __ ] thing
and that goes for just about everything
in life don't compete with anybody but
yourself because you are your only gauge
of your own success and who knows what
the other people have gone they may look
like they're winning the race but they
may have [ __ ] their pants and if they
win the race with [ __ ] in their pants
they still lost so if you didn't [ __ ]
your pants and you win the race second
place you win so don't judge your
success by
anybody else's success just cuz they're
doing something differently doesn't mean
they're winning I'm gonna try to get
back on track here all right
um this person is wondering if they
should branch out and then they want to
know is my knowledge that I know now
enough to have my own little successful
shop in the future I don't know exactly
what you know from the size of the grow
you said you were running you've got
multiple rooms that are a good size
you've got quite a few plants in there
you were running with this math you're
running close to 2,000 plants I don't
know how many people you have helping
you I don't know if this is a multi
person facility or a one-man show if
you're doing that on yourself on your
own I would rely on you to be a quality
lead cultivator you could probably lead
a team you could certainly manage a
decent-size facility you can do whatever
you need to do if the things you were
telling me are accurate if you're
pulling 80 to 90 pounds at 18 lights
you're doing better than most
professional cultivators in a lot of
facilities that have been around for
quite a while I don't want to boost up
your ego because I have not seen the
quality of the product you got a past
lab testing do you understand do you
understand pesticide applications and
pesticide safety are you compliant there
are a lot of other things to think about
but that is all legal stuff that is
gonna happen to you if you choose to
work with your own company or stay with
the folks you're working with now so I'm
not sure what to tell you I can't make
business decisions for you my friend he
says my family has always frowned upon
cannabis and I want to make the
difference and prove them wrong that I
can be a successful young man while
cultivating cannabis again I admire your
passion that you want to be a successful
cannabis cultivators but let's not do
something just to prove somebody wrong
prove yourself right prove your passion
is what you should be doing do what you
want to do to make your life happy for
yourself not to prove anybody else wrong
that's a big waste of time because
they're not spending their energy
proving you wrong on [ __ ] they don't
care they've moved on so don't waste
your energy doing something to prove
anybody wrong do what you're doing to
show what you are passionate about prove
it to yourself that you can do what you
set your mind and heart to do so set
some goals and reach those goals he
wraps up the message by saying I respect
your craft immensely and I am very eager
to hear what you have to say I really
gave some weird advice because I can't
tell you
to do with your personal life and with
your business life and with your career
I don't know what the options are I only
see a couple of words on paper I can't
see the long-term effects that this will
have on your life I would make sort of a
flowchart and this may sound silly for
some people but this is what successful
people will do draw a chart and say if I
choose decision a what will my life be
like in 1 week 2 weeks 6 weeks 2 months
3 months 6 months what will my life be
like one year from today if I make
decision a what will my life be like in
two years three years five years ten
years think about what your life will be
like in a certain amount of time from
decision a then do the same damn thing
for decision B what is best for you and
what is best for your family and what is
what you really want you don't have to
decide right now hopefully hopefully
you've got a few minutes to sit back and
think about it do whatever you do get a
clear head get a really clear head and
think about it
then put into your head whatever you
like to put in your head and think about
it if you want to smoke a fatty smoke a
fatty if you want to drink a beer drink
a beer if you want to eat some mushrooms
eat those damn mushrooms and think this
decision through then clear your head
again and make a solid decision when you
got a clear head so you think about it
completely sober then you get [ __ ]
wacky out of your brain and think about
it real good sleep on it for a couple
nights come back to it nice and crispy
make a good decision just think about it
I can't tell you what to do with your
life or I wish I really wish that I
could it is exciting to team up with
investors and create your own business
you were attaching your entire life to
that business you will wake up and be
that business you will fall asleep being
that business you were in you were
responsible for a lot of things you were
in you're basically having another child
if you start this business with other
people if you are working with the
company that is established that has
owners that has people that handle that
part you have a lot of the stress taken
off your back also you have a lot of the
paycheck taken off your back you have a
lot of the pride and a lot of the say-so
taken off of your back so you have to
decide what makes you happiest or I
really don't want to make a personal or
a career decision for one of my friends
I want to give you words of
encouragement and make you think about
it and I want to hope that you make the
best
decision for yourself and for your
family I also want to thank you for
listening to the show because you have
been a longtime listener we've been
emailing back and forth for quite some
time you sent me this email a little bit
back so I hope I'm not too late with the
reply but I do appreciate the support
and I do know that you helped me out on
the patreon channel so I want to give
you an extra fist bump and an extra
thank you for that and just be confident
that you will make the correct decision
and one thing I just thought of is this
cannabis industry is ever-changing and
ever-evolving you are a passionate and
an educated cannabis grower and you were
always going to have some sort of a spot
in the commercial cultivation industry
if you choose to do so I am a very
qualified commercial grower and I don't
spend a long time in the same facility
because things rotate in this industry
so drastically so if you were a skilled
cultivator and you can present yourself
well if you can write a resume if you
can interview well you will never be
without a job in the commercial
cultivation industry if you decide that
you don't like the way a facility is ran
or that an owner is implementing a new
rule or maybe an investor is being cheap
and not buying the appropriate equipment
you can leave that facility and find
employment at another facility in a very
short amount of time
once the industry is established is
actually very easy when the industry is
new because everybody needs a qualified
grower so don't be too afraid to jump in
somewhere do what you need to do for a
little while learn learn that style
every facility does something different
just because that's how they do it
they've got a lead cultivator that set
it up with an idea or they've got an
owner that set it up with an idea and
you've got to adapt to that so you will
learn things in every facility so don't
be afraid to leave something for
something better but if you are stable
and secure and you need to take care of
a family always keep that in mind as
well but don't be afraid there are jobs
in the commercial cultivation industry
and when one ends there's always another
one available just be careful of your
reputation because the community does
get quite small quite quickly we all
know each other in this cannabis
industry Colorado is a giant state but I
know folks
from Fort Collins down to Trinidad and
that is each end of our state from north
to south I could get in the car and
drive to every city and get out of the
car and walk into a dispensary and
high-five a friend I'm not trying to
toot my horn and say I know a lot of
people that is everybody in Colorado we
all know if you're in the industry we
all basically know each other there are
industry nights there's budtender nights
there's cultivator night there's all
kinds of there are all kinds of events
that keep us all connected and just like
any other industry we are a bunch of
gossipy [ __ ] so keep your reputation
clean do a good job keep your passion up
keep your education sharp keep learning
keep evolving stay on top of the
equipment stay on top of the methods
stay on top of the pesticide rules stay
advanced stay ever-evolving and as long
as you don't tarnish your reputation and
cause a major problem and people in the
industry aren't blaming you for a major
failure or a bunch of fuck-ups somewhere
you should always have gainful
employment in the cannabis industry if
you choose to do so so there may not
have been a lot of direct advice for
this situation but I hope I gave a lot
of useful life advice for you my friend
I hope everything goes well for you down
there in Florida please reach out and
let me know that you heard this response
on the podcast I look forward to your
email my friend get back to me I cannot
wait if anybody else out there has a
cultivation question a cannabis culture
question or they just want to reach out
say hello my email address is grow from
your heart at hotmail.com
and you know I look forward to hearing
from you ladies and gentlemen I do have
another email here in front of me let's
get right to it
this one says hey Rasta Jeff first of
all thanks for the podcast content which
you were providing it is truly
appreciated and helpful hey you were
very welcome thank you for saying thanks
that is like a big recharge and that
means a lot to me so we're gonna keep
moving it says I listen to the show
every day while working and I have
learned so much perfect I'm hitting my
goal I want to teach people so I'm doing
it right it says English is not my
native language so excuse me in advance
if you have a hard time reading this ah
man big compliments because so far your
English is better than most Americans so
congratulations a good job there it goes
on to say I am on my first grow using
LED lighting and a
wrote in that is in my room in my
apartment the tent is 23 inches by 23
inches by 60 inches so we've got about 2
feet by 2 feet by 5 feet and it goes on
to say I am concerned about light leaks
I have listened to your podcast and I
know light leaks are something to be
careful about I also know that a tent
needs good ventilation both of these
things are correct when we have our
plants in their dark period we need to
keep the dark period under uninterrupted
and that means zero light if there is
any light on that plant you are going to
have problems that will give you
potential hermaphrodites which will mess
up your crop that is undesirable so we
want zero light absolutely zero light
when people say is this too much light
yes any light too much zero light I mean
zero I want you to go in there and close
your eyes and put your hand directly in
front of your face and not be able to
see your hand I want you to wait for
like ten minutes I want your eyes to
adjust I want you to look around and
look for little leaks are there any
little prick holes in the material where
lights come in and we cannot have any
light so this is absolutely correct zero
light leaks that is a absolute thing to
be concerned about this person also said
that they need correct ventilation which
is absolutely correct so they have been
listening to the show and I am proud of
them so far so let's keep moving it says
right now my ceilings are getting fresh
air from the bottom of my tent
which has the classic duct holes in and
out for aeration I simply put a fan in
front of the hole so we're just blowing
air straight into the little mesh right
there which works beautifully that mash
is gonna slow down the wind so it
doesn't disturb the seedlings too much
and we're gonna get some air exchange so
far we're off to a good start the
message goes on to say but when it's
time for flowering I'm going to have to
shut down this vent so the light won't
come in because my tent is in a room
which can be illuminated illuminated
sometimes because I store things in this
room that is a common problem we do have
our grow tents in rooms where we have to
frequently turn off the regular light in
in the room it also goes on to say what
about fresh air so he's got to close up
the vents but they are now concerned
about fresh air because they don't want
light coming in through that bottom flap
it says how's the fresh air going to
enter the tent this may sound like an
ultimate noob question but I really do
not know how to solve this then it goes
on with maybe is it possible in a small
tent like this that I don't use a fan by
the way I plan to grow two plants and I
want to keep them pretty small
I do not care at all about having a huge
yield with great taste or [ __ ] I
actually do not smoke but I want to grow
some high CBD plants with my very
occasional migraine it's okay so we're
growing CBD plants to help with
migraines and also just growing because
I love the plant and I love growing
outdoors or indoors excuse me so this
person is just growing basically for the
passion of growing this could just be an
act of civil disobedience if they are in
an illegal place which I would
definitely admire um there's more than
we're gonna wrap it up and we'll answer
the question I hope I made myself clear
actually listening to your podcast helps
also a lot in learning English hey that
is great
your English is beautiful you did a
wonderful job you did better than most
Americans do with their emails your
message was very easy to read I really
like the idea that I am helping you
learn English I like to think that I
speak fairly well for a lazy American so
thank you I hope you're learning well
from me he wraps it up with cheers from
France also I may be a bit paranoid so
please do not use my name because weed
consumption and cultivation are highly
prohibited here so I won't say your name
at all but big thank you for the email
and big thank you and fist bump for your
act of civil disobedience by illegally
cultivating your medicine there in the
great country of France so let's talk a
little bit about now how to get air into
that tent once we need to close that
vent so the light does not come in there
are a couple of simple solutions I would
definitely recommend some sort of an
extraction fan on the top of that tent
to remove the heat and humidity from the
tent we need a way to get that old air
out and the general way to do that is to
put an extraction fan at the top there
is probably a hole or a duct or a port
on the top of that tent so I would put a
blower up there sucking air out and it
would just pull the
hot air out of that little tent and it
would just dump it into that room into
the bedroom or into the storage room or
you've got the tent now as that fan or
that blower pulls air up to the top of
that tent and out of the top of the tent
it is going to need to replace the air
somewhere that air will need to come
from somewhere the tent will crush in a
little bit that is okay that negative
pressure is not a problem I've talked
about this in another episode the tent
will cave in just a little bit that is
okay once the pressure gets strong
enough the air will start flowing
through the gaps in the tent there are
gaps in the zipper there are gaps in
little spots in the tent that the air
will find its way through so it will
suck right through there also you don't
have to velcro those flaps down
completely tight you can velcro them
down to where the light doesn't get
through but they can still be open
enough to where the air can pass through
there so you don't need the fan blowing
in I would put a fan sucking out that
fan will remove your humidity and that
fan will also remove excess heat and
that fan at the same time will help draw
air in through that passive vent on the
bottom and keep recycling and refreshing
the air in the tent now keep in mind you
can only refresh it with the air that is
available in that storage room so I
don't know how often that air gets
exchanged I don't know how large that
room is it must be decent because you're
growing in there but keep in mind that
that room is what is supplying your grow
tent with all of its environmental and
atmospheric conditions your co2 your
oxygen your temperature your humidity
they are all coming from that room so
that is going to have a lot to do with
the climate inside of that tent so you
do need to worry about the light leaks
but I think if you just let the flap
down and velcro it at the corners but
don't do it all the way across the
bottom then put an extraction fan at the
top maybe a four inch fan a 4 inch
blower like a squirrel cage blower or a
four inch it's just an extraction fan to
go at the top set that in there you can
just set it right on top it probably
doesn't weigh too much it'll just set
right on top and rest there make it to
where it is sucking air out and that's
gonna dump the air into your storage
area but that will also make the air
flow through that tin it'll come right
through the passive vents in the bottom
it will also come through the gaps in
the zipper
through any gaps in the stitching
they'll go right up out of the top and
then I'll just recycle into the room no
I would try to keep the lights on
minimally in that room I understand that
you have to visit that room to get
things you say here that it's used as a
storage room you're gonna have to get in
there occasionally maybe try to plan
your lights off schedule around times
when you are sleeping or times that you
won't have to visit that room try to
think about what hours of the day do I
go into that room I wake up at this time
of day I go to bed at this time of day
so that's only it's probably 16 hours of
the day you're probably sleeping eight
hours don't we only got to think about
four hours that we don't want to go in
there maybe cut four hours at this end
of the day or four hours at this end of
the day and time it around that it's
where you don't have to interrupt that
room that's part of being a grower we
have to plan around that stuff so just
try to schedule your lights off time
around times that you won't have to turn
on that light also most of the time
those tints are well enough made where
we won't get much light leakage a good
way to see if you are getting a white
leak is to turn off the lights in your
storage room turn on the lights in the
grow tent seal the tent up like normal
and just hang out for a few minutes in
that dark room and see if any little
pricks of light come shining out if you
can see little dots of light you may
need to put a piece of duct tape or
something over that just the stop light
from going the other way also keep in
mind the light in your storage area is
nowhere near as bright as the light
inside of your grow space so if it's
making an out it still may not be making
it in because that light is nowhere near
as intense so it sounds like the main
solution is going to be putting a small
blower at the top of the tent that way
we can suck air out and at the same time
pull air in and also try to adjust our
lighting our daily schedule around our
lighting schedule of our grow tent so we
don't cause any problems I understand
sometimes that's a struggle but the tent
should be well-made enough to where we
don't get light leaks and if not then we
can use some duct tape or something
similar to plug up any light leaks that
way we don't get hermaphrodites that way
we don't ruin the garden that way
we can have a successful grow ladies and
gentlemen I think you can hear my throat
burning out so it's time to start
wrapping up the show I want to thank our
friend for sending us an email all the
way from France
big thank you I do appreciate that I
hope your grow goes well keep me updated
I hope I answered your question
thoroughly if you've got any more
questions please send me an email again
the email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com I love answering
the emails ladies and gentlemen if you
feel like this episode was educational
informative or entertaining and you
would like to make a financial
contribution to the show you can do so
by visiting www.azcleanelections.gov and
again you know I love the listener
interaction ladies and gentlemen my
voice is done for this episode that is
all I've got for you I'll be back in
just a couple of days with fresh new
content I'm gonna give you a huge shout
out to my buddy Matthew Dixon and until
next time take a phat dab and give your
mom a hug for me bread in the oven here
comes our boy Jamaican bread in the oven
bake you come down
[Music]
yep