yeah what's up guys it's time for
another episode of The Grow from your
heart podcast that's right I made the
switch it is now the official grow fromy
heart podcast your source for Cannabis
News education and conversation welcome
to episode number 47 I'm your host rosta
Jeff and I'm coming to you again with
another solo episode today is Saturday
it's the Saturday after the New Year
it's the first Saturday of the New Year
I hope everybody had a great safe joyous
New Year I have a few people to thank
and a few things to talk about but
before we get that far let's pay a
couple of bills this podcast is brought
to you by our good friends at Natures
green remedies.com visit Natures green
remedies.com for gag green genetics
llata Labs Sin City rare dankness Mile
High can Aventure the Cali Connection iy
genetics and many more trusted Brands
Nature's green remedies is running a
coupon actually running a special for
our loyal podcast listeners type in
coupon code iy
2015 and you'll get 15% off any order
and you always get free priority
shipping at Nature's green remedies.com
that's iy 2015 I have to write that down
because I actually have to tell them the
coupon code that I use that might be
helpful
I 2011 5 I I e2015 all one word so
that's your coupon code for Nature's
green remedies.com you'll get 15% off
any order and free priority shipping
this uh coupon code let's see we'll make
it good for the entire month of January
this expires January 31st so get in
there and get some seeds while you can
big thanks and much respect to Nature's
green remedies what's up Yankee I hope
you're doing good
brother this podcast is also brought to
you by our good friends at hyro indoor
growing supplies hyro indoor growing
supplies has two locations to serve
Colorado check out the Denver store at
6271 Beach Street or visit my favorite
location the PUO store on 618 East 4th
Street in beautiful Pablo Colorado check
out hyro for competitive pricing and a
great selection of indoor grow supplies
hyro is always running a special for the
podcast listeners when you check out
tell them you listen to the IG gr
culture podcast well that's going to get
confusing cuz now you have to say you
listen to The Grow from your heart
podcast but let those guys know you
listen to the podcast and they will give
you commercial pricing on your entire
order so much respect to hyro indoor
growing supplies the Denver and PLO
location that's a sweet hookup for the
podcast uh Jesse and I have been talking
a little Jesse's been kind of a busy
dude but we are working on putting
together some prizes for episode 50
that's uh we're going to hang out in a
day or two and that's going to be our
priority of the conversation excuse my
sniffles uh we'll talk a little bit
about my sniffles here in a little bit I
Saw The String Cheese Incident for three
nights in Denver and it may have gotten
a little bit sniffly during that minus
16 night
uh this podcast is also brought to you
by our good friends at tree Thugger dcom
this episode is brought to you I just
read that part huh tree Thugger dcom
live music lifestyle magazine check out
tree Thugger dcom for concert and
Festival news and reviews look out at
the cookout with tree Thugger
docomo today uh big shout out much love
to both or all three of the sponsors I'm
high and stumbly I got to get my rhythm
in this episode all right so I want to
give a big shout out to the Mystic Roots
band uh the song you heard at the
opening of the show was called the doggy
dub from our good friends the Mystic
roots shout out to cat and coot I hope
you guys had a great New Year I hope
everybody had a great New Year I was
talking about going to see The String
Cheese Incident so uh we'll talk about
that a little bit I got to go see if you
don't know about the string cheese
they're a jam band from Colorado uh
they're from the boulder Estus Park area
they're uh from all over the place up
there so you can't pick one's place to
say but that's where they're from is
that kind of area uh they started off as
kind of a blueg grassy jam band now
they're kind of a more of a psychedelic
dub Steppy jam band uh they've got two
drummers or they've got a drummer and a
guy that plays percussion they've got a
keyboard player that tears it up they've
got an electric guitar player who plays
fiddle and electric guitar and mandolin
like a champ uh Bill nury plays acoustic
guitar and then their bass player is uh
he's solid dude he doesn't like stand
out he's not super flashy but he never
missed a note in three nights so The
String Cheese Incident they play uh the
only way I can describe it dude is
carnival music it's calypso music it's
Mambo music it's Samba it's rock it's
Funk it's ree but it's like one giant
Carnival the whole party the whole
concert was one giant Carnival it was a
great time so we saw a String Cheese
Incident they did three nights at the
First Bank Center in Broomfield uh so we
drove up to uh it was actually in
Westminster is where our hotel was so we
drove up to the hotel we stayed in the
hotel uh we went and saw the first show
and after the first set they do three
nights and the first night they played
for about an hour and 15 took a break
and then came out for about another hour
and a half and tore that night up after
the first set of the first night I said
where are they going to go from here cuz
they came out and they just tore it up
right off the bat they didn't start like
let's start slow and build it up no they
started like let's come out on fire and
just [ __ ] this all up and they did it it
was amazing so uh big thanks to the
String Cheese Incident that was awesome
so day two or we finished the show night
one went back to the hotel we beat
pretty much slept day two uh we kind of
just hung out in the hotel and we're
lazy it was cold it was uh minus 16°
that day and uh there was no real reason
to leave the hotel other than to get
food we had dabs and drinks and
everything we needed so we just on the
hotel until time for the show the second
night was amazing uh we pretty much we
ditched the shows at the end and head
right back to the hotel we're not real
party animals anymore uh I don't need to
eat a bunch of drugs and get spun out I
wanted to go home and get prepared for
the next day cuz New Year's was a big
party um they started a little bit early
and they played until about 1:45 if I
remember correctly they started at 8:45
and went till 145 with a couple of
breaks uh String Cheese Incident on New
Year's
uh I've never seen so much confetti so
many balloons I can't even begin to
describe what it was like we were me and
my girlfriend Angela were in the front
three rows uh right in front of Bill
nersey and kind of off to the side from
Kyle so there's a huge party right there
and after the first or second night
everybody knew who we were so everyone
just treated us like friends and family
so big shout out to all the new friends
and family that I made from The String
Cheese Incident but man they had these
giant uh they look like cocoons hanging
from the ceiling when we walked in that
night and you couldn't identify what
they were but as the midnight count down
began these cocoons opened up and there
were they became giant flowers that were
lit up and it was pretty amazing I
posted video on my Facebook uh if you
guys want to check that out you'll have
to find my personal Facebook I shouldn't
have said that but there are a lot of
cool videos of it check it out it was
amazing I was covered in confetti there
were so many balloons so a big thanks to
Angela for letting me go uh inviting me
to be your New Year's buddy and also for
thanks for that sweet New Year's kiss
babe we needed that it meant a lot to me
um let's see big thanks to all the
cheese kids and fans that I made I made
a list here I'm going to try to get some
of these people in here I'm going to
skip a bunch though big thanks to Pam
and Jessica um I met Pam for the first
time Angela speaks very highly of you
and now I see why uh Jessica I just met
that night had never heard of her uh
she's a big ball of smiley energy it was
great to meet you and hang out with you
uh big thanks to Mama Cass uh it was
great meeting you nice lady that calls
herself Mama Cass she had a lot of great
energy had a lot of good things to say
uh big thanks to the guy with the
amazing Candy I cannot remember your
name uh this dude next to me offers
offered me a lemon excuse me he offered
me a lemon candy and uh I said is it
just candy and he said yeah man my thing
is to just bring weird candies to the
show and they're delicious and so I took
this lemon candy from him and it was
amazing and later on in the show he
offered me something and when he pulled
it out of his pocket the guy next to him
patted me on the shoulder and said eat
one of those man and when I tried it it
was amazing it was some uh all the uh
packaging was in another language it's
like Chinese or Korean or something I'm
sorry if that's offensive I don't know
what [ __ ] language it is it looks
Chinese to me
and um it was mango flavored and
whatever I ate was amazing dude and it
did not have drugs in it so I was pretty
relieved about an hour later when I
wasn't flipping my face off so a big
shout to the candy guy also big shout
out to Dan kin Roland and Riley it was a
pleasure meeting all of my new friends
uh you guys are great great little
family you guys have there also shout
out to the girl that we named titty girl
um I never met her we never met her but
her boobs and her Vibes were amazing and
fun to watch uh she was so exposed that
my girlfriend told me to look because it
was ridiculous she said look to your
left that girl's boobs are out of her
shirt and I looked and it was it wasn't
even like I was looking to be a perve it
I was more looking like is she really
having her tits out of her shirt that
much at the show it was kind of
entertaining kind of ridiculous so big
shout out to titty girl she was a good
dancer she had a lot of good energy she
brought a little crew of chicks with her
that uh twirled around and brought a
nice little Vibe so that was neat dude
some of the girls at the show uh they
wear this eye makeup with beads in it
dude and I don't understand how you
ladies do that stuff uh you got like I'm
serious like right in the corner of your
eye where you wake up with eye crusties
on the outside not near your nose but
the other side they've got little beads
and [ __ ] there um I don't understand how
ladies tolerate that [ __ ] all night on
your face but I do however think it's
cute and I totally appreciate the effort
uh but it does make me make me be extra
glad to be the guy with dreadlocks I
wake up uh sometimes I take a shower
occasionally I mostly wake up put on
some clothes throw on a t-shirt shake my
head and put on a hat and I'm ready to
rock you can't tell if I just woke up or
if I've been working all day so it makes
me extra grateful to be a guy that could
be lazy but also thank you ladies for
looking great at the cheese show Angela
thank you for looking wonderful uh
thanks again for letting me have a good
time uh I did mention I got a little
cold I guess I got some sniffles bro I
just sniffled right into the mic to do
that that was rude but uh it was -6 Dees
one night and you got to go from the car
into the concert venue in Theus 16 and
then in the concert I just I took off
all my jackets and I had my t-shirt and
my pants on and my shoes and my hat and
I was sweating my ass off
so you got to try to negotiate the cold
and then the super hot heat and then
back to the car again and then let the
car warm up and get to the hotel so uh I
think all the climate changes uh I may
have got a little cold here and also I
smoked like 45 joints over three nights
at these concerts I rolled a bunch of
joints I smok like 45 joints with
strangers and I'm wondering if maybe I
got a little bit of String Cheese
Incident W flu but whatever I'll live
got some emergency and some yba mate I'm
going to be just fine uh it was fun
meeting a lot of Instagram followers I
met a lot of people they walked up to me
and they said hey are you iy genetics or
are you rosted Jeff and that's always
kind of nice when you're just out
randomly somewhere that uh there's a
band playing and you're not like it
wasn't a weed event I shouldn't have
been getting any attention but people
knew who I was It was kind of neat so
big shout out to all those folks that
said hi I really appreciate that I'm
digging through notes here oh huge shout
out to Aaron Brooks on the very last
night we were walking out of the venue
uh and if my girlfriend didn't have to
pee we would not have bumped into each
other so I'm so glad she had to pee and
I bumped into Aaron Brooks and got a big
old hug Aaron Brooks is an artist if
you're not following him you should be
uh let's see what else do I need to talk
about I wrote down a lot of stuff I feel
like I'm rambling we're already 11
minutes in guys this is going to be
another one of those short quick
episodes with just me um I put a lot of
work into this podcast but this week I
was obviously busy uh seeing the String
Cheese Incident I've been out of town I
was gone for four days it took me a
whole day to get my Gardens back to
where I felt they should be they missed
me and then I needed a day to get myself
back together I tried record yesterday
but it was chaotic so here I am I'm
recording this quick Short episode cuz I
love you guys and I don't want to leave
you hanging for a whole week but I do
promise that uh the next episodes are
going to be back to what you expect 48
49 and 50 are going to be Stellar
episodes I'm hoping to get Spencer on
pretty soon but I never never teased you
about that well let's see sorry I'm
choking I'm G to take a quick drink here
take a dab while I take a drink
oh shout out to water and root beer
those things keep me alive so uh remind
you guys of the name change that's my
next note I'm sure you noticed at the
beginning of the show that I said
welcome to the igro culture podcast I'm
doing my best to roll out the new
name um I'm doing it slowly so I don't
lose people so if it looks confusing for
a little bit I'm sure you guys are aware
what's going on if you're listening but
we are in the process of changing the
name from I gr culture to grow from your
heart bear with me um I still could use
more logos uh somebody sent me one logo
but I I asked for a couple of
adjustments it just it didn't fit the
way I needed it to fit to make uh
squares out of it I need a square logo
so if you can send me a 1400
x400 uh pixel image with the grow from
your heart podcast I would love that um
I also need a song if you guys want to
if anybody out there is an artist and
you want to make a grow from your heart
podcast theme song I will compensate you
in the future that' be really cool so
I'm starting to change the title in
social media places also I'm waiting on
a couple artists to submit some logos
that I've commissioned and once I've got
all the artwork I can fully roll out the
new title and start switching everything
over um I'm hoping by episode 50 that we
can actually just call this the grow
from your heart podcast and everything
will be switched right
over let's see also here's something
that I've been considering this is just
a personal thing for myself that I've
considering doing I may cancel the
Instagram for the podcast there is an
igro culture podcast inag stagram that I
haven't posted anything to in several
weeks honestly it kind of it's just a
distraction there's not a lot it's a
podcast and some of my guests don't want
me to take their picture Jesse doesn't
want his face on um Adam is cool with it
Mike is cool with it but some people do
not want to be seen and I feel like I'm
just going to overdo my Instagram
Presence by having the IR genetics and
the IG gr culture or the grow from your
heart podcast so I'm thinking about just
combining the two into one entity and
maybe I'll start posting a few things
from the grow from your heart podcast on
the I genetics Instagram so if you're
not already following iy genetics on
Instagram go there and follow that
because I'm really considering taking
down the Instagram for the podcast it's
just a distraction it's one more thing
to worry about um I'm also considering
and I'm not committing to this but it's
highly likely somebody had a talk with
me and it got me thinking but I'm
considering canceling my YouTube account
for the Agro culture grow from your
heart podcast you'd say why would you do
that people are listening they are but
not as many and I'm not I appreciate the
people that are listening but it takes
me a long time uh to get those episodes
up there I feel if I cancel that I feel
I can focus more on the show and if I
didn't have to create as many different
types of media I could make better
content uh just for the audio podcast
I'd rather spend the time creating
content instead of editing video and
setting up a camera and lighting uh and
editing the video again and then
rendering the video for YouTube it it
takes a few it's just a few more steps
but all of those steps matter I could
spend that much time preparing for this
show and making the show that much
better having that many more details
being that much more prepared getting
that much better of a guest on so the
Instagram and the YouTube may go away
and that's just personal things I'm
trying to free up more time to take what
I'm really passionate about to the next
level I don't want to drag my feet on
things that are not fulfilling me
honestly so May eliminate those and I do
appreciate the guys that watch me on
YouTube I've only gotten like 17 or 18
maybe 20 videos up on YouTube because
like I said it takes me an hour to make
each one and I feel like I could I'm
repeating myself I could just spend that
time doing stuff so I may take them down
I don't I don't want to abandon people
but if you are watching on YouTube you
should be able to find it on the igro
culture or the iy genetics website every
podcast is there and if you've got a
browser it works the same and there's
not you're not missing anything visually
really so those are mostly distractions
I feel like I'm going to stop
contributing to those just so that I can
improve the audio part of the show so
feel like I've been talking about that
for a long time I need to move on let's
see I appreciate all the emails I've
gotten holy crap you guys uh we're going
to continue to use the AGR culture
hotmail.com email address for now um by
episode 50 I will have created the new
email address and I'll start talking
about it and you can email me there but
from now on or for now keep using the
Agro culture at hotman mail.com email
address I did change the Twitter it's
still IG culture but if you look at it
the name is grow fromy heart podcast uh
it won't let me change my at name only
my display name
so that's something you can pay
attention to let's see I wrote a bunch
of notes and I have them in my computer
and I'm scrolling through the computer
and looking at a piece of paper trying
to read two things at once and um it's
honestly not working so uh episode 50 is
coming up you guys I've been talking
about that I'm planning a small
celebration episode but I would like
your input I asked for this on the last
episode but I want to know who your
favorite guests were what were some of
your favorite moments and what did you
learn and what would you like to hear
next so like I said send me some input
it's ulture hotmail.com you can tweet me
or you can find me on Facebook um it
looks like I need to change the Facebook
also you guys so it's still IG gr
culture but pretty soon it's going to be
the grow from your heart podcast on
Facebook all right I feel like I crap
sorry I feel like I got you guys caught
up on all of the uh stuff I had to
remind you of and talk about so now I
think it's time to uh read a couple of
news articles that I picked out for the
day uh this one says Colorado seeks
Federal okay for state colleges to grow
pot a lot of people from out of state
are going what but it'll make sense this
article is from The Denver Post it's
written by John inold it says Colorado
has made an unusual plea to Federal
authorities let our colleges grow pot in
a letter sent last month the state
attorney General's office asks federal
health and education officials for
permission on Colorado's colleges and
universities to obtain marijuana from
non-federal government resources for
research purposes uh the letter isn't
more specific on how the state's higher
education institutions might score weed
but it was sent pursuant to a law passed
in 2014 requiring State officials to ask
that Colorado colleges and universities
be allowed to cultivate marijuana and
its component
parts current research is riddled with
bias or insufficiencies and often
conflict with and often conflict with
one another reads the letter written by
Deputy Attorney General David Blake it
is critical that we be allowed to fill
the void of scientific research and this
may only be done with your assistance
and cooperation either request is lot
not a long shot while marijuana is with
qualifications legal in Colorado it
remains illegal under federal law and
getting permission to conduct research
on cannabis requires clearing a set of
high hurdles approval from multiple
federal agents and strict requirements
on how marijuana must be handled and
stored researchers that work without the
federal government's blessing risk
losing crucial Federal funding for their
institutions not to mention possible
imprisonment an inter an international
treaty that the United States signed in
signed in signed on to sorry I'm
stumbling I'm high uh signed on to
requires the federal government to
designate only one place in the country
that can legally grow marijuana for
research since 1968 that place has been
the University of Mississippi's National
care for Natural Products Research which
cultivates cannabis on a 12 acre plot
and sends it to approved researchers
guys that uh 12 acre plot is rumored to
be where the G13 came from many years
ago out of University of Mississippi so
if you know anything about that send me
some info I'd like to know about it all
right the article goes on to say
coincidentally the
national the National Institute on drug
abuse recently put the government's Pot
Farm contract up for rebid applicants
need to have 12 Acres of secured and
video monitored outdoor space and 1,000
ft of indoor space to grow marijuana to
be able to make marijuana extractions
test for potency and prepare preferably
by hand rolling a small batch of
marijuana cigarettes according to the
official solicitation the contract's
winner is expected to be announced uh in
the next couple of months a spokeswoman
for the National Institute of drug abuse
would not say how many institutions
applied for the contract or where they
are were sorry
spokesman for the University of Colorado
and Colorado State University said their
schools did not apply The Drug
Enforcement Administration in 2014
massively increased the amount of pot
the government's official supplier can
grow from 21 kilos to 650 kilos the
increase was the result of a boom in
marijuana research interest and the
University of Mississippi has pledged to
grow new strains of marijuana to give
research more options for their studies
as a long time ago there was a video out
a movie I cannot recall the name of the
movie it may it was something like the
union it may have been in the Union uh
it may have been um how the how weed won
the West maybe I can't remember the name
of which movie it was but they actually
showed us inside of this facility in
Mississippi where they grow this
cannabis and it was terrible um they
weren't growing high-grade cannabis I
[ __ ] about the weed at the dispensaries
and I would rather smoke the weed at the
dispensaries than the [ __ ] that I
saw being grown at University of
Mississippi that's stuff was terrible so
it's not really cool that they're doing
the research with that I hope they get I
hope since then they've gotten a real
grower and they've gotten some genetics
and they've learned a few things is what
I saw was [ __ ] we'll continue with the
article it says still the Colorado
attorney general's letter says the
federal government falls short of being
able to supply researchers with the
kinds of products available in
Colorado's commercial commercial
marijuana Market State Health officials
have just approved up to $8.4 million in
Grants for marijuana studies some of
which will examine Colorado specific
products but the Attorney General's
office says more needs to be done we
need to support or we need the support
of our federal Partners to overcome the
inertia that continues to complicate
state state efforts in this area the
letter States so it seems like they
caught on uh they know that we've got
the Dank here in Colorado they need they
know that they need toest excuse me they
know they need to examine Colorado
specific products so maybe they are
catching on maybe they know that that
stuff that they're growing out there at
that University as a bunch of mids uh
speaking of mids shout out to my buddy
Vigor lover I hope you're doing well bro
so what this says this article I want to
talk about this a minute we are actually
asking the federal government to let the
state of the state colleges or higher
educational centers in Colorado to grow
cannabis they want to grow pot uh that
means there will be courses or a class
that is accredited to a College where
somebody is growing weed it's probably
going to be a chemistry class or a
biology class it probably won't be a
horiculture class because they're not
worried about growing it they're more
worried about the effects and Science
and they know how to grow it that's
Horticulture that's already done these
guys are going to probably have some
students doing making extracts testing
the
extracts uh I'm not even sure what
they're going to do but I'm impressed
and I'm excited I hope this works
because I would love to see cannabis
grown in a university and tested here in
Colorado where we're not scared and
trying to lie about all of the results
and to see possibly some of my friends
that are college students able to study
cannabis in this way in a college and
actually get college credit and build a
future for themselves I really like this
I really love that cannabis has kind of
opened doors and gone from us hiding to
letting us kind of make a living for
ourselves this demographic this age
group of 25 to 40-year-old males and
there are females in there too but I'm
honestly the majority is males we were
struggling we were broke and now the 25
to 40y Old demographic has something to
do with ourselves we can grow great
cannabis and get in the industry it's
great all right so here's another news
article guys I feel like I'm going
really fast sorry I'm talking so fast
I've had some yerba mate and I'm
drinking a root beer maybe I just need
to slow down a little bit we're 25
minutes in it's going to be a short
episode but I promised you that anyway
so it's okay I found this article on the
Cannabis as well and I found it
entertaining it says it's actually a
long article I only want to read uh one
piece of it to you guys it says cannabis
Q&amp;A naming strains and federal
rescheduling riddle rescheduling riddle
the part I want to read about is naming
strains uh this is from it's by Susan
squib on the Cannabis staff and the
header is Welcome to our cannabis column
Welcome to our ask the Cannabis column
clearly you have questions about
marijuana be it a legal concern a health
curiosity a Colorado Centric inquiry or
something more far-reaching check out
our expensive 100 question Colorado
marijuana frequently asked questions
first and if you're still curious email
your questions to the Cannabis at and
then there's askthe Canabis gmail.com so
if you want to participate in that feel
free I get a lot of my news stuff from
these guys so participate with them if
you want uh the first question got my
attention it says Hey cannabis why would
someone name a strain of weed after a
bioweapon that killed thousands of
people uh and they signed the letter put
off pot
so this guy is asking why would somebody
name a strain a weed after a bioweapon
that killed thousands of people and the
Cannabis replies you must be talking
about agent orange huh I hear your
concern strain names can mean one thing
to a potential customer and something
else to a plant breeder naming the
strain while agent orange is not a
peaceful happy or euphoric name if you
view it in historical context there is
the other view that the name suggests an
orange scent and the potency is the bomb
the article says I chatted with Adam
Dunn host of the Adam Dunn show shout
out to the Adam dun show what's up Mitch
what's up Adam what's up everybody on
the show crunchy bike hope you guys are
all doing well uh but Adam is the
founder of the Amsterdam based Seed
Company th seeds and he says having
owned a seed company myself for 21 years
I can attest that many cannabis seed
companies are run by people who have a
bit more of a juvenile attitude
especially when it comes to name to the
names game dun says names like agent
orange AK-47
crack and wheelchair weed though quite
distasteful conjure up images of
something really strong and devastating
I doubt the people who named agent
orange really considered this was a
bioweapon that killed thousands of
people and destroyed lives of countless
more often strain names are creative uh
often strains are creative combinations
of the names that make up the genetic
lineage or other plant attributes Adam
dun says having been there at the naming
of AK-47 and my own MK Ultra I am guilty
of joining the hype dun says
I was dead wrong back in 1993 when I
said AK-47 was a terrible name it was
named for flowering on 47 days and AK-47
went on to become one of the most famous
strains in history uh with the start of
the legal adult use Market this year the
reactions of consumers to strain names
is a recent development in marijuana
marketing dun points out dun points out
that the Cannabis industry is very young
and will go through many
changes so uh I am guilty of this this
is why it got me attention I've got a
stram called Bounty Killer and I had a
friend named Nancy tell me that she
didn't really like the name and she was
reluctant to grow it because it was
called Bounty Killer um I called it
Bounty Killer honestly it's named after
one of my favorite reae artists is named
Bounty Killer uh he I like the way he
does things and I wanted to kind of
honor him I've got the ceton which is
also named after a reggae artist and
I've got the kangi Kush which is also
named after a reggae artist and the
Night Nurse is named after a ree song so
the reason I called Bounty Killer Bounty
Killer after the ree artist is cuz it
grows killer weed it is killer it'll
kick your ass and it grows huge colas
and huge harvests so that's the Bounty
there and it's the Bounty Killer so if
you don't know about reg it sounds like
you're reaping the Bounty you're killing
that huge Harvest or if you know ree you
know that it's the Bounty Killer and
it's kind of aggressive and kind of loud
and it's got a groovy beat to it and
that's why I call it the Bounty Killer
uh I want to talk about why I Nam Ste
things the way I name them and why uh
strains I've created have the names they
have uh I'm A Grateful Dead fan I'm a
dead head uh I'm kind of a into like the
whole spiritual side of life I'm
definitely a Rastafarian that's why my
company is called iy genetics uh I try
to honor the parents uh the parent
plants that I'm using when I create a
new strain but sometimes that just gets
redundant and you can't be creative so I
like to draw from rosta culture Grateful
Dead culture and like positive loving
hippie culture that's why I've got a
string called Heart of Gold uh it's the
Golden Goat cross to the Grateful Dog it
almost got called horn dog but that
didn't sound as good for the vibe I'm
trying to promote Heart of Gold when you
smoke that weed and you meditate your
heart is calm your heart is filled with
love what's better than a heart of gold
right you got a big heart of gold that's
just pumping love and positive energy
and it's got Golden Goat in it so it's
Heart of Gold uh lemon Jeffrey is Golden
Goat crossed to The Lemon Skunk uh so
there's lemon obviously the lemon right
and my name is Jeff and I wanted
something like uh you got aran's Hayes
and there's Neville's Hayes why not have
a lemon Jeffrey that's named after me
the guy that made it that was kind of my
little stingy move on the Cannabis World
there um these guys are talking about
agent orange I know who made agent
orange that was subcool it's orange
velvet it's an orange velvet to Jack the
Ripper cross and I think agent orange
was a perfect name and then I just said
another name Jack the Ripper uh it's
Jack herrer cross to other stuff
basically and subcool didn't want to use
the name Jack herrer so it's Jack the
Ripper I just that's how these names
come up uh I've got a strain that uh I
wanted to call it the Golden Road it's a
Golden Goat cross and of course that's a
Grateful Dead song so my names come from
trying to honor the parent
strains and uh so I did get creative I
I'm going to say this name here on the
show that it's not out yet but I've this
is my cross uh Gorilla Glue number four
crossed to the Grateful Dog is called
grip tape and that's for my skateboard
friends you know what grip tape is on
your skateboard it's that [ __ ] that
makes your feet stick to the board a
little bit uh I call it grip tape
because it is sticky uh it would be
called fly paper but fly paper is
already taken and grip tape kind of
honors my skateboard friends so that's
where the names come from We're Not Just
spouting out random [ __ ] some guys
are one of my best sellers lately has
actually been a strain that's called
blue healer that was named by our good
buddy Spence from the garden of Weeden
it's actually blue dream cross to the
Grateful Dog so grateful dog gives you a
dog name the blue blue healer uh it's
named after a dog to keep the Grateful
Dog reference and it's also got the word
healer in there because it's going to
make you feel better so it's just me
trying to be silly and trying to be
creative and honor the parents and you
have to name it something you know you
can't just call it X5 maybe you can but
that would be boring right that's not
good
marketing all right so that's enough of
that article I just wanted to talk about
how I name strange and why I named them
what I named them if you gave me like
anything that I crossed to ghost OG it's
going to be called ghost whatever I
crossed it to you know what I mean Ghost
Dog Ghost goat the golden ghost you know
[ __ ] like that it just if I cross Golden
Goat to stuff it probably got the word
gold put in there that's just how I do
it all right I've only been going for 32
minutes you guys but uh I don't have a
lot else to say I honestly didn't have
time to prepare for this episode I don't
I didn't want to stress out over this
one I wanted to hang out with you guys
take a couple dabs let's do do that
let's do that let's get a dab together
all right you guys take a second I'm
going to ramble here while you guys get
a dab together to dab with me I am proud
because I'm going to dab shatter that I
made myself ah yeah I did that I made
hash and then Spence V purged it for me
uh I got it in there and got it going
but I had to leave so he finished it for
me the stuff got purged for 35 hours
it's pretty damn dank I hope you got a
dab ready by now let's take a dab
together and then we'll start wrapping
up the
show I'm going to hit the uh I've got
the Hitman eer side car
with a highly educated Infinity nail on
it attached to the Highly Educated
Infinity nail is the emot tech uh gnail
that's always on I've got mine set to
850 right now which people say is kind
of high but honestly if I put it any
lower I don't get a big chunky dab when
I carb cap it so here we go shout out to
emotech shout out to Hitman shout out to
Highly Educated titanium and shout out
to Garden of Weeden and Angela too since
I'm doing shout outs here we go let's do
a
[Music]
dab
yeah I like those big old chunky dabs
when you're not sure if you're going to
cry or cough or
die all
right so this will be fun I'm going to
try to do the show closing without
coughing after pretty good size dab I
want to thank you guys for listening I
promise you the next episode is going to
be better I hope Spence will be here but
I can't promise you uh he'll be here
before episode 50 if not on episode 50
make sure you listen to episode 50 there
are going to be prizes uh here we go now
that the show is over please go to
iTunes Stitcher uh go to the iTunes or
Stitcher main page I told you I was high
search for igro culture sgrow fromyou
heart right now I've got both titles in
there it's igro culture sgrow fromyou
heart uh hopefully by the time episode
50 comes out everyone will be caught on
to grow from your heart podcast so find
the review section give me a festar
rating type in a comment let me know
what you think of the podcast and I will
read your comments on the
show excuse me don't forget that every
episode is available on iy gentics
colorado.com make sure you follow us on
Twitter follow follow us on Facebook and
follow iry genetics on Instagram it's
iry gentics on Instagram I may cancel
that Facebook or that Instagram and
YouTube so for the show so don't be sad
if they disappear it's nothing nothing
personal I just want to focus on more
important stuff so if you guys are
interested in sponsoring the podcast or
if you have a product that you like us
to review send me an email to um AGR
culture hotmail.com or I wrote the other
one down I made it and it
is grow fromy heart hotmail.com so email
me at ulture hotmail.com or grow from
yourheart hotmail.com both of those will
work uh I need a new logo you guys the
grow from your heart logo would really
nice so that I can get everything in
place and make the show new title
official I'm really high I'm like
talking in a circle uh we do need need a
theme song if you guys want to help uh
sounds like I should just end this show
and sign off for now so I look forward
to seeing you in seven days big shout
out to my ninja Spence thanks again for
listening you guys big shout out to
Angela for letting me go to The String
Cheese Incident until next time take a
fat dab give your mom a hug for
me I do not the coke only smoke I do not
the coke I only
smoke no Coke I only smoke I do not s
the coke I only smoke without a doubt I
am the boss and in my class I am the
teacher if music is the fruit of life
then I will be a Reaper if MC business
was a school then I would be at Master
if a car I'd be The Driver if a bike I'd
be the rider if MC business was a church
Pau would be the Vicor then instead of
calling me MCU or would call me preacher
but fun and joke aside I want get
serious in this matter and dedicate this
St to each and every cocaine dealer I do
not the coke I only smoke I do not SI
the coke I only
smoke Coke only smoke I do the coke only
smoke