all right here we go ladies and
gentlemen welcome to episode 470 if the
growth from your heart podcast this
episode of the show is brought to you by
our friends at seeds here now if you
need new regular feminized or auto
flower seeds in your garden I highly
recommend seeds here now and you can
find them at www.cpa.psu.edu or diesel
this concentrate definitely has a funky
dirty deliciously disgusting funky fuel
aroma and flavor to it my favorite part
is that it makes me stupid when i smoke
this concentrate it is full [ __ ] I
lose my keys when they're in my hand I
get lost when I'm not going anywhere
this concentrate makes me dumb and I
fully appreciate it so big shout out to
our friends at Green Dot labs for the
delicious and amazing halo live batter
ladies and gentlemen in this episode I'm
going to talk about a recent experience
I had at the bank I'm also going to read
a message that came from YouTube before
we get to that part of the show let's do
a few shout outs to some of our friends
from patreon let's start off with the
big giant Grohl from your heart podcast
shout out and a thank you to my friend
Tommy about a big giant thank you
shoutout to JM of course a giant troll
from your heart podcast thank you a
shout out and a hug to my buddy stabby
how about a big giant girl from your
heart podcast thank you to baked of
course I want to send a giant shout out
to my buddy dick goals always I want to
send a giant grow from your heart
podcast shout out and thank you to our
buddy Victor I want to send a special
thank you to our buddy Glen G and last
but certainly not least I want to send a
giant grow from your heart podcast shout
out
fist bump and a thank you to our buddy
Todd K big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who has supported the show on
the patreon campaign if you would like
to support the show you can do so by
visiting
www.hp.com
/ grow from your heart all of the
information you need will be right there
on the screen once again big thanks big
shout out big hug and big fist bump to
everybody who was supported the show on
the patreon campaign all right now let's
work our way into the fun part of the
show I hinted that I wanted to talk
about something it recently happened at
the bank so let's get right into that I
recently decided that it would be a wise
move to have another business bank
account we don't need to get into any of
those details here it was necessary so I
went to the bank and I explained to them
my needs and what I wanted to do and
they were happy to help me out a very
nice lady took me to her office I filled
out some paperwork she asked me a few
questions then she started typing some
details into the computer and that was
when she informed me that I would not be
allowed to open a business checking or
savings account with her bank I feel
like I immediately knew why but I chose
to play dumb I said well why is that
ma'am and she said because you are
currently a key holder and we cannot
offer a business banking account to
anybody who is a key holder and I said
what do you mean key holder I don't work
anywhere else I have my own business and
I just played dumb because I wanted to
see where this would go and she informed
me that her computer indicated to her
that I have a Colorado marijuana
Enforcement Division key position badge
now let me briefly explain this badge
anybody who works in a legal cannabis
facility in the state of Colorado is
required to have a Colorado marijuana
Enforcement Division badge and that
requires an intensive background check
it requires thorough fingerprinting and
it requires a lot of questionnaires and
a little bit of money anybody who wants
to work in the industry is required to
have this badge there are multiple
badges available at different levels
those different levels of badges give
you different opportunities and
availability for different positions in
the facilities most folks will have what
is called a support badge that is for
somebody who would be a trimmer or an
assistant grower if you are going to
have keys or make decisions you get what
is called a key back
if you are an owner you've got a red
badge and it means you own the place
there are transportation badges and
there are changes happening to the
badging system as we speak so by the
time this episode comes out this could
be inaccurate information but at this
time there are three badges that I'm
aware of possibly a fourth
transportation badge that I don't pay
attention to but the support the key and
the owner badge are the main badges I
think about I hold a support badge I'm
not the owner and I'm not a trimmer I am
somebody who has hands-on with the
plants and I make decisions about what
happens in the facility therefore the
bank has decided that they cannot offer
me any type of loan or accounts with
their establishment their reasoning for
this is since my source of income my
legal employment is federally illegal
they cannot risk taking my money and
banking with me because they are insured
by the FDIC which is federal so my
income is federally illegal they are a
federal institution they don't want to
mix my dirty federally illegal money
into their federally regulated
institution so they simply smiled at me
and said thank you for coming but we
simply cannot and will not help you so I
took the opportunity to ask them if they
had any recommendations are there any
other banks in the area that may be able
to service me and they said that this
new computer system Flags everybody with
a marijuana Enforcement Division badge
in their computer system when they
attempt to establish a new account she
said is something that is linked to
their computer they are directly linked
to the marijuana Enforcement Division I
don't think she was purposefully looking
to find my badge but it popped up and it
did not take her two minutes of typing
into that computer to have all of my
information and then when I played dumb
about having the badge she recited my
badge number and told me the expiration
date of my badge then she was kind
enough to tell me that when that badge
expires she would be more than happy to
open an account for me to come back in
December and we can do business she did
also indicate that if I lower my level
of my badge that then they could write a
letter to the bank and they would
consider giving me the services that I
require but I
don't want to reduce the level of badge
I have got right now because I need that
for my work in the legal cannabis
industry in a legal cannabis cultivation
facility to remain compliant you must
have a key badge holder on scene at all
times so if I am at a facility where I'm
registered as an employee I am on the
employee roster list I have got my key
badge
nobody has to babysit me they can say go
do your work Jeff go look at the grow go
inspect the grow go make the adjustments
you need to make have a good time they
can give me free rein of the grow and
nobody has to babysit me
if I only had a support badge there
would have to be somebody within visual
distance of me at all times I would not
be allowed to roam around that grow or
those grows or those cultivation areas
at my own free will I would need a
babysitter I would need some sort of an
escort I couldn't be in the cultivation
facilities by myself so at this time I
need that key badge so that I can
function and do my job properly so at
this time I am exploring more options
because I am sure that there are other
people like myself who are in the
medical cannabis industry who also may
own a small business who also may need
to get a bank loan for a vehicle who
also may need to get a bank loan for a
new home who also may just need banking
services because we need banks in
general I have heard of many other
people having similar experiences with
banking I have heard of friends having a
cow shut down I have seen friends have
their business accounts closed I have
seen and heard of people being denied
requests for loans and being denied the
ability to open a new checking or
savings account but I have never been
discriminated against like this since we
have fully legalized cannabis there were
times when cannabis was becoming freshly
legalized and people were still kind of
weird about it there were a few
restaurants that would treat us weird
when we showed up stinking like dank and
paid in a bunch of cash but since then I
haven't felt that kind of rejection or
discrimination from a business and it
was really uncomfortable so I am looking
into solutions I did ask this lady if
there were any other options
she said that credit unions may be able
to help out with my situation now in
many banking circumstances people with a
key badge or people with a support badge
she'd be able to attain a normal
checking or savings account what I was
trying to get was a small business
checking account so that I can have a
tax account where I just put money in
for taxes and don't spend it when tax
time comes
I've got tax when he's sitting there it
comes right out of that account that was
my intention but this bank has refused
to open my back up tax account so I just
got to pay my taxes out of my normal
business account not a big deal but not
what I wanted to do with my business
with my money I feel like I should be
able to put my money in the bank and
manage my money just like anybody else
because I worked for it legally just
like everybody else it feels kind of
shitty this is one of the ancillary
issues that we did not think about when
it came to legalizing cannabis this is
going to be an issue in every new legal
market until cannabis is federally legal
this will be a hurdle for everybody this
is a hurdle for businesses that are
trying to open this is a hurdle for
people who work in the industry or who
are trying to live a legitimate life the
people who work in these grows are not
all STONER pothead Bros there are people
of all walks of life of all ages working
in these facilities
there are cultivators there are trimmers
but there are also lawyers and
accountants and compliance managers and
people who live a completely different
life than anybody who has ever been in
the illegal side of the cannabis
industry it is a legal business now and
the majority of the people want to live
like upstanding legal citizens so it's a
little frustrating it's a little bit of
a slap in the face that we're able to go
to work every day and they take
employment taxes out of our check then
all of those cannabis businesses have to
pay their taxes but when it comes to
having a bank account they don't want
anything to do with us I think that's
kind of a slap in the face I think it's
kind of [ __ ] that we can't have a
bank account because it's federally
illegal but you'll take my tax money
even though it's federally illegal you
should pick one you can't have my dirty
money if it's dirty money you shouldn't
get it at all
I don't know why once you take it it
becomes clean now since it was dirty
when I had it that's [ __ ]
but that's just a side rant this is
going to be a problem everywhere
cannabis gets legalized so be prepared
for that think about that if you were
trying to open a business think about
that if you were trying to be in the
industry sometimes it may be challenging
establishing
maintaining your credit and your bank
accounts now like I said a moment ago I
am looking for solutions credit unions
may be the option I was told there are a
couple of banks here in my area bill
will work with people in the cannabis
industry again most of the time it is
easy to get an account if you only have
the support badge and if you are looking
for a personal account my struggle is
that I have got the key badge which
gives me too much access to too many
things is what the lady said she said
you've got access to everything the safe
the money the product she said that I am
too deeply involved is why they make the
differential between the key badge and
the support badge but my key badge and
the fact that I was trying to open a
business checking account flagged my
account and they refused to give me
service so I left the bank unsatisfied I
sat there for probably an hour waiting
for an appointment it was a total waste
of time now there are rules and laws in
the works and things are being discussed
but until those things are implemented
it is still going to be frustrating for
some folks in this industry all right
let's move away from banking and talk a
little bit about cannabis cultivation I
will send a very great message through
my youtube channel somebody comments it
on the YouTube channel I am scrolling
through my messages right now to find it
here we go this one came from a person
who calls themselves real rasher on
YouTube they commented on one of my
videos and the comment goes like this
couldn't you harvest one branch at a
time a week apart for several weeks
wouldn't that also be a way to gauge a
preferred maturation in one grow or with
the stress of each harvest alter the
remaining branches so this was a
question based on the harvest time
podcast episode we're talking about when
to harvest and how to determine ripeness
this person is asking if we can harvest
the plant in multiple phases maybe
taking one branch at a time for a week
and then continuing that for multiple
weeks until we have harvested the entire
plant that is an option that does work
for people growing one or two plants
outdoors there is nothing stopping you
from taking that top cola that's nice
and finished that will allow light to
get to some of those lower buds it'll
speed them up they'll also
get more light they'll get fatter
they'll get more density you'll have
more overall bud there it will also
allow more time for them to ripen up
then you can take those top buds again
and maybe have a third harvest of some
lower buds I wouldn't really do it
branch by branch that's gonna be a
little bit too tedious that's gonna
leave you too many days apart between
your branches that are cut you're gonna
have to be trimming a branch every day
you cut a few days later there's more
work to do you cut a branch you've got a
defoliant it's gonna hang in a few days
it's gonna Drive and you've got to do
work to it a couple more days from there
you've got to do more work to it you've
got to trim it you've got to dry and
cure it so if you've got a bunch of
branches that are three days apart it's
really going to make your drying and
curing process kind of a staggered
pain-in-the-ass
I would do it in two maybe three phases
if you were going to stagger it I would
do that top the main top section that's
really done then leave the middle and
take that middle and it finishes then
take the bottom if you're going to do it
in staggered phases at all I don't like
this method for several reasons mainly
because I am a commercial cultivator
when it's harvest time I cut everything
down I clean the room and I refill it so
there is zero downtime every square foot
of space in my facility is worth dollars
so having plants that are just waiting
to finish in some spots and not able to
refill the entire room and starter start
over completely gets frustrating in a
commercial environment we grow plants
that we know are going to be done at
sixty three days and a day sixty three
days they all come down and I can refill
it with more plants that take
sixty-three days I can stay on a cycle I
can pull five point seven seven harvests
per room per year on that rate if I put
eight week plants in there I can pull
six full harvests in there but I need to
stay on schedule because when I fall
behind schedule money doesn't come in at
the time we need it then paychecks can't
happen rent can't happen utility bills
can't happen everything falls to [ __ ] so
I have to stay on schedule that is my
main reason for not doing this type of a
thing in a commercial environment I
simply want to cut and clean and restart
and again I also don't want my trim crew
cutting half of a plant and having to
deal with half of that plant and coming
back a few days later and cutting the
other half of
plan and now we've got two different
harvest batches that are one week apart
and we've got to dry and cure these
[ __ ] a week apart it makes a problem
when it is on a large scale in your
small personal grow this would work
beautifully
especially in an outdoor environment
part of your question was will this
stress the plant possibly depending on
the genetics of your plant depending on
how rough you are depending on how late
or early you decide to start chopping
this could very well stress the plant if
you take the top and you're a little bit
too rough or you pissed that plant off
you could cause some stress to the lower
parts of the plants but if all things go
well you're going to cut it down in
seven to ten maybe fourteen days anyway
so none of those problems will have a
chance to present themselves you may
piss the plant off but it's not gonna
hermaphrodites
it's not going to spit out seeds on you
overnight and if it does her him on you
overnight it's not going to cause any
problems that quickly if you're paying
attention you'll see some hermaphrodite
flowers you'll be able to cut down the
plant before any of those flowers cause
any problems and honestly if you see
hermaphrodite flowers that laid into the
grow there's nothing to pollinate
because it is way too late to pollinate
that plant there aren't any other plants
that are available for pollen that late
in the season so it should not be a
problem
so technically yes you could start
harvesting the top and then you could
wait a few days and you could take the
middle and then you could wait another
week and take the bottom or you could
just do it in two phases but I wouldn't
do it branch by branch that is going to
be tedious it's gonna be frustrating and
that will stress out the plant but
harvesting your personal outdoor crop in
two or three chunks should not present
too many problems if you have a big
harvest that you can't manage by
yourself in one move now I know most
people are looking for peak ripeness out
of their trichomes and they want every
bud to be just perfect before they
harvest unless your plant is gigantic I
don't think you're going to notice much
difference in the buzz from the buds at
the top and the buzz at the bottom if we
cut the plant down on one day and we dry
it and cure it and smoke a bud from the
top and a bud from the bottom even
though those top buds are a little more
done I don't think you will notice
much of a difference unless you were
like an absolute super connoisseur I
really don't think you're gonna notice
much of a difference and most of the
time once those buds make it to the bag
or to the jar they all mix up anyway and
then you smoke a joint and it's usually
one or two buds ground up and mixed
together or you smoked a couple of bowls
and you will get the desired effect so
unless your plant is massive I don't
think you're going to notice much of a
difference I don't think it would be
worth the staggered harvest if that is
something you want to do because you
really want those trichomes dialed in
and if it's outdoors and there's nothing
stopping you from leaving the bottom
half for another week go ahead and let
it go have fun with it make sure you pay
attention to the temperature because it
is getting really cold outside and I
don't want you to leave that second half
out there and destroy it and not even
get to harvest that and also make sure
that the thieves don't come and get that
second half when they see you take the
tops down they'll go oh [ __ ] he's gonna
take that plant down soon we got to go
get the second half pay attention for
that but the main reason we don't do
this in an indoor situation is because
we really just need to chop and clean up
and get started again and our plants
aren't super massively large and an
indoor cultivation facility so the
difference between the top and the
bottom is very little I don't think
anybody would notice
and we've also selected cultivars that
finish in the timeframe that we need our
growth to run in which is generally nine
weeks in a commercial cultivation
facility so real rasher I hope I
answered your question I want to thank
you for supporting the show by following
the YouTube channel and thank you for
the interaction if anybody else out
there has a question I would love to
hear from you the easiest way to get
your question on the show is to send it
to me through email my email address is
grow from your heart at hotmail.com
you know that I would love to hear from
you ladies and gentlemen this is a
Thursday episode so I'm gonna wrap it up
now thank you for listening to a quick
show if you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
and you would like to make a financial
contribution to the show you can do so
by visiting www.hp.com slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
if you are not in a financial position
to support the show you can simply
support us by following the YouTube
channel and leaving comments
the videos go to youtube search for the
growth from your heart podcast click
subscribe on the channel then type in
some comments and let me know what you
think about the show again you know that
I love the listener interaction I would
also appreciate it if you join us on
cannabis cannabis is a free social media
application it is available on your
Android or Apple mobile device all you
have to do is download cannabis create
yourself a cool username login give me a
follow and join the community cannabis
is a lot like most of your favorite
social media applications but on
cannabis you are encouraged and allowed
to post your cannabis themed content you
cannot buy sell or trade cannabis but
you can post your weed photos you can
post your dab videos and quite often I
do some very cool giveaways so don't
miss out for your chance to win some
cool prizes by following me on cannabis
on cannabis I am Irie underscore
genetics give me a follow ladies and
gentlemen my voice is burning out so I'm
gonna wrap up the show I want to thank
you again for listening I want to give a
huge giant shout out to my buddy tube
and jar and until next time take a phat
dab and give your mom a hug for me