hi I'm Li ho neighbors it is time for
episode 471 of the girl from your heart
podcast this episode of the show is
brought to you by our friends at seeds
here now if you need new regular
feminised to our Auto flower seeds in
your garden I highly recommend seeds
here now and you can find them at
www.cdxzipstream.com trait smells
deliciously disgusting and it makes me
stupid when I smoke it so I am
completely enjoying this big shout out
to our friends at Green Dot labs for the
delicious halo live batter in this
episode I'm going to do a strain review
or a strain report on one of my favorite
crosses before I get there I would like
to do some shout outs to a couple of my
friends on patreon let's start off with
the big giant grow from your heart a
podcast shout out to my friend miss Mel
I also want to send a shout out to our
buddy Steve F about a giant girl from
your heart a podcast shout out thank you
- Brian B I want to send a giant thank
you to ethan g about a big shout out to
meredith honest into giant growth from
your heart podcast shoutout thank you to
sour D of course a big thank you to
Tanner M and last but certainly not
least a big grow from your heart podcast
shoutout thank you a fist bump and a
high-five - our friend BAFTA
if anybody else out there would like to
learn how to become a patron all you
need to do is go to www.petland.com
slash grow from your heart all of the
information you need will be right there
on the screen once again big shout out
and big thank you to everybody who has
supported the patreon campaign in the
past in the present and in the future
all right podcast world let's not waste
too much time in this episode I did say
that I wanted to do a strain review
let's talk about one of my favorite
strains that I have bred also a strain
that is getting really popular lately
let's talk about a cross that
I call Sunkiss what is sun kiss Sun kiss
is a cross of a female Platinum tangi
plant Platinum tangi comes from our
friends at the garden of Weeden big
shout out to Maddie and Spence and the
entire team Whedon what up kids I miss
you guys big high-five and a fist bumps
everybody out there I make sure you
scratch them dogs on the head for me
good dogs I miss you guys anyway the
platinum tan G is of course a platinum
cookies that is a Platinum Girl Scout
cookies female pollinated by a male
tangey plant that was named Julius that
was selected by Spence from the garden
of Weeden
so they pollinated the Platinum cookies
with the pollen from Julius and that
created the Platinum tangi the Platinum
tan G is a wonderful plant I came across
this plant in a commercial cultivation
it had been selected by somebody else
but they did a great job with the
selection it was a very good
representation of both parents it had
that cookies growth the cookies potency
but had that stink and that vigor of the
tangi it didn't take too long to flower
that plant was very pest resistant it
was very easy to grow it always gave
impressive test results impressive
harvest and the aromas and flavors were
very unique very orange dominant flavors
in that cross so Spence and Maddie did a
wonderful job breeding it whoever did
the phenotype selection did a wonderful
job with the selection I came across it
in a commercial facility and quickly
fell in love with it I acquired a cut
and I introduced that cut of the
Platinum tangi into my garden I began
playing with it and I've read it to
several things in this case we are going
to talk about breeding it to the arize
everybody knows I work with a strain
called arise arise comes from a golden
goat female pollinated by a Daybreaker
male Daybreaker is not a well known
strain so we'll talk about Daybreaker
briefly Daybreaker
is a Kim D female pollinated by a joseph
OG male so you've got chem dog and OG
cushion they're super stinky super funky
really nice vigorous growth big fat wide
leaves kind of short stocky plants I put
that pollen onto a golden goat female
that made crazy plants I that is called
a rise that tests really high in THC it
grows with high
vigor it is just a wonderful plant to
work with the aromas and flavors are
great
I found a male out of my arise breeding
project that I have named King Solomon I
have made many crosses from King Solomon
and they all have proven to be
tremendous crosses anything Solomon
touches it just improves it if you've
got a plant in this case that makes
amazing orange Terps and is very pests
and pathogens istant and is very easy to
grow you pollinate it with Solomon and
all of those traits were amplified it is
more potent it is easier to grow it has
more rapid vigour it just seems to
improve everything so I took my prized
King Solomon my arise male plant and I
sprinkled that magic dust all over that
female platinum tangi and that created
what I have called Sun kiss now I'm sure
you can assume with the name like Sun
kiss we are going to have tremendous
orange dominant Terps that is one of the
most noticeable things about this cross
we'll talk about that in just a minute
let's focus more on the growth
characteristics of this plant we've
talked about the cross it is a platinum
tangi cross to arise the Platinum tangi
plant stays fairly short that platinum
tangi plant didn't get real big it
didn't have a giant main Cola
it grows fairly even it does have a
dominant main apical top but it wasn't
that giant glory bud like a lot of
plants get most of the buds stayed even
and uniform which makes it great for a
commercial environment so that's part of
why I selected it i bred it to the arize
the arize is known to grow very quickly
it will get kind of tall on you I
figured this would even out that
shortness to that hyper vigor I would
add them together and it would just make
a normal speed growth plant and it
worked beautifully
many of the phenotypes that come from
the Sun kiss stay shorter and a little
bit whiter and when you flower them they
don't have that amazing stretch that a
lot of plants have a lot of plants when
he flipped them into flower for about
three weeks they're really going to take
off the Sun kiss does not stretch as
hard as a lot of other plants so that's
really advantageous for most grows she
does grow a little bit wider than some
plants you may need a little bit more
space if most of the time you give your
plants a two foot Center you may need a
three foot center if you
before you may need a 6 if you're
starting with 6 you may need to go 8
feet with a sun-kissed plant you're
gonna get a little bit wider growth than
what you're used to but that is great
because that means more production most
of us are limited by plant counts how
many plants we can grow is dictated by
our local government by our local
medical cannabis laws if you're a
personal home grower so we need to keep
the numbers low having a plant that
branches out like this and produces
really well is really advantageous so
they stay a little bit shorter they
don't get as tall as many of the other
plants however they will get a little
bit wider they will branch out but they
will not stretch is rapidly at the start
of flower that makes Sunkiss a really
good plant for something you want to
trellis out if you're working a screen
that is a really great plant for it just
screen it out it'll fill that screen
real well then put a second screen about
12 to 16 inches above that and it'll
fill right into that net if you're in a
commercial environment put up another
net because it's gonna get right into
that net if you've got those kavita's
banging it will grow into there so it's
gonna stay shorter it's gonna get a
little bit wider it's not gonna stretch
on you ridiculously tall it's not gonna
have that major apical dominant op if
you want something that grows even
canopy more easily so you don't have to
cut that main top out if you're not into
topping this is a great plant for that
sort of stuff however when you do top it
that [ __ ] will really take off and
branch out extra hard this is a great
plant for outdoor and greenhouses many
people ask me what would you recommend
for an outdoor environment or a
greenhouse from your lineup I start off
with the Sun kiss if you want a regular
seat I should mention this is not
feminized since this comes from King
Solomon this is not a feminized see this
is only regular there is a feminized
version it is known as Michelangelo it
is very similar it is currently sold out
but it will be back so check out the
Michelangelo if you need feminized seeds
let's keep talking about this where the
hell was I a lot of people ask me my
recommendation on outdoor strains this
is the one I recommend I recommend the
Sun kiss because she doesn't take nearly
as long to finish as a lot of my other
plants I've had people email me and say
hey dude this plants been going 45 or 50
days and she looks done is that possible
and I say send me pictures of the
trichomes and without a doubt those
plants were done at 45 or 50 days
outdoors so these plants are great
for outdoor or greenhouses they are very
pathogen and pest resistant they don't
get powdery mildew they don't get mold
for some reason the spider mites don't
really seem to like the orange turps
that come from this plant so Sunkiss is
a great selection for either a new
grower or somebody who is trying to grow
in an outdoor environment or in a
greenhouse environment or a lot of my
friends are on the coast people up in
the Pacific Northwest or up on the East
Coast they were saying hey what can I
grow outdoors this year I was
recommending the Sun kiss along with a
couple of other things but I like the
Sun kiss because it doesn't get powdery
mildew and it tends to finish before
people are going to have outdoor
problems so let's focus more on a few
growth characteristics and then we'll
move forward she won't get too tall on
you but she will get kind of wide she
will not stretch she will flower in less
time than most of my other plants I want
to say that most phenotypes will be done
around eight weeks there are some
outliers that will be done earlier and
some that will be done later like I said
before I was getting reports of this
strain being done at 45 and 50 days
outdoors I've also seen this plant go 65
or 70 days indoors so it just depends on
your phenotype and we're gonna talk
about that in a minute you do have the
opportunity of finding early finishing
phenotypes I recommend you grow a crop
indoors find a good one for the outdoor
put that early finisher outdoor and grow
the [ __ ] out of that next year outdoors
put a bunch of clones of that one out
there you know what to do you know what
to expect you know exactly how long it
takes that is setting yourself up for
success but there are some early
finishing phenotypes I can say 8 to 9
weeks on most phenotypes a lot of them
will finish around 8 some a little bit
earlier as a breeder if I say that this
plant will finish at 7 weeks people are
going to expect it to be done at the end
of 7 weeks and they will email me when
it's not so I can't say that some
phenotypes will do that more typically
you're going to see 8 weeks some will go
9 weeks very untypical II but there will
be some that will go 10 weeks another
great thing about Sunkist is that she
clones very easily if you're cloning in
a cube if you're cloning and rapid
rooters however you take your clones you
will have a great success with Sunkiss
she is very easy to clone and I believe
that that comes from the Platinum tangi
that plant just
clones you can just cut clones of it and
set them on the table and they will make
roots so big shout out to Spence for
that that is great work there but that
platinum tangi makes it super easy to
clone the Sunkist plants it just spits
out roots no problem they grow with
great vigor this plant will make robust
stocks very quickly these stocks get
super thick you may need to transplant
these plants earlier than you're used to
transplanting you may want to speed up
your schedule by about one full week if
you're working with good lighting and
good soil and you've got proper
nutrients and you know what you're doing
you could probably speed up your entire
entire cycle by one full week by running
something with the vigor that comes with
the Sunkist plant hyah cones really
quickly it doesn't get too big where
else was I its p.m. resistant you were
very unlikely to find powdery mildew on
a Sunkist plant indoors or outdoors I
don't see powdery mildew on this plant
that is one of my favorite traits about
it that is partly why I'd recommend it
to an indoor grower also it does not get
bugs I don't find bugs on this plant
nobody ever sends me a picture saying
hey there are bugs on this Sunkist plant
I get pictures of bugs on all other
strains but not Sunkist so that is
something that I think is really
advantageous if you're a new grower this
plant will work great for you I don't
see any intersex traits in this plant I
have never seen a photo of a
hermaphroditic Sunkist plant so this one
is great for new growers this one is
also great for outdoor growers or
greenhouse growers because it can really
handle stress and mistakes it also likes
a lot of food you can feed this [ __ ] out
of a Sunkist plant I've got one friend
who grows this plant in all organic
no-till type of environments and he
crushes it it produces delicious orange
crazy Terps and the plants are beautiful
I've grown this in a commercial
environment using all veg bloom and
commercial salty nutrients and it
crushes it it puts out giant plants I've
seen all kinds of different environments
really win with the Sun kiss again
this is an easy plant to grow if you're
a beginner or if you just need a break
if you're tired of struggling this is an
easy one to grow this one kind of goes
on autopilot if you know how to grow she
doesn't seem to get too upset if you
miss a feed she doesn't seem to get too
upset if you over feed and one great
thing is she really doesn't mind if you
[ __ ] up the pH a little bit too much
I'm not going to encourage you to
go in there and not adjust the pH but if
you're not the best grower if you're
kind of lazy and you're kind of not
checking your pH you're not gonna mess
up the crop with this when I've seen
some lazy growers some new growers and
some pro growers all crush it with Sun
kiss now she will get some pretty big
buds I said earlier that she doesn't get
that big apical dominant bud but she's
going to grow some long branches those
bottom branches are gonna reach to the
top so they may need some supports
that's one thing I should recommend I
would recommend I like growing with the
trellis like with a net with multiple
layers of netting I know that's not an
option for everybody in your environment
you may need a tomato cage a tomato cage
is great because the plants are gonna
push out they can fall right into that
tomato cage you can pull some branches
down and strap them to the cage or you
can use sticks I like to kind of spread
this plant out it kind of D foliate kind
of heavily and let a lot of sunshine get
into the bottom of that plant you don't
have to clean too far down the bottoms
of this plant are gonna make fat buds
also so don't clean too far down as long
as you get light in there as far as the
light goes you will get buds with this
plant some phenotypes will give you what
I like to call taco leaf it looks like
they're getting too warm I don't think
those plants are always too warm when I
see that taco leaf I think that is just
something in the genetics because I've
seen it in multiple environments the
good thing about that taco leaf is it is
usually just encrusted with trichomes
some of your smaller leaves now your fan
leaves but the secondary leaves that are
coming out of the buds will just kind of
curl up just a little bit and they'll
just coat themselves in trichomes at the
edges don't be worried if you see that
that is not a problem what you do have
to watch for is the tips of the leaves
starting to look like they're crisping
up that is when you're giving it too
much nutrient honestly I think you're
giving the plant just enough nutrient
when you see I call it getting their
nails done when you see the tips
starting to cook you know you've given
it just to its limit you're pushing it
it's starting to go hey boss do I really
have to work this hard that's when you
can go okay that's your limit I know how
far you can go and you know but there's
a difference between stress between too
much heat and between just seeing those
taco resin rails if you're getting a
little bit of a fold and a bunch of
trichomes coming across that you are not
overheating those plants they're a
loving life that is just a trait of the
plants now talking about traits let's
move toward talking about some of the
phenotypes most of the phenotypes are
fairly uniform are going
to see platinum tangi dominant
phenotypes and then we're going to see a
rise dominant phenotypes most of them
like I was talking about earlier are
going to be a beautiful combination
we got short squat plants that grow kind
of wide with a lot of vigor you're going
to get some that are a little taller
you're gonna get some that show a little
bit of stretch for the most part they're
going to be dense wide plants most of
the phenotype differences are going to
express themselves in aroma you're going
to get straight-up oranges like a basket
of fresh delicious oranges that somebody
cut one open right in the middle so it
smells real citrusy in the room you're
gonna get a real orange dominant type of
a phenotype then we're going to get sort
of a gassy funky orange phenotype it's
oranges and feet and that's coming from
the Daybreaker which is coming from the
Joseph og side of things coming from the
chem dog side of things put a little bit
of musty foot into that orange so it's
maybe like if you got to eat a slice of
oranges from somebody's dirty feet which
when it comes to cannabis that's a
[ __ ] ideal sort of a smell then there
was another phenotype that is a little
bit different it is a little I call it a
sharper of an aroma it is a little bit
more of an orange Ryan it's more like
you bit too far down into the orange you
shouldn't have eaten that far and it
tastes a little bit bitter but it's
still real citrusy and it's still really
sweet that one smells a little bit funky
on its own but it makes amazing
concentrates the concentrates don't come
out with that bitter smell they come out
super Jolly Rancher orange candy sweet
it is really delicious so that if you've
got that astringent funky orange
grapefruit sort of a smelling one in the
beginning it is going to turn into
straight-up orange candies when it dries
and cures or when you make concentrates
out of it that phenotype is identifiable
because it is taller and has skinnier
leaves that is going to be the
grapefruit flavored phenotype I believe
that that comes from the golden goat
side of things I think that that is
either the island sweet skunk or
possibly the Romulan doing that I really
think that there is a grapefruit
characteristic in the island sweet skunk
a sweet pink grapefruit Terp that is
just hidden back in there somewhere in
the genetics it is in there i unlock it
occasionally when I cross the golden go
to other things it comes out when I
cross the
arise to other things that turf comes
out I really believe that's coming from
the golden goat from the island sweet
skunk in the golden goat it is a
grapefruit sweet pink grapefruit sugary
grapefruit sort of a Terp you'll smell
that in flower you'll smell that in the
drain cure process and that will drop
out and it becomes complete orange Jolly
Rancher candies not like orange powder
not like orange juice
but that's sweet like when you put a
Jolly Rancher in your mouth and your
tongue gets wet like wow that's Orange E
it is that sort of orange e sort of a
thing and if you make good concentrates
out of that if you can make a good BHO
or a good live batter or I'm not dissing
whatever you're doing I like a good BHO
concentrate I feel like it really brings
out a good clean profile you can really
taste that orange candy just chilling on
your tongue it just dances around for a
little while really delicious so that's
the taller phenotype is what's going to
make that that's where I was with that
sorry I got distracted by enjoying that
phyno flavor in my mouth but if you're
looking for that grapefruit Terp
dominant phenotype you want the taller
one with the skinnier longer leaves
again I believe that comes from the
island sweet skunk if you want just the
straight orange e Terps I believe that
comes from the one with the more compact
leaves the leaves stay really close to
the plant the pedia yet really long and
if you've got the one with the purple
pea Deol's you've probably got the one
that has got a little bit of foot to it
because those long purple pea deals are
a trait of the day breaker and that's
where you're gonna get the foot aroma so
those are probably the three different
phenotypes you're gonna find you're
gonna find the street oranges you're
gonna find oranges and gasps and then
you're gonna get the astringent
grapefruit Ryne kind of orange peel
oranges they're all delicious they're
all amazing they're all beautiful in
their own way you may find some
different combos of different things
therein but I think you will be happy
with any phenotype you get of Sunkist I
have never gotten any bad reviews or
negative feedback on Sunkist and as a
seed maker as a breeder who has put out
a lot of seeds
I do get feedback and some of it
unfortunately is negative but that's how
you improve a business that's how you
improve a product there's always going
to be some type of negative feedback
that's how you improve but I never get
any negative feedback from Sunkiss so
I've talked about the phenotypes that
kind of talked about the flavors mostly
oranges it is just orange candy some of
those orange
tax order flavors I'm not as much like
orange tang but more fresh oranges gases
gassy oranges and then that that
straight-up Jolly Ranchers sweet
delicious drooly kind of orange flavor
those are the flavors you're gonna get
now let's talk a little bit about the
buzz from Sunkiss a lot of people ask me
for advice on flowers or concentrates it
would reduce anxiety or kind of calm
them down a lot of people get too high
and they get anxious when they smoke or
they're already experiencing anxiety
some people want something that will
help them in a social situation just to
be a little more a little more available
for social activity some of us don't
want to go out until we smoke and then
it kind of makes your brain a little
more friendly you want to go be around
more people be more social a lot of
people ask me for that type of a strain
I often recommend Sunkiss for that type
of situation Sunkiss will give you a
nice friendly smiley buzz you want to
talk you want to be around other people
and it doesn't give you that I hate
society kind of vibe that a lot of
people sort of seem to wake up with it
also just puts a smile on your face and
it'll give you a nice buzz without
making you anxious if you're prone to
getting anxiety when you smoke something
about the orange Terps are real calming
or real they put you in a friendly mood
they're just friendly Orange Terps I
can't describe it any other way there
are very few people that when they smell
oranges they say that is unpleasant most
of the planet really enjoys an orange
fragrant turf that is something that is
really popular those fruity sort of
Terps make almost everybody happy
the orange smell just puts everybody in
a good mood and when you smoked those
orange chirps it really just lifts you
up it's like a good breakfast dad or a
good breakfast joint so if you're
looking for something to smoke during
the day that's not gonna bog you out
that's not gonna make you too stupid
that's gonna keep you peppy gonna keep
your brain moving gonna keep you social
keep you functioning with people or if
you're looking for cannabis that you can
smoke that doesn't make you too anxious
cuz a lot of people get that anxiety you
take a DAB and you just start oh [ __ ] I
gotta go this will not give you dabbe
anxiety this should not give you smoke
anxiety if you want something that is
great for breakfast smoke for daytime
smoke Sunkiss is the way to go if you've
got to go talk to people and you're not
really in the mood to be around people
if if you got out maybe you work
somewhere where you got to deal with
customer
Sunkiss just may put a smile on your
face that you might not have had when he
started the day so that is my brief
report on Sunkiss at this point I would
usually talk about problems and
struggles you would run into while
growing this plant but this plan is such
a breeze to grow that I really don't
think you're going to find problems like
I said I don't get negative feedback on
this plan the only problem you will have
with Sunkiss is that if you leave the
jar around somebody will smoke all of
your buds because that [ __ ] smells
delicious all right podcast world that
is my story and I am sticking to it if
you would like to add some Sunkiss seeds
to your garden I've got a few sources I
can suggest for you I would start off by
checking with seeds here now.com you may
also be able to find Sunkist seeds at
the hella dank seed company you can find
them at dank seed dot store also I can
recommend the Oregon elite seed company
at Oregon elite seeds dot-com make sure
you shop around check out all three
vendors they all offer different sales
and specials at different times I know
everybody has their preferred seed bank
so shop where you're comfortable once
again I recommend seeds here now the
hella dank seed company and Oregon elite
seeds I can promise you that those are
official IRA genetics Sunkist seeds if
that is where you get them all right
podcast world I think that is all I've
got for you for this episode thank you
for listening to my strain review on
Sunkiss if you get some Sunkist seeds
and you do a grow with them I would love
to see your photos send me photos of any
I read genetics plants who are growing
that is how I select new testers if I
like the photos that you send me of your
current grow when I have new seeds that
I need grown those are the photos I look
through to find candidates to be
potential testers in the future so
please send me your photos of any high
region etic strains you may be growing
my email address is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com
and i look forward to hearing from you
ladies and gentlemen boys and girls
smokers and growers if you feel like
this episode was educational informative
or entertaining and you'd like to make a
financial contribution to the show you
can do so by visiting
www.azcleanelections.gov
click on the subscribe button maybe
watch a couple of videos maybe leave
some comments on the videos and let me
know what you think of the show again
you know that I do love listener
interaction if you've got something
you'd like to say you're not into all
that social media nonsense you can send
me an email
my email address is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com once again you know I
would love to hear from you ladies and
gentlemen my voice is burning out my
throat is gone so we are done with this
episode thank you again for listening I
want to give a giant grow from your
heart podcast shout out to my buddy
James but erson and until next time take
a phat dab and give your mom a hug for
me