hey what's up podcast world welcome to
episode 472 of the grow from your heart
podcast this episode of the show is
brought to you by my friends at seeds
here now if you need new regular
feminized or Auto flower seeds in your
garden I highly recommend seeds here now
and you can find them at
www.cdxzipstream.com the label the
flavor is described as sour fruit and
fuel I would definitely agree with the
fruity fuel part I'm not sure I get the
sour still a delicious and impressive
concentrate I'm gonna bust it open so I
can talk about the appearance and
consistency there are three perfect dab
size diamonds in here there were four or
five diamonds in here I am NOT going to
crush them up I'm going to take them as
individual tabs that means that this
gram will be five dabs there's just
enough Terp sauce in here to make it
delicious on the back of the container
it says that this product does contain
60.9 5 percent THC non detectable
amounts of CBD I am sure that the
remainder of that percentage is mostly
terpenes this product smells delicious
and ridiculous so big shout out to our
friends at green dot Labs for the
impressive dogfighter
full spectrum extract all right podcast
world in this episode I'm going to read
some customer reviews from the Apple
podcast application before I get there I
would like to do some shoutouts to a few
of our friends from patreon how about a
big girl from your heart podcast shot up
to JM I want to send a big thank you
shout out to Blackbird also a big giant
grow from your heart a podcast shout out
and thank you to Tyler are how about a
big fist bump and a shout-out to our
friend Justin of course a giant girl
from your heart a podcast shout out to
the zoso J of course I want to send a
giant girl from your heart podcast shout
out fist bump and thank you to our
friends down at Hogan's farms of course
a big shout out to Richard M I always
want to send a shout out to Darren W and
last but certainly not least I want to
send a giant girl from your heart
podcast shout out thank you
- fist bump - our friend David OQ and
again big giant thanks to everybody who
has supported the show on patreon if you
would like to learn how to support the
show you can do so by visiting
www.quicksustainablewealth.com
customer ratings and reviews if you are
listening to the podcast on the apple
podcast application and you would like
to leave a review on the show it is
really easy simply open up the podcast
however you listen to it if you're using
your Apple iPad or your iPhone you
probably open the podcast application
open that find the growth from your
heart podcast open that scroll to the
available episodes
keep scrolling right after that and then
it will show you customer ratings and
reviews it will give you an opportunity
to click on amount on an amount of stars
which you feel I deserve so far
everybody has given the show five stars
any reviews that were not 5 stars have
been deleted because they were deemed to
be spam and spiteful so we are standing
at nothing but 5 star reviews at this
point but click the amount of stars
which you feel I deserve then leave a
review about the podcast and let other
people know what you think about the
show I'm going to jump right into the
first Apple podcast customer
view of this episode I may have read
this one already honestly I don't
remember the last review I read this one
came in on August 6th from a person who
calls themselves Irie army six one nine
they gave us a five-star rating
I cannot read the full headline of the
review it starts off with great show
listen and learn then the thing gets cut
off here but then it continues there is
a full review it says Rasta Jeff is the
man his love for the plant and cannabis
community are very evident in every
episode and that means a lot to me
already this is a great review the whole
podcast uses passion and knowledge I
appreciate that both new growers and
experienced growers can learn something
from Rasta Jeff and they grow from your
heart pod cast man that is my exact goal
I'm trying to teach the new growers I'm
trying to keep the experienced growers
entertained while I'm doing it and
remind them of their roots so I'm
hitting my target which means a lot to
me he keeps going by saying keep
bringing the amazing content and I
promise to keep listening and sharing
the podcast hey I appreciate that tell
your friends about to show you guys it
goes on to say PS if possible please
bring more content about outdoor growing
for our friends in the Sun I appreciate
that I am NOT the most experienced
outdoor gardener so I do need to get
some friends on here it is actually
harvest season at this point so maybe by
next year we can get some outdoor
growers to come on here jesse has spent
most of the grow season in Mexico well
deserved so big shout out to our buddy
Jesse when he is back maybe we will get
him on the podcast to do a little
outdoor grow lesson hey thank you for
the great review thank you for the 5
stars let's keep moving I'm trying to
open up the next review now I don't like
the way that this application works now
but we are going to work with it I'm
clicking I'm clicking this one was left
on August 19th
this person calls themselves dawn grower
they left us a five star review the
headline says an awesome podcast and
easy but then they cut off the headlines
on the new application so you can't see
the rest of that however we can read the
full review it goes on to say Jeff great
show love the podcast and all of the
positivity and great advice my wife and
I are in Colorado Springs come by
sometime cheers hey I like that Don the
grower I am in Colorado Springs quite
frequently we will have to link up on
social media so that I can stop by and
dad
you out check out your garden and leave
some seeds so that you can grow some I
read genetics up there in Colorado
Springs I want to thank you for the
great review I want to thank you for the
5-star rating and I look forward to
hanging out at some Colorado Springs
dabbe event all right we're gonna keep
on moving this next review was left on
September 3rd by a person who calls
themselves Levi's son their headline was
nice and short it says awesome podcast
they did give us a 5-star rating the
review goes a lot like this I love your
podcast super helpful when I listen to
the grow lessons I take notes oh I have
to refresh the page because the review
just disappeared there we go it keeps on
going it says I take notes lots of info
don't stop making podcasts you're full
of knowledge and it's always great to
hear someone new and don't give up I
want to be listening till you get to
Episode one thousand while one thousand
episodes would be cool I'm almost up to
five hundred I think I'm about twenty
five away I don't remember what number
we're on here twenty five I'm 28
episodes away from being at 500 I think
a thousand is a reasonable goal I do not
see a reason to stop recording or making
podcasts as long as people keep
listening as long as the service is
still available as long as they don't
make some weird legal thing or some
changes to podcasts where they have to
be paid for or I have to pay to do it
then we should keep the go the show
going forever I don't see a reason to
stop and even if they do make me pay to
produce podcast I will still do it
because you guys support me quite well
and you've supported me for so long but
I would still continue to do it even if
it did cost me a little bit it does cost
me a little of course to host the
website to have all the equipment and
all that but patreon covers that so
thank you I want to keep going with this
review let's get back into it it says I
hope you don't give up and keep it up I
do not plan on giving it up there is no
reason to give up podcasting this is fun
I've got a lot of passion for this and
then every episode I put out I get at
least 12 or 15 replies on YouTube from
people saying great job thanks for all
of the help then I get a bunch of emails
from people saying wow you really solved
my problem in my grow it is very
rewarding so there is no reason to stop
doing the show I am [ __ ] rambly let's
keep going we've got some more reviews
to get through this one was left
on September 16th of 2019 by a person
who calls themselves Dean two to one the
headline is great I like that because it
fits in a little short spot they give
you now but our new friend gave us a
five-star rating I am opening the review
I have to refresh the screen again
because for some reason the reviews
disappear once you click on them you got
to unclick and click something else and
then go back to it that review is still
not there there's a blank space where
the review used to be there we go it
just popped back up I know I sound crazy
but if you're playing with the Apple
podcast application you'll see what I'm
talking about the new update is a little
weird that's why we're doing a test run
with this episode so it says most
informative and entertaining crow show
ever I appreciate that
rhasta Jeff is my hero that's [ __ ]
cool thank you I appreciate that
ah that's kind of scary but I do
appreciate it it also says I'm brand new
to stealth growing personal medicine and
I listen constantly I'm 63 and I feel
born again thanks Ross to Jeff man that
is kind of cool ah 63 and feels born
again thanks to this podcast and to
being able to grow personal cannabis
that is [ __ ] cool I appreciate that
that's my favorite review of the day it
goes on to say I want to reiterate Jeff
is so interesting just checking to see
if I can get Jeff another good review he
is a fascinating listen best ever man
that is really cool I appreciate that
not only am i delivering quality content
but this person feels that I am
interesting I didn't realize that was an
interesting person I do know that I've
got some cannabis knowledge I do know
that I talk too much but I did not
realize that other people found me
interesting outside of that so that is
really refreshing reassuring or
something like that I don't know what it
is but it feels good and it gives me
confidence so I want to thank you for
the great review and thanks again for
saying that I am an interesting person I
don't think I realized that people find
me interesting so thank you I appreciate
that big shout out to our new friend
Dean two-two-one who of course left a
five-star review I've got a couple of
more reviews left here on the screen I
know I'm talking really quickly I'm
going to blame that on a little bit of
caffeine and a whole lot of dogfighter
dabs from our friends at Green Dot let's
keep going this review is left on
September 28th of 2019 by a person who
calls themselves I can't tell if that's
me van or Melvin it looks like am i it's
me van 8:1
eight the headline of the review says
give thanks of course they gave us a
five-star rating the review goes just
like this this podcast has something for
everyone
that is my goal thank you I'm glad I'm
hitting the goal like I've said before I
want to get the new growers I want to
get the professional growers I want to
get the breeders I want to get the
commercial cultivators I want to get the
cannabis activists I want everybody
involved in the podcast so I'm glad that
I'm hitting that goal he says or they
say I love the girl episodes and the
push for activism to free the plant I am
a veteran who prefers organic medicine
thank you so much for what you have done
for my garden and especially for the
community I appreciate that I hope you
were growing quality medicine for
yourself
with my guidance I know I don't talk a
lot about or a lot about organic growing
I'm more of a a bottled nutrient of
course everybody knows I like veg bloom
and new millennium nutrients are some of
my favorites but I will get more organic
knowledge on the show for you I hope my
cultivation knowledge my grow lessons
are helping you out I will work more on
getting some organic based organic
focused info out on the show for you so
again big thanks to our friend me van
eight one eight I hope you were growing
some great medicine and he said you're a
veteran so I owe you a thank you I am
able to do what I do because you did
what you did so thank you I do
appreciate that
unless it's cannabis related I really
avoid talking about politics on this
show I don't share my political views or
ideals on this podcast because that is
not what this show is all about uh I do
not like war I don't like the idea of
that stuff however I do appreciate and
respect our soldiers I appreciate I
respect and I am grateful for anyone who
puts their life on the line to protect
people freedoms or anything that they
believe in so big respect for that now
let's get off this little weird so box
I've just created and let's keep reading
reviews again thank you I do appreciate
your service and thank you again for the
great review I've got one more review on
my screen this one comes from a person
who calls themselves Hobbit feet DGC big
shout out to anybody from the DGC that
is the dude grows crew if you are not
already checking out the dude
grows podcast I highly suggest you give
them a listen they were available on
iTunes that are available on stitcher
and of course they are available on
YouTube they are a great resource for
cannabis growers the Dude grow show of
course is hosted by a dude known as the
dude is backed up by a guy named Scottie
real and they've got a partner in crime
that they call guru who keeps all the
audio equipment running who keeps all of
the video equipment running and chimes
in with very useful horticultural
knowledge he is very well educated you
can tell the man has been to school you
can tell he is passionate about cannabis
and you can tell he is passionate about
our community so big shout out to all of
my boys from the dude grows crew make
sure you guys check out the dude grows
podcast become part of the dude grows
crew and then join us at some of the
dude grows events that we throw they
throw I just put myself right in the mix
what's up guys I'm part of that now join
us at some of the events which we throw
throughout the year in Colorado uh so
Big Shot uh said the DGC let's get my
high rambley ass back on track big shot
it's a hobbit feat DGC they give us a
five-star review the headline says
wonderful podcast so we got to give
thanks we got a awesome podcast we got a
great show got a bunch of great
headlines now let's focus in and read
the rest of this review from our friend
Hobbit feet of course the review just
disappeared off the screen here we go it
goes like this this is one of the best
growing podcasts for beginners and
experts I love that that is the theme of
the reviews it is a great show for
beginners and experts that means a lot
to me that I'm hitting my goal you guys
when you set out to do something and
you're not sure if you're getting it
right or not and a bunch of people say
best for beginners and experts and your
whole goal was to get for beginners and
experts that just makes you [ __ ]
dance in your chair yes I am dancing in
my chair right now I'm just doing a
little boogie don't even try to
visualize it it's [ __ ] goofy the
review goes I've learned so much and
laughed along the way again
that is my goal I was a bad student in
school I've got a TD like you would not
believe I'm sure you can tell just by
listening to me speak that my attention
goes crazy but I love to learn I love
filling my brain with knowledge and
useful facts I just don't want to learn
the dumb useless crap that we keep
repeating in school and I had to learn
over
/ I already know that teach me something
new let me learn expand my mind so I
hated school I had a few teachers that
made an effort to actually teach us they
weren't just reciting [ __ ] out of a
workbook and making us [ __ ] do
assignments they were making an effort
to be teachers to shape us as people for
the future those teachers I remember
them a lot of them were funny a lot of
them had a personality with which I
could connect that was harder to say
than it should have been but those
teachers are the teachers that made an
impact on me not the teachers that stood
in front of the class and droned on and
bored the [ __ ] out of me I don't
remember any of those teachers or their
classes there are a few teachers I
remember vividly because we connect it I
feel like if you connect with me a
little bit if I connect with you a
little bit I can teach you a lot and a
little bit of laughter makes you put
your guard down you get comfortable with
me and then you want to learn you put
down that a school you forget that
you're learning you're laughing and
you're absorbing information so I think
that a little bit of laughter and a lot
of Education is a perfect mix and I am
really hitting my goal with that and
this review makes me feel really good so
I'm sorry you got so rambley about it
we're gonna keep going it says Jeff is
an awesome human being and white mike is
the best you hear that way Mike somebody
thinks that you are the best we got to
get you back over here get you on the
podcast bro because people obviously
enjoy your presence the review just
disappeared off of the screen I've got a
refresh so we'll get it going again here
we go why Mike is the best it goes on to
say this podcast has it all
stay Irie hey Hobbit feet thank you for
the great review thank you for the five
stars I really appreciate that you guys
these were great iTunes podcast customer
reviews I know I keep saying it but it
means a lot to me to know that I am
perfectly hitting my goal I wanted to
teach everybody to grow I want to put a
little bit of laughter into it I want to
get the new growers I want to get the
pro growers I want to get the activists
and the advocates involved and it really
feels like that white Mike and myself
have really hit my goal so thank you to
everybody who is listening thank you to
everybody who has sent a review not just
on this episode but all of the reviews
that I've read in the past and any other
service if you're leaving reviews on
like YouTube or stitcher and I'm not
reading them
thank you for those reviews I do
appreciate it I will read some comments
and reviews from YouTube and a future
episode but I've gotten a couple of
emails that these episodes are not
people's favorites they would rather me
focus in on gross stuff which does make
sense this is the growth from your heart
podcasts not the review from your heart
podcast this is a Thursday episode and
once again this was a little beta test
to make sure that my recording gear is
working after a couple of updates so
once again big thank you to everybody
who has sent an iTunes review on this
episode or in a previous episode big
thanks for all of these stitcher
comments and a huge thank you to
everybody who has been leaving comments
on my youtube channel if you're not
already subscribed to youtube I would
appreciate it if you go to youtube
search for the grow from your heart
podcast subscribe to my channel leave
some comments let me know what you think
about the show and maybe I'll read your
comments on a future episode alright
ladies and gentlemen boys and girls
pimps and hoes chicks and bros smokers
and growers friends and foes flunkies
and bunkies I ain't got [ __ ] else I ran
out of a miles on a roll there for a
minute
big thanks to everybody for listening to
the show I'm gonna wrap up this episode
I'm going to go edit and make sure that
all the software works properly that way
I can be confident and record a solid
Monday episode for you don't forget
about the patreon campaign where you can
support the show financially simply go
to www.petland.com
slash grow from your heart all of the
information you need to support the show
will be right there on the screen again
I would appreciate it if you stock me on
youtube go to youtube search for the
grill from your heart podcast click
Subscribe leave some comments I love
that kind of interaction I also would
appreciate it if you follow us on
cannabis cannabis is a new cannabis
friendly social media application you
cannot buy sell or trade cannabis there
but you can post your cannabis
photography and cannabis videos on
cannabis if you're growing some plants
and you've got questions post a picture
of them tag me I'll go take a look we
can figure out what's wrong with your
plants and the entire cannabis community
will chime in with useful advice so join
us on cannabis checkout the IRA genetics
breeders group if you are growing or are
interested in growing any IRA genetics
crosses if you've got something you'd
like to say you're not into all that
social media nonsense
you can send me an email my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com again you know that I would
love to hear from you ladies and
gentlemen thank you again for listening
to episode 472 of The Grove from your
heart podcast I'll be back in just a
couple of days with fresh new content I
want to give a giant shout out to my
friend Jesse James and until next time
take a phat dad and give your mom a hug
for me