what's a podcast world it is time for
episode 475 of the growth from your
heart podcast this episode of the show
is brought to you by seeds here now if
you need new regular feminized or Auto
flower seeds in your garden I highly
recommend seeds here now and you can
find them at www.cdxzipstream.com it is
like you were eating Thanksgiving dinner
at the gas station that's kind of what
this makes me think of then when you dab
it that diesel flavor and aroma hits you
right in the face it's sort of funky
sort of gross then it's followed up by
that garlicky
robust savory flavor it kind of sits on
your tongue it gives you a really nice
cottonmouth then the buzz just makes you
want to chill out it makes me nice and
lazy kind of calms me down which is
something I can use
I tend to be going a little bit fast
lately so big shout out to our friends
at green dot Labs for the delicious
garlic banger live batter ladies and
gentlemen in this episode I'm going to
read a couple of listener emails before
I get to that part of the show I would
like to give some shout outs to a few of
our friends from
patreon let's start off with the big
giant grow from your heart podcast shout
out - thank you - JM I want to send a
big THANK YOU to Todd Kay I want to send
a big giant thank-you fist bump to
Blackbird 76 how about a big giant girl
from your heart podcast shout out to
Zozo Jay Ionis into giant thank you to
Tommy
of course a giant grow from your heart a
podcast shout out to Keith K I always
want to send a giant shout out to
Willie's armpit of course a big shot up
to Jacob W and last but certainly not
least I'd like to send a giant girl from
your heart podcast shout out and a thank
you to our friend Isaac G I want to
thank each and every one of you for
continuing to support the show on
patreon I also want to thank everybody
else out there who supports the show if
you would like to learn how to support
the show all you have to do is visit
www.reimaverick.com of emails printed
here in front of me I am trying to work
my way through the pile if you have sent
me an email and it has not made it to
the show yet please do not feel
discouraged I will get to your message I
honestly get about a hundred emails a
day I print out my favorites I put them
here in the pile and then when it comes
time to record I just start at the top
and work my way through the email on the
top of the pile today goes just like
this Rasta Jeff first and foremost I'd
like to extend my gratitude for all the
time you invest in your podcast platform
I have listened to all but a few of your
episodes and have to say that the amount
of knowledge you have imparted on me is
incredible and I want to extend my
gratefulness and this is a great message
I really like starting the show like
this you are very welcome thank you for
listening thank you for learning and
thank you for reaching out and
expressing your gratefulness so let's
keep going the message says thank you
your show definitely makes a difference
keep up the hard work
I appreciate that not a lot of people
realize that a podcast is hard work
people think I just turn on a microphone
and ramble for 40 minutes and that's how
it goes sometimes it's not that easy
sometimes it is that easy but there is
prep that goes into it I have to come up
with an idea for a show then I have to
actually do the show then there is
editing and there's posting and there's
a video and there's social media that
goes along with it so there's a lot of
work that goes into a podcast so thank
you for noticing that part of the deal
it goes on to say I do have a couple of
questions for you if you have the time
question number one you mentioned that
you will do an episode on your specific
breakdown of your use of veg bloom
nutrients I would be very interested in
this as I am currently using their full
line I'd like to see if there are some
better all
as I know you were using a blend of
their products that is a very good
question
I do still plan to deliver the nutrient
mix episode I am writing that episode
there are going to be a lot of details
in that episode people are going to ask
a lot of questions so I am taking my
time to write that show down and have a
lot of notes in most cases I make a very
minimal outline so I can keep the show
organic and feel like I'm having a
conversation the episode where I'm going
to teach you about my nutrient mix will
be quite detailed so I am taking my time
making that episode I also was trying to
get a couple of my friends to be on the
show for that episode but the timing for
that is not going to work out and now it
is starting to snow here in Colorado so
getting people to come to pueblos from
Denver or Fort Collins is going to be
challenging so I am now writing that
episode as a solo show and I do plan to
bring it to you as soon as I feel like I
have got the ingredients and the
instructions and the timeline documented
properly I already know that the moment
I drop that episode I'm going to get an
influx of emails asking for more details
people are going to have specific
questions I'm trying to cover all of
those details and answer those questions
before I put the episode out if you
listen to my last episode you'll know
that I am just trying to set myself up
for a success that's a good example of
setting yourself up for a success now
let's keep moving there is a second
question in this email the second
question goes just like this I have a
small assortment of some of your seeds
that I acquired at the DGC 7/10 Cup I've
been hesitant to pop these until I can
get some to keep in my genetic
collection I love that people collect my
seeds like their baseball cards I really
bred those seeds to be grown but I
really loved that people have taken to
collecting my seeds like there are
baseball cards or pokemon cards I know
people who have got the entire I read
genetics collection they've got seeds
from when I was releasing grateful dog
and heart of gold all the way up to the
lemon Jeffrey they've got the stomper
line that most people never even knew
about and then of course a lot of people
have all of the arize line but some
people have everything and some people
send me a message with their list and
they say what am I missing how can I
fill in the gaps
and some people have stuff that I don't
even have anymore so I find that really
impressive but I think it's really neat
that my supporters want to support me in
such a way that they feel like they need
to collect everything I release that
really means a lot to me I have a lot of
respect and appreciation for my
supporters my followers my friends my
family my fans I call them the Irie army
it really means a lot to me that you
guys want to collect everything I put
out and trust me I do realize that
without you guys I would not be able to
do this so big respect and big thank you
let's keep going with this it says is
there any way to source your gear
locally I live in Denver but I am
frequently in the Colorado Springs
Pueblo area so it would not be an issue
for me to travel to any of those
locations all right that is a great
question our friend wants to grow out
the IRA genetics seeds he has already
got but once he does that he's going to
have a gap in his collection so he wants
to know if there is a local source for
ira genetic seeds in the denver colorado
springs pueblo area and unfortunately my
seeds are not available in any colorado
dispensaries at this time that may
change in the year 2020 but I do not
want to make any promises or set any
expectations at this current time the
best way to acquire I read genetic seeds
is through seeds here now.com dank seed
dots store or Oregon elite seeds dot-com
however if you are a Colorado local or
if you come to the Denver Colorado
Springs Pueblo area and you happen to
bump into me there is a good chance that
I will have a lineup of ira genetic
seeds with me I also attend most of the
large events in Colorado so you have a
good opportunity to bump into me at the
endo Expo the endo Expo is at the end of
January it is January 25th and 26th at
the Denver Mart in Denver Colorado one
of those days is business day one of
those days is open to the public if you
can attend the public day I look forward
to seeing you at the endo Expo at this
time I also plan to attend the dude
grows cup which will be in April at
cultivated synergy that event has not
been announced
book tour schedule but most of the time
we do that event the weekend before or
after 4/20 and it is at cultivated
synergy and it is a consumption friendly
event you will be able to dab with me
you will be able to smoke a fat joint
with me but at the end o Expo
there will be no consumption so if
you're coming from out of state and
you're trying to meet up and take some
dabs the Indo Expo is a no consumption
event the dude grows cup which has not
been announced or confirmed yet but it
more than likely will happen because I'm
kind of forcing it right now I'm
manifesting that it's going to happen
that is a consumption friendly event so
you can show up we could take some dabs
we can smoke a joint and we can spend
some time together so if you're in
Colorado if you're in the Denver
Colorado Springs or Pueblo area there's
a good chance we could run into each
other if we don't run into each other
organically or we don't set something up
I'm sure you can find me at the endo
Expo they have not assigned me a booth
number yet but I'm sure I will be easy
to find it will be in all the
advertising my booth number will be on
the guide I've got a really large banner
and I'm also six foot five and I've got
dreadlocks to my ass almost to my knees
so I should be pretty easy to identify
so find me at the endo Expo if you don't
make it to the endo Expo find me at the
dude grows cup it cultivated synergy and
you guys I've said this before on
previous episodes if you see me at an
event and you've always wanted to say hi
shake my hand take a selfie anything
like that anything that's not creepy and
weird
I invite it come say hello don't tweet
me tomorrow and say hey I saw you with
the event looks like you were having fun
come shake my hand say hey Rasta Jeff I
like listening to the show or hey Rasta
Jeff I like growing your seeds come
introduce yourself if you have got some
buds that you grew of my genetics come
show them to me I would like to smell
your buds I want to see your work
especially if it's my genetics I want to
know what's happening in your grow I
want to be your friend you listen to me
ramble it's my turn to listen to you so
come introduce yourself come shake my
hand I look forward to meeting everybody
that listens to the show and then if
you're not in Colorado if you're not
able to come to the Denver area and meet
me in person again I recommend seeds
here now dot-com I also recommend dank
seed dot store and of course don't
forget our friends
at Oregon elite seeds now the person
that sent me this message was a Colorado
local so I look forward to hanging out
taking some dabs with you and talking
about which seeds you want to sprout
first to start growing some I read
genetics in your garden now you didn't
sign your name at the end of the email
but you did put the words local Colorado
grower in the subject line so big shout
out big thank you to local Colorado
grower for the great email all right
ladies and gentlemen boys and girls
let's keep moving through this mountain
of emails the next email for this
episode goes just like this
hey Rasta Jeff big shout out to you and
white Mike hey Mike you just got a shout
out bro that means that it's time for
you to come be on the show again
it goes on to say I do love listening to
you guys ramble that is a good thing
because when Mike comes on the show we
get a little bit stoned and we sure do
ramble so I'm glad you enjoy it the
message goes on to say I have been a
devoted listener to your podcast since
hearing about it from the dude grows
show and I am quickly making my way
through all of the episodes well I'm
glad you have found me I'm glad you
found me through the dude growth show of
course big shout out to my friends at
the dude grow show big shout out to the
entire DGC thanks for all the support
let's keep going with the email it says
every episode teaches me something new
or gives me some type of new perspective
so I truly appreciate all of the work
that you put into them hey that means a
lot to me man thank you
knowing that I am sparking your brain to
think in a different direction or maybe
just making you look at the grow from
another angle
that is kind of my goal because that is
how we learn if you keep looking at
things straight forward you're only
gonna see the straightforward view if
you take a step to the left oh my God
look at all that other [ __ ] we can see
from over here go take a step to the
right oh my god all kinds of new [ __ ]
you can see over here I like knowing
that you are learning something new from
each episode but it really means a lot
to me to hear that I am giving you a new
perspective so thank you for telling me
that that is a huge compliment and again
thank you for noticing all of the work
that I do put into these episodes we
talked about that in the last message
and it is a little bit of work let me
keep going with this email because I am
getting rambley this email says the
first question I have doesn't really
have to do anything with growing but
more about identifying and
scribing the seemingly limitless smells
and flavors which come from the cannabis
plants throughout Instagram and on your
podcast I often hear people describe
buds as smelling cushy hazy or og every
time I try to ask someone what this
exactly means the person has a very hard
time describing it to me in a way I can
get a real feel for what I'm supposed to
be looking for that is a very good
question because sometimes it can be
challenging to try and describe some of
these aromas and flavors some of them
are very complex some are very obvious
sometimes it is challenging to put your
nose and a label on all of these
different smells and aromas and all this
different information we are receiving
so let's spend a couple of minutes
talking about some of the most common
flavors and aromas people talk about
when we are describing cannabis plants
now the first one you asked about was
Khushi but I want to start with diesel
because diesel is going to help me
describe a few more things
the reason the strained diesel is called
diesel is because it smells like a
barrel of diesel fuel that has got a
funky sort of a astringent sharp smell
to it that kind of makes your your nose
it makes my nose want to wrinkle up a
little bit I feel it in my eyes it is a
very chemically dominant kind of a smell
it smells like diesel fuel there's
nothing that smells like diesel fuel
other than diesel fuel that is why the
strained diesel got that name if you
have got a bag of properly grown
real-deal diesel in your pocket
you smell like somebody just poured
diesel fuel in your pocket on your shoes
it is a very noticeable pungent aroma so
I want to start this with that diesel
fuel aroma because most of us know what
that smells like I think it smells warm
I think it smells like chemicals I think
it smells sharp I feel like I can feel
it in my nose and I feel like when I get
too close to it it makes me squint a
little bit
there is also an underlying hint of
skunk when it comes to the diesel strain
so think of diesel fuel and skunk I'm
going to try to build this flavor and
this aroma in your mind we have got
diesel fuel with a little bit of a skunk
background maybe somebody was putting
fuel in the diesel truck and got sprayed
by a skunk that's kind of the aroma that
we were working with it is funky it
is gross but for some reason it is
really delicious and really desirable
when it comes to cannabis
so skunk and diesel are two great bases
to start with two very obvious aromas
and two things that I think people
should be familiar with now let's work
our way toward cush and when we say cush
I'm talking about oh gee cush you listed
the flavor oh gee and you also listed
the word cush as flavors those are sort
of going to kind of fall into the same
palette here oh gee cush is a variety of
cush but it is the og it's the one we
should kind of base the flavor on then
everybody bred the cush to other things
and it started to dilute the cush flavor
we wanted to add bananas and
strawberries and oranges so we've got
orange cush banana cush but let's focus
on the original og cush flavor so I've
built a nice idea of what the diesel and
skunk aroma would kind of be like in
your head so let's kind of dial back the
diesel aroma a little bit and let's add
a little bit of pine to that maybe some
fresh pine trees maybe one of those pine
tree air fresheners you put in the
window of the car add some of that aroma
to it so we've got some skunk ass we've
got a little bit of diesel feel now we
are putting pine on top of it now we are
starting to get a little bit closer to
that og cush flavor now on top of that
skunk ass that diesel feel and a little
bit of pine I also want to add just a
hint of dirty feet just enough to make
you go what the [ __ ] and I know we've
already got skunk and diesel in there
but that dirty rotten foot just just a
little dirty rotten foot really makes
the rest of those aromas pop I know that
sounds disgusting but that dirty foot
aroma it comes out you got to smell it
and then you smell it it doesn't happen
on the original smell you go oooh diesel
and skunk and pine oh there's a foot in
there it hits you second so we've got
fuel and skunk then we've put pine in
there now we've put a little bit of a
dirty foot in there
now the next aromas i want to add are a
little bit of dankness and maybe a
little bit of swamp enos think about
like if you go into a basement that's
been sealed up for too long if it's kind
of smells a little musty a little damp a
little dank in there that flavor
kind of
comes in at the end of the OG Kush so it
starts off skunky and fuelie and then
it's got that pine dominance to it then
there's a feet aroma to it and then when
it finishes it is musty and funky and
dank now I hope I have painted a good
picture in your mind I can almost taste
some OG Kush right now from all these
descriptors now there will be variations
on this depending on which cush you are
smoking are you smoking oh gee Kush you
smoking bubba kush do you have tahoe OG
there are a lot of different pushes
available and unfortunately there are a
lot of plants and jars of weed out there
labeled cush that do not have any
cushion the genetics when the medical
marijuana movement swept colorado i
watched everybody go cush crazy I went
to the dispensary on Friday that had a
big variety it all smelled pretty decent
it all had neat names then cush got
popular I went on Monday and everything
had cush at the end of the name orange
cush strawberry cush blueberry cush
none of that [ __ ] was called cush last
week it just got popular so everybody
through the name cush at the end of it
and unfortunately that does work as a
great sales tactic in the medical and
recreational cannabis market so when
you're thinking about cush you should
think fuel and skunk and pine and feet
and dankness maybe a little bit of
swampy smell I kind of think it's got
like a warm and savory smell some cush
varietals will have a chocolate or a
coffee or maybe a dirt sort of a smell
to it again this depends on which cush
you are smoking and also this will
depend on how it was grown and dried and
cured let's talk about some things that
cush is not og cush is not sweet oh gee
cush does not taste like candy oh gee
cush does not taste like berries if you
were getting product that smells like
berries or fruit it is not real OG Kush
it is possibly some outcross of a cush
you may have like maybe og cush two
jellybeans will give you some orange
flavored cush maybe og cush the
blueberry would give you a blue cush but
if it tastes too fruity it is probably
not cush dominant a good og cush is more
on that gassy fuel chemical
Pyne dank musty skunky swampy chocolate
coffee dirt sort of side of the aroma
palette it will be very easy to confuse
the aromas of a good og cush with some
of the Kim dog or diesel varietals but
the main difference is going to be that
darker pine chocolate coffee swampy sort
of a thing the chem dog is going to have
that chemical aroma it's gonna have the
skunk in the feet but it's going to be
more on the ah like a fresh can of
tennis balls or fresh tires you're also
gonna have that aroma in there so
there's a little bit of a difference
when it comes to the Kim's the diesels
and the cush is unfortunately the only
real way to smell something is to smell
something so I recommend coming to
Colorado heading to a legal state and
going to a reputable dispensary and
smelling some good Kush and smelling
some good haze and smelling some good
whatever else is available so that you
can kind of get a nice idea of what the
different options are and what different
things smell like so I think it's time
for you to start planning a road trip
this listener does ask a few more
questions to ask about haze how do we
describe the flavor of haze that is a
very unique flavor I describe haze as a
sandalwood flavor it's got a woody
flavor sometimes I think haze smells a
little bit like a gentle incense it also
sometimes has a bit of a spicy flavor to
it sometimes I describe haze as a green
apple sort of a flavor so it's
sandalwood it's incense it's a little
bit spicy and it's got a green apple
flavor it's harder for me to describe
the flavor of a haze because it haze is
not as common a true haze plant is going
to take at least 11 or 12 probably 14
weeks if you're smoking the true haze so
it's going to be very unlikely that you
run into a true haze plant you may find
some haze crosses just like I was
talking about the OG Kush but a pure
haze is going to be very unlikely things
you can look for in a haze flavor like I
mentioned earlier are that woody flavor
sort of a sandalwood flavor some Hayes's
have a spicy green apple type of a
flavor to them some of them have got a
sweet perfumey sort of aroma to them
but most of the Haze's I have
experienced have been a hybrid duper
cross with something else to reduce
flowering time because like I mentioned
earlier a good haze takes too damn long
to flower so it's very unlikely you're
going to find a pure haze unless you or
one of your very close friends are
growing it for yourselves so I know my
description of the flavor of haze was
not as nearly in depth as my flavor
description of OG but that tells you how
much haze I have been exposed to and how
much og cush I have been exposed to like
I said a moment ago in Colorado when the
medical marijuana market took off
everybody went cush crazy
since haze takes so long to grow you
don't see it here in the commercial
market the legal cannabis cultivation
market in Colorado is already trying to
find ways to pinch every penny and save
every dollar so growing at 12 to 14 week
cultivar is really not an option in a
commercial cultivation facility
alright there is more to this message it
says being a relatively young ish grower
I started smoking cannabis right after
college and then began growing a few
years back I am unfamiliar with what
these strains are supposed to smell like
I feel like this question is great for
you because you do a very good job at
describing smells and flavors and seem
to have a real gift for doing so hey
thank you for that I hope I did a good
job I apologize that I did not have a
thoroughly detailed description on haze
but I think I made up for it with my
great description on the Kush so there
is still more to this email the last
paragraph says my other question is when
should I expect to see fading in my
plants for an organic grow I'm worried
that the beginning of fade I see earlier
on in flower and then he says weeks four
and five is a nutrient deficiency I
should deal with rather than an actual
proper fade then he wraps the email up
with thanks again for everything you do
I will continue to support you via
patreon and I will continue to look
forward to every new episode you roll
out best and then they sign their name I
don't know if you want your name set on
the show so big thank you for the great
email let's talk about this fading
question the question is when should I
expect to see fading and my plants in an
organic grow because this listener is
worried that the fade is beginning to
this listener has plants that are in
weeks four or five and they are showing
a fade and they are in fear that it is a
nutrient deficiency yes that is probably
a nutrient deficiency let's talk about
what the fade is toward the end of the
flowering phase we like to flush our
plants which means we are removing all
of the built-up nutrients from the soil
the soil is mix or whatever you've got
in your container we're just feeding
water for 10 to 14 days to rinse out
that container so the plants don't have
anything to eat and then they
essentially begin to cannibalize
themselves they will use their stored
nutrients which are stored within the
plant cells it will start sucking that
up that's all of their life that are
basically working off that fat belly
then once they don't have a fat belly
they're starving they begin looking a
little bit yellow that is exactly what
we want at the last part of the
flowering phase flushing the plants
cleaning out all of those nutrients will
make that final dried and cured bud
taste delicious
so later in Flour we look to see what we
call the fade we just want to watch
those leaves slowly turn from robust
lush green leaves to kind of faded out
yellow leaves some cultivars will get
really unique colors you'll see some
purples and oranges and yellows you'll
see a nice fall display come out of your
grow room our friend here has this
happening way too early it is happening
in weeks 4 &amp; 5 which means we have got a
nutrient deficiency without more info
without some pictures or some details I
cannot identify the deficiency but if
you were at week four or five in an
organic grow and you were seeing
yellowing you were going to be
struggling until the end of this girl
you were doing what is called chasing
the plant you are never going to catch
up with that plants appetite for
nutrients you did state that the grow is
organic I don't know if you're using a
super soil or some sort of amended soil
or if you were feeding teas or maybe
even organic bottled nutrients but you
do need to increase your feedings I may
recommend some type of a foliar feed one
thing I will really suggest is don't try
to correct this issue by radically
increasing your feeds a major increase
in feed is only going to cause more
problems I would carefully diagnose the
issue with the plan
what do you feel like the plant is
deficient and is it showing a nitrogen
deficiency is it phosphorus or potassium
deficient does it need cal-mag let's
correctly identify the deficiency then
let's use the appropriate amendment to
fix that deficiency I don't know again
if you're using super soil or teas or an
amended soil I don't know what you're
using so I don't know what the solution
will be when you're using organics many
of those products will take several days
if not several weeks to break down and
become bioavailable for that plant to
uptake to help solving your problem
that's why I recommend a full-year feed
you may be able to help this plan out by
directly spraying these nutrients on to
the plant don't spray undiluted
nutrients onto the plant
if you're going to foliar feed makes up
the appropriate nutrient dilute it very
very light we don't need strong
nutrients directly applied to the plants
very low ratios then spray that onto the
plant and then watch the plant recover
over a few days do not go in there and
think my plant is nitrogen deficient I'm
gonna feed the [ __ ] out of it with a
bunch of nitrogen and fix this problem
that will not work we need to increase
the nitrogen a little bit and then feed
it frequently and pay attention
unfortunately you probably will not be
able to catch up to this plant those
leaves that look like [ __ ] will always
look like [ __ ] if they are really
terrible pull them right off they don't
have to stay there just make sure that
the new growth is healthy so carefully
identify the deficiency then let's
increase that nutrient I'm not sure how
you're going to deliver that nutrient to
the plant because I don't know your
style of grow but it definitely sounds
like you are fading too early because
you have got a deficiency if you did use
a super soil or an amended soil it needs
to be a little richer next time or you
need to veg for less time and again I
know I keep saying this but without
seeing your plants and without a little
more information it's hard for me to
diagnose exactly what you are deficient
in but it does sound like you were
experiencing a nutrient deficiency in
your garden now before somebody out
there starts typing an email let me
address what I just said I did recommend
foliar feeding these plants that are in
flower they're nutrient deficient they
are going to struggle all
way through their life if we don't take
action we are four or five weeks into
flower I am assuming these buds are not
giant and chunky because bitter nutrient
deficient I think one or two foliar
feeds at the right time will rescue
these plants and not cause too much risk
of causing a problem to the buds we
won't get any bud mold because there's
not but there and we're not springing a
pesticide so it is not going to
contaminate our final product so if
you're typing an email because I just
told somebody to follow your feet in
week four or five just it cancel it's
going to be okay as long as those buds
aren't giant and chunky and as long as
we're not applying a pesticide and as
long as we don't completely soak those
plants like a giant sponge and then
close the room up and let it get
stagnant I think that this will be a
good idea to foliar feed those plants
with the correct nutrients now I will
assume that you want to keep your garden
as organic as possible but think about
this many of the organics will take time
to become bioavailable to your plant
your plant is already struggling salt
based bottled nutrients are much more
bioavailable to your plant and will be
up taken by the plant almost immediately
upon that nutrient finding a root you
will have much more success and much
more chance of rescuing this plant if
you bite the bullet and use a
non-organic bottled nutrient to attack
your problem if you want to stay organic
disregard that advice but if you really
want to rescue these plants it may be
time to think about switching it up and
adding a non-organic ingredient to your
grow again if that's not something
you're interested in doing totally
disregard this section but it may be
your best option at this time I do
really hope you are able to rescue this
crop and I want to thank you for the
great email this was sent a while back
so it is time for an update I would love
to hear an update what did you do how
did it work and how did the garden turn
out send me another email my email
address of course is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com ladies and
gentlemen that is all I've got for this
episode I want to thank you again for
listening
if you
like this episode was educational
informative or entertaining and you
would like to make a financial
contribution to the show you can do so
by visiting www.disabilitydenials.com
for plant and try to help you solve your
problems we have built a wonderful
community at cannabis
big shout out to my buddy cue grows big
shout out to junior token and I invite
you to come join us at canna buzz it is
a free application available on your
Apple or Android mobile device simply go
to your App Store download canna buzz
open it up log in create an account then
get me a follow
I'm Irie underscore genetics and I look
forward to seeing you on cannabis if
you've got something you'd like to say
you're not into all of that social media
nonsense you can send me an email my
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
and you know that I would love to hear
from you ladies and gentlemen I'll be
back in just a few days with fresh new
content I want to give you a huge shout
out to my buddy oh gee purple thumb and
until next time take a phat dad and give
your mom a hug for me