boo what's up ladies and gentlemen it is
Thursday it is Halloween and it is time
for episode 476 of the growth from your
heart podcast this episode of the show
is brought to you by our friends at
seeds here now if you need new regular
feminized or auto flower seeds in your
garden I highly recommend seeds here now
and you can find them at
www.cdxzipstream.com the pungent aroma
from this fatso full spectrum extract
and it's obviously got me super baked so
big shout out to our friends at green
dot labs for the delicious concentrate
in this episode I'm going to read a few
emails from a couple of our friends
before we get there I'd like to do a few
shoutouts to a few people who support us
on patreon let's start off with the big
giant girl from your heart podcast shot
on thank you to our buddy James Brown
how about a big THANK YOU shout out to
JM of course a giant shout out and a
fist bump to know me by my guacamole of
course I always want to send a giant
grow from your heart a podcast shout out
to our buddy stabby mixed a verse in a
big giant grove from your heart podcast
shout out to Gabriel I also want to send
a giant thank you shout out to og purple
thumb and last but certainly not least
let's send a giant girl from your heart
podcast shout out thank you and a fist
bump to our friend zoso J big fist bump
big thank you and big shout-out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you would like to
learn how to support the show you can do
so by visiting www.azcleanelections.gov
Cocco based organic grow my media is
cocoa that is heavily amended with crab
shell bone meal green sand etc the media
gets recycled Andrea mended then put
into 20 gallon fabric pots for veg I had
an issue with a magnesium deficiency
because of the recycled cocoa I have
corrected this by rebuffering and
soaking the media with mag from
cutting-edge solutions and adding some
dolomite lime my question is about
seedlings and clones well let's back up
before we get to the question you were
using Coco you were trying to stay
organic so you are recycling your coco
than you were rebuffering it because
you've had what you assume is a
magnesium deficiency that does make
sense in Coco those nutrients aren't
going to stick around they rinse out of
your media really quickly so it is very
likely you were getting a magnesium
deficiency it sounds like you have
corrected that this is a very unique
blend I don't know anybody else that is
using purely Coco as their base and then
amending it with things like crab shell
bone meal and green sand most folks are
using some sort of a peat or a soilless
mix to add to that so I find this to be
a rather unique mix but let's focus more
on the question it says my question is
about seedlings and clones I never had
any issues before my magnesium
deficiency but while that was happening
I could not get anything to clone or
root do you think it's because of the
lower cation exchange with the stripped
cocoa now while you were experiencing
this deficiency which we will assume was
probably a calcium and magnesium
deficiency they're usually going to come
together you were having problems
getting your clones to root now I'm not
sure if you mean you were trying to root
your clones directly into the cocoa mix
because that I would never suggest
trying to route clones directly into
cocoa that's not something I would do
there are much more options that are
much more successful for taking clones
so if that is what is giving you the
problem then I would recommend moving to
either an easy cloner or if you're
insistent on keeping it organic you can
move right over to the rapid rooters or
whatever type of plugs and use the dome
set up but I would not suggest going
directly into cocoa to attempt to cut a
clone now that may not be what you mean
let's talk the other route you may be
experiencing problems when you were
cutting clones in
to rapid Reuters into a dome however
you're doing it from these plants which
experience that deficiency and that is
very likely I'm going to assume that you
were talking about the clone donor
plants were the plants that experienced
this deficiency we took clones from
those plants they were not up to their
optimal health so it is very likely that
those clones will become stagnant
and not root well for you so I am going
to hope and assume that that is the case
you had that deficiency
you took clones from a plant that was
unhealthy and those clones were like now
I came from an unhealthy environment I
don't have enough of a start to survive
this stressful period and they just
burned out and died on you that is
probably the case and it wouldn't matter
what your media was if your plants are
unhealthy and you take cuts from them
they are probably going to be struggle
but the entire time now I'm not sure if
you were trying to route into the cocoa
which again I would not suggest if that
is your issue then I would recommend
moving over to the plug or another type
of a cloning setup if you were taking
clones from those plants that experience
the deficiencies I'm going to assume
that the problem was unhealthy mother
plants and the only solution is to nurse
those plants back to health and then
take clones from them again and
hopefully the clones from the healthier
mother plants will work better for you
this person did not sign the email with
their name but they said thanks Jeff
stay lifted I promise you I will stay
lifted if you would like to send me an
update to this question maybe a part two
and let me know if you were trying to
clone off of a plant that was unhealthy
or if you were actually trying to clone
directly into the amended Coco maybe we
could sort out your question and get you
a more dialed in solution either way I
want to thank you for the great email
and let's keep moving through the pile
of great questions this next email goes
a lot like this a Rasta Jeff so first of
all I just want to thank you for the
podcast the awesome stuff you're doing
with your genetics and the education
you're spreading around the world
I'm from pretty much the middle of
nowhere Canada and it's been
surprisingly difficult to get decent
reliable advice and your show has been
one of the best places for me to go man
that is a great opening line first off
they thanked us for the podcast you were
very welcome thank you for listening
awesome stuff I'm doing with the
genetics thank you for noticing and then
the education I'm spreading around the
world that is awesome that you notice
and thank you for listening all the way
up there in the middle of nowhere Canada
and like a lot of people say it is hard
for them to get reliable information
I've mentioned before that a lot of
stuff on the internet will steer you in
the completely wrong direction and I do
understand that finding reliable
accurate information can be challenging
so I'm glad you have found the show ah
let's continue with the message it says
so far I've read a few grow books and
Bibles as well as TLO and I'm just
starting on the teeming with series you
guys make sure you check out the teeming
with series there's teeming with
microbes teeming with nutrients and
there might be another one that I'm
missing I can't think of it but let's
just keep moving aside from all of that
I tend to listen to your show in the
afternoons and the dude grow show in the
mornings while I work in the trades as a
painter big shout out to our friends at
the dude gross show if you're not
listening to the dude gross show make
sure you find them whatever you're
listening to my podcast on the dude
gross show is available there as well
just type in dude gross it will pop up
give them a subscribe let them know
Rasta Jeff sent you so our friend is
listening to this podcast in the
afternoons and the dude grows in the
morning while painting I appreciate that
you were getting a cannabis education
while you were at work you're on the
clock and you were absorbing useful
knowledge bettering yourself while
making a paycheck great way to do life
let's keep moving with the message it
says on that note between both shows
I've gotten to dispel a few bad pieces
of info I've gotten from people it seems
that in Saskatchewan our farming culture
leads people to be really stubborn and
suggestive about their [ __ ]
gardening miracle solutions yes a lot of
people do things that their uncle's
brother taught them and they don't know
why they're doing it they just heard
some [ __ ] and they do it and then I say
why do you do that and they go well my
uncle said and I go yeah but do you see
any results from it they go well my
uncle said that my brother said that
when they did it and there's no real
scientific background or no reason it's
just another step it's probably a waste
of time it may actually be causing more
problems than its helping so I do see a
lot of [ __ ] gardening miracle
solutions I'm gonna keep going with the
message it says for example last night I
popped in
your live feed on Instagram and I asked
you about dipping the root ball into
boiling water before hanging the plants
to dry you immediately said that that is
an old wives tale yeah I hear I've heard
that for a long time now that when you
cut down the plant if you dunk the root
ball in boiling water it makes more
trichomes appear on the plant but
doesn't really make any sense and even
if it did work why would you want a
bunch of unripened trichome so we've had
those trichomes on that plant for weeks
now they've been getting ripe we've been
checking on with the scope making sure
they're amber why do we want fresh
trichomes on there suddenly at the end
also [ __ ] not going to happen it
says I was also told another trick of
watering your plants with carbonated
water for extra co2 and that again is
just craziness that doesn't actually
work yes that's absolutely accurate
watering your plants with carbonated
water will not increase co2 the roots do
not want co2 the roots want oxygen the
plants want the co2 so you're doing that
all wrong these are perfect examples of
some of the things that will cause more
problems in the grow then they will
actually help so we need to be very
careful where we get our information
this message keeps going it says but
despite all of this I have managed to
keep my first grow from failing and I've
got a few BC blueberry plants rockin and
I'm just about to flip into flower I
kinda wish I had found your podcast
earlier as I would have avoided a few
mistakes
it's very ok that you have made a few
mistakes that's how you learn you know
not what not to do next time you've seen
what happens when you do that so you
know maybe I shouldn't try that again or
maybe I could try that a little
differently you learn from your mistakes
I've done a full episode about that so
it's okay to make mistakes especially at
your stage of the learning experience
you're a white belt you've got a long
way to go before you're a black belt
you're gonna make a lot more mistakes so
don't be scared now let's keep going
with the message it says anyways instead
of asking you questions about my
specific grow I wanted to pick your
brain about a few larger concepts first
of all being a lighting spectrum
experiment I heard you mention that the
Sun puts the plants to sleep because of
the spectrum it generates throughout the
day so let's say you rigged up three
lights with dimmer switches one light
with the blues
trim comes on using the dimmer as it
gets brighter the middle light with the
white spectrum turns on while the blue
spectrum dims off a red spectrum light
comes on then as the day goes on the
white light dims off leaving only the
red spectrum which again will shut off
using the dimmer toward the end of the
day I am new to your podcast but has
this been covered on an episode of yours
if not are there any advantages of
trying this now let's talk a little bit
about what this person is referring to
in a previous episode I have talked
about far red light spectrums as the Sun
sets it puts off a spectrum what is
called far read that far red light
spectrum triggers a hormone and a
protein in the plant known as
phytochrome red that hormone tells the
plant it is nighttime so even though
there is still light in the sky that
plant is being told it is sleepy time so
it shuts down and starts doing its
nighttime productivity so that hormone
in that plant triggers a protein in that
plant and that is triggered by a certain
spectrum that comes from the Sun so this
listener is asking if they can set up
different kelvin raiding lights to
attempt to simulate the rising the
midday and the sunset spectrums of the
natural Sun this is a very good idea and
this would work very well in theory the
thing we need to focus more carefully on
is specific spectrums of lighting to put
the plants to sleep I do believe we need
a specific UV spectrum of lighting that
does not come from our standard
fluorescence or our HID lights the only
people I know putting out a light with
that spectrum at this time our spectrum
King I may be wrong our friends from
Canon may have produced a light with the
same spectrum there may be other brands
out there putting out the light with the
far red feature but to the best of my
knowledge at this time spectrum King is
the only brand offering that light again
I'm saying I may be wrong and by the
time this episode comes out or by the
time you listen to this episode there
could be 5 10 or 20 new brands that have
been launched so your idea would work
in theory however we need to dial in the
specific spectrums I don't think that
your basic red uh t5 light or t8 light
or any type of HID light is going to
produce that red spectrum so unless you
dial in the perfect spectrum for that
far red lighting to trigger that
phytochrome red response I think that
would probably be possibly more
stressful to the plant than it would be
beneficial to change that light spectrum
throughout the day like that a more
common practice is to use a bluer bulb
during the veg phase because we want the
plants to stay short and stocky and then
toward the flowering phase we usually
tend to move toward the redder bulbs
because that encourages fatter bud
growth in a lot of cases now we're
seeing mixed spectrums we're seeing high
pressure sodium bulbs in flower rooms
with a few metal halide bulbs in flower
rooms just to add to the spectrum and
I'm also seeing people put ceramic metal
halides in rooms I'm also seeing LEDs
and then I'm seeing mixtures and
combinations of all of the above
sometimes I feel like these combos don't
work because of the patterns in which
the lights are laid sometimes I feel
like it's a bit overkill but sometimes I
do see really great results from rooms
that are thought out with mixed
spectrums so your idea is great in
theory but if you are not dialing in the
exact red light spectrum it is not worth
the energy because it is not going to
trigger the phytochrome red response you
are looking for now let's keep moving
there is more to this email it goes on
to say now lastly and I'm sorry I know
this is getting long-winded but because
of my issues with getting bad info in my
area my plants were getting sick and I
was almost ready to quit then I was on
the road with my band and I tried to
purchase some legal cannabis from a
company he names the company here but
I'm going to leave their name out I
tried to purchase legal cannabis from a
company and it was [ __ ] atrocious and
then he also says it happened to be one
of my favorite strains which was Sour
tangi so that sucks when you go to the
store and he try to buy your favorite
strain and it is atrocious is the word
this person used so they continue it
says all day I was thinking how I can
get involved and
this then suddenly an opportunity to
work at a grouse nor presented itself
isn't it great how life just seems to
open doors for you like that the message
keeps going it says I've heard you say
but you get out of this plant what you
put into it and I know that that is
absolutely true so my question to you is
what would you like to see in a grouse
store or even a grouse store employee
and what kind of practices do you think
should be promoted I'm not looking for
product recommendations or anything I'm
just wondering if you were to go into a
grouse store what would really impress
you that is a great question he wraps it
up by saying being Canadian I will
apologize again for the [ __ ] novel of
an email here hey it's a great email
don't apologize I love all the
information I'm able to share and that
comes from good questions so it also
says hearing you talk on your show and
then finding out you're also a drummer I
just had to get these couple of things
out mostly just a big THANK YOU but also
to see your thoughts on these things
then they say thanks again for
everything and they signed their name I
don't know if they want their name set
on the show so big thank you to my new
Canadian drummer friend who has a new
job at a grouse store who wants to know
what do I find valuable in a grouse
store or a grouse store employee that's
a very good question
oftentimes when I go to the grouse store
I run into the same exact problems I run
into when I go to the music store I am a
very experienced and confident grower
and I'm a very experienced and confident
drummer when I go to the store to update
or replace my gear I know what I want
I've done some shopping I've gone on the
internet I have used equipment I've
shopped around I know what I want when I
walk in there and I say hey I would like
to buy product f6 355 and the person at
the counter looks at you with an
attitude because you like f6 355 that
brand sucks I like this brand and
depending on where you are you get a
different attitude at the grocer they go
bruh I use this and my growth comes out
way better and if you're a guitar centre
they [ __ ] twirl their hair they go
brah I play these and they sound way
better like don't be that guy if
somebody goes in there and they know
what they want confidently get it off of
the shelf and sell them extra
to go with it don't tell them their
product sucks ever if somebody walks in
and wants to buy something and they have
got cash you take their [ __ ] cash and
give them the product they asked for
don't ever belittle your customers your
customers are paying your rent
appreciate them so if somebody's buying
a product you do not approve of if you
think you can help somebody increase the
potential of their grow let them
purchase the product that they choose to
buy then the next time you see them say
hey I saw you were buying Fox farms and
we all know Fox farms is like
entry-level gross stuff say there's this
new company and they offer this and
we're going to have a sale on this
product next month I thought you may be
interested tell them why it would be a
step up from whatever they're using
don't belittle their [ __ ] let them buy
what they want to buy then next time
suggest the step up don't belittle
encourage growth so that's probably the
first most important piece of advice
that comes to my mind don't belittle me
because if the products I want to buy
and don't tell me how your product is
better and don't just try to put
yourself on me while I'm shopping I'm
not there for you I'm there for me to
buy [ __ ] for my grow so make me feel
like I'm the important one there make
your customer feel like the important
one there then get a very good
cultivation knowledge and have a good
glossary of terms understand the proper
words to use understand the parts of the
plan to understand the nutrients
understand the equipment understand what
you're selling don't try to sell people
[ __ ] just to make Commission sell them
what you think they will need and they
will come back and buy more [ __ ] from
you and you will still make your
Commission don't force-feed anybody any
products now a lot of what I'm telling
you I have learned in basic sales
schools a lot of time learn your
products and always have a good better
and best recommendation if I walk in and
I say hey I need something to do this
say oh here's the section where we keep
that here's one that you can get here's
the middle priced one this one's the
best then back up let me make my
decision don't force-feed me a product
if you see that I'm going for the one in
the middle and I may need something to
go with that be a good sales guy have my
back and go oh if you're gonna get that
you may also want this to go with it
when I get to the register that's when
you've got the opportunity to upsell me
do I have personal protective equipment
do I have gloves
do I have goggles do I have a facemask
there's always [ __ ] to upsell but make
sure you get what I need before you
upsell me on some [ __ ] don't just try to
get money out of my pocket without
sending me out of there happy if you
send me out of the grocery with a smile
I'll spend all my money but if you
bother me and you upset my shopping
experience I won't give you any of my
money I'll go somewhere where they do it
correctly so that is probably some of
the best advice I can give you that is
just basic sales school stuff be
friendly be knowledgeable don't be a
[ __ ] don't be in there to steal
money from people don't be in there to
get rich be there to help people out
don't pitch products because a company
told you to pitch a product pitch a
product because you believe in it but if
somebody doesn't want that have another
solution another option for them and
here's another great piece of advice
don't ever be afraid to say I don't know
if somebody comes in and they're trying
to tell you they've got a problem or ask
you for some sort of advice and you
don't have a solution just say wow I
don't know because if you tell me that I
have got this problem and I buy a bunch
of [ __ ] and try to go salute solve that
problem with your solution and all it
does is backtrack me guess who I'm never
trusting again guess where I'm never
gonna shop again that's you buddy
so give solid advice but don't be afraid
to say I don't know other than that bro
follow basic sales class techniques
approach position engage follow-through
it's pretty much all you got to do man
make the sale happen and it will sell
itself be friendly be a good person and
the customers will keep coming on back
so I want to thank you again for the
great email you're a drummer and you
said you were on tour so that means that
you've probably got some music you could
send to me and I can play that on the
show and we can get you some exposure so
I look forward to getting an mp3 from
you in the very near future all right
ladies and gentlemen boys and girls
pimps and hos smokers and growers I want
to thank everybody for listening to this
spooky Halloween edition of The Grove
from your heart podcast if you feel like
this episode was educational informative
or entertaining and you'd like to make a
financial contribution to the show again
you can do so by visiting www.hp.com
slash grow from your heart all of the
information you need to sign up will
right there on the screen I would also
appreciate it if you subscribe to my
youtube channel just go to youtube
that subscribe button like some videos
leave some comments let me know what you
think of the show you know I love that
type of listener interaction I would
also appreciate it if you stalk me on
cannabis cannabis is a new social media
application it is free it is available
on your Android or Apple mobile device
go to your App Store download cannabis
create yourself an account sign in give
me a follow I'm Irie underscore genetics
on cannabis
check out the new cannabis friendly
social media application if you've got
something you'd like to say or if you've
got a cannabis cultivation or cannabis
culture question you can send me an
email again my email address is grow
from your heart at hotmail.com
you know I would love to hear from you
ladies and gentlemen that is all I've
got for you for this Thursday episode I
hope everybody out there is staying warm
stand safe I wanna give a giant shout
out to my buddy junior token and until
next time take a phat dab and give your
mom a hug for me
[Music]
and something wicked this way wars so
they say
all about it USA Today a stepped-up
urine testing to make it go a the unis
are only
[Music]