what's up cannabis community it is time
for episode 477 of the growth from your
heart podcast this episode of the show
is brought to you by our friends at
seeds here now if you need new regular
feminized or Auto flower seeds in your
garden I highly recommend seeds here now
and you can find them at
www.cdxzipstream.com ah then once that
settles down that is when that sour
aroma kicks in then when I took a DAB
the first thing I noticed was that gassy
pungent flavor hit my tongue then on the
exhale it got earthy and then as it
settles down that gassy sourness skunk
enos kind of settles on the tongue and
it gives me a really delicious kind of
aftertaste sort of a thick layer of
cottonmouth that I really enjoy I've
really been enjoying this trend in the
gassy garlicky savory sort of flavors in
the concentrates or at least in my area
that seems to be a trend in the
concentrates and I am really enjoying
that gassy garlicky sort of a trend the
garlic banger the hemdale acam the fat
so the GMO just about anything with that
garlicky flavor to it
of course the Mac has got that pungent
aroma to it anything on that end of the
spectrum has been making me really happy
lately so big shout out to our friends
at green dot labs for the delicious kim
de la chem s1 live batter all right in
this episode i'm going to read a couple
of listener emails before we get there
you know that i would like to do some
shout outs to a few of our friends from
patreon let's start off with the big
giant grow from your heart podcast
shout out and a thank you to my friend
Glenn jeroni how about a big giant grow
from your heart a podcast shout out and
a thank you to James Brown how about a
big THANK YOU and a shout out and a fist
bump to Brett G of course a big giant
thank you shout out to Jacob W I want to
send a giant handshake a girl from your
heart fist bump and a thank you to keith
k of course I want to send a giant grow
from your heart podcast thank you a
shout out a fist bump and a high-five to
fat rabbit as always a giant thank you
shoutout to todd kay and last but
certainly not least I want to send a
giant grow from your heart podcast shout
out a high-five and a thank you to my
friend Blackbird 76 I want to thank each
and every one of you for the continued
patreon support and if anybody out there
would like to learn how to support the
show on patreon you can do so by
visiting www.disabilitydenials.com
hey that's a great compliment right
there I'm glad that you appreciate the
audio quality because I do put a little
bit of work into that I've got a lot of
toys making me sound like a pro I'm glad
that you enjoyed the content because
that is all my brain coming out goes
onto paper just a little bit very
minimal notes and then I just talk and
put it out there so I'm glad you're
enjoying the content and my talking
style that's just me being me I try to
speak clearly and try to speak in a way
that I think most people who speak
English would be able to understand and
comprehend what I'm saying so thank you
for that those are all great compliments
we should keep moving it goes on to say
you should definitely be proud of the
work you're doing here thank you I
appreciate that the message continues it
says I tried a few other shows and found
that yours has just the right amount of
[ __ ] bombs and given that I'm a huge
potty mouth
the growth from your heart podcast is
the show for me that is a very
interesting compliment and a very
interesting statement I'm glad that I'm
dropping just the
right amount of f-bombs for you I try
not to be a potty mouth but I do try to
be genuine and be myself and I say [ __ ]
sometimes so I do try to find that line
between being professional but also
being genuinely myself this is my show I
can say whatever I want to say and I
feel like censoring myself too much
makes me sound a little bit fake and
then when you do meet me and we hang out
and I smell your weed I'm gonna go that
[ __ ] smells [ __ ] good and you're
gonna look at me like wow I've never
heard you use profanity before and I'm
blown away by it now you already know
that that's who I am it's not surprising
people who have been listening to the
show for a long time may remember that
in the beginning I tried to do a swear
jar just the old-fashioned every time
you say the f-word you got to put a
dollar in the swear jar and then I did
that and eventually I gave that money to
a patient who needed some assistance
once I gave that money to somebody I
decided that was my final payment and I
was allowed to say whatever I wanted on
my show because there is no need to
censor me from being myself speaking of
being myself I am stoned and way off
track so let's get back on track here
with this email it goes like this
also I am the senior optical technician
for my dad's optical repair business
basically I repair binoculars mostly
antiques our shop is tucked into the
back of my dad's property we get the
majority of our business shipped to us
so we don't get many customers walking
in we listen to the G fyh podcast on the
shop stereo for hours on end and we have
gone as far as the low 200s in your
episode feed on iTunes wow that's
amazing you're listening to the old
stuff you may actually stumble across
that old swear jar episode but I think
that's awesome that you guys are
listening to my show while you were
working all day I hope you're exposing
some other employees to not only my
f-bombs but also to the grow knowledge
and maybe just opening up their minds to
cannabis in general maybe there's
somebody in the crew who wasn't a big
fan of cannabis and now you've
accidentally turned them into an
activist I'm stoned and rambling let's
keep moving with this email it goes on
to say I am planning a grow I'm growing
for myself my dad and my mom and we are
in Oklahoma so we were enjoying our new
found freedom yeah big shout out to all
of our friends down
in Oklahoma I've got quite a few friends
who have left Colorado to head down to
Oklahoma to help get started down there
and I've also made a lot of new friends
who are in Oklahoma who are new to the
cannabis industry who are getting
started in the business so big shout out
to everybody down there in Oklahoma
making the new medical marijuana
movement happen let's keep moving with
this email because I am obviously stoned
and rambley our friend Eric here says I
have been studying a lot I've been
reading books taking notes and
formulating my plan based on my grouse
style I like that that sounds very
enthusiastic it goes on to say your show
plays a huge part in that I can imagine
that your grow is going to look a little
bit like my grow or at least the version
of my grow which you have painted in
your head and I am really excited about
that for you it keeps going and it says
basically I'm doing everything the way
you'd say to do it and referencing my
literature for finer details and
specific information I'm building a grow
room in my garage
it measures 4.5 feet by 8 feet that has
an additional 2x3 closet that will house
a mother clones and seedlings alright it
sounds like we have a decent sized
flower room we've got a decent sized mom
and clone area it sounds like you're
really off to a good start you're
reading books
you're listening to podcasts and you
were formulating a plan it looks like
you've got a nice floor plan made let's
keep moving it goes on to say I have a
lot of plans to optimize this grow space
but for now I need to finish the main
construction to get growing eventually
I'll build a nice big cabinet with an
automated system and all of that alright
I like that you're eager to get started
you just want to get things rolling so
you can get growing but my question is
why don't you just do it right the first
time and build that big grow space that
you dream of
since you're building it in the garage
it's going to cost you time and money
anyway why not just go big or go home on
that first build instead of having to
redo it all over again I don't know your
situation but that would be my first
question is why aren't we just doing it
the way we want to do it the first time
I don't want to do [ __ ] twice we got to
do the work we got to spend the money
let's just do it one time but I again I
don't know your situation maybe you
don't have that space available maybe
you don't have the budget maybe you
don't have the time
I don't know your situation but my first
question is why are we gonna build it
twice let's keep moving with the message
it says so for now the actual gross
space inside the grow room for veg and
flour will be in a 2 by 4 grow tent I
really want to control the environment
as best as possible and I'm working with
limited floor space alright so for the
time being we are working with very
limited floor space so we are going to
grow in a 2x4 grow tin it sounds like
and one of the main goals is to really
control the environment as best as
possible that won't be too hard in such
a small environment if that tent is in a
larger room or a room which we can
ventilate so it goes on to say I will be
growing in a soilless mix using Fox
farms ocean forest and five gallon air
pots under an LED light that sounds like
a great setup that will work well for
you I plan on using only a few nutrients
only what's needed the small amount of
nutrients that I do use will be what you
have recommended you can grow a very
successful crop with very minimal
nutrients if you pay attention to what
you're doing and I'm sure you'll be
excited to hear that I am making
progress on the full mix episode I'm not
ready to record that yet I'm trying to
make sure that I get it right because
you guys are going to rely on that mix I
don't want to miss a single detail so
I'm working that very heavily before I
press record but I'm working on a full
mix episode so you can know what I feed
my plants every single week so look
forward to that but let's keep moving on
this email for now it says I will be
growing your arise I plan on growing the
[ __ ] out of a rise before moving on to
any other strains that is a very good
idea pop a pack of arise seeds
find a couple of keepers that you enjoy
growing row those keepers a couple of
times until you narrow it down to your
favorite then build a solid relationship
with that one cultivar and really learn
how to dial in that one plant to reach
its full potential that is a great
strategy it goes on to say I bought your
seeds on this past 4/20 from the hell a
dank seed company so big shout out to my
friends at the hell a dank seed company
you can find them at dank seed dot store
make sure you check them out if you need
new seeds so here is where we get to the
question part of the podcast that says I
have listened to your episode
honor rise and I took notes on it as
well and as I am writing the rough draft
for the veg phase of my plan these
questions came up so our friend here is
growing my strain arise I've done a full
Episode on the arise strain they're
listening they're taking notes they are
planning their grow they're planning so
far that they are writing down notes for
the veg phase and they have come up with
some questions let's get to the first
question the first question about arise
is does arise like to be scrog and by
ask raga mean a screen of green which is
when you put up a trellis net just above
your canopy and instead of letting that
plant grow straight up you use the net
to bend it over and make it grow
horizontally and you can maximize your
grow space instead of getting that plant
straight up into the light you can bend
the plant over and it will grow sideways
for a little bit then it will start to
grow back up as it starts to grow
straight up again you can grab that
growth and tuck it under the next square
in your trellis then you can fill that
space and have the entire trellis filled
with branching when you flip it into
flower you will fill your entire grow
area with buds so the question here is
does arise like to be scrubbed and the
answer is yes a rise takes very well to
scrog arise takes very well to popping
and twisting and topping and all sorts
of manipulation and training and I will
actually recommend that you do two maybe
three layers of trellis netting for your
arise plants I generally use the first
net as a spreader my plant is growing up
and it's getting tall right so I use
that first net to spread it out I want
one branch through each square of my
trellis net so I spread out the plant a
little bit the second one is to work it
to control the height that's when I
start bending the plant down so it
doesn't get too tall that third one is
to support those giant buds that are
gonna start developing around week four
five six and seven eight nine you may
need to consider adding another trellis
depending on how rapidly your buds are
growing this grow in question is
happening in a grow tent with an LED
light so you may not need that first
trellis net to work as a spreader as
much you may be able to use that one as
your canopy control net you'll just be
able to
the plants right into that one you won't
need that firstnet as a spreader because
you don't have as many plants you don't
have as much growth you don't have the
plants pressed together as closely as I
do in a commercial environment in a
commercial environment I'm using
double-ended Gavita lighting I'm using
three gallon pots I'm getting an auto
watering system and I vegetable to even
put in your small grow tent so I do
require at least two sometimes three
sometimes four layers of trellis netting
in a commercial environment so the short
answer is yes a rise loves to be
scrubbed the next question is what is
her favorite light cycle eighteen on six
off or sixteen on eight off that is a
very good question I would suggest to
the 18 on and six off but if you want to
get experimental I would almost suggest
a twenty hours on and four hours off
light cycle with arise of course you
have to pay attention to your plant to
dial this in but I have noticed that a
rise likes a lot of light she has got
some very tropical lineage to her she's
got a hawaiian sativa and an island
sweet skunk in her so that means that
she has got some tropical lineage which
means she probably was getting a lot of
light and long day time periods
somewhere down the line in her gene pool
so I assume that several of her parents
are used to getting a long daytime cycle
so a rise seems to want a lot of light
now pay attention to your leaves plants
have what is called the daily light
integral once they've had enough light
they'll start shutting down they will
take a nap
you can see this at the end of the light
cycle because the leaves just begin to
droop it looks like there's something
wrong with the plants there's absolutely
nothing wrong they've got enough light
for the day and they just said that's it
sweet dreams and they just took a little
nap they just tip their hat over their
eyes put their feet up and leaned back
and took a little sleeper for a minute
so if you've got the opportunity to run
20 hours on and four hours off I would
do that and pay attention to the plants
then if you see some of the plants
starting to droop around 16 17 18 hours
in then you can start adjusting your
timer accordingly but
go less than 18 on and six off because
of those tropical genetics that I spoke
of earlier if you give a rise to little
light and she gets rootbound she will
decide to flower on you if a rise
becomes rootbound
it will try to flower so make sure you
keep a rise in the appropriate sized pot
and make sure to give her plenty of
light so I would recommend starting with
a twenty on and four off and paying
attention to what happens to the plants
if they start looking like they are
drooping late into the veg cycle reduce
it by an hour reduce it by two hours but
don't go less than 18 on and six hours
off because your plants may try to
flower on you now one of the big
advantages of running your lights for 20
on and 4 off is that when you do click
that timer to 1212
those are rise plants are really going
to trigger into flower quite quickly
because you have just made a drastic
change in the light cycle they will have
no question that it is time to kick in
to flower gear now if you were unable or
uncomfortable with running a 20-hour on
and four hour off light cycle 18 and 6
will work for your arise plants but I've
been working with this strain for a very
long time and I know that there are many
phenotypes that would prefer a longer
day time veg cycle alright Eric I hope I
helped you plan your grow and plan your
veg cycle a little more closely if
you've got any more questions please
send me an email
you obviously know the email address it
is grow from your heart at hotmail.com I
look forward to hearing from you he
wraps up the message by saying thank you
for your time we here at Siddharth
optical repair love it when you ramble
sincerely Erik sue Darth and then the ad
it is cannibalization a buzz handle is
Darth light bender so make sure you go
follow Darth light bender on cannabis
Hey Dude once again thank you for the
great email I'm going to keep moving
right through the pile of emails this
next message goes just like this it says
hey Rasta Jeff I've been emailing
intermittently with you and I just
wanted to let you know I am starting to
work with the rise as one of my long
term
project strains that's really great
we've got two people talking about a
rise in this episode let's keep moving
with the message it says I have a diner
II started at Gro Diaries calm under the
moniker of I'm not sure if they want me
to say their name so I'm going to skip
that they go on to say I am only in the
first week as of now but feel free to
check it out from time to time and if
you guys aren't aware Gro Diaries calm
is a great website and it's exactly what
it sounds like it is a very detailed
grow diary one of the things I really
like about Gro Diaries calm is that I
can click on IRA genetics and it shows
me everybody who is growing or has grown
and I read genetics trained and made a
diary on the website and so I can just
scroll through and I can see our new
friend here since he just gave me his
name I can see that he pops up there he
is I can click on his diary and see his
photos of arise and any details or
information that he has typed in to
share with us will be easily accessible
for me to look at and then I can say oh
he's feeding at bat and that's what it's
doing cool and I can share that kind of
info with other people who may want to
grow that strain or you can go there
yourself and just take a look at it if
you're that type of an internet cruiser
our buddy Grimble the druid has a great
grow diary is grown a lot of I read
genetics and some other stuff and he
posts a lot of it to grow Diaries calm
so go check him out
but I'm stoned and rambley so let's get
back on track there is more it says I am
sure you have some better [ __ ] to do
than BS with me but any advice along the
way would not be refused alright my
first piece of advice would be to check
out episode number 329 of the growth
from your heart podcast I did an entire
episode about arise I'm going to assume
you have already heard that but if not
go check out number 329 I talked in
depth about the arise strain on episode
329 so check that out and then I'm sure
you just heard the two little add-ons I
did I talked about scrog arise and then
we just talked about timing for a rise
in veg so if you've got any more
questions please send me an email and I
will do my best to get those on the show
there is more to this message and it
says my goal in all of this is to be a
solid home
with aspirations of doing something
bigger in the cannabis revolution we are
currently in I am deep in prohibition
with no signs of my state coming out
soon but I love this hobby and this
plant if you're in prohibition land and
you would like some help working towards
legalization I would recommend finding
your local normal chapter normal is the
National Organization for the Reform of
Marijuana Laws and they will be able to
point you in the right direction to get
you in cannabis activism so you said
that your main goal is to become a what
is the word you used a solid home grower
and you've got aspirations of doing
something bigger with the cannabis
revolution so if you'd like to be part
of that revolution now is the time to
join the battle I recommend you find
your local normal chapter find your
local cannabis activism chapter whoever
it is wherever it is become involved
with them however you can and learn how
to make cannabis legal in your area so
you can be a bigger part of the cannabis
revolution they wrap up the message with
maybe one day I will be consistent
enough to be a test grower for you and
then they sign it with their name and
I'm not sure if they want their name
said on the show so so I won't reveal
their identity but I will say thank you
for the great message thank you for
sharing your grow of a rise on grow
Diaries calm I will definitely save that
in my favorites so I can go check that
out at least once a week and see what
your progress looks like and hopefully
one day you will be able to test some
brand new seeds for me so again thank
you for the great message and I look
forward to seeing your diary on grow
Diaries calm alright I've got one more
email for this episode the last email
for today's episode goes just like this
hey Rasta Jeff first off man I just want
to say thank you for all you do for the
cannabis community a thank you for the
recognition and you were very welcome
the message goes on to say my name is
Kodiak from Oklahoma and I admittedly am
new to finding your podcast but I can't
get enough of it well I'm glad you found
me welcome to the show the message goes
on to say your expert insight is
invaluable and exactly what I need I am
a longtime smoker but I am a toe
newbee to growing I am nearing the end
of my first grow and I've been fairly
pleased with my first attempt I credit
your knowledge for getting me through my
first grow I grow for myself so my
growing goal is just to grow bomb-ass
weed potency is what I want so I do have
a question for you alright so we've got
a good foundation here we've got a new
friend named Kodiak from Oklahoma they
are a new grower they are nearing the
end of their first grow they are fairly
pleased with the first grow they're
growing for themselves
and their main goal is potent bomb-ass
weed so they've got a question the
question goes like this something I have
found to be a little overwhelming as a
new grower is definitely nutrients and
additives alike this first go-around I
used Fox Farm ocean forest soil and Fox
farm bottled nutrients I have added
nothing else I use a 4 by 4 by 8 grow 10
my question is what would you recommend
for a small-time grower to use nutrient
wise going forward also bro I totally
imagine you as a hella busy dude and I
won't sweat in the slightest if you
don't respond here it's all love I just
figured I couldn't hurt to ask for
advice from the best I'm sending good
vibes to you they wrap it up with take
it easy and happy growing yeah I am a
busy dude but I've got a podcast and I
love helping people with my podcast so
you are in luck let's talk a little bit
about your question you started growing
with the Fox farms ocean forest soil
that is an acceptable soil not the most
expensive not the cheapest not the best
not the worst that is an acceptable
quality soilless mix nothing wrong with
that then you use the Fox Farms bottled
nutrients probably the trio you didn't
say exactly what you bought but you are
asking what you can use nutrient wise to
go forward you have got a lot of options
fortunately I am writing an episode all
about my own personal feed mix that will
take a couple of more weeks before I get
it out but it is coming in the meantime
let's talk about a couple of things we
can add
to this Fox farms mix I'm going to
assume you are using the trio they've
got a basic trio that they sell every
gross nor has it I think a lot of the
hardware stores with a garden center
actually offer Fox farms products at
this time so it is very available there
is nothing wrong with the Fox Farms
lineup and I have seen very high quality
product come from those nutrients but I
do feel like it is a very entry-level
product now since you're a new grower
that is perfect for you Fox farms
nutrients are gentle enough that if you
do make a small mistake in your feeding
you will not destroy a crop with one
simple mistake they're also very
affordable and it is very easy to mix
when you've only got three maybe four or
five bottles to deal with I really feel
like there is nothing wrong with that
product I just feel that there are
better options once you become a better
grower and you understand what to watch
for in the plants so for this situation
I am going to assume that you are using
the Fox farms trio as your base and that
is the grow big the tiger bloom and what
is the other one there it's the big
bloom I believe is what that's called
and they also offer three powdered
nutrients Open Sesame
chi-ching and what's the name of that
third one beastie blooms I used Fox
farms a really long time ago that might
have been the first or second product
that I attempted to use and I just was
not satisfied with it so I moved on but
let's just assume you were using the
trio to start with perhaps you've got
the three powders maybe you've got some
bush doctor but let's talk about a
couple of things you can add to your
nutrient recipe to enhance your next
crop I always recommend some sort of
microbes in your feeding regimen there
are many options when it comes to
microbes microbe products can be very
affordable and microbe products can also
be astronomically expensive before you
select any product for your grow do a
little bit of research on the product
itself find what it is made from find
out who is making it and find out how
you want to spend your dollars then find
a product that fits your price range and
add that to your mix
you do not have to use the most
expensive micro products you can find if
you can't afford something really
expensive
use the microbes you can afford because
some microbes are way better than no
microbes adding beneficial microbes to
your nutrient mix will be beneficial in
many ways the first way is that it will
simply increase root mass development
you will grow stronger fatter thicker
healthier roots in less time
fatter roots bigger fruits more healthy
roots more healthy plants adding
microbes to our nutrient regimen will
also help keep our plants pathogen free
if we have already developed colonies of
beneficial fungus in our root zone there
won't be room for pathogens if anything
else tries to come in those microbes go
nope this is our turf bro you're not
allowed here so I would always recommend
some sort of a microbe product now I
keep saying that there are many microbe
products available at many different
price points let me recommend three of
my favourite microbes to you I will
recommend recharge I will recommend plus
life and I will recommend mammoth peat
now those are three equal but very
different microbe products and they will
all fall at very different price points
you can use any microbe product
individually or you can use most of them
mixed together but I definitely
recommend you use at least one microbe
product at least once a week in your
nutrient mix so the first thing I would
add is a quality microbe product then
I've got a few other recommendations
that I would consider adding to that Fox
farms lineup I would add a product
called shine to my lineup
I think shine is a great product it is
made by the folks that make veg bloom it
is part of the veg bloom line-up it is
available from hydroponic Research you
can find them at hydroponic - research
com
now let's talk about why I recommend
shine
I think shine adds to my bud density
I think shine adds to my trichome
density I think shine adds to my aroma
and flavor and I also think that if I
use shine early in the flowering phase
it slows down part of my early stretch
so I would add shine to my mix and you
will see an increase in bud density and
trichome density and possibly an
increase in aromas and flavors so now
we've got microbes making things work a
little more quickly in the root zone now
we've got some shine beefing up the buds
give any more trichomes something else I
would add would be some fulvic acid and
I would recommend Ruby from our friends
at new millennium and I would use five
milliliters of Ruby for every gallon of
nutrient solution you mix up every time
you feed those plants now why do I
suggest fulvic acid we are feeding our
plants high-quality expensive nutrients
fulvic acid essentially makes those
nutrients more available and more
absorbable by our plants that is the
short explanation it is sort of like
that gas additive that they sell for
your car they say yeah that gas works
great in your car it makes the car go
vroom vroom add a little bit of this
[ __ ] to the gas and the car will go
broom broom broom broom so that's
basically what fulvic acid does it gives
you just a few more rpms a couple more
horsepower a little bit more turbo
charge it makes all of those expensive
nutrients we are feeding to the plant
more absorbable more available to our
plane so I would suggest or recommend
adding some fulvic acid to your feeding
regimen my favorite fulvic acid product
is again Ruby from new millennium and I
use Ruby at five milliliters per gallon
of everything I mix up if i mix
nutrients i put five milliliters of Ruby
in every gallon every time I feed now at
this point with this many new additives
we have kind of turbocharged our plants
we need to pay attention to
cal-mag are you getting a cal mag
deficiency if you don't have a cal mag
product this may be the time to consider
adding cal mag to your lineup do you
know what a cal mag deficiency looks
like because we are currently not adding
any calcium or magnesium supplements to
these plants with this
a nutrient feed so with these extra
additives we just put in the mix we may
need to watch for a cal-mag deficiency
so before we start boosting up our
nutrients I recommend you find the chart
on the internet that shows the cannabis
leaf and all of the nutrient symptoms of
deficiencies and toxicities it will show
you what cannabis li and it will say
nitrogen deficiency or toxicity calcium
toxicity or deficiency and it will show
you what they look like get a good idea
of what the cal-mag deficiency looks
like get a good idea of what the
nitrogen deficiency looks like get a
good idea of what phosphorus and
potassium deficiencies look like that
way when those things come up we know
how to adjust but right now we're
focusing on cal-mag learn what a cal-mag
deficiency looks like and think about if
it's time to start adding cal-mag to
your nutrient regimen so we have added
some microbes we've added some shine we
put some fulvic acid in there we may
need some cal-mag now that we're going
so hard with these plants were
turbocharging them what can we possibly
do next
at this point I would recommend a
product called winter frost from new
millennium winter frost is used right at
the end of the flowering phase just
before a flush I feel like if you use
winter frost and shine together you will
see tremendous results now you have to
be careful not to burn your plants when
you are adding this many additives to
your recipe I recommend that you start
slowly the first time you introduce
winter frost to your feed mix maybe go
half strength and see what it does does
it burn the plants did you notice
anything if it didn't have any adverse
effects to the plants increase the
dosage on the next feed make sure you
keep notes of what you are feeding your
plants so that you know how much you fed
it and how the plant responded so start
lightly maybe a quarter maybe 50% of the
recommended dosage feed it that see how
the plant responds next time feed it
more if you want to feed it less if you
need to but don't go full strength right
away when you are adding this many
additives to your nutrient solution now
I've still got a couple of things I'd
like to recommend so let
keep moving at this point I may suggest
adding some enzymes to your nutrient mix
enzymes work with the microbes enzymes
work with the folding acid and they help
to make all of the nutrients more
available to the plants enzymes will
also work with the microbes and the
folic acid to keep the plants pathogen
free so I would recommend adding an
enzymatic product to your nutrient mix
now the next product is just something
that I personally add to my personal
grows because I believe it adds aroma
and flavor I really think this product
brings out the skunky funky dirty cushy
aromas and the product I am talking
about is called liquid karma liquid
karma is from botanic air it is very
affordable it is more of a supplement
but it is a product that I add for aroma
and flavor and possibly a little bit of
bud density I don't know if I'm crazy I
don't know if I'm making it up it could
possibly be a placebo effect but I do
feel then when I use liquid karma that
my buds smell just a little bit stickier
than when I don't use it so that is the
last specific product I'm going to
recommend you may also want to add a
bloom booster to your regimen but I
don't have a specific bloom booster
recommendation there are countless
options available for bloom boosters
again stay tuned to the show because in
the very near future I am going to do a
very detailed episode possibly two
episodes on my very specific nutrient
recipe and how I mix it so let's recap i
think i said i would add microbes
because microbes will make the roots
grow faster and keep pathogens away then
i would add some shine because shine is
going to give us more trichomes and more
bud density and who doesn't like denser
trichome covered buds then i would add
some fulvic acid to make all of those
nutrients better available to the plants
at this point we may need some cal-mag
then i got a little bit random and i
went with some winter frost some liquid
karma some enzymes and possibly a bloom
booster so I hope I have opened
your mind giving you a few options of
things you can add to your Fox Farms
lineup again any of those products will
be beneficial a couple of them in
conjunction with each other will really
do a great job I would always recommend
some fulvic acid because you're already
paying for the nutrients why not add
that fulvic acid to actually make all of
the nutrients available to the plants
then once we've got the basic nutrition
covered that's when we want to start
adding things to give us beefier bulkier
plants with more stank and more resin
that's when we move in to the products
like shine the winter frost and then
eventually we end with bloom boosters so
I hope I have inspired you I hope I did
not overwhelm you and if you want to
learn more about nutrients and you want
to learn exactly what I am mixing stay
tuned because I like to keep teasing it
but in a few episodes I'm going to put
out a very detailed on exactly what I
feed and how I feed my plants I want to
thank my new friend Kodiak in Oklahoma
for the great email if anybody else out
there has a cannabis cultivation or a
cannabis culture question I would love
to hear from you my email address is
grow from your heart at hotmail.com
ladies and gentlemen that is all I've
got for this episode of the grow from
your heart podcast I want to thank you
again for listening if you feel like
this episode was educational informative
or entertaining and you'd like to make a
financial contribution to the show you
can do so by visiting
www.disabilitydenials.com for
I love to hear from you ladies and
gentlemen boys and girls that is all I
have got for this episode I'll be back
in just a few days with fresh new
content I want to give a giant shout out
to my buddy Mason Pitts and until next
time and give your mom a hug
[Music]
you used to teach at my high school it
got quiet
[Music]
yeah
they were the topic that made erupto
great went to the picture to take that
songs and I said it's not too late when
we asked them about their car
[Music]