here we go Clint you ready I am ready
Jeff welcome back podcast world at it's
time for episode 479 of the Grove from
your heart podcast to this episode of
the show is brought to you by our
friends at seeds here now if you need
new regular feminized or Auto flower
seeds in your garden I highly recommend
seeds here now and you can find them at
www.cpa.psu.edu or there I sure AM what
you smoking bra tonight I actually got
my hands on some well the the strain I
got told it was ak-47 some classics yeah
that's what I got told is that what I
took a puff off of yesterday yes it is
that was floral and fruity man very
delicious so I really think it's good
and fortunately uh you know I got a
clean pipe right now so everything
tastes a lot better through that I love
a nice fresh clean pipe my rig needs a
cleaning I might concentrate probably
would taste better how to clean that so
a good job on the clean pipe did did you
grow that herb that herb is actually a
close friend okay thank you very much
sir for sure we like to start the
podcast off by talking about what we're
smoking I usually talk about what I'm
smoking today I am smoking something
that I think tastes quite divine this is
the peach Recker
I've got a combo I've got the full
spectrum extract and I've also got the
live batter peach record full spectrum
extract and live batter from Green Dot
labs this is a blend of de wrecker and
peach oz on the package the flavor is
described as peach honey and gas when I
dad when I open it the first thing you
get is peach it is kind of like a fuzzy
navel this is how the flavor then when
you hit it that peach flavor hits you
first it's more like a white grape kind
of a peach thing like a generic peach
juice a fake peach juice you get at the
grocery store like a carton
it's got that peach juice flavor and
not dissing the flavor I'm just saying
that's the version of peach did I get
from it ah nice then on the exhale the
honey comes in I feel the honey on my
tongue it gets sweet and soft on my
tongue and that honey comes in on the
exhale and it just chills there and I
was really digging that the gas is there
but not as much as the peach and the
honey
yeah and it was definitely delicious so
I took a little glob of the the live
batter and got enough of that on the
dabber to work as a little bit of a
paste and then I stuck a giant full
spectrum extract diamond into that and
then I dip that in a little bit of the
Terp sauce in here and obviously it's
got me [ __ ] talkative and rambly
siliceous concentrate so we're doing the
night Jeff you make me want to do dabs
are you sure by the end of the show we
might get him to do a cab you guys they
just you're always putting them over man
they always sounds so delicious coming
out the flavor you can smell these
anytime you want reach over and smell
any of these delicious concerts there's
a table covered in yeah that's a good
one a good one
that's a big jar there so it's gonna
smell it will see what I got
that's perfect I got a insufficient nose
though for sufficient well untrained
nose yeah but it's a lot of that but to
the the non non connoisseur I like this
naked eye look at all the am I allowed
to say what I'm looking at yeah yeah
crystal Sephora gram jar mai tai
full-spectrum extract that's brand-new
that's untouched that's four grams yeah
it is beautiful would you say it looks
like golden caviar basically oh he's
giving it a sniff that smells so nice
can you describe it at all so that
smells like right when the plants get
into flowering like right like near the
end right before you're gonna harvest
like when you give them that squeeze and
it's like real floral still okay that's
what I smell all right and that's
because it's made from I'm pretty sure
that that one comes from fresh frozen
pointed gassi gassi all right that might
be more of just like I don't know I will
you give it a smell and oh for sure and
maybe we can compare on what we're
talking about
I get the floral I get a hint of
grandpa's aftershave damn for sure
that's in there okay yeah that's a fun
game to play that's fine do you smell
[Laughter]
doing the movie clerk he has like his
finger did you do you remember that
[Music]
delicious shutter to our friends at
Green Dot labs well we were smelling is
my tie it's a blend of sunset sherbet
and sherbert they put sherbert on here
it should be I don't know if that heart
goes in there or not but they can write
it their way and purple punch
it's called tropical fruit cocktails
what they describe it as I'm gonna agree
with that there's tropical fruit
cocktail cool fruit cooked but there's
also a hint of Colonia sort of a smell
that I enjoy yeah there's like some Brut
blue whatever comes in the old blue
bottle aftershave in a blue bottle we're
gonna get some emails great birdie like
six minutes in we haven't talked about
ganja at all this is gonna be great okay
so I opened another one real quick okay
this one has a huge crystal in it so
that's pretty tight I already know what
that is because of the huge crystal yeah
it says headbang or so head finger and
HSB so geez yeah for sure right oh then
that's the other garlic oh you got the
garlic banger I was gonna say well
you've got the garlic banger yeah
so that's gassy you get trashcan I just
mashed potatoes in trashcan I got the
trashcan for sure yeah it sounds like a
terrible description but when you smell
cannabis that smells and concentrates
that smell like a trash can for some
reason it's really desirable
it's so weird what I'm attracted to what
I was looking for weed but the nose nose
I'm gonna take the nose I've done a
podcast called follow your nose because
I feel like your nose knows what your
body needs does this and this is going
to be a really random question is there
almost a sexual aroma to this like
something they would all
trigger a sexual pheromone in that smell
that earthy almost kind of an armpit ii
summary and I don't mean like summer by
that I mean like somebody in the summer
smells like sex panther well Clint is a
part-time comedian so sex panther is
going to be the answer we go it it has
eight there's definitely a funk to it
like a body odor sort of a thing but
yeah I really think that one smells
really good that's pretty tight see in
the stuff that you got in front of is
just the most beautiful crystals and
stuff how pretty these things are coming
out is awesome I would say thank you but
all I did was hand money over for it
sure this is all of our friends at Green
Dot labs doing this good work here so I
guess I'm putting them over yeah let's
move on because we're gonna make people
frustrated with the plethora and buffet
of concentrates we've got there are
people listening in places that they
don't have access to this and we don't
need to rub it into their faces that
we've got to think all that out doses
and mimosas sitting here on the table
that looks like magic and some my tithe
that we got here Clint where the f are
we in this podcast what we're smoking on
I just hit the peach record Clinton is
smoking ak-47 we're stoned obviously
welcome to the show obviously let's
level out and get this going bro you
ready oh yeah here we go this is the
point in the show where we give shout
outs to our friends who support us on
patreon I'd like to start off with a big
giant I said giant so it's gonna be in
French today oh how about a big giant
throw for me on all the podcast now
let's just go back to English a shot I'm
gonna thank you too let's start off with
miss Mel let's go ladies first a big
thank you shout out to miss Mel how
about a giant thank you shot up to Todd
Kay of course I want to send a big THANK
YOU shout out to our Flint friend Glenn
jeroni
I want to send a big thank you shout out
to JM I always want to send a big thank
you to our buddy James Brown the hardest
working man in cannabis also a big giant
shout out to Keith Kay always we got to
send a huge giant shout out to our
friend fat rabbit that is the coolest
name ever also a giant shout out - thank
you - so so J you're gonna look sharp in
that girl from your heart a podcast for
that I read genetics hoodie and last but
certainly not least I want to send a
huge thank you to our buddy Willy's
armpit of course one of the most
creative names I've seen in a minute
a big shout out big thank you to
everybody who continues to support the
podcast if you would like to learn how
to support the show you can do so by
visiting www.azcleanelections.gov a good
plug you can get them on my website I
read genetics Colorado comm click on the
store I know the website doesn't look
very professional at this point it's
being rebuilt we will relaunch that new
things are coming in 2020 but there is a
web store you can get a hoodie go get a
t-shirt support the show support I read
genetics support that's the bottom line
there thank you guys for all the support
I know that without the Irie army
without the girl from your heart crew
that this wouldn't be a thing so big up
thank you guys oh yeah much respect
thank you I appreciate it
join the club boys join the club that's
the way to do it so if you guys listen
to the show frequently and even if you
don't you'll learn right now I am a huge
fan of comedy I like to laugh I think
laughter is medicine
mmm smoked cannabis and get told a joke
and you'll forget you even got problems
you'll just be too busy laughing and it
feels good it recharges your soul of
course you got to deal with your
problems appropriately but sometimes you
gotta just it helps the problems in your
mind a little bit did you hear that
through the microphone when I tap my
head it came through my mouth I'm Hollow
[Laughter]
we'll find out later I think laughter is
good for you
and I also think it's good to take your
friends to go see [ __ ] laughter also
yeah and I got to go see we got to go
see the fine gentlemen of who's live
anyway which is the live version of
whose line is it anyway from TV I'm sure
a lot of people that is on CW is what he
said yeah it's been on for years on
different channels yeah it was not the
tall guy not the
like I carry they tell you a lot but it
was mr. Greg Proops who if you listen
you know that's one of my favorite
comedians it was so funny last night -
he kind of works as a very gracious host
of the show
he's got good hosting skills I there's
also a comedian known as Jeff B Davis a
younger guy who fits in very well with
the improv group he's got a lot of
energy he brings a lot of energy and
creativity and movement to the group
yeah I really worked hard he did really
well and he's got to bring that younger
energy I'm not saying the other guys are
old cats but they're not spring chickens
they're older dudes and so to have Jeff
be Davis bring that young energy is
really a good thing for the show yeah -
some really like experienced improv guys
yes really cool and then there's a guy
named Joel Murray who is really funny he
does a lot of great voices a lot of good
character oh yeah what a good slightly
dry humor yeah he kind of has a Bob
Newhart sort of a delivery to it he
really did yeah
yeah he really played like the dad
almost on stage just the smartass like
if it got too funny he'd have one
comment just to shut you down yeah and
you didn't say a lot
it was just what he said yes correct
it's beautiful then there's another guy
that some people may have heard of a guy
named uh his name is Dave Foley Foley
Dave Foley
he's [ __ ] hilarious that guy's got a
lot of character yeah snazzy dresser
yeah they were always pretty swell Greg
Proops his themes is how do we dress as
sharp as possible and that's one of his
mottos all the time so they've of course
looked good and it would be rude to
overlook a very crucial member of the
group they have a musician whose name
who has escaped my head right now
but he brings a grand piano and a
keyboard and a couple of other small
instruments and he provides the musical
soundtrack for the evening and without
him it wouldn't be a show that guy is
amazing he's a great musician they do
improv songs he provides background
music and sound effects and he is
spot-on
people often forget about that guy in
the back making the music he needs a
special acknowledgement cuz he's [ __ ]
awesome yeah what an amazing talent yeah
just
they're doing an improv show and the
audience member is yelling out steps to
the Improv and so yeah the improv guys
and I'm not downplaying them they've got
to do improv they've got to make it
funny physically and verbally yeah those
guys got to make it funny musically he's
got to take your idea and make music to
it yeah he's got to give it like a
contra mall look at you bro you're
bringing out big words to the show Oh
like a company man yeah he's just like
pushing it ahead yes it's good I mean he
just he made the show really he's doing
the score and the sound effects at the
same time basically I remember they said
he was from Edmonton he's won a bunch of
awards for something a big thing in
Canada and I hate to be disrespectful
like that but he's definitely well-known
in Canada
of course I was plenty stoned because we
were going to a funny comedy show the
last thing I was thinking about was
remembering people's names but he
deserves some acknowledgement he's a
great [ __ ] musician if the Hoos live
anyway tour is coming to your
neighborhood I highly recommend you
highly go and go highly yeah baked and
go yes and big shout out to Jeff B Davis
a big shout out to Joe Elmore a of
course a giant shot at mr. Dave Foley I
shot it to the musician guy who a man I
feel rude for not remembering his name
but he was [ __ ] great second city in
Toronto is where he's famous from oh
that word just popped into my brain nice
I want to send a big shout out to our
friend Greg Proops we've met Proops a
couple of times we Proops interacts with
myself on twitter quite frequently he
calls me young Gabbar which i think is
[ __ ] funny which is perfect it fits
brought the dab fits I'll hit it yeah
but we may or may not have known exactly
where Proops was going to be moments
after the show and we may or may not
have approached him and he was
completely kind to us and he thanked us
for coming oh yeah and we got the shape
proofs his hand but I feel like we're on
a friendly basis with groups so it's
really cool to go see him and he's very
gracious when he sees us yeah he's such
a polite man oh he's so EQ shake your
hand and just be polite and man what a
great guy yeah yeah I know we're kissing
his ass a little bit but I just enjoyed
the show a whole bunch it was just
yesterday so it's like so fresh it's
just great I keep telling everybody I
took Clint to a comedy show and we had a
good time
I'm gonna give you a shout out there so
I and you're like hey bro you want a DAB
tonight I was like I got a record I was
like oh wait I know what to do Oh
microphone in front of Clinton yeah oh
man thanks for being a [ __ ] awesome
Road Dogg on the comedy show thing it's
been fun with you every time dude we've
had some really good times yeah it has
been fantastic we've seen Joey yep
hernán job Joe Joe Diaz go see Joe Joe
Rogan Joe Rogan Joe Diaz Brendan Schaub
Tommy Bonds Tom Segura I mean we saw
who's alive we've done quite a few cool
comedy shows lately yeah it's been
really good we got to see Derek Poston
oh that was a Shawne Ahmad I was saying
his name wrong he guys I was soon it's
we put a J in his name and Instagram and
Twitter and so I was saying that J but
that's like his middle name so it's on a
modify was a song just because it's what
it says on Instagram I apologize bro
that's right you're trying to show
people anybody even looked him up on
Instagram found him because of the way I
had pronounced it because they put the J
in there because I was saying I'm glad
they did cuz that guy's he's [ __ ]
funny and he's blowing up too but Derek
posted so very unexpected and very very
worth my ticket price he blew he blew
the roof off the place blew my mind and
I'm glad I got to see him cuz now I'm a
big fan and then got to meet him after
the show yeah it was just like what's up
man I was like you're [ __ ] funny cuz
that's what I do thank you yeah like
you're just humble and want to hang out
I like that yeah they were just so chill
and it's I don't know about all these
comedians that have come through have
just been so nice you know you know we
meet shop we'd be Proops again and like
we've hung out with groups for like an
hour you know probably tell this story
groups is like holding court and tell
this story and it's just me and Jeff and
like to other people hanging out and guy
always there and great you know so like
we're just all just chilling and it's
like just this real secluded little area
that we found and man he's telling this
story and some about baseball and also
Jeff gets hit across the chest like like
a Ric Flair choppy that I was out
anybody's in those proofs knows he's a
baseball stories and so he's stoned we
got him lit yeah telling a story about
baseball and he tagged me to express
that the runner was out and I was like
oh he did I looked at Clint like proof
just slap this step in like security
guard I was with him for like 45 minutes
I mean these always been such a
gentlemen in such a great host so
there's a great thing about that
comedian personality there's a need for
attention yeah and the thing that once
you've got an audience you don't want to
let it go yeah and so if we find him at
the right time and they're still in that
pocket they just keep going for us and
when they see us in that Club knows who
I am and so I may be given special
treatment and get special access to
people but once they meet us and they
calm down and they start smoke and they
realize these guys are harmless they're
not like sketchy fans they can ask us to
sign their ass sheets and not even over
eight times recently there's no photos
anywhere of it because it's no need for
that well you get to certain like
mentality and you just realize like dude
I'm enjoying this for this moment right
now it's in my brain I know what
happened so I kind of got when we meet
these people once you get them going you
smoke a bowl with number two and then
you don't get weird on them and they get
comfortable with you and they're a
comedy club and their safe zone and the
comedy club is kind of confirmed that
we're cool you know what I mean we've
been given that hey those guys are all
right yeah they chill out and they give
you they can't stop doing the thing like
they're still in a spotlight they're
still waiting to be told to show the
other show is over and that's the show
that they're just performing in life
today because that personality type has
a need for attention most of the
comedian's all their lives they're just
trying to get some of the [ __ ] pay
attention and now they are like oh I'll
talk until you're [ __ ] done yeah that
was it too like hanging out with Joey
Diaz for that hour we got to hang out
with him and him giving me comedy advice
back in the day like those were just
like
engrained in me and because I'm such a
fan boy you know so it's it's some of
that like it's it's just exciting to
like kind of beat your heroes and they
like bow to watch Joey talk I usually
I'm the mouthy one I know that I'm the
one that can just walk my way into a
situation I'm not shy to walk it off if
they're not gonna shoot me I could walk
up to the president casually but supper
on Ross to Jeff and stick-up man to
shake man I don't care if you're the
president I don't care if you're the
janitor I'm not shy we're gonna be
friends although joint no matter who you
are yes I'm usually the one that's like
kind of dominating the conversation
sometimes purposely sometimes not to
tell you the truth you know so when we
go to meet these famous people I know
how to be comfortable and make a
conversation happen and be casual and
you generally stand a little bit to the
back and let the conversation go and you
talk when it's necessary and let me run
my face
Joey decided you said I'm a stand-up
comedian and Joey was like oh yeah [ __ ]
this guy with dreadlocks like I just
stood back and let you and I watched you
and Joey Diaz have a conversation
there's a light right between you guys
just shine on both of your faces and I
just stood back I had a health stone
pipe with hash in it and I just sat
there and hit a ball a couple of times I
just chill that and watch Joey tell you
he laid it down but I remember I told
you they write every day and he I don't
know what's right every day I don't care
write your name across the page a
thousand times don't spin it I'll write
in every [ __ ] day [ __ ] yeah I
think that's part of the key but yeah
just to get those magical moments and to
watch him tell you that and it's the sit
back was kind of cool I wish I would
have had the balls to take out my phone
and snap a shot for you but yes the best
place you would have made it
uncomfortable would have broken all of
the magic I think the phone would have
ruined all of the magic at that yeah I
felt like we kind of just had like uh I
don't know there's like almost a social
like it's just like dude we're just
hanging out and that's part of why they
let it do that bro because we don't ever
fanboy out pull out our dicks or our
phones don't you just let us go no we're
just trying to hand them weed smoke
don't tell my secret
but every comedian that comes through
gets to get [ __ ] stoned with Rasta
Jeff that's comedians do you want to
talk about cannabis have fun in this
episode let's do both we've been having
fun let's talk about cannabis the next
thing I've got listed here on my paper
is the endo Expo is coming a lot of
people have been asking when is the next
big event the endo Expo January 25th and
26th in Denver Colorado with a Denver
Mart the 25th is industry day which
means you've got to get an industry
invite pass the 26th is general public
Day which means you are able to attend
everybody can attend there is a link you
have if you go to the endo Expo website
this is for the Denver endo Expo that
I'm talking about it'll be at the Denver
endo Expo if you'd like to come to the
booth come shake my hand come tell me if
you love or hate the podcast maybe pick
up some cool I read genetics merchandise
I just come say hi come check out the
endo Expo in Denver Colorado let me warn
you that is a non consumption event you
cannot consume any sort of cannabis or
buy or sell or trade cannabis in there
it is a cannabis trade show it's one of
the world's largest indoor cannabis
trade shows indoor grow based cannabis
trade shows there's an entire CBD and
hemp indoor pavilion they call the
indoor hip pavilion where they've got a
bunch of CBD vendors teaching about CBD
that Barry they actually do give away
CBD samples because that's anything
without THC they can give away they can
share with you but nothing with THC they
can share give away that's just
dispensary in Colorado State regulations
but you can check out all kinds of
nutrient companies you can check out
lighting companies there will be tons of
seed companies there if you need to
refill your genetic stash the endo Expo
is a great opportunity for things like
that also you can meet the industry also
if you plan properly and you do it
properly
bring a bag and you can fill that bag
with excellent freebies you can get soil
you've got nutrients you can get shirts
stickers hats you can get a fresh outfit
for the entire year if you want to rock
out like whatever company you like
probably I read genetics t-shirt maybe
you could get a new millennium t-shirt
you can get a vegetable
tshirt let's go visit all your favorite
vendors talk to them people are giving
out free merchandise that's a huge free
commercial I just wanted to invite
people to come [ __ ] and hang out at the
IRA booth and say what's up - I read
genetics at the event well it's a huge
events a huge event so that's so cool
thank you man it's fun to finally have
stepped up last year I shared a booth
with other folks I was invited to be
part of the organization
right on ah no offense to them but the
endo Expo reached out and they said hey
you're a local you're a Colorado boy we
love having the hometown heroes here
would you like to have a booth oh hell
yes I would so they gave me the I paid
the normal price for it I'm not gonna
say they gave me any special deal but
they reached out and said we want the
Colorado boy are you ready to do it
yes I am I've got a fool ten-by-ten
booth I got the booth ready to go
there'd be a lot of great things
available at the booth so yeah that's
that's my commercial for that come say
what's up yeah definitely come say
what's up I'm the tall white guy with
dreadlocks at the IRA genetics booth I'm
trying to get white mic to be able to
attend he does have two children and a
family and a lot of things going on that
time of year so 25th and 26th of January
Expo all right let's get a little more
serious because in a previous episode I
may have said something that was not a
hundred percent accurate I wasn't a huge
mistake but it's good I like I don't
like making mistakes I like learning
from my mistakes I like it I've got a
really good community the irie are me
the girl from your heart crew not only
did they support us well on patreon but
also they reached out and politely said
hey you gave some kind of funky
information on one of these episodes and
it wasn't a major mistake it's not gonna
kill anybody's plants honestly I will
admit that this is the area of growing
and cannabis where I can use the most
education and I am not afraid to admit
that I know a lot about most of this is
lighting and light spectrums which is
something that I know very minimal about
I should know more I'm not ashamed to
admit that that's awesome I know about
plants like a [ __ ] I know about
breeding I know about selection I can
look at your plants and tell you what's
wrong with their nutrients like I can
tell you a lot of things when it comes
to lighting I am a little ignorant I
need to read more books on that and I'm
not shy to admit that but luckily I
something that indicated straight up I'm
[ __ ] full of [ __ ] when it comes to
talking about lighting because some of
our friends stepped up and said Rasta
Jeff first off you're a little bit wrong
but then they helped me out and they
said here's the information that you
need so Big Shot it to all of my friends
who helped me out when I started reading
this one of our friends will say haha he
took my information so in a previous
episode I kind of said that the Sun
changes color as it sets and that that
color from the Sun creates a different
spectrum that helps the plants go to
sleep yep
the plant does the Sun does not change
colors that's true that is true I
honestly hadn't done I didn't write any
notes for that I was reading that
question and was just answering it from
my knowledge and I said that the Sun
changes colors it may look like it
changes colors that is not what happens
the atmosphere filters the light based
on the angle of the Sun in a comparison
to where we are seeing it so it doesn't
change colors it's basically a filter
because imagine if you held a light bulb
right above your head
it's gonna see bright here and you're
gonna get that other color of light down
here and then you'll move it it's gonna
the lights gonna shine differently
it's basically an atmosphere like if you
when it's foggy the [ __ ] light shines
differently because you can see it
that's the type of [ __ ] is it's going to
change completely obviously you can tell
I don't understand that concept fully
you can tell by the way I'm trying to
explain it in terms of light yes but
that happens because of the angle of the
Sun where you are and the atmosphere it
filters the light so I just wanted to
say I did that wrong and I am not afraid
to admit it and thank you to my friend
Jesse James for stepping up and
correcting me that means a lot to me
that I've got a team that will politely
say hey bro you sound dumb yeah yeah no
I mean a lot of people are listening so
we can't give out fake information no
and you're willing to [ __ ] make your
mistakes and learn from them you know
I've done a podcast all about making
mistakes so there's another one for you
yeah and also you guys I'm not [ __ ]
bulletproof I [ __ ] up I said some dumb
[ __ ] and Here I am Sam I said some dumb
[ __ ] sorry you guys
a lot of people rely on me you were
close you know and I I'm it's not a
plant thing this is more of a-- and so
we were talking about far red spectrums
and this is a spectrum that falls in the
seven to eight hundred nanometer range
and there's a little bit of a debate
on the Internet on what range is ideal
for the far-red spectrum some people say
it is seven to eight hundred I saw 7:30
to eight hundred and then more
specifically people dial it in to the
750 to 780 range but I'm also seeing
people go up to 8:30 so there's a little
bit of a debate where that read happens
which is most ideal for the cannabis
plant Julia just like all lighting
pretty much it's probably possibly
phenotype dependent plant specific I'll
bet it is yeah yeah because I mean we're
where plants are from they're gonna want
light right northern southern oh man
yep that's gonna be all right so that
makes a big difference as to where your
nanometers are gonna be absolutely I
would agree with that all right so I
think I corrected that big thanks to
Jesse James for that and I apologize for
kind of bleeding you guys astray yeah
but here I am addressing my mistakes
also I said that I would not recommend
cutting clones directly into cocoa
we had a listener saying that they were
taking their clones into cocoa and their
clones were dying I said that's not a
good idea I got several messages saying
basically go [ __ ] yourself because I cut
clones into cocoa so I believe you and
I'm sure that it does work for you but
for the listener who they were all dying
on yeah it obviously wasn't working and
I recommended they go back to basics
those people that it's working for
that's radit you've probably got a lot
of experience and you know really well
what you're doing you've dialed it in
and you're not killing clones yeah we
had a listener killing them so something
wasn't working and when it's not working
that's when I start going backwards and
saying what's going on what's wrong when
the engine doesn't work you got to take
it apart rebuild that [ __ ] and I was
just trying to take it apart and start
going back to the white belt level and
then we'll work our way back up and
maybe when they're good again they
understand the basics of cloning we'll
get them going back into cocoa but for
that person who wasn't working but I
can't say that no you cannot clone into
cocoa that's probably not the thing to
say it's probably not recommended for
beginners and if you're having problems
doing it abandon that because you'll
have much more success with the cloning
machine or probably easy cloner not easy
to honor the rapid Rooter
little plugs so you can clone into cocoa
I apologize if I upset you by missing
your tech it does work but not for
everybody thank God it's yeah well
people are just coming at me and I need
to be the corrections department
all right enough catching up let's move
on to something new what do we got the
next part is oh I got a really good
question on YouTube and this one was a
question about how do you feel about
eleven thirteen light schedules and then
I thought I could talk briefly about
that I'm an eleven thirteen flowering
schedule most of us do at twelve twelve
that seems to be the traditional on off
schedule twelve twelve makes your plants
flower you leave them there for nine or
ten weeks and you get good buds
djay short a while back started
preaching about doing Oh DJ shorts the
one that made it popular for most people
DJ shorts started talking about doing 11
hours on and 13 hours off and this has
several benefits the first benefit is it
will show more phenotypic expression if
you're drawing from seed you'll see more
variation in your different seedlings
you'll see different phenotypic
expressions more uh more expression I
guess I can say you'll see yeah they'll
show their variance is a little bit more
because it's just getting less light
less light more more time to express I
guess more time to show what they say
that kids grow in their sleep do the
plants do the same thing they started if
you watch a video of a plant on a
time-lapse camera they don't do a lot
during the day they get blown around
they try to stay there yeah at night
they look like they're swimming and they
grow the leaves go up and leaves go down
and leaves go up they go down it looks
like a jack you know what I mean like
when you move a jack you move the handle
down and Jack goes up let's say it looks
like the leaves are kind of swimming if
you watch them overnight
oh yes really neat to see really neat to
see so they do most of their growth most
of their production at nighttime right
and I've learned that if you give them
that more that longer extended night
period you do see a little bit different
you know typical expression it will also
in my opinion speed them up in their
flowering time you may save up to a week
maybe ten days on some phenotypes if
you've got a seventy day and you cut it
down to eleven thirteen you may have a
sixty five day or at this point yeah
don't take my word for it that's gonna
be plant and phenotype dependent hundred
percent but get your scope out start
paying attention you may notice
different things
Brown now this get them brown that
sounds grosser than it should this is
going to be plant and strain and
phenotype dependent on if this is best
for your plants or not if you want if
you're running from seed in a small tent
and you're just doing a phyno hunt i
would go with the 1113 hmm this also has
advantages in a large scale environment
imagine if you've got 24 lights and I
cut off one hour a day over a month
you've got 30 days at 24 lights that's
720 hours of lighting that you're not
paying for which is also air
conditioning you're not paying for so
those bulbs are also gonna last you that
hour longer so that just multiplies
you've got if you're running 24 what I
don't even know the numbers I started
with it 24 lights right so 24 lights
yeah so it just scales up if you go more
lights you save it more money
yeah so even just one hour but is that
pushing it Jeff like it just depends on
the strain I suppose you know if if
you're doing the pheno hunt I would
recommend it like to start off with that
just to find the one because it's gonna
show you they're able to express their
phenotypes more more fully I don't know
how else to say those words my god it's
like yeah the tall ones are gonna get
taller the purple ones will show more
purple the stinky one will get stinky or
in my opinion in my experience okay yeah
that may do a little bit to your yields
because we do say that light is the
number one source of energy and food for
the plant and you're cutting down an
hour of that mm-hmm
so that may show a small reduction in
yield and in harvest wait have you seen
a big difference in that not big enough
to make it worth it no I would rather do
the 11 13 really lot of times yes I'm
really going to throw the world off
Clint I'm going to imagine that several
people signed out of this episode
because we were a little bit rambling at
the beginning yeah they didn't think
they were gonna get this magical [ __ ]
grow tip probably add some magic here's
a tip that I don't share with a lot of
people that I don't talk about a lot
this is something this is an advanced
tip at the end of flowering I change my
timer I used to preach
for people to reduce time if you've got
a plant that takes way too long to
flower here's there's one piece of
advice and I'll share what I was gonna
say after that if you've got a plant
that takes too long to flower I'm going
to use lemon G as my example because
this works very well with lemon G if
you're growing lemon G or a lemon G
cross take note if you've got a cultivar
that takes 11 12 13 weeks this will work
for you this will be very helpful if
that plant takes too long you need it to
hurry up you're running 12 12 or you're
running 11 13 toward the end of flower
you can reduce the amount of light hours
and that will make that plant speed up
it does the same thing that happens
outdoors it makes the plan go oh [ __ ]
falls no it's here do my [ __ ] yeah it's
finishing up it can do all that
processing at nighttime so it starts
finishing up it starts speeding up that
finishing process it starts hardening up
the trichomes start ripening up so you
can slowly reduce the amount of daylight
hours you can get down to 8 hours a day
if you want to I just have 8 hours on
and 16 hours off and let the plant
finish like that for the last couple of
weeks there you go
quite often during flush I'll reduce so
if I've got something lemon G I'll
reduce the lights to 10 hours on for a
week and then I'll move them to eight
hours on for a week and for the last
week I'll put them on for 6 hours on and
that plant will really finish up and I'm
flushing through that time period also
yeah flushing is free I'm saving a lot
of money on less lights it's really an
economical way to help that plant finish
up so you can reduce the amount of
daylight hours to finish up a slower
finishing cultivar is uh wood
temperature in the room do anything for
that - like wood dropping the
temperature make things speed up a
little bit a little bit colder will help
you but you can't have too large of a
swing because that's when you start
promoting powdery mildew but if you
overall lower your daytime and nighttime
temperature slowly and keep your vapor
pressure deficit in line that is
something that you can do that'll bring
out purples that'll bring out density
and that'll also bring out some flavors
and some colors yeah I'll think about
outside when it starts getting cold we
start seeing those beautiful fall colors
that'll happen indoors with the
temperature and the slight adjustment as
well right on if you're doing the 1113
and then you start dropping the lights
down you're really gonna see that fall
change in your plants so when you get
some really cool photos yo the photos
come
excellent man you share some rad stuff
on your Instagram you've got some good
friends growing some good wheat it
sounds like I have refrained from
posting a lot of my own photos because
if the breeder can breed a strain and
grow it to perfection good job high five
if I can breed seeds and get them to a
friend who grows in a completely
different style than me and obey can
grow them to perfection and snapshots of
it that's when you know you've got a
winning seed and a winning plant right
there if the breeder can do it that's
expected that's [ __ ] required that's
like if Metallica plays inter Sandman
they better get it right if we went up
there and played under Sandman that's
gonna [ __ ] go yeah yeah for sure yeah
so when it comes well it's like all
right yeah yes here's what I want to
share here's what I want people to see
is that they can do this to you so I've
been sharing a lot of other people's and
thanks for noticing that I they've been
doing a really good job for me lately
dude you had some good friends yeah I've
got some people out there running
testers of stuff they don't even know
what it is
and they are killing it yeah yeah
because I don't want them to treat the
plant in any specific way because oh
it's got this in it or it's this or I
suspect it's this I just say this is
some some seeds these are seeds they're
feminized so you don't have to worry
about boys oh these grow them let me
know if you run into any problems take
good pictures document that [ __ ] and
they don't know what they've got and
they send stellar photos yeah yeah good
job my sisters thank you guys you've got
such amazing real grip like products
though yeah really well I know yeah dude
there are I don't want to I don't even
want to brag because it just depends on
when you catch me how much packaging
time I've had like I've had time to sit
here and just stuff seeds into packages
and like find the right seeds for the
right packages and count them out get
them going I've got a lot of lines
available package them all up so I feel
that yeah I was looking at there's a
grip of lemon Geoffrey seeds there might
be a few packs of lemon Geoffrey those
may or may not be for an exponent coming
up in January it might be gonna start
packing up early I'm trying to have you
know there might be a limited supply of
those stashed for Indo Expo that's tight
means
exciting let's move on to this lighting
thing because IT wheaties the world we
may have cut out once already and then I
tease that we're gonna give them a
secret tip that I don't share a lot and
we talked about others should I love
that you keep kept that T's going for a
while here is something I don't teach a
lot this is a really advanced trick this
is going to scare the [ __ ] out of a lot
of people this is gonna be controversial
I'm really glad that this game at the
end of this episode this is like a
golden nugget this is like this is go
the prize at the bottom of the [ __ ]
cereal that you want your parents will
let you dig for you gotta eat the cereal
before you get to it here's the prize
boys and girls um something that I find
very useful if I run a 12 12 or an 11 13
light cycle toward the end of flour
basically the day I begin flushing this
is probably ten days before I harvest
the plant
I will put my timer back on an 18 6
light cycle yes I will repeat that at
the very end of my flowering phase I
return my timer to an 18-6 light cycle
to wear my flowering plants receive 18
hours of daylight per day and 6 hours of
night cycle per day my flowering plants
now people are going what the [ __ ] are
you doing Rasta Jeff because I see Clint
kind of stroking his beard guys a lot of
splainin to do
oh man you throw them back and get them
grow and again it makes them grow it
makes them beef up and people are gonna
say won't that make your plants herm
isn't that gonna cause problems we've
got 10 days yeah 10 days or two weeks
and we're flushing you're flushing you
flip the light back on I said earlier
that light is the number one source of
food and energy for our plants
let's beef it up it will actually make
those buds swell up a lot of times a
good cultivar will beef up on the last
couple of weeks of flower imagine if
that beefy [ __ ] gets extra energy at
that last ten days the sons do that's
what the son would do so they really
swell up on you and people are gonna go
but they're gonna revenge or they're
gonna herm know you've only got 10 days
yeah even if they do her then you might
get a nanner but nothing's gonna happen
because that nanner will be sterile and
there's no time for anything to
pollinate even if it does drop pollen
there are no viable parts of the plant
that can receive pollen we are way past
that this plant is basically it's one of
the golden girls now bro it's not gonna
get pregnant on you it's too late for
that that's awesome yeah yeah
the plant is done at this point so it's
working on its end phases of life it's
not gonna get pollinated it's not going
to toss any pollen and it's just gonna
beef up and it may begin to revenge if
you let it go for too long but that's
gonna take you 14 15 17 days before you
see any signs of reef edge and you'll
know what that looks like if you're
familiar with your cultivar it'll look
like you just kind of Fox tailed a
little bit too much so that is something
you can try if you want to add a little
bit of beef a little bit of bulk if you
feel like you lost a little bit of beef
because you did the 11:13 at the end for
the last seven days
throw them [ __ ] back on eleven
thirteen this is something I would
recommend experimenting with don't start
right away by doing it for ten days
maybe do it for five days and see what
happens yeah then the next crop do it
for ten days and see what happens then
maybe extend it up to fourteen I
wouldn't go past fourteen days
now I have made other recommendations
for other light cycles that is basically
around my breeding programs I dunno
other things and other methods and other
schedules that I do when breeding we may
talk about that in a future episode but
if you want to get crazy if you want to
try something new turn those lights back
on
to eighteen hours on and six hours off
at the end of your flowering cycle as
you flush your plants and see if they
bulk up and beef up more than they have
in the past that is a golden nugget
right there yeah don't they listen to
that long I'm sure we'll get a couple
we'll see what the emails say Yeah right
it'll be a youtube comment as where it
will happen first so a big shout out to
all of our friends who listen to the
show on the you too
thanks guys like and subscribe please
there you go Clint set it for us um hey
Clint we've been going for almost 45
minutes hey we did it Jeff we did it
buddy excellent job
yeah good job oh man well I've got you
here on the microphone do you have
anything that you'd like to say to the
world or anything you'd like to plug you
know I do not have anything that I'm
doing lately there's sort of an
anonymous kind of a dude you're like dad
dad calm lately yeah that's good for you
I appreciate it dude so many people out
there aren't dad's at dad calm
they should be doing so big shout out
that you're doing it yeah I'm just happy
to be able to come and hang out
hopefully the podcast world's having a
good time with us so I'm sure they were
excited to hear your voice and bro you
went 45 minutes without crashing the
[ __ ] show you ready to do something
stupid dude yeah was I supposed to do a
DAB I was hoping that you're gonna catch
my hand that was [ __ ] awesome I
brought thanks for coming on the podcast
thanks for being an awesome guest thanks
for being a cool comedy buddy and just
thanks for being a good friend man yeah
dude it's been great thanks for hanging
out bro all right this podcast here
ladies and gentlemen here's the part
where I do that end of the show speech
if you feel like this podcast was
educational informative and/or
entertaining and you would like to
financially contribute to the show you
can do so by visiting
www.disabilitydenials.com was a lot
because there are good friends and
they're strong supporters of the
cannabis community and that's what we
need
cannabis cannabis is a free cannabis
friendly social media application that
is available on your Android or Apple
mobile device you cannot buy sell or
trade cannabis on cannabis but you can
join the cannabis community you can post
your cannabis photos you can post
cannabis questions or you can post your
fancy dab videos if you've got a plant
or a garden that as a problem post a
photo of it and we will kindly answer
your questions and tell you how to fix
your plants if you're interested in or
if you are currently growing I read
genetics strains there is a I read
there's an eye region that exteriors
group you like that good grammar that
hos perfect there's an IRA genetics
breeders group you can join the group
post pictures of your IRA genetics
plants you can ask questions join the
IRA army over there and occasionally
people in the group leave with some free
beans so time yeah so join the group
join us on cannabis give me a follow I
am i re underscore genetics on cannabis
join the family catch-up
buzz if you've got something else you'd
like to say perhaps you've got a product
you'd like me to review maybe you'd like
to sponsor the podcast maybe you're just
not in all that social media nonsense
you can send me an email my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com you know that I would love
to hear from you I want to thank
everybody once again for listening once
again a big shout out to Clint for
coming and hanging out on the show I'll
be back in a couple of days with fresh
new content I want to give a giant shout
out to my buddy oh gee purple thumb and
until next time take a phat dab and give
your mom a hug for me yeah I give your
mom a hug for us there we go wait for
that
[Music]
January winter brings the code on me
brings memories remember
[Music]
now look at me with my hands but making
me will just increase my awesome power
and when I finally see you imma love you
all over your belly but and then massage
your shoulders like a baby buddy I'll
even be your friend but here are
thinking about you again
[Music]
a down on me