[Music]
yeah what's up guys it's time for
another episode of the Grove from your
heart podcast your source for cannabis
news education and conversation welcome
it's episode number 48 we're creeping up
on number 50
I'm your host Rasta Jeff and I'm dad the
[ __ ] out but I've got good reason we're
joined today by Spence and Maddie from
the garden of Weeden how're you guys
doing over there damn I'm yelling at
that mic that means it was a lot I
apologize for yelling at everybody holy
[ __ ] Maddie I'm gonna push the mic right
in your faces we could hear you yeah
there you go
well that's tradition over here but I
think we kind of went a little extra
today holy crap you guys said you wanted
to go hard on the dads and we did it the
first thing Maddie said when she walked
into the house was I need a DAB welcome
if you need another one do there's dad's
over here there's a hot I got the email
on shout-out to giddy up an emo tech for
the gene/l we keep it on most of the
time isn't that dope
charge the phone all the time while
you're taking dabs and on Instagram and
on Instagram you charge the phone take
dabs and be on Instagram so what you're
doing over there
I got a lot of questions for you bro so
you got to be a part of this show
yup Maddie you are go ahead so this
headphone mic is [ __ ] up don't ever
buy the live wire solutions hero4 don't
ever buy one of those it's a piece of
[ __ ] yeah I hate that piece craps out on
us a lot so we were saying that maddie
was gonna be the first female on the
show actually that's inaccurate because
I took the podcast to the Brickyard one
time and we had special you're gonna be
special in just a second okay I'm gonna
skip bragging on the other people that
were there were other females but you're
the first female to be here on the show
we went somewhere else and there were
females there that were on the show but
you're the first lady to come be in the
Irie studio so welcome thank you for
sure Oh have you
damn it Spencer the first black person
on the podcast misters probably I'm
always the first black person in
anything Jeff does yeah black person in
my house black people around you live in
[ __ ] Pueblo true there's been a lot
of white people and a lot of Mexicans
here but you know you could say where we
are these guys came in to visit me
so dude welcome to show you guys I like
having some of my best friends here I
have to do a couple of ads right quick
that's tradition you guys can laugh at
me and take dad's all they do ads
however you want to do it the first dad
nature's green remedies dot-com check
out we're gonna do the quick version
check out nature's green remedies calm
for gage green genetics a lot of labs
Sin City rare dankness mile hike an
adventure use coupon code it's Irie 2015
for 15% off your whole order and you
always get free shipping at nature's
green remedies dot-com that was the
quickest I've ever done that ad who else
do we have tree sucker coms episode is
brought to you in part by tree thugger
comm live music lifestyle magazine check
out tree hugger comm for concert and
festival news and reviews one more add
this one's super special mad love to our
friends at Highgrove indoor growing
supplies this podcast is brought to you
by our friends at Highgrove indoor girl
supplies yeah big shout out dude I saw
those trays you got those are dope I
think I'm gonna copy you I worked there
part-time now so also come check me out
I'll be there two days a week now you
can go see miss Whedon and stop her I
don't know if you wanted to say that on
the show you might get some I'm happy to
help people I'm enjoying it I'm learning
a lot from it a lot more than I thought
it's great to have my friends working at
hydro shops when I go in there you don't
try to hustle me and sell me some [ __ ]
for sure
I definitely think Pablo has the best
prices in town actually if you listen to
the iGrow culture or the girl from your
heart podcast we're changing the name
you guys I'm gonna stutter and say the
wrong name a few times I'll remind you
about that later on on the show if you
go in there and you tell me listen to
this podcast you will get commercial
pricing on everything you buy he's
looking at me exciting Maddie didn't
know how to do that she's going I might
after
that's I that's all the ads let's not do
any more commercials everybody else that
paid for ads you'll get them some other
time that's cool all right so I got to
do also a shout-out to mr. Kreutzer let
me play their music they let me play all
of their music they gave me full access
to everything that's kind of cool shout
out to peaches the peaches are pears big
Micah wish you were here with the crew
but someone's got to take care of the
dogs
shout out to Soraka Nona hey what is
this posted Monday yeah Monday morning
710 in the morning people I asked you me
already nice everybody on Instagram and
stuff all right
so dude we just took some dabs only give
spins a huge shout-out on the show
Spence taught me how to make my own dabs
that's freakin awesome I appreciate it I
am self-sufficient it's great to learn
from one of who I consider the Masters
and also a brother so means a lot thanks
a lot bro no problem bro well it's about
time you have great product so in turn
that's gonna make great oil I appreciate
that
I want to brag on Maddie and it's all a
story about Maddie introduce you guys
Maddie and spins hanging out together
who live together that's how I met them
so one time Spence made Earl and Maddie
she's great already she knows where I'm
headed with this she took that pyrex
dish that had a little bit of vho left
in the bottom that we didn't feel like
scraping out and she decided to heat it
up and make brownies in that pan with
the BHO mix in there and she's laughing
because Spence and I are on the six-four
six-five level of life close to 200
pounds each and there was another guy
and another guy in the room that's about
the same same weight class and she
[ __ ] wrecked 4 dudes maybe five or
six dude I didn't even know that that it
was gonna be that potent oh my god the
whole outer layer of the brownie was
literally covered in a layer of shatter
almost and it coated inside of the
brownie but it worked itself in
perfectly to where it got us all so far
it made like a it's like a pineapple
upside-down cake layer of hash on the
outside of the brownies it was so it was
tasty but god I was high had to leave
about 30 minutes after I left the irate
I felt my arms drooping and I was like I
gotta go home everybody went to bed it
was fun back in the day that was the
only way I could really utilize a pyrex
dish without wasting it so so you said
back in the dam and asked a tech
question now what do you do now um
definitely do not blast into a pyrex
dish or use a pyrex dish in our process
anymore at all everything's closed loop
and use parchment when we process it to
go through the back of it so there's no
pirate session needed now
nice yeah you guys stopped me a way to
do it there's no pyrex dish involved in
how I was taught which is kind of neat
kind of smooth these guys are [ __ ]
badass at what they do so thanks for
company guys by the way welcome thanks
for having us was like what are we gonna
talk about and I was he kind of said
let's do a year in review and I thought
that would be kind of cool the one thing
that stood out to me too is you got
super [ __ ] sick at the end of the
year yeah you back you like 100% or you
95 I'm good on my way back that's what
you need so I lost a bunch of weight and
being skinny and losing a bunch of
weight ain't really good so now you
looked you looked anorexic and scary
skinny I think we realized in 2014
health is one of the most important
things that we have taking care of our
bodies is really sorry where should
happen on the computer here but it's
alright we're recording
take care of our bodies is really
important and with him getting so sick
now we're trying to get them back
together and get them healthy and
gaining some more weight eating properly
is one thing we've kind of clicked into
doing there see you guys taking great
care of yourselves
going to the gym too now well this will
be Spencer's first time going to the gym
today I don't want to go exercise in
front of anybody it's so and it's in our
location there are a lot of large people
so I'm sure you guys don't even look
that silly they're like an Olympic
athlete out there everything I am he's
in the NBA yeah
you're the only black person around here
well if you go by the college but then a
black a lot of black folk you should
wear your grill to the gym they just go
hard just go hard all day you lost your
grill on a different shelf for a minute
it's in a different pocket Maddy grew my
girl-scout cookies times king Kim grape
stop ROG cross and it looked beautiful
yeah I had two different nose I had four
plants all together but to fiy nose of
the same thing and one got huge and the
nodes were really far away totally
different color the smaller plant the
other Fino turned purple at the end of
flower but was super frosty the other
one wasn't as frosty though I thought
you did a good job I'm not sure if that
thing is never gonna get to market I
think that might just be something that
the crew around here gets to grow but
you did a good job with that so shout
out to understand show alright so for a
year in review both of you guys are
involved in these questions you can both
have an answer you can take turns
ah what were some of your favorite
strains to grow since we're all growers
in the room and I might answer on some
of these questions too and since we'll
do a year in review well let's see I
think at the beginning of the year I was
still stuck on the whole Girl Scout
cookie thing and I was anything Girl
Scout cookies I was kind of running
through and I still currently still have
a lot of different you know just
different unique cookie stuff but I
putted I grew that Yeti og and that kind
of put me onto the og side of you know
things so now I've been kind of trekking
and trying to find different strains
like I picked up triangle the other day
so that's another good one to have
around um but I'd probably say yetis far
as my favorite plant is a year to grow
Wow that's a huge compliment
yeah not suggesting I was gonna say
that's one Jessie found for what am I
follow up questions was gonna be do you
prefer to grow different stuff for oil
to if you're gonna smoke it for flour do
you grow up for yourself do you grow a
different strain and then grow different
for Earl um a lot of times oil is just
depending on
what we have available at the time so
like if we have certain strains that we
know that are better and oil than they
are in flour will make oil and they're
the same like we have Kanna tonic right
now which we're gonna you know split and
do some oil and then some like capsules
so there's a little bit of mix of oh
yeah that's why I feel real high they
also gave me too
two of those hash capsules right before
we started the show and we've done a lot
of yeah I was like how why am I getting
heavy and then you said that so Kanna
tonic is that the super high CBD strain
um it's not a crazy high it's a good
ratio so three two one THC or CBD THC
ratio so it's nice and great medicine
great medicine yeah sure yeah that'll
make great medicine for people are you
gonna take you to do you have a specific
patient in mind or a type of patient
like an epileptic or someone with us or
something I have a couple people have a
couple people who are also like cancer
patients that I want to try to get some
clefto and see if you know just it's not
gonna hurt to give it a try especially
when it's you know you're fighting
cancer you might as well try all you can
hell yeah I agree that's cool that you
guys help people out you guys came from
North Carolina and set up shop in
Colorado and they give away a lot of
medicine and for people to be able to
move at it from out of state and do that
is really cool because there are a lot
of people that are really stingy with
what they grow we just love to share
with other people and show people what
we do yeah
that's why you guys are so well-known
cuz you share and you're super kind I
think why we moved from North Carolina's
cuz I wanted it and when I lived in
North Carolina I wanted to tell
everybody I grew weed but he was illegal
but I was like yo come look at this room
like I'd crack the door open and people
be like what there's so many people that
you know like you you do the same thing
so it's like let me see your weed okay
here's my wheat here's my oil you know
it's just you know everything's comin
I'd one thing I do wish I do wish the
barter system with pot was a little bit
better because it would take money out
of the equation
yeah if I could just go to the
restaurant and pay for it an eighth I
know
you know Maddie what was your some of
your favorite [ __ ] to grow this year
definitely I don't know who it's from
but there was in New York City diesel
FINA we had and it tastes like and
smells like red wine and we had put it
in this big circle jar all of our
friends including me would just
literally stick their faces in it for it
was insane and then the oil from it was
even crazier it just had such a potent
flavor it was almost it mix it with
something else to kind of dial it down a
little bit and then definitely at the
end of the year one of my last favorites
is a tangerine haze times the white yeah
I just found out that I have two
packages of that in my little vault and
that [ __ ] is going to be ran well you're
looking at me like well lets you run it
and give me clones at the keeper
unfortunately we were in the middle of a
process where we didn't know what we
were doing with our garden or if we were
relocating so I decided not to take
clones of it which was a huge mistake
because I had a fee no that was heavier
in the white and had a really good
flavor to it the oil of course is
amazing tangerine oil tastes crazy yeah
she gave me a couple dabs of this
tangerine oil so I'll give you I've got
to pack two seeds I'll give you a pack
maybe both of them you run them and you
find that tangerine Fino and you give me
a climate and then that'll be a good
trade I'll take a keeper out of that
[ __ ] okay the nice tangerine flavored
one and then maybe I'll breed to that
tangerine flavored female I'm so glad
you said that because that was
definitely one of my favorite strains
that's from down with dirt seeds shout
out Riley that's a great stream good
selection usually if you breed to the
white it either comes out nothing like
you don't get any flavor or you get all
that dank and I had yeah like I said I
had one Fino that came out a really
strong white flavor and the tangerine
was still there but it was definitely a
back note to it which was nice whatever
you were giving me dabs of was delicious
for sure I was like y'all got some
overdose dabs
you're like falesha good dads go away
quickly I've been trying to conserve
what I made and it's hard
I just want to dab the [ __ ] out of my
dad's all day we're gonna take a battery
we keep saying the D word so many times
oh gee over here what do you got I've
got a little bit of live that I got from
my good friend Spence a while back it's
the gorilla haze and then I've also got
some some of the shatter that I made
that's parchment paper y'all imagine the
size of parchment that it takes to make
that sound you guys listeners yeah
that's a nice pizza there you go
nicely medicated highly-educated my next
question that I want to talk about for
the year I might mention a couple of
strains I don't even want to talk about
my own strains I should but that feels
Dilemma Joey it's your own or something
did you grow anything that you there's a
few strange you grew this year that you
know that white widow Vince was amazing
little boy I like the punchline emoji is
pretty unique there's some of it over
there in a jar curing still and I took a
bunch of that to the string cheese show
so what I would light it the people
around me would be like the glue came
around I think everybody's impressed
with what it does yeah I want to grow
that again
I took cuts to grow it again a couple
more times because I definitely want to
put it in a bigger pot to give it more
love more training more nitrogen guys if
you grow the gorilla glue feed the [ __ ]
out of that plant early like yeah it's
hungry it wants a little bit of
everything just over feed it if you
think you're gonna [ __ ] it up in week
four feed it more just feed it more it
should be okay I'm gonna take a dab
somebody's got to say something so I'll
ask a question what were some of your
biggest growing evolutions and one of my
favorites is lemon Jeffrey the white
widow and the Gorilla Glue I guess will
settle on those and the Yeti of course
what are some of your favorite the
biggest growing evolutions that you guys
made at the garden of Weeden this year
and I kind of know what you're gonna say
and I'm gonna give a shout out to
somebody after you do it and I'll know
what you want so she that's called the
cage thing oh yeah we kind of changed
what with you know stuff changing and
like regulation in laws and stuff like
that you kind of got a change with the
game so now we're kind of instead of
doing a roomful of multiple plants we're
doing less plants same space but just
bigger Longer veg plants so we really
get to take care of a lot of you know
get to spend more time with each plant
work on canopy management
you know stuff like that so shout out to
Greenworks
check it out right there on my paper
really set up an awesome plan for their
grow and a lot of people are catching on
to what they're doing because with the
plant account now we have to do
something better yeah as a breeder it's
scary to see these plank count
limitations coming but luckily I just
teamed up with the spot shout-out to the
spot so let's do some breeding in there
so those are those cages pretty much
your biggest evolution of growing yeah
we kind of learned you did a lot of T
stuff you advanced your T's I saw the
alfalfa sprouts I saw some [ __ ] like
that happen I did what do we do this
year we did the barley straw that has
like natural barley straw barley seeds
and it grows okay we did a lot of stuff
with uh grow kocchi kocchi like that was
a big hit this year a lot of girl cause
she's big and then just kind of going
back a lot of going back to the basics
the kavita's yeah I've been talking
about the light that Jessie gave me I
might not even be able to run it you
guys my grow rooms got like a 7-foot
ceiling I grow my plants to usually five
and a half feet tall and I've been told
that you got to keep the plants three
feet from those lights you'll burn them
I mean I don't want to say you will burn
them because there's probably cover
strains that could grow closer than
three feet but I just think they it
would definitely stresses a man it's
just too much spectrum and too much just
I mean that those if you've never been
in aggravated I'm totally like that you
know how powerful they are a spot they
just hired me at the spot there's 227
kavita's and they try on a small portion
and it's like it's like you just won't
good oh [ __ ] come on method seven if you
guys are listening I could use a sponsor
by you despise yeah they said they would
but I mean still if I can get them on
the on the DL from
actually harvest honey head a part of
Estonia help you out okay harvest honey
I don't mean to bust you out on the show
actually I do because she's trying to be
Miss High Times so check her out that's
I don't say vote for her but check her
out give her a good run do what you
think where the [ __ ] was I shout out to
Green Works follow those guys is it just
at Green Works on Instagram something
like that he's gonna search right quick
there the guys kind of inspired the idea
for Spence is cages single plants frogs
single plant a single plant Scroggs and
gigantic containers but did you tell
them how we switched our zone I mean
yeah people have seen pictures I don't
have to tell you can check out a garden
of Weeden on Instagram instead of just
instead of using the big squares I don't
want a copy moment [ __ ] from there it is
green underscore works underscore yeah
check it out Oh check them out they have
an awesome feed yeah and make sure you
follow a garden of Weeden don't follow
one of the fake garden of Weeden look
for pictures of these folks yeah don't
do that
yeah don't follow the punk one there's a
couple of the bunk garden of Whedon's
and they always send me messages and
[ __ ] don't reply because I don't want to
be a hater so just ignore it
but make sure that you find a picture of
the dude Spence is a six foot six foot
four six foot five black guy with the
beard and dreadlocks I mean if there's
not pictures of that dude on there don't
follow that one and then Maddie's a
pretty lady they're standing together so
I mean it's easy to spot them they
probably hit an expensive rig or in the
picture so we have expensive at least we
know we worked hard for it
yes I'm just saying you guys are always
at there hey not just your own you're
all the cool events and [ __ ] yeah we're
so lucky we have so many friends with
awesome toys that we get to play with
all the time yeah this industry is so
great when you make friends in this
community slash industry you get to hit
so many cool rigs and Master Shake yeah
he's up on the Shelf maybe later yeah
that that's a good competition there
Master Shake against the rig that Spence
brought over who made that rig you
brought
I don't know his name but it's BC glass
eye with a qwave crying something yeah
with a banger on it and this [ __ ] yeah
that thing kicks you right in the dick
and smiles it looks at you like you
should name it Nelson is that the guy
from the Simpsons is that his name they
should name it Nelson cuz it's just like
hits you and just kicks you right in the
dick and laughs it's a great rig but I'm
kind of offended by the way it hit me I
had a look at it a second time
reconsider if I wanted to hit again I
wanted to hit it again I will hit it
again but yeah I get that I ain't
scurred alright so we talked kind of
about growing evolutions I didn't change
too much I'm learning more about
breeding and I learned that one of the
methods I tried I overdid it and I don't
need to apply so damn much cuz it [ __ ]
up my plants I tried to I make my own
silver thiosulfate and I applied way too
many applications and I learned that if
you overdo it it just pisses the plants
off and you don't get enough pollen and
it sucks so that's what I learned
that's my growing evolution who'd you
guys notice this year other than Green
Works who stood out in the weed
community you can talk about good and or
bad stuff cuz you covered your face like
you [ __ ] or like well alright man
let's see I'll give a shout-out to like
all the people that are you know not
necessarily going away from bottle
nutrients but people who are you know
expanding their grow game into
biologicals um I was actually just in
differ on Monday and I got to meet up
with the microfusion guys I got some
bags in microfusion for you nice socks
um and then shout-out to the mills guys
um always hooking me up when I see you
pays the bills yes never used mills
never have back in the day - one time no
I used one of your homies used it on
Instagram I think I used to follow
somebody that talked about bills bills
people talking about it right Seattle
that started using it and she raved
about it for outdoor her plants were
beautiful too and
she is all about Mills so when he
started talking about it well I talked
to her a lot a bit about it she said it
was a good idea so we went ahead and got
samples and then when we met him and we
they teamed up microfusion
then they're doing shopping together now
their line is now teamed up so they have
their whole feeding chart with the
microfusion mixed in also one of these
days soon we're gonna make a field trip
it's gonna be Spence and Jesse and
myself and Maddy you can come too if you
want we're gonna go to the worm company
in Springs the rocky mountain worm
company and go visit Jay and stock up on
some organic keep the more in my kitchen
all right
so I'll do all the organic growers like
probiotics farmers alliance those types
of guys who were shot now for who we
noticed alright that's cool just miss
green thumb I met her one time on
accident I bought a beer rig and she was
sitting across the table Davin and I had
my shirt on and she complimented it and
was like you want to hit it and she's
like yet and then she goes here you're
that guy and I was like I am because she
recognized me from Instagram so
everybody at the secret check out Miss
green thumb on Instagram and check out
her calling on her feet so awesome when
everyone saying compliments to the
grower miss green thumb and she got a
lot of recognition for her for her work
this year so compliments to her yeah
yeah she grew arms the size of my are
buds the size of my arms for sure they
were long yeah yeah you and her probably
some of the are the two best female
growers that I know I appreciate for
sure maybe we can get her on the podcast
one day yeah I've told her she can come
I've told her so
people live in Denver and [ __ ] they
don't want to drive down this town a pod
cage number one the dangerous city in
because like every day there's just
violent crimes right it's just the
population around it's just a population
so why don't I mind my own business and
I don't have any problems do my own
thing all right so I guess since we're
talking about [ __ ] the town and stuff
that we see here's a great question
after seeing it's been a full year of
legalization like a year and five days
now since we've legalized recreational
adult use cannabis in the state of
Colorado I remember the moment that you
could buy a weed at a store in Colorado
but like after this full year how do you
feel about it and what have you seen
difference yes you guys are from a whole
other state it's it's legal so they have
to regulate it and some of the
regulations are shitty yeah but it's
stuff that has to be done if the whole
you know the country wants to use
Colorado or Washington as an example to
go legal across the board they're gonna
have to be it's gonna have to be
regulated like if it wants to be
everywhere so eventually like it's gonna
happen
it sucks first small people like myself
who are small business mom and pop
trying to be small business yeah kind of
always remember go to the moment pops
yeah you always find better stuff there
and you will the big store for sure yeah
check the spot first
all right Maddy what did you notice over
the last year so many people from out of
state are flooding into Colorado yeah
you know what a lot of people are from
North Carolina its North Carolina and
Texas that have moved here just cuz you
know us it's the only region in North
Carolina we are all from yeah
you brought the town of Dixie with you
yeah Dixie is empty now like just just
dust left only and all of our friends
though learned how to grow amazing weed
this year all of our friends are really
caught on quickly and learned a lot from
from us and also yourself and Instagram
it's not only social network a great
media to learn a lot your guyses table
at the should the new and the old house
as part of what started me thinking
about I should do something because I
would go to your place and guys it's
Vincent Maddie's old place and the new
place but people would fly from North
Carolina and come visit these guys and
just hang out for the weekend and when I
would show up to come dab them out and
kind of maybe give them some Irish seeds
and a t-shirt and some stickers for
visiting and maybe a hatpin they would
start asking weed questions and no [ __ ]
ten guys came and nine of them asked the
same exact first three questions and I
was like I should just record this
somewhere and play it back at him like
here is my answer like an automated weed
service or some [ __ ] but I got good at
talking to people at the table and
talking about growing weed like that and
so your guys's table kind of open this
up a little bit word I know you're here
so that's kind of silly our table is a
hot topic because we're always just
taking dabs and talking about different
growing subjects and there's always so
many different people there it's always
a different conversation there's always
something to learn such a crazy mix of
people black eye dart at that part of
the map and I missed trying to figure
out where I was aiming for there's an
Asian guy from his Vietnamese dude then
a couple of white dudes couple
chihuahuas couple people that I can't
even tell what they are my work ass it's
a nice mix of people over there yeah
people just flood in when there's legal
weed why wouldn't you we come from a
place where you can't have more than a
gram on you yeah well you get a citation
like if it's under 1/8 or half eighth or
something like
but if it's more you have the
possibility of going to jail that's
still that's still real in places I'm so
free we're going home at the end of the
month and so most nerve-racking because
we can't be ourselves there yeah we're
so used to Colorado everything's so
easygoing and free
I'm staying inside yeah yeah that's
smart that's smart here I forget that
we're still supposed to people forget
that there's an open container law that
applies to cannabis here you're supposed
to have your weed in a container that's
sealed up and out of your reach like in
it's probably supposed to be in the
trunk honestly I put mine I've got an
SUV so my trunk I can reach the trunk in
my car I can reach everything I'm
[ __ ] 65 and I have an SUV yeah so
know what no matter where I put it so I
put it in the backpack in a container
and my dabs are always out of reach and
in the backseat I mean that's how I roll
sometimes there may have been card abs I
wanted to be a smartass and ask why he
had no what time it was but none of my
jokes are gonna be appropriate oh that's
a good good change for the notice that
when everybody got sick everybody got
like deathly ill end of the year the new
guys older like [ __ ] cigarettes and then
he came back strong so that's good
Congrats on that I'm proud of you guys
accomplishment definitely dabs tastes
completely different once you get your
once you get your full palate back I
still haven't gotten mine full one back
I don't think so this is just Newports
the new boy that got me through some
years there's some stressful
my life is hard hard you know what we
didn't see after legalization a whole
bunch of crime all bunch of murder a
whole bunch of rape a whole bunch of
little kids running around smoking
spliffs a bunch of people walking in the
park just getting high it's everyone's
happy yeah yeah cuz yeah what is there
to fight over when it's legal it is it's
like the no-brainer I just don't
understand why other states don't follow
hear that Maddie's got a point guys if
you're in another state
[ __ ] legalize weed there what the hell
legalize cannabis around the country
would make yeah and have less people in
jail for pointless crimes and make some
money off of cannabis taxes because the
state of Colorado makes a [ __ ] ton I
could google it but that'll give me give
me sidetracked they make a whole [ __ ]
ton of money yes
I'll probably try to do that on episode
49 or 50 we'll talk about those numbers
I'll get Mike here Mike's good with
numbers what's up Mike you've been
working hard bros I'm Adam Jesse that
whole crew Tony they all been working
their asses off proud of them they're
getting some [ __ ] done what am I
supposed to say fish cut faster I think
that's what I'm supposed to say yeah
they listen to the podcast at the
worksite fish do something bro [ __ ]
do something come on man you play xbox
later brother come on man
all right so full year of legalization
and nobody's been [ __ ] raped and
killed no kids with joints what's my
next question oh the garden of Weeden
bro you guys want a bunch of awards this
year what are some of your proudest
achievements
sorry I just got deep on you we had to
go through a lot of hardships this year
so definitely getting our win for secret
cut mountain was awesome for us pulling
everything together and getting our
entry right and perfecting live resin or
not I don't know if you'd consider
perfecting but working on we just got
really good you guys are part of the
pioneering process of libraries trying
to perfect live resin
[ __ ] but I've been dad and I call
perfect I don't know what else you're
gonna do shit's good enough yeah I was
so awesome to win the secret cut because
we were with all of our friends and it
was an awesome competition it's pretty
fair in my opinion because you have four
if anybody doesn't know you have a box
with I how many entries were there this
year I think there were 32 maybe 30
something it's just cool because you
know you get to compete with especially
Colorado Colorado's like the first place
to do weed stuff yeah so like now you
got it's supposed to be like the mecca
of oil makers so it's cool to try to win
that you know or win it for Colorado and
compete against people you know who
because she can to just won the
Amsterdam Cup yeah with the comb when I
was standing there I was standing next
to my girl and they're like when Big B
announced he goes like y'all know who
won first place are you already know who
it is and I was like why don't know I
don't like I was like well then that
made me think well obviously it's not
spins cuz it's something that would be
it's like gonna be one of those popular
guys it's got stickers everywhere and
[ __ ] everyone knows him and they were
all high-fiving him as he walked in and
I was like I didn't [ __ ] see bomb
anywhere [ __ ] garden of Weeden in us
all I could say was holy [ __ ] I just
looked at my girl like did really do we
know them and you guys walked up to the
front she's like shouldn't you go up
there and I was like let my home he have
his minute for a minute like let him do
his thing and then everyone in the
crowds are gonna be like dude they moved
out of my way so that I could walk up
towards you guys and they did like all
like the lower the next but the bottom
Awards not bottom but like most times
yeah all that and we didn't win none of
that I was like [ __ ] and then they did
third place and it was who was third
place kind bill Oh
[ __ ] and then second place was cushy
candy and then I looked at Matty I was
like we win it and then he he went
through the whole rant was like it was
time so look on your face is great you
guys were kind of in shock for a minute
so shocked he didn't even know what to
say so he just had to you know his
speech was great though yeah perfect
yeah something about run even from here
so this is [ __ ] cool like do this and
I did this yeah
the best part about it is we had all of
our friends pretty much from North
Carolina we're at the event with us so
the best thing is to win with the people
beside you that you started with a lot
of people thought that I grew that
material and I had to correct a lot of
them cuz Spence was wearing as I read
genetics hoodie and so is Maddie there's
in the washer right now though good
clean the dog hair situation going on
shout out to all the dogs
what's that Jerry boy are you listening
maybe Stella are you there it's all the
dogs where was I oh yeah proudest
achievements so yeah win in that secret
company that was fun I was there with
you what's the other stuff you guys keep
winning on Thursday we wanna top-shelf
Thursday and ever there's multiple
social clubs in Denver too so if you're
ever bored and you want to go smoke
somewhere just drive the Denver and
Google social smoke Club this one is
called 7:10 social lounge okay
remember those but you can pay like a
member price you pay like 25 bucks and
you can go in there for any time you
want for a month no it's nice it's
really nice and they've last month they
did or last time they did a 16 person
bracket just and then it broke all the
way down to the finals and then I won
the finals I've got a free rig got a
bunch of stuff like that now they're
doing another round and now it's 32
people
yeah so it's a bigger bracket and they
wanted me to do it but I just I want to
focus more growing weed this year there
you go and I still make oil but I want
to focus on making sure my tweets at
where it should be at
before I even make oil and see that's
why I wasn't even making oil before I
wanted to breed and make sure that [ __ ]
was on point like do that and let you
hash makers there's a lot of fun making
hash firstly I should go from go ahead
oh one thing with all these competitions
this year also we met a lot of amazing
people in Denver specifically because we
used to go to Denver we used to not
really know that many people and then we
started going to the social club we kind
of connected with a lot other people so
if you are new to Colorado that's a good
opportunity to meet a lot of other
fellow dabbers even if you're just
somebody that's in the 7 10 or 20
community from Colorado and you want
other people to for sure find us it like
I'll beat the cannabis cup for sure
I don't really rep the high times events
but I'll be there it's the High Times
Cannabis Cup it's April 19th it's like
yeah it's three days this year a lot of
dope-ass events planned out I'll be
there I will not have a booth I was
offered a booth I declined
I'd rather roam around and do a task
rock style just take my backpack and do
what I can
yeah it'll go quickly I'm sure but it's
more fun that way I don't feel tied down
when I have a booth I can walk around
and go see who I want to and then get
the [ __ ] out when I'm ready and then
yeah yeah I'll get a booth in a couple
years I'm just not ready for that I
don't want to invest into that and be
tied down I need to have some employees
that will run the booth the whole time
for me that's what I want before I
measure yeah I'm not ready for that so
if you're looking forward to me having a
booth at the cup I apologize but I'm
really tall I'm really white I got
really long dreadlocks and I'm worn a
high region etics t-shirt and or hoodie
and I got a backpack no miss yeah let me
get a spot we're easy to find all right
so what's next for the garden of Weeden
you guys oh don't be like the gym after
this I mean you know 2015 focus on
growing and getting back to the basics
and really work well particularly lately
been working on our veg just getting our
veg absolutely perfect nice and just
making sure all of our stuff is top of
the line getting all of our equipment in
check we just four new growers
did you hear what Madi just said pay
attention
to the Venge you guys don't pay enough
attention to veg I'm not scolding any of
you I'm saying a lot of people don't pay
enough attention not you specifically
not you sorry no pay enough attention to
veg you could you could pay more I'm
sure I love that bedroom as much as you
love the flower room because that's
where it all starts healthy children
make healthy adults if you'd like you
can expect your flower plants to be
amazing when you have a shitty bed and
sometimes even us we sometimes start to
get so caught up in our flower room that
like I said our bed started falling
behind a little bit so we're gonna work
on just making sure all of our garden is
in check in/check you guys have a nice
team I like how you guys can handle [ __ ]
I've seen it happen you're like we got
to do something awesome so [ __ ]
awesome Big Mike you're my bigger Mike
call me Big Mike nine one nine on
Instagram check him out that's one of
our good homies okay Barack Oh gonzo
that's him that's him it's a rocking
Ana's bodyguard what's up Mikey come be
on the podcast whenever you want bro but
we're gonna give you big dabs like isn't
into the giant dab thing like we are
over here glob squad glob squad what's
up sloppy love you bro haven't heard
from you in a little while I don't have
a new phone number that's my excuse and
I really don't cuz I'm texting the old
phone number apparently I didn't know
you had a new number
oops I'm texting because they shouldn't
get those message for the show we've
been going like 45 minutes we should you
want to do that part um I'll go find
that on YouTube I think I got it save it
Spence is thinking don't think too hard
brushes too podcast I just put this
season I germinated of the lemon
Geoffrey time crossed you wanna have
that conversation
Jay Casey Jesus oh no nice so when you
guys are when we're taught this is just
random side talk when we're talking
about strains a lot of times people and
I tried to avoid it also but so many
people said it that I got sucked into it
a lot of
we'll say the [ __ ] the lintels times
the grateful dog and I like to say
crossed to but so what do you guys think
tweet me that it's agriculture which I
wish I could change that but I can't
[Music]
I'll think about it we'll see what we
could do just make a new one and then
add the link to that one in that one I
might have to do it I'm gonna write it
down new Twitter but tell me what you
think how should we say that is that
what does that X mean because it's not
math it doesn't mean x times two would
make the four you know if we've to bone
to it would have for was what would come
out it's all still though I just don't I
mean technically could be right me
personally I just think when it comes
out of my mouth it just does not sound
right because we're not doing math
alright so let's start something new
yeah what's new watch it if you come up
with something that somebody I'll give
you the opportunity if you can think of
can I get like phone friend or something
I mean you can take it down alive I'll
try to get this dabble live resin for
you man once I'm gonna have you come on
the show until the whole process I can't
afford that [ __ ] just beatboxing right I
mean her office we said that one was
cool just to not the woman Jeff [ __ ] the
Grateful dog I can say that when I talk
it like it the cannabis cup to people
they were gonna be offended some people
might like it yeah so and f is for
finial for a generational label alright
I'll let you take the dab and we'll let
you try I'll let you try again all right
well you guys hear that let's turn the
letter there it is
[Music]
all right now into the sky what's the
new word you should find a solution okay
and Jesse that's crazy
[Music]
this is a white people [ __ ] yeah but I
bet you ate it up just like the rice and
mushrooms yeah you did I appreciate it I
don't know if I'm gonna double up if I
play the garden of Weeden song I don't
know if I have some other [ __ ] plan bro
so learn and we're gonna double up on
two songs out of him awkward
[ __ ] everyone's heads all up all right
we're gonna start wrapping up this show
before we go I do you want to say a
couple of things first I want to thank
you guys for coming do there's an
awesome podcast that was fun
first girl on the or the first woman
credit woman on the show at your
location it's awesome thank you thank
you fist bump
who's Vince is looking at the weed
there's some lemon Geoffrey over there
in a jar that I grew there's some
platinum og some girls got cookies some
Grateful dog and some lemon Jeff grown
by me take a peach I can't told her this
from that angle
that's grateful dog I think I think so
crack it open cracking nugs I'm gonna
talk while he does that yeah guys thanks
for coming let me remind you guys a
couple things I'm changing the name it's
not agriculture it's the girl from your
heart podcast now I don't want to get
sued by that other company as I could
use a new logo by the way well it's my
fault that we'd bet fall out there but
it's so sticky you won't know it's I
stole somebody's name on accident I
didn't realize it but they got all
popular and now they're like oh you like
that so but it's cool I got a cool name
girl from your heart sounds good that's
what it's all about
could use a logo keep asking for a new
song you know I'm gonna keep playing
that song from the mystic roots man and
other mystic roots band songs cuz they
said I could and they're free and I like
it I'm cancelling the Instagram for the
podcast
there won't be an agriculture podcast
Instagram but the IRA genetics one will
exist what are you gonna leave it up so
you can go steal all the pictures or
whatever has the links I'll just start
posting those pictures to the Huayra
Genetics Instagram and have one feed
instead of having two feeds I'm trying
to keep up with it's just a lot of [ __ ]
and then it sounds like a bunch of
bitching but it is and I'll probably
cancel the YouTube for the podcast also
and just keep the and start doing
something with the IRA genetics YouTube
or something just so much goddamn media
I can't keep up and I want to focus on
doing a good podcast is really what I'm
gonna want to do if you guys want to
email me you can use agriculture
hotmail.com or grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
I check them both episode 50 is coming
up I think Spence will make it I think
Maddie will make it we'll have Jesse
hopefully get mine check it Adam you
guys are divided if you're listening
yeah there we go
Jesse Adam Mike Matty spins myself that
might fill this little
basically you guys might have to [ __ ]
go
yeah so episode 50 will be a small
celebration Jessie teased that he would
have some prizes I definitely have at
least an IRA genetics t-shirt or three
to give away like a hat pan anybody's
got any prizes or something I got some
teach okay yes Weedon prizes coming on
episode fifty it's always really like
that random prize yeah yeah that's kind
of what I'm doing too until I run
downstairs and check the little box that
I've been I've been just it into a pile
you know I don't want to dedicate too
much but when episode 50 comes Jessie
promised some stuff so what's up Jessie
if you listen to rap sub 50 is in like a
week and a half if you listen to this uh
guys I want you to message me let me
know what you learned on the podcast
because we want to talk about that on
episode 50 and recap for you like we did
the year in review I kind of want to
know your what you learned from the show
I wanna know who your favorite guests
were I think I just listed them right it
was [ __ ] Spencer Jesse Mike Adam
Maddy has been on the show lately Clint
an awesome guest Sean dude [ __ ] I
think Sean got the most listens
Sean definitely got the most listened
yeah if you want to come be on episode
50 you can bro but it's gonna be a party
I'd kind of rather reserve your
knowledge for when it's just even i
face-to-face cuz you [ __ ] school me
and it's awesome so guys if there's
somebody around here you'd like to have
on the podcast let me know it's hard for
me to reach out to people if you have
something you want me to ask other
people and you have some ideas if you
like get this person on back that up
with a like and ask them this and I'll
do that because that'll help me out go
for it
I was gonna say now I can no you can
nobody can hear you now so go for it I
got you back over there so send me some
input you guys it's Agriculture
hotmail.com girl from your heart
hotmail.com or you could tweet me it's
Agriculture I might make a new one since
been said that idea it's kind of smart I
probably will the girl from your heart
will have a new Twitter page I'm sure
there's something that's weird from your
heart somewhere else that's gonna
[ __ ] try to sue me for that too but
it's what we're getting or no
yeah we'll just we'll stand up for this
one I have had that on my website for a
long time so I think I own that one all
right cool big fist bumps everybody at
the table I'm gonna read this part it
goes now that the show is over please go
to iTunes or stitcher go to the iTunes
or stitcher main page and search for the
iGrow culture podcast search for the
girl from your heart podcast or one of
the two search for both find the review
section give us a five star rating after
that type in a comment let me know what
you think of the show and I will read
your comments on the podcast guys don't
forget that the show is available on
iTunes and stitcher and every single
episode will always be archived at I
read genetics Colorado com you can leave
comments there as well make sure you
follow everyone on Twitter Instagram and
Facebook its garden of Weeden all one
word with an end at the garden of weed
and make sure you follow those guys make
sure you follow Greenworks we told you
how to spell that earlier I hope you got
excite for God's I'm high highs for the
- you guys you showed up with a bunch of
great dabs man no problem definitely
brought the Yeti og that's one of our
favorites the flavor on it's ridiculous
that rig dude broke my face it made it a
whole challenge to do a podcast at the
beginning it was kind of mean make sure
you follow I read genetics on Instagram
please do that we're at like 10,000 and
some change now so that's kind of cool
if you guys are interested in sponsoring
the podcast or if you've got a product
you'd like us to review send me an email
to agriculture at hotmail.com or grow
from your heart at hotmail.com and I
will give you all the information you
need I do need a logo keep saying that
big shot at the manager Spence shout out
to Angela thanks again for listening you
guys until next time take a phat dab we
give her mom a hug for me we're gonna
end the show with a song by our boy
sloppy song it takes a second for it to
roll in so we might just ramble for a
second I'm actually gonna fire up a big
dab of this live resin and then we'll
turn the mics down and let the song kick
on in the garden weed and getting weeded
[Music]
everyone's why you gotta make it up in
Farsi
[Music]
in the garden with your girl we'd
[ __ ] all weekend if I don't need it
blow like a bomb my ribs
if you try you can slip if you try and
show you guess this flip rep before the
piece close right in my waist mommy I
know but we smoked just just be hands
down me put your hands down
it ain't fair man I just feel myself
better be a home hero break your own
chain control your own way influence
your all the fittings and backhands and
a puppeteer oboe only strings so move
ain't no puppies here chorus but all
read my state burning witches at the
stake while I keep my plate third eye
strong I can see they fade Indiana's hit
my box a Cavalier the Beast bestows his
three in the priests movies like a peach
and a brother Billy please take it first
place that's a secret don't be childish
Jean it is a crown target yet it holds
it down we don't break it down on blacks
and all these pounds
[Music]
yeah you know what it is yo garden we
didn't holding it down for North
Carolina alligator Colorado big
shout-out to a homie Spanish Betty TV
growing mine don't fish your buzzy
[ __ ] genetics
[Music]