here we go welcome back podcast world it
is time for episode 482 of the Grove
from your heart podcast this episode of
the show is brought to you by seeds here
now if you need new regular feminized or
Auto flower seeds in your garden I
highly recommend seeds here now and you
can find them at www.cdxzipstream.com
[Music]
--scent rate on the podcast before but I
really like dabbing the Curacao live
batter it does say that it tastes like a
vanilla fruit chew I don't remember the
description I gave last time I do know
that I just took a nice low temp dab out
of a freshly-cleaned rig with a fresh
brand new nail and it tastes a little
bit like a candy corn now people are
gonna say that's gross because I don't
like candy corns but imagine if you
could eat a candy corn and not have to
taste that waxy [ __ ] that comes with
it so without that waxy [ __ ] I think a
candy corn would taste really delicious
it's got that vanilla candy flavor it's
got a hint of a fruity flavor at the end
and this Curacao live batter left a
really nice sweet vanilla flavor on my
tongue and I am absolutely enjoying it
so big shout out to our friends at green
dot labs for the perfect Curacao live
batter ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls pimps and hos friends and foes in
this episode I am going to do a little
talk about defoliation we will talk
about why I do it we will talk about
when to do it and we will talk a little
bit about how to do it but before we get
there let's do some shout outs to our
friends who support the show on patreon
let's start off with ladies first how
about a big giant grow from your heart
podcast shout out and thank you to miss
Mel how about a big giant girl from your
heart podcast hi-5 - my buddy Glenn
jeroni how about a big giant shout out
and a thank you to ethan gee i always
want to send a grow from your heart
podcast shoutout and a fist bump to
melvin 8 1/8 of course a giant shout out
in a thank you to Justin I always want
to send a giant thank you to our friend
farmer John of course I want to send a
giant girl from your heart high-five and
a fist
to our friend Sam and last but certainly
not least I want to send a giant thank
you and to grow from your heart podcast
shout out in a fist bump to my friend oh
gee purple thumb big thanks and big
shout out for all of the continued
support if anybody out there would like
to learn how to support the show you can
do so by visiting
www.azcleanelections.gov plants a lot of
growers have a lot of opinions on
defoliating cannabis plants in this
episode i will tell you when and how to
properly defoliate your cannabis plants
before I do that part let me explain to
you why I feel like defoliation is a
good idea maybe I should start by
basically explaining what do I mean by
defoliation I mean taking off excessive
leaves in your grow room any leaves that
are too large that are blocking light
they may become a problem in the future
I take those leaves off early and flower
if not late into the vegetative cycle
and I do this for several reasons my
first reason is to allow light to
penetrate my canopy and get to potential
bud sites and bud sites for better
growth and bud development our main goal
is to grow big potent quality buds if we
can remove some leaf and put some of the
light on more of the buds spend more of
the energy on growing buds and less
energy on growing leaf we have the
potential to increase the overall
harvest weight and the overall quality
of our product so I like to take off
excess leaf to get more light into the
canopy more light to the buds and
potential bud sites I also like to
remove excess leaf to allow more airflow
I work in large scale commercial
environments airflow is important on any
size of scale you are growing but it
gets much more critical as we get into
larger environments and larger rooms and
larger buildings by removing excessive
foliage we can create better airflow
throughout the
entire grow room creating better airflow
through the environment will have
several advantages this will help us
regulate humidity in the grow room being
able to regulate humidity in the grow
room will help us prevent issues like
bud rot this will also help us prevent
issues like powdery mildew so by
removing excess leaf we help to reduce
humidity we also have less opportunity
for things like powdery mildew we also
give ourselves less opportunity for bud
rot now when we remove all those excess
leaves we also give ourselves less
opportunity for pests if you don't have
a bunch of leaves if you don't have a
bunch of excessive foliage there are
less places for bugs to hide it makes it
much easier to treat for pests if you do
have a problem it makes it much easier
to spray preventative sprays to make
sure you don't get a problem and when
your defoliating if you do have a
problem you will absolutely notice a
pest infestation while you're doing the
defoliation work now those are three
basic obvious advantages of defoliating
are cannabis plants and like I've said
before this becomes more necessary as we
increase the size of our grow spaces and
the number of plants I also think that
strategic defoliation will heavily
increase the productivity of the plants
and will also increase the overall
product harvest weight and potency so
there will be several advantages here it
will also make trimming much easier this
will speed up the trim crew yes we did
spend a few days in the growth peeling
off leaves before the trim crew ever got
to it but this will speed them up that
is that many less leaves that make it to
the harvest phase so that is why I
defoliate know a lot of people have this
mentality that the leaves are what hold
the nutrients bro we feed the [ __ ] out
of these plants we are spending a lot of
money on nutrients we are feeding
high-quality nutrients we are mixing up
high quality soils and soil assess and
we are feeding that to our plants they
are getting fed plenty they are not out
in the wilderness trying to survive
they're not homeless they're getting
taken care of they don't need those
excessive leaves you know what is going
to eat from those leaves spider mites
that's who's gonna live there that's
who's gonna feed off of that [ __ ]
let's get rid of that let's help
ourselves out I've said it in a previous
episode I'm going to keep saying it
let's set ourselves up for success so
again in my opinion proper strategic
defoliation can have many great benefits
now let's move toward talking about how
I do my defoliation there are a couple
of very important steps to preparing for
a proper defoliation session one
requirement is good music you need
proper music for a proper defoliation
session in a commercial environment you
can get tunnel vision you've got a large
room and very long rows that I tell four
or five guys hey your whole goal for
today is to D foliate this room give it
like a level three defoliation don't
strip it don't be a [ __ ] but get in
there and pull off a bunch of leaves I
want a bunch of 5-gallon buckets where
the leaves coming out of here get in
there and defoliate what will happen is
the guys will take a little break that's
another one of the requirements if it is
acceptable for you to medicate you've
got to get baked before you D foliate so
if that's your thing get plenty baked
then put on good music then the next
thing that I'm going to say you need is
gloves if you're defoliating take me
seriously on this one
you always need gloves when you were
defoliating plants but let's get back to
this music part why do I want people to
have good music on because the guys in
the big grow tend to get a little bit of
tunnel vision and they will work on one
area of the grow room really heavily and
they will forget to move to the next
table so you'll have 20 tables in the
room two of them will be very well D
foliated the other 18 need a lot of work
they got ignored they forgot they were
there so I tell the guys put on a song
if you're gonna put in ear buds do that
if you're gonna put on the big Bluetooth
speaker that everybody can hear do that
but put on some music put on some
regular music don't listen to fish or
the Grateful Dead because this technique
won't work with fish are the Grateful
Dead their songs are way too long
put on your Pandora or whatever you're
playing today and just let it play and
at the end of each song move down a few
feet or move down to the next table just
know that by the end of the day you've
got to get this whole room done and
don't get too stuck on one table that's
why I tell the guys put on music and
then move after each song just go to
another section move down move six feet
move to another
Table does make progress every song now
the reason I tell them to do that is
because I don't want them to strip one
section really heavily and then we have
to come back tomorrow and strip a couple
more sections really heavily I would
rather them strip the entire room really
lightly and then we'll come back in a
few days and we'll do the entire room
really lightly that way I don't have
like I keep saying section one tables
one two and three are butt naked there's
no leaves over here but tables 4 through
20 are coated and leaves still and it's
all furry we're gonna have different
humidity we're gonna have problems in
the room things are not consistent I
like consistency
I like uniformity in the grow it makes
things easy so I tell the guys go
through and give it all a level-one
strip most of the time the guys nail it
because they know what I expect from
them by now they've been trained pretty
well but they usually go through and
they give it a nice little strip they
don't strip and tour they're naked they
don't they aren't too [ __ ] about it and
leave too many leaves and leave it real
furry they know right where to go take
off those leaves but if I do want it a
little bit more I just saw him go back
through and just do another quick strip
and they can just go through and do
another quick strip that way they don't
go too hard that way they don't take too
many leaves off you can always take more
leaves off but you can never put more
leaves back on so that's another great
segue you will be amazed at how quickly
these leaves grow back and replace
themselves depending on your grow
environment depending on your genetics
and depending on your nutrients you may
cut off these leaves and in four or five
days the plant will be twice as leafy as
it was before and that's a good sign
that is showing that that plant is
productive and that it is growing that
also means that in four or five maybe
six or seven days we have to get back in
there and pull those leaves off again
but we're not there yet we are still on
the first layer of defoliation in most
cases I would recommend no matter what
size your girl environment is if you're
working in a 4x4 tent or if you're in a
hundred light room I would recommend
starting with a light nice even
defoliation then I would go back and
defoliate every few days and light
phases now if you're new and you're just
learning how to do this you may want to
pick one plant and defoliate the living
[ __ ] out of it you might want to pick
another plant and go
kind of hard then pick another one and
go medium then pick another one and go
real light and then pick another one and
don't defoliation then treat those
plants exactly the same otherwise and
see how you like the results does the
plant that you D foliated all the way
does that one grow better than the one
that you didn't defoliate you will
notice differences if you do tests like
that and I am skipping ahead on my notes
a little bit here but defoliation will
be very strain specific it will also
depend on your lighting your nutrients
and your overall grow environment if
your plants are getting a lot of light
and a lot of quality nutrients you're
going to see a lot of production if
you're under smaller lights or your
plants are lacking in nutrition you may
not see as rapid leaf development so
defoliation will depend heavily on your
environment but I'm skipping ahead so
let me keep myself on track here let's
talk about defoliating your grow
environment let's just say maybe you've
got a five by five you've got one light
in there the plants are looking great
they may be in a trellis they may have
sticks holding them up they may not have
any supports this will work for just
about any type of situation this is my
strategy for defoliation weight in the
veg cycle I like to pull all the crap
off the bottom of the plants any little
sucker branches any little leaves that
look like [ __ ] I really clean the plants
up about two weeks before they go into
flower I don't necessarily bottom and
lollipop the plants in veg I will leave
most of the branches on I mainly do just
a defoliation and kind of a those little
sucker branches that are only a quarter
of an inch long and they're just kind of
starting to develop I pull all that crap
off the bottom anything that the light
isn't going to reach I will take all
that crap off the bottom we don't need
that that is going to help the energy
move to the top of the plants and those
tops can grow and get bigger and beefier
that's where we're gonna get our big fat
buds so my defoliation will start late
in veg about two weeks maybe a week
before we go into flower again depending
on the strain and the environment so my
plant may be 12 inches tall coming out
of the pot everything on the bottom
three or four inches of that plant are
going to get cleaned up pretty well all
of the little starts and sucker shoots
that are sticking out off those branch
I'm just gonna clean those off I'll
leave the ends of the branches there and
leave all the foliage up the ends of the
branches but I'm just gonna clean off
the bottoms so that the bottoms of the
plants are nice and clean we don't have
a lot of leaf area down there we don't
have a lot of sucker branches down there
wasting nutrients wasting energy and not
getting any light that part's not gonna
grow for you let's just clean it right
off of there now this will start sending
energy up to the tops of the plants the
plants are gonna start growing a little
more quickly they're getting ready to go
into flower so the first day I put them
into flower is when my defoliation
really starts to begin on day one a
flower I like to begin a very strategic
defoliation now what do I mean by
strategic I want to remove the biggest
leaves in the room those are probably my
first targets I generally remove any
leaves that are blocking light from
getting to a bud site if you've got a
branch that will develop buds on it and
that branch is being blocked by a leaf
and not being allowed to get sufficient
light you can pull that leaf off and let
the light get to the bud site we want to
grow more buds not more leaves so any
leaves that are acting like an umbrella
that are shadowing buds or bud sites
below them I will remove those big
leaves one thing I tell the guys in the
commercial facilities is take off any
leaf with the purple stem if you've got
a big leaf about the size of your hand
and it's got a little purple stem on it
that leaf can go we don't need that leaf
on the plant but I do make a couple of
exceptions I like to leave the leaves at
the very tops of the plants if you've
got a couple of colas that are sticking
up at the top you will always see me
leave the leaves at the very tops of
those buds on there I don't know if that
is a visual thing for me I don't know if
that's an OCD thing something in me
makes me think that the plants want
those first few leaves at the top if
they are not blocking a lot of light
from getting to the lower parts of the
canopy I will leave those I think they
look really good and something in me
feels weird when I remove just those top
two or four big leaves from the top main
buds and again that is just something
inside of me that is something that the
plant says to me I have no science
behind
that is a personal thing that I have
noticed it feels weird to me to take off
those top leaves I will leave those on
until just before harvest it will take
those leaves off at the very end but
that is my one weird exception when it
comes to defoliating I like to take off
most of those giant leaves I will start
by removing every leaf with a purple pea
deol then if you want to dial in your
defoliation for optimal light
penetration here is a very good
technique and this depends on the
quality and power of the light which you
are using if you're using thousand watt
lights your lights are going to
penetrate the canopy much more deeply
than if you're using a 400 watt light so
your defoliation will depend again on
your lighting and your environment so
what you can do I like to put my hand in
the canopy just reach right into the
middle of the canopy and see is the
light hitting my hand and if the light
isn't getting to my hand what leaves
above my hand are blocking it then if I
feel like the light should be getting
that far into the canopy I will remove
the leaves that are in the way that are
not allowing that light to get down to
those bud sites that I want to get nice
and fat so if you've got any leaves
acting like an umbrella that are
covering up a bud site just feel free to
pull them off that will be very
beneficial to that bud site below now
you do have to consider the power of
that light what type of penetration do
you realistically expect from that light
we can only defoliate so heavily to
allow more penetration we may need to
remove stuff from the bottom because it
is not going to get light no matter how
many leaves we remove but we're gonna
talk about that in a future episode when
we talk about bottoming and Lolly
popping and popping and twisting the
plants let's stay focused here on
defoliation so if you've got a thousand
watt light and it's a few inches above
the plants and you feel like that light
should probably penetrate 18 to 24
inches into the canopy put your arm in
there about 18 inches in so you've got
your 6 to 12 inches from the light is
the top of your canopy and then go down
another 18 inches and that's where we're
hoping to get light penetration is the
light touching your hand are there a
bunch of shadows over your hand move
your hand you're gonna have to move
around branches and you're gonna have to
do some adjusting but move around are
you getting light on your hand if not
you can probably defoliate a little bit
now I've said this at the start of the
episode don't go in there and crazily
defoliate I don't know how leafy your
plants are I don't know what genetics
you're growing I don't know what type of
nutrients you're using I don't know what
kind of light you've got I don't know
what kind of VPD you're working with
I don't know how leafy you're starting
with and I don't know how the plants are
going to react so go light go in there
and just do a level-one defoliation I
don't know how big your room is so I
don't even know how many leaves you
should expect to pull out of there just
go pull a bunch of leaves and just look
in there and say does it look like I've
done anything and it probably won't just
leave it right there you'll be okay
see how the plants react then in two or
three days do it again and just keep
doing it until you think huh those look
a little bit bare once you start
thinking they kind of almost look like I
took too much off that's probably right
where you want to be but again you can
always take off more leaf we cannot glue
the leaves back onto the plants so let's
take off a few leaves here on day one if
you are new wait a few days
maybe three maybe five days and do a
visual inspection if you're comfortable
with taking off more leaves do that and
repeat that process until you are
comfortable with the art of defoliating
now once you are comfortable with it
I recommend a defoliation at the start
of week one we'll go semi-hard at week
one cuz we want to clean up we haven't
taken any leaves off it's a big thick
jungle a mess we got to get in there and
shave her up for the very first time and
make her look good week one we're gonna
go semi-hard
week three we're just gonna go back and
kind of clean up what is regrown then
again at week five we're starting to get
bud sites we can see where all the buds
are gonna be this is when I will clean
off any of the small sucker branches
that I'm sure are not gonna make it into
anything anything they got left behind
on previous cleanings and bottoming
'he's that's all gonna get removed at
this point and again I will do a medium
heavy defoliation around week five then
I'm going to go back around week seven
and I'm going to do the final
defoliation now this one is fun because
we are getting big sticky buds at this
time your arms are gonna get sticky your
shirts gonna get sticky wear proper
gloves and clothing
I really recommend long sleeve shirts
when you're in there defoliating because
when that red
start sticking to your arm here it
really becomes uncomfortable and it is
really a [ __ ] to get off if you don't
know grower tricks so on week one we're
going to get in there and we're going to
remove everything with a purple PDL
we're going to use our hand to reach
into the canopy and see if the light is
reaching our hand or our arm if it's not
we'll remove a few more leaves to try to
make that light get to those lower bud
sights if you're a new grower and you're
not comfortable with a strong
defoliation do a light defoliation and
pay attention to the plants and then
keep pulling leaves as you feel
comfortable and you will gain confidence
as you go when that plant doesn't die
and you see it increased productivity
because of your pulling of leaves you
will gain confidence and you will want
to go in there and remove more leaves
and then you will find that balance one
day you'll pull too many and you'll go
oh I pissed it off so get in there and
experiment and learn the balance once
you get comfortable we'll do a hard
strip on week one then on week three we
go back and we clean up the stuff that
it started to grow back we are starting
to see where the bud sites are popping
up at this point we have probably
bottomed and lollipop the plants so you
know how far your bud sites are going to
be up on the plant you know how far you
expect the penetration from the light to
get into the canopy so now we've got a
really good idea of what needs to be
defoliated so week three you will have a
lot of confidence and a lot of tips from
the environment and the plants
themselves on what to defoliate then on
week five that is a fun one we get to go
in there and we see all the buds getting
chunky and now we can see the leaves
that are obvious over the bud sites a
lot more leaves have grown back some of
the older leaves have gotten bigger
let's take off all the crap that is
blocking the light while you're doing
every defoliation carefully look for
bugs carefully look for issues that is
part of the job when you're defoliating
when you're doing anything with the
plants the secondary task on your mind
is looking for issues so on week five we
go in there and we pull out all the big
leaves that are covering up bud sites
then on week seven we are getting ready
for harvest we've only got maybe one
maybe three more weeks at the most until
we're going to harvest these plants you
may be beginning to see yellow leaves
absolutely remove those as soon as
possible at week seven I
like to take off the majority of the big
leaves I keep saying go slowly by this
point we're going to go in there and
pull off most of the leaves then a day
or two before harvest I send the trim
crew in and they do a pre harvest strip
they take off all of the giant leaves
and they will also take off a lot of the
sugar leaves and I didn't mention this
before 99% of this defoliation is done
by hand we are not using scissors just
grab the leaf and just pop it right off
it will come off some of the guys are so
quick that it is scary I'm gonna hit the
microphone and the speed that these guys
pull leaves it sounds like this and they
just go you tell him one two three go
and they've got good music on and
they're nice and motivated and they know
the job and they know how long it takes
so they just get in there and go once
you get good at it you will be a d
foliation monster you just use your
thumb to kind of grab that leaf and just
pop it right off of there over time once
you get comfortable and develop
experience you will also develop a lot
of confidence and you will start to see
the results of your defoliation and he
will start to learn how to dial it in
for each strain now some strains may not
react super well to defoliation the
strains that don't have a lot of leaves
may not respond well to a heavy
defoliation you're going to have to
learn to be plant specific when it comes
to tricks like this but as long as you
understand the main goal and you don't
go too hard you will become very good at
defoliating your cannabis garden in no
time so the main idea here is just take
off all the extra leaves and you will
start to identify what those extra
leaves are it is very easy to identify
anything with a long purple PDL just
take that right out of there we don't
need it now we've got a bunch of leaves
at the end what are we going to do with
all of these leaves that is a great
question some people choose to juice
their leaves now if you were spraying
any type of pesticide please do not
juice your leaves please do not give
them to anybody to be juiced if you've
sprayed pesticides or essential oils do
not do that we don't want to juice that
[ __ ] a lot of people use their leaves in
compost if you've got a way to compost
your leaves that is a great way to get
rid of them if you're running a no-till
garden if you're doing recycled beds
just throw those leaves
right into the compost right into the
recycled soil beds or you can just drop
them right into the no-till garden and
then they will decompose and they will
become energy and food for your plants
and for your worms now if you were going
to throw away these leaves be very
careful it looks extremely suspicious to
see a trash bag with pot leaves in it
sitting out by the curb when you're
waiting for the trash man to pick it up
now just imagine you take that bag of
trash out there and it's super fine but
then some punk-ass kid comes by and he's
on his bike and he hits the trash bag
with his bike and the pegs go right
through the bag and now your trash bags
open and now right in front of your
house is a bunch of weed leaves
depending on where you are it only takes
one leaf to cause giant problems for
yourself and your future so be very
careful with what you do with these
leaves once they're defoliated think
about that overall when you're growing
what are you going to do with all of the
trash are you going to compost it do you
have a wood chipper what is going to
happen to all that stuff how are you
going to get rid of it safely and not
get yourself into any trouble I feel
like I've covered the basics of
defoliation basically you take the
leaves off strategically I like to do it
at the start of week one of flower the
start of week three the start of week
five the start of week seven and then I
even do a pre harvest defoliation you'll
have to learn your plant specifics on
how hard to defoliate these plants the
main goal is to remove excess leaves to
make more room for light to penetrate
the canopy also that will help control
your humidity that is also going to help
prevent things like powdery mildew and
bud rot and we're also going to make
less hangout spaces less party zones for
pests like spider mites and thrips so I
hope that explains defoliation when I
work in a commercial environment
the day after ID foliate I generally do
some popping and twisting so in a future
episode we're going to have to talk
about popping and twisting and we will
also talk about bottoming and lolli
popping our ganja plants for increased
production ladies and gentlemen this was
a fun episode I hope you had as much fun
as I did if you feel like this episode
was educational informative or
entertaining and you would like to make
a financial contribution to the show you
can do so by visiting
eww patreon.com slash grow from your
heart all of the information you need
will be right there on the screen I
would also appreciate it if you support
the show on YouTube simply go to youtube
search for the growth from your heart
podcast click on the subscribe button
click like on some of the videos maybe
type in some comments and let me know
what you think about the show you can
also follow me on cannabis cannabis is a
cannabis friendly social media
application many of the popular social
media applications have been shutting
down accounts that post cannabis related
content on cannabis you can post your
cannabis related content with confidence
you cannot buy sell or trade cannabis on
cannabis but you can post your dab
videos you can post your pictures of
your plants you can post your bud shots
if you've got a plant that isn't growing
properly you can post a photo and you
can say what's wrong with my plant and a
bunch of people in the cannabis
community will chime in and give you
helpful and useful advice so please join
us on cannabis it is a free application
it is available on your Android or Apple
mobile device give it a download create
a username sign in and give me a follow
I am i re underscore genetics and I look
forward to seeing you on cannabis if
you've got something you'd like to say
you're not into all of that social media
nonsense you can send me an email my
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com you know that I would love
to hear from you ladies and gentlemen I
want to thank you again for listening to
this episode it really did have a lot of
fun doing this one I hope you learned a
lot from me I look forward to hearing
the emails and some feedback about this
episode that's all I've got for you for
today I'll be back in just a couple of
days with fresh new content I want to
give a giant shout out to my buddy
Dennis Richards and until next time take
a phat dab and give your mom a hug for
me
[Music]
the tires are the things on your car
that make contact
but tires are the things
Karthik
the tires are the things on your car
that make contact with the road the car
is the thing on the road that takes you
back to your
[Music]
the tires are the things on your car
that make contact
the tires are the planes are your car
Danica
other things on your car that make
contact with
[Music]
the car is the thing on the road that
takes you back to your above
[Music]
the tires are the fans
the tires
[Music]
are the things on your car that make
contact in the road
funders what you are when you go up to
your car and it's been tired
[Music]
I woke up one morning in November and I
realized I love you it's not your
headlights in front your tailpipe for
the skylight above you it's the way you
cling to the road when the wind tries to
shove you I'd never go driving away
[Music]
the tires are the things on your car
that make
on your car
the car
back to our
I'm a contract
[Music]
the
you