all right what's up podcast world it is
Rasta Jeff here taking a little break
I've been packing up seeds all evening
it is time to record episode 485 of the
Grove from your heart podcast this
episode of the show is brought to you by
seeds here now if you need new regular
feminized star Otto flower seeds in your
garden I highly recommend seeds here now
and you can find them at
www.cdxzipstream.com I know that sounds
disgusting but it is definitely an
appealing aroma when it comes to a
concentrate on the back of the package
it says this product contains sixty
point eight five percent THC and non
detectable amounts of CBD I really enjoy
the fortissimo full-spectrum extract
this was a four gram jar and when I
cracked it open it was all one big
crystal so big shout out to our friends
at Green Dot labs for the impressive
concentrates ladies and gentlemen boys
and girls pimps and hos friends and foes
smokers and growers in this episode I'm
going to read an email about strains
that I have bred before we get there
let's do some shoutouts to our friends
on patreon let's start off with a big
giant grow from your heart podcast
shoutout and a thank you to my good
friend miss Mel how about a big giant
grow from your heart podcast shot a to
our buddy Paul a of course I want to
send a girl from your heart podcast
shout out and thank you to 10 or M
I always want to send a big high-five
and a girl from your heart a podcast
shout out and thank you to our friends
at Hogan's farms of course a big thank
you to our friend captain mojo I always
want to send a big thank you high-five
to my buddy Aldridge I always need to
send a big THANK YOU to BAFTA and last
but certainly not least a big Viking
handshake to our friend Grimbold the
druid
big thanks big shout out and big love to
everybody who supports the show on
patreon if you would like to learn how
to support the show you can do so by
visiting Debbie
uw-w tree on Comm forward slash grow
from your heart all of the information
you need will be right there on the
screen
all right podcast world I did say that I
was going to read an email about strains
that I have bred let's jump right into
that this message came from our friend
Andrew in Massachusetts and it goes just
like this hi raasta Jeff feel free to
use my name I'm Andrew from
Massachusetts big shout out to my new
friend Andrew thank you for the great
email the question goes like this I was
wondering if you could do an episode on
some of your strains that are similar
but different
lemon Jeffrey is feminized but how
different is it from firefly or lemon
sunrise or sonic boom
or perhaps orange gasm versus sun kiss
maybe strawberry starburst versus pure
love with some being so close
genetically like cousins or aunts or
nieces I'm wondering if there will be
noticeable differences between strains
or should I settle for whatever I can
find in stock I just chopped down my
first arise and I could not be more
impressed I can't wait to run some more
I region etics and I just would like to
get as clear an idea as possible of the
traits of anything that shares common
ancestry then they sign it with much
love from Andrew hey Andrew there are a
lot of great questions in this email so
let's get right to it and just to catch
people up just in case people are not
aware I am a seed breeder I am the sole
breeder for eye region attics premium
seeds I make regular and feminized seeds
I work with a strain called arise that
is one of my most popular females and of
course I use in a rise male plant for
many other crosses I also have known for
the lemon Jeffrey and a few others but
let's focus more on the strains this
person asked about I just wanted
everybody to know what this message
stemmed from so the first question is
lemon Jeffrey is feminized but how
different is it from firefly or lemon
sunrise or even sonic boom so that is a
very good question because all of those
strains have very similar yet distinctly
different characteristics in the
description and many of them have very
similar parents and their lineage so
let's talk about that lemon Jeffrey what
is lemon Jeffrey
Jeffrey is a female golden goat it was
reversed to create feminized pollen
I used that feminized pollen on a female
Lemon skunk that is what created lemon
Jeffrey lemon Jeffrey is a reversed
golden goat to a female Lemon skunk I've
done a full Episode on lemon Jeffrey I
go into great detail on that strain for
this episode we will describe it as a
tropical lemon candy flavored sativa
dominant hybrid that's a really quick
description but then how is the lemon
Jeffrey different from Firefly that is a
really good question let's talk quickly
about Firefly Firefly is a cross of
lemon skunk and arise lemon skunk is the
same lemon skunk as used in the lemon
Jeffrey cross so that is lemon skunk to
arise it is very similar to the lemon
Jeffrey but you are going to get some
sort of funky gassy it doesn't have this
sweet tropical flavor from the golden
goat as much in there it does have
golden goat but it has only got a
quarter of the golden goat in its
lineage as compared to half so we've
watered down the golden goat a little
bit we've put some og cush and Kim D
flavors in there it's very similar to
the lemon Jeffrey however it is not
feminized the main difference is the
flavor and the aroma the Firefly will
get a little bit funkier it's got a
little bit more of a lemon pledge sort
of a thing and it also grows a little
bit taller with a little bit more dense
of a bud structure the next one you
asked about is the lemon sunrise and
that's a really good question how is
lemon Jeffrey different from lemon
sunrise lemon sunrise was my non
feminized response to requests for
non-fan lemon Jeffrey many people fell
in love with lemon Jeffrey but they did
not like feminized seeds many people
have a preference of feminized or non
Femmes that is up to you many people did
not want feminized lemon Jeffery seeds
so I pollinated the lemon Jeffrey with
my prized arise male and that made lemon
sunrise now let's backtrack and talk
about the differences between the
firefly and the lemon sunrise these are
both regular seeds these are non
feminized strains so let's talk about
the
Firefly like I said earlier has more of
the skunky dank funky aroma I say more
of a stank lemon flavor the lemon
sunrise is going to have a softer
sweeter lemon flavor so if you're
looking for lemon pledge gassy dirty
feet and lemons lemons and funk lemons
and cush the Firefly is the way to go
there if you want more of a softer
sweeter lemon sorbet kind of a flavor
the lemon sunrise is the route for that
one the Firefly and the lemon sunrise
will grow very similarly the Firefly
will make a little bit more dense of a
bud the lemon sunrise will make a little
airier of a bud but it's going to get a
little bigger of a but also it will
weigh the same in the end
now let's backtrack even more and talk
about the lemon Geoffrey and how it
varies from all of those the lemon
Geoffrey is different from the Firefly
because it is straight soft lemon head
candy flavors I describe it as if you
dumped out a box of lemon heads and
smelled the Box it's really soft it is
really smooth it's kind of lemon sorbet
country time lemonade powder it's more
gentle as the way I explain it but it is
feminized that's how that one really
stands out from the rest of the crowd
now there is another cross that is very
similar in this mix which you asked
about which is the sonic boom sonic boom
is actually lemon og haze cross to arise
lemon og haze came from our friends at
ethos collective big shout out to my
buddy Collin they're doing great work
over there the lemon og haze I
discovered her in a commercial facility
and I fell in love with that plant
immediately it grows like a champ you
can't beat it up you can't cause it
problems you can't stress it out it
doesn't like spider mites and it just
seemed to eat like a champ and no matter
what we did do it it put out giant colas
that always smell like lemon lime
Gatorade and I [ __ ] love it so that's
where the lemon og haze came from I
cross that to my arise my goal was to
increase the vigor and potency of the
lemon og haze and it absolutely worked
it is more of a gatorade lemon-lime sort
of a flavor more than the lemon flavor
of the other strains we've talked about
previously the sonic boom does not have
the lemon skunk as the lemon Jeffrey the
Firefly
or the lemon sunrise would carry him
there so that is going to be a vastly
different cross from the other three you
will see very large differences so I
think that wraps up the talk about the
lemon Jeffrey versus Firefly lemon
sunrise and sonic boom just quickly
lemon Jeffrey is a feminized seed so
that's why it stands out mainly it
produces that soft
lemon lemon head country time lemonade
flavor sort of a thing then the Firefly
is that same lemon skunk cross to the
arize it's more of a cushy gassy stinky
lemon the lemon sunrise is the lemon
Jeffrey to arise that brings the sweet
lemon it brings a hint of the gas but
not nearly as much as the Firefly then
we've got the sonic boom and that is a
vastly different flavor profile
completely different bud structure it
lacks all of the lemon skunk traits
because it does not have the lemon skunk
in there at all so now let's move
forward to the second part of the
question which is orange gasm versus
Sunkist I like that one a lot the common
parent in orange gasm and Sunkist is a
platinum tangi plant Platinum tangi came
from our friends at garden of Weeden
that is a female Platinum Girl Scout
cookies pollinated by a male tangey
plant that was known as julius and that
makes platinum tangi I really like the
platinum tangi plant for a lot of
reasons
it stays short it grows nice and squat
instead of getting tall and lanky it
makes a nice wide Bush I like the shape
I like the structure it grows very
easily it does not have a lot of
problems it finishes fairly early it has
nice robust stalks so it doesn't need a
lot of support it has a very nice leaf
shape and structure and the leaves that
need to be d foliated are very obvious
because of the size and shape of the
leaves
I like how early it finishes then when
you're done growing it what stands out
about the finished product is this
amazing orange flavor the oranges are
super strong then on the exhale you get
a hint of that Girl Scout cookie
funkiness and I really think it makes a
beautiful balance so that is the
platinum tangi that comes from our
friends at garden of Weeden I fell in
love with that one in a commercial
facility I acquired a cut and I've been
working with it for
years I have made quite a few strains
from that cut the orange gasm and the
Sunkiss and also the Michelangelo come
from that cut so let's talk a little bit
about the differences between orange
gasm and Sunkist orange gasm is the
Platinum tangi cut pollinated by that
reversed golden goat that makes lemon
Jeffrey those are made side by side
orange gasm and lemon Jeffrey are made
in the same room from the same reversed
golden goat so it is a platinum tangi
female pollinated by a reversed golden
goat that one brings out a lot of
citrusy sweet orange flavors you will
get a little bit of orange rind in there
some phenotypes may Express a flavor of
grapefruit there will be a hint of
grapefruit Terps in there that is not
the most common aroma or flavor but it
will pop up in some phenotypes now let's
talk about the Sun kiss Sun kiss is that
same platinum tangi female pollinated by
the arise now we are going to see a lot
of similarities in the orange gasm and
the Sun kiss because the arize also has
the golden goat golden goat is the
mother of arise but we are also going to
get a little bit of funk in there
because it's also got chem d and joseph
OG so we're gonna get some of the
Daybreaker traits we're going to get a
rise traits and we're going to get those
platinum cookies and the tangi traits in
their most phenotypes of the Sunkiss
stay short and squat and grow bushy the
orange gasm will do that as well but the
main difference you are going to see is
that we may get a little bit taller
phenotypes from the Sunkist and we may
get longer
finishing phenotypes from the Sun kiss
and we also may get a hint of funkier
nasty or cushier aromas from the sun
kiss the main difference is that those
are a regular and a feminized seed line
that is the main outstanding difference
between the two of those let's talk a
little bit about the michelangelo since
we're here you didn't mention that one
Michelangelo is that same platinum tangi
female pollinated by a reversed
blueberry cookies female they made
pollen so we've created the Michelangelo
feminized wine Michelangelo
has the same growth characteristics as
the orange gasm and the Sunkist
generally short squatty plants about
eight-week finishers you will find some
outliers and all of these that are
shorter and longer finishers but
generally we've got short squatty plants
with a very orange dominant aroma the
difference with the Michelangelo is that
we bring a little bit of a drapey blue
raspberry funky sort of a blue nerds
maybe those blue lollipops we used to
suck on when we were kids that turned
our whole face blue it's got a hint of
that flavor to it it's kind of like we
took some oranges and rolled them around
in grape fun dip or something like that
or a blue raspberry fun dip it is a
really neat flavor combination very
candy very orange e very funky then
sometimes you'll get a hint of that
cookies from the Tahoe and the cookies
in the background so the Michelangelo is
very similar to the orange gasm and the
Sunkist but it also has a little pizzazz
to it it's got a little bit of blue
color on there and I know it sounds
crazy that I express flavors in colors
but if you think about it when you see
red stuff you always think it's either
fruit punch or strawberry if you see
blue [ __ ] you think it's blueberry when
you see orange you think it's orange
flavored my brain works very much in
that sort of a thing that is why the
TMNT line got named the way it did I've
explained that before let's keep moving
here let's recap on the main differences
on the orange gasm the Sunkist and the
Michelangelo orange gasm is feminized
Michelangelo is feminized the main
difference is Sunkist is a non feminized
version of these lines it is a regular
seed Sunkist is going to be completely
orange II a little bit of funky orange
gasm orange II maybe a little bit more
citrus maybe some grapefruit in the
Michelangelo you're going to get oranges
with all those blue and purple flavors
attached to that let's move forward and
talk about strawberry starburst versus
pure love those are very different
crosses the strawberry starburst is
strawberry fields from Crockett family
farms that one I acquired at another
commercial facility it grows giant colas
that smell like strawberry candies I was
always satisfied with the harvest weight
and the appearance but I was never
satisfied with the potency so my goal
was to pollinate it with my King Solomon
and increase
the potency of the Strawberry Fields
that created strawberry starbursts I hit
my goal spot on with that one pure love
is a cross of Zack Hayes to arise Zack
Hayes is killer Hayes and Strawberry
Cough so the strawberry flavors are very
different than the strawberry starburst
flavor this is more of a an actual
strawberry aroma the strawberry
starburst is more like a strawberry gum
a strawberry candy it's also been
described as those candies that your
grandma has in the candy dish it's
wrapped in the strawberry looking
wrapper the strawberry starburst has
that flavor the pure love is more like a
an actual strawberry air freshener sort
of a thing there's a big difference
there in my opinion but the pure love
has some haze in it so you're going to
get the killer haze traits are going to
pop out of there that is going to make
the plants take a little bit longer to
finish they're going to get a little bit
taller they're going to have possibly
more of like a psychedelic sort of a
buzz
so the strawberry starburst is a little
bit more candy bubblegummy possibly
watermelon the pure love you're going to
get more of the funky aroma from the
arize they've both got the arize parent
in there you're gonna get some of that
funk in there from the arize it comes
more dominantly in the pure love so if
you want strawberry candy watermelons if
you want something to press and make
rosin out of strawberry starbursts is
the way to go if you're gonna make pho
out of it pure love is the way to go
that one's got a little bit more of a
real strawberry flavor as compared to
the artificial candy and it's also gonna
bring a little bit of that dirty foot
gassy cushy sort of a flavor another one
we should include in there is the
Raphael Raphael is the strawberry
starburst pollinated by that blueberry
cookies that I talked about earlier
Raphael brings that really sweet
strawberry candy flavor but it's also
got that blue raspberry funky Wang to it
those blue and purple flavors added on
top of it it really makes it really
unique strawberry blueberry combination
it's really fruity it's really
bubblegummy it can almost be a
watermelon blueberry bubblegum sort of a
thing there are a lot of really unique
flavors that come from that so the main
difference between strawberry starburst
and pure love strawberry starburst is
going to be more strawberry candy pure
love you're gonna get some of that gas
and then Raphael is strawberries with a
way
to it and of course the Raphael is a
feminized line the other two are regular
seeds so I'm sure by now you've noticed
that I am using a lot of the same
strains in a lot of my crosses I'm just
using different pollen donors on
different females to create diversity
and kind of branch out a little bit I'm
using several females I am mainly using
that King Solomon as my main real male
I'm also using several females and
reversing them to create more crosses
from proven and trusted females which I
know are reliable I've been working with
many of these crosses for several years
I've got a very verified stable I know
that everything I've got is exactly what
it is labeled I know where it came from
I know where that person got it I've
bred with it I've tested all of these
things several times so I've got a very
nice stable to work with my downfall or
my limiting factor is that I am limited
by the number of plants I can keep
because of Colorado laws I do have
access to commercial facilities and I
work with large groves
but most of my breeding happens in a
personal grow so I am limited to the
amount of mother plants I can keep I'm
limited to the amounts I can flower at a
time so that really makes my number of
keeper plants limited yes I do have
friends that can keep plants for me I do
have plenty of other friends around here
that do have gardens that maybe I can
have them keep my mother's but as a
breeder as somebody who relies on this
is like part of my life somebody who I
think I'm in love with these plants know
I know I'm in love with these plants I
don't want to rely on anybody else to
keep my genetics my business my passion
alive so I do my best to keep my very
favorite mothers to where I can keep my
selected moms my selected males and then
I still have enough room on my plant
count to do some pollination to make
some new crosses then occasionally I
have to call a few things I have to
sprout some seeds and I have to start
fresh with lower numbers so that's why
you see a lot of repeats and a lot of
things from the same sort of lines
working in my projects they are trusted
they are proven and as a breeder that is
part of what you rely on me for and
that's what I rely on myself and my
testers to test these lines for the
lines that come out in 2020 have been
being tested since 2019 and possibly
2018 so sometimes it takes me a little
while to get products out because I want
to thoroughly test them to make sure
that when you
your money you were getting a reliable
seed pack that when you grow that you'll
have something worth showing off
something worth consuming something to
make it worth off your time your energy
your effort and your money because I
know how much effort and dedication we
put into our grows so my main limiting
factor to keep my breeding from
expanding is plant counts I'm only
allowed to have so many plants but like
I said oftentimes I do coal things I
either get new plants from friends and I
breed with those then I make sure that
that offspring is worth using I will
send out those seeds to friends I will
grow those seeds myself sometimes I have
friends in commercial facilities that
will let me run a hundred seeds in one
of their test rooms then I can really
see what's happening there sometimes
I scrap projects sometimes I say we
probably shouldn't give these seeds out
to people sometimes I go holy [ __ ] I
cannot wait to get these seeds out to
people but when I make a first cross I
don't make a lot of them the first time
I'll make a couple of hundred so we can
test it then if it's good then I go back
and I make enough for we can actually
get it out to people so it is a long
process making testing and verifying
seeds and I am mainly limited by the
amount of keepers that I can keep
because of Colorado laws but there were
more questions in this email it said
with some of your strains being so close
genetically like cousins or aunts and
nieces I'm wondering if there will be
noticeable differences between strains
or if I should just settle on whatever I
can find in stock depending on which
strains you were referring to you may
see very subtle differences some of them
may be so close that you may just want
to grab what is in stock since I am only
able to keep so many mother plants and
father plants some strains will never be
made again so once they sell out they
are gone I've got a jar of those seeds I
make a bunch of packages they're
requested by the vendors they sell then
that is it
I cannot make any more of those because
I was forced or I chose to get rid of
one of the mother plants or the father
plant or part of that cross and I can no
longer make it so I would grab what is
in stock when you can if you can't find
the exact strain you were looking for
the last paragraph of this email says I
just chopped down my first runner of a
rise and I could not be more impressed
that is awesome I would love to see some
photos of your arise if you didn't get
photos while I was growing I hope to see
photos of your
to grow of I read genetics seeds it goes
on to say I cannot wait to run more I
regen etics just would like to get as
clear an idea as possible of the traits
of anything that shares common ancestry
I think I did a pretty good job of
giving you descriptions of things with
very similar traits and similar parents
if you've got more questions I would
love a follow-up email you know my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com you signed his email with
much love from andrew hey andrew thank
you for the great email I do look
forward to hearing from you in the
future I want to see photos of your irie
genetics grows all right podcast world I
think that is all I've got for you for
this episode I need to get back to
packaging up seeds for the endo Expo
don't forget that the endo Expo is
coming to Denver I read genetics has a
booth at the endo Expo in Denver January
25th and 26th the 25th is industry day
the 26th is open to the general public
so check out the endo Expo website grab
your tickets before they sell out
because it will sell out make your
travel arrangements early get yourself a
nice hotel get yourself a sweet air B&amp;B
and I look forward to seeing you at the
endo Expo if you are interested in
acquiring seeds of any of the strains I
spoke of on today's episode you can
acquire them at seeds here now and you
can find them at www.cpa.psu.edu or mure
heart all of the information you need
will be right there on the screen you
can also subscribe to the show on
youtube simply go to youtube search for
the grow from your heart podcast click
on the subscribe button
maybe type in a comment let me know what
you think about the show I would love
your support on YouTube if you've got
something you'd like to say maybe you'd
like to sponsor the show maybe you've
got a product you'd like me to review
maybe you're just not into all that
social media nonsense you can send me an
email my email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com
you know that I would love to hear from
you ladies and gentlemen I hope you have
a great week I will be back Thursday
with a fresh new episode I want to give
a giant shout out to my buddy mangled
remains
and until next time take a fat dad and
give your mom a hug for me eat it out my
labia waters food say every wants to
earn I needed I'm gonna let you see what
it's pretty right
live and directly straight away on a
really likely [ __ ]
with lightning in my head I am mr. Perry
White horns right and enteral my wife's
and White House in Revelation
declarations of war you ready for what
you got it if I love the war my Gideon
was it and my right
[Music]
you looking for water I've got it
job done close and get America
[Music]
I saw it sometimes shut up
these are done still write certain D
Jews I'm walking over you demanding my
shoes
Radio Lancashire transport and read the
lightning red warning
one destiny declaration is a man my
American agent
you all right
right now man
then I reckon all right great and I take
me to see top of the paps get a bit more
time to wrap time to rock the rappers
your puppets no more time to get it
unbe bc1 DBZ to a BBC true BBC for my
miserable bits and miserable heads and
walked around me miserable and daunting
immersion it's a reflex dream clear
doing waiting for the bad you might
spring clear spring
and if you think could be super
economics
[Music]
I didn't make it right or responded by
the trick
[Music]
make sure you springer be a sweetie and
wire here sweetie right in and wipe off
your ink on your Twitter
[Music]
just like read your badge interactive
when you sprinkle remember you sprinkle
it down it's sweet
why above your spring
[Music]