need a new cool catchphrase or something
what's up ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls pimps and hos friends and foes
smokers and growers all you bad
[ __ ] thank you for joining me
for episode 487 of the growth from your
heart podcast this episode of the show
is brought to you by seeds here now if
you need new regular feminized or Auto
flower seeds in your garden I highly
recommend seeds here now and you can
find them at www.ctvn.org de Chien punch
on the package the flavor is described
as Sitrus berries and frankincense I
think we've been over this before I sure
get the citrus I for sure get the
berries not so sure about the
frankincense there's something funky in
the background something must be
something earthy I'm not sure I would
agree with frankincense either way it is
a delicious and highly potent
concentrate on the back of the package
the label says this product contains 60
7.39 percent THC and non detectable
amounts of CBB I really approve of the
cutie berry live batter from our friends
at Green Dot labs alright in this
episode I'm going to answer an email
that asks a question about breeding
before we get there you know I like to
do some shoutouts to our friends on
patreon we've got a few new friends
let's start off with a giant grow from
your heart podcast shout out and a thank
you to our new friend Karen Crawford how
about a giant thank you shout out to
Tanner em of course I always want to
send a giant thank you shot out to Glen
G I need to send a big thank-you shout
out to reefer madness hey by the way
reefer madness congratulations on your
first breeding project that looks great
let's continue on with the big thank you
shout out to Paul a and last but
certainly not least I want to give a
giant grow from your heart podcast
high-five a shout-out and a thank you to
my buddy Aldridge big thank you big
shout out big respect to everybody who
has continued to support the show on
patreon if you'd like to learn how to
support the show you can do so by
visiting www.disabilitydenials.com
I think that covers the business part of
the podcast let's jump into the email
portion of the show I was spending most
of my evening packing up seeds for the
Indo Expo I will be at the Indo Expo in
Denver on January 25th and 26th the 25th
is industry and professionals and
business-to-business day but the 26th is
open to the general public so I do hope
to see you there
do get your tickets before you travel
because it will sell out and come stock
up on some fresh I read genetics anyway
while I was packing up those seeds I was
thinking about an email that I recently
received so I thought it might be a good
time to take a break from packing up
seeds take way too many dabs and then
knock out a podcast so let's jump into
the email that inspired today's podcast
episode this email starts off with a
question about LED lighting but then it
does work into a breeding question I'm
going to go quickly over the lighting
question but what I want to focus on
this episode is the breeding question so
let's jump right into the email it goes
what's up Rasta Jeff Jeff with the G
again I hope this email finds you well
what's up Jeff with the G good to hear
from you again
Jeff starts off by saying the reason I
am harassing today is about my first
time actually making an honest attempt
at growing your grow lesson compilation
was the tits and it has inspired me to
pull the trigger that is awesome I love
hearing that you thought my grow lessons
were the tits I don't think anybody has
ever told me that anything I've done was
the tits before so that's cool but I am
excited that you are now a grower and I
am excited for you let's keep going with
the message it says I scored at HBS lamp
and two LEDs I've got a tent a blower
and a filter I've got some heating pads
for the floor and a couple of other
things all for three hundred dollars man
that is a good deal I do recommend you
clean all of that equipment before you
put any plants in there but I think
you've got a good setup for a good price
so far it goes on to say I'm sorry that
I don't have all of my specs right now
it's all in a pile in the basement
currently that's completely fair on the
first question the message is I've
listened to your filter placement
episode but I want to still ask if I'm
good blowing directly into my basement
especially since I'm using the LEDs
first now that is sort of an odd way
I'm not sure exactly what you were
asking I know that in a previous episode
I've talked about carbon filter
placement we want the air to pass
through the carbon filter before it
leaves our grow space so that wherever
it goes it doesn't have cannabis aroma
in it so with that air is nice and clean
so nobody smells our grow it sounds like
Jeff with the G wants to blow the air
through the carbon filter out of his
tent and directly into the basement
which is not a problem at all that's a
good idea that's mainly what a lot of
folks do who are growing in the basement
as long as that basement doesn't
overheat as long as you're able to get
that heat out of there or as long as it
mixes with enough cool air to stabilize
the temperature inside of that tent that
should be fine it's the part about the
LEDs that throws me off here since I'm
especially since I'm running the LEDs
first I don't know why that makes a
difference I'm not sure what you're
questioning about that part so send me
another email and kind of clarify this
question and I'll give you further
advice but this is a great email because
I really like the second half the second
question is great and we're going to
spend a lot more time focusing on here
so I'm sorry I skipped over the first
part I'm not even sure what you're
asking there but the second part is gold
so let's get to that part it says also
after a few sessions I'd like to breed
and create my own strains can I request
an episode of breeding terms and methods
some of it is a little esoteric at the
moment and I'm getting ahead of myself
but I love learning about this plant
especially if you're the teacher hey
that means a lot to me
it also says I will have many more
questions and updates in the future but
this is where I am thus far thanks in
advance and keep blazing brother Jeff
with Ag I love the enthusiasm coming
from Jeff with the G he just got his
grow equipment it's not set up yet and
he's already asking questions about when
I breed how I do it how do I do this
correctly you are getting a little bit
ahead of yourself you were absolutely
correct there but this is a good
opportunity for me to talk about
breeding and breeding labels I'm not
going to focus too much on breeding
methods and too much of my tricks and
techniques and stuff like that on this
episode I'd like to focus more on the
labels and some of the wording that we
see on seed packaging I think that some
of the companies use a lot of trickery
and a lot of miss labeling
a lot of weird wordplay and I'm not sure
if these companies are doing it because
they're trying to sell more seeds and
they're trying to word things fancily so
that the consumer is kind of fooled and
wants to buy [ __ ] that sounds better or
if they really just they don't know how
to properly label it and those are the
words that they chose for their
packaging so we see a lot of different
things on packaging and oftentimes it
all means the same [ __ ] a lot of times
it doesn't mean anything
so let's kind of talk about some of the
things we see on seed packaging and we
may actually talk about some things that
we do not see on seed packaging that
should probably be there let's start off
with some of the very basics labeling we
will often see the name of the strain
today I'm going to pick one of my
strains because it's easy for me we're
going to go with the rise a lot of my
listeners know that arise is one of my
favorites I bred the arize I can talk
about it freely I know all the details
and I'm not gonna be wrong so let's pick
a rise is our strain for the day when I
label a rise I write a rise on the seed
package that's obvious now you know
those are a rise seeds in there
underneath the rise in parentheses I put
golden goat X Daybreaker and those are
in a parentheses together why did I put
that there because golden goat is the
female plant that was used to create
arise and Daybreaker was the male plant
it was used to create the arize now
you've got an idea of what the genetic
parents of the seeds you have purchased
are that provides you a little bit of
information as to how the plant will
grow possibly what it will taste like it
creates a little bit of familiarity if
you know what golden goat is you know
who I like golden goat or if you know
what Daybreaker is you say oh I like
Daybreaker or if you know what both of
them are you go oh I wonder what that's
like when he bred those together so when
we see two strain names in parenthesis
with an X in the middle that indicates
that those were the crossed plants that
created the named strain that's listed
above so again you'll see a rise and
then under that you've got parentheses
golden goat X Daybreaker
and then a parenthesis to close that and
that indicates that a rise is a cross of
golden goat to Daybreaker
now here is another detail that is often
overlooked by many see
Maker's it is proper practice to list
ladies first inside of that parentheses
so it would be proper to list
parentheses mother acts father
parentheses you've got golden goat today
breaker now we know that golden goat is
the female and Daybreaker was the male
in that cross there is no doubt about
that unfortunately that is not standard
practice across the board with all
breeders
it is proper practice in horticulture
but not all breeders have adopted this
practice sometimes you have to ask the
breeder what was the male used in your
project now we can take this even
further sometimes you will see something
in parentheses with the open and close
parentheses so you'll have golden goat x
Daybreaker in a set of parentheses then
you'll have another X then two other
things in a set of parentheses now that
indicates that we have taken this plant
in the set of parentheses that is one
plant so you've probably got golden goat
X Daybreaker and a set of parentheses
that may to rise then you've got I'm
just gonna pick something else over here
let's say we've got parentheses
Strawberry Fields X blueberry cookies
and then parentheses to close that so
that would indicate that we have taken
the progeny of the Strawberry Fields
cross two blueberry cookies and we've
got a male of that because it is on the
right side of the X then we've got the
golden goat on the left side of the X so
basically that would indicate that we
have now crossed the golden goat to the
Rafael is what the Strawberry Fields to
the blueberry cookies cross is so that
would be an indication that we have
crossed the rise to the Rafael and the
reason that we do the multiple sets of
parentheses is to kind of show
grandparents because breeder nerds like
myself and like many of you listening
want to know oh yeah so it's a rise to
Rafael what's a rise now you want to
know that a Rises gold and goats add a
breaker and you want to know what's
Rafael Rafael is strawberry fields two
blueberry cookies a lot of people like
to know a little further back what the
genetics are what the family tree looks
like it's just fun if you're a nerd some
people are into that some people really
do not care some breeders list that on
the packages some do not so mainly when
you see the parentheses that is one
plant when it has the parentheses and
then a bunch of words and then an X in
the middle and a bunch of word
and then more parentheses that was one
plant everything on the left side of
your axe is the female everything on the
right side of the X is your male and
then you close that up that's one plant
then you put an X in the middle that
means you're crossing that to the other
plant which could be just one plant we
don't have to have something in
parentheses over there you may have
taken golden goat to Daybreaker
in parentheses X blueberry cookies you
can do that so you don't have to have a
cross on the other side it could be one
thing hopefully this makes sense the way
I'm explaining it
the main reason this is done like I said
before is to let the purchaser the
consumer know the pedigree or the family
tree of their seeds now sometimes there
may be letters at the ends of those
equations we may have F's or s's or ours
and there also may be numbers in there
we'll talk about that in just a minute
let's talk about more of the basic
things we see on some seed packaging
most seed packages will indicate a
flowering time if we are working with
photo period seeds that flowering time
indicates the estimated time in which
those seeds will take to finish
flowering once the flowering stage has
been initiated now if you were growing
indoors flowering starts the day you
switch your light cycle to 1212 if you
were growing outdoors you have to pay
attention to your calendar your Farmers
Almanac and you also have to keep an eye
on the plants but when we are working
with photo period plants from photo
period seeds flowering time means the
amount of time that the plants will take
to finish flowering from the day we
initiate the flowering phase you can veg
them as long as you want these plants
will veg as long as we keep them
properly fed and they don't get root
bound and there are no environmental
factors that make them flower we can veg
them as long or as short as we want
in some cases I veg my plants for seven
to ten days then I initiate flower by
putting them under twelve twelve or
eleven thirteen lighting
sometimes I veg my plants for a hundred
days it's all about my goal and what I'm
trying to do with those plants but the
estimated flowering time that is printed
on seed packaging is an end
Asian of how long those seeds will take
to finish flowering from the time you
initiate the flowering cycle and again
if you are indoors day one of your
flowering cycle begins the day you turn
that timer to twelve hours on and twelve
hours off now we also have to keep in
mind that many breeders give you a range
of when we can expect those plants to be
finished we have to keep in mind that we
are working with seeds we've got nature
to work with these plants have been
selectively bred from phenotypes that
have been tested so we have a good idea
of how long they are going to take to
finish once they're bred we grow a bunch
of them out we take good notes we see
how long they take to finish in several
environments but they are plants and
there are different phenotypes in packs
of seeds so we have to give you an
estimated time frame in which those
plants will be finished I like to give
about a two-week window I say these
plants take eight to nine weeks to
finish that means somewhere between that
55 and 65 day mark those plants will be
done but there are a lot of factors that
contribute to when a plant will be
finished I can take the same clone and
grow it in my grow room and grow that
same clone in your grow room and if we
pay super close attention we will notice
that those plants reach peak ripeness at
different times in our different grow
rooms even if we've got the same
phenotype so we offer a time frame in
which we expect those plants to be
finished we are going to find different
phenotypes and they're going to be grown
in different environments so we tried to
give the best estimate we can based on
what our test results have shown most of
my packages say that the plants will be
finished within eight to nine weeks or
nine to ten weeks or ten to 11 weeks
that's the sort of range that I like to
put on my packaging to give the consumer
to give the grower a good idea of what
to expect when you were growing from a
pack of seeds and you don't know how
long those plants take to flower I
always recommend you go the longest
recommended time on the package some
strains really like to beef up the last
seven days some strains really like to
beef up the last five days some strains
do really interesting things if you let
them go past that sixty-three day mark
let it go to seven
days and see what it does maybe it
really beefs up maybe it really gets an
interesting aroma at the end maybe it
turns some really cool colors that you
never would have known about if you
didn't let it go that extra week yes the
trichomes are the boss always pay
attention to the trichomes but if you've
got the opportunity to let one plant go
longer just as an experiment let it go
see what happens you may be really
satisfied with the results so that is
what we're talking about when we list
the flowering time on the back of a
package of seeds another thing that I'm
more often see on websites not as
commonly on the package of seeds because
a package of seeds is very little we
don't have a lot of space to write a lot
of things I occupy most of my space with
cool artwork lately something I see on a
lot of websites is what is known as
morphology and that means what are these
plants going to look like what type of
growth characteristics can we expect
from these plants morphology is an
indicator of what types of phenotypes we
can expect from these plants so does it
say short squatty plants does it say
tall skinny plants does it say wide
bushy plants that is what we mean by
morphology shape and characteristics
growth characteristics and traits we can
expect from these plants I list that in
great detail on my website again I don't
list that on a lot of my packaging but
my packaging is ever-evolving and
ever-changing just like my brand so who
knows I may add morphology in the future
let's talk about something I do list on
many of my packages and that is aroma
and flavor that is quite obvious what do
I mean by aroma and flavor that is what
these buds what these flowers are going
to smell like and hopefully what they
taste like once you harvest dry and
properly cure them and another thing
that many breeders include on their
packaging is expected yield now I think
an expected yield and flavor and aroma
are things that many breeders kind of
get creative with when it comes to
typing details on their packaging and
their website descriptions I do my best
to be completely honest with my
consumers when I am labeling my packages
my flavor descriptions are compilations
of what I have smelled what I have
experienced what I have
through multiple phenotypes of these
plants I also use information from my
test growers I've got a lot of friends
out there the tests grow my strains
before they make it to the market big
shout outs all my testers thank you for
the great reports lately you guys are
doing great jobs I also have many great
friends around me who some of them are
cannabis snobs and some of them are
honestly cannabis noobs and I keep all
those friends around and when we have a
new thing to smoke I get all of their
information and I treat the cannabis
noobs better information is just as
important to me as the cannabis schnapps
because their palate they say oh that
tastes like this and if a noob says that
tastes just like tangerines and vanilla
cream and a snob says that tastes like
tangerines and vanilla cream it must be
accurate so both of their opinions
matter to me equally I have a lot of
people smoke and sample my products
before I put those words on the
packaging I also do the same with the
flowering times I've got test growers
out there that are growing stuff right
now and I ask all of my testers to keep
detailed notes for me I know exactly
what day they chopped down these plants
so I know if they're going 55 60 to 72
days I've got a friend out there right
now running a new strain of mine that is
being tested who has been going for 12
weeks and he's sending the amazing
reports every week so I'm getting
detailed reports that's where my
information comes from that I put on the
packages I do my best to be completely
honest with the consumers because you
know who I am if I sell you some [ __ ]
and it doesn't do what you expect you
know how to find me
you know who to email it's just me I am
honest I do my best I can't say that for
every seed company and breeder out there
but I wish I could so expected yield or
harvest weight that should be obvious
that is how much product you're going to
get but like I said not all breeders are
completely honest and I try to use like
general terms like big yields small
yields medium yields sometimes I will
say this may not be the fattest yield er
in my arsenal
but the Terps make up for it because
sometimes that's how it is with cannabis
and I am honest I want you to know that
you were getting connoisseur grade super
stinky cannabis but you may not get a
whole bunch of it that may be what some
growers want that may not
what you need for your area I am honest
as honest as I could be on my packaging
the flavors and aromas again like I said
we try to do our best when describing
flavors and aromas some people get
really creative so those are most of the
basic things we will see on a seed
package now let's talk more about some
of those random letters and numbers that
we see in the strain descriptions and in
the genetic listings so let's go back to
talking about arise let's talk about
that set of parentheses we had earlier
with golden goat X day breaker within
that set of parentheses so I took a
female golden goat plant and I
pollinated it with a day breaker that
created arise that was the first time
that those two plants met and the first
time they hooked up the first time they
met babies so that is the first
generation of arise the first filial
generation of arise so now that is
technically an arise f1 now some people
may argue that that is a poly hybrid and
they may be correct but for this story
we're going to focus on the f1 hybrid
being the accurate description the poly
hybrid we'll talk about more way in the
future because that is a way deeper
topic but let's focus on the f1 at this
point so golden go and Daybreaker they
hook up I'm a matchmaker I introduced
these two they do their thing they make
some babies those babies I named them
arise that is the first filial
generation of arise so they are arise f1
now most of the time you are not going
to see f1 listed on the packaging unless
there is an f2 or a further generation
made and that breeder is known or has
been known to use that filial generation
for other work so most of the time if
you don't see an F listed on the cross
it is an f1 so we have got a rise f1 if
I were to take and a rise male from that
f1 batch and in a rise female from that
f1 batch and I breed them together their
offspring will make the f2 generation
and the reason I would do that is to
find the traits in the f1 that are most
desirable and stabilize those tray
it's breed them together and make that
f2 have the traits
I want even stronger and then at that
point we kind of eliminate other traits
that we aren't looking for then to
stabilize those desirable traits I would
find a male from that f2 batch and I
would find a female from the f2 batch
and I would breed them together and that
subsequent offspring the progeny would
be known as the f3 filial generation and
it just continues that way most of the
time a breeder will take that to f3 or
f4 and they will have locked in the
exact traits they are looking for and
most of those seeds will actually grow
like clones of each other you will have
very stable genetics by the time you are
to the f5 or f6 generation now a moment
ago I talked about poly hybrids poly
hybrids are quite often overlooked in
the world of cannabis breeding many
people including myself are breeding
with poly hybrids that are actually
being called F ones let's talk about
poly hybrids versus F one's a poly
hybrid is basically what most people are
calling an f1 a poly hybrid is when you
take a strain like Daybreaker
and a strain like golden goat and you
breed them together those create a new
cross it could be considered an f1 but
it is actually a poly hybrid because the
parents were not worked for stability
for singled desirable traits now that
it's kind of a vague blanket statement
to cover the term poly hybrid but when I
talk about proper F ones it will make
more sense by breeding with an f1
version of Daybreaker and an f1 version
of golden goat I did not have the
opportunity to lock in the traits of my
parent plants to ensure that I got
offspring that showed those plants and
not their grandparents so the proper way
to do it would to have taken the golden
goat and work the golden goat to f3 f4
or maybe f5 until I locked in the traits
that I was searching for on the golden
goat side of the breeding project
what was I looking for on the golden
goat side I wanted that sweet tropical
flavor and that potency but then from
the Daybreaker side I also wanted that
cushy stinkiness my goal was to see what
happened when I put two plants that were
completely opposite together and I hit
the goal with that but proper breeding
would have been to breed the golden goat
until I locked in the traits that I
wanted and then also breed the
Daybreaker
to the f3 the f4 possibly the f5 or f6
generation to really lock in the traits
I'm looking for there then breed those
together and make the arise in theory
that would have made a more stable cross
we would have less variation in Fino
typical expression the reality is I only
had one golden goat because golden goat
is a clone only so I did not have the
opportunity to work that unless I did a
back cross which I have done we will
talk about back crossing in a moment and
honestly that was not my goal with this
cross my goal was to put that super
tropical golden goat to the super dank
and stanky OG Kush looking Daybreaker
and kind of create that poly hybrid I
knew that's what I was doing that was my
intention here but that is often
confused as an f1 is the point here
basically crossing to F ones that were
not stabilised makes a poly hybrid I'm
probably going to get some emails about
that because that was kind of fumbled
through that one honestly I don't have a
lot of notes here I didn't plan on
talking about poly hybrids let's keep
moving forward I do have a few more
things I did mention BX just a moment
ago what is a BX I did mention that I've
made a golden Gobi X so let's focus on
that one many people want golden goat
seeds golden goat is only available in a
female plant there was never a male
golden goat released golden goat is
what's known as a clone only there's
only a female the breeder
mr. dank from Topeka Kansas never put
out a mail people want golden goat seeds
I made feminized seeds of golden goat it
is available in Femmes
a lot of consumers do not want feminized
seeds but they still want a shot at the
golden goat so I have created a golden
goat backcross and I'll tell you how I
did that
golden goat back cross starts of course
with a golden goat female I pollinated
that golden goat female with a
Daybreaker
male yes this is how a rise was made
there is a really good reason for using
the Daybreaker male to create a golden
goat back cross the traits of golden
goat and Daybreaker
are very obviously visibly different
golden goat has long thin skinny pointy
leaves Daybreaker makes big fat white
leaves that you could [ __ ] camp under
so i bred them together then I grew out
a bunch of the seeds and took very close
notes on how these plants grew then I
found a male that looked exactly like my
female golden goat this male had the
exact same plant structure this male
took the same amount of time to go into
flower
this male smelled exactly the same on
the stem rub this male smelled exactly
like golden goat late and flower the
best part about this male was that the
leaves look just like the female golden
goat to the extent that it had the exact
same number of serait Shinzon the leaves
and the leaf tips did the same exact
little curling thing that the golden
goat female did when I overfed it this
was a beautiful replica of my golden
goat female and I could tell that it did
not have much of the Daybreaker traits
to it because it did not show any
Daybreaker traits at all it didn't smell
like it it didn't act like it it didn't
grow like it and it certainly did not
look like it so I was confident that I
had a very golden goat dominant male I
took that golden goat dominant male and
put that pollen on the original female
golden go now I have back crossed
because I have out crossed that golden
goat to the Daybreaker
and it made seeds then I found a male in
there that looks just like the female
and I put that pollen back on the female
the seeds that came out of there are a
golden goat back cross 1 which would be
labeled as a bx
if I were to grow those and find another
male it was even a more close
representation of that original female
golden go and back cross that on to the
original female again that would be a B
x2 fortunately for me I did enough work
finding my first male that I feel like
that back cross is a very close
representation of the original golden go
and everybody who has grown it has been
satisfied with the outcome so that is a
back cross indicated as ABX the main
reason for that is to make something
available in seed form it was not
available in seed without making it in a
feminized form because many people are
opposed to feminized seeds now I'm
actually going to work my way into some
feminized seed labels many people have a
strong bias against feminized seeds
I make them seeds I understand how
feminized seeds are made and how they
work I think they are a great option for
a grower who is limited on numbers or a
grower who needs every seed they plant
to be a female I understand the need for
feminized seeds let's talk about how
they are labeled we're not going to talk
too much about how they're made today
we're going to talk about how we label
them most often when it comes to
feminized seeds you will see either an R
or an S for a FEM seed let's talk about
s you may see something like a golden
goat s one I make golden goat s ones
that s indicates the word self what I
have done I have taken a female golden
goat plant and I've made two clones one
of them I have decided is going to be
treated with a solution that will become
my pollen donor the other one is going
to be a female she gets left alone she
becomes my pollen receiver I treat the
selected plant with a solution that
causes that plant to create pollen it
only contains female chromosomes because
there are no male chromosomes in that
plant it's a girl I treat it with the
solution
it creates pollen that pollen is all
female I put that female pollen on to
the golden goat so now we have taken
golden goat female pollen and put it on
a golden goat female plan
the outcome is all female golden goat
seeds now since there have not been any
other genetics introduced into that
project it is known as a self and s1 so
golden goat s1 represents a golden goat
selfed seed a female golden goat it was
reversed and that pollen was applied to
a golden goat plant now we are going to
move forward and talk about an r1 if I
were to take that golden goat pollen
which I spoke of before and I apply that
golden goat pollen to any other female
plant the resulting seeds are r1 that is
called a reversal lemon Jeffrey is an R
1 lemon Jeffrey is a female lemon skunk
plant which was pollinated by a reversed
golden goat plant reversed are reversed
1 it's a reversal 1 it is very similar
to the f1 that I spoke of much earlier
in the show but I used feminized pollen
so that is an R 1 so s indicates self
and R indicates reverse self means I did
it myself
R means reversed pollen that was put on
two different plants to create different
hybrids now you may see s 2 and R 2 and
things of that nature but those are very
less common than an F 2 and F 3 or a bee
x2 or something like that
the most common indicator you're going
to see on a feminized seed is usually
going to be that s 1 if you see
blueberry cookies s 1 or a golden go s 1
that means that that plant was simply
used reversed pollinated itself there
are no other genetics in there I find
those to be highly desirable if I've got
a strain that I need to preserve let's
just pick a strain will say I will say
lemon Jie I was growing lemon Jie for a
long time it was very desirable very
sought-after I kind of got bored with it
but I didn't want to give it up forever
so what did I do
I reversed it I made a few seeds now
I've got lemon Jie feminized seeds
stashed away in a stash I've got just
enough of them to where I think when I
grow them I will find very close
representations of the original lemon G
because there are no other genetics
added to that gene pool and every seat
I've got is a female so that is a very
great way to preserve a seed line if
there's a reason why you need to get rid
of it I chose to get rid of that lemon G
of course I gave clones of it to
Tennessee I gave clones of it to
everybody around me so that it could
live so that it can survive so that it
could get spread but I no longer have it
when I choose to have it again I've got
the lemon gs1 now here is proper
etiquette when I grow those lemon GS
ones if I share the clone I will label
it lemon gs1 also when I put the buds in
a bag they will be labeled lemon gs1
that way if there's a variance if
there's a difference if there's a
medical cannabis patient that smokes
lemon gene it works beautifully for them
I don't want to dupe them into thinking
they got lemon G when they just got my
lemon gs1 that is proper etiquette as a
grower as a pro as a good person so I
feel like we have covered r1 and s1
we've covered most of the feminized
talked we have covered the male and
female talk let's work our way toward
talking about a and B lines there's a
breeder that we all know quite well he's
dominating the damn seed game right now
I'm not gonna say his name or his brand
name he knows who he is big shout out
bro he likes to put out a and B lines
some people are confused by this I find
it to be a great idea and I understand
what is happening so let me talk a
little bit about a and B lines when it
comes to breeding and marketing and
releasing these packages I was talking
about poly hybrids and F ones and
stabilized strains earlier I used the
word work a lot to work a strain means
that you have either bred it to
something or you've taken it a further
generation you've out crossed it you
have done some work with it let's talk
about really working a strain as a
breeder to get sought-after desirable
traits as a breeder it is important to
start with a goal sometimes that goal is
a couple of traits in a specific plant
that we are really trying to narrow down
we may have two plants do we see great
potential in and we want to breed them
together
but we may not be able to get there by
making an f1 or what is more properly
labeled a Poli hybrid the first time we
breed that together our phenotypes are
going to vary widely 25% will probably
look like the mom 25% will probably look
like the dad and the other 50% are going
to be make smashes in between depending
on what your goal was you may have hit
your goal on this first round of
breeding but if we want more reliable
seeds there's a better way to go about
this but it takes much more work let's
talk about it let's say that my new goal
is to cross these two plants I just got
and I want to get the potency of this
plant and the flavor of this plant into
one solid hybrid and I want to put that
to market so that you guys can purchase
it and you can grow it and you can be
completely satisfied with your results
the easy and quick way to doing this is
to get a male of one of those strains
and another female of the opposite
strain and pollinate and now you've made
seeds now 25% of that progeny is going
to look like the mother 25% of the
progeny will look like the father the
other 50% are going to be variations of
the mom and dad and different
combinations of possibly the
grandparents and the mom and dad now if
I am okay with that my project can be
done or I can take it further if I
really want to lock in the potency from
that one strain and the flavor of the
other strain and have reliable offspring
I need to work this further now I could
continue just to work the F generations
down the line and hope that I get that
potency and that flavor that I'm really
looking for and that is just working the
f1 and then finding an f1 male and an f1
female that look like they're gonna do
what I need done and breathe them
together and continue down that path
working for both of those traits another
way to do this would be to work two
separate lines of the same project and
focus on the potency in one line and the
flavor on the other line so we'll say
that line a is the potency and line B is
the flavor but it's the same strain we
have still crossed the two parents
X
I have selected different offspring and
I'm focusing on different traits in two
completely different breeding projects
now depending on how much space how much
time how many plants I can dedicate to
this I may be able to do both of these
projects simultaneously and fast-track
this whole project unfortunately I am
limited by plant counts and space and
time so I may have to run the a line as
one project I can breed that to my
desired uniformity then I can work on
the B line breed that to my desired
uniformity then we'll talk about the
next step after that but what I would be
doing is I would take the line a I'm
looking for potency over here I'd forgot
what I aimed a lion a s but we're gonna
say a is potency I would breed f1 I
would find the most potent phenotype out
of there I could find then I would breed
that to an f2 then I would find the most
potent phenotype I could find I wouldn't
worry about the aroma I wouldn't worry
too much about the structure I wouldn't
be paying too many attention to the
other details I would only have maybe
one or two things I'm really focused on
the aroma and probably shape and
structure or what I'm after on this side
and then I'm gonna breed that all the
way to like f3 f4 maybe five or six
depending on how long it takes me to
lock in those traits that I'm looking
for I want 75 to 80% of my seeds that I
sprout to come out looking just like
what I'm after
I need that uniformity once I get there
I'll put that project on hold I'll get a
bunch of those f5 or f6 seeds and I
stash them they're on hold they're
waiting we'll talk about those in a
minute I'll go over here and now we're
gonna work wine be on line B I am only
working for that flavor I was searching
for if I'm looking for today we're just
gonna say strawberry bubblegum if that's
the flavor I'm seeking any phenotype
that doesn't have that strawberry
bubblegum dominance it's getting cold we
aren't working with it so I'm going to
find the most strawberry bubblegum
dominant phenotype I can find I'm gonna
breed that to an f2 then in that f2
batch find the most strawberry bubblegum
dominant phenotype I can find breed that
to f3 and keep going until I get
absolute uniformity around f5 f6 however
far it takes me to get the uniform
I'm looking for then I've got what I
have considered my a line and my B line
I've got new cross which is super potent
line a and new cross which is super
flavourful line B they're the same cross
but they've been bred selectively bred
for different traits some breeders will
release the F ones of those on both
sides some breeders may release the F
twos
some breeders may release one line of
that and not even let you know that
there's a beeline but in breeding it is
not uncommon to run an A and a B line
and focus on one or two desirable traits
on both of those lines then here's where
the magic happens we find a phenotype
from line a that holds that potency we
are looking for then we find a phenotype
from lion B that holds that flavor we're
looking for and we breed those f5 or
those f6 is together and it makes a
brand new real f1 hybrid that is no
longer a poly hybrid that is a true bred
solid f1 hybrid so I feel like we have
gone full circle I kind of got lost
earlier on a ramble about poly hybrids
but there we go I brought it back I feel
like I wrap that one up with a nice
little bow for you so that was the long
rant about the difference in the a line
and the B line and why sometimes we see
a lines and B lines it is just different
breeding for different traits and then
in the end we combine the a and the B to
create that super hybrid that brand-new
f1 that has the desirable traits that
are locked in then if you want to be a
real nerd you can start f2e
that and you can lock in traits even
further breeding gets fun breeding gets
addictive I've got one more type of
breeding written down that I really want
to talk about before I start wrapping up
this episode this one is kind of the
total opposite of working with an A in a
bee line or some sort of selection this
is what is called open pollination open
pollination is basically a big ole plant
orgy that is when you put multiple males
and multiple females in a room and just
let the pollen fly so you make it
females that have been pollinated by
this male and this male so one female
plant will contain several different
crosses this gives you an opportunity
for a lot of different phenotypes
open pollination can be done with all
the same strain or open pollination can
be done by mixing strains the reason it
would be done with all of the same
strain is to find diversity in your
progeny imagine if I put two males of a
rise and four females of a rise all
different phenotypes in the room and I
just let those two males pollinate all
four of those females we're going to
have a lot of different combinations of
offspring which will give me a lot of
opportunity to find a lot of great
winners to breed with in the future so
if I put to arise males and four arise
females in a room and I did a
pollination that would be known as in a
rise open pollination now if they were
all F ones I put in there there would be
in a rise F two open pollination and it
would be polite on the packaging or
somewhere in the description to say hey
I used to arise males and I pollinated
for females and these are some of the
seeds that came from all of that batch
that's an open pollination and that is
very acceptable and again the reason
that is great is because it will create
a lot of really interesting phenotypes
who will really open up the gene pool
and give you a lot of diversity now some
people will do an open pollination by
putting one or two different males in
with multiple different females this is
not ideal to me because I'm really picky
and I like to know what everything was
pollinated with but if you're just
trying to create seeds to play with for
the future and you're not too worried
about genetics about heritage about
pedigree that will work you will also
find a lot of great phenotypes again the
only thing I don't like about that is we
don't know what they are but to some
people that is not important at all they
just want to grow good weed there are
some people in some places that don't
have access to more seeds and they're
just growing the seeds that they produce
they may be tired of all the same old
[ __ ] they've been growing this may be a
great way to diversify your gene pool so
that is my talk on open pollination I
feel like I covered the basics we talked
about f1 and f2 s we talked about s ones
are ones we've talked about bat crossing
we've talked about open pollination I
need to listen back and see if I got my
part about poly hybrids right I also
need to review the part about a and B
lines and make sure I set that right I
do have very minimal
here in front of me so I need to go back
and make sure I said things correctly I
want to thank our friend Jeff with the G
for a great email if anybody else out
there has a grow question or perhaps you
need to make a correction on this
episode my email address is grow from
your heart at hotmail.com you know that
I would love to hear from you I also
look forward to seeing you at the endo
Expo join me at the endo Expo in Denver
Colorado on January 25th and 26th the
25th is business-to-business
Professionals Day but the 26th is open
to the general public I do recommend you
buy your tickets for the Expo before you
make your travel plans because the endo
Expo will sell out come by my booth come
shake my hand come say hi come take a
selfie I look forward to meeting you at
the endo Expo if you feel like this
episode was educational informative or
entertaining and you like to make a
financial contribution to the show you
can do so by visiting
www.azcleanelections.gov the grill from
your heart podcast I'll be back in a
couple of days with fresh new content I
want to give a giant shout out to my
friend big toe grows and until next time
take a phat dad and give your mom a hug
for me
[Music]
I heard about the things you just said
about the things you do hurting you is
the last thing I wanna do baby living
God knows how much I'll try love and
treat you every way that I choose baby
now I see that I'm holding on to
something I did
it's all lies but teach-ins got a
warning to stay but baby it's time to
say goodbye
we shake it's time to say goodbye
it's time to say goodbye
[Music]
I work hard each day and night trying to
make a little I write to you
[Music]
but baby we sang
heard about the things you say about the
things you do turning you in the last
thing I wanna do but I can't go on
living this life God knows how much I'll
try love and treat you every way bad
aren't you baby
[Music]
it's time to say goodbye it's time to
say goodbye do this love we share it's
time to say
[Music]