all right here we go it's time for
episode 488 of the growth from your
heart podcast this episode of the show
is brought to you by seeds here now
if you need new regular feminized or
auto flower seeds in your garden I
highly recommend seeds here now and you
can find them at www.ctvn.org Daz gas
earth and bitter skunk I absolutely
agree with that this stuff smells
ridiculous it tastes amazing and it is
super potent on the back of the package
the label says it contains 65 point zero
six percent THC and non detectable
amounts of CBD big shout-out to our
friends at green dye labs for this
delicious and potent infinity oh gee
all right podcast world in this episode
I'm going to cover a couple of breeding
terms that I left out in the last
episode before we get there let's give a
shout out to a few of our friends that
support the show on patreon let's start
off with the big growth from your heart
podcast shout out and a thank you to
grow and Granny let's send a big thank
you shout out to Karen Crawford I'd like
to send a big girl from your heart
podcast high-five thank you shout out to
my buddy Glenn jeroni I need to send a
giant thank you shout out to okie Gro
720 of course I need to send a huge
thank you shout out to dude day UK and
last but certainly not least I want to
send a big giant girl from your heart
podcast shout out and a thank you to our
friend big toe grows big shout out and
big thank you to everybody who supports
the show on patreon if you'd like to
learn how to support the show you can do
so by visiting www.hud.gov more things I
should mention one thing that is really
important my friend Clint just left and
he wanted me to make sure to tell
everybody hello so big shout out from my
friend Clint to all of you guys Clint
come back on the show sometime come hang
when you've got more time don't be a
stranger anyway Clint wanted me to say
hello I told him I would say hello so
there we go
shoutout from Clint what's up dude I
hope you hear this what is next let's
talk about my garden update occasionally
I like to update you folks on what is
happening in my garden if you've been
following along you know that I recently
pollinated several females with a
reversed blueberry cookies pollen donor
that was a blueberry cookies female
plant that was treated with a solution
that encouraged that plant to create
pollen which only contains female
chromosomes that pollen will be put on
several selected females and that will
make several lines of feminized seeds in
that room of females being pollinated by
the reversed blueberry cookies is of
course another blueberry cookies female
that will receive pollen there's a
platinum tangi there is a Strawberry
Fields there's a lemon skunk there's
also a female of my favorite arise and
also there is a Durbin poison in that
room there also may be a couple of other
females in there that have not been
pollinated by this reversed blueberry
cookies before so when those seeds are
done I will test them I'll get some out
to my other tester friends will see if
they are up to par if they meet my
standards and if so we will add those to
the lineup the next time I reverse the
blueberry cookies I will make more of
those and we will release those with the
rest of the lineup but the females in
the room have been successfully
pollinated the pistols are starting to
get brown they're kind of curling up it
has been about three or four days since
I pollinated and I can already see that
there are plenty of seeds developing in
that room I've cleaned up most of the
excess pollen I've taken a shot back and
sucked up all the corners I'll clean up
the room real well at this point I just
need to keep feeding the plants really
well and make sure nothing goes wrong in
just a few days I will adjust the timer
and I will give my plants more light to
encourage healthier fatter seeds and
those seeds should finish in about 50 to
60 days this episode should come out on
December 11th which means those seeds
should be ready around the end of
February so that is what is happening in
my garden we have had successful
pollination I can visibly see that the
pistils are curling up I can visibly see
the spots where seeds are beginning to
form the plants look very happy all of
the equipment in the room seems to be in
good shape
everything is dialed in everything is
running properly it is a little bit cold
outside which makes it really easy to
keep the temperatures in the room nice I
don't have to compete with the hot
sunshiny days this should be a very
successful situation I'm going to
increase the amount of light hours which
will make the seeds harvest earlier it
will also be fatter and more healthy so
right now I think we're on the perfect
path all right that's what's happening
in the grow room let's get on to the
main topic of this podcast I said I
wanted to cover some glossary terms some
things I may have missed in a previous
episode when I was talking about
breathing let's jump into that and talk
about some popular terms that you may
see on seed packaging you may see in
forums you just may hear people talking
about when it comes to growing and
breeding let's talk about some of those
terms in the last episode I kept saying
to work something to take a strain or a
plant and work it what did I mean by
work it let's say that I bought a pack
of seeds from a breeder that breeder is
called water bottle because there's a
water bottle in front of me so this
water bottle breeder sold me a package
of seeds and I grow those seeds I find a
male out of those seeds I've got free
reign to breed with that male because I
have paid for those seeds those are mine
nobody can tell me what to do in my
opinion nobody can tell me what to do
with my seeds nobody can tell me what to
do with my plants once I've paid for
them they're in my garden I've done my
work with them and I feel the same way
about the seeds that I breed that are
available to people if you've got my
seeds you're allowed to breed with them
I can't stop you I almost encourage it I
want to see what my plants will do in
future generations
I feel like breeding is really fun it's
really fulfilling and if that's
something you want to do my seeds offer
great potential
so I almost encourage you to breed with
my stuff but let's get back on track
I've got a pack of water bottle seeds
here this guy sold me some seeds they're
great I find a male in there I choose to
breed with that male that's cool but I
didn't work the male I just used water
bottles work to create more stuff what I
should do is use water bottles mail to
some other persons female or another
female that I've worked with and then
create my own seed and then use a male
out of that I've got to do some work to
it to kind of make it my own
not just grabbing stuff off the shelf
and mixing it together I've got to do a
little bit of ingredient working myself
I've got to do the work on my own so
that's what I mean when I say work it
and I just get a plant get a clone get a
male plant out of a pack of seeds and do
some dusting and make seeds that's
acceptable that works but it means a
little bit more when a breeder does some
working when you take things to
different generations when you in breed
or out breed or backcross or do some
work to it you just have to do a little
work make it your own instead of just
using that pack of seeds from water
bottle using his mail and making my own
seed company out of that so if you're
just breeding for your own personal
fulfillment feel free to use whatever
mail you've got access to that fits your
breeding criteria but if you're trying
to put something to market it's better
Attica to work something and build your
own mail instead of just pulling
something out of a pack and reproducing
more stuff out of that that's what I
meant when I kept saying work it and
make it your own
in the last episode now let's move
forward and talk about something a
little more useful what is a phrase that
I hear quite often that may be confusing
to some growers the phrase is clone only
in a previous episode I spoke about
Gorilla Glue number four being a clone
only strain I also talked about golden
goat being a clone only and Girl Scout
cookies being a clone only now what do I
mean by a clone only strain what I mean
by a clone only is that no males of
these plants were ever released and no
seeds of these plants were ever released
by the original breeders so the female
that was released is known as a clone
only because there was no way to
reproduce that plant the only way it was
circulated was as a clone a very
specific cut and we're going to talk
about specific cuts and cut names in a
minute here so when I'm saying clone
only I mean it's only available in clone
form so something like golden goat and
gorilla glue those plants just happen to
be accident but they are also clone only
because the person who created those
plants never intended to make seeds for
commercial production so those seeds
were never released
they grew those small batches themselves
then they found the keeper the prized
cut out of those seats the
star phenotype then they gave that clone
out to their friends and they never
released any mails or any seeds so it is
a clone only female now I know people
are already going but I've got seeds of
golden goat you put out seeds of golden
goat how can that be a clone only there
are breeders like myself and many others
who have learned how to reverse plants
which means I can take a clone only
plant and I can treat it with a solution
that solution will trigger a hormone
reaction inside of the plant which makes
it create pollen sacks which contain
pollen which only contain female
chromosomes then I take that female
golden goat pollen and put it right back
on a female golden goat plant and I make
female golden goat seeds until that
became a popular practice and a lot of
people started learning how to do it
these clone only strains were much more
sought-after
and were much harder to acquire now I do
believe if you grow my golden goat from
seed you should label the bag and all of
your plants golden goat s1 because it is
not the original golden goat cut it will
be a very close representation but it is
your responsibility to properly label it
as a golden goat s1 so that is what we
mean when we say a clone only that plant
is a clone only there were never seeds
released by the original breeder the
only way you're going to find seeds of
that is if somebody made feminized seeds
or perhaps maybe somebody did a back
cross but that needs to be labeled
appropriately if you're making seeds
please learn how to label them correctly
and please do not mislead people
now I also said we would talk about
specific cuts what does it mean when I
hear that there's a strain and then
there's a specific cut of that strain a
very popular example is the Mac from
kappa later the Mac is a plant that is
available in seed form so you can buy
Mac seeds the Mac is also available in a
clone there is a very popular Mac cut
known as Mac one it is also known as cap
you laters cut now cap did release the
mash
in seed form but he has also shared his
favorite cut with his friends and there
is a story and some rules that go along
with the Mack cut you've got to share it
with growers that you respect and people
that you feel will deserve it and you
cannot take money for it it's got to be
gifted there are some rules that come
with that cut I really appreciate and
respect that but the one bit cap you
later gave out to people is caps cut
that is Mac one so it has been labeled
Mac one and caps cut to indicate that
that is the sought-after prized cut from
that batch of seeds you can buy the
seeds but you cannot label any of the
seeds they come from that batch caps cut
or Mac one you can label it the Mac if
that's what the seed pack says but you
cannot call it Mac one because Mac one
is a clone only and that's just the
first strain that came to the top of my
head when I wanted to talk about strains
that are clone onlys that have their own
specific name so that may also be known
as a breeders cut I've also got a prized
cut of my arise of course I've got
almost unlimited amounts of seeds of a
rise that I can grow through I have
grown a lot of a rise plants I've been
able to select my favorites out of
countless seeds I've got a cut that is a
champion if I were to release that I
call that the breeders cut that's the
one everybody would want that is the
best one you're going to find I've
called several to replace them with this
one and I upgrade any time I find one
that's better
that one replaces the older one so I've
got the breeders cut of a rise there
isn't a rise number for that I've
released to a few friends they carefully
label it a rise number four because that
is a popular sought-after cut that is
the breeders cut it is the number four
so that's how some of these strains get
their names that's why they get called
specific cuts you may see like the the
the profit the 505 cut that's because
the profit was bred by IRA genetics but
my friends down in Albuquerque found a
very beautiful phenotype of the profit
and they call it the 505 cut because
they pass it around and they share it
and so when other people grow the profit
and they offer clones
like hey I got clones at the profit
their friends will probably go
you got that 505 cut or did you just
grow it from seed because everybody's
gonna want that 505 that's the special
one so that's where you get specific cut
and specific cut names you may get
regional cuts you may get breeder cuts
also dispensaries have very popular cuts
of certain strains there is a dispensary
in Denver that grows the lemon Jeffrey
and they have got a very beautiful
phenotype of the lemon Jeffrey and they
do offer clones of it on occasion when
you get those clones you have got the
kind love cut so if you go to kind love
you get lemon Jeffrey you can call that
the kind love cut that is the one they
run that's the one that they share they
are known for that cut of that lemon
Jeffrey so that's how these certain
strains get their cut names or their sub
names they're either grown by a grower
who is popular and they get the cut
named after them the Rasta Jeff cut or
it could be regional or it could just
have some sort of a story behind it
that's also a popular thing another
thing that happens is sometimes the
breeders will identify specific
phenotypes before the seeds are released
and they will tell you to look for
specific phenotypes within the batches I
am known for identifying phenotypes in
my batches and I give very good
descriptions of the phenotypes on some
of my podcasts I'm gonna go off on a
little mini rant here I'm going to stop
talking so much about desirable
phenotypes because those are what are
desirable to me when you're growing a
pack of seeds from seed I feel like you
should find the phenotype that is more
desirable for you and your garden kind
of don't worry about what I said you're
growing it for you get what you like
I've got good recommendations but
sometimes I feel like when I start
talking about phenotypes
i sway people's hunt and they don't get
what they want they get what I want and
that's not why we're growing that's not
why we're Fino hunting so I'm going to
back off a little bit on some of my
phenotype recommendations I'll still
make descriptions and things but I'm not
going to recommend sometimes I often say
that one's the keeper I may get away
from doing that I'll say the one you
like the best is the keeper so let me
try to figure out where I was and get
back on track
I was working my way into talking about
a breeder who tells us about specific
phenotypes of a specific strain and what
I'm getting toward is Jillybean when you
buy Jillybean we know that we can look
for the candy-store Fino and the orange
vino those are two very popular and very
reliable phenotypes that will come out
of a pack of Jillybean so those are two
very popular phenotypes you always hear
about the candy store jill and the
orange jill so that's basically what we
mean when we say like basically a
subtitle or a sub name to a strain like
hey I've got the jellybeans and then
your buddy will go do you have the
orange cut or the candy store cut and
you'll go oh and then if you've got both
of them if you grow a pack of seeds it's
very likely you will get the candy store
and the orange and you won't know when
you smell you go oh that's obviously the
candy store then you smell the other one
you go oh that's obviously the orange
dominant phenotype so Jillybean is very
well known for the orange and the candy
store phenotype that's where you start
hearing those subtitles I guess it is
when we're talking about strain names
now really quickly I should cover land
race genetics I am NOT an expert when it
comes to land races I have always said
that there are seed breeders and seed
collectors then there is a sub culture
of land race growers breeders and seed
orders they're kind of the subculture
within the subculture the extra nerdy
among the nerdy so my take on land races
is essentially this land race seeds are
seeds that are acquired from a region or
the plants and the cannabis breeding has
not been disrupted by selection from man
so if you think about in some places
they've got a large field of cannabis
growing outdoors they let the males and
the females grow side-by-side they do
not remove the male plants those male
plants open pollinate all of the females
as the plants are harvested those seeds
are dropped right back into the ground
naturally just from the plants being
shaken by the harvest method just by
Nature despite being there those seeds
fall back into the ground then next year
those seeds grow up again male and
female plants are allowed to grow that
males are not cold those males pollinate
those females so each female plant
contain
seeds from multiple mail plants from
that area so this happens over
generations over generations without
being adulterated by mankind nobody goes
there and disrupts the breeding of these
plants the only thing that people are
doing is removing the finished plants we
are allowing the seeds to fall and they
are allowed to grow next year we aren't
doing any selection Nature is doing all
of the selection here for these seeds
the plants that grow the best in that
environment they thrive and they live
then those plants with survivor
instincts get pollinated the male's get
to shoot pollen the future generations
have those traits even more solidified
this has been happening for generations
among generations without interruption
of mankind
those are land race genetics if you go
to one of those regions and you acquire
those seeds and you bring them back home
those seeds you acquired we're land
races the minute you [ __ ] with them that
offspring is no longer a land race you
can label it secret tibetan mountain f2
or you can label it something like that
but you cannot call it a land race
anymore it has been adulterated by
mankind it has been worked it is no
longer a land race worked by the land
there may be people who argue with my
definition of what a land races but to
my understanding to my standards that is
what I would call a land race seeds that
have been unadulterated by human
interaction they've been breeding and
selecting themselves in nature in their
own environment and they have adjusted
themselves to grow through evolution in
their environment alright ladies and
gentlemen boys and girls pimps and hos
friends and foes smokers and growers I
hope you enjoyed my lesson on breeding
talk and a little bit of glossary terms
if you've got any Corrections or
suggestions I do encourage that type of
growth please send me an email my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com and I do look forward to
hearing from the corrections department
I also look forward to seeing all of my
friends at the endo Expo in Denver
Colorado
I read genetics has a booth at the endo
Expo in Denver Colorado on January 25th
and January 26th the 25th is
business-to-business day the 26th is
to the general public if you plan on
attending the endo Expo in Denver please
get your tickets before you travel
the event will sell out please make
arrangements if you make it to the endo
Expo please stop by the I read genetics
booth come say hello give me a high five
give me a fist bump maybe take a selfie
with me I would love to meet you if you
feel like this episode of the show is
educational informative or entertaining
and you'd like to make a financial
contribution to the show you can do so
by visiting www.hp.com forward slash
grow from your heart all of the
information you need to sign up will be
right there on the screen if you're not
any position to make a financial
contribution to the show you can support
us for free on YouTube all you have to
do is go to youtube search for the grow
from your heart podcast click subscribe
maybe leave some comments on some videos
let me know what you think about the
show and I would appreciate your support
that way if you've got something you'd
like to say and you're not into all of
that social media nonsense
maybe you've got a product you'd like me
to review maybe you'd like to sponsor
the podcast maybe you've got a cannabis
cultivation or cannabis culture question
you can send me an email my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
again you know I would love to hear from
you ladies and gentlemen that is all
I've got for you for this episode I'll
be back Monday with a fresh new episode
I'm gonna give a giant shout out to my
buddy James but erson and until next
time take a phat dab and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]
I'm down the case of bird talk to me
what did I do
what did I say always the good will come
but the days away when you know the time
is right and coming from the inside
[Music]
he said give me what you got
you