yo what's up Internet world it is Rasta
Jeff and it's time for episode 489 of
the grow from your heart podcast this
episode of the show is brought to you by
our friends at seeds here now if you
need new regular feminized or Auto
flower seeds in your garden I highly
recommend seeds here now and you can
find them at www.cpa.psu.edu or Oh on
the package the flavor is described as
hashey grape fuel and garlic I'm going
to say that that is completely accurate
there is a fuel and garlic aroma and
then as you exhale that hashey grape
sort of lingers on your tongue it's a
great description great buzz great
concentrate on the back of the package
it says that the product contains sixty
eight point seven seven percent THC and
non-detectable CBD I really enjoyed the
flavor aroma and the buzz from the first
class funk live batter so big shout out
to our friends at Green Dot labs in this
episode I'm going to read an email from
a longtime listener before we get there
let's do a shout out to a few of the
folks who support the show on patreon
let's start off with the big growth from
your heart podcast shout out and a thank
you to our friend Jacob W let's send a
big thank you shout out and a high-five
to James Brown how about a big thank you
shout out to Keith K I'd like to send a
giant grow from your heart a podcast
thank you shout out to todd k also a
giant thank you shout out to JM of
course i always need to send a thank you
to blackbird let's send a big fat grow
from your heart podcast shout out and a
thank you and a fist bump to zoso j of
course we need to send a big shout out
to Tommy of course a giant grow from
your heart podcast shout out and a thank
you and a fist bump to Brent G and last
but certainly not least I want to send a
big THANK YOU shout out to my friend
stabby make stab wood big thanks big
shout out to everybody who supports the
show if you would like to learn how to
support the show on patreon you can do
so by visiting www.disabilitydenials.com
to support the show we'll be right there
on the screen once again big thank you
to everybody who is supported the show
in the past in the present and in the
future now let's jump into that email I
said I was going to read this one comes
from a longtime listener someone who I
also consider a friend this one comes
from our friend Zane Decker big shout
out to Zane it's good to hear from your
buddy I hope you're doing well the
message from Zane goes just like this
Canada is taking off with sustainable
cannabis growing utilizing aquaponics
what companies in Colorado can I support
that are using sustainable techniques
and furthermore what sustainability
techniques do you use or would you
recommend for commercial or home use
thanks for your time brother keep
slinging that green thingy they did not
sign it but I know who it's from big
shout out to our buddy Zane thanks for
the great message Zane this is a great
question and I'm glad you brought this
to our attention let's talk a little bit
about sustainability there are so many
different things to touch on when it
comes to sustainably growing and
producing cannabis especially when it
comes to commercial production there is
a lot of waste in the production then
there is an excessive amount of waste in
the packaging so let's talk a little bit
about sustainability and commercial
growing in Colorado let's first talk
about this first question that Zane
asked it says what companies in Colorado
can I support that are using sustainable
techniques unfortunately I cannot tell
you off the top of my head any companies
that boast or brag about using
sustainable techniques there are a few
no-till grows there are a few boutique
style growers that are trying to do it
sustainably but most of the commercial
grows in Colorado in my experience our
turn and burn waste machines they want
plants on the ground they want those
plants in flower they want them
harvested they want them processed they
want them turned into whatever product
they're going to they need that on the
Shelf they want the money to come back
so they can pay to repeat that cycle so
unfortunately I cannot point you
directly to any companies in Colorado
that are working on sustainability so
then he follows up with furthermore what
sustainability techniques do you use or
would you recommend for commercial or
home use
is a great way to follow this up I try
to be mindful being mindful is the first
step to being sustainable and I will
admit that I am a salt grower I am NOT
an organic sky that is just not my
method that is not my technique that is
not how I learned how to do it that's
not how I prefer to do it if you like
going full organic if you like growing
no-till do that grow the way that makes
you happy and don't [ __ ] at other
people for doing it the way that works
for them but I do understand that I am
having nutrients I'm having salts
shipped across the country for my grow I
understand that but I try to be mindful
there are a lot of things to think about
I try to think about how many lights
I've got running do I need all of these
lights on in most situations I'm working
in very large environments and I'm
talking a hundred or five hundred lights
in Flour at a time which gives me a
hundred to two hundred veg lights
sometimes more than that sometimes if we
can move this row of plants over here
and turn off four lights for a week
that'll save us a little bit of money
and that helps environmentally and that
keeps us a little bit more sustainable
so I think about lighting when it comes
with lighting we also have less HVAC to
run if I'm not running that many lights
I don't need that much HVAC so those are
a couple of things that I look at
immediately when I go into a growth to
find ways to cut costs one of my job's
is to cut costs in the grow as well as
increase productivity so I find ways to
turn off a few lights by pushing a few
plants closer together just be mindful
think about what you're doing think
about what you're seeing another thing
to be mindful about is nutrients I just
said I know I'm having my nutrients
shipped across the country I have
shifted to mostly powdered nutrients
many of the nutrients we are purchasing
that are in bottles are mostly water so
we are paying to have water driven
across the country we are paying
shipping for water so if you can buy
powdered nutrients I would suggest a
powder nutrient again I understand that
we've got the things we like in the
methods we prefer I like new millennium
nutrients those are not powdered
nutrients I also like veg bloom they are
powdered nutrients I understand that
people like different things and we have
different preferences you just have to
use your mind and think about do you
want to pay for the shipping is this
good for the environment is this going
to be cost-effective
so that's the next thing I think about
is shipping everything has to be put on
a truck and sent to us most of the
things we use are not locally made I try
to source things that are at least in
Colorado oftentimes I have to have stuff
sent from California or other regions
but I try to get most of my stuff from
Colorado so be mindful of shipping and
shipping costs I also work on
sustainability by working on what is
known as best practices what are the
best practices in your commercial what
is your culture in your grow environment
what are you doing in your environment
in your grow in your facility to make
sure you are leaving as little footprint
on our planet as possible what are you
doing what is in your employee handbook
what is in your standard operating
procedure that helps you protect
yourself and the environment
think about those sorts of things there
are a lot of things and your grow that
you can adjust like I said earlier the
first things in most grows I go to I
look at how many lights are on and how
many plants are under each light and can
we simply move a few plants over ten
feet and turn off a whole entire row of
lights those are things that each grow
will have something like that you can
look at is there a huge leak where your
HVAC is just blowing fresh air right out
of the building and wasting all that
cool air you just put in there are you
pumping co2 out as you exhaust the room
things like that look at your best
practices how are you mixing your
nutrients are you wasting water are you
wasting nutrients another important
thing is pesticide safety are you
handling are you mixing are you applying
pesticides safely especially in an
outdoor environment where is that going
you may be aiming at the cannabis plant
directly in front of you where is the
wind taking the rest of that pesticide
is it blowing on the orchard down the
row from you where is it going be
mindful of that sort of stuff that stuff
is very important you may want to
destroy the bugs in your crop I don't
want you destroying the bugs on my
property I don't have a cannabis farm
I've got other plants that are natural
and local to my area I don't know what
your pesticide is going to do to those
plants out there in my beautiful looking
yard to my desirable insects that are
out there taking care of my yard having
a little nature like they should be I
understand we got to get rid of the bugs
on the cannabis don't get rid of the
bugs in my yard I like them there
be mindful with your pesticide
applications now this is really going to
be contradictory to the last thing I
said we have to wear gloves and personal
protective equipment when we were in the
grow at all times especially when
handling pesticides and other chemicals
or whatever you want to call them but
try to not waste a bunch of gloves be
mindful of how many gloves you were
using in a commercial environment we can
go through a box of gloves in a day if
there are one or two guys wearing the
same size gloves you think about it you
come in you put on a pair of gloves you
do a job then you probably change gloves
and use the men's room you wash your
hands you come back you put on another
gloves you're already at two pairs of
gloves two pair of gloves before the
first break of the day then we go to
break
you take a break you do whatever you do
a break you come back you put on more
gloves
hopefully you're working hard maybe you
break a glove you got to put on more
gloves I think we go between five and
twelve pair of gloves per person per day
in a commercial environment and that can
add up quite quickly look at that much
wasted latex and a pile and think about
first of all how much latex you're
throwing away you're putting that into a
landfill then also that had to be
shipped to you so you're wasting stuff
two times when we're wasting too many
gloves I understand we have to use that
stuff but be mindful and another thing
we need to be more mindful of is the
wasting of water don't get me wrong I
have overflowed a reservoir in every
single grow in which I have worked I'm
not trying to say I don't do it but we
all need to pay more attention to the
amount of water we are using and wasting
in our commercial environments after we
water a room a few times we should know
how many gallons of water that room
needs we should not mix up too much we
should not be throwing away excess
nutrient solution and if you were
throwing that away where is it going
where are you dumping your excess
nutrient solution be mindful of that if
you were running a drain to waste system
or you've got runoff water where is that
water going is that going in a floor
drain I know that once it hits the floor
drain that's out of your mind but where
does it go after that if you've got to
take some water and dump it out back or
dump it somewhere in your facility where
is that water going is that going right
into the drain that
back to the river is that going to some
sort of recycling is that just draining
right into the dirt right in your area
or all the bushes outside of your grow
growing rapidly and you can't figure out
why because you're dumping all that
nutrient water out there or the bunnies
eating that are you destroying the
natural environment that should be out
there be mindful of that sort of stuff
let's not waste too much water I'm
getting thirsty just talking about
wasting water one day we may run out of
water and when we do we are [ __ ] so be
mindful how much water you were mixing
when you're mixing a nutrient solution
be mindful if you're filling a reservoir
just set a timer and don't let that [ __ ]
overflow on to the floor and if you are
running a drain to waste off you're
disposing of some sort of water be
mindful of where that water is going
like I said before out of sight out of
mind right once it goes down the drain
who cares what happens to it you
probably should care what happens once
it goes down the drain so the main tips
I can give about being more sustainable
are basically being more mindful and
being aware of what we're doing just
simple steps that we may not have paid
attention to try to recycle more
appropriately if possible try not to
waste waste is a big cost in the grow
environment waste is a big cost to our
environment in general now let's kind of
work into some things we can do on a
larger scale that will help us be more
sustainable and of course the first
obvious things to help us be more
sustainable would be to grow outdoors
outdoors is much more cost effective
than an indoor grow you don't have to
pay for lights the Sun is the best
natural light ever that's why it's there
that's how everything started is it all
grew because the Sun gave it light and
life so use the Sun it is free then if
you're growing outdoors you don't have
to add an air conditioner because you're
outdoors you can't air condition the
entire outdoors those plants have to
deal with it now you're not wasting HVAC
that's that much more chemical gas that
is not being released into our
environment we're getting better already
now I understand we can't all grow
outdoors I'm in Colorado my outdoor grow
season is very limited we build
greenhouses and hang lights in them we
use the sunshine when we can we
supplement with grow lights as needed so
I understand we can't all grow outdoors
this is an ideal world now if you are
forced to use grow lights what would be
a most helpful option would be solar the
only problem with that is it costs a
little bit of money to install solar so
you've got to put the money out upfront
then it's got to pay for itself over
time a lot of companies a lot of
environments a lot of situations cannot
afford to put the money for solar
outright upfront so grow outdoors you
don't have to pay for lighting grow
outdoors you don't have to pay for air
conditioning if we move indoors let's
try to utilize the power of solar that
way we can take that energy from the Sun
and we can still power our plants with
that natural Sun energy now when it
comes to solar we have to do our
research because does it cost more
damage to the environment to make those
solar panels than it does to actually
run the electricity there's a lot of
thinking to be done when it comes to
designing big facilities and trying to
set up solar and trying to think
ethically and trying to put your money
somewhere
we are not causing more problems so
obviously growing outdoors would be our
first step to sustainability the next
step to becoming more sustainable and
environmentally friendly would be to run
some sort of a no-till type of
environment a no-till environment would
give you much less waste and waste is a
huge problem in a commercial facility
imagine if I've got a room with 200 3
gallon pots filled with cocoa we harvest
now I've got a dumpster filled with 3
gallon pots filled with cocoa if we were
running no-till we would basically pull
out the main root ball we would put in
another plant backfill with some compost
and we would be good to go there would
be very minimal waste we could actually
throw that root ball and that leftover
stick and probably most of my other
sticks and all my trim right into my
compost bin and it would become food
again for my plants in the future that
is a much more sustainable way to
operate a grow unfortunately in my
experience it is much more difficult to
operate a commercial environment in a
no-till type of setup I'm sure people
are doing it I'm sure they kick ass at
it but it is not my style I am NOT good
at that
I am a salt grower I'm a bottled
nutrients grower I set up a drip system
I know how to train guys where they can
feed these nutrients to these plants at
this week and I can train them to do
that
in multiple facilities and I'm going to
get the same outcome in multiple
environments that is why I like my
regimen but going full no-till going
fully organic would be much more
sustainable it would be much more
environmentally friendly it would be
fully organic which is already a
headstart
you don't have to ship all of those
bottles that's a big advantage and there
is much less waste and like I said a
minute ago most of the waste from a
no-till grow can be put right back into
the compost bin it will become composted
and you can use it right back on the
plants in the future and that will feed
your plants again and keep that cycle
going there is very minimal waste and
that type of a setup
so my first tips to becoming more
sustainable would be to learn to grow
outdoors that is much more
environmentally friendly I understand
that is not always everybody's option
the next step would be to learn to grow
no-till or at least fully organically
and stop shipping bottles around the
country the next steps to learning to
grow more sustainable are being mindful
in your environment what can you do in
your grow situation to save some tread
on the earth and also save some tread on
your wallet they will go very well
together they'll both make you feel very
good about your choices so when you were
in your grow and you're mixing your
nutrients or you're applying your
pesticide or you're doing whatever
you're in your grow doing be mindful say
all right there I'm probably [ __ ] up
the environment just a little bit more
than I need to
I could probably dial back my footprint
just a little bit just by skipping that
step or by may be doing this one extra
step so just be more mindful in your
garden pay more attention to what you're
doing and look for opportunities to be
more gentle on the environment and also
more gentle on your wallet now let's
talk about another thing that I find to
be completely embarrassing about the
Colorado legal cannabis industry one of
the most wasteful things you could ever
find is cannabis packaging in Colorado
if you buy a pre-roll joint it comes in
a tube that is about six inches long and
an inch in diameter and it's got a label
on it from the company this is a
whatever joint and then once you
purchase it the dispensary is required
to put a sticker on it that says that it
was grown at this play
it was rolled at this place it was sold
at this place and it was bought by this
person then it's got to be sold to you
in some sort of a childproof container
if that tube isn't already childproof
they've got to put it in an exit bag or
another childproof container then they
probably throw that into a brown paper
bag then they give you a receipt then
they usually give you some sort of a
pamphlet about a new product that's
coming out that you do not care about
because you just bought the product that
you enjoy then they high-five you until
you two have a good day then
most of us get to the car and we throw
away all of that packaging all we need
is that pre-roll joint it was in that
tube and a lighter we don't need any of
the other [ __ ] every product in
Colorado comes with excessive
ridiculously wasteful packaging many of
the concentrate companies will sell you
a gram of concentrate but that gram of
concentrate will be inside of a fancy
cardboard box with a lot of fancy
labeling you open the top of that
cardboard box and there is a small like
a jewelry pouch something that a hippie
would keep their little magic rocks in a
little tiny Crown Royal bag so you've
got a cardboard box I cracked that open
now there's a little Crown Royal bag in
there I cracked bad open both of those
immediately go in the trash [ __ ] that
Crown Royal bag [ __ ] that cardboard box
do not need that for anything
now inside is a little glass container
that's a little tiny container
it weighs I'm gonna drop it on the table
so you can hear how heavy these
containers are I was one hash container
for one gram of concentrate I don't need
that much packaging I know that there's
a gram of hash in here just a little
container would have been just fine I
don't need all of this packaging then
they put this in a brown paper bag
they put stickers on it to show where it
was purchased who purchased it what time
I purchased it then I've got a receipt
there is so much [ __ ] coming along
with this one gram I wish I could get a
little container and put it in my pocket
and say thanks bro have a great day I
don't need all the extra [ __ ] to throw
away I don't need the paper trail
there's no need for all of that I wish
that Colorado did not require all of the
ridiculous packaging everything has to
be childproof everything has to be
ridiculously labeled sometimes I think
that the packages are only this big so
we can fit all of the requirements on
here we have to have a small billboard
for all of our requirements on our pack
so when you are creating legislation in
your area please be mindful of all of
the packaging requirements in Colorado
and how embarrassingly wasteful this has
become I was just looking at the
products on my table I've got a couple
of vape cartridges from a very
well-known company you guys know whose
vape carts I will smoke and who's I will
not consume this company is required
this is not their fault this is the
requirement of the state for a vape
cartridge this thing is probably
unscrewing it from the battery now to
get a good idea of what size this this
is probably it's smaller than my pinkie
this thing is definitely smaller than my
pinkie probably the size of the average
person's pinkie this is about a pinky
finger the packaging that this comes in
is about the size bigger than a pack of
cigarettes it's a little bit bigger than
a pack of cigarettes so this little tiny
thing has got to come in something about
the size of a package of cigarettes so
then you try to open that up and it's
any childproof pack it's got this little
press thing you got a press here squeeze
here pull here
honestly I usually just end up tearing
the packages apart because that should
only works half the time then on the
inside there's like four or five things
folded together to keep this little tiny
product in place they could have done
this with very minimal packaging if
Colorado did not require all of these
first of all probably this billboard on
the back of the package is part of it
and then all this child proof and this
over-excessive safety stuff I don't
think it's necessary it reminds me of
when I was young and I used to go to the
record store and try to buy a cassette
or a CD and you had to carry that giant
contraption up to the front desk so that
they could get your CD out of there they
had to put in that little machine and
try to break it out that's kind of what
it's like when you go to buy products in
Colorado there is a ridiculous amount of
packaging all right Dekker I really got
off on a ramble there
you asked what companies should you
support in Colorado that are sustainable
unfortunately I don't have any companies
I can point you to directly that are
more sustainable hopefully people are
listening to this episode and there are
people it grows there are people in
facilities that are going to say hey
Rasta Jeff use us and as an example we
grow sustainably here are some photos
here's what we do give us a shout out
and I will if you send me info
qualifies I'll give you a shout out and
say that you deserve a fist bump for
being sustainable then you ask what
techniques I could recommend for home or
commercial use to make us more
sustainable I hope I gave you a lot of
examples almost everything I said will
apply in a commercial environment or in
a small craft or home grow they should
apply all the way around mainly pay
attention and be mindful what are you
doing in your grow wonder if you saw
somebody else doing that would you go oh
man you're dumb or would you go oh
that's the perfect way to do it watch
yourself on camera
watch yourself from the third-person
view just think about everything you
were doing in your grow everything you
were doing in your outdoor and your
indoor and your greenhouse think about
it all pay attention and think about how
you would react if I told you I was
doing that in my grow if I was like hey
bro today I hung from a ladder and
[ __ ] held on to a light with one hand
and applied pesticides without any
personal protective equipment you'd be
like bro what the [ __ ] are you doing
think about it like you're telling me
what you're doing in your grow and the
look I'm gonna give you when you tell me
about it there we go that's a beautiful
marketing idea let's make some of those
plastic what would Rasta Jeff do
bracelets maybe make some what would
Rasta Jeff do signs we can hang those up
in your grow you'll remind you to always
be a good grower all right podcast world
I feel like this episode was short and
sweet but I got right to the point
there's no need to ramble and try to
extend this I'm going to start wrapping
up this episode right here I want to
thank you for listening big shout out to
my buddy Decker for the great email if
anybody else out there has a question a
cannabis culture question a cannabis
cultivation question maybe you'd like to
sponsor the show or maybe you've just
got something you'd like to say my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com you know I would love to
hear from you
I also hope to see you at the endo Expo
in Denver that's right the endo Expo in
Denver Colorado on January 25th and 26th
the 25th is industry day but the 26th is
open to the general public I do hope to
see you I've got a booth stop by the
booth shake my hand
say hi grab some I read genetics take a
selfie with me I hope to see you there
do make sure you get your tickets before
you travel because that event will sell
out be prepared also don't forget to
visit our sponsors
seeds here now of course they are at
www.cdxzipstream.com forward slash grow
from your heart sign up help us out on
patreon I do appreciate that I would
also appreciate it if you stalked me on
YouTube simply go to youtube search for
the growth from your heart podcast click
subscribe on the channel maybe comment
on some of the videos let me know what
you think about the show I would love to
hear from you there ladies and gentlemen
that is all I've got for you for this
episode I want to thank you once again
for listening to episode 489 of the girl
from your heart podcast I'll be back in
just a couple of days with fresh new
content I wanna give a giant shout out
to my buddy Jesse grows and until next
time take a phat dab and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]