here we go what's up podcast world it's
time for episode 490 if the growth from
your heart podcast this episode of the
show is brought to you by seeds here now
if you need new regular feminized or
Otto flower seeds in your garden I
highly recommend seeds here now and you
can find them at www.cpa.psu.edu or
fuel and lemon cake I really get the
lemon cake I for sure get the fuel there
is a sweetness kind of a frosting flavor
that I will say could be animal crackers
the one thing I certainly did get from
this concentrate is stoned as [ __ ] I
feel like my eyes are nice and heavy
feel like I'm kind of lazy my body feels
nice and chill nice and relaxed I am
ready for a great podcast on the back of
the package it does say this product
contains sixty one point four three
percent THC and non detectable amounts
of CBD I really approve of the Sour
animal live batter from our friends at
Green Dot labs in this episode I'm going
to read an email that came from one of
my patreon supporters but before I get
to the message let's do some shoutouts
to a few of our friends from patreon
let's give a big grow from your heart
podcast shout out to okie grow I bet a
big giant growth from your heart podcast
shout-out to JM let's give a big thank
you shout out to fat rabbit how about a
big giant grow from your heart fist bump
to Jakob W of course I want to send a
giant thank you to Steve Earth I always
want to send a giant thank you to James
Brown I need to send a big thank-you
high-five to Keith's K of course I
always want to send a fist bump too
baked pwn and last but certainly not
least I want to send a big grow from
your heart podcast high-five a fist bump
and a thank you to my buddy
dick goals big thanks to everybody who
supports the show on patreon if you
would like to learn how to support the
show you can do so by visiting
www.disabilitydenials.com
patreon link and the show notes now that
we have got all of the business out of
the way let's jump right into this
message that came from our buddy Dan
dank UK Dan sent the message through
patreon and the message goes just like
this hi raasta Jeff greetings from the
UK hey thanks for listening way over
there
it also says your podcast has given me a
great education to make my next grow
even better so many thanks for that you
were very welcome that is exactly my
goal is to help you improve your garden
and understand your plants better so we
are both reaching our goals
congratulations and thanks for the
compliment and goes on to say my
question is I'm going to harvest my
plants in about 10 days and this was my
first grow some buds look great like
lollipops but some others are more the
popcorn type what is the best way to
harvest these do they need to stay
attached to a branch and hung up to dry
or can some of these smaller buds dry
sitting in a bowl you can read my name
but it's fake as we are in prohibition
here in England many thanks take care
dude from dude dank UK hey my new friend
dude dank with a fake name over there in
the UK thank you for listening to the
show thank you for the patreon support
and thank you for the great question
let's talk a little bit about hanging or
drying these little popcorn buds it
sounds like you've got the right idea
you said that some of your buds are a
lollipop type that makes me think that
you at least attempted to clean up the
lower parts of your plants and you were
mostly successful and you were able to
get most of the energy up to the tops so
it sounds like you've got a good grasp
on growing however you did not Wally pop
sufficiently
and you've got some little popcorn we
call it larf in my area it's little
larkey buds just little popcorn Nuggets
just little lowers they probably could
have been pinched off that energy
possibly could have gone up higher into
the plant but here we are at harvest and
we've got some of these little popcorn
buds what do we do with them those buds
do not have to stay on a stick or
anything they can get cut off they can
get put into a bowl they can get put
onto a tray often times growers use
those tiered racks they hang from the
ceiling or they hang from something and
it's a it's a cylinder type thing with
multiple shelves in there and it's
mash the main thing to think about is
not letting these buds get pressed
together or get too tightly squished so
that you start getting any sort of a
mold or a funky aroma or any problems
like that from the buds being pressed
together we want plenty of airflow while
they dry now depending on the density of
these little buds you may want to spread
them out a little bit you may not want
to put them in a bowl you may want to
put them flatter on something like a
tray but if they're fluffy if they're
really Airy a bowl shouldn't cause you
any problems just pay attention to them
maybe give them a stir every few hours
just to make sure that none of that
stuff is getting moldy getting funky
getting too compressed on the bottom
again that all depends on how much of
this little popcorn buddy you've got and
the density it does not need to stay on
the stick it is really convenient just
to chop it all off
spread it out maybe trim it up a little
bit what are you going to do with it are
you going to use it for smoke are you
going to use it to make concentrates are
you going to make edibles out of it
decide what you want to do with it if
you're not even going to smoke it you
don't have to bother trimming that
little stuff here in Colorado cannabis
is abundant anything that is not the
size I've got big thumbs anything that's
not the size of most people's thumb it's
tossed into what we call the hash pile
and we make concentrates out of that so
if you're not going to smoke it as flour
don't bother trimming it there's no need
to take the time to take the leaves off
of it if you're going to turn it into
edibles or a concentrate or make
topicals out of it or if it is going to
be consumed any other way than by
smoking it don't bother trimming it
because it is just going to be a waste
of time so the short answer is yes it
should be safe to put those little
popcorn buds on a tray or in a bowl I
would recommend something flatter and
wider so they're not stacked up once
they're a little drier you can start
bowling it stacking it up a little bit
consolidating saving some space while
it's fresh and wet I may not stack it up
I may leave it nice and wide and spread
out it won't take too long for it to dry
especially if it's just popcorn buds it
should dry up quickly enough to where
you just gather it up into a bowl then
you can handle it that way just like you
would intend it again it all depends on
the size and density of those buds and
how long it takes them to dry how much
moisture is in those buds at the time of
harvest some people water their plants
up till the day of harvest some folks
will water
chopped down tonight some people will
still water today some people will stop
watering a few days before harvest to
kind of speed up the dry and cure
process but I think you're going to do
great because you were smart enough to
ask this question you've already got the
right idea
congratulations on your first harvest I
hope it goes well if you are comfortable
with it I would love to see some photos
and then I really look forward to seeing
how we can improve your garden next time
through just one cycle of practice one
cycle of trial and error and then you
get a few more episodes of the show
under your belt you've probably got some
confidence now that you've got one
successful harvest I really look forward
to seeing how you improve in your next
cycle so good luck with the next run I
hope this harvest cycle goes well I hope
you dry and cure it properly please
listen to the dry and cure episode and
if you've got any questions about the
dry and cure or about your next cycle
please send me more emails I would love
to help you out once again big shout out
to my new buddy dude dank UK from over
there in England thank you for all of
the patreon support and again thank you
for the great message alright now we're
going to work on some listen or emails
this one came straight to the Grove from
your heart at hotmail.com email address
this one goes a lot like this it says
what's up Russ - Jeff
my name is we're gonna skip the names
I'm not sure if they want me to say that
but the message goes just like this my
father-in-law to be passed during a
heart valve replacement just two months
before my upcoming wedding wow that's
heavy I am sorry to hear that the
message goes on to say he had a way with
any and all plants a true mr. green
thumb' and he was growing some cannabis
outdoors tucked into his garden bed to
gift out to his friends after the
harvest
he doesn't even smoke anymore he just
loves this plant that's wonderful and
terrible it sounds like you lost a
wonderful person the message goes on to
say due to the fact that his wife would
not have taken it well or appreciated it
if she stumbled across the plants his
daughter my fiance and I had to perform
operation get the [ __ ] out of Dodge and
saved these plants from being found this
is kind of a sad tale but it is taking a
very interesting twist this is almost
like a a Hollywood movie but I would go
watch so let's keep going it's
obviously we have taken on the task of
finishing this round and I am keeping
them indoors to finish flowering as they
have vastly outgrown my tent limits and
they're doing amazingly with the organic
soil additives which I have been adding
as well as worm castings from our
personal worm composting bin to keep the
memory of this amazing man alive I am
attempting to keep these genetics going
by cloning these plants I have very
minimal experience with growing but I
have never attempted cloning alright so
let's talk about where we are so far on
this this person was getting married and
their fiance's father-in-law passed
during a heart valve replacement this
man who passed was growing cannabis in
his outdoor garden to share with his
friends this man's daughter and new
son-in-law have taken it upon themselves
to rescue this plant not only for the
sake of the cannabis plant to preserve
the plant and preserve its genetics but
also to preserve the past man's
reputation because nobody knew he was
growing and it would have made him look
bad so they got the plant the [ __ ] out
of there they took it indoors now they
are attempting to clone this plant to
preserve the father's genetics to
preserve his work so let's catch up into
the email it says when we saved them
they were already showing pre flowers so
I cut clones ASAP I used sterile blades
I follow your method is described in the
podcast dipped into rooting hormones and
placed the cuttings into root riot cubes
but I soaked in distilled water and then
squeezed the excess water out of I
purchased all necessities for a tent set
up and got the clones a 7 inch dome
under my LED light I do have a seedling
mat running due to the fact that it's in
my basement in the cold New York
concrete the tray is off the ground with
the mat just below providing minimal
heat instead of direct contact alright
so the plants were starting to show pre
flower so they decided to cut clones
that is okay you've got great success
rate from clones at that point they
purchased all of the equipment they used
sterile blades they followed my method
they dipped the clones into rooting
hormones and place them into root riot
cubes they were soaked in distilled
water so far the distilled water is the
only
part that's got me concerned then we
talk about the LED light that should be
okay the heat Matt we may want a little
bit more heat I don't know the
temperature in there but if it's a cold
New York basement we may want that heat
directly under those clones just to give
them a little umph
but again I don't have a thermometer I'm
not there I can't tell you exactly how
cold it is I'm just guessing there is
more to the message though it goes on to
say it has been about four weeks and I
still do not have roots the leaves are
beginning to turn slightly yellow but
everything else looks healthy the
humidity is kept high between 75 and 90
percent the dome is constantly sweating
and I spray the inside of the dome down
with water pH to around 6 to 6.5 when it
dries all right I may have gone a little
lower on the pH there I may have gotten
closer to 6 and not as close to 6 5 the
humidity I think you're doing okay it
says the temperature is kept between 70
and 80 between day and night and I have
the lights set on an 18-6 time schedule
so I may have gone just a touch warmer I
may have gone closer to 75 to 85 and I
would have gone 24 hours a day of light
I would never have given them any dark
time until I saw roots probably until I
transplant them but that's okay it was
your first try you did a great job
trying it goes on to say the lights are
placed about 26 inches above the top of
the dome I would have gone much closer I
almost let's see I'm gonna read about
your light I'm using a multi spectrum
LED 600 watt equivalent with only the
veg spectrum activated at this time also
I am not using any nutrients okay your
life may be correctly the correct
distance since you're using an LED if it
were a t5 I'd go much closer it sounds
like your LED may be right
one thing I would do is put my hand
right at the top of the dome and feel
the heat is your hand comfortable there
do you want to move your hand if you
want to move your hand it is too warm if
you can just leave your hand there then
that light is not cooking the plants it
is probably okay now it does say I am
not using any nutrients at this time
with the distilled water and the rapid
rooters and the lack of nutrients and
the 18:6 light schedule and probably a
little bit of cold I'm going to say
those things are what added up to a lack
of roots
the message goes on to say could this
slow root growth be due to the fact that
the plants were in flower when cut I
really don't think that has anything to
do with it a lot of times some growers
like to take their cuts from plants
which are in flower and then revert
those to veg because it does make really
monstrous clones ayah says are my lights
too close I am not familiar with your
particular light it sounds like you've
got the right idea
with it being 26 inches above the top of
the dome you've got only the veg
spectrum activated it should be right
like I said put your hand underneath
there see if it feels too warm I don't
think you're cooking them with the light
but honestly I am not familiar with the
LED and I'm not sure how strong that 600
LED is for those clones I don't have
that experience that could be part of
the problem it doesn't sound like it to
me from what I'm reading the message
goes on to say is there anything else
that you could see me doing incorrectly
from this information yes like I
mentioned before I definitely would have
some nutrients in those rapid rooters
and I would definitely be feeding the
plants some sort of feed when you were
spraying the dome I would have some
light nutrients in that water when you
were spraying the dome that is how the
plants are going to get fed they don't
have any roots so they're relying on the
leaves to catch that foliar feed and
keep them alive until they do root so
that would have been very beneficial to
put some nutrients in that spray when
you were misting the domes and then I
think a little bit of heat would have
helped you and then having it on a 24
hour light schedule definitely would
have helped out that would have
encouraged roots to happen much more
quickly unfortunately if it has been
four weeks since these clones were cut I
would start losing faith in them very
soon I don't keep anything around for
four weeks if it doesn't root by the
third week it is goodbye in my garden I
do understand that these plants are
special to you they're probably worth
another week of trying I would add some
nutrients to that foliar feed that
you're giving them on the dome dries out
I'm a rewarder those plugs with
something that's got a liquid beneficial
bacteria some sort of a root inoculant
in there if you can get some liquid
great white maybe some mammoth pee just
to get some beneficial fungus into those
clones and encourage some root growth
and one mistake that a lot of new clone
make is they try to keep those plugs way
too wet for way too long give them an
opportunity to kind of dry out you don't
want them dry and brittle but when they
start to get dry is when you were most
likely to get roots popping it's a funny
joke amongst growers that you say yeah
the best way to get my clones to root is
to forget about them you go ah [ __ ] I
haven't checked on my clones in like two
or three days and you go look at them
and they're starting to get a little bit
dry and they're finally starting to root
like a son of a [ __ ] so a little bit of
dryness may help you out again
unfortunately I feel like four weeks has
passed the limit they're probably
starting to get a little bit of mold or
rot where they're stuck into the clone
plugs they're probably losing life that
is probably game over for these clones I
hate to be the bearer of bad news but it
is probably too late to get these to
root now I know we really wanted to keep
these genetics around because these were
plants that came from a very special
person he obviously had a good heart he
was growing cannabis in his garden
secretly he doesn't even smoke maybe he
secretly smokes too and we just don't
know that but he says he doesn't smoke
and he was passing out this herb to his
friends to be a good person to share
with people that is super kind what that
makes me think is that this is the kind
of guy that has probably got some seeds
stashed somewhere amongst his personal
possessions somewhere in this man's area
every old guy has an area if it's your
workshop if it's your chair if it's your
stool every old guy's got a space as we
get older our space gets smaller all of
our [ __ ] ends up right here so we don't
have to go anywhere to get it that old
guy has probably got some good seeds
stashed away somewhere and I encourage
you to find those seeds and I hope you
get to grow those seeds to honor your
father-in-law now there is one more
sentence to this message and it says if
you need any further information or
pictures let me know I've learned so
much listening to your grow lesson
series of podcasts during work you are
the [ __ ] man hey thank you I
appreciate that it sounds like your
father involves the [ __ ] man too so
big shout out to him says I appreciate
what you do and any help you may be able
to provide to keep these particularly
special plants cycling in our lives and
then they sign it with much love and
then their name I'm not sure if they
want that set they know who they are
hey thank you for the great message
thank you for this work that you did for
this plant also you came across a ganja
plant that needed rescue it was kind of
a dog on the street and you gave it
shelter and you tried to pet it and you
tried to feed it and try to love it like
it was your own little puppy so thanks
for stepping up and taking care of the
cannabis plant it sounds like you bought
all of the equipment to take care of
this plant so I'm wondering if you were
still growing
did you continue to grow would you like
to continue to grow did you find any
seeds in your father-in-law stash do you
need any seeds send me an email give me
an update let me know how things are
going in your garden let me know if you
need any more help I would love to get
an update and again thank you for
listening to the girl from your heart
podcast alright ladies and gentlemen I
feel like that is enough for a Thursday
episode I want to thank everybody for
listening to this show I'm going to wrap
it up and start packaging more seeds for
the Indo Expo that's right it never ends
just package more seeds for the end o
Expo Indo Expo I hope to see you at the
end o Expo January 25th and 26th in
Denver Colorado the 25th is industry day
the 26th is open to the general public
please get your tickets for the Indo
Expo before you travel because it will
sell out come stop by my booth come say
hi grab some I read genetics give me a
high five take a selfie I would love to
meet you at the endo Expo ladies and
gentlemen boys and girls pimps and hos
friends and foes if you feel like this
episode was educational informative or
entertaining and you would like to make
a financial contribution to the show you
can do so by visiting
www.disabilitydenials.com for mama hug
for me
[Music]
big times when the