alright I'm doing something new I
usually don't press record during the
dab session before the show tonight I've
decided to press record right before I
dab I'm gonna take this dab and then we
might jump into the show who knows I may
end up editing this part of the show out
I am heating up the dab nail right now
getting it nice and warm for myself I've
got a big fat dab lined up we'll talk
about that dab in just a moment this is
awkward because I'm trying to work the
dab torch trying to hold the rig I've
got my dad prepared and also I've got a
microphone in my face so that's a new
obstacle to work with but I'm sure I can
figure this out getting the nail hot
it's nice and hot now it needs a couple
of seconds just to cool down
I got a carb cap Within Reach I got my
concentrate Within Reach this is going
to work out ladies and gentlemen I have
faith in this endeavor I feel like we're
at the right temperature ladies and
gentleman dab with me and then we will
do a podcast oh wow I am seriously lit
as [ __ ] so that's a fun way to start a
podcast I need to kind of get my brain
together and catch my breath but let's
get it going
welcome it's time for episode 491 if the
girl from your heart podcast this
episode of the show is brought to you by
our friends at seeds here now if you
need new regular feminized or Auto
flower seeds in your garden I highly
recommend seeds here now and you can
find them at www.cdxzipstream.com
you immediately get that lemon meringue
in your face
boom punch of lemons then there is a
sharp astringent cleaner flavor and it's
Pleasant it is not
bad at all it sounds like it may not be
good but it is definitely delicious then
on the exhale I get a gross delicious
funky lemon cleaner sort of a flavor
it's very similar to that gross nosov
lemon g it's kind of garlicky it's kind
of armpit like it's kind of gross and
deliciously disgusting but it's all
topped off with this wonderful lemon
flavor and then the best part is this
stuff gets me high as [ __ ] some
concentrates get me stoned some give me
a nice buzz this one just makes me
[ __ ] high I'm sure you could sell
over the past couple of seconds I've
just gotten more energized and more
rambley this one makes me want to run
laps makes me want to go play my drums
makes me want to ramble so this will be
delicious and wonderful podcast
concentrates on the back of the package
it says the product does contain 65
point 65 percent THC and non detectable
amounts of CBD it is delicious I'm high
as [ __ ] big shout-out to our friends at
Green Dot labs all right that was a fun
way to start a show I should do more
dabs on the show like that I'm in this
episode I'm going to do a strain update
or a strain review a lot of people enjoy
those strain reviews I've gotten a
couple of requests for one specific
strain and it's time to talk about that
before we get there let's do some
shoutouts to our friends who support the
show on patreon let's start off with the
big growth from your heart podcast shout
out to thank you to my buddy fat rabbit
I've got a big thank you shout out to
big toe grows I always want to send a
big thank-you shout out to okie gross
720 of course I want to send a huge
thank-you high-five to my buddy Jay M I
always want to send a huge thank-you
high-five shout out a fist bump and a
hug to my buddy Todd K I always want to
send a big growth from your heart
podcast thank you shot up to Blackbird
76 of course a big what's up shout out
to my buddy Tommy I always want to send
some love to Glen G I want to send a
giant high-five and a fist bump to
Victor and last but certainly not least
I want to send a big bro from your heart
podcast Thank You high-five fist bump to
her friend hug gabacho big thanks and
big high-five for all of the continued
patreon support if anybody else out
there would like to learn how to support
the show via patreon you can do so by
visiting www.disabilitydenials.com
all of the information you need will be
right there on the screen all right
ladies and gentlemen boys and girls
friends and foes pimps and hos smokers
and growers all you bad [ __ ] I
got a great email asking about a
specific strain there is no reason to
waste time let's jump right into this
email so we can start a strain review
this email comes from our friend in
Toronto Canada I'm not sure if they want
their name said they know who they are
the message goes just like this hey Russ
- Jeff big up for all of the mad content
I just got authorization for 50 plants
for medical usage nice 50 plants for
medical use I miss those days
now goes on to say I just ordered some
of your hellfire oh gee I thought that
the parents would give a crazy contrast
so I ordered these beans I like that you
did some research and that you were
intrigued by the parents and then you
were excited to see what's gonna come
out of those you are the type of grower
that becomes a breeder in the future
that's the type of passion that leads to
breeding how the message goes on it says
if you could please give me a brief
description of the fee knows I may
expect and any other tips with growing
this strain it would be much appreciated
I'm spreading your name and love across
Toronto thanks for everything you do
stay good never synthetic then they sign
it with their name big up big shout out
big respect to my new friend up there in
Toronto Canadia they asked for a brief
description of hellfire OG here is what
I call a brief description one thing I
should mention before I get too far into
this is I have been notified and I am
aware that there is another breeder who
is using the name Hellfire OG honestly I
think that breeder may have had it first
I apologize I [ __ ] up I guess I didn't
do my proper research and do my due
diligence as a breeder who releases
seeds for commercial purposes I [ __ ]
up that was my fault that's not cool I
should not have done that I let that
seed strain out a lot of people bought
it a lot of people grew it they posted
pictures of it they tagged it Hellfire
OG the other breeder went hey mother
[ __ ] that's my screen name and I went
oh [ __ ] I'm sorry so the people that
bought Hellfire ROG you got really lucky
because I am NOT going to make any more
I have gotten rid of the female plant
that I use I have discontinued that
cross I am not making any more of those
seeds
that I don't [ __ ] with that guy's other
product I don't want to change the name
of it that's rude that feels strange
that also feels shifty so it's a limited
batch what I made is made a lot of it is
already gone there are very few packs
left I've got very few 10 packs left
myself so it is discontinued if you've
got some [ __ ] hold on to it or grow
it if you want some get it quickly
because it will be gone very soon and I
will not make any more because I stole
somebody else's name and that's just
straight-up wrong so that is not going
to be made anymore I apologize if that
breeder hears this bro I know I did that
that wasn't on purpose
I [ __ ] up this is what I can do about
it I can stop making it so let me get
off of that so box and we'll move
forward and actually talk about the
strain itself why did I call it Hellfire
og because it is a cross of hell's og
and arise hell's og is also known as
biker cush hell's og is also known as
Hell's Angels og there's a long story of
dispensaries in Colorado having Hells
Angels og on the shelf and the actual
Hells Angels organization sent him a
letter from their lawyer requesting they
change the name so the Hells Angels og
was no longer called that it got called
either hell's og or biker cush so that
got spread around I acquired a clone of
the hell's og from a good friend I
decided that it was an awesome plant but
it could use some improvement that's why
I decided to breed with it it had many
great desirable traits also so does my
arise so it was kind of like a match
made in heaven as a plant breeder as a
seed maker I see things in certain
plants and I go oh if those plants right
they're bred together they would make
amazing offspring most of the time I'm
right I will admit that sometimes I'm
wrong as [ __ ] and we throw large
quantities of seeds away or we feed them
to the birds but most of the time I
strike gold with most of my intuition so
let's get my high ass back on track
Hellfire o G is a cross of hell's og to
my arise male who is known as King
Solomon when I name a cross I try to
honor the parents train or keep some of
the lineage in the name to make it sort
of obvious what the cross came from so
Hellfire was an obvious name for Hell's
OG to arise I also thought about calling
it the Phoenix but I think the Phoenix
has already taken
there's also a Steel Pulse song called
earth crisis and one of the lines he
just says he'll fire and that's part of
where it came from also yes I listened
to a lot of reggae music I named a lot
of my strains after Grateful Dead
after reggae type inspired sort of stuff
so that's where my mind is that's where
my
names are coming from and also of course
I like cartoons I've got the TMNT stuff
there also allegedly maybe some GI Joe
named stuff out there that's well that's
where my brain is and things like arise
and horizon those are just one word
positive names they look good on
packaging and sound nice and are
memorable and words that stick with you
and are uplifting words that's where my
name schemes come from so that's where
the name Hellfire OG comes from it's a
hell's OD female to my male arise also
known as King Solomon about a little
more info about the hell's og that is a
cross of OG Kush and Blackberry when I
grew that I thought it smelled like gas
and cushy I know that sounds very cliche
but it's hell's oh gee because it smells
like OG Kush it smells sweet cushy like
what cush is supposed to smell like it's
got some pine to it it's got some dirty
feet it's got a bunch of gas to it when
it grows it grows rocks the buds are
just straight dense hard rocks and it
makes a little pine cone type rocks
maybe some golf balls it is not a huge
yielder that was the problem in my
opinion with the hell's OG it put out
very high quality product but it put out
kind of stringy thin plants with not
huge buds and I wanted just a better
producer and I thought maybe I could
carry that aroma and that frost right
into the progeny and kind of increase
the productivity and the production of
that plant making a better plant for a
commercial environment and then here's a
little bit of info on the father which
was in a rise male I keep calling him
King Solomon if you listen to my podcast
a lot you know that King Solomon is used
in many of my crosses that isn't a rise
male that is a golden goat female
pollinated by a day breaker male
Daybreaker is chem D and Joseph og so
we've got chem dog and og cush in there
to give you that real funky aroma
I took the pollen from that plant I put
it on a goal
and NGO that created arise I selected a
very unique male out of that batch of
plants and I have named him King Solomon
I used that as my main stud breeding
male is a [ __ ] champion everything I
put pollen on from King Solomon turns
into gold it improves everything I breed
it to it fixes problems it increases
potency and vigor I think it is a
magical planet that's why I use it so
much so now let's talk a little bit more
about this Hellfire og cross like I
mentioned earlier I really enjoyed the
aromas and flavors and the buzz of the
Hells OG but it did not live up to
expectations and standards for a
commercial grow environment so my goal
was to increase the vigor and kind of
increase the harvest weight and yields
of the Hellfire OG I wanted to keep the
gas and dank and cush skunky tennis-ball
flavors and aromas in that cross and I
feel like I achieved that goal I get a
lot of the fresh tennis ball fresh tires
cushy gassy dirty feet sort of aromas
coming from many of the phenotypes some
of them have a sweet bubblegum
maybe juicy fruit gum or some kind of
sweet tropical candy flavor coming from
them on the back end after that cushy
smell and that's coming from the golden
goat side of the arise but since we've
got so many earthy and cushy flavors
most of them are very dominated by that
fuelie earthy kush fresh tennis ball
maybe some fresh sneakers kind of an
aroma there's a place in California
called the Norwalk indoor swap meet and
very few people have probably been there
that listen to this show but I think
sometimes some dank weed has a hint of
the smell of some of the shoes at the
Norwalk indoor swap meet allegedly
possibly some of those boots may have
some knockoff Air Jordans and they smell
really unique and that is sort of
sometimes what some of this cush smells
like I'll talk about specific phenotypes
and stuff like that in a moment but I
want to talk about the buzz that comes
from most of the phenotypes from the
Hellfire og I am a heavy smoker and I
like potent cannabis and potent extracts
most of the time I do smoke concentrates
but if I go to a concert if I go
somewhere I'll roll up a
couple of joints and take those with me
so I can enjoy them when I'm out doing
whatever I'm doing I also like to smoke
a joint of whatever I just bread if I
breed something new I grow a bunch of
those seeds and then I get to smoke it
first I like to get that first flavor
it's like my work I want to see what it
tastes like it's like being a chef I've
created this potential masterpiece or a
potential disaster so I've got to stick
my finger in there and see what it
tastes like so that I can assure that
I've got a quality product before I
serve it to the world so the first time
I drew out some Hellfire OG I grew it I
dried it I cured it trimmed it up
properly I rolled it up into a big fat
joint I laid it up and everybody went
damn that smells good that was the first
thing that people say when you light up
a joint of some good weed they go hot
smells good and I took a couple of puffs
off of it I passed it around the room
and it came back and I took a couple of
puffs off of it then I noticed I'm
[ __ ] up Hellfire og brings that OG
Kush potency that just punches you in
the face
and I call it time travel weed or tunnel
vision weed this is where the word faded
came from I think we used to hear people
say brah faded I think they might have
smoked some good og cush and they might
have possibly had somehow fire OG
because you just get faded your
peripheral vision is gone you just get
tunnel vision you can only focus on
what's right in front of you and you can
barely focus on that so I love that just
stoned tunnel vision just straight to
the face [ __ ] forgot where my keys
are and they're in my pocket I'm looking
for my sunglasses and I'm wearing them
still that's the kind of herb that I
love and the Hellfire OG brings that
punch to the face potency and I love
that and some herb that good dank flavor
and that punch to the face that is what
I was looking for quite often when
people say recommend your cushiest
gaseous strain to me
the Hellfire and the liberation are the
two that I recommend for gas and dank
and cushy aromas so now we know how it
smells we know what it tastes like we
know that you're gonna get [ __ ] lint
when you smoke it now let's talk a
little bit about the growing aspects of
the Hellfire OG if we're gonna grow this
what should and could we expect from
this plan there are a couple of distinct
phenotypes most of them unfortunately
grow tall and they are quite stretchy
these plants will take off at the
beginning of flower just like any
oh gee cush they take off they tend to
get rather tall you can do some popping
and twisting and some lollipops and
maybe some trellis work and that will
prevent the stretch but they will
stretch I'm not one to push products on
my podcast but something that will help
you reduce the amount of stretch in the
first 21 days of your flowering process
is a product called decision from new
millennium nutrients it is a great
product it tells those plants quit
stretching start flowering use that when
you initiate flower and it will reduce
the stretch also if you do some popping
and twisting of the stems which I'm
going to do an episode on very soon when
you do that popping and twisting at the
start of flower the plants don't have
the energy to stretch because they're
trying to repair their cellular
structure that you just broke which is
fine we want to disrupt that structure
so that they build fatter thicker more
robust stems also they don't stretch as
much we slowdown that growth they get
thicker and they don't get taller which
is what we want so that's a way to
prevent that stretch with some of this
oh gee cush stuff these plants are going
to get tall on you so be prepared for
tall kind of lanky stretchy plants with
a little bit of stretchy internodal
spacing don't be worried if they look
stretchy that is just what these plants
do you may see a phenotype that gets
gigantic leaves if you've got a plant
with gigantic fan leaves that you could
have a nice shady spot underneath on a
hot sunny day
if those leaves are continuously droopy
it is not a problem with the plan the
plan is not thirsty the plant has not
had too much light that is a trait that
comes from the Daybreaker father so that
is actually the grandfather it's coming
from the day breaker don't worry don't
stress if you've got big fat purple
leaves that are droopy that is just a
trait that comes with this plant don't
be paranoid and generally that happens
with the darker green phenotypes almost
a purple leaf you'll notice the darker
colored leaves make it a little bit
droopy err on you this one is fun to
grow because it does turn a lot of great
colors that'll get dark green it'll get
purple on you you may see some oranges
in it you may see some like tints of
yellow toward the end it's kind of neat
watching this one change colors now the
main phenotypes that you will see are
what I call the golf-ball phenotype and
that is very representative of almost
any oh gee cush family plant you're
getting
a lot of OG cush in there you're seeing
big fat golf balls just fist size golf
balls up here stems
it doesn't make long fat colas but every
one of those golf balls is just covered
in frosty trichome so you're gonna get
the golf ball phenotype and then you're
going to get the more desirable one the
big Cola phenotype and you will know the
difference about four or five weeks into
Flowery ago yep those are golf balls and
that's a [ __ ] monster Cola you will
be able to tell the difference now
here's what happens with most cannabis
when you grow the golf ball phenotype it
is going to be covered in trichomes and
it's going to taste amazing the other
one doesn't have as much frost but it
tastes just as good so you've got to
make the decision between do I want this
super [ __ ] frosty plant or do I want
more like that is then when it comes to
being a connoisseur grower sometimes
that's a hard decision to make
if you're drawing for personal use you
probably want that golf ball phenotype
if you're trying to take this to a
production facility if you're a cash
crop er if you're looking to profit in
any way you probably want that big fat
Cola phenotype
they're both going to have beautiful bag
appeal the only person who is going to
notice a difference on the other end is
the grower the person trying to pay the
bills one is going to give you quite a
bit more product than the other and it
will be very obvious now sometimes I do
see a phenotype that is a little bit
squatty ER and a little bit pointy er
and that may sound strange but when you
see them lined up you'll go
that's the squatty pointy one that short
squatty your phenotype in my opinion is
expressing a lot of golden goat traits I
feel like it is showing a lot of Romulan
traits that one finishes a little bit
earlier most of the phenotypes are going
to finish around 70 days this romulan
dominant phenotype will finish closer to
60 days however it lacks that dank cushy
funk it is more like a sweet golden goat
cush sort of a cross it is not the most
desirable sought-after phenotype but
here is something I want to mention that
I've been thinking about when it comes
to talking about phenotypes and
identifying phenotypes for my people who
are buying my seeds I don't want you to
see the phenotypes that I like I want
you to seek the phenotypes which you
like find the fee
type that grows best in your garden find
the phenotype that does best for your
medical or recreational needs find the
phenotype that does best for your cash
crop needs find the one that suits your
desires I prefer the one that is kind of
stretchy the one that makes the golf
ball buds that smell like dirty feet and
armpits that's the one I would go for if
you're running a cash crop you're gonna
tell me to go [ __ ] myself with that one
because you're not going to make any
profit that is the connoisseur head
stash plant you want the other one that
makes the big gigantic buds oftentimes I
noticed the girls really prefer the
phenotype that is a little bit sweeter
and golden goat dominant and I'm not
being sexist towards the women that is
what I've noticed if I put out multiple
jars and I say take your pick the ladies
will tend to pick the sweeter smelling
product most of the time as just my
observation from paying attention to
offering product to different people
that golden goat dominant phenotype is
more desirable for the ladies so when it
comes to picking your phenotypes take my
advice on what you can expect heed my
words on what is coming from those
packages and how you can adjust your
grow to that sort of thing but don't
seek a phenotype based on my
descriptions get what you want
that's like me trying to say bro you
really want to go to this restaurant and
get this meal it's going to be perfect
I'm a vegetarian you might be a steak
eater if I send you to my favorite
restaurant you're gonna leave pissed off
and hungry and I'm gonna do the same at
your favorite restaurant so find that
phenotype it works best for you let me
get my high ass back on track here and
talk about Hellfire OG a little bit more
something you can count on with all
phenotypes of Hellfire OG is that they
are going to want more cal-mag
and I know that sounds funny that sounds
like a joke most of the OG Kush
varietals are going to be happier with
more cal-mag they want more cow mac give
them more also this one may go nutrient
deficient on you late in Flour if you
don't feed it properly
so I'm not saying to overdose it early
I'm saying to keep a good eye on it
instead of tapering off your nutrients
toward the end of flour you may need to
ride them out an extra week and make
sure this plant does not run out of
energy now I say this about many of the
strains that I breed because King
Solomon makes tall plants
I extra mean it with this one you will
need multiple layers of supports when
you're growing Hellfire og this is a
tall lanky skinny plant it's going to
need some supports if you grow it
properly
hopefully you need two maybe three or
four layers of trellis net I would
spread it out really far with that first
net spread it really far and wide and
then let it grow up into that second net
then flip it into flower and put up a
third net because it is going to grow
into that third layer of trellis be
prepared for tall stretchy plants
Hellfire og is probably not a plant I
would recommend for beginner growers if
you have never grown an OG Kush or chem
dog type varietal you may want some
practice with something a little less
finicky than the Hellfire OG the og cush
genetics in this plant give you a little
bit of a challenge when it comes to
growing there are a lot of things to
look out for sometimes they don't want
as much water as other plants sometimes
they need a lower pH than your other
plants and like I said a moment ago
Hellfire og is certainly going to want
more cal-mag than most of your other
plants and I think those things are true
for most
oh gee cush type varietals you're gonna
find those things true with almost
anything
oh gee and if you haven't grown OG
before it is a special experience it
doesn't grow like most of your other
cannabis they don't want as much water
they get a little bit stretchy they take
a lot more work but they are very
rewarding there was a time period here
in Colorado when all you could find was
some type of cush now I've talked about
this on the show before unfortunately
during that time period people were just
slapping the words OG and cush on every
strain in the dispensary you went to the
dispensary on Friday before a cush got
super popular and they had 12 different
strains that none of them had the words
OG or cush in them over the weekend cush
got popular you went back on Monday and
now they had 12 different cushions how
the [ __ ] did that happen I think they
just relabeled everything so that does
happen unfortunately in this industry
let me get back on track again because
this lysergic lemon concentrate has got
me [ __ ] rambly my point is that
Coosh type cultivars are very
challenging to grow but they are very
very rewarding I tried to take some of
the challenge out of the hell's og by
breeding it to the arize but
unfortunately it kept that challenge but
I think it is worth the struggle because
the final product is very rewarding the
aromas the flavors the kick to the face
type of a buzz I think it is all very
much worth the extra work you have to
put in when you're growing some OG Kush
now when I say this part it sounds like
I'm just bragging and making [ __ ] up I
would highly recommend extra carbon
filters when you're growing Hellfire OG
this is very skunky very stanky very few
ly if you're growing in an area where
growing is not welcomed and accepted
somebody is going to smell your Hellfire
OG and they may talk about it because it
is stanky it is potent it will make your
eyes burn when I trim it I'm not sure if
it's making me tear up with pride or if
it's making my eyes burn because it's so
stanky but it definitely does something
to my face while I'm trimming it is also
a finicky plant you have to keep your
cal-mag dialed in you have to keep your
vapor pressure deficit proper these
plants don't want a dry environment they
want a little bit of a damp environment
don't let them get dry in the air but do
let them get dry in the pots they do not
like to be over watered you will not
kill an OG Kush varietal by under
watering it you are much more likely to
kill an OG Kush plant by over watering
so keep that in mind when it comes to
cush type varietals the hellfire OG also
tends to like lower pH and she also
really enjoys kelp type products I think
the kelp really brings out the aromas
and the stinky feet flavors from the
Hellfire og that will also help you
lower the pH of your nutrient solution
so that works out very well I often talk
about defoliating in a commercial grow
and also in a small-scale personal grow
environment
I do not defoliate the Hellfire og as
heavily I do remove some of those
amazingly large leaves but I don't take
off a lot of leaf because she does not
respond well to excessive defoliation
this is one of the rare exceptions in my
lineup where I will say do not defoliate
her
- heavily it will piss her off she makes
those gigantic leaves so you don't have
a lot of opportunity for defoliation if
it's bigger than my hand I tend to pull
it off if it's not much bigger than that
I like to leave it there and just let it
grow toward the end of the flowering
phase these plants will turn some
amazing dark colors you'll get blacks
you'll get purples you may see some
Silver's I've seen some red and yellows
on the leaves before the colors that
come from these plants are very
beautiful so if you're a photographer
you'll get those cliche bug shot
pictures around weeks five six and seven
but around weeks eight and nine when you
start flushing and then into week ten
you will have some amazing photo
opportunities with some amazing colors I
have also noticed that Hellfire OG
appreciates lower temperatures toward
the end of flower don't go to extreme
because you will have big fat buds you
don't want to risk getting powdery
mildew but if you can drop your
temperatures slowly toward the end of
flower and get kind of cold at the end
of flower maybe even reduce the lights
toward the end of the flowering cycle
also helps speed up and create some
density in the Hellfire OG I think I
mentioned before that most phenotypes
will take nine to ten weeks there are a
couple of outliers that do take closer
to eight weeks in my opinion those are
the non desirable phenotypes again you
can reduce that flowering time if you
reduce the amount of light hours during
the flush cycle instead of running 12 12
or 11 13 maybe drop it down to 10 hours
of light then a couple of days later put
it down to 8 hours of light and then
harvest after that there are tricks you
can do to speed up the end cycle also
add a little bit of density I don't
recommend that 24 or 48 hours of
darkness that's not something I do but
you can reduce the overall amount of
darkness that that plant gets every day
that will help speed it up also I'm sure
you've heard me talk about increasing
the light toward the end of the
flowering cycle to kind of make your
plants beef up that is something I
recommend for more advanced growers who
know what to look for and can pay
attention to their plants so that if
they do experience any problems they can
cut down right away and not have any
terrible outcomes but that is
experimentation and that is for you to
decide do you want to run 12 12 or 1113
all the way through flush all the way to
the end
a commercial grow and you've got
multiple tables and multiple cycles in
one room that's what you're gonna do
you've got to go 12 12 all the way
through if you've got the opportunity
maybe you'll cut it down to ten hours of
daylight and have 14 hours of darkness
for a couple of days maybe you'll kick
it down to eight hours of daylight and
they'll have sixteen hours of darkness
just for the last couple of days or
maybe for the last week to ten days you
can turn your timer back on to eighteen
six and try to add on a little bit of
bulk there at the end those are all
experiments that you have to do in your
own garden to dial in your grow style
your phenotype and your goals but those
are options that are always there to
play with
holy-shit ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls I feel like I got on a good ramble
for this podcast I hope we learned a lot
about Hellfire OG like I said before I
will not be making anymore Hellfire og
seeds
so what armaid armaid i've only got a
few packs left myself if you are
interested they are available at seeds
here now.com i also may have a few packs
set aside for the Indo Expo find me
early before they disappear alright you
guys I think that covers my strain
review for Hellfire OG I hope you
enjoyed that if you've got any more
questions please send me an email my
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I want to thank my friend up
there in Toronto Canadia for the great
message I hope I was able to help you
out I hope you have great success in
your medical grow good luck up there in
Canadia ladies and gentlemen if you feel
like this episode was educational
informative or entertaining and you'd
like to make a financial contribution to
the show you can do so by visiting
www.hp.com forward slash grow from your
heart again all the information you need
to support the show will be right there
on the screen I would also appreciate it
if you subscribe to my youtube channel
go to youtube search for the growth from
your heart podcast click on the
subscribe tab
maybe type in some comments on the
videos and let me know what you think
about the show if you've got something
you like to say in your not into all of
that social media junk you can send me
an email my email address is grow from
your heart at hotmail.com
you know I love the listener interaction
ladies and gentlemen that is all I've
got for you for this episode I want to
thank you once again for listening I
hope everybody has a great holiday
whatever winter holiday you celebrate
enjoy it spend some time with some
beloved
smoked some tanker eat some good food
take good care of yourself and put a
smile on your face
ladies and gentlemen I'll be back in
just a few days with fresh new content I
want to give a giant shout out to my
buddy Willy's armpit and until next time
take a phat dad and give your mom a hug
for me
[Music]
Wow
love is the order on Sunday you better
find it I'm a big man I put my problems
behind me I smoke marijuana thing about
the witches
[Music]
yeah
stea bones are we kids and
[Music]
[Applause]
I smoke marijuana stay
I'm feeling very good about myself
big uns ain't feeling good well and
that's the problem I smooth the
marijuana yet still yeah boom the we
kids
and when i got problem my thumb
domestically on my lady just wanna play
with me my reminder I'm still your bum
the wicked
love is the day you gotta find us I'm a
big my problem
[Music]