all right here we go podcast world this
is a quick Thursday episode I wanted to
wish everybody a happy holiday before I
sat down to record I was told that there
was a death in my family so I am really
not in the mood or in the right mind to
record a podcast I wanted to come on
here and thank everybody for all the
support that you've shown to the podcast
and wish everybody a happy holiday
season so I'm going to do that very
quickly happy holidays everybody
unfortunately there was a death in my
family and I've got a lot to deal with
so I'm going to be distracted from the
podcast momentarily I may be away from
social media for a couple of days I just
need a break I need to take good care of
my family I need to get my head right I
may be a way for a funeral here very
soon don't worry the podcast is not
going away I just need a moment to
regroup and handle my family and handle
my life and then I will be back with
quality content I wish I had a better
holiday episode for you I wish I had a
better message for you other than happy
holidays and you guys go spend some time
with the people you love tell them you
love them people aren't gonna be around
forever and it [ __ ] hurts when they
go so go spend some time with people you
love go be around people you care about
go eat some good food take good care of
yourself I'll do my best to get a Monday
episode out I make no promises on that
Monday episode I haven't missed a Monday
in five years it feels really weird to
think about even missing a Monday show
but I've got a lot more stuff to deal
with right now than a podcast so excuse
me I apologize I'll be back as soon as I
can get it together and I'll have fresh
new content for you I do have that mix
episode written I've got a lot of great
content written it's just gonna be a
struggle to produce an episode for a
couple of days so ladies and gentlemen
take great care of yourselves please and
until next time take a phat dab and give
your mom a hug for me