my favorite part of the night right now
is that you're dancing to music that is
not playing I'm always doing that what
song are you dancing to you bro I
honestly I just got a beat my heart
brother you're just moving over there
buddy you know you just try to be
excited for the things you like doing
man here we are ladies and gentlemen
welcome it's time for episode 492 of The
Grove from your heart podcast sitting
across the table from me once again is
tall Clint welcome to the show buddy hey
friends how are you guys doing hope
everybody's having a great day go cop
write with a microphone they're
professional way to start a show good
morning if you guys cannot tell we are
smoking I am taking some dabs Clint
still hasn't dad yeah dude I'm pretty
cool I'm pretty cool
you get stoned off the flowers you do
smoke so that's cool I'm kind of jealous
yeah I don't I I like I'm jealous of you
gettin to like taste everything that
seems like a fun like connoisseur thing
to do like because I don't drink I don't
have like that microbrew
oh let's introduce the show cast episode
492 Clint's here we're getting stoned
obviously I'm Gavin Clint smokin flour
Clint is smoking did you say that's
ak-47 that's correct
that smells wonderful actually smoked
some of that flour it tastes delicious
aye it was well grown it was well cured
could have been trimmed a little tiny
bit better that's on me dude while I'm
thinking about it shout-out to dirt man
Dan for the incredible gift he gave me
these little um I don't know what
they're called but there are basically
little thumb scissors it's just a little
condom that goes on your thumb and it's
got a little like a thumbnail
like a metal thumbnail on it and it's
for trim and weed or you probably from a
lot of other things but it makes if
you're a hand trimmer and you just trim
if you dry trim weed that's already kind
of dry I've got a beautiful method for
using these things I know exactly how
I'll use them thank you Dan it's gonna
be it's a great product I don't know the
company that makes them or anything
they're over there in a package you sent
them to me as a Christmas present wow so
nice yeah that was really cool I know
exactly what they are I know exactly how
they'll be used [ __ ] cool thank you
Dan I appreciate that the ad D is
kicking in Clint is good and stoned that
we've could have been trimmed a little
bit better
zombie well-baked I smoked some of that
weed I took some dabs do you want to
describe the flavors and aromas of your
flower or are you even into that
I have such a hard time I know as soon
as I started asking I was like Clint's
not really a descriptive kind of guy
like that no I don't taste like an
overall tastes would you say bubblegummy
and slightly fruity no I would I need to
try it again real quick and I'll let you
know give me one moment Jeff as soon as
you open the jar with it when you of it
when you got here it smelled bubblegummy
and kind of fruity and I was like that
smells pretty damn good
no when I hit it that bubblegum and
fruit flavor came through that means it
was dried and cured properly I like it
well it's a good flower whoever grew
that big shout out to the chef
yeah I I did the drying and curing on
that one it was a broken branch off of a
friend's plan cool well that friend
until they broke the branch they did a
pretty good job well you know that it
happens when you get some heavy buds
going up there and you don't have the
trellising set up well so sometimes
branches break you guys I'm just talking
[ __ ] it's picking up you it's good weed
good job dude I'm smoking I'm smoking on
the sour best lemons full-spectrum
extract from Green Dot labs this is a
blend of s B s e I don't know what SBS
East ants for I should have done some
research there it's s BSE and lemon tree
Northern Lights on the package the
flavor is described as lemons lemons and
more lemons is what the package says
that's what's been described as its
should be lemony it is um absolutely
[ __ ] lemony dude yeah I was tipping
the package over I like to take photos
of my concentrates and then I share them
to my social media feed I only put them
on my story I don't put them in my
Instagram post because Instagram can be
haters when I post photos of
concentrates and they'll take the
picture down really so I put it up in
the story and it stays for 24 hours and
it disappears and then my good friends
at Green Dot labs they repost it so it
gets to be seen by a few more folks but
I do post the photos as I was thinking a
photo of this I noticed there are so
many Terps in this jar this is a four
gram jar I think it's two and a half
grams of Terps minus the quarter grandma
Terps that poured out onto my finger I
didn't realize it was coming out so just
a little bit of Terp sauce on my finger
it looks like ah a little maple syrup
little pancakes or not the color but the
consistency of like maybe some honey or
some maple syrup on my finger thick and
I didn't know what to do with it
think I panicked I was gonna take a
picture because it was really pretty I
was like oh that's really pretty just
tripping off my finger it was gonna drip
onto the table and or the floor and I
didn't want that to happen so I licked
it off my finger I'm not sure if that
was a good or bad idea you did say that
was the first time you've ever done I
think to the best of my memory that's
the first time I may have had some lemon
Jeffery Terps and a smaller dose in that
manner but that was a nice little boy
fool and my tongue had a weird sensation
for a few minutes it felt like my tongue
was kind of tingly and kind of vibrating
then it tasted like lemons and lemons
and more lemons also tasted like the
forest
it was very pine tree in my mouth very
uh it was like if you took me there's a
National Forest 40 minutes south of here
if you took me there and you're like
breathe in that's what my mouth tasted
like just foresty it was delicious but
that was a very unique thing I'm not
sure because I did take two fat dabs of
the sour best lemons and a couple of
puffs off that bowl I'm high and I don't
know if I got extra high from the part
that I put on my tongue or not but I am
certainly [ __ ] in a different way - yeah
we're just getting it sublingually maybe
is that when it goes straight into your
tongue like that
it was mostly Terps it was turbid Delic
on my face it lasted for a long day was
almost spicy like spicy lemons and I
don't know if that makes any sense but
the sour Betts lemons full spectrum
extract has me rambling like a [ __ ]
fool so far delicious concentrate on the
back it says seventy one point nine
three percent THC and non-detectable CBD
I really approve good job to our friends
at Green Dot labs what do we do next we
never did the seeds here now at this
episode's brought to you by our friends
at seeds here now it's what I usually do
I like to send people to seeds here now
to go get their seeds any new seeds in
your garden regular feminized OTO
flowers all of the above you can get
them at seeds here now how do you find
them Clint cc0 lost it stoned I like it
yeah that's working you're here alright
um we're going to talk about some fun
[ __ ] on the show do we do this part or
do we do this part let's just do the
patreon part next
keep going down how we normally do it
let's give some shoutouts to our friends
on patreon we have a lot of kind folks
who support the show through patreon
let's start off with a shout out - how
about a shout out to Karen Crawford how
about a big girl from your heart podcast
out to Ryan s wanna send a big thank you
to Tanner and we got to give a big thank
you to sour D of course a shot at our
friend Eric R who we got to give a giant
shot at our buddy reefer madness a shot
at the Greg s want to send a shot at the
Sam about a big girl from your heart
podcast high-five - my buddy Aldridge
and last but not least I want to send a
shout-out to big toe grows big thanks to
all those folks because they support the
show on patreon that really helps us out
if anybody else out there would like to
learn how to support the show on patreon
you can do so by visiting
www.azcleanelections.gov it that's a
good segue that's a good segue I said I
may have needed it you guys I want to
send a thank you to everybody who has
sent me some love and some support and
some words of encouragement on the last
episode I did have to break bad news at
a very close family member pass away
on Christmas Eve he that was surprising
it was sudden he wasn't very sick for
very long he got sick like [ __ ]
Wednesday and died like [ __ ] Thursday
or something uh yeah quick with the
support of my friends like Clint and the
rest of my good family and Mike and I
can't list everybody because I'll forget
somebody but you guys know who you are
everybody who reached out to me and sent
me some love ah thank you that sort of
stuff that means a lot to somebody who
puts their my whole life is out on the
internet so when people return all that
love that means a lot to me thank you
guys for getting me through that I was
my uncle Eric who passed away he was a
bad [ __ ] he was a cool dude
that's Brad he was a cool guy yeah I get
a lot of my smartass personality from
him my my
miss Abby my comedic sense of timing
kind of came from him so I'm gonna miss
him a lot but I'm doing a lot better
since I got all these friends around all
the support and since I just made a
[ __ ] big mouthful of [ __ ]
concentrates I'm in a much better mood
so thank you guys I want to say thanks
to everybody I got a lot of emails a lot
of a lot of YouTube comments many many
YouTube guys thanks you too yeah a lot
of Instagram messages a lot of Facebook
support a lot of text messages a lot of
phone calls so thank you guys the family
is gonna be okay
I think we'll all be alright just man
take a minute to hug the people that you
love I know I said that on the last
episode but this dude got sick like like
I said it took just a couple of days it
was like I don't feel good
I'm dead it was just [ __ ] quick yeah
so maybe that's better for him you know
I don't want to get sick and suffer I'm
gonna go [ __ ] I've got what oh I'm dead
yeah what a nuclear bomb it's over
[Music]
sounds it sounds exciting when you do it
like that yeah have a fun death yeah
instead of just dragging it out and
[ __ ] waiting for the day yeah great
[ __ ] dude big shout-out to the rest
of my family big thanks uncle yeah dude
I'll see you there one day bro save me
some room ah but thanks to everybody who
sent me some support that means a lot to
me
we're here doing a Monday show you guys
got me in the good spirits and got me
ready I couldn't be down for too long I
could I could sit there and [ __ ] cry
and be depressed and hate life for all
this but now what's that gonna do we got
a [ __ ] and smile and Erica would say
bro do your show [ __ ] is pretty cool
I'm dead what are you gonna do dude I
cried plenty yeah I cried plenty and but
none that's it's time to do a podcast
now not that I so I missed the dude but
what are we gonna do man you would told
me go smoke a joint get over it bro
that's what he would have said he's one
of the so I wasn't gonna talk about my
uncle for too long but this is where
this goes when I was younger my uncle's
had a lot to do with my life they were
rowdy bunch they were like me now you
know what I mean that's just what I
learned it is from them cuz they're
always the stoners in the back room
smoking a joint so
one day we're driving to a concert they
took me to my first real concert they're
playing Metallica in the [ __ ] car and
they don't realize that I've been around
some stoners already but they're smoking
a joint up front they don't realize how
stoned I got in the back of that [ __ ]
[ __ ] yeah it was baked and we were to
the concert had the best time and I
think they might have realized I was
stoned and because after that they
started offering to smoke with me and
and they played Metallica the Black
Album on that ride and that's part of
why I became a drummer we'll move
forward from talking about my uncle but
big shout out thanks for all the love
you guys um the next note says Clint is
here but you guys know that Clint's here
by now hi guys
how you doing bro I'm doing pretty good
thanks for coming over
short notice thanks for driving you live
like 30 minutes away bro well you know
you're gonna make time for the things
that are important I appreciate same
city 30 minutes away that take it don't
censor yourself be yourself be yourself
keep a family watch no this is not a
family-friendly show we do not claim to
be no don't worry about that thanks come
on the beard is gnarly bro thank you sir
trim that for you do that oh if you paid
that lady but someone will edit this
conversation to make it a two bears one
cave conversation we don't need none of
that yeah I don't need to be saying bad
things about the nice lady gonna get me
read yeah I don't need that but that
shows funny yeah two bears one cave you
guys check that [ __ ] out Burt and Tom
Tom and Burt one goes topless the other
words the shirt
this is the last grow from your heart
podcast episode of this year it's not
the final episode it is the last episode
of 2020 no 2019 I wrote 2020 on the
paper
three time travel time soon it's the
last episode of 2019 yeah the last
episode of 2019 episode 500 is coming up
that's what yeah so I've got two things
- to branch off of that since this is
the last episode of the year and we've
got 2020 coming up sorry I said the
wrong you
I might have thought some people are
looking at their calendars and freaking
the [ __ ] out right now well they should
because we just dog time trap we're back
back to the future um set some goals
that's what I think you should do set
some goals for 2020 if it's I mean this
is a grow show
I encourage you to do something better
in your garden what do you suck at G are
you not good at cloning are you not good
at trimming do you not know how to tell
when to harvest are you really bad at
telling when you've got bugs get better
at that find something find your
weakness find your weak link and improve
upon that find your skill which you lack
in in the garden and brush up on it you
can get good at it there are books their
websites their podcast episodes their
standard operating procedures written on
just about every step of the growth you
can improve and make your weak link your
strongest link and improve your entire
grow so set some goals that would be my
recommendation for the garden find what
you're sucking at and do better at it
get out of your comfort zone like if
you're really good at throwing sidekicks
but you're no good at sweeps just work
on sweeps until you're good at it get
better at everything in life by working
at something you suck at if you go play
the video game that you're really good
at and play the level you're really good
at smoke everybody all day you're just
beating your [ __ ] ego yeah if you go
play the level that's hard and you play
against harder people you're feeding
your soul so go feed your soul a little
bit yeah there he goes it's so hard dude
clay and I have been having some
conversations some existential
conversations about life here we're both
that we're pretty good friends yeah
we're good friends and we're both
approaching a different generate or a
different age of life you know we're
both I'm [ __ ] 40 bro people probably
don't know that when they see me and
listen to the show they a lot of people
think I'm younger right behind you yeah
I'm a 40 year old man so I've got a lot
of different insight lately people have
passed away in my life and things have
changed so definitely one of those
introspective type of months when I've
had some great conversations I'm gonna
get myself back on track you're really a
[ __ ] stone normally set some goals
you guys set some goals in the garden
you're only as good as your weakest part
so get good at everything get good at
that [ __ ] work on some soil building
skills then also where do you suck at in
life like what are you [ __ ] up do
that better next year but just be honest
with yourself first he finds out what JT
that's what you suck at is being honest
with yourself dude I think that's that's
ego man you know I just if
if there's okay so I guess I'm answering
mine it's like work on ego there we go
we know what Kalia needs to work on I
just always I always have I think I take
on too many things I try to satisfy the
demands of too many different sources
and I don't mind trying to do it but
sometimes I dig myself a hole because I
make too many commitments that I mean
while trying to do so many things but I
can only do so many so I end up doing
ten things 90% as well as I could have
if I would have only chosen to do eight
things a hundred percent that's one of
my downfalls it's something I should
work on but set some goals guys so you
know we've got some goals we could work
on it doesn't have to be like I want to
make a thousand dollars doing this or I
want to buy a new car if that's what you
want
that could be your goal but it could be
something really little it can be
something really large if you struggle
just sticking to a commitment maybe
that's your new New Year's goal anyone
have to set a goal on it on the new you
could start today sorry right now but
set some goals for your life set some
goals for yourself and then write them
down because if you don't write it down
it's just an imagination it's just a
thought you got to put it on some paper
and then put that paper where you're
going to look at it put it next to your
money put it on the fridge put it next
to your weed just write just a couple of
words I don't if you're one of those if
you want to go real far and be one of
those vision board people it'll do that
I just write words I just got a couple
of words and those words remind me
everyday of oh yeah like do these things
keep the hustle on yeah keep moving stay
strong to keep your mind strong and keep
your mental health strong keep your body
strong and reach your goals keep
something around to inspire you and
remind you of all of those things yeah
be humble you know it's easy to forget
people a lot of people like to wear the
there are different pieces of religious
jewelry the people where I'm not gonna
mention I'm oh I don't want to leave
anybody out or include anybody but he's
left religious things that hang on their
body or adorn themselves what they
remind them of that people have those
what would Jesus do bracelets know
something there's something like that
that you see on a an occasion so you
just go oh yeah I've got this here a lot
of people wear a necklace with a certain
shape on it I don't care what you choose
to wear but there are certain shapes of
people that represent certain things to
them put one of those onion just remind
me I gotta be good I got to do my stuff
I got to do my my mental chores my
physical chores and get to my goals try
to get to some goals this year Ben
- so - yeah don't if you're not gonna
reach your goals don't beat yourself up
you try it just do your best
hey just take a step towards it yeah
that's all okay
I'm not you life is a good aspiration
yeah yeah this turned into a different
kind of podcast than usual but that's
cool done impress yourself katrana
prestor see else who tryin to impress
everybody else the internet doesn't care
we're just doing [ __ ] for bikes and
cliques and what does it get you get you
likes and cliques and that's all you got
once you log out you ain't got [ __ ]
laughs oh hey how many likes did you get
on that post two months ago I don't even
remember exactly I think it may be
better that Instagram has taken off the
amount of likes it doesn't show you how
many likes you get on your post and I
think it may be healthier for people I
hope so yeah there's a disease going
through just humans right now with the
way we're using phones I'm sorry derail
at the stamp screens bro no screens we
went to a comedy show and we went to a
comedy show at a very large the Denver
convention centers never that places
yeah that's right so the Belko theater
is hidden inside the Denver Convention
Center inside the Denver Convention
Center is basically a six foot by nine
foot iPad and it's interactive and Clint
and I were hanging out and I found us
both mesmerised by this big screen they
didn't tear anything really except you
to press here and tell it where you want
to go and it would draw you a map from
here to here there was lead you how to
get there yeah we're [ __ ] smart
people we could [ __ ] walk from point
A to point B pretty well that's pretty
neat seeing the future stuff though we
did we were just mesmerized by that
thing there was a list of things you
cannot take in to the comedy show we
read the whole list just because it was
on some interactive screen don't give a
[ __ ] we couldn't we didn't have any of
those things you don't care there's no
chance we had any of that pretty stone -
so oh yeah we're going to see Tommy
Bonds or Joe Rogan so we were definitely
heavily medicated - at that time yeah
because we were pretty wiped out when we
were going to see Tommy Bonds
yeah have you seen the guy with pot
tattooed across his forehead I think
that guy looks a lot like Jeff Tate
there's a guy you'll see him on social
media he's got the word pothead wine
he's got joints for eyebrows oh yeah
well since I gonna say right set some
goals you guys it doesn't have to be in
the grow just set some goals and you
don't have to beat yourself up over it
doesn't have to be anything amazing I do
one thing do something one last time do
something one more time whatever just
improve in some way shape or form and be
honest with yourself about it and then
also remember that social media is just
a game and you don't have to win nobody
wins quit trying to impress everybody on
social media you'll be much happier then
uh episode 500 is coming
it'll be toward the end of January if my
scheduling is appropriate oh my goodness
where else is at the end of January oh
goodness it's crazy that you asked I
just dropped my pen I was trying to do
the David Letterman trick the other
thing the endow Expo January 25th and
26th at the Denver Martin Denver
Colorado
booth and a booth come say hi I forgot
my booth number I've got it written down
somewhere I will be posting that to the
social media so that everybody can find
that stuff but the endo Expo yeah come
check us out that should be a really
good time I've been packing up things
for days there's so good quite the
selection thank you I appreciate that
yes I think there are 20 items on the
menu there's a rumor
this guy Clint may show up the Indo Expo
and could be at my booth for some time
at some point I mean I heard that I hear
that and also I don't want to confirm
anything but I also hear that white mic
may be at the booth so people should
come by and say what's up to Clint
Clint's the tall guy missing a tooth and
white white white mic that was harder to
say than it was supposed to be I'm done
we're gonna edit that white mic is the
tall guy with the glasses on the
earrings come say hi yeah keep calling
him Clint it'll be fun
okay I'm the tall white guy with
dreadlocks I'm easy to spot come say
what's up the endo Expo but yeah I was I
was more focused on that's that's gonna
be a fun time that's gonna be chaotic
and fun get your tickets early make your
travel plans book your hotels all that
good stuff yeah
excited that's Kimmy's fun man yeah
cannot wait but before we get there I've
got to record episode 500 before I can
even leave for the Indo Expo it's got to
be recorded before I get in the car for
that I think it comes out to Monday
after the Indo Expo yeah so we've got to
have it pre pre recorded ready to rock
that's not hard to do no I could do that
but when I'm reaching out for is I would
like my listeners my friends my audience
you you who are listening I would like
you to give me your ideas what we gonna
do for 500 I don't know what to do for
episode 500 did we just do a normal
episode do I invite Clint and Mike and
possibly Kevin over do we just record do
we just do a normal Gro episode what
would you like on episode 500 and I know
I've been promising that mix episode
I'll turn to the pages right now so they
can see look at all that look at all
those notes that should exist right yeah
like five pages there that's unreal
that's the mix episode it's written I
will record that I've got my head back
on my shoulders most of the way there
will be a service and a funeral here but
right after that I'll be able to start
working on more episodes back to back
I'll get that mix episode out but what
do we do for 500 you guys what we go and
do this is like 493 just together yeah a
couple of weeks I can throw a show
together quickly I just need some ideas
some inputs and feedback what would you
guys like help me up I'll make it happen
for you I mean just even an idea that's
you have seen somebody else do maybe
it's a good idea yeah give me a shout
out let us know what you'd like send me
your feedback at grow from your heart at
hotmail.com is probably the best way to
get in touch with me grow from your
heart at hotmail.com I like that look on
your face client very professional look
oh great bro we've been going for like a
good 25 minutes now I don't think we
should open any more Pandora's boxes and
get rambling and start talking about too
much stuff here I don't have any more
notes do you have anything you'd like to
say well you've got a microphone and a
small audience oh oh yes it's growing
man
it's so nice to have like been a part of
something that's growing like this you
know because I'm just supporting on the
sidelines for the most part you know
you're a great supporter
you're not a cannabis grower uh you are
part of the cannabis community because
you do consume and it's been fun
watching you go from I don't smoked I
kind of smoke to I smoke pretty decently
now yeah like you can keep up
you still know dad that's okay we're not
going to twist your arm but I appreciate
the support man I need all kinds of
members on my team cheerleaders and
[ __ ] quarterbacks and eat them all so
I appreciate it thanks for being a good
cheerleader [ __ ] you know man and you're
here man you're here so that's what's
important that's what friends before
yeah what else you gonna say bro you
know for me I like it that's a friend
where I left you you guys this was a fun
episode I just wanted to come and have
Clint on the show and just gonna hang
out record a little bit tell everybody
thank you for all the love and support
you've been giving me while I'm going
through some weird [ __ ] with my uncle
passing away I'm okay because I'm gonna
be alright
I've got no other choice and to be
alright but I'm alright Glenn's here
I've had a lot of good friends patch
through and say hi the holidays were
being with my family made the holidays a
lot better it kind of brought us
together that was kind of cool had
Christmas dinner and Christmas dinner I
think we all felt a little bit of relief
like just being together and tell some
stories and laughing and talking chicks
that's what my uncle would have wanted
us to get together
does his two sisters and his brothers
were there so they're just talking [ __ ]
about him and each other and just like
it should have been you know what I mean
that's like it it took a minute to get
there but once we got there it was it
was great as well we needed so we're
gonna be alright you guys I appreciate
it I send all of the love back to you
thank you you know let's do this part of
the show
Clint thanks for hanging out dude I
appreciate it you're welcome brother
Clint now you're gonna hang out for a
few minutes after the show so you guys
thank you for listening if you liked
this episode was educational informative
or entertaining I don't remember the
words I'm supposed to say there if you'd
like to make a financial contribution of
the show you can do so by visiting
www.azcleanelections.gov
email addresses grow from your heart at
hotmail.com you know I would love to
hear from you that's all I've got for
you ladies and gentlemen boys and girls
I'll be back Thursday I think is the
next episode I will have my [ __ ] back
together I'll have some great new
content for you I want to thank you for
listening I want to send a giant shout
out to Deb and granny and until next
time take a phat dad and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]
I know
I'm okay
baby terrain your only two friend now
[Music]
thank you real
bleh
[Music]
do my dirty work scapegoat
real
[Music]
you know it
sad
[Music]
[Applause]
five
yeah
life and I no longer
[Music]
Steele
by a stunning
[Music]