[Music]
welcome back ladies and gentlemen boys
and girls pimps and hos friends and foes
smokers and growers it is time for
episode 496 of the grow from your heart
podcast this episode of the show is
brought to you by my friends at seeds
here now if you need new regular
feminised for auto flower seeds in your
garden I highly recommend seeds here now
and you can find them at
www.cdxzipstream.com
on the back of the package it says that
this product does contain sixty nine
point eight four percent total THC and
non detectable amounts of CBD big
shout-out to our friends at Green Dot
labs for the delicious cherry fluff full
spectrum extract ladies and gentlemen in
this episode I'm going to read some
listen or emails before we get to that
point of the show let's do some shout
outs to a few of our friends from
patreon let's start off with the big
giant grow from your heart podcast shout
out and thank you to my friend Woodside
one-nine-five I also want to send a
giant thank you shout out to bong breath
I also want to send a giant thank you
shout out to Steve Smith I always want
to send a giant grow from your heart
podcast hi-5 and thank you to todd kay
how about a big giant thank you to our
buddy dan the indoor man of course i
need to send a thank you shoutout to Roo
lighting Tim always want to send a giant
thank you shout out to Blackbird 76 of
course we owe a big high-five and a
thank you to Oki gross 720 I always need
to send that big thank-you shoutout to
fat rabbit and last but certainly not
least let's send a big giant grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to our friend willies armpit big thanks
big shout out to everybody who continues
to support the show on patreon I do
appreciate the support if you would like
to learn how to support the show you can
do so by visiting
/go from your heart all of the
information you need to support the show
will be right there on the screen all
right let's turn down that music and
focus a little bit on this podcast let's
start with this thank you I feel like I
am back I did not miss an episode but I
feel like I kind of checked out mentally
for a couple of episodes I did have a
death in my family that messed up my
rhythm that took me out of the game but
I feel like I am back I've got my head
back on my shoulders my life rhythms are
back in order I've got a lot of great
friends and a lot of great family who
supported me through that so big thanks
to everybody who supported me kept me
happy kept me stoned kept me smile and
kept me distracted big thanks big
respect I appreciate all of that the
friends around here the family around
here but also the people that reached
out online the people that sent me
emails the people that sent me Instagram
and Facebook messages the people that
sent me text messages I received all of
those messages I did not reply to all of
them because it was overwhelming but
thank you I do appreciate it so I am
back I'm back on my game I've got my
[ __ ] together
we'll get this podcast flowing again and
it is right on time because episode
number 500 is coming up I've been
working on some ideas for that I've been
asking you to share ideas I've gotten a
lot of great feedback on that so I'm
excited for episode 500 then shortly
after episode 500 I will start the
series of episodes where I describe the
mix that I use in a commercial grow
environment I will go in thorough detail
about my nutrient mix and how I feed my
plants that will happen shortly after
episode 500 so stay tuned for that also
I've got a great episode about popping
and twisting our plants I've also got a
great episode about lolli popping I've
got a lot of great stuff coming up so
I'm excited to be back in the game and
bring you some quality podcasts again
thank you to everybody who supported me
and kind of let me take a little bit of
a break while I was having a rough time
I'm also getting excited because the
endo Expo is coming up really soon
that's right the endo Expo in Denver
Colorado that is on January 25th and
26th at the Denver Mart in Denver
Saturday is a business to business day
Sunday is open to the general public if
you need tickets I suggest you get that
now because the event will sell out and
if you do get tickets get there early
because there is a long line to get into
the building but the endo Expo is a
wonderful tradeshow it's a very large
event many of your favorite breeders
will be there with a booth I will be
there at booth 533 drop by say hi shake
my hand
grab a few packs of fresh I region etics
beans I look forward to seeing you at
the endo Expo alright that music just
politely faded itself out so let's jump
right into the email portion of this
podcast the first email in this episode
comes from our friend of the Kanna Kratt
big shout out to the Kanna Kratt
mechanic rat has been supporting the
growth from your heart podcast for quite
a while also a big supporter of the dood
grow show it's a big shout-out to the
Canon Kratt thank you for being a
crucial member of the cannabis and the
cannabis podcast community his message
goes like this hey dude I just wanted to
take a minute to wish you a Happy New
Year well happy [ __ ] New Year bro
thanks for reaching out it goes on to
say I hope 2020 brings you your family
and your businesses great success and I
have no doubt it will thank you man that
means a lot to me happy New Year to
yourself as well I hope 2020 blesses you
your family your business and your
garden and like you said I have no doubt
that your year will be amazing your
great [ __ ] dude and you're killing it
in the grow let's keep moving with the
message it says also I wanted to extend
my thoughts about your recent loss again
as your uncle seemed like a fun dude
Thank You Man I appreciate that all
these kind messages really keep me fuel
and it helps out it goes on to say you
told the Metallica story on one of the
very first episodes of the drove from
your heart podcasts that I listened to
and I was like this dude's cool I should
keep listening to this podcast and now
you're about to be at 500 episodes and
that's a great way to tie everything
together
I do remember talking about my uncle and
talking about Metallica early on in the
podcast because that's influential [ __ ]
to me that's really important so that's
gonna come up sometimes in a show or
sometimes in conversation so I love that
you caught an episode where I talked
about my uncle and I talked about
Metallica and then I did it just again a
couple of episodes ago and you've been
listening for quite a while and you're
right bro we are approaching episode 500
that means four episodes from now we'll
be number 500
I actually just sent a text message to a
few of your favorites that have been on
the show inviting them to come back and
be on the show four or five hundred
we've got a group chat going on we're
going to get a date together we'll sit
down a record episode 500 hopefully by
the end of the weekend so 500 is coming
up and yes I am super excited about that
he says Congrats
thank you bro I appreciate that thank
you for being here for so long also I
goes on to say so 500 you were asking
for some ideas yes I reached out on the
podcast and I said what do we do for
episode 500 should it be ceremonious or
do we just smoke out and record a normal
show just like we normally do and here
is some feedback from my friend the can
of crack he says do it live and that's a
really good idea it says rotating cast
white mic Clint Jesse a few hours of
dabs rambles and general bullshitting
about cannabis that sounds like a great
idea one of the only downsides to that
is I believe Jesse is in Mexico Jesse
likes to take random vacations down
there in Mexico he speaks better Spanish
than he does English now he's got a
thing for Mexico
I think it's tacos he [ __ ] loves
tacos Jesse is half taco at this point
but so Jesse won't be around but of
course I did invite white Mike to
episode 500 it wouldn't be episode 500
without white Mike it would be rude as
hell to not invite white Mike I feel he
needs to be here so I did invite cracker
Mike for that also I invited Clint I
also invited Dumbledore tank I'm waiting
to see ah let those three guys kind of
lock in a date get some stuff scheduled
and then I've got two or three other
people I'm going to send a text to once
I have a better idea of who is coming
and how many chairs and microphones I've
got left I've got one or two more people
that I do need to invite I just want to
walk in a date and tell these people
this is when it happens because that's
how they work you know some of your
friends you let them schedule some of
them you just have to tell them Tuesday
at 5:00 and then they'll show up Tuesday
at 7:30
just like you anticipated you know how
your stoner friends are let's move
forward I would love to get my friends
the crew the Irie army over for the show
it is hard to schedule that but if I can
get a few people over and if I can get
them all to agree to it I would not have
any issue with doing some of the podcast
live I may not do the
tool Podcast portion of the podcast life
I may do a pre-show dab session on
Instagram live would be the easiest way
for me to do that I could just set up
the iPad prop it up on something across
the room so it gets the whole smoking
section into the shot and then we could
just do a little dab session and say
what's up to everybody on the live show
and then we could turn off that and then
actually record the actual podcast maybe
do a little bit of a bonus live party
before maybe I'll get to stoned after
that and I'll forget to turn off the
camera and we may keep rolling and I may
record the entire podcast episode and if
it is not too challenging I'm a piece it
into a YouTube video
but honestly video editing is not my
favorite thing and it is very time
consuming and I've got a lot going on
this month with the Indo Expo so I make
no promises for video but I may do a
live chat before you guys these dad's
got me [ __ ] rambly I've had plenty of
caffeine I smoked that cherry fluff and
I cannot shut the [ __ ] up this is gonna
be a longer podcast than I anticipated
you are welcome Kenny crack goes on to
say general bullshitting about cannabis
yes that is what we do then he says
YouTube on a Saturday evening or
something just my two cents the two days
I offered everybody to do the show are
the coming Friday and Saturday we had a
couple people say Friday I think one
person said Saturday so we will dial
that in I will do my best to post to
social media and let people know that I
am about to go live then he wraps that
up and says just my two cents hey bro
your two cents is heavy around here
you've been around for a while you've
proven yourself I know you are capable
of rational thought so your two cents
goes a long way thanks for reaching out
bro he goes on to say I've had a great
run with I read genetics in 2019 and
will strive to be an even better grower
and human in 2020 peace dude Vinny
signed with his real name I don't know
if he wants his real name out there but
big thanks big respect to the Kanak rat
and if you're on Instagram or cannabis I
highly recommend you check out an
application called cannabis here's a
shameless plug for cannabis and then
we'll wrap that up with a shameless plug
for my buddy the Kanak rat cannabis is a
cannabis friendly social media
application you cannot buy sell or trade
cannabis but you can pose
your cannabis related content to
cannabis you could post your cannabis
weed photos you can post your dab videos
you could post your bong rip videos you
can post your videos yourself smoking a
joint and being silly any of those
photos that Instagram has been taking
down cannabis invites you to come post
cannabis is a free application it's
available for your Android it's
available for your iPhone and you can
even access the application through the
website I encourage you to join cannabis
then once you've joined cannabis give me
a follow I'm Irie underscore genetics on
cannabis then once you're all set up on
cannabis I recommend you follow the
underscore canna underscore crack the
canna Kratts on Instagram and the Canada
Kratt on cannabis he's been posting some
amazing ganja photos he's got a
beautiful grow of the profit growing and
it looks amazing
I can almost smell it through his photos
I keep scratching my phone screen and
holding it up to my face just wishing I
could get some scratch and sniff
smellivision
technology so you guys make sure you
give the can of crap a big follow shout
out bro your plants really do look
[ __ ] super good man all right let's
keep moving forward because I am high
and rambley this next email comes from
our friend who calls themselves dude
dank and it goes a lot like this hey
Jeff its dude dank here again I just
thought that since you asked for ideas
since you have episode 500 coming up and
the DGC have episode 1000 coming up why
not collaborate and do an anniversary
show together and pull off a bit of a
party and that is a cool [ __ ] idea
that would be a really good time you
said just an idea thought it might be
good that's a really good idea he said I
support and love both shows hey thank
you for the great idea I support and
love both shows as well big shout out to
the full DGC crew big shout out to the
dude of course big shout it to Scottie
big shout out to guru and everybody
behind the scenes I know there are a lot
of folks that make that show happen that
we don't get to see that we don't talk
about a lot so let's give them some love
right now big thanks big shout out big
fist bump to all of the folks behind the
scenes at the dude Gro show that we
never get to see I really do love the
idea of doing a party
in episode us doing 500 and them doing
number 1000 the problem is the dude
grows studio where Scottie is is about
four hours away from my location and
then the dude is in Canada so if we
wanted to do something like that it
would take a lot of planning and a lot
of internet technology and that would
basically eliminate the possibility of
getting my crew here to be able to be on
the show as well we would need too many
computers too many cameras too much
equipment too much preparation it would
be a lot of work and I don't have any
gurus I don't have any warehouse kyle's
or any errands or anybody like that to
come do my [ __ ] for me the girl from
your heart podcast is all me it's a
one-man show over here so I don't have
the technology the gear or the true for
that but it's a cool idea I can see it
in my head it would be the greatest
party ever we do actually have a couple
of events that become the dude grows
event but it is also a lot of the growth
from your heart podcast listeners a lot
of the I read genetics crew the IRA army
is all the same people we all show up to
the same event those events are thrown
by the dude grows crew it is the dude
grows cup around 4:20 and then we get
together again around 7:10 and we do the
dude grows concentration celebration so
we've got two great events thrown by the
dude grows crew by the dude gross show
big shout-out to the dude for the dude
grows cup and big shot at the Scotty for
the dude grows concentration celebration
but at those events it becomes a big
dude grows crew grow from your heart pod
cast crew Irie army crew sort of a
gathering because we're all listening to
the same shows we all support the same
people we're all the same community we
are all on the same team and we all have
the same goal so we have a great party
which is coming up that wasn't going to
be a plug for the event but the dude
grows Cup is coming up in April stay
tuned for announcements and details make
sure you listen to the dude gross show
for all of the information on that one
shut up it's all my friends at the dude
gross show once again much love in much
respect he wraps up this message with
take care dude dank u K hey my friend
dude dank from the UK thank you for
listening to the podcast thank you for
all of the support and thank you for the
great suggestions for Epis
five hundred I have another email right
in front of me there is no need to stop
let's keep moving the next message comes
from my buddy dick goals and it goes
just alike at this it says Merry
Christmas Rasta Jeff Merry Christmas
back atcha my friend then it goes on to
say thank you for all of your wisdom
conversation inspiration and seeds wow
that's amazing
you're welcome thank you for noticing ah
wisdom conversation and inspiration yeah
I guess I do deliver all of those thank
you that is a great compliment and thank
you for noticing and pointing that out
and complimenting me that is [ __ ]
cool it's a great compliment so it goes
on to say oh and your work preserving
and improving cannabis genetics that's
important hey thank you for noticing my
friend that is a huge cluster of great
compliments I appreciate that
perfectly time thank you I goes on to
say I wouldn't be as inspired to grow
and I certainly wouldn't be doing as
well so early on without the hours of
fantastic content you put out there that
is awesome to hear thank you I am
delighted to hear that my little work
I've done sitting here and writing and
talking I'm delighted to hear that that
effort has made your grow experience
more enjoyable and more successful I
thought I think those two things may
come together the enjoyment and success
may reflect each other but it does mean
a lot for me to hear that you feel like
you did better because of the little
effort I put out you had to put a lot of
effort out as well my friend so it was a
group effort there is more to this it
goes on to say in an industry quickly
becoming corporate where people
increasingly try to hide their knowledge
as trade secret you put it almost all
out there and thus improve the quality
of cannabis for everyone exactly that is
kind of my goal I feel like I learn
rather quickly I learned things that I
care about rather quickly I've got a
very absorbent brain I'm not sure if
that's the appropriate terms for it I
talk about how smart I am and I don't
even know the [ __ ] words to use for
it right I feel like I I can retain
knowledge that I care about quite
quickly obviously I care a lot about
cannabis I care a lot about growing
cannabis I care a lot about smoking
consuming cannabis I absolutely care a
lot about breeding cannabis I just have
a big passion for cannabis it's a big
part of my life and I feel like it has
taken me
very far I feel like I am successful in
life not a lot of people can actually
say they feel successful and I feel like
I'm doing what I enjoy doing and I'm
surviving semi comfortably by doing
something that I have passion for so I
don't feel like I'm working my ass off I
work very hard but since I love it and
have passion for it I don't feel like
I'm slaving away working for myself and
doing something that I have passion for
it just feels like I'm having the best
day every day when I'm working and I'm
doing a little air quotes when I say the
word working it is work but it's not
work that a lot of people have to endure
so I feel like I'm very and I hate to
sound cliche right now but I am very
blessed I am very grateful for the fact
that I don't have to work for a
corporation or that I don't have to have
one of those nine-to-five jobs that
everybody hates I'm very grateful that I
don't have to do that so I feel like
since this plant took me so far since I
had such great passion for the plant
since I was able to learn so quickly and
there was such a need for this knowledge
I feel like it was kind of my duty in my
job to put all of this stuff I learned
out there there is so much bad advice on
the internet there are so many bad
growers offering what looks like expert
advice online and a lot of that stuff is
going to cause more problems I felt like
it was partly my responsibility I've got
a big mouth I can't stop talking I've
got a huge passion for cannabis I've got
all this beautiful gear I felt like
something came together and said you
need to put this information out there
for everybody to be able to grow the
quality cannabis the you and your
friends are producing in your area I was
around the Colorado medical marijuana
market early I was growing in another
state before it was legal we won't talk
too much about that but it may have been
happening so I had a lot of experience I
was a little bit ahead of the game I may
have been doing it before it was legal
so I had a little bit of practice and as
soon as it was legal all I had to do is
go look I know how to grow and everybody
needed help and needed guidance and I
was more than happy to return that karma
back to the world because I got away
with illegal grows in illegal states I
started my cannabis career as a
black-market
just a joint seller I worked in a
restaurant I sold joints to the kitchen
crew and then eventually I sold
ates to the kitchen crew and then
eventually I sold a bunch of quarters to
all of my friends and then eventually I
was selling quarter pounds and then you
know you're just selling a bunch of
pounds and then you're doing crazy [ __ ]
that you don't want to be doing anymore
and now those days are over for me and
I'm here in the legal cannabis industry
and I feel like I kind of got away with
a bunch of [ __ ] that I may or may not
allegedly have done back in the day
involving cannabis and now I feel like
my karma is to put this knowledge back
out here and help everybody produce
top-shelf medicine or recreational
cannabis I believe that's medicine also
I feel better after I consume cannabis
and that means it's probably medicinal
in some sort of way it's absolutely
therapeutic for me so maybe we'll just
make up a new term therapeutic cannabis
it's right in the middle between
recreational and medicinal
so my first dab is medicinal marijuana
my second dad is medicinal marijuana my
third one is therapeutic my fourth one
that's recreational you guys I'm [ __ ]
rambley from the recreational dad's I've
been taking let's finish up this email
because I got off way on a tangent there
it says I hope you have a fantastic
Christmas with your friends and family I
cannot wait to shake your hand and say
hello at the endo Expo dick goals I'm
excited to meet you my friend we've been
talking online for quite a while I am
very excited to shake your hand
he wraps it up with thanks again for all
you do for myself and the cannabis
community it doesn't go unnoticed
thank you brother that does mean a lot
they wrap it up with best then they sign
it from rich and that's my buddy dick
goals so big shout out to dick goals out
there in the world I'm gonna live with
the name dick goals it's probably fun
sometimes
probably [ __ ] horrible sometimes hey
dick thank you for all the love and all
the support ah thanks for noticing that
I am doing a lot for the cannabis
community and thank you for the great
email hope you have a great Christmas
and a great New Year and I look forward
to shaking your hand at the endo Expo
that sounds like another great
opportunity for a shameless plug for the
endo Expo that's right January 25th and
26th at the Denver Mart in Denver
Colorado it is the endo Expo January
25th is business-to-business Day January
26th is open to the general public you
do need to get your tickets
I know I keep saying that the event will
sell out also get there early because
the lines do get long rather quickly
come find I read genetics at booth 533
drop by shake my hand take a selfie say
hello
grab some I read genetics I look forward
to meeting everybody at the endo Expo
don't be shy you guys I don't want to
get an email or a tweet or a text
message or an Instagram message from you
the day after the endo Expo saying
walked by your booth bro you looked busy
it would have been cool to shake your
hand bro come shake my hand that's what
I'm there for
even if you got to wait in line for a
couple of seconds come say hi come shake
my hand don't be shy say what's up I
want to be your friend also I know I'm
six five I got dreads to my [ __ ]
knees almost and I may look a little
crazy I'm a nice dude I want to be your
friend I won't bite alright come say hi
alright Podcast rolled my voice is
burning out I feel like this was a good
Thursday show I want to thank everybody
for listening if you feel like this
episode was educational informative or
entertaining and you would like to
support the show financially you can do
so by visiting www.disabilitydenials.com
10th i want to give a giant shout out to
my buddy ryedawg and until next time
take a phat dab and give your mom a hug
for me
[Music]
[Applause]