ladies and gentleman welcome back it is
time for episode 502 of the Grove from
your heart podcast sitting at the table
with me this counter [ __ ] clockwise
yeah counter clockwise sitting at the
table is white Mike we got Dumbledore
dank and tall Clint are back
welcome to the show boys and girls
thanks for hanging out hello how's it
going everybody that's a super awkward
intro I [ __ ] love it ladies and
gentlemen this episode of the show is
brought to you by our friends at seeds
here now if you need new regular
feminized or auto flower seeds in your
garden I highly highly recommend seeds
here now and of course you can find them
at seeds here now
dot-com we usually start the show by
talking about what we're dabbing I just
took some fat dabs of ice cream live
batter from Green Dot labs but we've got
a special treat at the table tonight
Matt tell us about what we're dad or
what we're smoking over there um we
actually have a little bit of flour from
love and in her eyes we've got some
lovin in her eyes flour the lovely lovin
in her eyes stopped by the booth at the
endo Expo and dropped off some grape
cake
it smells [ __ ] grape it looks like
[ __ ] connoisseur if you've ever seen
lovin in her eyes as photos if you
haven't looked yet go look loving in her
eyes on Instagram these buds are
beautiful it is sparkly it's FRA it's
stuck to my finger I can't put the weed
back in the jar this is mine now bro
sorry yeah mine it's cured perfectly I
gotta say first you know I was very very
impressed with her stuff beautiful
product big shout-out to loving in her
eyes a beautiful person wonderful person
got to meet her and her other half they
showed up at the booth at the endo Expo
was an honor to meet them it's an honor
to be smoking some grape cake grown by
love and her eyes on the show thanks for
bringing that Matt yeah yeah I was lucky
enough to get to tray her a little bit
of mine so I'm hoping she enjoyed some
of that as well I hope you get some
feedback from her she's actually growing
a couple of my crosses now so we may see
some photos in the future yeah yeah I
was gonna wait to talk about this but
since we kind of segue it into that
accidentally let's do an update on the
IRA genetics Instagram page recently I
discovered that Instagram [ __ ] up the
IRA genetics Instagram page and made it
Iowa's shadow band really strongly
then they changed it to where it was
only viewable by viewers who were 21 of
years of age or older then I discovered
that most people couldn't even see the
page at all so I went poking around and
found some settings I think I've
corrected some of the settings and you
should be able to view my Instagram page
now so if we met you at the endo Expo
and you've been trying to find my
Instagram its back so give me another
chance find me it's Irie underscore
genetics on Instagram I've been posting
a lot of high quality cannabis
photography a bunch of Indo Expo photos
so please find me again we would
appreciate it I miss you guys who'd be
good to see you so that is the Instagram
update it is traditional that we do some
shoutouts to our friends from patreon at
the start of the show so let's do that
let's give a giant shout out to our
friend Meredith let's give some
shoutouts to Steve Smith I also want to
send a giant shout out to Rick roller do
a big THANK YOU to Debbie Hays I bet a
big THANK YOU to Brett G and Jacob
Debbie you also want to send some love
to James Brown the hardest working man
in cannabis I also send a giant shoutout
to Keith K Todd K and last but not least
how about a big THANK YOU shot it's a
black bird 76 big shout-out to all those
people for supporting us on patreon if
you were not supporting the show on
patreon and you would like to support us
you can do so by visiting
www.disabilitydenials.com endowment
largest indoor cultivation expo they
have all of the nutrient companies all
of the lighting companies all of these
seed companies what else was there you
guys what am I missing there is
everything a nice track any business
tied to marijuana cannabis
[Music]
air ten things it was there if you
everything but consuming accessories
there wasn't much glass it wasn't a
vaporizer to sale there was some yes
there was clothing available then also
there was an entire hemp pavilion that
was focused on hemp and CBD products so
it had all of the cultivation covered
you could get free samples of nutrients
you could get lights you could get
stickers from every company on the
planet and there were plenty of people
who did plenty of people got a lot of
great steaks of his tribe but these boys
these gentlemen these wonderful men came
and helped out at the IRA genetics booth
at the endo Expo I owe them a big thank
you so thank you guys great time you
guys did a great job we had a lot of
people visit the booth it was a yes big
thanks to everybody if you just stop by
and grabbed a sticker if you fist bumped
us a lot of people just walked by and
gave that friendly nod because they
didn't want to disrupt business if you
came and spent a couple of bucks if you
came and chatted our ears off big shout
out big thank you for all of the support
to everyone who showed us love at the
endo Expo but these guys did a great job
there were a lot of people and for a
couple of moments it was overwhelming
for everybody including myself I'm used
to this type of a crowd and this type of
[ __ ] I was like oh god that's a lot of
people we got a speed up our game right
but these guys took good care of
everybody and the people that came to
the booth they understood like it can
only help so many people at a time and
they wanted to meet Rasta Jeff most of
the people wanted to shake my hand and
say hi at our booth wasn't the only line
I ran into
it was yeah there were a lot of wines at
the event I really enjoyed that when I
people would meet me I'd say hey do you
listen to the show and they'd say yes
and I go that's Clint and that's Mike
and that's a double-door tank and people
be like holy [ __ ] they would want to
meet you guys too it was really cool to
kind of share that love cuz usually do
these events by myself or with one other
person who doesn't care to be noticed or
anything who hasn't been on the show so
it's cool to get you guys some love and
get you out there get you some high
fives it was really cool to meet a lot
of people that was fun and I really had
a good time I it was all positive
experience there was zero drama up there
it was so nice meeting people it was so
fun meeting someone and then them
looking at me and going is it and then
you like tell them hey that's Clint oh
alright you've got a pretty distinct
beep voice you know what I mean when we
talk about you being a tall guys I get
excited though and it gets a little
higher
I was forever known as helper monkey
yeah I had him just really funny
they give us four passes for the event
and I wasn't sure who was going to be my
fourth helper I had somebody I was
thinking about having helped me but then
I thought that Matt would be a better
fit so when I registered the badge I
just put the word helper monkey on there
because that's what they were gonna be
and we got away with that so it was all
cool I thought until I registered and I
got an email that said all right you're
registered helper monkey make sure to
bring your ID and I was like oh [ __ ] no
what do I do I made it work so it was
awesome somebody was telling me how
great of a vertical like grower he was
and I was like yeah he is man he's a
badass guy that guy does a good job yeah
I really thought it was fun I've been
going to these events for a long time
years High Times Cannabis Cup endo Expos
dude grows cups whatever you want to
talk about I've probably been to the
event in Colorado seven ten cup secret
cup secret sash haven't hit them for a
while so I know most of the industry
most of the seed breeders most of the
growers most of the Instagram people or
whatever a couple of these guys at the
table Clint doesn't give a [ __ ] about
celebrities and popular people that's
just not his thing no offense to Clint a
lot of people don't care about that
stuff that hype doesn't get them Clint's
got other [ __ ] on his mind so when he
meets famous people is like hey you're
famous hi
it doesn't really he doesn't get
superstar star those at the time I don't
know and then everybody's just human so
yeah and when people some people would
meet me and get starstruck and I'd be
like no I got hungry today and I poop
today just like you like it was fun to
watch yeah sometimes people would come
to the booth and say hi and it would be
somebody from the industry that's like
that I find to be kind of you know
somebody to look up to somebody who's
important and these guys would have no
idea who the [ __ ] I'm talking to and
it'd be somebody that owns another seed
company that I've looked up to or
somebody that has inspired me and when
they would walk away and be like hey
Matt do you know who that was like no
who was that oh that's just this guy
that owns this company and he's like oh
my holy [ __ ] it was just these guys had
no idea who they were standing new
standing next to half the time and then
when they did it was funny to watch you
guys get kind of starstruck a couple of
times that was pretty fun especially
Matt cuz he's kind of silly younger than
me new to this those willing to watch
well I do follow a lot of the social
media stuff too so like you know I spent
like the last couple years just watching
like certain people's page and like to
get
it's like oh [ __ ] yeah they just just
awesome to come say hi like Oh a lot of
people to hide what they look like
really well off of their Instagram you
know purposely so you don't really have
an idea okay this is you know I love and
in her eyes you can know it's a girl
probably because you know it has sets
her in there but half of the other ones
you don't know it could be a guy could
be a girl it you know and so when you're
like hey you know who that was and I'm
like now who the [ __ ] was it yeah then
I'm like well that was this personally
who the [ __ ] is that and I tell you
there's this on Instagram you're like oh
[ __ ] yeah yeah it's really funny like
trying to figure out and then I have
this thing where I'm not sure I know
people's real names
I know people's Instagram names and I
know their email addresses and sometimes
I'm talking to three different
conversations thinking it might be three
different people and then sometimes it
hits me that oh this guy is also this
guy is also this guy or sometimes I'm
thinking of talking but it's so hard to
keep all the social media and real and
email all those conversations like I
don't know maybe it's just me being
weird but it's hard to keep all those
names and faces together a lot of them I
don't have faces for until the end o
Expo so that's really fun like getting
to put a face to all these emails
finally is really nice oh yeah there was
a lot of people that came up and it's
like hey I'm on this on cata buzz it was
it was really cool to see that yeah oh
that's what you look like that was cool
it's really fun seeing what our
demographic looks like because I have no
idea and it was fun watching them
discover daily we're all six foot
something tall they're looking at us
like what the [ __ ] Oh matt said it's a
good thing it wasn't a breeders
basketball tournament oh god yeah no I
watched like a couple of them walked by
and just look like oh it was great
we're all peaceful where's we I didn't
make myself six five it's gonna be and
then a lot of people didn't realize I
had dreadlocks that were this ridiculous
they're pretty well tied up for the
event but you can tell I got a lot of
threads up here and people like you got
a lot of hair dude it's interesting to
see I just think it's funny that the
shortest dude at the booth is six two
and that was me yeah you're the tiniest
dude there that's why you're the helper
monkey bro I know ah Clint said it best
a moment ago can abuzz let's talk about
cannabis a lot of our friends from
cannabis were at the event big shout out
to junior token it was I was wonderful
to smoke some
you spent some time with you get some
love on Sunday we ran out of cannabis
stickers and pamphlets and junior token
fell from the sky I don't know where he
came from nowhere
poof was at the corner of the booth
there like eight minutes after we
realized we'd ran out of cannabis set
stickers and pamphlets down gave Mike a
fist bump and vanished into the crowd
like a superhero again we're like well
that was pretty [ __ ] cool just
replenished us with advertising and left
yeah he was a cool guy school I had a
good conversation with him I don't get
to spend much time with that dude and it
was really great to spend some time with
him and a lot if I hey guys if we got to
hang out this weekend I'm not gonna give
everybody a shout out but you know who
you are it really means a lot to me to
sit down and or even if it's at the
booth and I'm just shaking your hand for
a moment it means a lot to me to shake
your hand to look you in the eye if we
shared a moment that does mean a [ __ ]
lot to me I know it means a lot to you
guys cuz you listen and you feel like
you've been hearing me but it means just
as much to me to meet you and sit down
to shake your hand like I got to hang
out the embracing organics crew we hang
out online but to sit down and actually
smoke with those guys and actually be
friends with them that [ __ ] is always
fun so it meant a lot to me to just hang
out that whole crew and if you came to
the booth if you shared some energy with
us that means a lot it's a lot of work
doing these shows it's a lot of work
being a breeder and being but I hate to
act like I'm somebody online but a lot
of people know who I am I get a lot of
questions and a lot of interaction it's
exhausting but these types of events all
these hugs high-fives compliments
encouragement fist bumps simple nods all
that [ __ ] is like a battery recharger
and I [ __ ] love it so thank you guys
you filled me back up for another six or
seven months worth of [ __ ] energy
like that it's really awesome
cannabis make sure you follow us on
cannabis I read genetics on cannabis at
at the junior token let's see endo Expo
do we have so many fun people come to
the booth that I don't want to try to
mention too many people cuz we're gonna
forget people and miss stuff but well
you had an overwhelming you had an
overwhelming amount of support this year
from all kind of companies different
breeders
would come by I mean you really got the
support and kind of Sunday I took more
selfies with people on Sunday then I've
taken all the past year it was so much
fun I love it and big shout out to
everybody big thanks if you came by
don't be the guy that was like
I saw you didn't want to come by thank
you if you brought a gift thank you I'm
looking at the table right now of gifts
and freebies and love that people
brought to me there are t-shirts there's
weed there's nutrients there's a mug
there's probably enough t-shirts that
are out enough to do laundry for a month
yeah people were super generous I mean
one guy kept coming around some cookies
and I you know that's big Tim from
organic Oh what's up Tim thanks for
keeping my crew mini yeah man thanks for
the cookie sick shout out to Tim and
Myles and of course a big shout out to
miss Amy was a pleasure seeing all that
everybody that came up from New Mexico
we had a lot of Albuquerque folks and
New Mexico friends out there I was
surprised at the variety of places
people came in from like New Mexico
Arizona Las Vegas Philly Philly Illinois
our friend we came from London London I
had a couple of friends from Oregon yep
yeah big shout out to grows oh she was
not really more as both days it was I
mean a really great event um what was
you guys his favorite moment at the Indo
Expo let's just go let's go [ __ ] left
to right so Mike did you have any
standout moments twice on Saturday
listeners to the show know that this
show and the dude gross show do a lot to
support each other
Scotty and the dude were at the expo and
stop by our booth a couple times both
times on Saturday that they stopped by
our booth for a minute well they were
kind of standing on the right edge of
our booth at the left edge of our booth
there was somebody talking to Jeff who
was said saying enthusiastically I found
you guys through the DGC I love both
your shows you guys are so awesome I'm
so glad I found you it's so cool that
you're here I love the DGC I love
everything you guys are doing together
without any hint of awareness that
Scotty in the Deuter standing 1618
inches behind yep if it happened twice
in an hour within an hour from each
other it was just a beautiful fun
convention thing that I just it's been
amusing me since it happened man I've
been smiling because of it so if you
don't watch the video show up the dude
gross show you don't know what the dude
and Scotty looked like
I don't know if they were primary
listeners or if they were just call it
in the spirit of the convention yeah and
not paying a lot of attention to who
else was right around them some people
were um heavily medicated might be the
words yeah you know it was really
convenient you want to tell them about
the discovery you made Mike but the the
gender segregated babe loans just yeah
about 40 feet from our booth yeah it was
really interesting Mike pointed out that
there was a gender specific vape lounge
just to the right and I went in
allegedly allegedly mom said no there
I'm about 40 almost 40 years old I've
been to a lot of events in Colorado over
the last four decades and never once is
a bathroom ever smelled that nice you
know it was not a problem
you'd open that door and it looks like
well it's most kind of nice in here yeah
I couldn't figure out why there were a
bunch of urinals in the bait lounge but
I used them yeah I mean it was
convenient it was really nice it was
really convenient there's about thirty
or forty feet from our booth it made for
a really nice weekend big shout out to
our friends at Green Dot labs for these
beautiful Green Dot lab cartridges and
pins thank you for the support of super
functional you know is also cool because
I got to finally meet the guy that runs
the Green Dot labs Instagram page also
dreadlock white guy what's up bro team
dreadlocks nice I've been sharing a lot
of posts or posting a lot of photos of
my Green Dot concentrates and that dude
shares my post and gives me a lot of
support so it's really cool to finally
meet the dude like I'm saying earlier is
[ __ ] nice to put some faces to all
these Instagram accounts and finally say
hey thank you because a lot of people
give me a lot of support I'm gonna give
a special thank you to my friend Jaron
from new millennium nutrients every
event I go to I bump into Jaron I ran
into journey at the fish shows this
summer and hung out with him there and
burned down with him one night at the
fish shows yeah like Jaron is just we're
destined to be friends so I see him at
every event and he is much more
experienced at going to these events
than myself I feel like and he always
makes me feel a little at ease and a
little comfortable it's like when you
find like the first day of school when
you're nervous and you find one of your
friends like [ __ ] I gotta go find Mike
school sucks by myself and when I see
Jerry and I'm always like how this event
will be just fine like
shoutout to Jaron he's a good dude he
brought some new millennium products to
the table so he can display them all so
I brought them home with me at the end
of the event that was a rental fee for
that space on the table so thanks for
the nutrients private do big support for
new millennium I'm going to do that
episode that I keep telling everybody
about the mix episode it's probably
gonna be around episode 505 so stay
tuned that is coming I'm not lying to
you
I just got thrown off so Mike's favorite
moments were when the dude and Scotty
were standing there and people were
telling me how much they loved them and
did you were you at least polite enough
to be like well that tall guy on that
short guy beavis and butthead right
there I try Scotty but both times the
the person talking was a little bit
starstruck they were too into talking to
you in the moment to catch that there
were other people around them and all
really I mean it was just it was just a
really fun convention moment that I
don't know to perfect not to share with
the that's pretty fun shout out to the
dude and Scotty and also to guru guru it
was good seeing all you guys alright
Matt you're over there packing a bowl
you're being a good helper monkey but it
is time let's ask a man what was your
one of your favorite or you can have
more than one but what are some standout
moments for you Indo Expo this weekend
um I don't know man there's a lot of
people who came by and just the amount
of love and the things they wanted to
talk to you and take pictures with you
is just kind of amazing to see like how
much support you have from all over the
country and there was also like funny
moments as well where like somebody
would come over just hammer drunk
because even though it wasn't like you
know an open consumption event they had
a bar going so I'm not sure that guy was
drunk you talk about not sure that was
alcohol bro I think yeah no no he was
definitely not on our plane oh man yeah
it was tripping his face off is what I
think I talked to my community I
attempted communication with that person
bro if you're listening it's okay yeah
it's totally cool it just wasn't having
this show it was an Indo Expo so gonna
have to adjust but yeah that dude was
tripping his [ __ ] PB off man yeah
yeah he was hugging the table as he's
talking to me like about strains
he's like well what do you got and he's
like hugging the table and I'm like I I
got I gotta find you a chairs what I got
is he was having a hard time putting his
day together so tripping dude was your
favorite part um that yeah I mean that
and just being able to look around at
the end of it
we had kind of a hangout session and
being able to look around and see like
all of the people that you know I
watching the podcast and stuff and just
like ya see them like smoking a bowl
with me and [ __ ] it's just kind of it's
kind of nice because you know you watch
them and you know we had a little
after-party mmm well frosty McNuggets
his house I don't know if I'm supposed
to say that but big shot at the frosty
McNuggets he threw an awesome after
party that place there's a little
basement bro II but it was honestly
exactly what I [ __ ] wanted that
evening I got to hang out with all my
friends from embracing organics I got to
hang out with Mike was there Matt was
there Clint was there usually I don't
have my hometown crew with me so I get
to come back and tell you guys how much
fun I had it was really fun spending
that with you guys kind of taking you to
my world because I always come back I'm
like I did this I did this
and it sounds fantastical and now you
guys are like holy [ __ ] he really does
this stuff sometimes so you got to come
see it and experience it but the
embracing organics crew is their fuel
adore was [ __ ] there he came in we
never get to hang out humidor that was
my first time with humidor the dude
grows crew was there for a little bit
they couldn't all the dude couldn't make
it but Scotty was there so it was really
nice just like you said to have all the
podcast crew there half of the d GC was
there a bunch of the Irie army was there
Pedro and dizzy showed up yeah it was
such a cool [ __ ] party and it was a
great time I was feeling the same kind
of vibe that you were like this is all
the people and like I only get to see
them online so it's kind of cool to just
chill out with them and actually pass a
bowl around it takes of dabs and looking
yeah smoke together it was kind of nice
yeah man it was a gathering of a lot of
great people everybody was super nice
and it was there to welcoming you know
was there as well yeah oh you're a great
guy Clint all right so Matt thanks for
your input let's move over to Clint you
already know the question I hope oh man
I had such your favorite movie no I'm
just gonna you know Benson man all right
don't ever do that again oh my favorite
movie is will never do that it's [ __ ]
accurate - so what was one or two or all
of your favorite moments at the Indo
expose I get to meet so many cool people
there was zero drama all weekend's it
was so fun
throughout the whole weekend you know we
got to meet Theo von that was cool so I
didn't even touch on that did we bro
it's I mean we'll get to that later you
know I mean that was some I guess you
know we'll just go for it now we get we
get to go to a comedy show Friday and
that was Theo von yeah boy I'm gonna
please tell me Ari what was his opener
or I'm sorry I don't re Mannis Thank You
Ari manas and then what was his openers
name I can't remember the other guy
opener yeah the first one Billy
something is really a really plain guy
plain white guy
sorry plain white guy yeah that is
Mike's job so we got to go see if the
Oban we got we got to talk with him for
a minute
he was cool as hell and there was a long
line behind us so I didn't want to take
up much of his time so yeah they did
we're good at that we noticed to shake
hands get out they gave us good seats
they and this was at this comedy work
south club yes the landmark not a normal
Club and it was nice seeing some faces
that I recognized from the other Club
that must just like go back and forth
that like a managerial level or
something right
those guys are cool new waitresses are
awesome I I don't know I hadn't been to
this club before so it was really fun to
go to this one it was a different
feeling there please different vibe as a
completely different feeling completely
different setup you're absolutely
correct there so that was my favorite
part I didn't mean to like take away
from these guys can't really comment on
it so it's tough to know I wanted to
have a good segue to talk about Theo
there's a note right here that says Theo
so yeah Friday I went and set up for the
Indo Expo I basically put up the banner
throw up a tablecloth and carried in a
box of shirts and then I met up with
Clint and we got to go see Theo
I thought it was a pretty good show the
crowd was disruptive the show was
disorganized chaos
was in disarray and that's exactly what
you expect when you go see Theo I think
that's probably it's like when you go
see buck in a baseball game you expect
to see dudes in baseball pants throwing
a ball and we I expected to see exactly
what I got when I went to go see Theo
yeah his haircut says what he's gonna be
doing on stage that is basically
absolutely all you gotta say about that
show that haircut tells you what you're
gonna get
okay yep that was fun we got some fun
meet Theo got a good picture with him he
took a couple of pictures with me
because the lighting wasn't right in the
first one so he went back for another
photo I've never had an artist actually
made sure that my photo was good before
us without school well we were first in
line so if he wanted to make sure that
everybody else's photos got I mean I
thought it was smart as hell just he
wanted to get the lighting right on you
so that way okay himself and the next
person in the right spot every time all
right that makes a lot more sense makes
more sense to me all right
I think thank you to our friend Kelsey
at Comedy Works we met Kelsey at what
show was that who did we see I was when
Elia Woolsey opened for who do we see
this recently we talked about it a lot
bamboo do we smoke too much we was the
last show comedy works Kelsey there yeah
this weekend is all that's on my brain I
can't think of the comedy show before
that one come on somebody help us out
who did we see [ __ ] Santino bro we
saw cheeto Santino so we're at Santino
and we met Kelsey because I had my Brody
Stephens pin on my hat and she said hey
I like your hat and I told her positive
energy and then I said something about
enjoy and she said you got it and now
we're friends for life so yeah so shout
out to Kelsey she got us some pretty
decent seats over there the comedy works
thank you white perfect seats legroom
and a great view legroom and comedy
works I might have to check out the
original location be me so thanks to our
friends at Comedy Works big thanks to
frosty McNuggets for throwing that party
thanks to everybody that showed up so
that was that your favorite part of
Clint was the comedy show and all the
cool last people you got to meet that
stood out yeah all the cool people
everybody had such a good vibe to him I
mean the whole event was
fairly well-run I didn't see any like
huge problems or anything like that but
there wasn't a lot of food going around
that could have been better maybe for
next year definitely could he use some
some food bending inside but I don't
know I think maybe we just didn't see it
it was there were so many people there
so it was spot food finding inside would
take up boot space for exhibitors the
the expo was massive two days they tried
to walk around a little bit I ate I know
I only saw maybe 20% of it there's a
subway inside the place there's a cafe
inside the place so there's food we just
didn't fight you guys didn't find the
subway it's in there we were hanging out
of the booth it was fun I made it to the
booth into the men's vape lounge is as
far as I got all weekend I didn't get to
go see I want to go hang out with Colin
Gordon for a moment didn't get go see
him I wanted to go see a couple of
people I made a quick stop at the organ
elite seeds booth and the seeds here now
booth just to say hey what's up give
them hugs cuz we work together and I was
back to the booth as quickly as I could
I was nervous away from the booth that
felt like my post was left unmanned and
I trust you guys I know you got it but
I'm still like man I gotta be that my
face is on the [ __ ] banner yeah so I
was waiting to get back there it
honestly felt like a mad rush for seeds
this year as far as people going to like
just I had a cell for other people
mentioned that the crowds were good
around each seed booth yeah it was
people who were doing other stuff like
heavy high end extraction equipment
stuff like that and they pretty much all
uniformly mentioned like see seed
companies look like that's the hot spot
this month it's how those events that's
why they spread us out I don't know if
you noticed it was by every pretty
strategic sides in about three down from
each other every time there would be a
seed breeder they knew they knew what
they were getting into this was the
third or fifth and oh I really can't
remember how many there be there's so
many of these events and they do them in
the same building and so they all look
the same to me not to be a dentist but
it's just a bunch of boots with bucking
people and like the cup and the expo and
they all look the same by now so I don't
know how many there have been but you
have the seed breeders that's where it's
at we all got our fair
sher that's what I love that nobody like
we all had basically the same nice
amount of flow like I talked about like
their bands everyone's gonna like
certain bands and so nobody got all of
it nobody got left out that's pretty
cool that we all got a fair amount of
business this weekend I really enjoyed
that Glenn did we wrap up your part I
don't want to cut you off
I appreciate you Jeff yeah that was that
was everything I mean just shout outs to
everybody that came by and everybody was
really super [ __ ] cool dude you were
pitching the podcast hard to everybody
and doing a really good job with it so I
bet you there are 20 to 50 maybe a
hundred people listening right now
because you gave them a girl from your
heart podcast flier and you guys helped
out with that also so [ __ ] thank you
guys for that
hell yeah you don't want to grow this
thing and then if you guys will play it
and I mean the grow lessons are just so
valuable that I I don't know it's free
information please go back and listen
yes
target audience we were hitting them
they were there that day um one is some
of my favorite stuff at the event
I just loved all the people that wanted
to [ __ ] meet me bro that is really
cool it feels good I said it's
recharging it's overwhelming because
it's a lot of people to meet hands to
shake and hugs to give in names to try
to [ __ ] remember but it feels so good
that's I don't know that's just all the
social recharge that a person needs just
to feel good about themselves so that's
a big ego boost and a big if I were like
a sim video game my social meter would
just be filled up for the next [ __ ]
four months I'm cool on that thank you
um this year was the first year we
brought our own big booth to the event
before I've shared with other vendors
and other breeders and I've done things
with other companies and I wasn't there
by myself we didn't put our name on the
booth this year cuz I read genetics I
brought just yes I brought my banner I
brought my crew I hired the team that I
wanted there we did it my way not to be
we did it your guys his [ __ ] way you
guys had fun I was like you're the seeds
this is how much they cost make this
[ __ ] happen there's [ __ ] not kind of
guys if you guys do what you want it's
lows we've all worked enough retail and
enough events stuff like that that we
all just dropped into pro rhythm in the
gym went pretty well
Clint's not super well versed and seed
so he was doing well at pitching the
podcast
mike is pretty well-versed at seeds and
has been a budtender so he's doing
pretty good with strain recommendations
you guys were finding your niches and
doing a good job helper monkey over here
was super popular because of his bird
grow people wanted vertical grow advice
they remembered him from the show so
that was kind of cool
he's just spunky two's ice bucket cool
he's energetic man I'm sure you met you
met a cool guy I'm glad you met up with
one of our friends I'm not gonna spill
too much of your beans but you made a
really good contact I'm kind of proud of
you for yeah this guy's awesome and he
kind of takes what I do and I don't
wanna get too much weight on him but he
kind of does it on a bigger scale than
what I'm doing right now
sure that when the time is right yeah I
got a couple of really cool
opportunities there are a couple things
you guys heard up that are coming up
hopefully if they emailed back yeah
there will be some really cool
opportunities one of my other favorite
things that happened this year at the
endo Expo so I was kind of segue into
this and I got my ID aside track my damn
snow itself this is the first year we
brought the big booth is the first time
I bought the team and the crew and it
wasn't me joining somebody else like the
little dog in this industry in this
community there is people try to act
like there's a hierarchy and people are
better than people that's just how every
industry is every business goes that way
every click every community this year
some of the people that have had their
noses up - I read genetics they [ __ ]
put their heads down and looked me in
the eye and nodded their heads and they
finally like they realize we're [ __ ]
here Clint kept saying it is a kind of a
funny joke by the end of the day Sunday
we were tired and high and exhausted and
by the end of Sunday Clint's pitch was
or ivory genetics and we're not [ __ ]
around but that's not a joke you guys
people finally realized we were here or
something real it's here to stay it's
not going anywhere this is the first
event when people went oh [ __ ] we can't
we see them coming that's a seed company
we got to pay attention to
so we're there now we got on the team
they let us in this time bro was it at
the big boys table I would literally
watch people circling because you had so
many people wanting to take selfies with
you and just meet you that they would
circle around and you'd see them come
back ten minutes later like okay just
finally free let me go talk to him and
you see them light up it was great
feeling man let's [ __ ] funny I don't
I don't get to see that cuz I I don't
get to look past like two people and I
see the guy I'm talking to and I kind of
make eye contact with the guy behind him
and nod like you're gonna be next bro
like I let them know that I acknowledge
them and I just right to focus so that's
that's [ __ ] great to know that people
are looping around and coming back and
enthusiastic yeah and you know even a
lot of company support as well it wasn't
even just like you know average people
there's a lot of companies who are super
stoked on you know our booth and just
being a part of you know what you're
doing
veg bloom came by new mill came by I got
a really cool zip up Hoodie from new
mill I think so it was a lot of the
conversation happened five or six times
with different people they come up and
go hey Jeff I just want to introduce
myself I'm so-and-so I run blank
company's Instagram and you guys would
go it's fun to finally meet those people
we've been interacting you know every
other day for two years they send me
products and [ __ ] I used the products
and I've been growing like new
millennium new try no that guy for a
while but like yeah I know here talking
about oh my god green dot was the main
one that I was like bro we talked like
every day it was just kind of fun yeah
that that's just a lot of fun he's a
dreaded white guy too so it was even
more fun to be like hey to dreaded white
guys hi-5 is just funny for me like we
know that everybody's watching it's
extra funny there was a lot of real
energizing getting to meet a bunch of
fans of the show coming up just wanted
to say hi and shake our hands and the
people to booth next to us were confused
yeah really energizes our the desire to
do the show and do it well like that was
fun the people next to us just not
getting anything going on and we had a
constant like crowd of people and they
had free food how do you how do you not
know man I really appreciate everybody
come out but they were super nice they
were super nice guys everybody at the
event was super nice I got to hang out
with swerve from the Cali connection
just spend a few minutes that dudes been
at it since before we were while we were
all figuring it out he was doing it
already got to hang out with James bean
from seeds here now that's awesome
because we do a lot of work together I
just got to meet a lot of good see
covert from covert genetics got to see
ol Chris Casas gonna see a bunch of
people that we don't normally get to see
but we met a lot we need a lot of good
friends got a lot of great gifts got a
lot of business cards bro it's gonna be
a long email in session on today and
tomorrow
yeah I've been wading through emails
already it it was a fun Expo if you
missed it you missed out you should
definitely be on it for next year yes
the endo Expo pay attention to that I
saw a lot of people unlike the Friday
and Thursday before it's an hey how do I
get in to Expo passes bro bro for like
six months before the end of those
people start flooding people with emails
and advertisements get your passes don't
sleep on it next year so let's uh let's
tell them finally what they missed out
on since you didn't release what you
were gonna do before the expo let's tell
them what free packs visit on everybody
a lot of people saw it on social media I
was giving away free packs of GMO to
arised everybody that came to the booth
and bought a pack of seeds so free gog
arrives with almost every purchase i
think what else do we give away Mike oh
yes yes our friends at PL Gro systems
were kind enough to give a way a PL
minder unit to the person who spent the
most money at my business it was a
random surprise for somebody that I know
that person's happy right now I know
he's almost had he didn't want me he
wouldn't look at me because he had a
little little drippy of it a little bit
of material design if he wasn't my
friend I wouldn't say that out loud like
that but he had a little meeting yeah
that I'm glad his beard was hiding his
tears bro big fella happy birthday bro
we all love you everybody here's the
girl from the heart podcast we were
picking on you rats only because we
[ __ ] love you bro your family give
you a big hug yes I would rub my beard
on yours and we change beard fungus and
we'd be bros forever and I only wanted
to bring that up so next year people
they know they know you know they're
early we weren't the only booth giving
away cool [ __ ] there was a lot of that
going on this year every booth was
giving out some [ __ ] it was fun and if
you didn't get enough stickers at the
event you weren't trying hard enough
yeah yeah there were stickers for days
alright guys I feel like we've rambled
for close to 40 minutes on an Indo Expo
recap we got to talk about Theo we got
to talk about all the wonderful friends
we saw all we got to talk about all the
thanks that we need to give to everybody
Thanks we had fun you guys I want to
thank my crew Mike you [ __ ] killed it
bro you're awesome helper monkey you
were only there for one day
you [ __ ] crushed it bro thank you
my client almost called you micro I
apologize I'll never do that again all
right you're sorry I'm sorry dude
don't look at me like that bro I'm sorry
I'm sorry you know I don't know what
you're thinking anyway all right hey
Clint thank you bro you kicked ass at
the endo Expo ah and you guys carried my
[ __ ] out for me Sunday I didn't carry
anything I was like wonder what do I
pick up you guys like [ __ ] it you own
the company and I was like well then I
guess I don't carry [ __ ] I'll open the
car door hey you guys kicked ass dude he
cleaned up everything you [ __ ] helped
all the people that came you've greeted
everybody you guys are awesome and so I
can't wait to do this [ __ ] take you
guys with me two more shows and kick
some more ass bro make us all look and
happy at the shows oh yeah dude there's
a blast yeah we can you know go to other
states it'd be great to meet people out
there too and then try to spread the
podcast like that - don't tease them I'm
not gonna be saying places I just would
like - okay great info in my email you
guys could help us out patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart
that's the way there's a big cannabis of
that several months out and in your area
shoot us an email make sure we know
about it do that let us know invite us
also send us
booth information let me know just don't
waste time soon to be hated we have an
event tell me how much it is where it is
let's get right to it
yeah um also the dude gross Cup is
coming up so I will see you there
yeah dude you speak up yes the dude
grows Cup I'll talk more about that when
I know the exact date time and location
- uh I will be there with the booth and
with a small part of the team on the
[ __ ] come on guys all you can come
yeah even if I gotta buy your ticket so
you guys are all coming up to the D G C
cup come meet the team they'll be there
you guys all right ladies and gentlemen
boys and girls pimps and hos friends and
foes smokers grower seed hoarders led
growers hid growers soilless makes
growers organic growers hydro growers
robots gender neutral folks binary folks
aliens animals fish new friends old
friends Oh Vivian oh [ __ ] Iraq
marsupials all of you if you're here
love you thank you for listening to the
show if you've liked this episode was
educational informative and or enter
you like to make a financial
contribution to the show you can do so
by visiting www.patiyer.com forward
slash grow from your heart all the
information you need to help out the
show will be right there on the screen I
do appreciate all of that support that
keeps my MacBook going that keeps the
website alive the website is where I
host the show that's why it's free for
you because we cover the cost with the
patreon contribution so thank you guys
for all that patreon.com forward slash
gore from your heart also check out the
YouTube channel go to youtube search for
the girl from your heart podcast find
the channel click subscribe click like
on some videos maybe leave some comments
on the videos let me know what you think
of the show what else do we got
Instagram follow me on Instagram we've
got the growth from your heart podcast
Instagram and of course there's the IRA
underscore Genetics Instagram bless you
Mike no that's how it goes Bryce are you
trying to hold it for a minute if there
is any social media that you guys would
like to plug I'll give you the
opportunity well that might go last cuz
he's picked in a space so go ahead man I
just wanted to give a shout out to
everybody who listens to show all the
time he's a big fan Vinny boombots so if
you're listening dude guys I'm glad
you're listening man I'm glad that we
turned you on to the show keep spreading
love you call him girl any boombots yeah
any boomba
it sounds like a troublemaker he's an
old friend of mine here actually owns a
recording studio
oh shut up - Vinny boombots sounds like
a [ __ ] yeah in Jersey yawns yeah yeah
you know he's a bass player yeah he's
funky but is he slap it or is he picking
[Music]
harmonics and [ __ ] like two handed
tapping and [ __ ] all four fingers you
just talked him up some [ __ ] stalkers
now that's kind of [ __ ] he's a
prodigy let's jam bro let's jam I got
some drums all right Clint any social
media that you would like Matt thank you
by the way I mean yeah yeah no no no I'm
keeping a show moving your doober monkey
got two highs what
helper monkey it was really nice to
people this crew up there it was really
fun yeah it was that was the other thing
is that's why just zero drama between
the four bus an extravagant dinner
Saturday night that we had yeah awesome
you guys were very welcome thank you
thank you for that yeah I don't think
Mike was I couldn't make it Mike would
do dinner with somebody else well we
went to the hotel rule first we took
[ __ ] allegedly mat night took gnarly
dads in the car like the hotel we ain't
sure because my hotel they remind me six
or eight times in my check-in process
that I can't consume cannabis and around
near or while I'm thinking about that
hotel they're like you can leave here
and do whatever you want but please
don't even get your pipe out in the
parking lot I'm like I'm cool with that
so we go off their property and we may
have got heavily medicated and while we
were doing that bro I ordered [ __ ]
pizzas to the room please sat on the
[ __ ] chairs in the room with no shoes
on and we just ate pizza like lazy
[ __ ] and it was the most perfect
dinner we could have had we've been on
our feet and around people all day it
was basically silent other than a couple
of them and then see them funnier
because you were staying in like a
[ __ ] five-star hotel and there's
these for dirty stoners [ __ ] eaten or
three three of us eating pizza and this
perfect super baller [ __ ] place it
was great it was exactly what we needed
at the time I just needed some pizza
yeah you can follow me at it's all
Clint's on it does guys we made so many
new friends it's such a good time thanks
for being there I like that it's a good
way to wrap it up Mike for sensible
fifteen stoners I know thank you said hi
everybody it it was a pleasure to meet
everybody and I can't wait to see who
shows up and oh I suppose next year and
if the dude
well why did my voice very white I
forget that that's an event and every
time I remember it makes me smile it's a
thing that's gonna happen yeah and then
the guys from normal came by to thank
you again to those guys for what they do
go be an activist yes get it going all
right boys and girls we're gonna wrap
this up or we could ramble all day if
you've got any questions or anything
like that you can find me and I read
genetics know how about growth from your
heart at hotmail.com
that's more appropriate grow from your
heart at hotmail.com ladies and
gentlemen I'll be back in a couple of
days with fresh new content let's give a
giant shout out to our buddy dick goals
and until next time take a phat dad and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
I never realized italics the papyri a
shampoo that unify really defrost Trish
and inspect them on so did stop Archer
[Music]
everybody wants to read upon
everybody wants a big on everybody wants
[Music]
my god everybody want to redefine office
in your
John compete with police John will not
be
[Music]
I was