what's up ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls pimps and hos friends and foes
grab your pipes grab your bongs pack up
a fat ball roll up a fat joint because
in this episode we are going to
celebrate the weed nerd ladies and
gentlemen I woke up to a text message
from a close friend letting me know that
one of my heroes one of my idols one of
my mentors passed away this morning many
of you will know who sub cool was but if
you're not sure sub cool was a cannabis
breeder sub cool was a cannabis pioneer
sub cool was a cannabis educator and a
cannabis activist sub cool was the
creator of very many popular strains sub
cool made Jack the Ripper sub cool made
vortex sub cool made space Queen sub
cool is very well known in the cannabis
industry he's got very many High Times
Cannabis Cup awards he's gotten a High
Times Lifetime Achievement Award he was
also known as the weed nerd sub who was
very influential in my cannabis career
my cannabis development and heavily
influential in my cannabis photography
if you look at his photography then you
look at the evolution of my photography
you can for sure see subbies influence
in my work sub cool did a lot of things
for our community another thing he was
very well known for was his super soil
sub cool has a great super soil recipe
online that many people based their
super soil recipes off of to this day
sub cool also did what was known as the
school of dank where he would do a large
seminar type class where a lot of people
would fly from around the world and sub
cool would teach a multiple day class
and then most of the time the proceeds
from those classes were donated to a
charity many times it was to autism
awareness and to raise funds for kids
with autism so sub cool did a lot of
great things not just for the cannabis
community but for his regular community
and the people around him obviously and
unfortunately sub cool has left the
building sub cool is no longer with us
sub cool had been battling a condition
known as alpha 1 for quite a while if
you follow him online you know that he's
been getting injections and medicine for
quite a while to treat this condition
unfortunately his body finally gave out
and he did not wake up this morning so
he went peacefully in his sleep so
hopefully that was quick and
I'm [ __ ] heart broken but subby
wouldn't want me to sit here and cry
about it sub e would want me to smoke a
fat joint sub cool would want me to
sprout some seeds and then sub cool
would want me to get back to business
teaching you how to grow top-shelf
cannabis so I'm gonna press pause for a
moment gonna blow my nose I'm gonna take
about forty seven fat dabs and then when
I get back I promise to deliver a
top-shelf podcast dedicated to my buddy
sub cool
all right I'm back through the magic of
editing here I am already that was quick
I took a lot of fat dabs feel a lot
better you know I wasn't going to do a
full episode on sub cool I had some
other stuff I was gonna talk about here
is gonna do a regular show but while I
was taking my dad's and was just
chilling and thinking about subby and I
was like we should give the dude a full
show why not so this is going to be a
brief episode fully dedicated to sub
cool or sitting here dad and I'm trying
to catch my breath no I just didn't want
any of these thoughts to escape my head
so I just wanted to hit record and get
talking but I remember chilling out way
back in the day growing sub cool strains
and sitting on the couch watching sub
cools weed nerd videos while I was
trimming sub cool strains so I've been
following sub E for quite a while I was
watching the weed nerd shows before they
were the weed nerd he had a bunch of
just random sub cool videos that he
would put out and I remember watching
all of those way before he was the weed
nerd
I think some of the very first seeds I
purchased from the atitude seed bank my
first order had sub cool seeds in that
order they were TGA sub cool seeds I
remember ordering them so I've been
following sub cool for quite a while and
I've learned a lot from the guy one
thing I will address before we get too
far as yeah the dude had some quirks he
did some weird [ __ ] but we all have our
own quirks and we all do weird [ __ ] I'm
going to excuse that for this episode
because I've got nothing but love and
respect for the guy and this is a
tribute to him so if you're gonna say
something negative about him in the
comments or out loud or something to
shut the [ __ ] up right now cuz I've got
his back so I'm gonna keep moving
forward with my tribute to my bro I just
had to address that sub cool is a
teacher bro he taught me so much and you
can see it in my gross style I used to
run seven gallon pot
with tomato cages I used to top him I
used to branch him out real wide I used
to cram too many into a room I used to
get the light too close to him my rooms
looked just like sub cool came in there
and built my rooms you could see my
evolution of my growing I was doing a
whole bunch of one gallon pots and
trying to pack the room and then I
started watching sub cool and he was
like why don't you top him spread him
out a little bit put him in tomato cages
get a little bit bigger of a plant start
growing it this way he was showing me
that he was pulling this much weight
from each plant and I was like well [ __ ]
I'm running the same genetics why don't
I do it that way and it started working
really well I got better at growing
through watching a lot of sub cool stuff
and then if I or anybody else ever had a
question about something he said on the
weed nerd show you could just send him a
message and he would answer you he would
answer you directly you'd say Oh bro
this is what's going on then he would
ask you questions that means when he's
asking questions he actually cares he's
engaging he wants more info so that he
can answer you again appropriately and
get your garden going so sub cool was a
great resource he was a valuable asset
to a new grower he was a valuable asset
to an educated grower he knew a lot of
[ __ ] he knew a lot of ins and outs of
the industry he made some predictions to
me in conversations about the industry
about people and that [ __ ] always came
true another thing I need to give sub
cool some credit for is a lot of the
development of my cannabis photography
he inspired me and educated me a lot on
my cannabis photography the way I frame
a shot the way I outline a shot the way
I background a shot the way I set up a
shot is very inspired by sub cool sub
cool put out a couple of books sub cools
the science of dank had a lot of great
photography and that photography really
improved my photography it inspired me
so much that I wanted to do things
differently and I started taking better
photos that leads me into another thing
that I really want a shout sub cool out
for sub e was one of the first people I
saw taking and sharing photos of male
plants he was posting photos of one of
his legendary studs that he called the
space dude he was posting those photos a
long time ago in forums the space dude
is featured in a book there are some
any beautiful pictures of the male
flowers we don't see enough of that and
sub took some great great shots of his
male plants and shared those he told a
lot of great stories about how he found
his male plant and then he used the [ __ ]
out of that male plant you may see some
similarities here I did find a stud male
and of course I used the [ __ ] out of him
he became just as popular as some of my
females so for some of you it sounds
like I'm just kissing the soil guys ass
but he was honestly very important and
very influential in my development I
region etics would not exist if sub cool
did not pave the way and kind of teach
me how to do this there are a lot of
other breeders and growers and
influential people along that path but
sub cool was a very big part of my
education and my development he was
doing the weed nerd show he kind of
taught us how to go online and do this
sort of thing he was doing it before a
lot of us so sub cool did inspire me and
kind of teach me how to do it in a way
he's got a few years on me he got
started before me he definitely had a
great torch to pass and I'm proud to
have grabbed one of the torches that sub
cool is passing out to keep carrying
because he taught a lot of people sub
cool did a lot of time for cannabis sub
cool has been arrested and served a lot
of his life in jail because of this
cannabis plant we got to give a big
shout out to miss Jill while subby was
serving time miss Jill was finding
cannabis books and in jail you can't
have books that have the word weed or
cannabis or reefer in it right and you
definitely can't have books to teach you
how to grow cannabis in jail so miss
Jill was finding cannabis grow books and
rewriting them and taking out the word
cannabis and putting tomatoes or
blueberries in there so that sub was
able to read these books while he was in
jail and keep up on his cannabis
education so we got to give a big
shout-out to miss Jill also she was a
huge part of TGA she is actually now the
owner of TGA it's a big shout out to
Jill I do know that sub and Jill had a
rocky relationship that was very public
I'm not putting any information out
there that's private but I do know they
resolved their [ __ ] before sub you was
gone and I know that she was a huge part
of the team and she took great care of
sub and Jill takes great care of
everybody around her so I want to send
her a big shout out also
since we're talking about TGA and the
green Avenger family and sub cool
history because Jill is a major part of
that Jill actually bred the Jilly bean
so when you talk about Jilly bean coming
from sub cool and TGA that was one of
Miss Jill's creations she's still
killing it so make sure you guys support
TGA and Miss Jill still but I wanted to
make sure to send her some love
she took care of sub II she helped out
sub you while he was in jail she was a
great partner in crime for sub cool I've
been going for almost ten minutes
talking about my buddy sub E I'm going
to wrap up this tribute here very
quickly but let's talk about some of the
strains that sub cool is very known for
breeding you guys if you have ever
smoked Jack the Ripper that is a sub
cool strain if you've ever smoked space
clean that was a sub cool and miss Jill
strain that could have been miss Jill
but I'm sure sub and miss Jill worked on
that one together
if you've ever smoked the vortex that
was from sub cool a lot of that old
stuff back in the day was coming from
sub cool and you didn't even know it
back around 2010 there was a dispensary
in Denver called the clinic and they
carried some vortex batter it was bred
by sub cool and grown by somebody there
in Denver and extracted by a local guy
in Denver and it was available on the
shelf at the clinic that vortex
concentrate was one of my favorite
concentrates ever that place is a
hundred and thirty miles from my house I
would drive up there as soon as I saw
that [ __ ] come up on weed Maps I would
drive up there and buy as much as they
would sell me then they started making
limits so I had to take friends with me
so they could buy as much as they would
sell them also I used to love that
vortex concentrate it would give me the
dad sweats it would make me shake a
little bit it would give me a little bit
of paranoia I'd be looking for my
sunglasses while I was [ __ ] wearing
them I tried to find my keys while they
were in my hand it was amazing I love
that sort of high so I missed that
vortex concentrate but that's the kind
of stuff that sub-cooled bred mostly
sativa dominant kind of high THC a lot
of real candy flavored sort of stuff but
he did a lot of great breeding and I
used many of his creations in my work I
actually used his plush berry in my
black
um I also used his space clean in one of
my crosses I used a female space queen I
reversed a grateful dog plant and I made
what I called space [ __ ] it was space
Queen to grateful dog and it was
feminized I found a sweet female out of
there and I pollinated that with my
arise male and I called that creation
space force and that is still available
today there are only a few packs left
but space force is one of my crosses
that came from one of sub cools
creations so you guys I just wanted to
take a minute actually I guess I wanted
to take 12 minutes and I wanted to kind
of pay tribute to somebody who really
helped me develop as a cannabis grower
as a cannabis breeder as a cannabis
business person as a cannabis educator I
wanted to give a giant shout out to my
friends sub cool so sub cool thank you
bro I wouldn't be where I am without
your guidance and inspiration ladies and
gentleman I'm not gonna do a lot of
advertising at the end of this show I
want to thank you for listening I want
to give a giant shout out to sub cool
giant shout out to miss Jill and a giant
shout out to the entire TGA crew until
next time take a phat dab and give your
mom a hug for me