all right here we go welcome back
podcast world it is time for episode 504
of the growth from your heart podcast
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff welcome to the show this episode of
the show is brought to you by our only
official sponsor seeds here now that's
right if you need new regular feminized
or Auto flower seeds in your garden I
highly recommend seeds here now and you
can find them at www.cdxzipstream.com
but I will give it lemon rind and tea
tree oil those flavors are absolutely
present the flavor just lingers on your
tongue when you hit this concentrate on
the back of the package it does say the
product contains 66.7% THC when I hit
this stuff I get a really nice tunnel
vision II chattery rambly sort of a buzz
so I think this will make great podcast
concentrates big shout out to my friends
at Green Dot labs for the delicious
lemon wreath live batter
ladies and gentlemen in this episode I'm
going to read a couple of listen or
emails before we get to that portion of
the show let's do some shoutouts to a
few of our friends from patreon let's
start off with the big giant grow from
your heart podcast shout out and a thank
you to our new friend learning and
burnin
I always want to send a giant shout out
to n Wagner let's send a big giant grow
from your heart podcast shoutout to
gabriel i always want to send a giant
thank you shout out to jacob w of course
we need to send a giant high-five to
James Brown
I always owe a big fist bump and a thank
you to keith k of course let's send a
giant grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out and a high-five to
zoso J I always want to send some love
to my friend Tommy of course a big THANK
YOU to Steven Smith I always want to
send a big thank-you to fat
and last but certainly not least let's
send a big grow from your heart podcast
thank you a high five and a shout-out to
our friend Willy's armpit big thanks and
big shout out to everybody who continues
to support the show on the patreon
campaign if you would like to learn how
to support the show on patreon all you
have to do is visit www.reimaverick.com
forward slash grow from your heart to
find my actual patreon support page you
can't go to patreon and search for my
name to find it you have to use the
actual URL it's patr
e o n that's patreon.com forward slash
grow from your heart that will take you
directly there unfortunately I think
I've been shadow banned because of the
content that I do provide is cannabis
based either way you can find it by
typing in the full URL and I will
appreciate your support and I'll give
you a shout-out on the show all right
let's move away from that it's starting
to feel like a pledge drive let's move
into the email portion of this podcast
ladies and gentlemen I love answering
gro questions from my listeners if you
send me an email and you ask me a
cultivation or a cannabis culture
question I will do my best to read and
answer your question on the show so send
me all of your cannabis cultivation and
culture questions my email address is
grow from your heart at hotmail.com the
first email in today's episode goes a
lot like this it says dear Rasta Jeff I
have a question but first I would like
to tell you why I enjoy listening to
your podcast it says you speak well and
are well-spoken hey thank you that means
a lot to me I try to speak clearly I get
going way too fast for my own good
sometimes my brain travels much more
quickly than my mouth so I try to keep
that under control thank you for
noticing I'm trying to control my face
and make the right sounds I do
appreciate that
it goes on to say regardless of how much
knowledge someone may have I cannot
stand to listen to poor speakers or poor
quality audio I completely agree with
that if somebody calls in on a podcast
and I can tell they're on the phone or
if they're calling in on a shitty Skype
connection and there's a long delay or
if it sounds like this and they're
talking from the phone behind the
microphone I can't [ __ ] stand it I
will not listen to that show so I agree
with you I think quality audio is very
important I started off in the music
scene in the music industry before I
wanted to be a podcaster actually had
another friend who was doing a podcast
and he asked me to be a guest and I
actually refused to be a guest on his
show unless he allowed me to produce the
episode on which I appeared because
until then his show did not sound up to
my standards I have a lot of equipment
from the time I spent recording and
producing and participating in the music
industry I used to play drums on the
road I've done a lot of music stuff I
had a lot of fancy toys so I told my
buddy come to my spot let's do your show
here I got really good at recording I
made that podcast sound good in my
opinion so I've had a lot of practice
and I've come a long way so the short
answer to that is I agree with you bro
it's hard to listen to a poor quality
podcast and somebody that doesn't speak
well is even harder for me to listen to
I'm gonna get back on track I told you
that lemon wreath dab got me [ __ ]
rambly I'm gonna try to focus for you
where are we it says you are very
knowledgeable and he presented well it
is obvious you take the time to plan and
lay out the podcast hey that means a lot
to me a lot of people probably don't
realize that it takes a little bit of
time and effort to actually create a
podcast the ideas have to come from
somewhere what am I going to talk about
if somebody didn't send me an email to
prompt my brain I don't have a subject
I've got to invent a topic I've got to
make an outline then I've got to record
it then of course I edit it and I put it
up on all the servers it does take a
little bit of effort so thank you for
noticing that I do take a little bit of
time out of my life out of my day to
actually lay
the podcasts to make it something they
can be useful for many different
listeners I want everybody to be able to
learn from this and it sounds like I'm
hitting my target let me keep moving
because there is a lot more to this
message it says you are funny
which makes listening entertaining as
well as informative I've said this
before when I went to school I loved
learning but I hated sitting there being
bored it felt like I was being lectured
many of my teachers did not have any
flavor or style to their teaching
they basically opened up a curriculum
book and shot it at us and we were
supposed to absorb it I did have a few
teachers who would take their time and
actually learn their students and figure
out how we learn best and find the
obstacles we're experiencing and help us
get over those I had a few very
wonderful teachers but unfortunately
that was not the regular experience most
of the time I was bored in school or
frustrated in school I felt like I
learned things rather quickly and when
everybody else was catching on I was
finding a way to get in trouble so I
hated being in school but I loved
learning when I had entertaining
teachers or teachers that took a moment
to connect I really excelled so I feel
like if I sneak a couple of jokes or say
something a little bit silly just to
keep your attention going and kind of
it's like throwing you a treat you know
what I mean you've had all this learning
that here's a little snack for your
brain it's a little bit of a reward it
makes you smile it makes learning fun
and you want to do it more nobody wants
to be [ __ ] lectured so I try to keep
it a little bit fun that way it keeps
your attention that way you can learn
some stuff and have a good time so I do
appreciate that you think I'm funny but
do not encourage me
I don't need encouragement to be the
class clown I do appreciate all of the
compliments I do appreciate all of the
words of encouragement but let's move to
the question part of this email the
question goes like this now for my
question I listened to your series of
grow lessons which were very helpful in
episode 73 you discuss a perpetual grow
where you are harvesting one plant every
two weeks it says I like this idea but
how do you deal with the light being
further or closer to the plants since
they are all different
and that is a very good question so this
listener is listening to episode 73
where I did discuss creating a perpetual
harvest in a small environment I do
believe it was in a 5x5 tent under one
light where you've got four seven gallon
pots flowering at all times in that
perpetual scenario you would harvest a
seven gallon pot every two weeks and
replace it with a fresh seven gallon pot
now this person does raise a very
interesting point they ask what do you
do with that brand-new pot that is much
smaller and much shorter than the plants
that have been in there for two four six
and eight weeks the light is at the top
of the tent because you've got many
plants that have grown really tall what
do I do with this shorter plant that
hasn't had time to grow in the situation
I was talking about the light is not
movable the light needs to remain at the
very top of the tent because we've got
plants that are fully mature in that
room so the light cannot be adjusted
that means we've got to work from the
bottom we can't move the light down so
we have either got to move the floor up
or figure out a way to raise the plant
so let's raise the plant a very common
way to lift plants up off the ground is
to get another pot the same size as the
pot you're using and simply flip it
upside down use it as a table and set
the pot right on top of that now a seven
gallon pot is probably going to lift you
up somewhere between 12 16 maybe even 18
inches just depending on the depth and
diameter of the seven gallon pot you've
chosen to buy so that's going to raise
your plant up at least 12 maybe 14 16
maybe 18 inches and that should be
sufficient because that plan is going to
begin to grow rapidly and it's only
going to be the smallest plant in the
room for two weeks so hopefully after
two weeks you can take that one off the
pot set it on the floor and the next one
that comes in can go on that inverted
pot so that is a very easy affordable
and safe way to raise your new plant up
a little bit higher and get it closer to
the light and if you think about it
you've got one seven gallon pot upside
down that's probably will say sixteen
inches tall you've got another seven
gallon pot on top of that that's another
six
inches at that point we are getting
close to three feet off the ground
before we've got any plant coming out of
the container if you're in a tent
you've probably only got six and a half
maybe seven feet worth of vertical
height minus your light so you're
already getting that plant plenty close
to the light in my opinion so that is a
very affordable and very effective way
to raise your plant about 16 inches and
get it closer to the light
get it up there to the top of the canopy
and I understand that you want to get
that light to all of your plants but you
are going to have a little bit of a
difference that you cannot fight that's
okay
those big butted plants are going to get
more light your smaller plants are going
to get less light that is just fine in
that five by five tent if you've got a
six hundred or a thousand watt light you
will be pumping out enough light
throughout that tiny reflective space
where all of the plants should get
enough light to be happy and if you feel
like you may need to defoliate or move
some branches over a certain way don't
be afraid to D foliate strategically
don't be afraid to bottom and lollipop
strategically if a leaf is blocking a
bud site feel free to take it out of
there eventually you'll learn how to
snap and pop the stems and just move
them the way you need them right out of
the way you'll be able to shape and
structure your plants the way you want
we will talk more about shaping and
structuring our plants in a future
episode alright let's wrap up this email
it says thanks keep up the great podcast
from your friend Rodney it Rodney thank
you for the great email if you do run
that perpetual grow I would love to see
pictures if you have any questions or if
you need more help please send me a
follow-up email you know how to find me
it's grow from your heart at hotmail.com
alright I do have another email right
here in front of me let's see if they
want their name said this one comes from
our friend Trent and it goes just like
at this it says hey Rasta Jeff I'm a
longtime listener and I've learned a lot
from you hey thank you for listening and
I'm glad you were learning from the show
it goes on to say I greatly appreciate
all of the info you give to our
community I do have one question I was
hoping you could help me with I just
started to flower in my tent and I'm
looking into what I want to grow for my
to run I definitely want to grow
something from your line hey thank you
I'm honored
it also says but I want to make sure my
environment is right for the seeds I buy
hey that is very smart of you to have
some forethought to make sure you get
the appropriate seeds for your grow
space many people just see some seeds
they see a strain they see some hype
they spend their money they get the
seeds they try to grow it their grow and
they go this does not work for what I
thought I was going to do so I'm really
proud of you for thinking about this in
advance and actually reaching out to the
guy who makes the seeds to get some
guidance that's really smart of you I
wish everybody had the foresight you
were using now it goes on to say I'm in
a four by four tent with a 260 watt
quantum board and a rapid LED grow mal 5
V 3 2x2 do-it-yourself kit honestly most
of that is abbreviated and I'm kind of
proud of myself for nailing that on the
first try or at least I think I got it
on the first try so our friend Trent is
growing in a 4x4 tent he's got two LED
lights in there I honestly don't know
about those two lights I don't know how
much light that is we're going to act
like that's enough light for the room it
goes on to say my tent is exhausted to
another part of my house so you're able
to move the humidity and heat away from
the plants hopefully you've got a carbon
filter in there it also says I grow in
an amended soil mix of cocoa perlite
worm castings and a bag of super soil
and ocean forests that sounds like a
great mix it says I don't use nutrients
and tell flour with all that stuff
you've got in there I think that's gonna
work we've got amended soil I don't know
the amendments but it sounds like you
probably put a lot in there you got
cocoa pearlite worm castings oh the bag
of super soil will get you through there
and the ocean forests will help you out
no nutrients until flower you may get a
better performance out of the veg plants
if you added a few things but if it's
working for you keep doing that then it
says IU's nectar of the Gods nutrients
it focuses its regimen with a pH between
six one and six five that's gonna work
for you it also focuses on using calcium
as the main source of everything through
veg and through flour
I'm not familiar with how that line is
made I just know that it is quality I've
seen some great outcomes with it I don't
know any details about how they make it
it sounds like you know enough and its
quality for you so keep doing that it
says there is 52 inches from my soil to
my lights however I use scrog Nets all
right so you can grow some semi longer
growing things with that much space 52
inches from the soil to the lights is
just over 4 feet so without those scrog
Nets you're gonna have to flip something
about a foot and a half two feet tall
which is not bad if you top it once you
can get a nice bush or if you're using
that strong net like you talked about
maybe you let it grow about a third
maybe halfway up and then flip it don't
let it go too tall because you will
start getting close to the lights if
you're using one of my strains but let's
keep talking more about your environment
it says my temps at night are 76 degrees
and 84 degrees during the day I can
control the humidity with my humidifier
and dehumidifier I was hoping with all
of this information maybe we could
figure out a strain to grow I'm really
interested in doing a bit of phenol
hunting to narrow down to the best 4 to
grow out so I would probably need like a
5 to 10 pack and I would prefer fins as
well I hope to hear from you soon your
friend Trent
all right Trent its ends like you've got
a pretty nice environment you don't have
too much of a day and night swing the
only major limiting factor here is that
52 inches from the soil to the lights
that is not much space for the way I
like to grow it sounds like you have
figured it out by using these scrog Nets
you were looking for recommendations
from my line you also indicated that you
would prefer feminized seeds so let's
talk briefly about some things I would
suggest for your grow space let's start
off with feminized recommendations if I
were to recommend a couple of feminized
seeds for your space I would start off
with the orange gasm I think orange gasm
would work very well in your space
because it is a shorter and squatter
your plant you don't have a lot of
height so you do need a plant that
doesn't get too tall and orange gasm
will fit that bill it also will
a little bit earlier so you don't have
to worry about it stretching for that
extra week or two
another feminized seed I would recommend
for your grow is the Michelangelo
Michelangelo is quite similar to the Sun
kiss because it has that same Platinum
tangi female plant in the mix the
difference is the orange gasm is made
with a golden goat reversed female and
the Michelangelo is made with a
blueberry cookies reversed female both
of those are feminized both of them are
going to offer very orange candy
dominant turps the Sun kiss is going to
be more orange and possibly grapefruit
II the Michelangelo is going to be
oranges and some sort of candy and
skittle e-type flavors those strains are
both very forgiving and very easy to
grow and I think it would work very well
in your temperatures and with your
nutrient mix and in your space
another feminized cross that I think may
work well for you is the golden goat if
you are able to scrog it properly the
golden goat will perform very well in
that environment
I love golden goat in a commercial
setting because it reacts very well to
being netted down it makes a lot of
branches and it loves that type of
training in the description of your room
you said the room hits 84 degrees which
mean you may have a possible spike of 85
or 86 on occasion the golden goat will
handle temperature spikes it does not
get mad at you if it gets a little bit
hot in your grow room so the golden goat
may work for that high temperature
environment you also indicated that this
would be your winter run so maybe you'll
be able to push it and keep it nice and
cool in there but just in case that
golden goat if it grows too close to the
light it may be able to tolerate those
higher temperatures so those are the
three that I would recommend if you want
to stick with feminised seeds from my
line I feel like the lemon Geoffrey may
get too tall on you in that space
if you don't scrog it and also it does
get a little bit long so you may get a
little bit of space between your buds it
may not be ideal for the scrog
environment with such a low type of
situation I would prefer
two or three layers of sprog nets for
the lemon Geoffrey because it is going
to get long really quickly but I do
think you would have great success with
golden go feminized seeds I think you
would have great success with Sunkist
and I also think you would have great
success with Michelangelo seeds in that
grow now let's talk about a few things
you could do if you don't want to run
feminized seeds the number one
recommendation from my line I would
suggest if you're going to go with the
regular seed would be prana prana stays
nice and short nice and squat nice and
bushy you can spread it out real far and
she doesn't mind being stretched and
scrubbed and trained out she'll actually
respond very well to that type of
treatment prana actually finishes quite
early you may find a phenotype that
finishes at the end of week seven maybe
at the end of week eight the longest
they should go is nine weeks so I think
prana would work beautifully in your
environment
I can also recommend morning do morning
do likes to be strong morning do likes
to be stretched out she will produce big
fat chunky buds but they won't get super
tall and stretchy on you so it will work
very well in that scrog environment I do
recommend with most of my strains if
you're gonna do a scrog in that
fifty-two inch space I would put the
first net about a third of the way down
and then put that next net probably half
way or maybe a little bit higher up than
half way so that you've got some support
I would like to see two layers of scrog
net in that environment if that's at all
possible the first one is a spreader the
second one acts as a support and then
try to fill that entire environment with
giant chunky colas and my third
recommendation for your environment if
we are not going to do a feminized seed
would be Sun kiss Sun kiss is the
Platinum tangi to arise it does like to
stay nice and short and squat and it
puts off that wonderful orange aroma it
is very similar to the orange gasm it is
very similar to the Michelangelo because
it's got that platinum tangi mom in
there you can tell I really enjoy
breeding to the Platinum tangi big shout
out to Maddie and Spence from the garden
of Weeden they are the ones who made the
Platinum tan G that I love so much but
that plant makes short squat bushy
spring and it is very easy to grow so
that's why I breed with it that's why I
work with it so much and that's why I
recommend it so much for this type of
situation so if you're going to run
regular seeds I would recommend the
prana the morning dew and the Sun kiss
if you're not a super experienced grower
and you want a really easy grow I would
go with one of those fem lines and I
would go with one of the orange dominant
ones either the Michelangelo or the
orange gasm if you want to run regular
seeds and you want a really easy grow I
would recommend that Sun kiss if you're
an experienced grower I would recommend
maybe trying that golden goat if you
want to go with regular seeds then you
can try the prana or maybe the morning
dew or maybe the Sun kiss the morning
dew is probably going to be the most
challenging plant out of all of those
the Sun kiss and the morning dew should
be quite easy to grow I will tell you
now that if you grow the prana or the
morning dew and that type of environment
be prepared to do some defoliation
because both of those plants get quite
large leaves and you'll want to pull off
some of those big hand sized leaves to
keep the airflow and the light
penetration optimal in your tight space
all right Trent I want to thank you for
the great email I want to wish you great
success in your tent grow when you are
ready to grab those seeds for your
winter run don't forget my friends at
seeds here now
dot-com all right ladies and gentlemen
boys and girls pimps and hos friends and
foes smokers and growers all you bad
[ __ ] out there I want to thank
you once again for listening to episode
504 of the Grove from your heart podcast
if you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
and you would like to make a financial
contribution to the show again you can
do so by visiting www.uniquevanities.com
come hang out with myself come hang out
with the dude
rose crew come hang out the dude coming
out scotty real who knows who else i may
take to the event come have a good time
with us in denver at the dude grows cup
is a private party
visit dude grows dot-com for full
details also don't forget to check out
my youtube channel you guys my youtube
channel has been growing rapidly and i
appreciate all of the support if you're
not subscribed to my youtube channel
please go to youtube search for the
growth from your heart podcast subscribe
to the channel
maybe click like on some videos maybe
even leave some comments and let me know
what you think about the show big shout
out to everybody who is subscribed to
the channel and big shout out and
high-five to everybody who's been
leaving comments i truly appreciate that
type of interaction and support that
really helps out more than you know i
also want to thank everybody for all of
the support on instagram a couple of
episodes back i talked about my IRA
genetics instagram page being shut down
that page is back and it is now viewable
by everybody so please follow us on
instagram its irie underscore genetics
also don't forget about the grow from
your heart podcast instagram page i do
appreciate all of the social media
support ladies and gentlemen if you've
got something you'd like to say nor not
into all of that social media nonsense
you can send me an e-mail of course my
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com you know i would love to
hear from you i think that is all I've
got for you for this episode I'll be
back in a couple of days with fresh new
content I want to send one more giant
shout out to my buddy sub cool and until
next time take a phat dab and give your
mom a hug for me
my heart crazy to see how the YouTube
struggling
Sophie for you and me for you and me we
have some and become so I was into me
while often though they find it so hot
there's the link in the trash you can
see every day you eyes
in the morning you find the same old
thing then you start to imagine what the
rest of the meeting may bring to you so
you make it about
and then Nana something make you eat
everything doesn't seem so bad then you
turn
to lead you to a shame
so you look up in the sky or the end and
wonder why then you look
you just know you spill over
doesn't seem so bad
then you turn to the lady
leave you to us and so you look up in
the sky hold your head and wonder why
then you
thanks below you still around so housing
in the
plenty so many people still live Minami
we have it so many things easy
[Music]
to see how the new stem struggling
with laser feel for you and me for you
and me why won't you
[Music]
they need to be free don't you try to
slow them down whoa
let them go let them go