all right here we go welcome back
podcast world at is time for episode 505
of the growth from your heart podcast
this episode of the show is brought to
you by my friends at seeds here now if
you need new regular feminized or Auto
flower seeds in your garden I highly
recommend seeds here now and you can
find them at www.cpa.psu.edu or a before
on the show I completely agree with that
flavor description I completely love
that flavor and I absolutely love the
buzz from the I scream live batter from
Green Dot labs on the back of the
package it says the product does contain
sixty five point zero four percent THC
big shout-out to our friends at Green
Dot labs for the delicious I scream live
batter ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls pimps and hos friends and foes
smokers and growers all you bad
[ __ ] out there this is one of
the long awaited mix episodes so in this
episode I'm going to talk about my
nutrient regimen and how I mix my
nutrients in this episode we are going
to start with the clone mix we will work
our way into the veg mix and then the
next episode will be the beginning of
the flowering mix before we get to the
mix part of this episode let's do some
shout outs to a few of our friends from
patreon let's start off with a big giant
gruel from your heart podcast shout out
to my friend Todd kay I want to send a
giant grow from your heart podcast shout
out to JM I always want to send a big
thank you shout out to my buddy Grimble
the druid I always want to send a big
thank-you high-five and a shout out to
squirrel tactics how about a big thank
you shout out to my buddy BAFTA we
always need to send a big thank-you
shout out to Willy's armpit of course a
big thank you to Blackbird 76 I need to
send a big thank you to my buddy Glenn
jeroni and last but certainly not least
let's send a big grow from your heart
podcast high-five thank you shout out to
my friend baked P WN
big thanks big shout out to everybody
who continues to support the show on
patreon if you would like to learn how
to support the show you can do so by
visiting www.hp.com forward slash grow
from your heart all of the information
you need to support the show will be
right there on the screen and again you
cannot go to patreon and search for grow
from your heart you have to type in the
entire URL also to make it easier for
you I have included a link in the show
notes so if you were listening to the
podcast on Apple podcasts or on stitcher
radio just scroll to the notes section
and you will find a link to my patreon
campaign click on the link help us out
if you are watching on youtube scroll
down to the video description and you
will see a patreon link right there it's
very easy to find for some reason
patreon doesn't bring us up in the
search bar but I've made it easy I put
the link in the show notes so big thanks
to everybody who helps out on patreon
all right podcast world now it is time
for you to bust out a notebook and a pen
or pencil or maybe bust open a note app
on your phone because I am going to do a
very detailed lesson on my very specific
nutrient mix there's a lot to this
episode I will try to be as clear as
possible I will try to give as many
details as possible I also want to make
it easy for everybody to understand so
I'll try not to ramble too much but you
know me so ladies and gentlemen with no
further ado let's take a deep dive into
my nutrient mix before we get into this
I want to say that nobody pays me to
advertise their nutrients or products I
do not have any paid sponsors or
advertisers on this episode everything I
am talking about is because I really do
use this in a commercial grow setting or
in my personal grow setting none of this
is product placement none of this is
advertising this is the Rasta Jeff grow
style this is what I do
so please don't think I'm doing this
episode just to sell you some products
just to be a shill for some company I'm
going to mention a lot of specific
products and a lot of very specific
brands none of those brands or companies
or people paid me anything to do this
episode this is an episode to help my
listeners because a lot of people are
very curious about what I do in my grow
in my specific grow they want to know my
specific stuff so here it is I'm going
to tell you what I do in my grow I'm
going to tell you a lot of things that I
have learned through a lot of
experimentation through a lot of trial
and error through buying and trying a
lot of different products through
reading a lot of forums I've learned a
lot by doing a lot of side-by-side
comparisons I've got the advantage of
working in multiple commercial
environments and that means I've got
facilities all over Colorado where I can
do experiments and as long as the plants
come out happy and we reach our goals I
am able to play with the nutrient mixes
and the gross styles a little bit at
each facility and see what works and
what does not work I have also been
growing and experimenting with nutrient
regiments in my own personal gardens for
countless years we won't even talk about
how long because I may allegedly have
started doing that before we had any
type of legalization so I've been mixing
nutrients and experimenting with
products for quite a while this is what
I have discovered works best for me and
my personal grow as well as in a
commercial environment I've also found
that these types of nutrient mixes are
very replicable I can write SOPs for
these I can do a podcast for these mixes
and I can teach people how to do it on a
very consistent basis which comes in
very handy when I'm training people in a
commercial environment let me get myself
back on track because I did say I was
going to try not to ramble a lot my
point here is that nobody is paying me
to do this episode nobody has paid me in
nutrients nobody has given me anything
this is what I'm doing and I want to
share it with you so let's talk about my
nutrient mix again this works for me
this may not be perfect for you but I
have learned that this mix and this
gross style works very well
for what I am trying to do in a
commercial and in a home grow type
environment in a commercial environment
I like to use cocoa as my base for my
small plants I will use 70 to 80 percent
cocoa and 20 to 30
sent perlite I think that having 20 to
30 percent perlite and my cocoa makes a
nice fluffy aerated mix if we do
overwater those pots we don't have to
worry about all of that cocoa compacting
and crushing and suffocating my roots so
for the smaller plants I do 70% cocoa
and 30 percent perlite for my larger
plants in three gallon pots I like to
use 70% cocoa and 20 percent perlite and
10 percent per so light per so light is
basically larger and chunkier perlite
when you're mixing the three gallon pots
when you're mixing large batches
it really helps fill it it also adds a
very nice aeration to the mix that way
again if somebody in the cultivation
facility does over water those plants we
don't suffocate those roots with that
compacted cocoa we've got plenty of
perlite and plenty of perlite in the
containers so ideally we would have 70%
cocoa 20 percent perlite and 10 percent
personal life if you do not have access
to the purse light if you don't want to
add the personal light to your mix just
do 25 percent perlite and your plants
will be happy the cocoa will be plenty
aerated for you I will give a lot more
detail about pot sizes later but I
generally start from a clone I use an EZ
cloner I go from the EZ cloner into a 4
or 6 inch net pot with that 70 to 30%
mix then once the plants are large
enough I move them into a 3 gallon
fabric pot and that 3 gallon fabric pot
that's where I like to use the 70% cocoa
20 percent perlite 10 percent
personalized very well mixed up in the
three gallon pots in my commercial
environment I finish in the three gallon
pots I like the time that it takes those
pots to dry down I'm able to get two
waterings in a day on a very large plant
and I'm able to fit enough pots on a
table I don't see a need to do larger
pots I don't see a need for more
transplants so I generally go from the
cloner to a 6-inch net pot to a three
gallon pot and that is that plant
forever pot that's its finishing home
while I am talking about cocoa and
mixing your perlite and purse alight one
thing I should mention for you is make
sure you rinse your cocoa make sure you
rinse your perlite make sure you rinse
your purse alight also wear a mask when
you are playing with the perlite and
purse alight we need to rinse all of
these products because they are dirty
that cocoa was made overseas it's a
bunch of cocoa husks it was crushed
together put into a container and
shipped to the States on a ship it may
have a bunch of salts in it it may have
a bunch of unknown stuff in it I don't
know who you were buying your cocoa from
some companies have very salty cocoa so
rinse that out before you put your
plants in it or you will shock burn and
kill your plants I also recommend you
rinse your perlite and your purse alight
I also recommend you wear that dust mask
when you're working with the perlite and
personal life because you don't want to
breathe in that little dust that comes
off of that stuff
it is like inhaling glass it cannot be
good for you please take care of
yourself alright so we have covered the
pots we usually use a cloner I like to
use a clone machine or clone plugs we'll
talk more about that then I go into that
4 or 6 inch net pot we've got my 70 to
30% mix then I will go into a 3 gallon
fabric pot where I use that 70 20 10
percent mix and my reminder once again
rinse all of your stuff your cocoa your
perlite your purse alight make sure you
rinse all the excess salt out of your
cocoa wash all that dust off the perlite
and personal light and wear a mask when
you're playing with the perlite and
personal light alright I feel like we've
got the containers covered we are making
great progress on this episode in my
commercial environments I like to make
an auto watering system there are many
variations on an auto watering system in
some places I have machines mixing
nutrients and know people have to even
touch it little machines spit out this
much cal-mag this much nitrogen this
much phosphorus into a reservoir a mixer
mixes it up for me another machine
measures the pH if it's too low or too
high it spits in the appropriate up or
down then it feeds that to the plants
it's got a little sensor in some of the
plants when that moisture meter gets to
the right meter it stops watering when
it gets to dry out waters again some
facilities are
very automated some of them we've got to
mix up the tanks ourselves then we plug
in a pump and that pump waters but in
all situations in all flower rooms it is
ideal that I have got some sort of a
drip feed or sprinkler or emitter or
auto water system in all flower rooms it
is so much easier it is much more
consistent and the plants really enjoy
and appreciate that type of consistency
in timing and how much water they get
and when you use the right type of
emitter or sprinkler
I think you really add just enough
oxygen to the mix to make the plants go
Kapow when you water them so in my
commercial environments I have always
got my flowering plants on some type of
an auto watering system depending on the
size of my plants and how old the plants
are and the environment of the room
sometimes the plants get watered once
per day I like to water right as the
lights come on I like to water within
the first hour of the lights coming on
if I can we are in a commercial
environment sometimes we've got multiple
rooms sometimes we've got a lot of
plants sometimes we can't water every
room right at nine o'clock because we
can't be in every single room so when
the lights come on at 8:00 or run the
lights come on at 9:00 I try to water
this room as quickly as I can then get
to this one and then get to this one and
get all of the plants watered within an
hour of the lights coming on so they can
use all of that water all day metabolize
all of those nutrients to just get to
work and get to action and honestly in a
commercial environment by the time the
lights come on those plants are usually
ready for a drink of water they've had a
long night they've been growing there's
been a lot of activity they're hungry
they are thirsty so I like to water
right when the lights come on then if
the plants are large enough if you work
in a commercial environment you might
want to water right before you leave
that way they aren't dead when you come
back the next morning so based on the
size of the plants and a three gallon
pot I'm usually watering first thing in
the morning and then later in Flour I'm
watering right as we leave for the end
of the day I like to water my plants to
20% runoff I want runoff every time I
feed and water those plants and since
I'm using cocoa I am putting nutrients
in my water every time I am feeding
these plants every time I water because
ko
go does not hang on to the nutrients the
nutrients just fall right out they rinse
right out along with the water so I'm
adding nutrients at every watering in
most commercial environments in Colorado
I am not using RO water in fact at this
time I am not using reverse osmosis
water in any of my situations in any of
my cultivations none of the commercial
grows none of my home grows none of my
friends grows that I'm helping with we
are not using any RO water I think a big
boy filter or something simple like that
is good enough here in Colorado we have
got good water also when you start going
with RO water it makes it a little more
challenging to pH balance everything
it's a little bit more of a struggle if
you are not experienced and I don't find
it necessary here in Colorado we've got
great water they take good care of our
water there's no need to struggle with
the RO there is also a tremendous amount
of waste when it comes to RO so I do not
do that something I do is I frequently
check the pH and the EC of the water
that comes out of my tap in all of my
facilities and my home grows your local
water company changes the chemicals they
put in their treatment plants based on
this season we're using water for
different things based on the seasons we
are using different amounts of water I
would imagine there are different
problems that occur in water that are
happening in different seasons you
probably get different allergies in the
summer you probably get different [ __ ]
in the winter it's probably different
based on your location so they treat the
water differently at different times of
the year it's always a good idea just to
get a little bit of water and put your
pH pin in there put your EC meter in
there and just know what's coming out of
your faucet it's always good to know
what you're starting with so mark that
down occasionally also always mark down
the pH and the EC or the ppm or the TDS
of any solution you mix to feed your
plants make that a habit when you mix up
your nutrients as soon as you're done
grab your pH meter and grab your ppm pen
and just stick them both in your
nutrient solution watch for it to
register what it is it should be
somewhere between six point one and six
point five and then I don't know what's
on your EC meter over here it may be
real high it may be real low just
depends on who you are but write that
[ __ ] down why not maybe later if you've
got a problem you can look back and you
can go oh look on Tuesday I fed it way
to high opm's and it didn't like that or
when your crop is done and it's awesome
you can say what did we do I want to do
that all over again so I like to write
down a lot of information I write down
everything I put in the mix I've got a
Google document for every commercial
grow I work with when the guys mix up
something they write exactly what they
put in the mix five mils of this 10 mils
of this 6 mils of this they write it
down they write down the pH they write
down the EC then they water the plants
as the plants get watered we collect a
little bit of the runoff off of each
table so we have another Google document
that says room a table 1 pH runoff EC
runoff and we mark that for each table
for each room so we're documenting every
nutrient that goes into the solution
then we are documenting the pH of that
solution we are also documenting the
PPM's of that solution before we feed it
to the plants then we are also
documenting the pH and ppm of the runoff
that comes out of the pots after we
water now I rarely need to use that data
for anything but when I do need it it is
always very obvious where the problem
started and what the problem was it
always helps us diagnose a problem even
if it's just through a process of
elimination we can look and see look the
pH coming out is just fine the EC coming
out is just fine so it's not the feed
it's got to be something else in the
room let's look and see if we've got
bugs so that is why I document
everything when I feed the plants it
sounds excessive but when you've got
multi-million dollar commercial
facilities at your hands and you've got
multiple guys working guys and gals
working in these places you need
accountability and documentation and
like I said a moment ago if something
goes wrong it's always nice to be able
to look back and say this is where we
messed up but it's even better when [ __ ]
goes right and you can look back and go
do it exactly like this all over again
that way you've got every nutrient
you've got every reading you can imagine
just replicate that you can do it all
over and you can have repeat
outcomes everybody gets bonus checks
everybody's happy
alright another detail I should talk
about is in my commercial environments
is everything in Flour is underneath a
thousand watt Gavita double and in light
I like to use the thousand watt double
ended bulbs in a commercial grow I
really think that's where I get the best
performance from the plants a lot of
people will have different opinions and
ideas I've been doing it a lot I've done
it for a while and my favorite is the
Gavita thousand watt double ended bulb
that works wonderfully for everything
I've tried to put it through for every
plant it performs so that is what I use
I also like to have my plants up off the
ground so I use those greenhouse tables
I have them custom-built for the length
of the room they are generally six foot
wide and the length of the room
they come with trellis bars that you
attach to the tables I think the table
sections are six or eight feet long in
each six or eight foot long section I
know exactly how many plants of each
strain fit in that section I've got a
very beautiful plan for setting up those
tables so I've got greenhouse tables
that are the length of the room there's
six feet wide and they move eighteen
inches left or right so that you can
function in the room you can make an
aisle and then when you're done working
you can push all of the tables all the
way to the right side so that you can
just have one walkway at the left side
of the room and not waste a bunch of
space those are the tables I like to use
and again everything is on a drip feeder
or some sort of an auto feeder so you've
got plants on tables there Auto fed it
is really easy it is really efficient to
work in these rooms it's really easy to
get in there and hang up trellis it's
really easy to get in and bottom and
defoliate I've made it really easy for
the crew to get work done in these rooms
so now let's focus on a few different
approaches to feeding the plants I keep
talking about my commercial environments
in a commercial grow we were watering
every plant at least once a day
sometimes we are watering plants twice a
day just depending on the performance
and the environment and the pot size and
how much water they go through I
understand that everybody is in a
different situation so I'm going to try
to make this work for everybody's grow
also keep in mind that everything I say
were
for me none of this is set in stone this
is not a rulebook this is not a Bible
this is my standard operating procedure
you can adjust this to work for you
however you want you can add you can
subtract steps you can modify this to
work however you would like I'm just
trying to share with you my standard
operating procedure and I encourage you
to adjust this and custom tailor this to
work for your grow and again I'm going
to try to give you examples to where
this will work for multiple different
setups in my first example I will tell
you what I do in my commercial
environments in a commercial grow
environment where I'm watering every day
sometimes multiple times a day I don't
find it necessary to feed every nutrient
or every bottle or every product to my
plants every time I water them I'm going
to get a lot of opportunities to feed
these plants so I break up the nutrients
throughout the week in a big commercial
grow I will feed base nutrients at every
watering so if I'm using veg blue I will
put in a veg bloom bass mix and every
watering if I'm using new millennium I
will use either autumn gold or summer
shift or Equinox or something similar to
that at every watering then I will
rotate a series of other products which
I call boosts throughout the week so on
Monday we will add those base nutrients
whether it's the veg blue mix or if it's
the new millennium bass mix I will start
with that but then on Monday maybe I'll
add something like cal-mag and then on
Tuesday maybe we'll add something like
plus life and then on Wednesday maybe
we'll add epsom salts but I will add
different things throughout the week so
the plants get fed all of those
different nutrients or all of those
different products but I don't blast
them to the plant all at one time so I
will do a base mix on every watering and
then I will write a list of boosts and
they will be I'm just being hypothetical
because I don't have a week or I don't
have an idea right now but I'll write on
the board
cal-mag plus life lightning start epsom
salts maybe something like that in a row
there may be three of them there may be
seven of them four
entire week but what we do is we just
rotate through that list so like I said
on Monday you mix up your bass notes
we're gonna use bass nutrients every
time you look at the list you go oh it
says cal-mag so you put however much
cal-mag is required into the mix and
then you just write the date next to it
I put cal-mag in here on Monday the
first and that way we know Monday the
first they got cal-mag Tuesday when we
come in we do the bass nutrients because
we do that every day you just move to
the second one on the list I don't know
what I said I'm gonna guess that it was
probably plus life so we mix in the
appropriate amount of plus life in the
mark on the board on Tuesday the second
I added plus life so on the third or on
the fourth day whatever because by day
four people start getting confused if
it's me working if it's another guy
working he just looks at the board and
goes today is the fourth I've got to put
in the fourth product and if he's at the
bottom of the list and we've done them
all you just simply go back to the top
of the list and start all over again and
that makes it very easy to keep those
boost products fed to the plants it's a
very easy way to schedule it and it's a
very easy way to keep my staff on top of
what has been done and what needs to be
done and as a back-up plan we're also
writing all of those nutrients that were
put into the solution in that Google
document so if somebody forgot to update
the board or if you're not sure what was
on the board maybe you can't read some
handwriting or something you've always
got that Google document as a back-up
plan so that method we're going to call
that the base nutrients everyday and add
a boost throughout the week method
that's the rotate the boost method I
don't really have a name for it but
that's how we do it I use base nutrients
every day and then we add a booster
throughout the week and I will do this
to my veg plants and my flower plants
that is how I assign nutrient schedules
in a commercial environment another way
to do this is a lot of people like to
mix up a big fat tank of really strong
nutrient mix on Monday feed it
everything what are we gonna feed the
plants this week they get it all on
Monday every product every bottle every
nutrient put it all in there
feed the plants all of that on Monday
then throughout the week since we're
feeding in cocoa we're just gonna feed
them base nutrients may be some cal-mag
because they will need it if we're just
feeding them on Mondays
that method does work it works for some
people it works
a commercial grow but that is not my
preferred method another way to do it is
to simply fill your reservoir on Monday
put everything you need in there and use
that reservoir throughout the week and
just keep feeding it that same nutrient
mix all week you have got several
options you can do what works for you
again the thing that I do is I feed my
base nutrients every day and throughout
the week I rotate different add-ons or
different boosts into my mix you may
have to make decisions based on how
often you're available or how often
you're able to mix nutrients can you mix
up your nutrients every single day like
I like to do can you be there every day
to mix those nutrients can you mix a
fresh batch of nutrients every single
morning or can you only show up on
Monday can you only show up on Mondays
and Wednesdays those are going to be the
things they determine how you mix and
how often you mix and how you run your
nutrient regimen I am a very hands-on
grower I've got a very hands-on staff
maybe that's a big part of it for me as
I know that I've got a staff and I know
there's going to be people there seven
days a week that are going to be able to
hand mix these nutrients if I need them
to and make sure that every plant gets
the appropriate feeding many people
don't have that luxury many people want
to take a day off many people want to go
on vacation many people have a day job
in a family and they aren't able to
focus and spend that much time on a grow
every single day those are going to be
the types of determining factors that
decide how you set up your grow and
you're watering style so you've got a
couple of options do you want to mix
everything on Monday and feed that
throughout the week do you want to do
base nutrients and boosts every day of
the week do you want to feed a big blast
on Monday and then just do nutrients and
Cal mag throughout the week those are
things you'll have to think about and
plan ahead are you going on vacation are
you going to have visitors are you gonna
have to take a new job something's gonna
come up so just plan ahead when you were
thinking about how you were going to
water and mix your nutrients another
thing I should talk about is clean your
reservoir whatever you are mixing your
nutrients in whatever container or tank
you are keeping your nutrient solution
in it is going to get funky drain it
occasionally let it get completely dry
clean it you
some sort of a product and clean it
really well then once you've cleaned it
really well let it dry then rinse it out
really well to make sure there is no
leftover cleaner in there so we don't
mix that up with our nutrient solution
and cause problems to our plants another
thing I should have mentioned it
previously but it just now dawned on me
is please make sure to calibrate your pH
meters and your ppm meters and any sort
of meter or device you are using that
gives you a reading
please calibrate that stuff at least
once a month I recommend every week if
you can take the time all right I feel
like we've got a good foundation we know
what kind of pots to use we know what to
put in the pots we know that we are Auto
feeding these plants we know that these
pots are on tables we know there are
under a thousand watt lights we've
talked about a few different options on
when and how to mix up our nutrients and
how to water the plants now I think it
is time to actually get more in depth on
the nutrient mix I am going to break
this up into several episodes that maybe
two it maybe three it could end up being
four episodes I'm not sure I am in the
first episode so I can't tell how long
it's going to take yet but the schedule
that I am going to give for my nutrients
is a nine week flowering phase so we're
going to focus on a nine week flowering
phase everything I talk about is
probably measured in milliliters per
gallon or grams per gallon some of the
things I use our dry powdered nutrients
so I will try to be specific if it
changes I will really try to pay
attention and talk about different units
of measure very specifically I said at
the start of the show that this works
for me and my gross style and my plants
in my environment you have to pay
attention to your plants you have to pay
attention to your leaves I highly
recommend doing runoff reports I will do
a full Episode on runoff reports way in
the future that one will be a long ways
away I've got a lot of stuff planned
before that but you must pay attention
to the plants no matter what I say no
matter what you think no matter what
your equipment says no matter what your
meters say the plants are the boss if
they don't
look happy adjust the plants are not
going to adjust to the meters you have
to adjust everything to the plants pay
attention to them
the plants are always the boss you're
not the boss the owner of the facility
is not the boss the investors are not
the boss the consumers are not the boss
all of those plants in that grow room
those are your bosses it's like you've
got a whole roomful of girlfriends and
you've got to learn to make all of them
happy
all right you guys I just realized I've
been talking for like 30 minutes I could
use a drink
I really need a DAB I'm going to press
pause for a moment and when I get back I
will tell you how I mix up my clone
solution and we will get this mix
episode really moving take a DAB with me
and I'll be right back
all right podcast world I am back I'm
heavily medicated during my break I took
a bunch of fat dabs of cowboy Kush full
spectrum extract this is a blend of h a
OG and star dawg the flavor is described
as earthy fuel and leather I really
enjoy that funky earthy feely flavor I'm
not sure I got leather out of it what I
did get was a punch to the face this one
kind of makes me lazy makes me want to
sit down and chill out
it also makes me nice and focused so
this should be good
Podcast concentrates let's jump right
back into it before I took my dad break
I said I was going to tell you how I mix
my solution for my cloners in a
commercial environment I run easy
cloners I run turbo cloners I run all of
the automated Aero cloners you can think
of I also run the traditional tray and
dome type clone setup in all of those
environments I use that basic purple
clone X dipping solution and the yellow
clone X cloning solution if I am using
the tray and clone plug and dome
technique to make my clones
I will generally buy a bunch of rapid
Rooter clone plugs then I will soak
those rapid rooters in a solution it is
just water and the yellow clone X
cloning solution not the purple dippin
stuff but the yellow solution in the
taller bottle I will mix that to
approximately a 1.0 to one point
- II see and I will adjust the pH of
that solution to five point seven - six
point two then I put those rapid rooters
in the little trays and there are little
slots
I cut the clones I dip them into the
purple clonic solution and put them
gently into the clone plug then I place
a dome over those clones I close the
vents and I put it under a t5 light with
that light fairly close and I do not
touch those clones for approximately
three to five days I basically ignore
them until it looks like they need some
water when they need water
I will re moisten them again with that
same solution not the same bucket I
won't have that same solution laying
around I will remix a fresh batch of the
same solution it is water and that clone
X yellow solution I'll mix it up in an
EC of one point zero to one point two
and again I will adjust the pH to five
point seven to six point two and I will
saturate those clone plugs I'll let it
sit open for a minute while those plugs
are saturated then before I close it I
will dump off all of the water that is
ran out of those plugs that is in the
tray that way they're not sitting in too
much stagnant water but the clone plugs
are nice and saturated I'll put the dome
back on there and probably leave them
alone for a day or two before I begin
cracking those vents slowly and start
introducing more airflow to those clones
but that is basically the feed the mix
that I use for my clones in a clone tray
I do a very similar thing to my clones
in an easy cloner or a turbo cloner one
of the most important things is to clean
everything on the turbo cloner or the EZ
cloner make sure it is sanitary and
sterilized I like to sanitize the cloner
and the clone plugs every time I use it
so start off with a clean machine and
set yourself up for success then fill
your reservoir on your clone machine to
the appropriate level and add the yellow
clone X solution until you reach an EC
of 1.0 - 1.2 this is really easy to do
you've got your water in the reservoir
to the level you want it
ICI meter in there and add a very small
amount of the clonic solution now stir
that around with your meter make sure
you're stirring it all around get that
solution all in that water now what does
your EC meter say does it say point six
does it say one point zero if it says
point six you obviously need to add a
little bit more go very slowly when you
were adding your nutrient solution but
slowly add until you reach that EC of
one point zero to one point two and if
you go a little bit too high you can
just add more water and dilute it this
may take a couple of tries to get it
right try to pay attention to how much
of the solution you added to the water
to achieve that one point zero to one
point two EC and maybe right down I used
30 mils and it got me really close and
then I had to start using a dropper to
get it dialed in where I wanted it or
maybe you need 50 mils I don't know how
big your reservoir is so I don't know
how much to tell you to use I can tell
you to get it to one point zero to one
point two and it's fun
learning how to dial that in you add
solution you measure it you say I'm too
high or too low you either add more
solution or you don't then it's way too
high now you have to add water you end
up putting in more solution you just
keep playing that game until you get it
right once you've got the appropriate EC
that is when you adjust the pH do not
adjust the pH until after you have
achieved the appropriate EC if you are
going to add more water or more
nutrients there is no need to correct
the pH at this time you're going to have
to do it again so you've got your
reservoir it is filled appropriately
it's got the right solution in it it is
at the right pH then I cut my clones I
dip them into that purple clone x gel I
put them in the clone collar I put them
to where they stick about I think that's
about an inch maybe a little more maybe
a little bit less than an inch is
exposed on the bottom side of the clone
collar so the water being misted hits
the bottom of that clone and makes big
fat roots any part that is going to be
under the clone collar I try to code it
in the clone x solution I've done a very
in-depth episode on cutting clones in an
easy corner so we don't need to talk too
much about that he
but the next day you will find that all
of that purple gel has fallen off of
your clones and it is now in your water
in your reservoir in your cloner I
suggest that you unplug the cloner take
the top portion off of the cloner this
is where all the clones are take that
off and just set it on the table if you
set it down on a level table you won't
damage the clones they're not sticking
out far enough to cause any problems
just set that down somewhere where you
don't mess up the bottoms of the clones
those will be safe for a few minutes
without getting sprayed on the bottom
use your meters to measure your pH and
your EC all of that purple Clone x gel
solution dripping off of your clones has
changed the pH and the EC of the water
in that reservoir also that sprayer
spraying overnight has changed the pH
and the EC of the water in that
reservoir you've had some evaporation
you've had some mix time you've
introduced more oxygen things have
changed over the past 12 or 24 hours and
we need to correct them so that our
clones will survive so open up the
cloner use your meters investigate find
out the numbers and adjust accordingly
if the pH went too high make it lower if
the pH went too low make it higher if
the EC is too low make it higher if the
EC has gotten too high add more water
because some water may have sprayed out
of the cloner some water may have
evaporated I don't know what could have
happened overnight in your cloner there
are countless opportunities and
possibilities when it comes to working
with easy cloners so while we've got the
cloner open this is a good time to add
another product I like to add something
called clear res I like to add clear res
today and every 5 days that means we
need to mark it down whatever the date
is today when you're adding the clear
res right
I put clear res in here on Tuesday the
first then on the 6th you need to add 30
more milliliters of clear res and if
that cloner is going again in 5 more
days add 30 more mils and it probably
shouldn't be going for another round of
clear res but if it is make sure you add
it and write it down
every time this may sound crazy but even
if you run the grow by yourself right
beings down like somebody else is going
to come and help you out act like there
is another person that needs that
information because we are cannabis
consumers we have a lot on our mind the
world is overwhelming take a lot of
notes help yourself out set yourself up
for success just leave yourself a little
note a little hint a little path a
little treasure map give yourself a clue
take as many detailed notes as you can
so make sure you mark down when you were
putting clear res in the reservoir so
that you know that it does get done at
this point you have basically got your
easy cloner on autopilot all you have to
do is open it up every morning and check
the EC and check the pH and if those are
correct you can leave it alone if one of
those needs to be adjusted
adjust accordingly if the EC has gone
too high because water has evaporated
add water after you add water check the
pH again it will need to be adjusted if
the EC has gone too low add more
nutrient solution after that correct the
pH again you're always going to be
checking and adjusting the pH in these
easy cloners it is very important but it
will make strong fathealthy clones I
think the clones that come from these
easy cloners I personally think they
take off a little more quickly and
they're a little more healthy than the
clones that come from the clone plugs I
think they just have a little more
Kabang to them so that is my basic feed
for my clones I am basically mixing up
that yellow clone X clone solution at an
EC of one point zero to one point two
and then I am adjusting my pH to five
point seven to six point two and I am
doing that if I'm using rapid Rooter or
whatever type of clone plugs even if
it's a rock wool plug I'll do the same
mix and if I'm using a turbo cloner or
an EZ cloner or some type of an arrow
cloner I use the exact same mix I just
have more maintenance and more things to
do throughout the week there is one more
detail I should mention when it comes to
cloning I do personally like perma clone
clone callers yes that is a blatant
advertisement for a product but I like
them because they don't get moldy and
they don't get funky and they don't fall
apart and you can sanitize them and
reuse them
reusable clone
dollars are worth every penny in my
opinion that's less stuff to throw away
that's less stuff to buy again and we
can just sanitize it and keep using it
so I recommend perma clone clone callers
now let's work our way into talking
about the small veg mix once my plants
come from the cloner I put them into a
four inch or a six inch net pot this is
where I like to use 70% cocoa and 30
percent perlite these plants are going
to be in these four to six inch net pots
for approximately two to four weeks it
just depends on the strain and how these
plants perform but be prepared for them
to be in these pots for approximately
two to four weeks some of your faster
growing strains they'll be ready for an
up pot in approximately two weeks some
of your oh geez and your slower growing
pushes we'll leave them in these tighter
pots for closer to four weeks now let's
talk about what we are going to feed our
a small veg plants I consider these
small veg until I transplant them into
their three gallon pots then they will
become large veg so this is what I feed
my small veg plants I've got two options
for base nutrients in some of my
facilities I am running veg bloom
powdered nutrients I'm sure you have
seen the veg Plus bloom logo at your
local grocer or somewhere online I
really enjoy I really am satisfied with
the outcome and the quality of my
product when I use veg bloom base
nutrients veg bloom offers several
different types of base nutrients
depending on the type of water you have
in your location they offer an ro based
nutrient which is for reverse osmosis
water they offer a dirty which is for
places with what they consider dirty
water they offer another product called
hard which is for places with what we
would consider hard water they recommend
a water test you check your water you
look on their website and they will make
the appropriate recommendation of base
nutrient for your grow in most cases
you're probably going to want the dirty
or the HD unless you're running RO water
then you
obviously want ro so in many cases I am
running veg bloom based nutrients but
also in many facilities I do like to use
new millennium nutrients new millennium
makes a great line of nutrients I really
like the way the plants perform and I
really like the way they have broken
down the bottles and the way to feed the
plants so I will give you a couple of
different options of how I feed my small
veg plants most of the time my veg
plants are hand water they are not in an
auto watering system until they get into
their three gallon pots so these are
being watered by a pitcher or something
similar to that they're getting watered
by a person who is paying attention to
every plant my nutrient solution is
usually mixed into a large reservoir
we've usually got 30 or 50 gallon
reservoirs for the bedrooms and this is
what I am mixing into my nutrient
reservoirs I usually start with 5 grams
of veg bloom powdered base nutrients per
gallon of water ok if I am using veg
bloom I'll repeat that if I am using veg
bloom I use 5 grams of powdered base
nutrients per gallon of water if I'm
using veg bloom if I am not using veg
bloom I will use and pay attention
because I don't use these at the same
time I either use veg bloom or new
millennium if I use the new millennium
in my small veg I will use 3 milliliters
per gallon of equinox and nine
milliliters per gallon of summer shift
ok so we've got 2 different options here
you've got the veg bloom or the new
millennium base then I will add this to
whichever base I have chosen to use I
will use 5 milliliters per gallon of
water of Ruby and I will also use 1
milliliter per gallon of water of
lightening start so we are either using
that veg bloom base mix or we are using
the new millennium base mix don't use
both bases you will burn the plants then
to that base mix every day I am adding
by
milliliters of Ruby and one milliliter
of lightning start and I want this to be
very clear that you do not use both of
those bases because you will ruin your
plants so one example for the base would
be three milliliters of equinox and nine
milliliters of summer shipped along with
five milliliters of Ruby and one
milliliter of lightning start that is
one base set up the other base set up
option is five grams of veg bloom based
nutrients plus five milliliters of Ruby
plus one milliliter of lightning start
those are your options don't do both of
them please I hope I made that very
clear now we are going to feed one of
those as a base mix if you were doing
the daily blast they get that every day
if you're doing the Monday mix they get
that every Monday now these are the
things that I would add to that mix as a
boost on a daily rotation I would start
off with plus life the day I transplant
those plants I would like to mix a half
gram per gallon of water of plus life
into my nutrient solution and feed it to
the plants on day one of transplant to
get that mycorrhizal fungus and get
those beneficial bacteria
started in my plants just get them nice
and healthy get those roots going so I
start with a half a gram of plus life
that is my first boost my second boost
is cal-mag I cannot recommend how much
cal-mag you feed your small plants
because I do not know which brand of
cal-mag you have purchased I don't want
to make a recommendation and ruin your
plants on your bottle of cal-mag it will
recommend how much to feed your plants
based on their size when your plants are
little I recommend you use half of what
that bottle recommends they're going to
suggest a little bit more so that you
use more so that you have to buy more I
think you can get away with half of that
bottles recommended cal-mag while your
plants are
so on day one we're going to boost with
plus life on day two we're going to
boost with cal-mag on day three I want
to use five milliliters of lightening
star per gallon of water so if you're
mixing up a ten gallon rez you're going
to put 50 milliliters of lightning start
into that reservoir so we've got five
milliliters of lightning start is our
third boost then on day four I would
like to use one gram of epsom salts per
gallon of water as my boost on day four
so we are using our base nutrient mix
every single day then throughout the
week we are rotating our boosts we are
starting with plus life then we're
moving to kalmyk then we're doing a
lightning start and then on day four we
are adding epsom salts on day five I do
not add a boost I will skip that day
then on day six we're going to go right
back around and start with that plus
life again and repeat the cycle and I
will repeat that cycle on my small veg
plants until the day they are
transplanted into their three gallon
pots and they begin receiving their
large veg feed now for your small veg
mix feeding and Coco with a nice
pearlite mix I do recommend you adjust
the pH of your solution to six point one
to six point four before watering your
plants so that is the small vegetative
mix and we're going to feed that again
until we transplant them into the three
gallon pots now I know I've said this a
lot I know I repeated this a whole bunch
but do not double up on those bases that
I talked about either use a new
millennium base or use a veg bloom base
either one will work wonderfully and it
is up to you it is okay to use a veg
bloom base and new millennium additives
it is okay to use a certain brand and
add another brand if you understand what
you were doing I've got a pretty good
map here and I will get us to our goal I
understand what I'm doing as long as you
don't double up
on those basis this will be a beautiful
mix just please don't double up on that
bass mix that will fry your plants you
will have a terrible experience and then
you'll send me an angry email and I'll
have to tell you bro I said don't double
up on the bass so just a quick recap on
that and we will move into the large veg
mix you've got the options of a veg
bloom bass or a new millennium base that
veg bloom base is simply 5 grams of your
base mix per gallon of water that's
either ro dirty hard HD whichever one
you select 5 grams per gallon of water
is your veg bloom base mix to that you
will add five millilitres of Ruby and
you will also add one milliliter of
lightening start your other option if
you go with the new millennium base mix
is three milliliters of equinox and nine
milliliters of summer shift to that you
will also add the 5 mils of Ruby and 1
mil of lightning start those are your
two options for a base then I'll recap
quickly our booths we want to use plus
life cal-mag lightning start epsom salts
then skip a day and always adjust that
to six point one to six point four all
right that's a quick recap on the small
veg mix that means it is time to work
our way into the large vegetative feed
mix this is when we move our plants into
three gallon fabric pots this is where
we use that 70% cocoa 20 percent perlite
and 15 percent personal light mix we're
going to keep these plants in these
three gallon pots until harvest time in
my facilities they live to the end of
their life in a three gallon pot they're
going to veg in these pots for
approximately three to four weeks then
they will flower in these pots for
approximately eight to ten weeks in this
lesson we're going to focus on nine
weeks but let's talk about the veg mix
for my large veg plants again you've got
the options of a veg bloom base mix or a
new millennium base
mix the veg bloom bass mix is very
simple it is 5 grams of veg bloom bass
nutrient powder per gallon of water make
sure you carefully weigh 5 grams per
gallon of water so if you've got a 10
gallon reservoir you're going to want to
put 50 grams of veg bloom base mix into
that water so you start with the 5 grams
of veg bloom then you're going to add to
that 5 milliliters per gallon of water
of Ruby we are always going to use Ruby
Ruby is fulvic acid fulvic acid makes
your nutrients more available to your
plant that is the simple way to put it
it is like adding an octane booster to
your gas tank we are paying a lot of
money for all of these expensive
nutrients by adding a little bit of Ruby
you unlock more potential so your plants
can absorb more of those nutrients it's
a little bit of a turbocharged or an
octane booster so let's always add 5
milliliters of Ruby per gallon of water
just about every time we're mixing up
nutrients so let's stay focused we are
working on the veg bloom base mix for
large bed plants we have started with 5
grams of veg bloom base powder we have
added 5 milliliters of Ruby let's also
add one milliliter of lightening start
from new millennium so that is one of
your base nutrient options if you're
going with the veg bloom you've got 5
grams of veg bloom powder 5 milliliters
of Ruby and one milliliter of lightening
start here is another option again don't
mix this with the veg bloom you'll kill
your plants and you'll be mad at me here
is your other option if you want to use
a new millennium base mix I recommend 4
milliliters of Equinox 2 millilitres of
autumn gold and 10 milliliters of summer
shift per gallon of water so that's for
equinox - autumn gold and 10 summer
shift then to that we are going to add
that standard 5 milliliters of room
we want that fulvic acid in there then
we're also going to add one milliliter
of lightning start lightning start is to
help develop roots healthy roots make
fast growing plants so we're always
going to add the Ruby and the lightning
start to our veg mixes just to give them
a little turbo charge so those are your
two options for large veg base mixes
then we are going to work in our boosts
again if you want to mix all of this up
on Monday you can do this as a Monday
mix if you want to do this as a boost
throughout the week this is how I would
suggest it I like to start the week off
with that plus life so on day one we
were going to add a half a gram of plus
life per gallon of water 1/2 of a gram
per gallon then on day 2 we're going to
go with cal-mag again I can't make a
recommendation on how much cal-mag you
add to your plants because I don't know
which brand of cal-mag you have
purchased if you have got the g-h brand
of Kali magic you can probably use 1 to
2 milliliters per gallon and your plants
will be happy then the next day I would
recommend we use 5 milliliters of
lightning start add that to the one
milliliter that you're already using
because this is a separate boost we are
adding this to give a little more root
development and make the plants go a
little faster then our next boost is
going to be epsom salts one gram of
epsom salts per gallon of water on day
four then on day 5 we are not going to
add a boost then we are going to go
right back to the start with our half
gram of plus life and repeat the list so
again it is plus life cal-mag
lightning start Epsom salt and just
repeat that cycle and tell these plants
go into flour now for my large bed mix I
will recommend that we do adjust the pH
to somewhere between six point one and
six point four and of course make sure
you are getting plenty of runoff when
you were watering these plants alright I
feel like we're making great progress on
the mix episode here we have talked
about what to feed our clone
we have talked about what to feed our
small veg I feel like we've got a solid
idea of what to feed our large Badge
plants I've got one more thing I feel
like I should make sure to cover at this
stage of the game it is really important
to have a solid integrated pest
management strategy in place we need to
make sure not to get bugs it is almost
time to put our plants into flour I
really don't like putting plants into
flour if there is a pest problem I'll do
my best to eradicate that problem before
we go into bloom because once you were
in bloom you are very limited on your
options for getting rid of bugs so make
sure you are working on some sort of
integrated pest management strategy
multiple modes of attack multiple
methods pay good attention have a lot of
indicators in there that is a whole
another episode what I wanted to make
sure to add into that part was when I
apply a sprayed on pesticide I always
mix in a product called push pushes from
veg bloom they do recommend that you
don't mix push with other products but
if I am applying a pesticide I always
add the recommended dosage of push to
that pesticide it is a foliar feed I
feel like if I'm gonna put something
shitty on the plants they may compromise
their health that I can offset some of
that damage by adding something healthy
and I think that good healthy product is
push so every time I apply a pesticide I
mix a little bit of push in the mix and
spray that onto the plants as
recommended I also like to use push once
a week with or without a pesticide if
I'm not applying a pesticide I will mix
up the recommended dosage of push I do
believe it's 50 milliliters per gallon
shake the [ __ ] out of it and apply that
to the plants when the lights are off
and I feel like I can see the growth
that comes from using push so pushes and
other products I like to use throughout
the entire veg phase right up to the
time I start seeing bud sites develop
pushes a great product and I think I can
actually see the results from using it
so something you can add is push about
once a week at 50 mils per gallon
applied as a foliar feed and also add it
every
time you apply a sprayed on pesticide
alright ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls smokers and growers I think that
concludes my first mix episode I really
hope you learned a lot I hope you
enjoyed that I had a lot of fun teaching
you about what I feed my plants in the
next episode we will work our way into
my flowering nutrient mixes I've got a
lot of great things to share with you
please stick around for that one if you
feel like this episode was educational
informative or entertaining and you
would like to make a financial
contribution to the show you can do so
by visiting www.disabilitydenials.com
and gentlemen boys and girls pimps and
hos friends and foes I'll be back in
just a few days with another mix episode
I wanna give a giant shout out to my
friend James but erson and until next
time take a phat dad and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]