welcome to the show podcast world it is
time for episode 506 of the growth from
your heart podcast this episode of the
show is brought to you by seeds here
now.com if you need new regular
feminized or auto flower seeds in your
garden I highly recommend seeds here
now.com seeds here now.com carries all
the top cannabis breeders in the
industry all backed by their
award-winning
satisfaction guarantee and for my
friends on a tight budget seeds here
now.com offers several packs for under
$30 and they do offer many amazing
monthly sales you can also save a few
bucks by using coupon code GFY h10 at
checkout again that's coupon code g fyh
10 at seeds here now dot-com you know I
like to start the podcast off by talking
about what I'm smoking today I've been
taking dabs of lemon wreaths live batter
from our friends at Green Dot labs this
is a blend of cam Brule and secret cush
mints on the package the flavor is
described as lemon rind and tea tree oil
I will agree with that I'm going to say
there is also an extra funk to it I
really enjoy the flavor and buzz from
the lemon wreath life batter
it obviously has me talkative it's got
me in a really good mood so this is
going to be a wonderful podcast ladies
and gentlemen this is going to be the
second installment of my mix episode in
this episode we're going to focus on my
flowering nutrient mix before we get to
that part of the show let's do some
shout outs to a few of the people who
helped us out on patreon let's start off
with the big giant grow from your heart
podcast shout out and thank you to our
friend JM how about a big girl from your
heart podcast high-five thank you shot
up to zoso J I always want to send a
thank you shout out to Learning and
burnin let's send a big high-five - ruh
lightning Tim I always want to send a
big thank you to Michael w of course I
always want to send a thank-you
high-five to Justin how about a big girl
from your heart podcast fist bump to my
buddy Todd K I always want to send a
special thank you to Blackbird 76 I
always want to send a big high-five to
my buddy big toe grows and last but
certainly not least let's give a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to my friend
the indoor man big thank you and big
respect to everybody who supports the
show on patreon if you would like to
learn how to support the show you can do
so by visiting www.disabilitydenials.com
for
nutrient mix I said this in the last
episode but I want to repeat it before I
start talking about my mix this nutrient
mix works for me in my environment with
my plants I don't know what strains
you're running I don't know what kind of
lights you're using I don't know how
much airflow is in your room I don't
know what's happening in your
environment this works beautifully for
me on many different setups I run this
nutrient mix in a commercial environment
and I run this nutrient mix in my own
personal environment and it works very
well pay attention to your plants no
matter what I teach you no matter what
the bottles teach you no matter what the
meters in the room tell you the plants
are the boss pay attention to them and
adjust accordingly
don't say Rasta jeff said to feed it
cal-mag i'm going to give it cal-mag
don't do that I cannot see your plants
if the plants have a problem let them
tell you what the problem is and adjust
don't force the plants to do anything
because it will not work
for you so keep in mind that everything
I am teaching you works for me you have
got to pay close attention to the plants
and make adjustments there will be
gametime decisions there will be
adjustments and I do encourage you to
adjust and custom tailor this recipe to
work for your grow and now the last
disclaimer that I'm going to make before
I jump into this is nobody pays me to
talk about any of these nutrients that
I'm going to tell you about this is all
stuff that I have tested and
experimented with and this is what I am
using in commercial grows throughout
Colorado this is what I have taught
people in commercial grows in Oklahoma
to run this is what people in Missouri
are running in commercial cultivation
facilities this is what people in
Massachusetts and New Mexico are running
based on my consultations and my setups
in my experience I've got people all
over the country running this exact
nutrient mix and the table type of setup
I explained in the previous episode so
my point is nobody pays me this is all
stuff that I use because it works for me
again it works for me you may have to
adjust some things to work for you your
environment may be different your lights
may be different your watering style is
probably different your strains and your
genetics are most likely
completely different so you will need to
make adjustments now with all of that
being said let's dive into my nutrient
mix my flowering plants are in three
gallon pots they are filled with cocoa
that is amended with perlite and purse
alight we've gone over that in the last
episode I'm going to water until I get
about 20% run off every time I water I
want approximately 20% run off at the
beginning of the flowering phase I'm
generally watering my plants every
morning I like to water right when the
lights come on so as soon as the lights
come on at 8 or 9 o'clock or maybe seven
o'clock in some places we've got a
nutrient mix ready to go the lights
click on and those plants get water I
like to water them right when the lights
come on then as they get bigger later in
the flowering cycle they may need
another watering before we leave for the
end of the day so I like to water them
one more time around five or six o'clock
so that when we come back the next
morning that are not crispy and dead
so I'm generally watering these plants
once or twice a day they get nutrients
at every watering in the previous
episode I talked about different styles
of mixing your nutrients you can do the
Monday blast where you get everything in
the nutrient tank Monday and the plants
get fed everything on Monday then the
rest of the week they get base nutrients
and maybe some cal-mag or you can do the
thing that I like to do where you feed
them a base mix every single day and
then you add a boost every day on top of
that because in my environment like I
said I'm watering every day so I'm able
to mix up a different mix on a daily
basis and feed my plants exactly what
they want every single day maybe you
don't have access to your plants in your
reservoir and your rooms as often as I
do so you've got to either mix up on
Monday and put everything in there and
feed it throughout the week maybe you
can feed it one big fat heavy feed on
Monday and then just supplement with
just base nutrients through the week or
maybe you're able to do the big base
nutrient mix with a boost every day like
I like to do that is something you're
going to have to figure out in my
example I'm going to tell you what I use
for base nutrients then I will tell you
what I use for boost nutrients it is up
to you to decide how you want to apply
those boosts again I mix a base mix
every single day then I rotate boost
products throughout the week to add to
that so we'll say Monday I'll mix up my
base we'll say that my base is 5 grams
of veg bloom powder one milliliter of
liquid lightening start and 5
milliliters of Ruby that is my base then
throughout the week I will rotate
through boosts so we'll say day one we
will use plus life on day two I will use
cal-mag and on day three I will use
lightening start then we'll just go back
to the top of the list and repeat that
through the entire week as we feed the
plants that is how I do my boosts you
may like I said a moment ago need to mix
up your reservoir and put that five
grams of Base nutrient in there the
lightening start the Ruby
and you may be adding all of those
boosters all at one time that is up to
you as long as the plants accept your
feeding properly you are not doing it
wrong do what works for your lifestyle
your grouse style your gardening style
and most of all do what works for the
plants throughout the flowering phase I
do recommend that we adjust our pH of
our nutrient solution to somewhere
between six point two and six point four
that's an ideal range since we are
working in cocoa and we're using a lot
of nutrients and we've got a lot of
fulvic acid that will be perfect for our
plants so through the entire process
adjust your pH solution to six one two
six point four now let's talk about the
actual nutrients I am using in my
flowering nutrient solution and I'm
going to go through this week by week we
are going to do a nine week schedule and
of course the last 10 to 14 days of that
schedule will be a flush with probably
no nutrients maybe a couple of very
specific products if you want to add
them once we get through the whole
lesson I will talk about a few other
options you can add if it suits your
budget and if it suits your experience
level and if you're comfortable adding a
few more things so I feel like I've been
teasing it I feel like I've been
building a lot of hype let's actually
discuss my flowering nutrient mix here
we go in the previous mix episode I
talked about having two different base
mixes we are going to do a very similar
idea in this episode and again it is
very important that you do not double up
on your base mixes what I mean by that
is I like to use veg bloom powdered
nutrients as my base in some facilities
in other facilities I am using all new
millennium bottled nutrients where I'm
using the veg bloom powder nutrients I
will subtract the new millennium base
mix so I have two different options for
base mixes and I will make them both
very clear in each week's mix recipe
most of you have probably already made a
decision you
no if you're going to use the veg bloom
powdered nutrients or you know if you're
going to use the new millennium liquid
bottled nutrients so as soon as you hear
the appropriate mix you will know which
recipe to follow I will make it very
clear for you so please follow along
here we go
for week 1 we've got two options for
base mixes let's start with that 5 grams
a veg bloom base mix per gallon of water
so we've got 5 grams of veg bloom per
gallon or if you are going to use the
new millennium bottled nutrients replace
that 5 grams with 4 milliliters of
equinox 6 milliliters of summer shift
and 6 milliliters of autumn gold per
gallon of water now if you use the veg
bloom or the new millennium either way
you are going to add one milliliter of
lightening start and 5 milliliters of
Ruby
so just to recap the liquid formula is 4
milliliters of equinox 6 milliliters of
summer shift and 6 milliliters of autumn
gold that is your base then you will add
one milliliter of lightning start and 5
milliliters of Ruby per gallon to your
solution that is if you are using the
new millennium mix if you're using the
veg bloom base it will be 5 grams of veg
bloom powder one milliliter of lightning
start and 5 milliliters of Ruby per
gallon of water those are your two
options for base mixes for week 1 of
flower now these are the boosts which I
would recommend adding through week one
I would recommend that you add a little
bit of cal-mag at this time I don't know
which brand of cal-mag you have
purchased I don't know which bottle
you've got if you were using the general
hydroponics Kali magic I recommend one
to two milliliters per gallon of cal-mag
as a boost in this recipe
then I also recommend one milliliter per
gallon of lightning start as a boost in
this recipe
I also recommend one half to one full
gram of plus life per gallon of water as
a boost in this recipe so you will have
your base mix that you will feed every
day then if you are going to rotate your
boosts you will do cal-mag at one to two
mils per gallon lightning start at one
milliliter per gallon and then plus life
at one half to one full gram per gallon
and that is the week one mix now let's
move into week two of the flowering
cycle for our base mix we have got the
option we can use five grams of veg
bloom dried nutrients or you can use
five milliliters of equinox six
milliliters of summer shift and six
milliliters of autumn gold per gallon of
water so it's five milliliters of
equinox six milliliters of summer shift
and six milliliters of autumn gold to
that if you are using the veg bloom
dried mix or that veg bloom liquid mix I
just spoke of we are going to add one
milliliter per gallon of appetite from
new millennium we are also going to add
five mils of Ruby basically what we have
done we have increased the equinox by
one milliliter to add a little more
energy to the plants and we have swapped
out the Lightning start for the appetite
because I think we've got enough roots
at this time we're going to focus more
on the PK so that is our base mix if
you're using the five grams of veg blue
mix or the new millennium liquid mix
make sure to add that one mil of
appetite and five milliliters of Ruby
our boosts for week two are going to be
one to two mils of cal-mag one
milliliter of lightening star and one
half to one full gram of plus life per
gallon of water so weeks one and two are
very
similar the main difference is that we
have now introduced the appetite PK to
start increasing phosphorus and
potassium to give us fatter buds now
let's move into week 3 week 3 as when we
are going to add a product called shine
shine as part of the veg bloom lineup I
think that adding shine early and flower
will help reduce stretch so that our
plants don't get so stretchy for the
first three weeks I also think it helps
start speeding up bud development and I
know it absolutely helps start
developing trichomes early so let's add
a little bit of shine to the mix we'll
get more specific on that in a moment
let's focus on the base mix for week 3
of course you can use the veg bloom
powdered nutrients at 5 grams per gallon
or you can use the new millennium base
mix for week 3 that is going to be 5
milliliters of equinox 5 milliliters of
summer shift and we've increased to 10
milliliters of autumn gold per gallon of
water so that is our main base mix you
can either use the 5 grams of dried
nutrients or 5 milliliters of equinox 5
milliliters of summer shift and 10
milliliters of autumn gold but again
please do not mix the 5 grams and that
solution together that will fry the [ __ ]
out of your crop now whichever base mix
you have chosen to work with to that we
are going to add the 1 milliliter per
gallon of appetite and we are also going
to add 5 milliliters per gallon of Ruby
basically every time we mix up a
nutrient solution in this facility we
are going to add 5 milliliters per
gallon of water of Ruby every time so
we've got our base mix we've got our 5
milliliters of equinox 5 milliliters of
summer shift 10 milliliters of autumn
gold or 5 grams of veg bloom powdered
nutrients to that we have mixed in our
one milliliter of appetite we've added 5
mils of Ruby then our boosts for week 3
are going to be cal-mag once again we
will do cal-mag at 1 to 2 milli
per gallon I'm not sure which brand you
have purchased adjust accordingly you
guys pay attention to what the bottle
says read the back of the bottle maybe
use half of the recommended dosage and
pay attention to the plants and if you
see a cow mag deficiency coming on don't
try to boost it up really hard increase
it slowly and the plants will appreciate
you so our boosts are cal mag we're also
going to use one milliliter of lightning
start we're also going to use 1/2 to 1
gram of plus life per gallon of water
and this week we are going to add shine
let's add one gram of shine per gallon
of water so our boosts for week three
are cal-mag lightning star plus life and
shine now by the end of week three we
should start seeing nice bud sets little
bud developments those little dandelions
are popping up it is starting to get
exciting now it is time to increase the
appetite and increase the shine to start
building up those big fat buds let's
focus on the week for base mix or week
four you do have the option of five
grams per gallon of veg bloom base
nutrients or if you are using new
millennium liquid nutrients you can use
five milliliters per gallon of water of
equinox five milliliters per gallon of
summer shift and ten milliliters per
gallon of autumn gold so for week four
our base is either five grams of dried
nutrients or five mils of equinox five
mils of summer shift and 10 mils of
autumn gold to either one of those mixes
we are going to add two milliliters of
apatite and five milliliters of Ruby
don't forget that every time we mix up a
nutrient solution we are going to add
five mils of Ruby to make it worth our
time that Ruby works like an octane
booster or a turbocharger for our
nutrients let's be sure to add that now
for our boosts for week four we are
going to add 1 to 2 milliliters of
cal-mag we are also going to
one half to one full gram of + life now
this week we are going to increase to
two grams of shine per gallon of water
now we are working our way into week
five we are starting to see nice bud
development now we are going to take the
summer shift out of the mix we aren't
using summer shift anymore our mixes are
going to change a little bit let's talk
about the week five flowering feed mix
on week five of course you can use five
grams of dried veg
your base mix or you can use four
milliliters of equinox and sixteen
milliliters of autumn gold per gallon as
your base mix so your options are five
grams of veg bloom dried powdered
nutrients or four milliliters of equinox
and sixteen milliliters of autumn gold
per gallon of water but do not double up
again I know I keep repeating this but
do not use both base mixes because you
will cook your plants I'm giving you two
options because some people want to use
veg bloom and some people want to use
new millennium I find that they work
beautifully when you combine the two so
I like to use the powdered base
nutrients and then add in the boosters
and the add-ins from new millennium so
let's refocus our options are 5 grams of
dried nutrients or 4 mils of equinox and
16 millilitres of autumn gold those are
your options don't mix the dry and the
wet nutrients at the same time to that
whichever base you have chosen we are
going to add 2 milliliters of appetite
and 5 milliliters of Ruby per gallon of
water that is our base set up for week 5
our boost for week 5 will be 1 to 2
milliliters of cal-mag 1/2 to 1 gram of
plus life and 2 grams of shine per
gallon of water now let's move into week
6 week 6 is going to be very similar
we've got the 5 grams of veg bloom dried
base nutrients
or four milliliters of equinox and
sixteen milliliters of autumn gold this
week we're going to increase the
appetite because our buds are getting
bigger we want a little more PK a little
more energy a little more beef a little
more chunk in there so we have now got
three milliliters of appetite per gallon
of water and as always we are going to
add the five milliliters of Ruby now our
boosts for week six are going to be one
to two milliliters of cal-mag one half
to one full gram of plus life and again
we are adding in two full grams of shine
per gallon now if you are going to have
nutrient deficiencies if you're going to
run into a nitrogen deficiency if you're
going to have a cal mag deficiency now
is really when it is going to start
standing out be prepared for nutrient
deficiencies at this point in time you
may have to adjust things I don't know
what's happening in your grow I cannot
see your leaves I don't know what to
adjust but now is the time when you
really need to pay close attention to
the plants we are getting to the home
stretch the plants are at high
performance mode this is when it is very
likely that you will notice the early
onset of nutrient deficiencies so pay
attention
make sure your pH is properly dialed in
before you water the plants make sure
you are taking the runoff reports I've
spoken of in previous episodes we are
getting really close to harvest time but
we are also getting to the critical time
where the plants will begin to show and
express problems so be on the lookout
every day be in the grow as often as you
can
looking at leaves up top looking at
leaves down low pay attention to your
grow because now we are putting these
plants in high performance mode and the
heat is on we are halfway through the
grow and we can either make it amazing
or we can ruin it at this point so be
prepared and stay on top of your game
don't get lazy because you've gotten
this far in you've got to keep crushing
it now let's keep me focused and work
our way into week seven of the flowering
phase in week seven you can use the 5
grams of veg bloom powdered based
nutrient mix
or you can use four milliliters of
equinox and sixteen milliliters of
autumn gold per gallon of water again
don't mix the five grands with the four
and the sixteen do one or the other
please I hope I can quit saying that by
the time we get to week nine all right
on top of that base mix we're going to
add four milliliters per gallon of
appetite and five milliliters per gallon
of Ruby our boosts for week seven are
going to be one to two milliliters of
cal-mag one half to one full gram of
plus life and two grams of shine now if
you were an experienced grower and you
know what to watch for and you're not
adding anything else you may be able to
increase the amount of shine you add at
this time I would increase slowly maybe
a half a gram at a time don't go more
than one gram but you may be able to get
two and a half to three grams of shine
into the plants at this time without
causing any issues that depends on how
much light you've got what kind of
plants you're growing what strains
you've got how they take nutrients and
the rest of the environment in the room
will also be a factor but you may be
able to increase the shine at this time
now it is time to move into week eight
in my gross schedule
I plan on growing these plants for nine
weeks sometimes I'm able to go for nine
and a half weeks but most of the time I
try to stick to a sixty three-day
flowering schedule if I press it too far
one way or the other
I throw the other rooms off which throws
the entire facility off which throws
production off and that ripples
throughout the grow we don't get back on
schedule for several months when I do
[ __ ] moves like that so I try very
carefully to keep my rooms on a 63 day
flowering schedule that means at week
eight we need to consider flushing I
want to get at least 10 days maybe 14
days of flushing out of these plants in
this scenario we are going to feed these
plants for
first four days of week eight then we
are going to transition to a flush phase
we are growing in cocoa so nutrients are
not hanging around
we are also watering the plants twice a
day which means this cocoa is going to
get rinsed out approximately 20 times
before we go to harvest we are going to
have plenty of flush time and plenty of
flush activity on these three gallon
pots for 10 days before we harvest so
before we get there let's focus on the
four days of week eight which we are
going to feed these plants there is no
need to add nitrogen for the last four
days of our feeding regimen because we
were going to work on pushing that out
of the plants right now we want to focus
on fat chunky bud development and
trichome development so we were going to
ditch most of the nutrients we are going
to focus on five millilitres of Ruby per
gallon we are also going to use ten
milliliters of winter frost per gallon
winter frost is from new millennium it
is time to bust out that winter frost
and add that to the mix our boosts for
week eight are going to be 1/2 to 1 gram
of plus life and 4 milliliters per
gallon of appetite so every day we are
going to get the 5 milliliters of Ruby
and 10 milliliters of winter frost then
we are going to do a day of plus life a
day of appetite a day of plus life and a
day of appetite then we are going to
begin flushing on the fifth day of week
eight that will give us day 5 6 &amp; 7 of
week 8 for flush and we get all of week
9 for flush that will give us a
beautiful flush our buds will taste
delicious they will burn nice and clean
we will have a wonderful product if we
dry and cure it properly but that's a
whole nother episode let's talk about
this flush phase in most cases I don't
recommend adding any products during
flush there is no reason to add anything
at this time we're trying to rinse out
that cocoa to where there are no
nutrients in there
that makes the plants starve themselves
then they begin to cannibalize
themselves they eat up all the leftover
sugars and nutrients that way our buds
taste good and our Bulls burn smoothly
so let's work on a flush all we have to
do is water the plants as needed water
them in the morning get that 20% runoff
water them again before you leave get
that 20% runoff then at the end of week
nine when you harvest those plants
should taste delicious and they should
burn beautifully without weird ashes and
weird aromas again that does depend on a
proper dry and cure now if you did
experience any nutrient burn any
problems during the flowering phase when
you are flushing you can use a product
called SLE f100 it is an enzyme it will
help clean your cocoa it will help clean
out the rhizosphere during the flush
phase and it will help give you a
cleaner product and it will help speed
up the flush phase I generally don't
recommend a flushing agent or a flush
product I find that to be unnecessary in
cocoa if you're going to do something
like that I would use slf 100 as a NIN's
I'm but in most situations there is no
need to add anything during the flush
phase just run plenty of water through
those plants don't drown them at the end
just flush them we want to rinse out the
cocoa for the last few days of flush I
don't even a just the pH because I'm not
worried about the pH of the solution
because I don't need the plants able to
absorb nutrients anyway
adjusting the pH is all about making
nutrients available I'm not worried
about that for the last couple of days
I'm basically just watering the plants
to keep them alive until I choose to
give them the chop alright that is the
basic recipe for my new millennium and
veg bloom nutrient mix I did mention
that there were some things I would add
and things that more experienced growers
can add if your budget allows it if your
skill level makes you comfortable let's
talk about a few more things you can add
to this mix I really like a product
called decision I like to use decision
at day one of flower add it to your
nutrient mix
at a rate of 15 milliliters per gallon
and you will see that your plants begin
to flower
sooner than they would have if you did
not use decision
so I recommend decision on day 1 of the
flowering phase I would also recommend a
product called carbonaria that is
basically carbs to give the plants
energy I like to add carbonaria
at a rate of 5 milliliters per gallon in
mid-to-late flower I would start this
probably around week 4 or week 5 be
careful with the carbonaria
because it is sticky and goopy if you
are using some sort of an auto watering
system you will need to use your filters
also stir it up very well and put the
card in there stir the [ __ ] out of it
then add the shine and plus life if you
add them together without stirring
you're going to make a big ball of
funkiness so if you do use the carbene
area make sure you stir the [ __ ] out of
it and I recommend using a filter if
you're using an auto watering system you
folks that build the irrigation systems
you know what I mean by adding a filter
or a pre-filter I also will recommend a
product called bud swell bud swell is a
bloom booster that is mainly guano based
it is liquid
I recommend bud swell at a rate of 2
milliliters per gallon and let me back
up before we get carried away the
carbonaria and bud swell would be used
as a booster just add those to your down
the daily sheet like your Monday Tuesday
Wednesday maybe Wednesday you're gonna
add carbonaria
maybe Thursday you're gonna add bud
swell now just add one more booster to
the list and keep that in the rotation
the decision you will only use once and
that is the first day of flower if
you're mixing up your nutrients for the
full week you will be ok feeding that
through the entire first week that will
just trigger your plants to go into
flower that much more quickly let's get
back to the bud swell I think I said 2
milliliters per gallon and I would start
that at mid to late flower sometime
around week five or week
six if it fits the budget at it early if
you need to save a few bucks wait until
week six another product I like is
siliceous Elysium is silicates I
recommend two to four milliliters per
gallon of water and I recommend you can
use Cilicia from the time you go to
large veg all the way up to the time you
begin to flush i think thats illicium
adds a little bit of strength to the
plants and they recover a little more
when we do pop and crack and twist them
so Cilicia at two to four milliliters
per gallon from large veg all the way up
to flush that product is a little pricey
that's why I say it's an add-on if it is
something you want to add if it's
something that fits the budget and if
you feel it's necessary for your grow
another product that I will recommend is
s LF one hundred at five milliliters per
gallon s LF one hundred is enzymes I
would recommend using that toward the
end of flower and during the flush phase
if it fits your budget maybe consider
using s LF one hundred once per week
once you go into flower and again you
guys these last few items are not
necessary these are just things for when
you feel comfortable with the original
mix if you want to step up your game a
little bit more if you feel like you can
identify a problem and correct and
adjust to problems on the fly then you
can step up your game a little bit and
add a few of these products when your
skill level and your budget are ready
that's when you can add these things and
I recommend you add them maybe one at a
time maybe have a harvest and buy
another bottle and then have another
harvest and buy another bottle you don't
have to buy everything all at once
slowly increase your game step up your
skill level step up the amount of
products you're using and I think your
garden will appreciate you taking your
time and building up slowly now I've got
one or two more things I'm going to
recommend another product I really like
is liquid karma from botanic air I use a
lot of liquid karma I think when I use
liquid karma and mid to late flower it
adds a little bit of funky aroma to my
grow it makes my cushy stuff a little
bit
cushier it makes my sweet stuff a little
bit sweeter I really believe that that
comes from the kelp so I would recommend
liquid karma or a similar kelp based
product for mid to late flower if you go
with liquid karma I will recommend three
to five milliliters of liquid karma per
gallon again that would be added as a
boost in the rotation now the last thing
I'm going to recommend is a product from
the veg bloom lineup called push I like
to apply push as a foliar feed once per
week by itself I also add push to my
integrated pest management program any
time I apply a sprayed on pesticide I
add the recommended dosage of push to
that pesticide so if the budget allows
it I highly recommend a once a week
foliar feeding of a product called push
I like to apply push from the time I go
into those four or six inch net pots and
I will apply push all the way up until
week four or five of flour just
depending on how big and chunky the buds
have gotten once the buds are spongy and
they're able to kind of suck up some of
that moisture
I will not apply a foliar feed but I
will spray right up until they get a
little bit chunky with that push just be
very careful and don't spray big buds
and don't let that moisture hang around
for too long
don't let that air get stagnant in your
room that will give you opportunities
for problems alright ladies and
gentlemen boys and girls pimps and hos
friends and foes clone cutters and
pollen chuckers I think that wraps up my
nutrient mix episode I want to thank you
for joining me if you feel like this
episode was educational informative or
entertaining and you would like to make
a financial contribution to the show you
can do so by visiting
www.uniquevanities.com the link it'll
take you right there
big thank you to everybody who's
supported the show also don't forget to
support our sponsor seeds here now.com
if you need new regular feminized or
auto flower seeds in your garden I
highly recommend seeds here now calm and
make sure you use coupon code Z fyh 10
at checkout at seeds here now dot-com
you can also find us on all of the
social media on Facebook simply search
for the growth from your heart podcast
on Instagram search for the growth from
your heart podcast and on Twitter
it's @gf wih podcast if you've got
something you'd like to say in you're
not into all of that social media
nonsense you can send me an email my
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com you know that I would love
to hear from you ladies and gentlemen I
want to thank you once again for
listening I'll be back in just a couple
of days with fresh new content I'm gonna
give a big shout out to my buddy
Aldridge and until next time take a phat
dad and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]