welcome back podcast world it's time for
episode 507 of the growth from your
heart podcast this episode of the show
is brought to you by seeds here now.com
seeds here now.com carries all of the
industry's favorite breeders including
miss Jill genetics Duke diamond IRA
genetics DJ short seeds and if you're
looking for auto flower seeds they even
carry Mephisto genetics everything at
seeds here now.com is backed by their
award-winning satisfaction guarantee and
for my friends on a tight budget seeds
here now.com offers several packs for
under $30 as well as amazing monthly
sales use coupon code get in at checkout
to save even more
once again that's coupon code g fyh
tenet check out all one word to save a
few bucks when you were shopping at
seeds here now dot-com it has become a
tradition that I start this podcast off
by talking about what I'm dabbing I just
took a dab of copper chem full spectrum
extract that made me go sit down on the
couch for 5 or 10 minutes and try to get
my life together before I could do a
podcast the copper chem full spectrum
extract is a blend of chem 4 and star
dog two of my favorite strains
individually they were bred together to
make a beautiful strain this stuff
tastes delicious on the package the
flavor is described as globba juice and
watermelon I think I will agree with
that plus a little bit of foot fuelie
funk there is something funky in there
that I really enjoy big shout out to my
friends at Green Dot labs for the
delicious copper Kim full spectrum
extract all right podcast world this is
going to be a listen or email episode
before I get to the email let's do a few
shoutouts to our friends on patreon
let's start off with the big grill from
your heart podcast shout out thank you
to my friend okey Gro 720 I'd like to
send a big thank-you shout-out to my
friend big toe grows I always want to
send a big thank-you high-five - my
buddy Tommy always want to send a big
giant girl from your heart podcasts
thank you shout out to fat rabbit of
course let's send a big thank-you shout
out to Dan the indoor man let's make
sure to send a big thank-you hi-5 2hd
chop I always want to send a big THANK
YOU to sefirot big thank you shout out
to bong breath I always want to send a
high-five and a hug
we need to send a big thank you shot it
to Steve Smith and last but certainly
not least let's send a big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
high-five and a fist bump to my friend
willies armpit big thank you big shout
out big respect to everybody who
supports the show and has continued to
support the show on patreon if you would
like to learn how to support the show
you can do so by visiting www.hp.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need to support
the show will be right there on the
screen patreon does not make it easy you
cannot go to patreon and search for the
growth from your heart podcast I will
not pop up you've actually got to use
the complete URL I made it easy for you
I included the link in the show notes
all right you guys I think it is time to
move into the email portion of this
podcast if you would like to send me a
cannabis culture or a cannabis
cultivation question I would be
delighted to help you out with your
questions my email address is grow from
your heart at hotmail.com and I do look
forward to hearing from you the email
I've got in my hand goes adjust like
this it starts off with feel free to use
my name this one comes from my new
friend David what's up David thank you
for the wonderful email the message goes
like this
I've recently received a 6x6 tent with
two 600 watt closed hood lights with
dimmable metal halide HPS ballasts so
far we're off to a good start we got
1200 watts and a 6x6 it's gonna be a
little bit more than enough I think this
will work well
the tent is 6x6 and has two six-inch
fans to clip on the poles and two
six-inch inline fans and a carbon filter
that is a great setup I know exactly
what to do with this I can get you going
it says it has been a while since I've
ran HPS as I flour with LEDs now and I
only veg under metal halides NH PS I
would like to use this new setup as a
second flour room all right that makes
sense there's a few things we can skip
here in this we don't need to read all
of this here's the part we need to focus
on it says however I was wondering
mostly how to set everything up inside
the tent as to not have it collapse
under the weight of the equipment and if
the ballast should be outside of the
tent for
he issues also best practices for
venting the filter through hoods then
out of the room if I should have the fan
outside of the tent or inside because
again weight issues are real I do
appreciate all of the love good vibes
and knowledge you spread then they
signed it
respect Rasta from David he David this
is a great email I started off my grow
career in tents well when I got serious
about growing I started buying tents
before I had we all had those little
rooms that you just kind of hung up a
light and wished for the best when I
really thought I'm going to make this
happen one of my first investments was a
tent and then I got really good at
growing in tents and I set up a bunch of
tents for myself and friends all over
this town we were all growing in Nice
five by five and four by eight tents all
over I've got a lot of experience in
this let's talk a little bit about
setting up your tent I like that you
included the equipment list that makes
it very easy for me I know that I'm
working with a six by six tent I know
that I've got two 600 watt lights I know
we've got two blowers we've probably got
some ducting we've got a couple of fans
which are just small accessories to deal
with it sounds like we've got a nice
setup the main thing I would start
thinking about is can the room in which
you intend to set this tent up provide
enough electricity to run to 600 watt
lights and all of the accessories safely
I don't know what kind of ballasts
you're using I don't know if they're
magnetic I don't know if they're digital
I don't know what else is in the room I
don't know if this is in a house I don't
know if this is in a warehouse I don't
know if this is in a really old house or
a modern house I would start by doing a
safety inspection on my electricity I
would make sure that the plugins in the
wall are up to today's modern standards
I would make sure that all of the wiring
is up to today's modern standards I
would make sure that the breaker box and
all of the breakers are up to code and
up to today's modern standards many old
houses will have old sockets old plugins
old wiring and old breakers those old
houses will probably handle a 600 with
no problem
those old houses may not be able to run
to 600 watt lights in one room from the
same breaker you may need to do some
Electrical modification or some
electrical adjustments and if you do
that make sure it is done by somebody
who is qualified please don't burn down
your house in the name of growing ganja
please don't do that to the movement
please don't do that to the whole
cannabis legalization scene
now I know sometimes I get excessive
when it comes to talking about safety
and things but I really don't want you
to burn down your house I don't want you
to burn down the house and only to hurt
yourself I don't want you to hurt
anybody else
we have to be responsible cannabis
growers we have to be responsible people
I have to be a responsible educator and
podcaster so my first piece of advice is
to make sure that the place in which you
intend to plug in these two 600 watt
ballasts can handle that much
electricity safely 600 watts of light in
that 6x6 tent will be sufficient 1,200
would be really cool 600 will get you by
and your plants will be happy I would
much rather see you run one 600 watt
light and not burn down the house then
try to push to 600 s and possibly burn
down an old house all right I will move
forward and I'll quit talking about the
safety part because you've heard it
you're going to either heed my advice or
you're gonna do your own thing and
you've got freedom to do whatever you
want because America and you're an adult
so let's move forward
you do raise a really good question with
this email when they sell us those tents
and they recommend where to install
everything
it is a real prayer hoping that
everything stays where you put it
without that flimsy aluminum tubing just
collapsing on you and it's even more
stressful once you've got plants that
are growing in there every day just gets
more stressful you're like oh this thing
falls over now I've crushed ten weeks
worth of work so it does become
stressful I understand I don't like to
hang too many things from the tent they
give you those two or four poles that go
across the ceiling that you're supposed
to be able to mount your [ __ ] to I don't
trust that very much so I do agree with
you that it can be very stressful trying
to mount everything in a tent
sufficiently and efficiently so let's
talk about a few options you've got two
vented hoods you've also got two 6-inch
inline blowers but you have only got one
carbon filter so I do have a very good
set up idea
for this tent this will work if you
choose to run one or two of those vented
hoods now I have completely agreed with
you that it is sketchy hanging a lot of
items a lot of equipment from the top of
that grow tent so in this setup we are
only going to hang the one or two grow
lights whichever you choose to do and if
you're listening out there and you're
setting up a tent this will work
beautifully for you with one or two grow
lights I'm going to kind of focus the
lesson on one light and then I'll just
briefly talk about where to add the
second light it's basically just a piece
of ducting and you continue the chain
but this is exactly how I set up my
tents in a small room if I have got a
couple of blowers and a carbon filter
and ducted lights if you've only got one
blower we will talk about a different
option for that a little further in the
lesson this setup is going to focus on
two six-inch blowers a vented light and
when I say vented light let me talk
about that for a moment I'm talking
about a grow light that's got an input
for a duct on one side and an output for
a duct on the other and then underneath
where the bulb goes there's a piece of
glass in there so your bulb is basically
kept inside of a box which is sealed
with that piece of glass that allows the
light to illuminate down but then the
heat is moved away from that light away
from the grow area by using the blowers
which we're talking about the six inch
inline fans that hooks up the ducting
you turn that blower on it blows air
through there then the heat from that
light bulb gets removed from your grow
environment it is much easier to cool
the room the downside to that is you
lose a small percentage of your light
power because of that glass between the
bulb and the canopy and you've also got
to make sure to keep that glass clean
but in some environments this is an
ideal setup in a tent it will work
beautifully that's exactly what I do but
we've got the two blowers we've got the
two vented lights we've got the carbon
filter we've got the two clip-on fans
and I was agreeing that I don't want to
hang too many items too many heavy units
from that top bar of the tent it is
sketchy so in a perfect world we would
mount that carbon filter and blower at
the very top dead center of the tent but
we don't have that option because I
don't trust the tents in a tent
environment I'm going to recommend that
we set the carbon
filter in one of the back corners off of
the floor on either a cinderblock or
some sort of a crate or something like
that just to lift it up off the ground
just a little bit now I know you're
already thinking that's going to take up
some of the real estate in your tent but
it is worth every inch of space that it
takes up we need to make sure the air
leaving our grow environment does not
get us in trouble so I think it's worth
it and a carbon filter really doesn't
take up that much space just push it
into the corner you've got it crammed
into the corner it's doing its job it's
sucking all the humidity all this stale
air right out of that tent blowing it
out of the room and it's not snitching
on you while it does it so just put it
in the corner I like to set it on a
cinder block or on a crate I just like
to get it up off the ground if you can
make some sort of a stand or something
for it and get it higher and higher up
off the ground that is better but I
don't like to hang it you're absolutely
correct on the idea of not wanting to
hang that heavy carbon filter and blower
from the ceiling of that grow so get a
cinder block maybe two cinder blocks set
them in the back left corner of the grow
maybe the back right corner of the girl
I'm not sure where the exit duct is on
the top of your tent I don't know which
brand do you bought but put that carbon
filter right in the very back corner
then set the blower directly on top of
the carbon filter now you're off to a
really good start now we are almost done
with setting up the carbon filter and
that blower the next step is to run
ducting from the blower out of the tent
just go through that exit hole at the
very top most of them have a six-inch
hole right at the ceiling go right out
of that hole then continue that ducting
and run it wherever you need to to
efficiently get that air away from your
grow tent keep in mind that heat rises
so keep that duct up high
you'll be dispersing the hot air up high
wherever it goes you may be able to keep
it in the same room you'll keep that hot
air up high and the tent will bring in
the fresh air through the passive vents
at the bottom and you'll get that fresh
cool air on the bottom if I set up a
tent in my spare bedroom in my house my
normal air in my house we'll keep that
tent cool if I vent it properly if I
point the end of that ducting right out
of that room and it's blowing that heat
into the rest of the house to where it
could just be dispersed into the house
and kind of circulate and cycle and
become part of the regular atmosphere of
the house the center
air will cool that air and the central
air also blows fresh air into that
bedroom or I've got that grow tent and
with a little bit of thinking and proper
circulation I can keep the house and the
grow room very comfortable without any
extra strain on my HVAC system or
without any weird adjustments to my
daily life in my house so if you've got
two blowers and a carbon filter it is
really easy to put the carbon filter on
some sort of a shelf just get it up off
the ground put it in the back corner of
the tent then you've got carbon filter
put the blower on there put a piece of
duct tape between them so you make a
nice seal put ducting on there put a
plenty of duct tape on there a nice seal
on that so you don't get any air leakage
then run that ducting wherever you need
it to get it away from that tent or away
from that room now at this point all of
the air leaving your grow tent should be
passing through that carbon filter and
should be odor free and you should be
safe now let's talk about how to set up
the grow lights our main option for
hanging the grow lights is to use those
provided bars and hang them from the
ceiling just like recommended I would do
that I don't like to hang much more than
a grow light from that top bar but let's
go ahead and hang the grow lights from
the top as recommended I like to use
some sort of height adjustable light
hanger something like a yo-yo or
whatever is available at your local
grocer or because I like to be able to
adjust that light very easily without
any stress on my body and without
risking causing any problems in the grow
so I recommend one of those ratchet
style light mover hangers those are make
your life much easier so hang the light
install the bulb don't leave any
fingerprints or hand marks on the bulb
when you were screwing the bulb into
your reflector I recommend wearing a
rubber glove or even one of those felty
gloves so that you don't leave any marks
on the bulb then when you were done I
also recommend wiping that bulb off with
a paper towel or something
please don't leave any fingerprints on
it that's not good for your bulb and
it's very easy to prevent so let's clean
off the bulb you are potentially going
to hang two lights in this grow so let's
hang both of them up if that is what you
choose to do so now we have got two
lights hanging we don't have any ducting
on there but we've got the bulbs in now
it is time to install that ducting now
is the time to
about which direction you need to move
the air where does that air need to go
how are you getting it out of that room
where does it go once it leaves the tent
I would run that duct to where your goal
destination for that air is are you
going to dump it right by the doorway so
that it could cycle out of that room
into the other room are you gonna run it
just to the opposite side of the room
far away from the tent and hope that it
works that way it possibly will but now
is the time to think about that
put that ducting there then run it to
your tent and at the tops of the tents
there is an in and an out on each side
they don't come from the ceiling there
toward the top of the tent on the sides
most tents have these ducts in and out
for this exact purpose we're going to
run a length of ducting in one side of
the tent and we will attach that to one
of your grow lights I recommend a piece
of duct tape and I also recommend a hose
clamp around that then we're going to
run another piece of ducting from the
other side of that light to the other
light now make a nice little bend don't
make a nice sharp angle make kind of a
curve the more of a curve you can make
the better you don't want a super sharp
angle that lessens the efficiency of
your blower so we want a nice curve and
we need to attach that ducting securely
to our second light so you have got
ducting running from essentially your
exit point into the tent attached to the
first light then off of the other side
of that light you've got ducting
attaching that to the next light now the
obvious next step in this chain is to
run ducting off of light number two and
out of that vent on the other side of
the tent whichever side you went in
there is another exit port on the other
side of the tent run it right through
there we have now created a tunnel that
goes in one side of the tent over light
number one over light number two and out
of the tent
essentially the air that travels through
that tunnel never makes it into your
grow environment now how do we move that
heat and that air away from the lights
we use that second six inch blower that
we spoke of earlier you can attach your
second six inch inline fan to that
ducting outside of the tent and you can
either hang that six inch inline fan
from the ceiling or you can set it on a
cinder block on the floor
the main point of that fan is to blow
air through the ducting over the lights
and out of the other side all you were
doing is moving that heat away from the
grow tent and away from the lights you
don't have to worry about that air being
filtered because that air never comes in
contact with your gross space it's just
simply blowing through a tube it goes
right through the room it's kind of a
little subway tunnel that just runs
right through the city of your grow it
doesn't interact with the grow in any
way it's it's own little air chain now
you will need to run that end ducting to
your exit point wherever you need to get
rid of that heat wherever you're running
that other duct I would recommend
running them right to the same point and
get that stale stagnant air and that
grow like heat right away from your grow
tent as far as you can so that sounded
too simple in my mind when I said it so
I'm going to recap to make sure we got
it correct
the first blower and carbon filter will
simply set on the floor or on a shelf in
the back corner of the grow tent
you've got the carbon filter you've got
the blower on top of that pointing tour
it is sucking the air through the filter
and up to the ducting you run that
ducting out of the ceiling of the grow
tent and now you're filtered air your
stale humid air is leaving that grow
tent and now you run that ducting
wherever that needs to go that carbon
filter and that blower creating that
suction will result in fresh air coming
in through the passive vents in the
bottom of your grow tent so now we are
getting rid of stale air we're getting
rid of humidity and we're also replacing
that with fresh air and the aroma of
cannabis is not escaping the tent if we
zip it up appropriately now we have
installed the two lights they're hanging
in the middle of the tent
we've run ducting into the tent to the
first light out of the end of the second
light into the N of light number two
then out of light number two we've ran
ducting going all the way out of the
tent all the way to our second six-inch
inline fan you can set that six-inch
inline fan to push or pull that air over
the lights whichever way you prefer I do
not have any science to back it up but
in my experience I think that those
blowers those inline fans are more
efficient at pulling air than they are
pushing air they've got more suction
power
been blowing power in my opinion so
simply run that ducting through the tent
through the lights and right back out of
the tent make sure that it is sealed in
every opportunity for air to leak you
need to seal that up make sure you seal
everything if you have got your blower
pulling air across those lights and it
is sucking air this way you have got the
opportunity to suck aroma up through the
lights and then out of that ducting if
it is not sealed appropriately so make
sure you seal everything and even though
it's more efficient to suck the air you
may want to push it because that way
you're pushing Aaron if you have any
leaks the leaky air will leak into your
grow tent and you won't be pushing
odoriferous air out of the environment
so that may be a safety factor if you
don't seal it up all the way
push the air that way the aroma gets
left into the tent and it doesn't sneak
out I hope that makes sense think of it
this way if you've got a blower and then
you've got some other things with gaps
in there and you were sucking you can
pull air through the gaps and since
we're not putting a filter on this
blower we can't pull any air through our
gaps because that air will have cannabis
aroma through it so if we're sucking
we've got the opportunity to pull
unfiltered air from the grow tent and
expel that into the environment if we
are pushing any leaks you'll actually be
pushing the fresh air from outside of
the grow into your grow tent and you may
get some of that heat from the grow
light but you won't be blasting cannabis
scented air out for everybody in the
neighborhood to smell so think about the
chain of airflow and make sure that
everything is sealed so that you don't
get any aroma leaks you can't see it so
you can't see if it's happening and
you've been around those plants so often
that you probably don't smell it so be
very careful and seal it up so that
nobody else it's the opportunity to
smell that grow I say it a lot and this
is a good opportunity to remember to set
yourself up for a success now let's talk
about the same setup but with just one
blower maybe you don't have two blowers
maybe it doesn't fit the budget maybe
you didn't score two blowers in your
deal let's do the same setup but with
only one six inch inline fan we're going
to start off with the very same theory
with the carbon filter we don't want to
hang that heavy filter
from the ceiling we don't want to break
our plants we don't want to break the
tent so let's put the carbon filter on a
couple of cinder blocks or on a couple
of milk crates on the floor in the grow
tent it does take up a little bit of
space but not enough to make me complain
it is very well worth the space in my
opinion now we've got the carbon filter
set on our makeshift shelf I don't know
if you're using a cinder block I don't
know if you've built an actual shelf
maybe you went and bought a fancy table
I don't know what you're doing but we've
got the carbon filter now we've got the
blower sitting on top of the carbon
filter put a ring of tape around that to
seal that make sure you have got the
blower pointed the right direction so
the air is being sucked through the
carbon filter then out of the blower
then we are going to attach ducting to
that blower that ducting is going to run
directly to our lights if you've got two
lights it should be fairly obvious you
go carbon filter blower ducting into
light number one you will come out of
light number one into light number two
you will come out of light number two
then you will take ducting and you can
either run it out of the top like the
chimney or you can run it out of one of
those top side vents that is up to you
whatever works best for your setup
whatever makes you comfortable whatever
looks best whatever is most
aesthetically pleasing go ahead and do
that as long as that ducting is running
out of your grow tent and it extends
away from the tent to get that like heat
and also the humidity and stale air away
from your tent it will work beautifully
I run that ducting right to the edge of
that room right to the door and point it
right at the door so as you walk in you
get a little blast of warm air on your
forehead but then it goes away
immediately and once you're in the room
you don't notice that there is heat or
humidity in there because I've removed
it with that six inch inline fan so that
is a very affordable and very efficient
way to duct and cool your grow tent all
in one move and I'll repeat it for you
I'm doing carbon filter then the blower
the blower is sucking the air through
the filter and pushing it through the
duct then that air goes through light
number one if you've got light number
two it goes through light number two if
you don't have light number two skip it
it's that easy just don't add the second
light and the second piece of
that should be really obvious for you
then we come out of light number two all
we've got to do now is run ducting to
wherever we want that air to end up
where is the final destination of that
air where do we want to dump it do you
want to run it to the top corner of that
bedroom do you want to run it out of the
bedroom are you able to cut a hole in
the wall and run it right into the attic
it is safe to dump that air wherever you
need because it will not smell like
cannabis because it has gone through
your carbon filter again be careful make
sure that you seal up all of the steps
make sure you seal up every duct to
joint between the lights and the filter
every opportunity for a leak please put
some duct tape on there do keep in mind
that this air may be warm you're going
to run it over the grow light you may
have a 600 you may have two six hundreds
you may have multiple thousand watt
lights if you're doing multiple tents or
if you've done this in a large room keep
in mind that the air is going to be warm
if you're going to run this air outside
think about that air being warm people
may realize you've got some
inappropriately weird air coming out of
your house at a weird random spot all
year long maybe it snows and maybe the
back of your house has just one little
3x3 section where there is no snow and
you're telling everybody there's some
weird [ __ ] happening here in my backyard
be aware of that sort of stuff it
doesn't stink but that air will be warm
alright I feel like I went over both of
those setups quite quickly so I'm going
to reiterate the one blower style that
is basically carbon filter blower
ducting light out of the tent run the
ducting where you need it
keep it simple stoner and you will
succeed I think a lot of the time we
were really trying to overcomplicate
growing now let's talk about some of the
other accessories that you have got to
go with your grow tent those two small
clip-on fans if they're a small clip-on
fans
I think the tent will do just fine
supporting those fans click those
wherever you feel comfortable I usually
like one about canopy high right at the
top of the plants and then sometimes
I'll put one about the light height just
to move the heat away from the light if
you've got to you can experiment move
them as you feel necessary make your
plants happy have fun with it maybe put
some sort of a monitor in there and
check out the VPD
and get the fans moving to keep that VPD
in line now one of your major questions
was where do I put the ballasts I would
absolutely recommend those ballasts do
not go inside of the tent keep them out
of the tent
those ballasts are going to create a lot
of heat you don't want to fight that
heat inside of the tent so set yourself
up for a success by putting them outside
of the tent don't add more heat in that
environment than you've already got from
the grow lights all right I've got one
more detail we should talk about when it
comes to setting up a grow tent when we
run all of this ducting over our vent at
lights we create a great opportunity for
a light leak many people will say these
tents are sealed up I shouldn't get any
light leaks in here you really shouldn't
but we are using ducting that is
reflective on the inside I don't know
why the companies that make the ducting
for hydroponic use insist on making it
reflective on the inside it would be
much better if it were flat black and
did not reflect light what will happen
in many situations is light will get up
into the ducting and reflect all the way
through that ducting and shine through
your light hoods just like you've got a
light on in your grow tent so make sure
you check that the light is not
reflecting down your ducting through
your lights and into your plants when
you think the lights are off if your
plants are getting light when you think
they're dark they might not go into
flower you may think they've been in
12/12 but since you've got that light on
in your bedroom all day they've never
gone into flower they've been getting 24
hours of light and you're way off
schedule now or you may be going in
there just occasionally and flipping on
the light while you're playing video
games for a couple hours and then you
turn it off and leave or maybe you go in
there and read a book maybe just go and
hang out and [ __ ] smoke a bowl in
there and then you turn off the lights
and leave and the light cycle in your
grow tent just got interrupted because
it was supposed to be on the dark cycle
so I recommend that you go in that tent
before you put plants in there turn on
the lights in the room in which the tent
is in then go in the tent with no lights
and hang out and see if you can see any
light if you can see your hand in front
of your face at all in the dark it is
not dark you've got to make it
completely dark in that
when it is dark so make sure no light is
coming through your ducting another spot
where people often get light leaks is
from the passive intake vents on the
bottom of the tents on most of the tents
there is basically a small mesh window
at the bottom with a little flap that
you can velcro and roll it up or let it
down kind of just works like a little
shade many people like to roll that up
or lift that up and let some air flow
into the bottom of that tent
I do not lift those things all the way
up I leave them about 50% velcro to
where they can't flap up but some air
can flow through there you've got a six
inch inline fan sucking air out of that
tent if you close the zipper and close
most of those passive vents you will
notice that your tent wants to cave in a
little bit it's sucking in on itself
that inline fan will create enough
pressure that you will get air coming in
through the gaps in the fabric through
the gaps in your zipper through all of
the little tiny holes in that material
you will replace all of the air that
goes out of that blower so you don't
have to lift up those passive flaps all
the way they will suck enough air
through their air travels through the
path of least resistance and physics
dictates that all of the air that comes
in has to go out all of the air that
goes out has to come back in it's called
displacement so power that blower up and
roll those vents down and just let the
walls of that tent suck in a little bit
and I don't think you'll get any light
leaks and I do think you will get plenty
of air exchange if you are running that
six inch inline fan like my new friend
David another thing I've seen people do
is simply make a little bit of a shade
cloth on the outside of those tins I've
seen guys buy those strips of HEPA
filters and just duct tape that over
those bottom vents that helps to keep
out extra light and it also works as an
extra layer of filtration you'll notice
that those vents down there at the
bottom they'll get kind of you'll get a
bunch of dog hair if you've got a dog
you'll get a bunch of hippie hair if you
got a hippie you get a bunch of dust
bunnies and crap built up along the
bottom of there make sure you dust that
off and clean it up more than
occasionally get to that about once a
week or it'll really start to build up
but if you've got light leaks I
recommend just roll those
flaps down and only do half the velcro
that way they'll be able to lift up
halfway they'll let air in but they
won't let any light in and if you don't
feel comfortable with that put something
over the outside just a black sheet a
black cloth or I've seen guys use those
long strips of HEPA filters and you just
put some duct tape on the outside of it
and tape it right to the outside of your
tent you could probably do it on the
inside but since we get that natural
suction when you do it on the outside it
just sucks itself right to the tent tape
it in place it'll stay right there for
you all right David I feel like I really
talked for a long time about setting up
a grow tent I really hope I helped you
out I'm sure I have sparked more
questions so I do look forward to a
follow-up email if you're growing in a
tent and you've got any questions out
there my email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com
you know I would love to help you out
all right ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls pimps and hos friends and foes
smokers and growers clone cutters and
pollen chuckers all you bad
[ __ ] out there I want to thank
everybody for listening to episode 507
of the growth from your heart podcast if
you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
and you would like to make a financial
contribution to the show you can do so
by visiting www.disabilitydenials.com
tent I want to give a giant shout out to
my buddy Ridge patch and until next time
take a phat dab and give your mom a hug
for me 501
they're all all engine running liftoff
we have a liftoff
[Music]