hey what's up podcast world I'm your
host Rasta Jeff and it is time for
episode 508 of the Grove from your heart
podcast this episode of the show is
brought to you by seeds here now.com
seeds here now.com carries all of the
industry's favorite breeders including
duke diamond I read genetics and miss
Jill and they are all backed by their
award-winning satisfaction guarantee for
my friends on a tight budget seeds here
now.com offers several packs for under
$30 as well as amazing monthly sales
make sure to use coupon code Jeff wih
ten at checkout to save yourself a few
more bucks
that's coupon code GFY h10 at checkout
to save a few more bucks at seeds here
now dot-com you know I like to start the
podcast off by talking about what I'm
smoking today I've been taking big dabs
of double og full-spectrum extract from
our friends at Green Dot labs this is a
blend of legend oh gee and sour double
on the package the flavor is described
as pine sour and lemons I will
completely agree with that flavor
description it smells like somebody
cleaned a skunk's ass with lemon pledge
here in my recording space on the back
of the package it says this product
contains sixty two point zero three
percent THC I really love the flavor I
really love the buzz of the double og so
big shout-out to our friends at Green
Dot labs for the delicious full spectrum
extract all right podcast world I've got
a great Thursday show lined up for you
before we get to the details let's do
some shoutouts to a few of our friends
who support the show on patreon let's
start off with a big giant growth from
your heart podcast high five and a fake
you shout out to my friend red beard I
want to send a big thank you shout out
to my buddy Roo lightning Tim I always
wanted to send a big thank-you shout out
to my buddy Michael Debbie you let's
send a big thank-you fist bump and a
high-five to learning and burnin I
always want to send a big thank you to
my friend Victor let's send a big grow
from your heart podcast high-five and
thank you to Woodside one-nine-five I
always want to send that big thank you
shout out to my friend the gabacho we
always owe a big thank-you fist bump and
a high-five to Riley how about a big
THANK YOU shout out to my new friend
Jose Paz and of course I always need to
send up
hi-five and a fake you shout-out to my
good friend stabby
makes stab wood big thanks and big
shout-out to everybody who supports the
show and has continued to support the
show on patreon I could not do it
without your support the computer that I
am using to record this show was
actually funded by patreon contributions
that was covered just a couple of years
ago recently I've noticed that my
MacBook is acting a little bit funny and
it is also warped on the bottom I don't
know how that happened I don't know what
does that but it is starting to bubble
so it is almost time to replace this
MacBook that will not be stressful that
will not be a problem there will be no
issue because my friends from patreon
have helped out so well that I'll just
be able to go to the computer place and
say I need a new computer and it will be
covered through my friends on patreon so
big thanks and big shout out for all of
the continued patreon support if you are
not supporting the show on patreon and
you would like to learn how to do so all
you need to do is visit
www.reimaverick.com page and actually
search for the podcast in the search bar
I think you actually have to type in
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart they don't allow us to come up in
their search bar because we are cannabis
content providers but they haven't
banned us from the service so I don't
complain you just have to type in the
full URL or I have made it easy for you
I have included a link in the show notes
so if you're listening on Apple podcast
or on stitcher radio or on Google Play
or whatever podcast service you're
listening to click on the show scroll
down find the show notes and there will
be a link to the patreon campaign in the
notes I have also included the link in
the video description on YouTube so once
again big thank you big shout out to
everybody who supports the show on
patreon I am trying to make it easy for
everybody to support the show because I
do get at least one email every week
saying hey I'm looking for the show
cannot find it on patreon what do I do
it is real easy simply follow the link
in the show notes or the video
description
alright the next order of business I
have gotten written down
is to apologize for my stuffy nose I
sound like I've got a stuffy nose I
sound like kind of sound like I'm
talking a little bit like this it is
worth it it is all for good cause this
evening I walked into the flower room
where I've got a male plant who was just
dumping pollen and I gave him a nice
little tap a nice little flick and I let
all that pollen go flying around all
over a bunch of lovely ladies so there
has been a successful phase 1
pollination that happened today I will
do another pollination in three to five
days depending on how the male and the
female plants look then once all that
pollen is shaken out I'll collect a
little bit of it I may store some of it
properly we'll talk about Paul and
storage in another episode that's not
what we're here for today but I may
store some of that pollen then cut down
that male then we will change the light
schedule and in approximately 50 to 70
days we will have more fresh seeds some
of the items that have been sold out
will be replenished and there may be
some new things that need to be tested
and tried out before they can go to
market but if I do sound a little bit
fuzzy in my voice today if I sound like
I'm on the verge of sneezing that is
absolutely accurate it is because I
played with a male plant and spread a
bunch of pollen throughout a room and it
is messing me up a little bit today I
can taste it and I can certainly feel it
in my face so I apologize if you can
hear it now speaking of pollen rooms I
do have another update for you a while
back I was talking about replenishing
and remaking the TMNT line many of you
know what I'm talking about when I say
the TMNT line many of you may be
confused there is a strain in that
lineup called Leonardo there's a strain
and they're called Raphael there's a
strain called Donatello there is a
strain called Michelangelo there's a
bebop in a Rocksteady and I may have
recently created a strain by the name of
shredder so I call that the TMNT line
we've got to be careful with some of the
words we use but I am excited to
announce that those plants have been
harvested and I am slowly getting those
packages put together many people have
been asking for TMNT packages and the
best update I have got for you is that
the plants have been harvested they have
been dried it have been crumbled up and
the seeds have been removed and a large
portion of them have begun the packaging
phase
is just me doing the packaging on these
beans so please be patient I do all of
the seed sorting and packaging by myself
so it does take me a while but as soon
as I am done these seeds will land at
seeds here now dot-com and I'll make
sure you know that they are there
through the podcast I know a lot of
people have been paying attention and
waiting for that update and for that
announcement so the best date I can give
you is I will have those seeds to the
vendors by March 1st so by March 1st the
TMNT line will be replenished but do not
miss it because they will go very
quickly make sure you're signed up to
all of the seeds here now text alerts
and all of their social media and also
that you're on all of my social media so
you don't miss the TMNT seed drop and
just a quick heads up the best place to
follow my social media for info on seed
drops is on Instagram follow irie
underscore genetics also make sure you
follow the real seeds here now on
Instagram I also suggest you go to seeds
here now.com and sign up for their text
message blasts you will get a lot of
great updates and deals through that
service all right that's enough garden
updates I told you that seeds will be
available soon I told you that I have
pollinated another round we are making
great success in the breeding programs
in 2020 thank you for following along
the next thing I should talk about is I
recently did an episode about my
nutrient mix I did a very introductory
episode that talked about how and why I
do many of the things I do then I
discussed my vegetative nutrient mix
then I followed that masterpiece up with
another episode which included my
flowering nutrient mix it was very
detailed it was very in-depth and I
think I covered most of the necessary
details I did get quite a few messages
emails and comments and questions after
I posted those episodes one of the most
common questions was why don't you list
your ppm and your pH in
week now I do mention the pH quite often
and I say that through flour I generally
recommend we keep our pH between six
point two and six point four that is a
great range for our plants you have to
adjust to each specific plant possibly
each specific phenotype but I do believe
that six two two six four will work for
most plants in most Gardens if you've
got a lot of plants you can find that
most of them will be happy within that
range so I did mention that a couple of
times I didn't feel like I needed to say
that on every week's mix details so if
you go back and listen you will hear
that I say a lot of times six point two
to six point four is the recommended pH
if you are running cocoa or soilless mix
and you were running the nutrient mix
which I suggested and again that mix
that I recommend is only going to work
in cocoa don't do that every day in a
soilless mix you'll burn your plants you
can do that just break it down you'll
need waterings without all that
nutrients in between now I'm rambling
let's stay focused the other thing
people wanted to know is why don't I
mention the EC or the PPM's of my
specific mix each week if you listen to
both episodes you'll remember that I
said I do not use reverse osmosis water
I don't find it necessary where I am
because we've got good water you may
need it where you are you may not that
is up to you I don't want to waste that
much water if it's not necessary water
is expensive water is limited we don't
have unlimited water one day we will run
out of water I don't want to see that
world but it will happen one day I don't
want to [ __ ] up and waste too much water
so I don't use the RO unnecessarily
which means that my starting PPM's and
my starting EC are quite possibly very
different than your starting numbers I
don't know what is in your municipal
water I don't know what's in your well
water I don't know what is in your tap
water I don't know what is in whatever
water you were using we have different
water sources so if we are 250 PPM's off
when we start our math is not going to
add up now I could have done a simple
calculation I could have filled up a
container of water and I could have
checked my PPM's there and see what I
start with and then I could have gone
back and done the
nutrient mix and measure the PM's and
tell you what I ended with but if I only
missed one detail in that episode I am
not mad at myself that that is the thing
I skip I feel like I did a pretty good
job on that episode so I apologize that
I did not include the EC or the ppm of
the nutrient solutions I have been
mixing these mixes for quite a while in
quite a few rooms and I've written down
the EC and the mix quite a few times and
I do remember off the top of my head
that we generally stay within the one
point seven to one point nine EC range
sometimes very rarely we will get up
near the two point one EC range and that
also is going to vary based on which
method you choose to use are you using
the monday big mix are you mixing
everything all at once are you adding
boosts that is going to make a
difference
everything you add in will absolutely
change your EC and your ppm s so that is
my update that is my disclaimer and that
is my apology for not including the EC
or the PPM's in my nutrient mix episode
all right podcast world let's segue into
the email portion of this show if you've
got a cannabis culture or a cannabis
cultivation question and you would like
to ask me I would love to hear from you
my email address is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com the first email on
today's episode comes from my friend
giant Mike from cannabis and it goes a
lot like this yo Rusted Jeff I wrote to
you last year around 4:20 to talk about
what 4/20 means to me and it was about
my mother
then I recently met you at the Indo Expo
and I want to compliment you again on
your professionalism at the endo Expo I
remember exactly who you are and the
moment I read this email I remembered
this situation and it meant a lot to me
it was a great moment I'm glad somebody
else saw it let's keep reading it says
you probably don't remember me because
I'm sure it happened more than once but
I was directly behind what appeared to
be and then he describes a couple of
friends of mine we don't have to go into
a full description
I don't know if they want to be
described on the podcast uh he was
standing directly behind friends of mine
he gives a good description it says but
you were trying to handle business and
they kept thanking you for everything
you do and reached over the table at the
booth and tried to give you a big hug
yes I remember that exact moment
those are good friends of mine they are
very huge supporters of I read genetics
I'm pretty sure they listened to this
podcast and they make sure to come say
hi to me at every single cannabis
industry event in Colorado if there is
an event and I am there I can rely on my
friends to come give me a high five and
a hug I know exactly who you're talking
about great folks a little tiny short
couple good friends of mine super sweet
people I love that they are a couple
that they both interact with me a lot of
times when you go to a cannabis event or
a cannabis Industry sort of thing it's a
bunch of dudes and a bunch of bros
talking to each other and the
girlfriends look like they're getting
drugged along by their boyfriends I
always make sure to politely and in a
friendly way say hi to the girlfriends
to make sure they can be included in the
event as well
this couple always shows up as equals
they've both got a big smile on their
face they're both equally as excited to
be at the event they're both equally
excited to see me so I love it when a
couple comes to the booth like that
let's get my stoned ass back on track it
says I've been a car salesman for 15
years from time to time people will get
excited about their car and want to hug
their salesmen or sales women and even
try to kiss us I know that awkward
feeling and I get how to handle them by
sidestepping them and changing the flow
of conversation to move on and make them
forget about it but you surprised me
Rasta Jeff you actually came out of your
booth and walked around and gave them a
hug and took a picture with them I think
you are a class act for that hey I'm
really glad that you caught that moment
I'm really glad I got to take that photo
with my friends and that's what it's all
about I was at the Indo Expo with a
booth I was there in a business mode but
when I see my friends I want to make
sure to stop and give my friends a
high-five or a handshake or a hug I
really made sure to try to connect with
everybody they came to my booth that
weekend I stuck my hand out and said I'm
Jeff what is your name I try to treat
everybody like they're one of my best
friends and also
they are one of the most important
people on the planet because they are I
like to treat people how I expect to be
treated that's with kindness that's with
friendship that's with respect all that
stuff that we expect I try to give that
as well and I'm getting it in return the
world is giving that back to me so I do
try to shake people's hands and look
them in the eye
of course I had a long weekend and I was
heavily medicated so there's a little
bit of that you miss a little bit of
that personal connection because of that
but I do my best to be present and say
hi to everybody because they're not
there just to purchase seeds they want
to meet me
they want to shake my hand they've
learned a lot from me and it means a lot
to them to return the energy they want
to give me a hug and thank me and it
means a lot so I appreciate that you
noticed that I'm that somebody actually
caught me coming out from behind my
booth and hugging my friends they're not
my customers those are my friends that's
my community and thank you I'm glad you
caught that but let's keep going with
this email because I'm getting all gushy
here it says I don't know I guess it's
the little things like that we really
don't think about but people notice and
something so small can make people start
drinking the IRA genetics kool-aid hey I
don't have any kool-aid to spill man I
hope that everybody just follows along
because I'm doing a good positive thing
I feel like we are a seed breeders and
the cannabis community we're kind of
like a band there are different breeders
that do different things that have
different styles and if you're into
their music you'll listen to them I try
to put out some positive music a
positive vibe a positive brand I try to
be reliable and honest and I think it's
working just being me is working the
best that it can it has taken a while to
get here but it is really starting to
show so let's continue with the message
it says I've been drinking the irie
kool-aid for a few years now but other
people noticed it too and many people
behind me were shocked that you came out
from behind the booth man again that's
what I'm there for I'm not some sort of
uh I'm there's no ivory tower there's no
sort of invisible fence there's nothing
like that come give me a hug come say hi
come shake my hand come give me a
high-five I'm a really friendly dude I
like to meet the people all of that
thanks and all of those hugs
that's what recharges me I do make a
little bit of patreon funding from this
podcast but that covers the computer and
a few costs those hugs those high-fives
those good jobs all
that stuff that is what recharges my
soul recharges my spirit that's what
keeps me able to just ramble into a
microphone and share my passion with you
so thank you for that thank you for
noticing there is so much more to this
message this person also says sorry I'm
kind of rambling but my point is keep up
the good work you represent you and your
company very well thank you I appreciate
that it is grape it somebody at an event
caught that it was just me being myself
so that is a huge compliment now here is
another part the last paragraph of this
email reads just a like of this it says
I'm sure you were getting flooded with
questions about that mix episode my
question is really sure it says i
noticed you did not mention mammoth pea
have you not gotten good results from
mammoth pea I am on the fence with it
only because of the cost I started using
it the week before I flip my plants I
have been long awaiting your mix episode
to hear if you use it and your take on
it I'm gonna jump in right there and say
I do love mammoth pea it is a great
product if you guys aren't familiar with
mammoth pea give it a quick google check
it out it is a great product
however we agreed in the commercial
facilities that it is not cost-effective
I am NOT trying to bash mammoth pea I
don't have anything negative to say
about mammoth pea except when you were
trying to convince an investor and an
owner that you need to spend that type
of money on one bottle they do get
sticker shock and in a commercial
environment we need to order a lot of
mammoth pea so we opted to not use the
mammoth pea in the commercial
environments and honestly the plants
look extremely happy so we have opted to
not use it in the commercial environment
like you said mainly for the cost
another small reason why we don't use
mammoth pea is basically a logistics
issue we buy most of our products from
one warehouse everything comes on one
truck it's really easy just to go down
the sheet and order all of the things we
need and unfortunately that warehouse
does not carry mammoth P so with the
products already being a little bit not
cost-effective and then it's not carried
by my normal distributor I don't make an
extra order to add
that product to my lineup so those are
two solid reasons why I'm not using
Mammoth be in a commercial grow again
let me reiterate I don't want a bash
mammoth P there is nothing wrong with
mammoth P it is a wonderful product I
have seen explosive root growth when
mammoth pea is added in the early phases
and I have seen giant fat tasty buds
when mammoth pea is added in later
phases I do like to add mammoth pea and
my personal grows I absolutely like to
use mammoth P in my breeding projects
but those are my personal grows where I
am in charge of all the nutrients all
the budgeting everything is up to me so
in those situations I do apply mammoth
peat I am also funding a much smaller
personal garden I don't have to buy
several five-gallon bottles of mammoth
pee so in my personal grows I like the
mammoth P in my breeding program I
certainly add mammoth pee and I do
notice that my seeds look fatter fuller
and healthier when I use the mammoth P
in my personal breeding projects so
that's the first part of that question I
basically don't use mammoth pee and the
commercial grow because it is very
expensive and it is also not available
from my main distributor so I'd have to
pay another hundred to one hundred and
fifty dollars to have a truck deliver me
another pallet of another very expensive
product so we just decided to skip that
step and honestly the plants look
beautiful the plants are very happy so
they're not missing anything they don't
even know they're not getting it there
is a little bit more to this question it
goes on it says honestly everyone else I
know in Colorado uses mammoth pee or
recharge or both so I was shocked to not
here either on the mix episodes is plus
life really that good then they sign it
with thanks for your time giant Mike
from cannabis a giant Mike thank you for
the great message let's talk more about
+ life and recharge everybody knows I'm
a good friend and a big fan of Scottie
real Scottie real of course is real
growers real growers is who makes
recharge big shout out to my buddy
Scottie real and guru while I'm at it
let's give a big shout out to the dude
and also the entire DGC crew
gang Scottie real is my buddy Scottie
real makes recharge I should be using
recharge in my commercial environments
unfortunately my distributor does not
carry recharge at their big warehouse so
once again it's not available at my main
distributor recharge is a great product
recharge is cost-effective I will say
that it is cost-effective I like to use
recharge in my personal growth
Scottie makes sure that I never run out
of recharge once again Thank You Scottie
for always taking good care of me
I like recharge once a week at two point
five grams of recharge per gallon of
water once a week I feed every plant
recharged it goes in whatever I'm mixing
in Monday every week recharged goes in
there for every plant recharged is a
great product again it's not sold
through my major supplier the
distributes for my commercial
environments so that is honestly the
main determining factor of why I do not
use recharge in my commercial grows and
why it was not included in my nutrient
mix episode
I love Scottie real I love recharge that
[ __ ] is awesome I did not include it
because it is not available through my
vendor and through my distributor I
recommend it and my personal grow I use
it all the time I recommend it for your
personal grow or your commercial grow as
well big shout out to recharge great
product there is absolutely no reason to
not use it there are a million and one
reasons why you should use it now the
last part of this email is is plus life
really that good yes I do believe that
plus life is a quality product that is
cost effective and it is doing exactly
what I expect it to and it works as
advertised so yes I do think that plus
life is that good of a product and since
I'm already using the veg bloom base I'm
using the booster which is shine I'm
using the foliar feed which is push I
feel like it works very well just to go
ahead and round out the recipe with the
plus life so that is a quick rundown of
why I did not include mammoth pea or
recharge in my nutrient mix episodes
there is
nothing wrong with those products they
are great products that is just not what
I am doing in my commercial environment
at this time I told you I was going to
be completely honest with you and tell
you what I use and I honestly I'm not
using those products in my commercial
environment at this time I am using
recharge in my personal grow all the
time and I like to use mammoth pee in my
flowering plants that are seeded because
my seeds do show to be fatter they're
rounder they are harder and they finish
even sooner when I use the mammoth pee
so once again big shout-out to my
friends at mammoth pee and also giant
shout out to my buddy
Scottie real and real growers also let's
send one more giant shout out to my
buddy giant Mike from cannabis thank you
for the great email my dude it's always
good to hear from you ladies and
gentlemen boys and girls pimps and hoes
friends and foes smokers and growers
clone cutters and pollen chuckers all
you sexy [ __ ] out there I want
to thank you again for listening to
episode 508 of the Grove from your heart
podcast don't forget to check out my
friends at seeds here now calm once
again seeds here now calm carry seeds
from all of your favorite breeders
including Duke diamond
I read genetics and don't forget about
miss Jill genetics and also when you're
shopping at seeds here now.com don't
forget to use coupon code Z Y h10 that
will get you 10% off save a few bucks
also let them know they're Rasta Jeff
sent you ladies and gentlemen if you
feel like this episode was educational
informative and/or entertaining and you
would like to make a financial
contribution to the show you can do so
by visiting www.azcleanelections.gov
from your heart podcast on twitter it's
at g f YH podcast on instagram you can
follow the podcast it's grow from your
heart podcast or you can follow my
cannabis photography page which is Irie
underscore genetics on instagram don't
forget about the grow from your heart
podcast youtube channel simply go to
youtube search for the grow from your
heart podcast click on that subscribe
then maybe leave some comments on the
videos and let me know what you think
about the show
alright cannabis community we made it
through the episode without sneezing I
want to thank everybody for listening
I'll be back in just a couple of days
with fresh new content I'm gonna give a
giant shout out to my buddy rich memo
and until next time take a phat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
so
so one of a kind
no the way she told me she has the
qualities purple Queens she's a queen
boo
what can I try the beauty no need to
make but to be a cutie cheese a'queen
she's a queen
honey when they ask what a [ __ ] ones
made of
she's not afraid I'm ashamed so one of a
kind
[Music]
yes I can I
I know the kid 19 prone see I'm tired so
I never leave inside just leave with me
in the Twilight tightness if she says
she's not mine correct I know good man
is hard to find but she telling about
that giant maligning that's why she has
no tires at this time okay
I know many men not trying but she needs
to be more than wined and dined the cars
so define the way she knew I'd be she
has the qualities of a queen so supreme
I tried building no need no makeup to be
a cutie she's the queen so slippery
yeah and when they ask what a good
woman's makeup she's not afraid I'm
ashamed of who she is
[Music]
so one of a kind
no no the way should be she has the
qualities
[Music]