[Music]
all right here we go let's see how this
goes welcome to the show five cast world
I was setting up the recording equipment
and I just happen to notice that it is
4:18 in Colorado so happy three for
twenty Mountain time let's smoke a DAB
and then let's do a podcast I'm getting
myself together a DAB right now I'm
working on some double og full-spectrum
extract it is a blend of legend oh gee
and sour double the package says it
should taste like pine sour and lemons
the back of the package says sixty two
point zero three percent THC we are
rapidly approaching 420 I'm getting my
[ __ ] together I'm going to start heating
up this dad mail and we're gonna take a
DAB and we are going to do a podcast
ladies and gentlemen thanks for jumping
in thanks for hanging out with me I'm
just kind of rambling while I heat up
this dad nail get it nice and hot so we
could take a bag together and keeping an
eye on the time got just a few seconds
and it is going to be 420 all right I
feel like this dad nail should be
getting hot enough that should be plenty
of heat for now we're gonna take a fat
dad let that cool down for just a couple
seconds don't need to roast my lungs off
here give that just a few seconds I'm
just gonna ramble while it cools down
I don't need my dad nail super hot I
just want to caught enough to roast this
dab and then want to put the carb cap on
I want it to get nice and milky pink
with smoke we are just about to the I
feel temperature here it is 420 the
clock has struck 420 ladies and
gentlemen let's take a DAB together
happy 4/20
all right that is a tasty dab that is
the double og full-spectrum extract from
our friends at Green Dot labs I mean
talking a little bit funny it makes me
want to choke I'm definitely getting the
tab sweats that is some delicious
concentrate I can feel every milligram
of THC flowing through my brain and body
oh that's effective all right let's try
to get my [ __ ] together and start a
podcast here we go just like this
welcome back podcast world it is time
for episode 509 of the growth from your
heart podcast this episode of the show
is brought to you by our friends at
seeds here now.com seeds here now calm
Carrie seeds from all of your favorite
breeders including I read genetics Duke
diamond and of course miss Jill genetics
everything it seeds here now is backed
by their 100% satisfaction guarantee and
you can save a few extra bucks by using
coupon code GFY h10 at checkout again
that is coupon code GFY h10 at checkout
to save a few more bucks at seeds here
now dot-com since I'd like to stick with
traditions let's talk about what I'm
smoking you guys just heard me take a
fat dab of double og full-spectrum
extract from Green Dot labs again it is
a blend of legend oh gee and sour double
on the package the flavor is described
as pine sour and lemon when I first hit
it I got that pine straight to the face
well the smoke was in my face while it
was in my lungs and as it came out of my
mouth I certainly did taste that sour
it was piney and sour coming out and now
that it's been a couple of seconds my
mouth and the room taste and smell like
lemons so I will agree that that is a
perfect description pine sour and lemons
that also might be three of my favorite
combinations together for a flavor in a
concentrate this stuff tastes delicious
and obviously I am heavily medicated
because I cannot stop rambling so big
shout out to my friends at Green Dot
labs for the double og full spectrum
extract alright all you freaky people in
this episode I'm going to read an email
from one of our friends before we get
there
let's do some shoutouts to a few of our
friends who support the show on patreon
let's start off with the big girl from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to my buddy baked pwn I want to send a
special high-five thank you shout out to
my good friend dick goals I always need
to send a big fist bump to my buddy
Glenn jeroni I also want to send a
thank-you shout out to my buddy Steve F
I always want to pass a bowl over to my
buddy basta let's send a big thank you
dab to my friend sefirot also let's send
a big thank-you shoutout to our buddy
freak fish I always want to send a big
special thank-you to my friend Gramps
Richard memo how about a big thank-you
shout out to Rick roller and I also want
to send a big special thank-you
shout-out and a high five to my buddy
bong breath big thanks and big shout out
to everybody who continues to support
the show on patreon if you would like to
learn how to support the show you can do
so by visiting www.azcleanelections.gov
in the future and you guys I get a lot
of emails and messages from people who
say that they want to contribute to
patreon in the future but they are not
in a financial situation to help out
right now that is okay do not stress
yourself out over helping my patreon
campaign I don't expect anything in
return for this podcast I do this
podcast because I was given a gift
I learned the ability the skills the art
of growing cannabis
very quickly it came to me very
naturally I got plants and they flowered
and looked amazing I didn't have any
problems in my first run I did have
spider mites but we got rid of them
pretty quickly and my very first
personal grow I had spider my
we got rid of them not a big deal I feel
like I've been very blessed with my
ability to cultivate cannabis on the
level on which I am able to do so I've
been able to do it in personal grows
I've been blessed with large commercial
facilities I'm able to travel to
different states and different locations
and see their cultivation facilities and
learn how they do things and also offer
help and opportunities to improve their
facilities so I've been very blessed and
I also feel like I am very blessed to
have this gift of communication I feel
like I speak pretty well I feel like I
speak in a way that a lot of people can
communicate with me I feel like the
dudes and hippies they can talk to me I
feel like the young ladies can talk to
me I feel like grandma can talk to me I
feel like the gangsters and whoever else
we can all understand the way that I
speak if you're from the East Coast the
West Coast may be from other countries I
think I speak clearly enough that you
can understand what I'm saying so I feel
like I used those two gifts and if I
didn't use those two gifts that I was
given whatever you believe in that
creation gave me these gifts and if I
didn't use it it would be disrespectful
to that creation I feel like I would
explode or something I play the drums I
grow cannabis I do a few other things
with great passion and I feel like if I
didn't share that passion with the world
something would go wrong inside of me
physically and/or mentally like the
rubber bands inside that hold me
together would all just start popping if
I did not do this podcast for you so
that's the long way of saying I do this
because I love you because I love
cannabis and I want you to grow the best
cannabis you can grow so don't ever feel
obligated to contribute to my podcast or
to pay me anything if you can say hey
thank you or if you can give me a high
five or one of those add up boys or a
pat on the back or some [ __ ] like that
that is free and it means just as much
to me as a patreon contribution don't
get me wrong I love the patreon support
don't stop doing it but if you're not in
a position that is OK the show is free
for a reason and those folks that do
contribute to patreon I'm sure they do
not mind you listening for free since
they're able to help out we're all in
different spots in life some of us can
do a lot of things financially some of
us can do a lot of things physically
some of us can do a lot of things
spiritually we're all blessed in certain
ways don't feel like you need to share a
blessing with me if it would put you out
in
way at all listen to the show for free
and do your best in your garden is a
great way to show me love and respect
and maybe also just tell a friend about
the show that's another great way to pay
me back a little bit to say hey have you
heard this show this guy's [ __ ] cool
he does a cool show you may learn
something and then if you're the friend
listening do it again I just keep
telling people and then the show will
grow and then more people can grow
better cannabis and there will be better
cannabis for medical patients
recreational patients for everybody to
smoke throughout the country throughout
the world then the price of cannabis
will go down we'll all be growing the
best but on the planet it'll be good
weed everywhere nobody will be sick
everybody will be in a good mood that's
the biggest payment that I could ask for
so show respect to the plant show
respect and love to me that's all I need
but big thanks to everybody on patreon
big thanks to everybody listening I told
you that dad got me rambling alright I
do have an email here in front of me but
before I read it I want to read a
message from one of my patreon
supporters somebody who I've developed a
friendship with this guy says hey I'm
sorry for the delay and my patreon
renewal I had to wait for a replacement
card and then I got hit by a car so I
was out of commission for a few days
there's more to this message but dude
you got hit by a car please don't
apologize to me for anything I hope
you're okay if there is anything that
myself or the Irie army or any of the
grow from your heart crew can do for you
you let me know man reach out to me
you've got a crushed foot a bruised knee
a pinched nerve in your neck some [ __ ]
up disks sounds like you've got a lot
going on a minute says my question is
what strain will heal my crush and
fractured foot faster and what's good
for overall toes to head pain and relief
I don't know what will help heal your
crush and fractured foot I'd say stay
off of it that is probably the best
thing for that don't put any weight and
pressure on it I'm not the doctor I'm
sure the doc said that plenty of times
if it hurts don't do it the part where I
can be helpful is where you ask about a
strain which would be good for pain from
toes to head because you are seeking
relief because everything hurts right
now there are a couple of options you
can smoke something that will make your
body go numb and you won't hurt for
or you can also smoke something that
gets you so high you forget that your
body hurts those are two great ways that
cannabis works the only downside I have
experienced to using cannabis for pain
relief in a situation like this is
sometimes if you break something or pull
something or mess your body up real good
in one specific spot or you've got a lot
of bruising and a lot of blood flow when
you smoke it may elevate your heart rate
it may increase your blood flow which
sometimes makes the painful spot throb a
little bit extra that may be strain
dependent that is definitely going to be
injury and body and all kinds of
different things dependent there are so
many factors here so you may get nice
and baked and wherever you hurt this
foot your discs your neck your back your
neck and your back they may hurt more
than they do now
it may get warm it may get red it may
start throbbing there is just an
increased blood flow to that area now I
don't know if that is going to help heal
that area or not by having more blood
there you would think maybe by having
more blood move around maybe it would
help it heal also you could think by
having more blood move around in a
bruised area it could make it worse
again I have zero medical professional
qualifications zero not a doctor so my
advice would be to find a really strong
sativa dominant strain smoke that see
how that works for you something like a
double dragon or a lemon Jeffrey
something in that real high sativa area
then I would find something more indica
dominant something like the Hellfire o G
or the liberation o G then smoke a fat
bowl of that first thing in the morning
try that as your first smoke of the day
and see how that works for you make sure
that's the first one you've smoked so
you start off nice and fresh your
palates nice and clean your mind and
your body are still clear and sore and
you can see what kind of effect each
strain have on your body then you've
done an indica dominant you've done a
sativa dominant let's work our way
towards something more hybrid like maybe
try some morning dew smoke a fat bowl of
morning dew first thing the next morning
and see what that does for you one of
those is going to make you throw up one
of those is gonna make you feel better
and one of those you probably won't even
notice
then if none of those provide the relief
and comfort you were looking for that's
where we turn to CBD you may go to CBD
first I'm not sure which route you want
to take I think I know you from our
conversations I'm pretty sure you want
to try these th sea routes first but the
CBD never hurts to try when you do get
your CBD make sure it is from a reliable
source I've given that speech enough
times don't buy your CBD from the gas
station don't buy some [ __ ] get a
quality CBD product spend as much time
energy effort and money on your CBD as
you do your cannabis and you should have
positive results I guess that's not
accurate money doesn't always mean
quality but do the work put in the
effort and you should find a quality
product but again I would recommend find
an indica find a sativa and find a
hybrid and smoke on those and see which
one gives you the relief one may make it
throb if you get a nice sativa you may
get so stoned that you forgot your back
even hurts that is one of the magical
wonders of cannabis it makes you forget
stuff if you get a nice indica it may
make you so relaxed that nothing hurts
also both of those have the opportunity
to really enhance the pain you may get
so stoned that all you can think about
is that [ __ ] leg and that foot and
your neck your back your neck and your
back that may be the only thing you can
focus on so those are the best
recommendations I can make because it is
going to be strained specific body type
specific it is all going to be up to
your body and the flowers that you find
and that is one of my favorite parts
about cannabis also one of the most
frustrating parts about cannabis you
already know that cannabis is going to
help but we have to kind of dial it in
like do you want a sativa do you need an
end because there's a specific Terp or a
specific cannabinoid that helps with
your condition I love that we can go
sour selves since you can't you cannot
die from consuming cannabis you can
smoke as much as you need to to find
relief and you can find that level and
then it's okay to go a little bit past
that level to put yourself in that state
where you almost panic and you feel a
little bit of discomfort and then you
know that's what happens when I go this
far maybe I take three puffs off this
joint and my neck doesn't hurt maybe I
take four puffs off this joint my neck
feels really good that fifth puff I
start getting a little bit giggly by
number six oh [ __ ] I need
call a friend for help you got to learn
how to do that and learn how to get
there but once you learn how to dial in
that medicine you really know how to
take care of yourself with your medicine
you know exactly how often to hit that
bowl how hard to hit it how many puffs
to take I know about every this often I
need about this big of a dad to keep my
body in my mind right where I want them
I think it's about an hour at every hour
so I want a pretty decent-sized chunky
dab and it's just ideal I don't if I
don't get my dab every hour I'm gonna
survive but in an ideal world if I just
could whip out the rig and pull a fat
dab every hour I'd take a decent dab I
think it's come down to about every
three or four hours because of stupid
reality and stuff but you know we
understand how to dose ourselves we
don't have to get a bottle that says
every six hours take one of these pills
now you go to the dispensary and you get
as much as you need and when it's time
to take your medicine you take it if
your budget allows unfortunately sorry
some folks aren't able to do that and if
you're not in a medical state is that's
not an option but that is one of the
great things about cannabis you're not
gonna die from it and you get to learn
your dosage you can find your I always
say that my first dab is medical the
first step makes all the back pain go
away it makes my brain unscramble the
second dab that might be it might be
heavily medicated myself that third dab
that's recreational we're just having
fun with the third one now I'm just
hanging out with Mike trying to talk
some [ __ ] trying to ramble into a
microphone
speaking of rambling let's get my high
ass back on track hey Gramps Richard
memo thank you for the great message
dude don't worry about contributing to
the podcast while you were down take
good care of yourself take care of your
body microphones and podcast equipment
are replaceable your foot your body and
your life only happened once make sure
you take the best care of that while you
can and enjoy it don't stress on me I
will be here when you're better keep
listening to the show and get some good
flowers and just smoke on it bro and if
the flowers don't get you nice and
medicated maybe it's time to move up to
dabs and if dabs aren't available in
your area that's when we start playing
with edibles if you're eating edibles I
think you're an experienced cannabis
consumer but I'm gonna say this one time
go lightly and then work your way up you
cannot uh need those edibles once the
milligrams are in you all you can do is
ride that [ __ ] out
so start lightly maybe ten milligrams if
you're a bigger dude maybe twenty
punch it down wait for some relief
you're either gonna feel it or not in
about 45 to an hour and 15 decide from
there do I need more or not maybe smoke
a bowl at that point if you smoke a bowl
and have that edible in you they're
gonna blend in together they're gonna
kick each other off you may get the
relief you need you're just gonna have
to experiment with what's available I
don't know if you've got a dispensary
around you I don't know if you're an
illegal or a medical state but I'm sure
you're a grown-ass man and you can
figure out how to get the medicine that
you need hopefully you've got a good
friend who's got your back while you're
on one foot and while your neck your
back your neck and your back are out of
commission holy [ __ ] you guys I am super
rambly I do have another email here in
front of me this one is going to trigger
another ramble fest because I do like
this one so let's just jump right into
it this one goes just like this it says
hey there Rasta Jeff dro man 80 here I
caught your guest appearance on the DGC
big shout out to my friends at the dude
gross show this listener found me
through the dude grows podcast if you're
not listening to the dude grow show you
better give them a follow they are on
YouTube that shows available on Apple
podcasts and any other qualified
reputable podcast service the dude grows
show is hosted by my friend the dude
also hosted and/or co-hosted by another
good dude called Scottie real and then
it is kind of technically led by a guy
known as guru there are a lot of
wonderful dudes behind the scenes I
can't even begin to give all of them
shoutouts but they're great friends of
mine and I have made a lot of friends
and earned a lot of followers and fans
through their so big thanks to the DGC
this message goes on it says I always
heard great things about you so anyway
I'm here in trim jail big shout outs all
my friends in trim jail sitting there at
a table let some headphones on or with
the Bluetooth speaker just blasting they
got the podcast going big shout out fist
bump
shout out all my trimmer friends thank
you for keeping those herbs looking
pretty getting them to the shelf the
growers do a lot of work we rely on you
guys to finish up our product big
respect to the trimmers if anybody
trolls you or picks on you for being a
trimmer tell them Rasta Jeff said to eat
a dick you're a badass trimmer we got to
respect the trimmers we would just have
big furry buds without you guys so thank
you let's see there's more I got to keep
moving forward it says Oh
your podcast on while I'm here in trim
jail and man you have me hooked
I don't per se have a question about
growing but my question is what got you
into growing that is a very good
question it goes on to say what pitfalls
did you have upon your grow career and
what did you use as motivation to keep
pushing forward when life didn't go as
you planned and then last but not least
I'm going to become a patreon supporter
within the week and I'm curious what you
recommend from your line very dense
nighttime potent as a high calyx to leaf
ratio height isn't an issue much love
and respect from my brother from another
mother but we share the same holy flower
big shout-out to my friend Rome an ad I
know I read that kind of quickly but
there's a lot to cover here so let's
talk about the patreon you're going to
become a patreon supporter thank you I
appreciate that then you're asking about
a strain recommendation for nighttime
very potent and high calyx to leaf ratio
you were looking for liberation oh gee
my friend that is the strain I would
recommend for you from my lineup
liberation og should be available at
seeds here now.com of course use coupon
code GF y h 10 save yourself a few bucks
at seeds here now dot-com alright enough
advertising and that really wasn't the
question I didn't just plant that in
there let's get to the main part of this
email here my question is what got you
into growing that's a really good spot
to start what got me into growing I have
been around cannabis for as long as I
can remember when I was a little kid I
can remember my uncles and my family
members just smoking a joint at a family
gathering if there was a party if there
was an event if I went somewhere with my
uncle rest in peace to my uncle Eric but
he would always be the one it made that
face to everybody you know when your
stoner friends just look across the room
and you make the big eyes or you shrug
your shoulders and that means I think
it's time to burn one dude do you agree
with me and of course everybody [ __ ]
agrees because when my uncle Eric made
that face everybody knew it is time to
go smoke a [ __ ] joint so I've been
around ganja or cannabis or weed in some
way shape or form as long as I can
remember I can remember about fur
grade approximately that on the back
patio of our little house maybe a little
apartment that we had one of those
little wooden planter boxes and one of
my uncle's was teaching somebody who
lived at my house how to grow weed in
those little planter boxes and I'm
pretty sure this was first grade I had
to be about seven years old because I
remember the building in which we lived
at the time I could see the backyard
very well I remember the neighbors and
know the time so it's about first grade
so I was about seven years old and my
uncle and somebody else are teaching
each other how to grow weed and my
little back patio there and later on in
the day somebody was telling somebody
what to do and I had to chime in and say
no you're telling them wrong I remember
what Eric said Eric said to do it like
this
so everybody looked at me like oh [ __ ]
little man's been paying attention he
kind of caught on he might know what to
do and I always loved this smell of weed
I was just a little kid but I loved it
and I knew that when everybody hung out
and smoked weed it was always chill but
I knew that when people drank I could
see at a young age than when people
drank my family got [ __ ] silly and
out of control when they would drink but
when they would smoke they'd all just
chill out and it was a much better vibe
so as I got older I started watching
everybody else around me smoke and then
one day my buddy Chris was like you want
to hit this and I was like yes and I
just acted like I'd been doing it for a
million years and I took a hit off of
his pipe and I was like that's why
everybody does this like this is it was
time for this [ __ ] to happen and I'm
pretty sure that I'd been getting a
contact buzz just being around my uncles
being in their cars being in their
little dad a little you know all the
stoner dudes have that one room or they
smoke and they just let me hang out in
the room because I was a cool little kid
and they wanted me to be like them and I
[ __ ] em now but that's where I learned
it so eventually one day my buddy Chris
is like smoke this with me and I smoked
and I loved smoking at that point but
shortly after that I moved to Colorado I
was just a kid so I had to move to
Colorado my family moved here started
kind of a they started a new business
here I went to a new school I had to
establish all new friends here and I
moved to Colorado in the middle of the
winter and it was snowy and miserable
and all I got to do was meet my neighbor
across the street who took me to school
and all I did was go to school every day
and then come home and then do my home
and go back to school because it was so
cold and shitty when I moved here and I
hated it because I did not know what how
to dress or how to survive in this cold
and I also didn't know where to get any
weed and my neighbors in my neighborhood
definitely were not little smokers or
stoners or weed heads they were
definitely more square folks eventually
I turned them into stoners but I did not
know where to get weed at the time but
I'd been watching the kids at school
paying attention to who like might look
like their stone or might smell like
their stone or whatever it might smell
like they got some weed on him started
paying attention and then I joined a
band and then one day we went camping
and that was when everybody was like hey
are you cool and I was like [ __ ] I'm the
coolest [ __ ] you know and I'm
like we thought so and they all busted
out their weed maybe a few other things
and I smoked down and I missed it I
missed it so much so I started buying a
lot of weed around here I found the
people you could buy the herb from and
unfortunately they weren't the most
reliable responsible friendly honest
people sometimes your bag would not
weigh even [ __ ] close to what it was
supposed to weigh but sometimes it would
and then I started uh maybe buying so
they wouldn't sell to some people and
some of my friends were afraid to
approach some of these people because of
their appearance but I'm from California
and those guys have the good weed the
guys that were my friends were afraid of
I know that they got the good weed so I
just hit him up I was like I know I'm
from California bro you guys always had
the good weed in California ah you guys
got the good weed out here too and
they're like we got the good weed ese
and I was like I want to buy a lot of it
and so first they sold me a quarter and
then I bought a lot of quarters and so
they are like you need to buy an ounce
so I started buying a lot of ounces and
all my friends were getting weed from me
because they wouldn't mess with those
guys so like that's not our crew and so
I was like I'm not worried about those
guys I'd go buy they're from them and
then sell to all the hippies and then go
back to them and eventually as doing
larger quantities so by this point I am
deeply immersed in the cannabis game and
the statute of limitations has got to be
gone for all this cuz I'm on a good
ramble totally incriminating myself here
I just got deeply immersed into the
cannabis industry the cannabis game the
business then through my music
connections and being in a band I ended
up moving to another state deeper into
the Midwest from Colorado I was a choice
that I made to be in this band and it
was a really good decision
one day while in this
location I was at a friend's house and
my eyes were hit by this really familiar
light spectrum I went whoa what what is
that and went oh he's got a grow light
up there and at this point I had had a
little bit of experience helping other
people run gardens but I'd never ran a
garden by myself I'd been around it
since I was a kid so whenever I saw
plants I was just enthusiastic and my
friends would always want to show off
and show me their grows so I'd been in
several grows and been around it and I'd
done a few little chores and things but
I'd never really been super hands-on and
so at the end of the evening I let
everybody leave and I politely told my
buddy I go hey your metal-halide light
hit me right in the face when I was
doing this part of the day and he goes
oh [ __ ] so you saw my lights and I go
yet no worries he goes no dude if you
saw the lights maybe you can help me and
he took me into his grow space and he
had a problem and I was quickly able to
diagnose that problem I think it was
from being around the plants when I was
a little kid with my family I think I
learned how to identify that problem
from then and it stuck in my head is
like a seven and eight year old kid so
we corrected my buddy's problem and he's
like hey I've got to go out of town for
a couple of days next week
kind of a surprise mission didn't know I
had to go I need somebody to take care
of these plants can you do it and as
like I got you bro so he leaves town I
took care of his plants they came out
amazing
stellar he had to stay gone longer than
anticipated and when the dude came back
he was really anxious to get to his
plants this was before we had all this
internet stuff where I could just send
you a picture with my phone every day
and I don't think we would have been
comfortable doing that because of our
location and because of the time frame
but he came home and he was amazed he's
like bro my plants have never looked
this good before
and he told me he'd give me a little bit
of the crop for helping him he gave me a
nice portion of that crop for helping
him and then I showed him how to trim
even better because I'd been a trimmer
was one I think we all start off as
trimmers you start trimming and then you
earn the respect he showed that you
could do it but I've been trimming a lot
by then so I showed him how to trim real
nicely so I was proud of myself at that
point then we will fast forward several
years because this story is getting long
I found some friends who were trying to
open a dispensary in my neighborhood
they had a lot of great ideas they were
older folks so they were missing a
younger hipper element that could
actually hit this
and put the word on the street that
there was a dispensary out and maybe I
could put some younger hipper vibes into
the dispensary so I started going to
this place and it was just an office
where you would go in and he would
consult with the weird guy and he would
recommend product and you would leave
this man quickly realized that I knew
more about cannabis than him so he asked
me to transplant plants with him the
next day and I didn't realize that that
was basically my application for
becoming an employee with his dispensary
he hired me to be the first budtender
then he hired me to be a helper in the
garden then I told him one day that we
could improve the grow by doing a few
things and he kind of laughed at me and
I said no it would work so he threw some
plants at me and told me go home and
show me so I went to the store about a
very small setup and I built a very
small grow in my house and then I grew
product that was better than his product
and he had been growing for quite a few
years I loved those plants I loved being
around the plants I love being near the
plants and then I got to take that
product to the dispensary and people
would come into the store and they would
buy the flowers that I grew and they
would take it home and they would smoke
it and they would come back two or three
maybe a week later and they would tell
me man I smoked that stuff that you grew
and whatever pain was in my foot or in
my back or in my neck or my neck and my
back that pain went away and the first
time I met these people they would look
sad and in pain like their life wasn't
as good as it could be and then I drew a
product that they smoked it and they
felt better they could put their cane
away
I had a friend leave without his cane he
showed up with his cane and we medicated
him so heavily he got up and walked away
and had to come back and laugh I forgot
my cane dude and he didn't realize how
profound that was like you left your
cane here because of cannabis you were
able to stand up and walk away and
giggle and he'd been a grouchy old
[ __ ] for several years he's gone now
love you bro rest in peace but it's
funny as [ __ ] that that old man forgot
his cane and giggled about it because he
was a crotchety old dude and we smoked
him into oblivion and he smiled and he
forgot that life sucked for him for a
few minutes he was able to enjoy himself
he put away all that [ __ ] he forgot
about his car wreck he forgot about his
divorce he forgot about his pain and
suffering and he in
life and that happened because of a
product that I took some time to nurture
and grow and that nurturing of that
plant nurtured me I feel better for it
it's some focus it slows my brain down
it makes me forget about whatever is
hurting me whatever is paining me so
then I grow that and then I get to smoke
it with my friend and I get to watch him
feel better then imagine how many people
I have smoked with I was a grower I was
a budtender I had the only dispensary
here in my city for like two years
imagine how many people's lives I got to
touch I got to make their quality of
life better by growing a quality product
and also by spending a moment with them
not as a but as a good bud tender then
you didn't just here's an eight I want
fifty bucks it was how are you like as
soon as you walk into my bud room how
are you are you okay are you like I knew
my people by first names I knew about
their families I knew why they were
smoking so I could ask you know how's
that foot has that broken foot feeling
any better is that sciatica healing up
and remember what I sold you last time
did it work for you
here and this was really cool back that
back then in the dispensary we could
smoke in there so I would oftentimes
have a bowl or a joint so it's a hey
this is the new [ __ ] take a puff off of
this and they'd smoke it and you could
immediately watch their pain or their
anxiety just melt away a little bit so
that was I'm rambling a lot because I
have a lot of passion for this but I
guess that is the bottom line of why I
got into this and why I started growing
I was buying product from dispensaries
and buying products and it wasn't up to
par I didn't like it I knew I could do
better and then the owner and grower at
this dispensary challenged me he said if
you think you can do it as good as me go
ahead and do it I knew that if I took my
passion and my education and some books
and some time and energy that I could
create an amazing product and I did that
and I have never looked back I've looked
at improving my garden my grow knowledge
my grow skills every single day what I'm
able to share on here is minimal I know
a lot of stuff but I just have to be
able to put it into a show so I learned
something every day don't think that I
have ever stopped learning that's when
you burnout that's when you fail so that
is what got me into growing I started
growing because of the demand for
cannabis I didn't like paying for it I
didn't like the quality and then I was
challenged somebody said you can't do
as good as me and when you say that to
me I kind of have to show you that yes I
can especially when it came to anything
involved in cannabis because I was a
giant weed nerd I thought I was a weed
expert and so I had to just grow the
best weed ever
and then I saw the results I saw little
old ladies not feel like [ __ ]
I saw athletes with broken knees able to
do athletic [ __ ] again I saw guys with
mental conditions they can't form a
complete sense able to calm down and
have a conversation and actually achieve
a relationship and have friends and
girlfriends so I've seen a lot of great
results from cannabis that's what got me
into it and that is what kept me there
in one word bro the answer to that is
passion I'm sorry it took me 20 minutes
to get to that point so now there is
more to this question what pitfalls did
you have upon your grow career and what
did you use as motivation to keep
pushing forward when life didn't go as
you planned
I do life will never go as planned it
will go kind of the way it should you
can kind of foresee the future and try
to hope and prepare for the best but but
life will never go as planned and
accepting that and being able to flow
with that is one of the biggest
challenges and obstacles to overcome but
once you've accepted the fact that you
have zero control over this life you
don't have any control over tomorrow you
don't have any control over the other
people all you can really control is
what you do and what you put out and how
you react and respond to things once you
accept that and understand that it is so
much easier to just relax and enjoy life
so there have been a lot of pitfalls as
a cannabis grower we've always had to
worry about legalities pitfalls I have
driven up to houses that may allegedly
have had nine to twelve lights in that
house and possibly somewhere between 75
to 100 plants and I may have seen a
bunch of red and blue lights in front of
that house and you just keep going like
you don't know that house even existed
you just drive right past it what did I
lose there 9 to 12 lights bulbs ballast
hoods [ __ ] nutrients equipment
measuring equipment and also however
many [ __ ] plants were in the room and
that house is gone it's not in my name
it's in somebody else's name all the
utilities are in the homeowners name
it's just a rental but you just keep on
driving alleged
you don't even stop so that house is
gone that is one of the pitfalls and
being a cannabis grower also it messes
with relationships because when cannabis
was not legal to grow you had to have
alibis and stories of why you've always
got to go home every 12 hours and water
some [ __ ] plants you got to have an
alibi
of why nobody can come to your house
because it smells like a giant skunk and
diesel fuel factory you've got to have
alibis why nobody can use their restroom
because that's where there are no filter
and all the water equipment is it's the
being a grower can mess up relationships
you have to have an alibi of why you
can't hang out with anybody for like two
weeks because you're trying to trim a
crop and you can't have anybody help you
because nobody knows about it
you just got to disappear and trim all
this [ __ ] and get it dried and cured you
can't ignore it because it's wet weed
and that stuff messes up your mind your
relationships your scheduling it kind of
gives you a little bit of paranoia it'll
make you a little bit weird in your head
so that's one of the major pitfalls also
you've got the risks of getting raided
and all that sort of [ __ ] in the back of
your mind at all times that's a pitfall
so there are things like that been a
major pitfall I talked about that
dispensary that I had with a bunch of
friends Mike was my assistant budtender
I was basically the manager and [ __ ]
I ran that [ __ ] and then one day the
city came in and they said hey guess
what you can't do this anymore
we had established a very functional
business with standard operating
procedures and flows and employees and
we had a lot of things happening the
community was relying on us to supply
medicine I was relying on that place for
a paycheck
we were doing a lot of things together
and then suddenly one day it was gone so
that was a major pitfall everybody had
to reestablish themselves after being
the major force of one dispensary no
other dispensary would hire me because I
was already attached to one place I had
a reputation they all thought I was
coming to sabotage them or do something
wrong when honestly I just needed
employment so I had to reestablish Andry
figure out my life and figure out my
position and I have no complaints or no
problems with that because I really
think that that helped me grow it helped
me move on I think being stuck at that
one dispensary being in that one
position I would have been in that one
position forever I would have just ran
that place and I would still be there
doing the same old thing I think that
change encourages growth so I'm glad
that that happened in a way but that was
a major pitfall
I didn't have my place of employment I
didn't have my place for a community
that wasn't only where I sold cannabis
where I worked that was where I saw
people I got to see the medical
marijuana community we had such a nice
community here that a member of our
medical marijuana community got in big
trouble and had to go to court and as
show support we had about 30 to 50
members of our medical marijuana
community show up at his court case
every single day to go show support for
this man and they were all people that
came to our dispensary that had all
developed a relationship as friends so
that was what we were doing for the
community I missed that that was gone
I had to reinvent that around here we
had to reestablish so we have had a lot
of great pitfalls in the cannabis
industry so those are a couple of great
examples of pitfalls I have had timers
fail I have had equipment fail that
always happens then here's my favorite
part it says what do you use as
motivation to keep pushing forward when
life didn't go as planned
sometimes it wasn't always easy to be as
positive and to stay motivated as it has
become but now I'm a grown man I'm 40
years old I've got 40 years worth of
experience to look back and say hey
shit's been worse than this you've had
worse struggles than this you've had
bigger problems than this and if you
haven't you at least have more skills
and tools to understand how to deal with
the [ __ ] that's coming at you so I just
think that I try to stay positive by
knowing I've been through this and if I
haven't been through this when I get
through the other side of whatever the
struggle is I'm going to have a lot more
skills I'm going to know how to solve
that problem for next time I just think
that basically what doesn't kill me
makes me stronger
and if you don't keep learning every day
what are you doing and if you don't keep
moving every day all you're going to do
is collect dust and nobody needs to sit
there and get dusty so I just use every
day as motivation every mistake is
motivation I have killed so many plants
some on purpose some on accident but
every plant that I killed I made sure to
learn why I killed it how I killed it
and how not to do that dumb [ __ ] again
so I think every mistake every pitfall
instead of using it as all I made a
mistake I use it as a whoop
probably shouldn't do that again and I
try to laugh at a mistake sometimes that
can be frustrating to some people you
just laughed at a major mistake yeah
what do you want me to do flip the table
over and kick some [ __ ] or would you
rather me laugh and go look how bad I
[ __ ] a bad up like we've got a really
serious opportunity in life every day -
laughs - smile - love or you can kick
some [ __ ] you can be angry you could be
mad at some [ __ ] it's all a decision
just choose the right one and we all
know what to choose and if you're on a
bad channel change the channel so at
this point in life what motivates me and
what keeps me going when life doesn't go
my way is knowing that life is never
going to go your way there are millions
of people on this planet I didn't Google
to find out how many there are so
[ __ ] many people on this planet and
how can we expect it to go all of their
way none of us want the same [ __ ] maybe
a little bit we all want peace we all
want to get laid we all want to eat some
food but maybe we all want to get laid
by the same person and that just creates
a problem right there so how can we all
get our own way how can we be so selfish
to expect that the world is going to go
our way we can set ourselves up for
success in small ways we can make our
bubble function the way we need it to
but just realizing and believing that I
can't control anything but me and
sometimes I don't even have full control
over that that makes it so easy to just
get over dumb [ __ ] and realize that most
of it is dumb [ __ ] yes I have had some
struggles this year I had I lost an
uncle who was very close to me but I am
still here and I can't just let that
kill me as well I've got to push on I've
got to make him proud I've got to make
myself proud I've got a lot of stuff to
do trust me I miss my uncle and I love
him I wish he was still here I wish we
could [ __ ] smoke a joint and go see a
concert together but what can I do
I've just got to live on I've got to be
stronger from that and now guess what
when if anybody else in my life passes
I'm a little bit stronger and I've got a
little bit more skill to deal with
losing somebody that I love so just keep
learning get stronger every single
[ __ ] day that's all we can do you
guys this became a really long rambling
podcast there was very little cannabis
conversation in here but this was one of
my favorite episodes that I've gotten to
do in a long time I pressed record and I
talked for 40 minutes without
interruption thank you for hanging out
this was therapy
to me so I appreciate you for being my
friends I appreciate you for listening
I'm gonna start wrapping up the show I
want to give a big shout out to my buddy
dro man 80 I hope I answered your
question cuz I got super rambling on
this podcast big thank you for the
message if anybody else out there would
like to send me an email my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com if you feel like this
episode was educational informative
and/or entertaining and you'd like to
make a financial contribution to the
show you can do so by visiting
www.hp.com forward slash grow from your
heart again you cannot search for the
show all that ramble use the link in the
description also don't forget to check
out our sponsors seeds here now.com
seeds here now.com carries all of your
favorite breeders make sure you use
coupon code Z F YH 10 that's letters G f
YH and the numbers 1 0 you will get
yourself a nice discount at checkout
again that's G f YH 10 at checkout save
yourself a few bucks at seeds here now
dot-com
I would also appreciate it if you
subscribe to my youtube channel it's
really easy go to youtube search for the
growth from your heart podcast click on
subscribe maybe leave some comments on
the videos let me know what you think
about the show I do appreciate that type
of support that is all I've got for you
for this week ladies and gentlemen thank
you thank you thank you for letting me
ramble at you for about 40 minutes I'll
be back in just a couple of days with
fresh new content I want to give a giant
shout out to my buddy Glen jeroni
and until next time take a phat dad and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
I'm taking meds till I choke and he very
nicely medicated high education
I sell tie nails just to get your finger
yeah demonstrated in the oil jump and in
my chair elevated in my wardrobe another
vapor cloud say deepening out
contemplated helps cuz I hate it in it
out I said about in my nosebleed stay
stay up because I don't sleep break my
mom was like god you're so clean make a
protein shake a go eat cake show up it
work a whole week late
still over inks from a smoke weed break
wait Artie told y'all I switch the dad
getting cracking [ __ ] other
suckers gonna get a bash you know I'm
kickin ass ain't got time to take me
this is my Call of Duty's and I don't
play games broadcasting room the border
with the boondocks we drop it like the
water through your rooftop [ __ ]
so it's unfortunate you poos not gonna
change users like to order in a jukebox
my bad this sort of things do not but
nine dabs has been orbiting like moon
rocks flying as if the bar ordering a
gift shop Takas it some breasts that are
torturing the trim time come on Linus to
fight in a strong fire nobody in this
town bodies and my mom likes us and a
boycott and I feel like we're done Amy
went ringtone rappers deserves to be
gone silence
but I don't give a [ __ ] I'm a singing
[ __ ] bro a nice little rough flow and
you can't get enough donations go to
1036 bodied up calling in the back