welcome to the show podcast world it is
time for episode 513 of the growth from
your heart podcast this episode of the
show is brought to you by our friends at
seeds here now.com seeds here now.com
carries all of the industry's favorite
breeders all backed by their
award-winning satisfaction guarantee for
my friends on a tight budget seeds here
now.com offers several packs for under
$30 as well as amazing monthly sales
make sure you use coupon code Z F YH
tenant checkout once again that's G f YH
tent at checkout to save a few more
bucks at seeds here now dot-com
you know I like to start the show by
talking about what I'm smoking today
I've been taking dad's of Malibu pure
cush and Broza from apothecary farms the
label on the package says that this
product contains seventy two point nine
percent THC and eighty four point seven
percent total cannabinoids I'm gonna
crack it open and give you a fresh smell
it smells gassy it smells earthy and it
smells funky and this is one of my
favorite aromas one of my favorite
flavors and I for sure love these Stony
buzz it makes me nice and relaxed makes
me nice and mellow I'm kind of jello
here in the chair while I'm recording
just chilled out not going anywhere
got my shoes off nice and comfy big
shout out to my friends at apothecary
farms for the delicious Malibu pure Kush
ambrosia alright in this episode I'm
going to read a couple of listen or
emails before we get there let's do some
shout outs to a few of our friends who
support the show on patreon let's start
off with the big giant girl from your
heart podcast shout out a thank you and
a fist bump to our friend Meredith how
about a big giant girl from your heart a
podcast shout out thank you high five
and a fist bump to Karen Crawford
let's roll a big old fat joint for our
buddy Sam let's heat up a big fat dab
for my buddy farmer John how about a big
girl from your heart podcast bong rip
from my buddy daddy Hays let's send a
big THANK YOU shout out and a big fat
joint over to my buddy Mason six six two
I always want to send a giant girl from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
and a man-to-man handshake to my buddy
Aldridge I also want to send a big THANK
YOU shout out and a phat dab to my buddy
Carlos B and last but certainly not
least
I want to smoke a big fat growth from
your heart podcast joint with my buddy
Bobby see big shout out big thank you to
everybody who supports the show on
patreon if you are not supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so all you have to do is visit
www.reimaverick.com
patreon all right I've got one more
thing I want to talk about and give
thanks for before I move on to the email
portion of this episode but last week
was my birthday Sunday was officially my
birthday I've been having an amazing
birthday week big shout out big thanks
to all of my friends who've been
spoiling me and spending time with me
and hanging out make sure I'm having a
smile on my face and well fed and
heavily medicated it has been a great
week but the birthday week has continued
it has not slowed down it has not
stopped yet on Wednesday I was hanging
out doing my chores and I got a phone
call from an unfamiliar number I
answered it and they said is this Jeff
and I said that's me and they said hey
it's this guy from Comedy Works I'm not
gonna say its name but he said it's me
from Comedy Works you know why I'm
calling and I said oh [ __ ] did you guys
get me tickets and they said happy
birthday buddy we got you two tickets
for Tom Segura tonight at Comedy Works
and I said holy [ __ ] I live about two
hours from Comedy Works so I had to
regroup my day rearrange my plans that
didn't take much effort but I knew that
my next mission was to call Clint and
make sure that Clint could get off of
work early so that we could travel up to
Denver so I made the quick call I said
Clint bro I've got a major emergency
Comedy Works just called I've got two
tickets to see Tommy Segura tonight I
would love for you to be my buddy for
the show and he said I'll be there bro
so Clint showed up to my house around
3:30 allegedly we may or may not have
gotten a little bit medicated we made
the adventure up to Denver traffic was
kind of a little [ __ ] that night but we
made it right on time I wanted to be at
the parking lot at 6:30 we were there at
6:28
I may or may not have taken a gigantic
dab in the car then we made it into the
Comedy Works venue we were given amazing
seats big shout out big thanks to
all of my friends at Comedy Works Comedy
Works is in my opinion one of the best
to comedy clubs on the planet and they
treat me like a VIP rock star every time
I go there they all remember my name
they greet me by name they all have a
smile on their face they remember what I
order when I get snacks and drinks so
big shout out to that club for taking
such good care of me
big shout out to Comedy Works for
calling me with tickets for my birthday
that was super awesome and super kind of
them I do appreciate that
then also big shout out to Clint for
being able to get off work a little bit
early and make it to an awesome comedy
show Tom Segura made it clear that he
did not have a lot of new material he
just put out a comedy special so he's
got an hour of brand-new material out
there it's available on Netflix really
soon you'll be able to watch that but
when a comedian puts out a special they
don't do that material anymore that's
like old [ __ ] you don't want to go to
the comedy club and see the special that
you just watched on Netflix so he is
working on a brand new hour of material
and he stopped if the Comedy Works in
Denver to run some of his new jokes by
us most of his new material is [ __ ]
hilarious a couple of jokes were kind of
duds but it was even funnier watching
Tom Segura throw out a joke that was
kind of like and that needs work bro but
he would look at the crowd be like is
there something there and it was just
real funny it's a small club so you can
he can see all of our faces it's a real
intimate experience I thought it was
great big thanks to Tom Segura for
dropping into the comedy works on a
Wednesday night just to come run some
new material by us and see if it was
funny dude that [ __ ] was funny also
let's give a big shout-out to Adam
Clayton Holland for being an amazing
opening act that dude crushed it he does
a bit about Guinness beer I'm not gonna
blow any of the bit but that bit is
[ __ ] hilarious dude if you happen to
hear this I was laughing until I was
piss in my pants and then when you do
the bro and the dude voice bro that
could be me you might be doing my voice
that was [ __ ] funny to me then also I
want to give a big shout-out and a thank
you to Brant Tobler Brant Tobler is an
amazing comedian he's from Cheyenne
Wyoming he is now based in Denver
Colorado he's a comedy works
local a Comedy Works regular he does a
lot of works with the Comedy Works crew
a lot of opening work there a lot of
headlining work he has also got a
podcast a big shout out to every
you buddy who performed on the stage
that night they all did an amazing job
you guys I cannot tell you how exciting
it was to get a call from somebody
saying hey bro we got you two tickets to
see Tom Segura tonight because that show
sold out in about 30 seconds I got an
email saying Tommy's gonna go on sale
today at this time make sure you've got
your computer ready I was ready I was
clicking and clicking and clicking and
clicking and by the time I got through
it tickets were sold out so I was really
blessed
I felt really privileged you've gotten
tickets to that show it was a [ __ ]
good time
I'm gonna quit bragging about that let's
take a DAB and then let's read some
emails from our listeners you guys I'm
gonna press pause so you don't have to
listen to the torch and all that
[ __ ] but I am going to take a big
fat dab and want to get back we were
going to read some emails from some
listeners dab something you guys I'll be
right back
[Music]
and that is what it sounds like in my
head right now welcome back everybody I
just took a ridiculous dab of the Malibu
pure Kush kind of feels like I am
swimming underwater while I'm sitting
here at this table feels like I put a
little while has cemented my face down
my eyes are super heavy my arms are
super ridiculously heavy I kinda wish I
had a seatbelt on my chair right now I
think I'm gonna be okay I am going to
move forward to the email portion of
this podcast if anybody out there has a
cannabis culture or cannabis cultivation
question I would love to hear from you
my email address is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com the first email on
today's episode goes just like this it
says hello I am on day 60 a flower with
orange gasm the plants look and smell
amazing my question is does day one of
flowers start the day you flipped it
twelve twelve or when you see the first
flowers my next grow will be lemon
Jeffrey I'm looking forward to that one
I really enjoy your podcast they did not
sign their name I don't know if they
want their name set on the show they
know who they are big shout out big
thank you for the great question I get
this question a lot so I will try to
answer it very clearly right now when
you are working in an indoor environment
day one of flower is when you flip those
lights to twelve twelve or whatever
desired flowering cycle you are going to
work with that is day one that's when
you start counting day one of flower if
I've recommended sixty to seventy days
that is when the day one begins is when
you change the light cycle in most cases
you're not going to see any flowers or
pre flowers until around day ten twelve
fourteen maybe a little bit further in
so if you start counting that as day one
you are already ten twelve or fourteen
days behind schedule you were way off
none of your feed charts are gonna match
none of the recommendations I make are
going to match day one is when you flip
those lights to your twelve twelve or
your eleven thirteen flowering cycle
they wrap this message up by saying my
next grow will be lemon Jeffrey and I
look forward to that one I look forward
to that one as well I hope to see
pictures of the or
Yasim and the lemon Jeffrey you can send
them to me at grow from your heart at
hotmail.com hey thank you for the great
message and I do look forward to those
photos all right let's keep this show
moving the next email
in today's episode goes just like this
it says rasta thank you for the bounty
of information hey you were very welcome
thank you for listening and for all of
the support I recognized your name here
so thank you for the support it goes on
to say I have started collecting and
popping your seeds I really appreciate
that I love that you're popping the
seeds and I really love that people are
collecting the seeds and the genetics
that I have made and created I did not
know that would be a thing when I
started making seeds for people I didn't
know when I put packages out that people
would stash them and hoard them and try
to collect all of them like Pokemon or
baseball cards but I love that people
are trying to catch them all that really
means a lot to me I'm going to keep
going on the email it says while I'm on
a Fino hunt should i top these first run
seed plants or not I normally taught my
clones two to three times will I be
affecting these seed plants by topping
them because I'm looking for the best
one but I'm thinking maybe I should let
them go naturally during the pheno hein
during the pheno hunt my plan was to top
thinking I could get more side growth
for cloning I would love your view on
this topic thank you from Scott from
Clayton Washington hey big shout out to
my new buddy Scott out there in Clayton
Washington let's talk a little bit about
topping or not topping our Fino hunt
plants this is a very good question some
people may not understand what I'm
talking about when it comes to talking
about topping and Fino hunting so let's
do a little bit of a catch up
this person has purchased a pack of
seeds and they're running the seeds they
don't know which of those seeds are
going to be the keepers there may be a
really stellar plant that works really
well for this person's garden or their
medical condition or whatever they are
looking for that plant may be in this
package of seeds
there will be genetic variation amongst
each seed in that package so when we run
a seam pack for the first time our main
goal with that first run is to find the
keeper in that pack that works for you
and you do that by doing what is called
a FINA hunt you grow your seeds you take
notes you take pictures you document the
grow then you harvest those plants and
you smoke them and you document which
one you like the best
hopefully the one that grew the best for
you and produce the best and was the
easiest to function and work with is the
one that smokes the best also but that
is very rarely the case
so this person is going through the
process that we call a phyno hunt they
are going to sprout their seeds they're
going to veg them then they're going to
flower them then they will dry them and
cure them and smoke them and they'll see
which plant works the best for their
needs then they will probably eliminate
the remaining plants and keep that one
plant to work with for the future that
way they can take clones from that one
plant and have a reliable medicine over
and over again they can develop a
relationship with this one plant and
learn how much calcium it likes how much
potassium it likes exactly how long to
flower it you can learn the quirks and
tics of each plant by growing it
multiple times and developing a
relationship with it so this person is
in the process of starting a phyno hunt
now the other part of this question is
do they want to top their plants during
a Fino hunt they don't know what they've
got they would like to see the full
potential of these plants and they don't
want to lessen or degrade the outcome of
these plants by doing any sort of
experimental tactics to them so their
question is should they top these plants
because a top plant will produce more a
top plant will give you if it's done
correctly and properly timed a topped
plant will give you more product more
buds it will also give you more
branching because this listener said
they wanted to top it to create more
branching to get more side growth for
cloning which does make great sense so
the question here is do i top my Fino
hunt plants from seeds when I don't know
what I'm working with but I would still
like to see their full potential now I
did reply through email to this listener
because I did not want them to have to
wait for me to put this podcast together
to get some useful advice out of me what
I said was my quick answer is that if
you intend to top your plants in the
next runs top them as Fino hunters
if you generally don't top your plants
in the next runs don't top them as Fino
hunters so if you do top top them
because that's what you're going to be
doing in your environment we need to
know if these plants work when you top
them if that's what you normally do do
it if it's not what you normally do
don't do it this advice only applies if
you are running a test garden for
yourself if you are running a test grow
for a breeder such as myself or any
other breeder who is gifted you seeds
with the intention of feedback whether
that's in the form of photos or grow
reports or maybe you smoke some of the
finished product with them if you were
running tester seeds for a breeder do
not top them do not do any weird [ __ ] to
them do not do any weird experimentation
on tester seeds put all of the test
seeds in a grow room give them all the
same environment give them all the same
treatment do the exact same thing to all
of them vej them just long enough to
make them grow flower them out
immediately take a lot of photos take a
lot of notes get those notes and photos
to the breeder get them dried and cured
and finished up as soon as possible so
that you can smoke them so that you can
give your breeder a quality smoke report
we want to find out if the seeds we
created are worth a [ __ ] and we need to
know pretty quickly we don't need them
topped and twist it and Lolly popped and
trellis now we don't need 9 weeks worth
of work on a tester plant we want that
done I think you can veg for 3045 days
then flip them in a perfect world my
test seeds are done in 90 to 120 days
for a full cycle that is germination
that is veg that is flower then you cut
them down dry them cure them smoke them
send me reports so if you are running a
Fino hunt for yourself and you're
looking for something that works well
into your garden
due to those Fino hunting plants what
you're going to do to them in your main
garden we need to know how they're going
to perform under that environment but
those seeds you probably paid money for
and we know that they're reliable
they've been tested we know they're not
hermaphrodites we know they're not a
bunch of mutants we know that they're
going to be a good ratio of male to
females in those seeds so those seeds it
is ok to dedicate some time to
some work with them if you want to the
tester seeds don't spend a lot of time
on them because we don't know if those
are hermaphrodites we don't know if
they're mutants those could be all boys
they could just be trash genetics we
don't know what we have created when we
send you testers and we're relying on
the testers to give us quality results
and we really don't want to wait eight
weeks for you to veg a plant out and
mainline it do all kinds of weird [ __ ]
and then we find out you only did two of
them and we sent you twenty seeds we
were really hoping you did twenty of
them side by side just did them real
small don't do a lot of experiments the
experiment is are these worthless [ __ ]
we want to find out if they're any good
so those are two different types of
phenyl hunting environments in both
environments I do recommend you treat
all plants the same if you are phenol
hunting and you feed this plant one
thing and this plant another how do you
know if that plan is better and that
plan is not better that's like giving me
steroids and the guy that I've got a
fight not giving him steroids I'm gonna
kick the [ __ ] out of him cuz I'm on
steroids if you give both of us steroids
it's still a fair fight if you don't
give either one of us steroids it's
still a fair fight I would never take
steroids guys I just picked a weird way
to describe that but when you were doing
phenyl hunts when you were doing testing
feed everything the same treat every
plant the same if you're going to
lollipop one plant volley pop all of the
other plants if you're gonna top one top
all of the others when you do a phenol
hunt or testing keep it scientific make
sure that all of the plants get the same
treatment so we get a reliable outcome
that is my point here so the short
answer is if you are going to top your
plants and all of the future runs top
your phenol hunters if you plan on
letting them grow that one glory bud
don't top them and see how they go with
that one big glory bud and quickly i'll
tell you how i do phenol hunts and i do
them in a couple of different ways if
i'm trying to find a mother plant and i
know that I'm going to keep something
around
I generally veg in three gallon pots I
veg and tell there about just a little
bit taller than my knee I'm a tall
person I'm six foot five so my knee may
be a little bit taller than yours but I
veg until the plants are probably I'm
guessing they're about table high
I've veg until they're the height of
this table at that point I top them I
take the main top out of the plant and
make a clone from that I generally clean
up the bottoms of the plant
just a little bit before flower anyway
so I will take two clones off the
bottoms of each plants and I've got
three clones off of every plant so that
if I do find a keeper I've got three
opportunities to keep that bad dog
around for future runs
so I've edged my original plant to about
knee high I take the top out of it I
make a clone from that top I take two
bottoms off of it I take two clones from
those bottoms now I've got that original
big plant in a three gallon pot now it's
about knee-high I've got three clones
now we've got a decision to make
do we want to flower that big plant or
do we want to flower the clones to find
out what we've got there are pros and
cons to both flowering out that big
plant it's already fetched out it's
already knee-high it's ready to go
you can flower that bad dog out and you
can get a nice amount of flowers off of
that plant and it's already there ready
to go or you can fetch out those clones
and you can get those clones up to the
right size and you can flower those out
and those clones will show you what
you've got now if you flower out that
big plant that came from the seed you've
got a really healthy big vigorous mother
plant that's been cranking out lots of
branches that is already ready to give
you a bunch of clones a lot of people
prefer to keep that seed plant the plant
that came from the original seed as
their mother plant many people prefer
that as their keeper they keep that one
around and take clones from that forever
a lot of people will run that big plant
in the flower room and finish it out
because like I said earlier it's already
got a lot of growth on it it's ready to
go we can flower it at this point why
not put that bad dog in the flower room
flip it get some product out of it then
we've got three clones over here in the
cloner or in the clone dome it will
become our keepers hopefully one out of
three of those root if you're not good
at cutting clones maybe wait until you
see roots on one of your clones before
you put that big plant into flower it's
only gonna be 14 days you can wait that
long hopefully so now you've got three
clones aside you've got a big plant and
flower three of those clones are gonna
grow out one the best one out of that
will become your new mother plant the
other two you can either give them to
your friends you can share the genetics
so the genetics don't get lost or you
can put those in your bedroom you can
grow them out make them your next flower
run now you've got a mother
and you've got to vegging for your next
flower run already if you need to you
can cut clones from all three of those
to fill up the tray that you need and
then you can have a full room of that
one
select cultivar it's all about planning
it's all about making the decision on
which plant you need do you really
prefer to keep that seed plant as your
mother or are you okay with keeping that
best clone as your mother many people in
the cannabis world were stuck on the
idea of genetic drift I've done a
podcast episode on the way that we have
been using the term genetic drift and
what we thought it was that is not
accurate that is not happening in
cannabis so we don't have to worry about
genetic drift if we were trying to
select a mother from a clone you don't
have to worry about that if your clones
were properly cut if everything was
healthy that will not be an issue so I
would personally use my clones as my new
mother I would flower out that big plant
since it's already grown as soon as I
determine if that big plant is a male or
a female if it's male and I don't need
male plants I would pull that male plant
out of the room and get the pot out of
the room I would allow more space for
those females to grow then I would go
and remove those subsequent male clones
from the tray remember we cut three
clones from each plant so if you remove
plant number six you got to go find
three clones that are labeled number six
all three of those need to come from the
dome we don't want those around unless
we do intend to do some breeding so that
is how I would do it I think that since
we've already veg doubt that big plant
let's flower it we don't need to waste
all that time and space getting that
plant that big and then keeping it as a
mother when we can keep a clone as a
mother when we don't even know if we've
got a plant that we want it could be a
boy it may not even be the phenotype
we're looking for so let's flip it let's
see what we've got
and one more little side rant or ending
rant maybe it's a tail rant to add to
this I'm going to say this one more time
but always take a clone from every plant
you grow you are going to be very
heartbroken if you buy a pack of seeds
you run a pack of seeds and you find a
phenotype from my genetics that I have
never seen before and I am blown away by
it and you didn't even take a clone so
before you put your plants into flower
please just take one or two clones
if you're not really good at cloning
make sure those clones have roots before
you put your plants into flour so you've
got a genetic preserve of that plant if
you grow it out and like I said before
maybe it's that one plant that one
specific phenotype that cures an ailment
that has been bugging you for your whole
life and now you could just grow this
one you can roll it up you can smoke it
and now whatever has been bothering you
it stops you've got a full hour maybe
two hours of relief make sure you have
got a clone of that because if you don't
have a clone of that all you're going to
do is be chasing that relief forever
you're gonna know what it felt like
you're gonna remember you're gonna try
to buy more and more packs of seeds in
that and if it's some rare magical
phenotype you may not ever find it again
we try to breed reliable repeatable
phenotypes but this is genetics you're
going to find outliers and if you find
that amazing outlier I can't promise you
it will pop up in a pack of seeds again
so the short version of that long ramble
which I will blame on the Malibu pure
Kush is always take a clone of every
seed you sprout before you put it into
flour because you never know if you've
got the next you might have the next
Girl Scout cookies or the next tangi or
you could have the next Gorilla Glue or
whatever is popular today in the next
gelato you could have the next wedding
cake
you may have the next hitter sitting
right there in your grow room and you
didn't take a clone of it now if you do
fail to take clones we can always
revenge I think I've done a revenge
episode before if not I will put one
together so we can talk about revenge
Keeper plants just in case we did not
get a clone all right Scott I think I'm
more than answered your question I want
to thank you for the great email big
shout out to our buddy Scott D out there
in Clayton Washington thank you for all
the support for the show if you have any
more questions dude please send me an
email I love helping my friends out on
the podcast alright I do have one more
email here in front of me for this
episode let's get right into it it says
hey there Ross - Jeff my name is Brendon
I'm a 20 year old medical patient and
grower in Michigan big shout out to my
new friend Brendon it's a pleasure to
meet your buddy
it says you can use my name if this work
to make it on the podcast well there you
go I said your name a couple of times
I'm glad
got your permission it says I started
listening to your podcast about two
months ago and I really appreciate all
of the knowledge you have given me thus
far thank you man that's a great
compliment thank you for listening keep
it up you have got a lot of catching up
to do
it says I can't tell you how much faster
time goes by in the cubicle when
listening to the growth from your heart
podcast so shout out to you and white
mic for that that is awesome man I love
hearing that I'm helping people pass the
day at a boring job that means a lot to
us and while you're sitting there at
work you are getting paid to become a
better ganja grower so I appreciate that
man thank you
so the message keeps going it says I
have a quick question which I haven't
heard you address in your podcast yet
unless I have missed it I am running
feminised seeds from a reputable breeder
sadly they are not I read genetics but I
recently scored a 6-pack of lemon
Jeffrey and golden goat so I will be
getting I read in the future runs
alright so just to be clear this guy is
growing some feminized seeds from a
reputable breeder which is not I read
genetics but he's got some Irie on deck
for the future now the message goes on
to say I just went into the garden and
one of my feminized plants which has
grown from seed has a few branches that
showed sex within a day or two and have
pre flowers while I have my lights on an
18-6 veg cycle what are the possible
causes and what should I do with this
plant have you ever experienced this
much love from Michigan State I read
some
Brendon all right Brendan I think I have
a couple of ideas what could be going on
in your garden all right so Brendan has
got some feminized seeds in his garden
they are on an 18-6 light cycle which
means they should be continuing to veg
they should not be flowering
unfortunately he has discovered that a
couple of branches have showed sex and
pre flowers while these plants are still
on the 18:6
light cycle so he is curious what
possible causes could have caused this
and what to do with the plant now I
really wish I knew how long these plants
had been vegging I really wish I knew
how much
white these plants were getting and what
type of light they were getting I also
really wish I knew what size container
and what type of soilless mix or cocoa
or soil you were working with and also
what they have been getting fed but
without that information I can give you
a few ideas of what could be happening
the number one guess you may have Auto
flours I cannot support or denied that
claim in any way but they are flowering
under an 18-6 light cycle makes me think
maybe auto flours
I think the only way to determine if
they are actually Auto flours is to keep
an eye on them are they actually going
into full flower or is that just a
little bit of a tease is a little bit of
a pre flower are they giving you signs
because earlier I said I wondered how
much light they were getting are they
getting enough light yes you've got them
on an 18-6 light cycle but if you've got
too many plants crowded in and they're
not getting enough actual light on their
leaves they're not absorbing enough
light the amount of hours which that
grow light is on in your grow room won't
make a difference if the plants are
being shaded by other plants if they're
pressed in too closely together or if
they're just simply too far from the
light source so if they think they are
not getting enough light if they're not
reaching their daily light integral they
will begin to flower simply because
they're not getting enough light energy
and they think that the end of the world
the end of the season is coming so
another reason that these plants may
begin to flower on you is because they
may be root bound what size pot are they
in how long have they been in that pot
if those roots are trying to grow and
they don't have anywhere to go they're
all bound up they're all twisted around
in that pot that plant is gonna say [ __ ]
it I got nothing left to do but flower
I've only got a few weeks left in this
pot before it's gonna be terrible your
plants may be stuck wearing shoes that
are way too small and they may be angry
about it and they just want bigger shoes
and until you give them bigger shoes
they're going to flower imagine if one
day when you were like seven or eight
years old I put some shoes on you I
laced them up real nice I was like those
are your shoes buddy and now you got to
live your whole life in those shoes now
that you're a grown-ass adult those
little kid shoe
are gonna be so super tight and so
uncomfortable that plant has lived its
entire life in that container and it may
be root bound it may be really
uncomfortable its toes are cramped it
has no choice but to flower now just
because that's its final survival
instinct it's like this is what I know
how to do this was my entire goal in
life a cannabis plants main goal is to
reproduce and make more seed for the
next season that's its main goal and it
does that by going into flower the male
plants get taller than the other plants
so they could drop their pollen down on
the females the females get white and
bushy so they can make a lot of bud
sites a lot of pistols they can receive
a lot of pollen they can get pollinated
they can drop seeds for the future the
cannabis plants main goal is to receive
pollen it cannot do that until it goes
into flower so when you stress it you
piss it off it goes this is what I'm
gonna do I'm going to flower because I
need to get out of this situation the
only way I can do that is the flower
then they'll cut me down and smoke me or
I get to make seeds for the next
generation now there are also some
nutrients and things you could spray or
feed to your plants which may trigger
them to flower I've talked about some
products I know that advance nutrients
used to sell up but ignitor
if you accidentally fed that to your veg
plants they would be in flower next week
you couldn't do anything about it you
fed them but ignitor they're switching
get ready go so there are products that
if you accidentally feed those will
possibly potentially make your plants
flip too early if your plants are
stressed if they're not getting fed
enough if they're getting fed too much
if there are more than one or two
stressors on a plant it can make that
plant pre flower I really think your
plant is probably root bound or you
possibly don't have enough light or the
worst case scenario is you ended up with
some accidental auto flower seeds
alright Brendan I hope I answered your
question sufficiently I want to thank
you for the great email if anybody else
out there has a cannabis culture or
cannabis cultivation question I would
love to hear from you my email address
is grow from your heart at hotmail.com
alright ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls pimps and hos friends and foes
chicks and bros smokers growers clone
cutters pollen chuckers all you sexy
[ __ ] out there I want to thank
you guys again
listening to episode 513 of the growth
from your heart podcast if you feel like
this episode was educational informative
or entertaining and you would like to
make a financial contribution to the
show you can do so by visiting
www.disabilitydenials.com end seeds here
now.com seeds here now calm carey seeds
from all of your favorite breeders
they've got miss Jill they've got eye
region etics they've got Duke diamond
they've got all of this stuff you were
looking for go check them out make sure
you use coupon code key fyh ten at
checkout again that's coupon code g FY h
ten at checkout to save a few more bucks
at seeds here now dot-com if you've got
any questions or if you like to sponsor
the show or maybe you've got a product
you'd like me to review you can send me
an email my email address is grow from
your heart at hotmail.com again you know
that i would love to hear from you
ladies and gentlemen that is all I've
got for you for this episode I want to
give a giant shout out to my buddy buzz
bros and until next time take a phat dad
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]