whoa what's up cannabis community I'm
your host Rasta Jeff and it is time for
episode 517 of the Grove from your heart
podcast this episode of the show is
brought to you by our friends at seeds
here now.com seeds here now.com carries
all the industry's favorite breeders
including duke diamond miss Jill
genetics and of course I read genetics
everything at seeds here now.com is
backed by their award-winning
satisfaction guarantee and for my
friends on a tight budget seeds here
now.com offers several packs for under
$30 as well as amazing monthly sales use
coupon code g fyh 10 at checkout to save
a few bucks once again that is coupon
code g fyh 10 at checkout to save a few
bucks at seeds here now dot-com you know
I like to start the podcast off by
talking about what I'm dabbing this
evening I've been taking dad's of cowboy
Kush full-spectrum extract from our
friends at Green Dot labs this is a
blend of H a o G and star dog on the
package the flavor is described as
earthy fuel and leather I'm going to
agree with the earthy the fuel is
certainly there there may be some
leather one thing I am noticing if I
smell this jar and I pull it away from
my face quickly I do get a hint of
strawberries or watermelons and I
believe that is coming from the star dog
if you let the star dog flower for just
a little bit too long it will produce a
little bit of a berry flavor I really
think that this product represents that
strawberry watermelon sort of flavor and
aroma I really enjoy it of course I like
the buzz the most impressive part about
this package it is a four gram container
when I cracked open the jar it is just
one giant diamond in the middle of the
jar with just enough Terp sauce around
it to make it delicious I was really
impressed with the appearance of this
product of course I love the aroma and
I'm sure you can tell by how chatty I am
that I completely love the buzz of the
cowboy Kush full spectrum extract all
right ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls in this episode I am going to do a
lesson on re vegging our flowering
plants did you grow a plant that was
perfect for you the jus
- winner but for some reason you don't
have a clone of that plant and you
really wish you could grow it again I do
have a solution for you there is the
option of revenge before we get to the
lesson on revenge our plants let's do a
shout out to a few of our friends who
support the show on patreon let's start
off with the big girl from your heart
podcast high-five
thank you shout out and a fist bump to
my buddy Godfather cush let's roll up a
big fat joint and give a shout out to my
buddy James Brown let's pack up a big
fresh bull to my buddy Roux lighting Tim
I always want to send a big thank-you
shout out to my friend Michael W of
course let's send a big giant grill from
your heart podcast high-five and a fist
bump to my buddy Blackbird 76 let's roll
up a fat joint for our buddy
okie gross 720 I always wanted to send a
big thank you to my buddy learning and
burnin let's heat up the dab nail and
give a big fat dab to my buddies Steve
Smith I always want to send a big
high-five and a thank you to my buddy
Tommy of course we need to send a big
thank-you shout out to my buddy captain
mojo and last but certainly not least
let's roll up a big fat blunt from my
buddy Nate W big thanks big shoutout to
everybody who supports the show who has
continued to support the show on patreon
I truly do appreciate all of that
support if you'd like to learn how to
support the show all you have to do is
go to www.petland.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need will be
right there on the screen and of course
I did include a link in the show notes
just click on the link it will get you
right where you need to be alright let's
work our way into this grow lesson I
teased it enough we're going to talk
about Reve edging our cannabis plants
before we get into the actual process
let's talk about why we might want to
revenge
a cannabis plant I teased about it
earlier sometimes you may grow a plant
from seed you may grow a plant from
clone and you may realize this is
amazing cannabis this is the plant I've
been searching for my entire life not
all plants are the same not all growers
are the same not all grow environments
are the same to find the perfect plant
for the grower for the room is sometimes
a real it's in a
accomplishment you feel really excited
like I've got the [ __ ] plant for me
this is the one that does what I need
recreationally maybe this is the one
that is doing what I need financially it
probably grows perfectly for you it
smokes beautifully for you it tastes
perfectly it cures your ailments or it's
stacking up your wallet real well
however you're working with it sometimes
you find that perfect plant but then you
realize I didn't take a clone of this
plant then you are heartbroken
sometimes you take a clone of it and the
clones don't root sometimes the clones
die sometimes [ __ ] happens maybe your
helper kills the clones maybe your cat
kills the clones I don't know what
happens but sometimes we grow the most
beautiful plant we've ever seen and we
don't have a clone but we really are
kicking ourselves in the ass wishing
that we've done some sort of
preservation so we can grow that plant
again and that is where Reve edging
comes into play Reve edging happens at
the end of the flowering phase I like to
start Reeve edging around the same time
that I begin flushing a finished crop so
you grow your plants they're almost done
it is almost time to harvest then the
last 10 to 14 days of the flowering
phase we should be flushing our plants
we should just be feeding them clean
water these plants are getting ready for
the harvest phase this is when I like to
begin the re veg process now I do
understand that what I am about to say
is kind of new and unique to some people
and it may freak you out a little bit so
if you don't want to start your revenge
process when you begin the flush phase
that is okay you can start your revenge
process after you have harvested the
rest of the room just save that plant
that you need and most of my
instructions will be basically the same
we will catch up when we get to that
part now we're going to focus on the
revenge phase happening during the flush
phase or the last two weeks of the
flowering cycle the thing that is going
to tell our plants that we want it to
revenge is the light schedule we made
these plants flower by reducing the
light to 12 12 we gave that plant a long
enough dark period to make the plant
think that it is the fall season and it
should go into flower because the end of
its life is near these plants are
accustomed to living for one full cycle
they get one cycle out of life and then
they die
an annual plant they don't come back
they make seeds and those seeds are what
carries on the generation the plants
don't plan on living more than one
season so if we can trigger our plants
into going into the flowering phase by
manipulating the light cycle we can also
trigger these plants to go back into the
vegetative stage by manipulating the
light cycle the opposite direction so
about 10 to 14 days before I plan to
harvest my room I will put my light
cycle back on an 18 and 6 light schedule
now I know that may sound alarming to a
lot of new growers that may sound
alarming to a lot of experienced growers
we want these plants to flower we want
them to keep going we want beautiful
fatties sticky buds with nice trichomes
all over them that is our main goal for
this garden and now I am telling you to
flip your light cycle back to a veg
cycle while you're almost done flowering
I know it sounds crazy I know it sounds
scary
let me explain myself we are 10 to 14
days away from cutting down these plants
remember that when we flip the plants
into flower
it took them approximately 12 to 15 days
before they started flowering these
plants are going to take 10 to 14 days
before they start showing you any
difference that they are trying to go
back into a vegetative state and before
these plants get to that we're going to
cut them down this increased light
period is also going to make the buds
get thicker and fatter and beefier and
chunkier you will actually potentially
increase your harvest weight this may
also potentially speed up your harvest
time by a day or three so pay attention
to the trichomes also pay attention to
the plants if you see them starting to
do any weird things at the tips it'll be
right at the tips of the buds the very
tops of the buds will start to look like
they're getting new growth the minute
you see that it is time to harvest they
are starting to go into a vegetative
state and revenge most plants will not
show you a rebadged growth until about
day 17 maybe day 21 so I think my 10 to
14 day recommendation of increasing the
hours of light will put you in a safe
timeframe if
you harvest in that 10 to 14 day window
again this is plant specific this is
environment specific so pay attention to
your plants if you know the plants you
are growing and you're familiar with
them feel comfortable with that 14 days
if they are new plants and you're not
sure what to expect maybe only go for 10
days but I truly do not think you will
have a problem with any sort of revenge
before harvest if you start this 10 to
14 days before you plan to cut down so
step number one is to increase the
lights if you can increase the lights
from 12 12 or 11 13 if you can put them
back on in 18 6 or perhaps a 19 and 5
light cycle the more light the merrier
at this point that's what I would
recommend
do not go 24 hours of light at this time
I don't find that to be necessary if you
do want to run a 24-hour schedule after
you harvest that is effective but let's
not do it yet until we chop down the
usable part of the plant so now we have
got our plants on an 18-6 perhaps a 19-5
cycle you will notice that the plants
that are closest to the light that are
getting the most light will begin to
revenge the earliest so if you've got
one specific plant which you want to
revenge maybe get that plant in the
middle give it the prime real estate
where it is getting the best optimal
light and that will help speed up your
process now for the next 10 to 14 days
we are on that extended light cycle we
are going to continue to flush the
plants now we need to pay attention to
the trichomes we also need to watch for
that Revenge growth but things should go
just as planned
just like they normally would if we
hadn't changed that light cycle you may
get to harvest one to three days early
not a big deal
pay attention to the trichomes now we
are going to harvest just like normal
except I would recommend to leave some
of the very bottom small buds if you've
got four or five buds on that plant that
are the size of your thumb I've got big
thumbs if they're the size of my thumb
or your thumb that is fine leave
yourself somewhere between three and
five little buds on the bottom of that
plant cut the rest of it off leave those
buds there so that you've just got some
sticks with four or five little buds on
it and that is going to be your new
plant that you are going to focus on
reef edging
plant has already been under an extended
white cycle so it is already beginning
to adjust to that light cycle it knows
inside that we want it to begin Reeve
edging it already is trying to do that
now we have removed all those giant buds
we've just got a little bit of that
plant left it is much easier for that
plant to revert that little tiny batch
of hormones to fix that little tiny part
of that plant instead of trying to
revert that entire plant back to veg so
now we've just got a couple little buds
four or five little buds and they're
going to start Reeve edging they're
going to slowly go back to the veg phase
I mentioned earlier that at this point
if you've got a room where you can do it
you can put this plant under 24/7
lighting you want 24 hours a day
lighting for this plant if you've got
that space if you don't have that space
put it under an 18-6 or a 19-5 veg
schedule and this plant will slowly
begin to grow new growth it will start
to make kind of funky kind of twisted
kind of weird leaves that is what is
expected from a plant that is revenge
you just took a plant and basically put
it through puberty and made that plant
go from a pubescent teenager all the way
to an adult all the way to the point
where it thought it should die and now
you were returning it back to that
prepubescent stage of its life it is
going to make some weird shaped leaves
for a little while it'll look like dill
it'll look like mint it'll make some
really weird leaves don't freak out be
patient that is to be expected
eventually those leaves will grow out
and make shoots they begin to look like
normal cannabis leaves they will look
just like the leaves that drew on that
plant the first time you grew it the
amount of time it is going to take for
this plant to start revenge
depends on several factors the first
factor is genetics where is this plant
from what part of the planet that this
plant originated from how much light
does it expect to get how much light is
it used to getting and then how much
light are you giving it light is
probably the second determining factor
when it comes to a reef edge if you've
got good genetics and you've got enough
light it may revenge much more quickly
than
genetics under weak lights also before I
mentioned turning that light cycle to an
18-6 or a 19-5 while we are in flower if
you did that you are going to be two
weeks ahead of the game as opposed to if
you did not change your light cycle
until you harvest it both methods will
work the second method where we don't
change the light until after harvest is
obviously going to put us two weeks
behind the revenge game so pay attention
to those leaves that's where we were pay
attention to the leaves are gonna start
growing dill looking leaves are gonna
start growing really weird
curly twisty leaves that is okay the
plant is going to freak out for a little
while be patient with the plant while
the plant is freaking out there are a
few things we can do to make it more
comfortable and also speed up this
process one thing to consider is that
this plant has spent its entire life in
the container which it is potted in it
may be useful to repot this plant into a
larger container if this plant was in a
three gallon maybe consider putting it
in a five if it was in a five maybe go
for a seven maybe go for a ten if you
chose the appropriate size pot for that
plant on its first run it should be
greatly rootbound inside that container
by now those roots should fill all of
that space plants that are root bound
want to go into flower they are in panic
mode they're going hey my shoes are too
tight I got to do something and they
start freaking out it will be more
challenging to revenge a plant which is
root bound so a good idea something that
may help you out would be to up pot that
plant into a larger pot and when you
take that pot it's real easy don't be
scared lay the plant on its side shimmy
that pot right off of it then take that
root ball and kind of break it up with
your fingers a little bit and then have
that next container of soil filled about
halfway set your plant right in there
and then just top fill the rest of the
soil on it and then give it a good water
your plant will be happy with you for
giving it new shoes bigger tires a fresh
home just be careful not to break any of
the branches you've only got a couple of
small buds left on there it should be a
fairly easy process
so one useful tip is
two up pot your plant into a larger
container that way it is not root bound
that way it knows hey this guy wants me
to grow more it's expecting a little
more for me then hopefully it will give
it to you another way to get more from
this plant is to begin feeding it a
solid vegetative nutrient mix let's go
back to veg newts we don't want it to
flower
we need nitrogen let's start giving it
vegetative newts and don't forget that
just because you've got a small plant
you still have a large root zone water
that container like you've got a large
root zone it will take a few days for it
to dry but it will be okay keep in mind
that you've got more roots in there then
you've got plant up top think about that
as you were watering don't go drowning
the plant because I said that and then
blame it on me but keep in mind there's
more below the ground than what you see
and that part up top is just a very
small representation of the root ball
hopefully you saw that root zone when
you repot it you know exactly how much
you need the water so now we've got our
plants on an extended light cycle
they're either on eighteen six nineteen
five or twenty four and zero another
thing to keep in mind is the appropriate
spectrum at this time we want to use a
vegetative light maybe you've got a
metal halide light maybe you're using a
ceramic metal halide maybe you're using
an LED it would be ideal to use the
appropriate spectrum more of a blue
light and less of a red light something
geared aimed more at vegetative growth
we were trying to get the plant to go
back into veg so let's give it the
appropriate spectrum guys I'm gonna hit
pause and take a drink I don't let me
lose my place
alright that was quick I'm sure you can
hear my voice mess it up I did not want
that to continue here we go we've got
our extended light cycle we have up
potted our plants now they are on the
way to trying to revenge we are feeding
them vegetative nutrients we want to
give them strong veg newts maybe give
them some type of a kelp product that
will encourage them to revenge and speed
up for you so the plants will continue
to grow they will continue to come out
of that weird growth you'll start like I
said before you'll start seeing weird
leaves come out of your buds just weird
looking oddly shaped leaves they may be
twisty they may be curly they may not go
the right direction let that plant grow
over time it will begin to produce
normal-looking shoots it'll just have
little shoots grow
right out in the bud those shoots will
begin to produce normal-looking leaves
it will kind of look like you just cut a
clone and put a clone right inside one
of your buds and a clone grew out of
your bud and it will begin to make
perfect leaves just like the original
plant did and like I mentioned before I
don't know exactly when to expect this
because this is going to be strain
dependant environment dependent feed
dependent and also it's going to depend
on when you started changing that white
schedule so pay attention
once it starts making good looking
clones come out of the top of the buds
that is when it is time to clone that
plant take that part that looks like a
clone coming out of your bud and simply
clone it snip it off of there and clone
it just like you would any other clone
if you're going into an easy cloner do
it just like you would cut it put a
little snip in the middle dip it in the
cloning gel put it in the easy cloner
and let it rock for four to seven days
you'll start seeing roots if you're
going to put your clone in a rapid
Rooter or a root riot or maybe a rock
wool cube whatever you prefer
take your clone cut that nice 45 degree
angle on there scrape the clone up a
little bit to take off that outer
surface dip it right in your cloning
solution put it in your rapid Rooter put
it in the dome
make sure your rooters are treated and
soaked properly and don't touch it for
four or five days open it up and check
on it and over time whichever method you
choose you will have a beautiful new
clone now what I recommend is that you
take that clone and pot it and treat it
as a mother plant let that plant grow up
and start producing branches and arms
and shoots then use those branches and
arms and shoots as your new clones for
your next crop so let me kind of repeat
that you are going to clone the chute
that grows out of the bud that is going
to become your new mother plant once
that plant creates branches take clones
off of that plant and grow those those
branches and those shoots are ready to
rock you won't see any stress from them
they won't even remember that they were
revenged those plants that you cut
should act just like that original mom
plant that you fell in love with that we
forgot to take clones from so I feel
like I have covered a quick lesson on
rivetting
I'm going to recap really quickly just
to make sure I didn't leave anything out
it all starts before harvest at the
flush time change your lights back to
eighteen six if you can if not that is
understandable we will wait until after
harvest and we will deal with that then
we were going to harvest we were going
to leave somewhere between three and
five little buds at the bottom of the
plant just with the few leaves sticking
off of them so that we've got
opportunity for fresh growth so we have
fixed our lights we have harvested we've
left a few small buds now let's change
the light cycle back to eighteen six or
twenty-four seven
whichever works best for you then up pot
bat plant if you've got the opportunity
the pot the soil and the space I really
recommend that then we've got to feed
these plants a vegetative mix then over
time you'll see that new growths start
coming out pay attention to bat don't
cut off any of that funky [ __ ] just let
it grow the hormones are moving around
the plants doing what it needs to do let
that weird [ __ ] grow
it'll stop happening then eventually
you'll see beautiful new growth coming
out of it
once you see that new growth it looks
normal it looks like the old familiar
plant take a few clones use those clones
as future clone donors we also call
those mother plants but grow those
plants up and take clones off of those
and use those clones as your next crop
so yes you do have to revenge the plant
then you have to clone it then you have
to clone that clone and those clones
will be reliable I feel like those
plants will be back to normal you won't
see any stress or any issues and like I
said before they will not even remember
that the plant they came from had ever
been flowered so that is my quick lesson
on revenge that is my quick recap I hope
you guys followed along I hope I made it
clear if you've got any questions or
concerns please send me an email I would
love to hear from you my email address
is grow from your heart at hotmail.com
I look forward to all of the feedback
ladies and gentlemen this was a fun
episode thanks again for hanging out if
you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
and you'd like to make a financial
contribution to the show once again you
can do so
by visiting www.unityhouston.org a
one-word GFY h10 I check out to save a
few bucks at seeds here now dot-com
don't forget to subscribe to my youtube
channel it's really easy
go to youtube search for the Grove from
your heart podcast click subscribe maybe
leave some comments on some videos let
me know what you think of the show I do
appreciate that type of support ladies
and gentlemen boys and girls pimps and
hoes friends and foes smokers and
growers that is all I have got free for
this episode I'll be back in just a
couple of days with fresh new content I
want to give a giant shout out to my
buddy Jack Green stock and until next
time take of bat dad and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]
[Applause]
side
[Music]
for the time
see
[Music]
now
by the way
[Music]
my mind
for the time
[Music]
I think it's time to
see this is
[Music]
think it's time to leave it all behind
I try to
[Music]
you