welcome to the show cannabis community
it is time for episode 518 of the Grove
from your heart podcast
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff thank you for joining me this
episode of the show is brought to you by
seeds here now.com seeds here now.com
carry seeds from all of the industry's
favorite breeders including duke diamond
miss Jill and of course I read genetics
everything it scenes here now.com is
backed by their 100% satisfaction
guarantee and for my friends on a budget
seeds here now.com offers several packs
for under $30 as well as amazing monthly
deals use coupon code GF wih tenet check
out again that is coupon code G fyh
tenant checkout to save yourself a few
bucks at seeds here now dot-com
you know I like to start the podcast off
by talking about what I'm smoking today
I've been taking dabs of orange skittles
live batter from apothecary farms on the
package it says the product contains
seventy seven point two percent total
cannabinoids the best way I can describe
this product is when I open the jar it
smells like a bag of sour skittles
sitting next to some funky greasy
oranges I love this delicious sour
orange II smell and I absolutely love
the buzz I get from the orange skittles
it makes me nice and talkative it puts
me in a good friendly mood it is going
to be perfect Podcast concentrate so big
shout out to my friends at apothecary
farms for the orange skittles live
batter alright ladies and gentlemen boys
and girls I do have a great show lined
up for you before we get to the main
topic of the show let's do some
shoutouts to a few of the folks who
support us on patreon let's start off by
rolling up a big fat joint for our buddy
med Denver let's send a big shout-out to
zoso jay i always want to send a big
high-five and a fist bump to my buddy
glen jeroni let's roll up a big fat
joint for dick goals i always want to
send a fresh bong ripp over to my buddy
grants memo we've always got a fat dad
for my buddy fat rabbit i always want to
send a big thank-you shout-out on a fist
bump and a handshake to todd kay let's
send a big hug and roll up a fat joint
to grow and granny i always want to send
a big thank-you shoutout and a fat dab
to michael w
and last but certainly not least let's
bake a fresh batch of edibles and send a
big thank-you shoutout to my big buddy
stabby mixed a Burson big thanks big
shoutout to everybody who continues to
support the show on patreon if you would
like to learn how to support the show
all you have to do is visit
www.opm.gov/health
for all of my friends just click on the
show notes or the video description the
link will take you right to patreon all
right I feel like I've got all of the
business handled I like to handle the
business right at the top of the show so
that we can sit back and relax and have
fun on the show and this episode is
going to be extra fun because it is our
birthday episode this episode will come
out on March 26 and on March 28th it
will be the podcasts sixth birthday
that's right the first episode of The
Grove from your heart podcast came out
on March 28th 2014 so we have been doing
this for six years ladies and gentlemen
six years I have not missed a Monday
I've been fairly consistent with the
Thursday's I have been having a great
time and I could not have done it I
would not have done it without you and
all of the support so thank you thanks
for all of the emails thanks for all the
messages thanks for all of the youtube
comments thanks for all the iTunes
comments and extra big thanks for all of
the support on patreon and of course all
of the support with my other endeavors
whatever that is if it's I read genetics
if it's podcasting if it's the Instagram
live stuff thank you guys for all of the
support you guys really make my life
wonderful without you guys my life would
not be what it is and I see it I
appreciate it and I respect it so big
thank you to everybody for the continued
support we recently hit episode 500
which felt like a huge milestone and now
we are at 6 years of podcasting which
feels like another huge milestone I
really see no end in sight you guys I am
going to keep podcasting as long as I've
got a voice a microphone and a couple of
good toys to play with and we've got the
Internet I will keep putting out quality
podcasts so thank you
for the support and look forward to many
more years of continued quality
podcasting I feel like at this point in
time at this state of affairs in this
weird situation in the world
I feel like content providers and
content creators will be a big part of
what get us through these strange times
a lot of our entertainment avenues have
been shut down
we can't go to comedy clubs we can't go
see live music the bars have been closed
the restaurants have been closed we're
all facing weird times because of this
coronavirus so I think that people are
going to turn to podcasts and YouTube
and other forms of entertainment to keep
them sane so I am going to do my best to
keep quality podcasting coming until
there is a major reason for me to stop
they're gonna have to stop me they're
gonna have to take this microphone away
they're gonna have to take my toys away
I'm gonna do it till the end because I
know that people are relying on me not
just to keep their Gardens up to speed
at this point in time we're relying on
each other just for sanity I'm doing
podcasts to fill the time we were doing
a little self quarantine a little social
distancing during that time I won't see
a lot of my friends I won't be going out
and about like I normally do so I will
have more opportunity to sit here and
focus on better podcasting and I'm going
to make an effort to do that because I
know you need that at this time I'm
getting a lot of my social interaction
through social media I do Instagram live
videos I go watch my friends videos I've
been facetiming more we're gonna have to
find better ways safer ways different
ways alternative ways to communicate to
socialize and get our entertainment and
I really feel like it is time for
podcasters and content providers to step
up and fill that gap we're stuck at home
we might as well produce better content
for you so here we are thank you I'm
gonna keep it going
I feel like I've been really ranting on
a couple of episodes lately but we've
been faced with a lot of weird things
and I've got a lot of weird [ __ ] on my
mind and maybe since I'm not getting out
and seeing my friends and my friends
aren't coming here maybe I'm just extra
talkative when I turn on the mic just
got a lot of [ __ ] to say it feels like
these are crazy times you guys and if
you think about it we are a big part of
history if you are here listening to
this podcast you have gotten to see a
lot of
monumental moments in history world
history American history if you're here
listening you are seeing the
legalization of cannabis right now that
is way on the back burner of everybody's
mind for the next couple of weeks but
we're in the midst of nationwide
cannabis legalization it started several
years ago in California then it's slowly
crept through other states then once
California Colorado and Washington all
had major cannabis laws in place and it
was working that's when [ __ ] started
flowing and now I think we have got more
states with positive cannabis laws than
we do states with complete prohibition
so you are witnessing the sweep the
shift the transition of cannabis
legalization nationwide in America you
are getting to see that also if you are
witnessing and you were part of this
coronavirus you were seeing something
that we have never seen before we have
seen many weird tragedies and weird
things and events unfold in the States
and in the world but we've never seen
anything like this so it may seem weird
it may seem uncomfortable it may seem
scary it may just seem like a big joke
to you whatever it seems like pay some
attention because this is a major
historical monumental time we are going
to be talking about this for a hundred
years we're going to be talking about
this to our grandchildren and their
children so pay attention take some
notes just be aware of what's going on
around you because this is a crazy time
now I know I keep saying this but in
these crazy times the most important
thing to do is to be good to one another
and look after each other we can't get
through these crazy times on our own
some crazy [ __ ] people will get
through on their own but most of us need
each other most of us don't want to get
by on our own most of us would rather
put a hand out and help somebody and
have somebody stick their hand out and
help us in return that's the way it
should work so be kind to everybody
right now have a little bit of extra
patience with everybody around you and
remember that everybody is dealing with
this weird situation and we are all
going to deal with it in our own weird
way we don't all respond to situations
similarly that should be
obvious by social media some people are
completely freaking out some people
don't give a [ __ ] and some people are
right there in the middle however you
were choosing to deal with these weird
times with this weird situation keep in
mind that we are all dealing with weird
[ __ ] as well we are all uncomfortable
we're all adjusting our lives and
schedules we've all been cooped up we
all want to make sure we eat we all want
to make sure that our families survive
we all want to stay healthy you're not
the only one let's do our part together
to keep an eye on each other and keep
each other safe and happy and healthy
and let's just be kind to one another in
any and every way that we can you guys
I'm sure that most of my audience most
of my friends most of the irie are me
and the girl from your heart crew
doesn't need to hear that but it's just
a simple reminder sometimes in weird
times we forget the basic [ __ ] the most
important basic [ __ ] is to love one
another and be kind to each other and we
will get through this all right you guys
I feel like I'm [ __ ] super ranty and
super preachy but I also feel like if
it's my responsibility to provide
content and keep people entertained I've
also got to speak the positive message
so there you go that's the message we
can [ __ ] do this we're gonna be just
fine take care of everybody now let's
focus on a cannabis based podcast this
is the part of the show where I start
reading emails sent in from our
listeners if you've got a cannabis
culture or a cannabis cultivation
question I would love to hear from you
my email address is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com
the first email for today's episode goes
just 'like this what up Rasta Jeff if
this makes it to your show feel free to
throw my name out there hey I recognize
your name I think I've said your name on
the show big shout out to our friend
Thor he is back with another question it
says I got a few head scratchers I want
to run by you and see what you think it
starts off with my little brother has
ADHD really badly which he takes
adderall for he's been on adderall
pretty much his whole life it makes him
very irritable and a zombie so I'm in
the works of trying to get my mom to try
him on CBD my question for you is if I
was to run a CBD plant in the same tent
with my other babies would it hurt
anything
I've been holding onto these CBD seeds
for a while now because I'm scared the
CBD will affect my THC content on my
other plants that's a very good question
and you were honestly not the first
person to ask that question I'm gonna
kind of clear up the question for other
listeners our friend Thor here has a
garden with normal cannabis plants where
he is growing to achieve high THC
potency he wants that THC buzz and most
of his garden unfortunately he's got a
family member who was on medication that
makes them a zombie and he's trying to
offer CBD as an alternative and he wants
to take it upon himself to grow that CBD
in his grow tent with his THC rich
plants and he is concerned that that CBD
plant may somehow disrupt or contaminate
his THC garden have no fear my friend
because nothing bad will happen to your
THC crop you will be able to grow your
THC plants right alongside your CBD
plants and everything will be perfectly
happy nothing will go wrong
you are basically growing a different
phenotype of the same type of plant next
to other plants so if you've got I'm
just gonna make up strains if you've got
a rise and you've got golden goat and
you've got oh gee cush in one room when
you add whichever CBD varietal you're
gonna put in there it's going to think
you just put in another oh gee Kush or
another golden goat or another arise
it's basically just like putting another
cannabis plant in there the main
difference is that that plant has bred
to express different cannabinoids the
plants who are familiar with growing if
I bred them if other breeders bred them
we probably bred them to be rich in THC
those plants that are rich in CBD are
the same plants just bred for a
different goal they bred they found
plants with CBD in there then they
isolated those and bred to those again
and repeated the process until they
stabilized that CBD dominant trait so it
is the same type of a plant it will grow
similarly they may have different
characteristics it may want slightly
different things because it is
phenotypically different but it will not
have any adverse effects to your THC
plants a really simple way to think
about this is if you
got a farm full of chickens and you put
a turkey on the farm do your chickens
turn into turkeys everybody just stays
exactly what they are your cannabis
plants are going to continue to produce
that THC rich bud your CBD plants will
begin to produce that CBD rich bud
everything will go just as nature
intended and I think you'll be a happy
camper and I really hope that the CBD
medicine works well for your brother so
we can help out with that ADHD and maybe
kind of we can't take away the adderall
right away I'm not a doctor but maybe we
can minimize that get a little
personality back into them make them a
fun little brother again hopefully that
works for you all right so that is the
first half of the question you can
totally put your CBD rich plants in with
your THC plants nothing will happen
nothing bad will happen if you grow
properly you will have two marvelous
types of medicine they'll work for your
brother and yourself like I said before
if you put a goose in the chicken pan or
if you put a turkey in the cow pen we
don't get different types of animals
everybody stays the same to the best of
my knowledge plants will work just the
same you're definitely not going to
disrupt the THC production or the CBD
production there is another half to this
question I'm super rambling because of
that dad let's keep going it says my
other question is about nutrients I'm
currently trying the advanced nutrients
three-part grow micro and bloom on the
label they advertise that their product
is pH perfect I still check my pH when I
water because I'm not sure if it is safe
to trust do you have any experience with
advanced nutrients and pH perfect
products yes I do have some experience
and some input and some feedback when I
first started taking growing seriously
and was really trying to up my
production I was sold by the advanced
nutrients pitch if you will get 30% more
products just by using all of our
bottles I really thought that that would
work well for me I did achieve that 30%
that they talked about I noticed that my
yields and my harvests were bigger the
thing I did not like about advanced
nutrients and this is just my opinion I
have no hatred for anybody this was just
my experience I ran multiple different
strains in the same room I had cherry
widow in there I had blueberry in there
I had white rhino and
room I had several different varietals
in that room and when I grew them using
advanced nutrients bottled nutrients
most of my flowers looked and smelled
the same once they were harvested there
was not a big variation in my products
and I carefully selected my strains I
had that cherry widow because it's
cherry it's got that really funky cherry
flavor
I had blueberry because it's got a very
distinct blueberry flavor
I had white rhino because it would make
giant buds that were covered and resin
and had this really sweet flavor to it
but in the end of the grow it all looks
like white rhino it all looks like
cherry widow you couldn't tell the buds
apart if you put them in a bag and I
really blame that I really attribute
that to the advance nutrients product
line I don't know exactly what does it I
have my assumptions in my theories I
cannot prove that I'm not going to say
it because I have no science to back it
up but I really think those nutrients
made all of my flowers all of my buds
look smell and taste exactly the same so
now let's talk about the pH perfect part
I don't know the science behind it but
if you mix their nutrients in the proper
ratios they will come out pH perfect at
6.5 if 6.5 is your goal that is a
beautiful process that does save you a
step I would however check every time I
mix my nutrients if it is off that may
indicate that you skipped a bottle or
perhaps it doubled up on a bottle but in
my experience those solutions did mix up
to pH perfect at 6.5 if I used the
appropriate amounts of each product and
if I mixed it appropriately so the claim
of pH perfect does hold up in my
experience the claim of 30% more product
does hold up in my experience the only
downside I noticed from using that line
of products was that most of my flowers
looked smelled and tasted exactly the
same so instead of growing multiple
strains I should have just ran a whole
bunch of one strain to make the entire
room uniform but nobody wants a whole
bunch of one product you would like
variety at least in my circle in my area
people demand variety so that's the way
I had to do it
so the pH did work for me but again I
recommend that you do check your pH
every time you mix just to be safe that
can tell you if you messed up in your
mix I can tell you if you over fed
something if you under fed something
also it's a good way to make sure that
that pH pin is working if something is
off
calibrate the pin then check the
solution again then you know if your pin
or your solution is off you guys make
sure you calibrate your equipment I know
I just went on a wayside road we're
gonna get lost on this side street for a
minute come have fun with me
it's always fun on the side roads make
it a habit to routinely calibrate your
pH meters make it a habit to routinely
clean your pH meter make it a habit to
routinely clean your EC meters clean and
calibrate all of your tools and
equipment also if you've got anything
with a filter in it if you've got an
air-conditioner with a filter clean that
filter on a regular basis every month or
every two weeks should be your standard
cleaning schedule get in there at least
once a month and clean the [ __ ] out of
everything that needs to be cleaned and
also every harvest do a thorough deep
cleaning before you refill the room with
plants if you're running a perpetual
grow there is one area of that grow that
is a [ __ ] mess take a minute to clean
it up before you put the next batch of
plants in there when it comes to
gardening cleanliness is next to
godliness clean that [ __ ] up you're
playing God in there keep it clean so
that's my side rant you guys calibrate
your equipment clean all your equipment
keep everything nice and tidy and nice
and organized a nice clean workspace
makes everything flow so much more
smoothly it helps you keep your tools
your equipment and your thoughts and
your plans and your goals more organized
so calibrate your [ __ ] clean your
filters and just clean up and organize
your gross space it only takes a few
minutes and if you really clean up it'll
save you time in the future you won't
wonder where your scissors are they're
right there you won't wonder where your
pH pen is it's right there right where
it should be clean up after yourself it
will save you so much time in the future
and that scrambling feeling in your
brain will minimize and you can focus
more on the task at hand I need to get
myself back on track speaking of tasks
and there is more to this email it says
where can I find some lemon Geoffrey
genetics and of course the answer to
that is seeds here now dot-com make sure
you use coupon code ten at checkout and
you will save 10% all right he wraps up
the message with your podcast has easily
become my favorite podcast which I
listen to every day also not to mention
it has educated me so much as a grower
so thank you for all of your information
and hard work man that's a great way to
wrap up an email I'm glad that I'm your
favorite podcast I'm glad you're
listening every day I'm glad you're
getting educated man I'm glad you're
becoming a better grower because of the
time I spend talking into a microphone
that means a lot to me people are
getting better at their craft they're
getting better at their passion they're
getting more passionate about it and
also they're making a better product
with that passion so that means a lot to
me thank you that is a huge compliment
you're welcome for all of the
information I feel like I've been given
a serious gift I've got a lot of gifts
the gift to absorb information and learn
so quickly and then also to have been in
the place where cannabis was legalized
where I had all these opportunities I
know that those two things were major
gifts that lined up then also to have
this personality this gift of gab this
uh this inability to shut the [ __ ] up
this constant need to be talking and
teaching and sharing ideas I think that
that is a gift sometimes it's a curse
don't get me wrong but I think I have
harnessed it and turned it into a gift
the gift of being able to learn
something and then also the gift of
being here in Colorado where cannabis
was legalized and then this other gift
of being able to share my ideas
articulately I think that that was
something that was given to me that I am
supposed to use in this exact manner if
I didn't do this I think something would
go wrong like I would just explode I may
spontaneously combust nothing in my
world would be right if I didn't share
this information and this knowledge I
feel like whatever you believe in if
it's God if it's Jesus if it's the son
if you believe in bacon whatever you
believe in I'm gonna go with yours
because it's much easier whatever you
believe in that diet II that creation
gave me this gift and if I didn't use it
it would all
be disrespectful to bacon or the Sun or
whoever you believe in I'm cool with
whatever you believe in I'm pretty
open-minded you know what I'm down with
but it's much more friendly if I just
let you have yours for a moment so
whatever you believe in gave me this
ability and it would be disrespectful
and selfish to bottle it up and not put
that out so thank you for noticing and
thank you for listening thank you for
the great email he wraps up the message
with take a fat dab and give your mom a
hug for me bra from Thor a Thor I am
going to take a gigantic dab as soon as
I wrap up this podcast and I promise you
that the next time I see my mama I will
give her a big old hug and then I'm in
tell her that was from my buddy Thor and
she's gonna be really confused but
that's okay thank you for the great
message bro if anybody else out there
has a cannabis cultivation or a cannabis
culture question you can send me an
email my email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com I would love to
read your question on a future episode
alright ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls pimps and hos friends and foes
smokers and growers all you bad
[ __ ] out there I want to thank
you again for listening to another
episode of The Grove from your heart
podcast I hope you had fun on the
birthday celebration episode I'll be
back in a couple of days with fresh new
content if you feel like this episode
was educational informative or
entertaining and you'd like to make a
financial contribution to the show you
can do so by visiting
www.disabilitydenials.com for you I want
to give a giant shout out to my buddy
lobster Bush and until next time take a
phat dad and give your mom a hug
[Music]
don't you come on
full of mud
[Music]
just science cover and I know my car
will start
[Music]
bass guitar
[Applause]
[Music]
the breeze arose
but
- everyone's
[Music]
with you tonight
to face dancing in the phone
[Music]
shields are
[Applause]
[Music]