[Music]
yeah what's up cannabis Community it's
time for episode 52 of the grow your
heart podcast your source for Cannabis
News education and conversation if
you're a new grower or a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
veteran Dabber if you're a cannabis
activist or if you're just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you thanks
for joining me I'm your host rosta Jeff
I want to send a huge thanks to the
Mystic Roots band thanks a lot for
letting me play your music on the show
guys you're listening to The Mystic
Roots band the song is DJ and a dance
the instrumental version uh the intro I
usually play is called the doggy dub I
wanted to switch it up you know bring
some spice to your life variety is the
spice of life so big shout out to cat
and coot from the Mystic Roots band how
are you guys doing thanks for joining me
coming to you on today was our good
friend Jesse's birthday and it was also
cousin Tat's birthday so I just got home
from uh Jesse and Tat's birthday party
um dude that was a fun party I am not an
alcohol drinker so I left uh when the
alcohol kind of got a little heavy but
uh we retreated back to the Garden of
Weeden and Spence and Maddie and Michael
and Big Mike and myself and Joe hung out
took some dabs after the uh the uh rest
of the party but man big shout out to
Jesse and tater uh I keep calling you
Tater dude your name is Jason what's up
cousin Tater and Uncle Jesse happy
birthday you guys I hope you had as much
fun as I did thanks for uh bringing me
to your party also huge huge shout out
to MD and Spence they had a little
dinner uh at their house before the
party we went to a bowling alley and
tried to bowl but it was too damn
crowded so everyone just ended up in the
bar but uh before that we went to Spence
and mty's and had some food and I'm a
vegetarian and I will not eat anything
with animals or animal products in it
that's just my personal preference I
don't uh you can eat what you want I
don't judge you but I don't eat animals
they were nice enough to make me uh
several uh uh there was an entree for me
they made a portabello a big Portell
mushroom and I put it on a bun and I
called it a Portell mushroom burger I
put a couple slices of avocado some
swiss cheese I put a little bit of onion
on there it was delicious uh they made
some potatoes that were delicious and
some potato Sal or some pasta salad that
was amazing so big huge shout out to
those guys for catering to my picky ass
and taking care of me and my picky diet
that's really cool so shout out to
Spence and Maddie appreciate it you guys
uh thanks for having me at the party
love it love you guys every day so uh
yesterday was Bob Marley's birthday
since we're doing birthday shout outs I
got dreadlocks and I'm a rosta so you
know I love me some Bob Marley big shout
out to Bob Marley um there's a lot of
other rega you guys everyone always
tells me when they see my dreadlocks
their first thing a lot of people says I
love Bob Marley dude there's more reggae
listen to some other reggae check out
some Steel Pulse check out some Morgan
Heritage and if you're into it it's a
little bit different check out some
Bounty Killer and some Capleton and see
where I was inspired to name my strains
from I honored two of my favorite ree
artists actually three of them the kangi
is after szla kangi so check out szla
Bounty Killer and Capleton also and see
where I decided to name some of my
strains that I've read from I'm doing an
episode by myself guys so I'm just going
to be rambling for a little while I've
got some news articles and this will be
the episode where I am going to announce
the winners from episode number 50 so
I'm probably going to probably going to
do that towards the end of the show just
to keep you listening um because that's
how you build suspense and keep people
listening but this is the one so if you
entered the contest on Facebook Andor
Instagram uh this could be the show
where you're going to get excited and
win some [ __ ] so keep listening I'll
tell you the winners in a minute here
before we get that far I have to do this
part this podcast is brought to you by
some of my good friends some of my
favorite people Jesse and burn over at H
gr indoor growing supplies H gr indoor
growing supplies has two locations to
serve Colorado visit the Denver store at
6271 Beach Street or check out the pbl
location on 618 East 4th Street in
beautiful PLO Colorado check out hyro
for competitive pricing and a great
selection of indoor grow supplies hyro
is running a special for the podcast
listeners when you check out at H grro
tell them that you listen to The Grow
from your heart podcast and they will
give you commercial pricing on your
entire order you're going to pay what I
pay when you shop at hyro indoor growing
supplies it's a nice little discount
every penny helps with the way the
economy is is if you can save a little
bit of money on your grow that's
definitely going to help you out so tell
them that you listen to The Grow from
your heart podcast also new to hydro
indor growing supplies they are now
carrying Rocky Mountain worm company
worm castings dude if you've messed with
worm castings before the minute you pick
up this bag of worm castings you will
know that this is a high quality bag of
castings uh nobody paid me to say that I
bought a bag of it myself and it smells
rich like worm casting should it's the
proper color uh I made a little bit of
tea out of it and that tea foamed up
really nice uh it smelled good A lot of
people are going to think I'm gross cuz
I think the the worm tea smells good but
it smelled the way it was supposed to uh
Quality quality worm castings I
apologize for the mic bump right there
that was weird all right so check out Hy
gr indoor growing supplies also big
shout out to Jay and the Rocky Mountain
worm company they are scheduled Jay and
one of his Partners whose first name I
do not know I know his Instagram name
but I don't know his real name Jay from
Rocky Mountain worm company and one of
his partners are scheduled to be here on
this podcast they're supposed to be here
Tuesday afternoon um I think we said
6:00 it might have been 5:00 I'll check
my scheduling but they will be here to
record a podcast so next episode should
be Jay from Rocky Mountain worm company
and we are going to talk about worms and
um environmentally sustainable cannabis
and Organics and we'll see what Jay
brings to the table I'm going to kind of
let them talk and tell us what they want
to
say um and coming up after that I think
we'll be an episode with Jesse talking
about um we want to give a lesson on
light deprivation so that you guys can
get your outdoor crops going a little
bit earlier this year so we're going to
start we're starting to plan more
outdoor lessons I'm just letting you
guys know we got a lot of cool [ __ ]
coming up I'm not slacking off like I
used to I'm trying to get more on top of
the podcast I used to do it week by week
now I'm trying to be a week or two ahead
of myself uh it just feels better and I
feel like I'm bringing you a better show
which I want to keep doing thanks for
listening thanks to somebody told me
that they went back and listened to a
bunch of old episodes and I felt
embarrassed but then they told me don't
be embarrassed because I'm kicking ass
now and they got to see the progression
so that's cool thanks a lot dude the guy
that said that you know who you are one
more ad this podcast is brought to you
by your good friends at Natures green
remedies.com visit Natures green
remedies.com for gag green genetics llat
Labs Sin City rare dankness mile high
can Aventure the Cali Connection MTG iy
genetics and many more trusted Brands
Nature's green remedies is running a
special for our podcast listeners type
in coupon code iy 2015 for 15% off any
order and of course you always get free
priority shipping at naturegreen
remedies.com uh this coupon code is good
through the month of February I don't
know if it's leapy or not so it either
expires on the 28th or the 29th either
way it expires on the 29th get it before
that right I guess that's what you got
to do uh big thanks much shout out big
thanks and much shout out that's silly
uh much respect to Nature's green
remedies for the promotion and the
continued support they've been with us
since the beginning of the show they are
our longest they are our longest running
sponsor so big love to those guys
all right if you guys are interested in
sponsoring the podcast all you have to
do is send me an email it's grow fromy
yourheart hotmail.com and I'll get you
all of the information that you need if
you want to run your ad on one episode I
will do that if you want a continued ad
through a lot of episodes we can do that
if you've got a product that you want to
send me let me play with it and give you
a review on the show I will definitely
do that for you uh I like uh bringing
information to my listeners and that's a
good way to do it as product
reviews so uh where was I I want to take
a minute and read a couple of the
Facebook and Stitcher comments that I
have gotten recently I had to save them
on my phone so I'm searching through the
phone right now to find that come on
iPhone man my iPhone has been slow
lately all right here we
go this uh is a comment that was left on
our iTunes The Grow from your heart
iTunes page this comment was from a
person who calls himself sticky Wiki he
gave us five stars and he says good
recently found the podcast I have
followed iy genetics on IG which is
Instagram I followed iy genetics on
Instagram for a while now and I'm really
enjoying some of these episodes and take
care so right on dude uh sticky Wiki
gave us five stars and loves the show
thanks for listening bro uh thanks for
also thanks for following iire genetics
on Instagram I'm glad to have you on
there go comment on something and I will
follow you show me who you are and I'll
follow you back our next comment was
from a guy named buzzer with a bunch of
Z's he said sweet show five stars and
his comment was thanks for making this
for us um dude you're very welcome
thanks for listening thanks for
commenting uh thanks for showing me that
you appreciate it that makes it all
worth it uh I hope you're growing better
cannabis than you were before and I hope
you have a better understanding of the
cannabis plant the community and uh my
goal of the plant I hope you learned
some stuff and thanks a lot man and then
Robert Lee commented Robert Lee I know
who you are dude thanks for finally
listening to the show I've been trying
to get you to listen to the podcast for
a little while you seem to be uh
reluctant to hear me on the show but
thanks for listening his comment was
left on Stitcher and he said I really
enjoyed this episode very informative
and he left that comment on episode 51
our CBD episode which featured Angela
and my good buddy
Clint if you guys listen to that you
understand why I'm goingon to give a
huge shout out to Angela for letting me
post that entire show without editing
anything that was really cool of her
some of what she said there was kind of
personal and could have been
embarrassing but she's a badass chick
she's a badass woman she deserves more
respect than being called a chick she's
a badass woman and she let me post the
entire conversation without a single
edit so that's really cool thank you I
hope you're listening to this episode
all right so that was the um Stitcher
and in or and iTunes comment S I had a
little bit of a brain fart there I
really appreciate you guys leaving
comments it shows me that you are
listening to the show and um if you hate
the show you can leave a comment because
I haven't gotten the shitty comment yet
and did people just not do that do you
just not you probably skipped it and
don't even want to listen if you you
hated it right you don't even go leave a
shitty review but it makes me feel good
that people are liking it and giving me
lots of good stars please leave me a
review you guys because what that does
is it boosts me up in the iTunes and in
the stitcher rankings and then more
people see the show and then the more
people see the show the more listen and
then the more people grow better
cannabis and the more people have a
better education about cannabis and then
we can dispel a lot of the stupid myths
and rumors and then we can legalize
cannabis worldwide that's that's our I
think that's our goal for now is to
legalize it and grow the best we can
those are our two main objectives if
we're going to assign ourselves main
goals that's it grow the best cannabis
we can and legalize the [ __ ] everywhere
all right I'm really rambly today which
is good because I'm by myself I think
it's time to get into some news
articles our first article has nothing
to do with cannabis well it Loosely has
something to do with cannabis um it's
something that is personal to me and I
found it very entertaining the remaining
members of the Grateful Dead along with
Trey from fish uh I know some of you
guys are going blah blah blah right now
but just give me 10 seconds um there's a
concert in Chicago on the four the third
fourth and fth of July at Soldier Field
in Chicago it is uh celebrating 50 years
of the Grateful Dead it's Mickey Hart
Bill kutzman Phil Les Bob we TR
Anastasio Jeff chimenti Andrew uh Bruce
Hornsby sorry that was hard to read um
they're doing three shows it's all
Grateful Dead music um this article
comes from jambase.com it says if you're
like us you were wondering just how many
mail orders were received for the fail
for fair the well which will bring
together Grateful Dead members Bob wear
Phil Les Mickey Hart and Bill kutzman
along with Trey Anastasio Jeff chimin
and Bruce Hornsby for three nights of
shows in Chicago or the over the Fourth
of July weekend the answer is almost
unbelievable and this is the part I
wanted to talk about uh as a note on the
events website mentions that 60,000 plus
envelopes were received so far uh which
is handling by the company that's
handling their mail order fulfillment so
the tickets only went on sale through
mail order which is um only the people
that know what's up are going to be able
to order the mail order this isn't like
a publicly known thing you got to kind
of be on the
inside they got 60,000 requests just
from the mail order that is amazing
that's crazy this is going to be a huge
event you guys um if you're in Chicago
on the 3D fourth or 5ifth of July make
sure you go check out Soldier Field even
if you don't want to go to the concert
go see what it's like to be on a
Grateful Dead lot the parking lot scene
just go see that hippie scene go see
that community that is um I didn't get
to see the Grateful Dead cuz I'm kind of
I was kind of I was only 15 when Jerry
died I think 15 or 16 but I did see
plenty of fish and fish is kind of at
the time fish kind of took over for the
Grateful Dead Soul uh the The Dead Fish
all of that stuff kind of means
something to me so if you guys go see
that lot go see that show you never know
roster Jeff could be there I have not
committed to anything yet uh go see that
show go check that [ __ ] out dude go see
what it's like it's that's a lot of why
I am who I am and a lot of what made me
who I am and honestly The Strain Chim
dog was discovered in a bag of weed that
was bought on a Grateful Dead parking
lot at a Grateful Dead show that's where
chem dog came from so if there weren't
these silly hippies traveling around
being dead heads chem dog would not
exist and a lot of the strands that we
work with now would not exist most of my
lineup would not exist because a lot of
my stuff is crossed with chem dog anyway
news article here number two uh it says
new regulations on pot Edibles designed
to protect children and adults this was
put out January 30th uh this is actually
from CBS Denver Channel
4 um it says new regulations on pot
Edibles go into effect Sunday those
regulations are designed to protect
children and warn adults about the
potency of marijuana edibles the law is
being put into place by the Colorado
Department of Revenue the agency is
hoping to prevent problems that have put
Colorado's budding retail pot industry
under scrutiny and then there's a
picture of this African student uh and
they're trying to blame a lot of this on
him keep reading uh last year African
student an African an African student in
Wyoming Levi uh I'm just going to say
Levi Tamba CU I'm not sure how to
pronounce that uh Levi TBA died after
eating an entire marijuana infused
cookie and jumping off a hotel balcony
uh there have also been several cases of
children mistaking pot for candy that
means some changes for Edibles including
placing marijuana infused candy and
baked goods in childproof packaging each
individual square of chocolate must be
marked according to how potent it is so
you guys back in the day when you would
buy I can't even pick a brand because I
don't want to like single out of brand
back in the day when you would buy a
large edible of a candy bar it would be
the size of your normal candy bar that
you buy at the gas station or wherever
at the grocery store wherever you get
your candy bar right you would buy that
one candy bar and it would just look it
would be it would be in a wrapper that
was plainly marked this is a ganja candy
bar but then once you open it you can't
tell it all and now every single piece
they have made a mold that you pour your
chocolate into not you but the companies
they pour their chocolate into there
and it m it divides it for you into
little squares and they're showing a
picture of it the whole candy bar is 100
milligrams but now they've divided it
into 10 little squares and they're all
labeled 10 uh milligrams THC for each
little square so now it's it's a little
better because sometimes when you buy
Edibles uh you don't remember if what
you bought or you don't remember which
is which or sometimes uh the it's hard
to tell if this is a third or if this is
a quarter so now these guys have really
made it nice and easy for you I'll keep
reading the article it's says at The
Incredibles Edibles shop they Mark each
square of chocolate with the number 10
to indicate 10 Mig of THC the
psychoactive ingredient of marijuana 10
is the standard
serving uh in the past Chocolate didn't
have to indicate the amount of THC in
each bar some of them were in line with
what industry feels will improve I'm
going to start that sense again I'm
sorry some of them are in line with what
the industry feels will improve safety
out there others seem like Overkill but
we were happy to do it said incredible
spokesman Bob Asino uh some clerks
working at retail pot shops have been
recommending much more which could cause
some issues with those who had not had
much experience with Edibles now edible
packaging contains warnings to eat only
a small amount and then wait before
eating more so it says wait 45 minutes
so when you eat this wait 40 this is a
weirdly worded article so it says wait
45 minutes so when you eat this wait 45
minutes to see how it affects you and
then you can continue with another dose
if you really wanted to says Sweet Leaf
spokeswoman uh Elizabeth
D that's a long last name Elizabeth D I
won't butcher that for you so they're
showing a picture of the package and it
totally shows like a little it says to
educate and to medicate and there's like
a little clock on there like the one
that you'd see at the store that says be
back in 10 minutes instead it shows it
says take one square wait two hours so
they're trying to encourage you to take
one and wait two hours the problem is a
lot of people don't dude they think
they're badasses and they can just eat
it all but back into the article a
variety of the marijuana infused
products includes including drinks
cookies and cies come in single servings
we just want to educate people that 5
Mig is a good serving not too much not
over the top make it safe said Elizabeth
I can't read her last name I'm sorry
it's long uh this is the first step in
regulation for the Edibles industry this
is a good idea you guys but something I
wanted to bring up uh this is going to
crush a couple of companies I'm sure
because this came up quickly and it had
to happen I think it went into effect on
the first of this month and they didn't
get a lot of time people people had to
pull product that they have already made
already have packaged they had to pull
it all off the shelf and then they had
to repackage it or I don't know if they
were even allowed to repackage it
because if the pieces weren't properly
labeled they had to destroy those candy
bars so I'm certain that this put at
least one or two small businesses out of
business because of these new
regulations they keep pushing on
us I kind of agree with the whole
situation
because um well I work at the dispensary
and I hang out with people that work
there all day and we insist to people
just take this and they laugh like
they're going to be able like they're
Superman and they don't realize what
they're buying is proper like they're
used to buying brownies that their
cousin made or that their Stoner Uncle
made and they weren't that potent so
they're buying these medical Edibles and
they're just getting or they're wreck
edibles but I mean they're made by the
same people to make medical they're
buying these quality Edibles and they're
just getting [ __ ] up so I kind of like
the idea that we're marking them each
piece but it's hard for I'm sure it's
hard for a business to keep itself going
when every month there's a new
regulation they're like oh you guys put
all those stripes on the package now you
have to put the stripes plus a hologram
you know so that's going to crush
somebody all right let's get into
another news article because that one is
boring as [ __ ] this one is from the
Cannabis what's up to the Cannabis they
read a lot of their stuff this article
is by David magoya he's a writer for The
Denver Post the headline says Oregon's M
Bank pulls out of Colorado a week after
taking on pot accounts a lot of you are
going to say say what but I'll catch you
up to speed it says the Oregon Community
Bank that a week ago openly welcomed
Colorado marijuana industry customers
has changed its mind publicly saying it
doesn't have the infrastructure to
handle the overwhelming response for
service but people familiar with the
move say the retreat was pressed by
Federal Banking Regulators who stepped
in late last week to tell mbank
Executives that Crossing several states
to work with an with an industry that
remains illegal under federal law was
simply too risky following national
press the volume of inquiries in or
Washington and Colorado has been so
overwhelming that we don't currently
have the INF infrastructure to
adequately support all of these
customers and Bank CEO Jeff Baker said
Monday Colorado is the furthest from our
market area and the most difficult to
provide the quality customer service to
there are nearly 2200 pot retail
manufacturing and grow businesses in
Colorado according to the State
Licensing data the bank will continue to
serve legal marijuana businesses in
Oregon and Washington baker said
industry insiders said the pullback was
not unexpected we've become accustomed
to our banking Solutions not actually
working out said Michael Elliot
executive director of the marijuana
Industry Group after all uh after all
after they got all that press I was
wondering if they'd get increased
scrutiny and pressure as a result just
like all the other banks have part of
the issue baker said was M bank's lack
of Colorado uh M bank's lack of a
Colorado branch which would require
approval from the state banking
authorities it did not need approval to
accept deposits from Colorado businesses
so they're just searching for loopholes
to not want to do business with us all
right it says without Branch cash
deposits millions of dollars that often
must be treated uh with cleaners such as
fze to remove the pungent marijuana
smell would have to be made at a Federal
Reserve Bank such as one located in
downtown Denver from there deposits
would be electronically credited to M
bank's accounts then to its marijuana
business depositors founded in 1995 the
$165 million bank has three orgon
locations in and around Portland it
nearly closed in 2009 following a string
of problems that ranged from inadequate
board management to a balance a balance
sheet weigh God I can't even read I'm
sorry you guys that range from
inadequate board management to a balance
sheet weighed down by toxic and poorly
performing loans that was hard to say
dude I'm going to take a dab here after
this article trust me all right baker
said the five Colorado based marijuana
business accounts that were open will
most likely be closed I'm not 100% on
that but we're reviewing it another
another 60 inquiries from Colorado pot
shop owners will be sheld he said when
mbank went public with its desire to
bank the marijuana sector last week it's
brazenness raised industry eyebrows
banking Regulators such as the Federal
Deposit Insurance Corporation which
oversees mbank have have frowned on
institutions that are overt about
working with legal cannabis businesses
Colorado's legal pot businesses have
long lamented that their accounts are
closed as soon as uh okay as soon as
where they are banking becomes public
that was odd uh this is exactly the
reason why the marijuana industry cannot
say who they have a bank account with
and why the banks don't want it public
Elliot said Baker sidestepped the
question about whether the FDIC the
agency he said offered its tactic
approval to the idea only a week ago
that pushed mbank out of control out of
Colorado we are regulated by the
government and the expectation is that
we run our bank in a safe and sound
matter in the event we don't we Face
severe repercussions from our Regulators
baker said certainly regul ERS influence
our decisions but It ultimately is our
call so they were definitely co-worked
into it by the FDIC they don't want the
feds don't want cannabis money they
don't want us to be able to bank I
think all right I'll continue with the
article sorry I needed a drink others
familiar with the outcome of the FDIC
frowned at the public nature of M bank's
move making it unclear whether the plan
would have met approval had it not been
so uh well publicized The Regulators
have the gun and all the bullets said
One banking Insider who is familiar with
the FDI and its methods any of us who
have survived the financial crisis knows
exactly how this works if we're not team
players our life becomes
miserable Colorado has had several
efforts at banking at banking the
marijuana industry go a ride the most
recent a long delay in the opening of
the fourth Corner Credit Union the
world's first credit union created
specifically for the pot industry had
expected to open at the new year but it
has not yet been granted a master
account by the Federal Reserve Bank in
Kansas City so there are already two 2
months almost 3 months behind in getting
that open because the feds don't want us
to put our money in the banks so that we
can have it on us when they rate US
that's why they can take it all from us
all right I'll keep reading a move last
year by the Colorado legislature uh set
the stage for banking for a banking
Cooperative similar to a credit union
but has made no progress despite
numerous discussions that's because it
too would require the same master
account necessary to access the nation's
money system Colorado Springs State Bank
the last Colorado bank to open work with
the marijuana industry closed about 300
accounts in late 2011 that made concerns
of working with companies that violate
federal law baker said he'll likely
revisit the Colorado plan but it might
take some time the position of state and
federal Regulators is that they do not
OB to banking services being provided to
the Cannabis industry he said however
they absolutely expect the development
of strong programs time and experience
will allow programs to become stronger
uh it doesn't sound like they want to
work with us at all to tell you the
truth um these dispensaries are making a
lot of money and without having a bank
uh I see how difficult it can be because
other businesses don't want to be paid
in cash like whatever businesses are
attached to your dispensary I don't want
to if you have a you have to have a
security guard all day long so you have
to pay for security service the security
service does not want to be paid in cash
uh all of the dispensary customers paid
in cash so now the dispensary is sitting
on a [ __ ] ton of cash they have to turn
that into some sort of of currency that
they can pay the electricity they got to
pay payroll they've got to pay the
accountant they got to pay the lawyer
they've got to pay the employees they
got to pay the master grower they got to
buy nutrients you know so it's a pain in
the ass to deal with this guys I'm going
to press pause for a second I'm going to
take a drink and a dab and I'll be right
back with you hold on all right guys
thanks for letting me get a quick drink
I needed that was getting all dried out
all right I got a couple more news
articles and then we're going to get to
the part that everyone's waiting for I
going to give away some prizes some
prizes just bear with me through a
couple more articles I'm building up
suspense that's all I've got another
article in a minute that's going to come
from my hometown so that's a little bit
interesting I'm going to click over and
see how long we' been going at this 25
minutes yeah couple more articles and
I'll give away the prizes and I'll get
out of here let you guys get back onto
your
day um let's see this article is from
Ricardo Baka from the Cannabis once
again it says $573 million in pot sales
here are 12 stats that Define the year
in marijuana so a couple a couple
episodes ago Spence and matd came on and
we talked about the year in review and
then in episode 50 we talked about live
resin kind of being one of the big dicks
of the year uh the Cannabis went and put
together their 12 stats of the Year I'll
read most of these I probably won't read
all 12 of them because I want to get to
the prizes you guys the first one says
number one
130.3 metric tons that's Colorado's
annual demand for marijuana equal to
36.8 million es of cannabis flour so
every year can Colorado sells Andor
smokes 36.8 million es that's a lot of
es um if you're buying them at a shop
that's averaging you about $65 to $70 e
that's a lot of freaking money we're
bringing in it says makes you wonder how
many Colorado how many Colorado on use
regularly uh the answer to that is
485,000 that's the number of adults who
are 21 and older using marijuana
regularly which they account for at
least once a month
and it's about 9% of the state's
population and then it says and what
about those using more often than that
23% that's the amount of that's the
amount of Colorado's user population
that consumes cannabis nearly daily so
if you're in my club 23% of us we're in
the 23 club we smoke cannabis on a daily
basis uh but what about the out of state
tourists visiting Colorado that purchase
legal weed
90% that's the amount of recreational
pot sales out of state tourists are
responsible for at shops in Mountain
Town Resort communities so they're
saying places like bre and Vil uh 90% of
pot sales are from outof State tourists
in my neighborhood in our area what we
have observed I'm going to say about 70%
of the people that stop into the spot
dispensary are from out of state and I'm
going to say 50% of the people are from
Texas that's just what we have observed
uh being in the place a lot the uh next
one says but how much of Colorado's
annual demand are these tourists
actually buying 7% That's the amount of
Colorado's annual pot demand purchased
by outof state
tourists um 9% is the price drop on a
recreational eighth of marijuana at a
dozen prominent Colorado shops since the
1st of January so an eth has gone from
$55 or $
5388 to
$48.95 is how much the price is have
dropped I'm going to skip over a couple
of these cuz they're just ridiculous
numbers
um so jeez is that 20 is that a million
okay 246
m810
5993 is the state's total recreational
marijuana sales as counted from January
to October uh because November and
December data was not available at the
time of this article from the Colorado
Department of Revenue so $2 46 million
you guys that's nine digits you got your
hundreds you got your thousands your 100
thou your 10 thousands your 100,000 then
you got these other three digits over
here there's two commas in that sets of
money that's a lot of damn money so of
course you're going to ask what about
Total Medical sales uh
m716
27359 can you guys fathom that much
money that's $9 digits that's a lot of
money dude that's Colorado's total
medical marijuana sales also from
January to October uh somebody do some
math on that that's uh
five
560 $572 million dude $572 million we
made on cannabis legal cannabis
sales gosh that's a lot of money imagine
where that was going before we had legal
ized cannabis of course A lot of it is
coming from out of state people and
stuff but imagine where that money was
going before we had legalized cannabis
where was that going what was happening
with it um so the next number is 103,104
he's going to go I believe you cuz he's
a doctor and he's compassionate so hell
yeah use that one it hurts pick a spot
and say it hurts um 600 or $ 60.1
million that's the amount of col the
amount Colorado has brought in Via taxes
licenses and fees on recreational and
medical Mar I'm not going to say
marijuana recreational and medical
cannabis from January to October so $6.1
million has been brought into the state
of Colorado just from taxes licenses and
fees nothing was sold no product passed
hands that way simply licensing and
taxing people 60.1
million oh my goodness all right what
about the cannabis infused Edibles the
cookies and gummies and brownies that
proved to be surprisingly popular in
this first year of recreational sales
and then the answer is 10 milligrams of
THC that's the state's standard single
serving size for marijuana edibles with
100 Mig maximum allowed in an
individually packaged product being sold
recreationally um 100 mgram incredible
bar is fine there's nothing you don't
need more than that if you're from out
of state and you're coming here and
you're going to buy a 100 milligram
edible you're good don't eat that whole
thing I see that that is a a decent a
decent amount 100 milligrams is a good
limit and you can buy multiple of those
because you're allowed up to uh if
you're out of state you're allowed up to
seven grams of cannabis you're allowed
to divide that into milligrams however
Mill many milligrams are in that candy
bar you can get that many
so um here's a neat fact it says and did
any of these Edibles end up making for a
crazy Halloween as some thought they
would and then the response is zero
that's the number of reports of THC
laced candy given to trick-or-treaters
on Halloween regardless of widespread
concern that legal marijuana would lead
to pot laced candies in children's
Halloween
Halls yeah nobody got ganja Edibles
because they're expensive and because if
you bought it you probably ate it
yourself and didn't want to give it to
some kid so those are 12 interesting
facts uh statistics I guess they are
from the state of Colorado for the first
year of legal cannabis and I've got one
more article this comes from uh part of
this happened in my hometown in the
lovely lovely town of peblo
Colorado um this is why I have said stop
shipping cannabis because this dude got
caught and he is going to get [ __ ] and
then he'll probably get [ __ ] after
that but I'm not going to go there um
the articles from the Cannabis and it
says police found
$63,000 in marijuana and pot products in
a UPS package and then the headline is
Pablo Police Texas man arrested after
trying to ship 63k of marijuana there's
a picture of a table with uh it looks
like this dude has a bunch of eights and
they're rolled up oh no those are
probably ounces those are ounces it
looks like I'm trying to zoom in here
he's got ounces and they're wrapped up
and then those ounces are all shoved
into bags and it looks like he's got 1
two three four of those ounces per bag
and then he's got 1 2 3 four five
they're like eight of them on the table
and whatever I just push made the thing
refresh but yeah he's got several pounds
there and then there's another picture
of a bunch of Edibles uh there's a
monkey bar on there which is one of my
favorite Edibles there's a bunch of uh a
bunch of really popular Edibles there's
some Aatma
concentrates so it looks like this dude
was trying to send the goods back to
Texas and let's read about what happened
to him this article is by Jesse Paul
from The Denver Post I found founded on
the Cannabis it says a Texas man was
arrested Wednesday on suspicion of
trying to send himself an estimated
$63,000 in marijuana and marijuana
products some of which was legally
purchased uh from poblo back home um and
I'm curious because they say
$63,000 is that Texas price or was that
the price at the dispensary when he
bought it or is that street price or is
that DEA markup price I'm curious um
should I say this guy's name I don't
want to say his name I'll read his name
in the article I don't want to cuz makes
him popular he's going to get credit
Johnny Wolf was arrested by the San
Angelo Police Department in Texas at his
residence and is being held at the Tom
Green County jail in lie of a
$100,000 cash only Bond Pueblo Police
said wolf has been charged with
possession of marijuano with intent to
distribute here's where the article gets
interesting to me uh police in Pablo
began investigating investigating wolf
early last month after United Parcel
Service employees reported receiving a
package that was suspicious the package
was sent by wolf out of peblo to himself
at an address in San Angelo Texas uh I
want to know what makes a a package
suspicious because uh they show a
picture of this guy and this dude's got
long hair and he looks like he'd be a
Rowdy Texas Troublemaker sorry dude I
just called you out but you do man you
got that long hair I got dreadlocks too
bro I know what it's like but you look
like [ __ ] trouble I wonder if that
was all it took to make him suspicious
that and the fact that he sent the uh
package to himself in Texas uh he's like
I'm Justin wolf and I want to send this
to Justin wolf that might have been it
but I'll keep reading it says inside
police found several double vacuum
sealed packages with a total of nine
pounds of high-grade marijuana police
said investigators say the package also
had cannabis Edibles cough syrup skin
patches and wax concentrate that had
been legally purchased from two separate
dispensaries in poblo
Colorado Police estimate the marijuana
to be worth $58,000 and the Cannabis
products worth to be $5,000 BL BL police
say they drafted a warrant on Tuesday
for wolf's arrest and contacted police
in Texas who arrested him I actually
read this article somewhere else um they
said that they already have a team in
Texas that works on this so they the way
they just called their Bros you know hey
we got another one guys and they just
went and picked him up so my point the
reason I'm reading this article stop
[ __ ] shipping things out of state you
guys you're [ __ ] it up for Colorado
we've got a good thing here if you want
some weed come get it and enjoy it while
you're here if you want weed while
you're at home in Texas or North
Carolina or Alabama or [ __ ] Arkansas
do what you got to do to make cannabis
legal there don't come here and mail
yourself some [ __ ] to your state and
[ __ ] it up for us and you're [ __ ] it
up for yourself because you're going to
go to jail and you're thwarting your
legalization efforts in your own place
you could have spent that energy that
time and that money legalizing cannabis
where you are that's my rant on that
don't don't send [ __ ] in the mail dude
it's dumb this guy is going to go to
prison and he's got long hair and he's a
skinny white dude
I he will not do well in prison we're
the same build I don't want to go to
prison it's not going to be fun don't
chip some [ __ ] you guys all right I'll
quit bitching at you about shipping [ __ ]
because most of the people that listen
to the show aren't the people that are
going to ship some stuff anyway so I'll
quit bitching at you I guess it is time
to get to the fun part let's see how
long the show has been going we're 37
minutes in and I haven't given out any
prizes yet oh my god let's do this all
right I read that part I read that part
I read that part here we go let's get to
this paper are you guys ready for this
somebody answer me all right so on
episode 50 we uh gave some instructions
on how you guys could win some great
prizes I'm gonna go from the bottom
here um on Instagram I posted an iy hat
pin so this these are I'm just going to
do it kind of quickly these are the
Instagram Prize winners going from the
bottom the iy Hat pin Was Won by not you
again
883 iy hatpin not you again 83 from
Instagram
the Highly Educated titanium t-shirt Was
Won by
Logistics the white iy genetics t-shirt
in large the winner is Bob
renit the black iy genetics t-shirt in
extra large is won by dabin mile high
The Garden of weed and package which
features a sweet pendant by ghost cat
glass a garden of Weeden t-shirt and
some stickers that is won by roster
Ralph congratulations roster Ralph I
will say this guys roster Ralph is a
friend of ours I know him but the the
contest said uh put a reason why you
should win this and honestly roster
Ralph wrote the best reason why he
should win that prize dude so roster
Ralph wins um our second prize winner
this is the one that is going to be
exciting the second prize winner on
Instagram this is the nutrient package
without the gashi and the ogt this is
the second prize not the grand prize you
guys so the winner of the second prize
package from Instagram is Nate mcvillain
so congratulations to all of my
Instagram winners Nate mcvillain roster
Ralph dab in High Bob renit Logistics
and not you again 83 here's what you do
to claim your prize I need you to email
me at grow fromy yourheart hotmail.com
tell me your Instagram name so I know
who the hell you are give me your real
name and your mailing address and I will
get these prizes to you as soon as I can
it may be it's going to be a little bit
because I'm going to try to mail all of
them at once so I don't have to keep
going to the post office but as soon as
you guys get me all your info I can get
all the packages out so Nate mcvillain
roster Ralph dabin mile
Bob renit Logistics and not you again 83
send me your mailing information
congratulations you've got some prizes
coming to you all right now let's do the
Facebook winners if you guys enter the
contest on Facebook you should be paying
attention the iy genetics hat pin will
go to Mr Stewart Coleman the large iy
genetics t-shirt goes to my friend Jake
Henry I don't know Jake but he's my
friend now uh the extra- large t-shirt
goes to Jason box the second place prize
this is the prize package without the
grow Kashi and the ogt um this has I
don't remember what's in there I'm not
going to try to Rattle it off there's
stickers there's nutrients there's a
whole bunch of heavy 16 [ __ ] in there
it's a great Prize Package the winner is
Fred Garvin is the winner of the second
place prize package from Facebook so
Fred Garvin Jason box Jake Henry and
steuart Coleman please email me grow
from yourheart
hotmail.com um I've already got your
real name here just uh tell me who you
are give me your name and a shipping
address where I can send these packages
too and I will get them to you uh don't
worry about where I'm shipping it
because honestly this is all just grow
merchandise or grow equipment uh
merchandise gifts there's there will not
be any IR gentic seeds in here I promise
you we just read an article about
shipping [ __ ] I think seeds would be
just as bad probably get me in just as
much
trouble so you guys want to know who won
the grand prize right how do I build
suspense I just go I tell you what's in
there there's a bag of ogt there's a big
ass bag of Gro Kashi there are so many
bottles of nutrients there's a bottle of
plant Catalyst uh there's a whole bunch
of heavy 16 stuff in there there are I
genetics stickers in there uh there is a
t-shirt in there uh it is heavy it's
going to cost me a lot of money to ship
it so you're lucky I put all that stuff
in one Prize Package going to do a drum
roll on the table here I don't know if
you can hear me the winner of the grand
prize package that was donated to us by
our good friends at Hy gr indoor growing
supplies in Denver and pelo make sure
you support high grow indoor growing
supplies the winner of The Prize Package
is none other than Rich milahan because
rich is awesome he commented on Facebook
and Instagram he followed the rules he
followed who he needed to follow and his
comments were beautiful so
congratulations Rich you win a sweet ass
Prize Package from the grow from your
heart podcast from iy genetics from Hy
gr indoor growing supplies uh this will
make you a better grower dude you're
using you just got the [ __ ] that I use
uh the ogt the grok Kashi that's in my
lineup all the time so you just want
some cool [ __ ] congratulations thank you
guys for entering the contest if you
didn't win I feel bad I don't like doing
contests because that means that
somebody didn't win and I feel like [ __ ]
for that so if you didn't win I'm sorry
uh I feel guilty already so don't feel
bad that you didn't win it was hard to
pick winners I only had so many prizes
and I had a lot of entries thank you to
everybody that enter the contest that
means a lot to me thank you to everybody
that listened to the podcast uh episode
got more listens than any other show and
it pushed us up to 888 in the stitcher
ranks there are 25,000 shows on Stitcher
and this little show that happens here
in my kitchen at my dining room table
has placed
888 out of 25,000 shows so I'm kind of
proud it's not me that did that it's you
guys because I don't listen to it I just
produce it and record it and talk into a
mic so thank you guys for doing that
that is super awesome you guys make sure
you email me Rich email me Fred Garvin
Jason box Jake Henry Nate mcvillain
roster Ralph dabin Mile High Bob rennett
Logistics not you again 83 please email
me also um there was an extra prize
package that I did not list I'm going to
make sure I'm going to look over there
one more time because I realized that
there's another prize pack I'm going to
look got to peek across the
room there are four bags over there you
guys and I only gave away three of them
so that meant that I had an extra bag
and that extra bag has heavy 16
nutrients uh there's I gentic stickers
in there there's heavy 16 stickers
there's random [ __ ] from high grow into
growing supplies and I would like to
give that bag to El Roo uh he entered on
he entered his comment on Instagram so
El Roo bro I need your contact
information also you won the prize that
I forgot to list because you commented
on the nutrient package and since
there's another one bro you get it so
message me and I'll get that to you it's
grow fromy heart at hotmail.com you guys
talking really fast huh I'm going to
take a dab the show is almost over let's
take a dab together I had to pause for
the last dab cuz I needed a drink so
badly get yourselves a dab guys I got
the enail going so I'm already ahead of
you um I'm gonna dab some sativa mix
that I made shout out to the Garden of
Weeden and Spence for and Big Mike
helped a lot and Michael those guys have
got me making pretty good hash thanks a
lot so we're going to take a dab wrap up
the
show all right three two one let's dab
you guys
I might have been bigger than I wanted
to take on the podcast but we'll be all
right all right so I'm going to tell one
quick story before I wrap it up because
I just hit my Hitman rig and it made me
think of something yesterday uh I
straight dropped and broke a $300 Hitman
phe 2 cake it hit the table and it just
[ __ ] broke broke and I know
everyone's going oh my god really you
broke a $300 rig yeah I did and I felt
like a real dumbass about it I kind of
had like a moment of guilt in my heart
for it and I sat at the table and I was
like you just dropped one of your
favorite rigs dude and
then what do you do there's broken glass
on the table you can be mad for a minute
you can be brokenhearted but then you
you got to grab the broom and the dust
pan and sweep up the [ __ ] broken
glass and you got to throw that glass in
the trash and you got to move on right
that's all I could do because it's
broken uh I can't glue it back together
duct tape is not going to work that
shit's done so I had a Moment of Zen as
I was sweeping up this broken glass I
thought there's so many things that
happen in your life that suck and they
hurt or maybe they're good but you can't
cling to things because you could drop
that glass at any minute and that [ __ ]
could break dude and you can't put it
back together and sometimes you just got
to sweep some [ __ ] up throw it in the
trash can and [ __ ] walk away and just
move on so uh when you have some [ __ ]
happen to you just try to learn
something think about it like that
because I've been stuck on something and
breaking that
rig was definitely symbolic in some way
to me and I learned something from it I
just wanted to share that with you guys
I broke a rig and I learned a huge Life
Lesson from it that had nothing to do
with the rig itself I just this Moment
of Zen came over me and taught me a huge
life lesson wanted to share that I hope
you enjoyed it I hope you learned
something from it also if there's
something that you're [ __ ] stuck on
that you're clinging to just let it go
dude I know it's easier said than done
but I dropped a three $100 rig and I
swept it up and threw it away there's
nothing we can do about it just
sometimes you got to sweep some [ __ ] up
and move on I didn't get cut from the
rig and I had fun hitting it when I hit
it so that's all I could do with that
being said you guys now that the show is
over please go to iTunes or Stitcher go
to the iTunes or the stitcher main page
search for the grow from your heart
podcast find the review section give me
a festar rating after that type in a
comment let me know what you think of
the show and I will read your comments
on the show big shout out to all the
people that left comments I read them at
the start of the show I love it I really
love it interacting with you guys makes
me feel like you're paying attention
makes it worth my time and effort don't
forget that the show is available on
iTunes Stitcher and every single episode
is archived on iy genetics.com don't
forget that I've have added a donation
button to the podcast page if you go to
iy genetics colorado.com you'll have to
agree that you're over 18 and then
you're going to go to the podcast page
it says grow from your heart podcast
click on
that uh in the top right part of the
page there's a PayPal donate button if
you feel that this show was worth a
dollar or $5 or however much you felt it
was worth if you want to donate a couple
of bucks go ahead and throw a few
dollars in there and that goes directly
to my Paypal account um right now my
daughter is trying to raise money to go
on a Hawaiian educational Adventure any
money that goes to that PayPal account
uh from now until the time that
Adventure happens that's where that
money goes that goes to my 11-year-old
little girl so I'm not going to buy a
new dab rig I'm not going to smoke it up
I'm not going to buy a new hat uh it's
going to my little kid so if you want to
contribute to the show I appreciate it
I'm not begging the only reason I put it
there is because a listener said if I
had it he would contribute so you
haven't contributed bro I'm letting you
know it's there just kind of being a
smartass with that um yeah follow iy
genetics on Instagram if you're
interested in sponsoring the podcast or
if you have a product that You' like me
to review sorry I'm choking on that dab
if you have a product you'd like me to
review just send me an email it's grow
fromy yourheart hotmail.com I'll get you
all of the information that you need
once again huge happy birthday to Bob
Marley this week huge huge happy happy
birthday to Tater and also huge happy
birthday to Jesse Gro make sure you
follow all my friends on Instagram uh
shout out to my ninja Spence thanks
again for listening you guys until next
time take a fat dab give your mom a hug
for me
[Music]
I'm DJ in a dance come watch me DJ in
your dance a long long time I'm DJ in a
dance come watch me nice of the dance a
long long time I'm on a DJ in a dance
come watch me DJ in your dance a long
long time I'm on DJ in a dance come
watch me nice dance
dce