[Music]
yeah welcome back podcast world it is
time for episode 525 of the Grove from
your heart podcast happy 4/20 today is
4/20 I hope you've got a big fat joint I
hope you've got a phat bong load maybe
you're smoking some dad's maybe you're
eating too many edibles whatever you do
I hope you're getting lit and well
medicated thank you for celebrating 4/20
with me today this episode of the show
is brought to you by our friends at
seeds here now.com seeds here now.com
offers seeds from all of your favorite
breeders including miss Jill genetics
dupe diamond and of course I read
genetics everything at seeds here
now.com is backed by their award-winning
satisfaction guarantee for my friends on
a tight budget seeds here now.com offers
several packs for under 30 bucks as well
as amazing monthly sales be sure to use
coupon code GFY h10 while checking out
to save a few bucks at seeds here now
calm again that is coupon code G f YH 10
at seeds here now calm ladies and
gentlemen it is 4/20 it is my pre 4/20
celebration I'm getting heavily
medicated for this show today I am
dabbing on crescendo live batter from
Green Dot labs the crescendo is a cross
of chem VI 95 and Mandarin cookies on
the package the flavor is described as
heavy chem gas and cookie dough I will
agree with all of that when you crack
the jar open you are greeted with a very
pleasant cookie dough sweetness then
that is followed by a gassy chem punch
that I really enjoy as soon as it hits
the dab nail I get a really nice chem
gas flavor the aftertaste is a little
bit chemi with some sweetness the buzz
is perfect and very desirable this is
perfect concentrate for me I love it I
bought as much as they would let me have
it the dispensary
Big Ups to my friends a Colorado
cannabis exchange for the grape
concentrates all the time
I'm opening up the jar I'm getting
punched in the face with that delicious
cookie dough smell and as I look at it
it looks like a beautiful the texture
the color is perfect it's a beautiful
and golden yellow dollop of cheesecake
batter right in the middle of the
container perfect I want to stop and
take another dab but we're gonna
continue on with the show big shout out
to Green Dot labs big shout out to my
friends at Colorado cannabis exchange
for keeping me heavily medicated you
guys I am excited it is 4/20 it is not
the normal 4/20 usually 4/20 is
different usually I've got friends here
I've got Bros here we're smoking out
we're having a good time it is a lonely
4/20 the only interaction I'm going to
get is going to be digital and virtual
4/20 action this is a new world you guys
I hope you are dealing with things
appropriately through the kovat 19
situation I hope you're not going
stir-crazy
I hope you're making sure to check on
your diet check on your physical health
make sure and I just eaten snacks and
cakes and junk the whole time eat
something good maybe go outside and get
some pressure we're not supposed to go
too far we're not supposed to be around
people you've got a backyard you got a
front porch go hear some birds go smell
some air make sure your pants still fit
right you may be two or three pant sizes
bigger and you don't even know it so go
check on that also check on your mental
health are you doing okay are your
friends okay it may be a good idea to
watch some comedy and laugh a little bit
it may be a good time to FaceTime a bro
or a friend or someone you have to talk
to maybe check in with some family
members see that everybody's doing okay
we can all use a little bit of a hug a
digital check-in get some exercise check
on yourself check your mental health
laughs a little bit you guys it's gonna
be okay it's 4/20 we're still gonna have
a good time and I promise that when all
of this stuff is over we are going to
have the biggest what do we miss we
missed Easter we missed st. Patrick's
Day we're about to miss 4:20 we're gonna
have the biggest Easter st. Patrick's
4/20 whatever kind of celebration you
want to call that we're going to do
eggs and drink beer and smoke a bunch of
that sounds like a good time we'll
probably get Cinco de Mayo in there as
well
I'm from Pueblo Colorado that's a paid
holiday here we're gonna miss a lot of
stuff we were going to make up for it
when the time is right don't worry all
right is that music fades out
let's work into the part of the show
where we do shoutouts to our friends who
support the show on patreon once again
we've got to do digital and virtual dabs
and bong rips so let's start off with a
big girl from your heart virtual dab and
virtual bong rip - my friend miss mal
let's roll up a big fat virtual joint
and send that over to my buddy dick
goals I've always got a big virtual
digital dab for my friend prospect once
again let's bake way potent edibles and
send them over to my buddy red beard
let's get a big fat virtual blunt rolled
up for my buddy the corporate rebel
let's pack a big digital dab for my
buddy Glenn jeroni I've always got a big
fat bong rip of digital dankness from my
buddy Richard Gramps memo how about a
big giant digital dab for my buddy come
attic I've always got some too hot of a
dab and also since he's always
cross-faded let's go give a digital dab
and a digital shot or a drink to my
buddy Aldridge and last but certainly
not least let's pack up a big fresh
digital bong load and send that over to
my buddy Paul T big thanks big digital
dabs and big shout out to everybody who
continues to support the show on patreon
if you would like to learn how to
support the show you can do so by
visiting www.azcleanelections.gov April
ironically it is 4/20 2020 so it has
been 4/20 all month
we don't even get to really celebrate
kind of a bummer usually this time of
year I would be gearing up to go to the
dude grows cup and we'd see all of our
friends at the DGC Cup we'd have a good
time do some bending do a bunch of
smoking have a little cannabis
competition a little friendly award
ceremony there that event is not gonna
happen for a couple of months because
we've got to push that back there would
also be one other event which I would
attend usually there's one random event
I booked for the 4/20 weekend it is not
happening this year so that is kind of
weird all of my 4/20 events and
activities have basically been online
they've been on skype or they've been on
zoom' or they've been on FaceTime
I've done a couple of things on
Instagram live but that has been most of
my 4/20 celebration I did a really cool
live show on YouTube with scotty reel
and tennessee gardens and our friend
stone trout bum i thought that was a
really good time but we are lacking in
social interaction I need a concert I
need a comedy show I need some bros I
need a high-five I need some people
around dude it it's starting to get kind
of weird but then when I think about
that I also think about how long is it
going to be before we are all
comfortable just congregating and
smoking together
first of all congregating together do
you want to be around a large group of
people right now a lot of people are
fine a lot of people like I don't care
let's do it let's [ __ ] smoke those
are the people we got to look out for
but how long until a lot of us are
comfortable getting in a big room and
just being together do you want 10
strangers in a small room with you and
then then we're gonna think about
smoking do you want to light up a joint
and put your lips on a joint that that
guy just put his lips on or that girl
just put her lips on or whichever D are
you a little bit worried I might be I'm
not sure I'm still a little bit
skeptical and brainwashed and paranoid
over the whole situation I don't want to
get sick I know my main risk is getting
other people sick because I'm fairly
healthy but I still don't want to get a
little bit sick I don't want to be down
for a couple of days I don't want to get
slowed down I got [ __ ] to do every day I
can't take a day off for a [ __ ]
stupid virus that tried to kick my ass
or kill me I don't need that so I've
been laying low during this whole
quarantine situation I'm kind of taking
it seriously
I think the weed growers and the video
gamers and also the fans all
girls all the girls the thirsty girls
the model girls the snapchat girls on
Instagram social media they're the ones
living it up we've been waiting for this
we're a professional since we've been in
training for years the growers have been
isolated the breeders have been extra
isolated for a while I get a large
portion of my social interaction through
online stuff through Instagram live
through that sort of thing but I've been
laying low through most of this
quarantine stuff because I really don't
need to be out there there's nothing for
me to go do everything is closed
everywhere is shut down I can go to the
dispensary occasionally and I can get
groceries and those are mainly the
things that I need to do today I drove
through the drive-through car wash so
that I could wash my car because I was
just going stir-crazy I drove around the
block about 14 times and went through
the car wash once the car was all the
way dry I came back home that's how
exciting my day was today other than
hanging out here and smoking that's
about all I've done I've done ridiculous
amounts of online shopping but now I'm
getting [ __ ] delivered that I can't use
any works I can't go anywhere to wear
any of shoes I can't go out in a new
shirt it's kind of silly right now
things are weird but I'm really not sure
how long it's going to be until it is
not weird
people are going to remain paranoid for
a long time even if the government or
whoever you trust or believe this Center
for Disease Control or the epidemic
people whoever you're watching on TV
once they finally say it's okay for you
to go out a lot of people are still
gonna be skeptical they're not gonna
want to go out they're not gonna want to
participate are you going to want to go
like I said earlier be most of the smoke
events we go to where you can consume
they are in fairly small buildings those
buildings are fairly tight without a lot
of ventilation you can see what happens
I'm a big guy I take a fairly large dab
when I take a dab and blow it out I can
watch my dab go across my record in my
dining room
my little dining-room area is probably
an 8 by 8 square maybe 6 by 6 square
where the table is it's just a little
tucked in like a cove part of the
kitchen off the kitchen so the dad fills
this area no problem within a few
seconds it drifts into the actual
kitchen area then it goes into the
kitchen then it moves over like toward
the laundry room area and then it starts
drifting down a hallway and it only
takes a minute for that dab smoke to get
all the way into my laundry room which
is the opposite end of the house and all
the way into the kitchen
or the bedroom if the exact opposite end
of the house takes a minute and my smoke
which is probably carrying my germs and
whatever else has now traveled through
the entire house
it is everywhere I can watch it the Sun
shines in through this curtain I can see
where my smoke travels through if I take
a bong rip or a dab in the living room
it fills that living room as soon as I
exhale it comes out it [ __ ] bounces
off of that wall it bounces off of that
wall you can see my smoke just kind of
swirling and chillin it looks like a big
presence in the room some sort of smokey
aberration just chilling out with us or
maybe it's a smoky vibration it's a
blessing just be in there with us but
you can see it just floating around in
the room so you can see my bong rip and
then when we're at events you can see
everybody else's dabs and bong rips just
circling around the room you watch
people blow out real hard so they got a
fresh lung they don't have any air in
their lungs they're empty they blow out
now they just blew out a bunch of fresh
air then they go and dab in they suck
that dab or that bong rip in or real
hard and get a big fresh lung full and
then they blow it right back out and all
of their virus and lung junk just comes
out right into the air and now we're all
gonna breathe it together and then they
start coughing so they start breathing
even more heavily because they're trying
to recover from a big-ass dab or a fat
bong rip and all they're doing is
sucking in more smoke because those
events are so cloudy so it's harder to
recover it takes even longer
you're just gasping for oxygen so there
are several before you actually get your
[ __ ] together and you've just filled the
room with all of your junk enough
there's ten people in there imagine 10
people's worth of just junky breathy
filled up in the room I'm sure we never
really thought too much about that until
now I saw people trying to take
precautions at events we always bring
the alcohol swabs the little while like
a handy wipe it's an alcohol swab and
just a little like a condom package you
pop it open wipe the rig down throw that
in the trash keep dabbing try to wipe it
off between every user but we get lazy
and we're friends it feels kind of rude
to be like hey bro wipe that off before
I smoked after you that's part of the
point of smoking with your friends is to
show that we were peaceful and were
united and we will smoke together that's
where the smoke circle originated you
know that's part of the whole deal you
bring the pipe I bring the goods or we
both bring half of the pipe and we share
the goods that way we know there's
nothing weird in the pipe there's a lot
of things behind smoking together there
are a lot of ceremonies and rituals that
involve that so
on that pipe together was part of the
whole thing we started seeing people
with a little ceramic or what's it
silicone insert that pops into your rig
or into your bong and then you put your
mouth on that we've seen people wearing
those on necklaces and lanyards we've
seen people trying to take precautions
but not everybody was taking anything
seriously when we would go to these
events especially at some of the smoke
lounges and things there will be people
just lined up to hit the same rig I need
to hit that I want to hit that you don't
see everybody clean it before and after
each use so how long is it gonna be
before we're comfortable congregating
with ten people in a room 20 people 70
people some of the events we go to have
300 and something people some of them
are even larger than that how
comfortable are you gonna be with that
many people in there then how soon will
it be before you're ready to just grab a
joint that you just you don't know where
it came from you saw me hit it and then
I'm passing it to you you know it's at
least got my drool and germs on it how
many people before me hit it how far
down is that joint burned how
comfortable are you gonna be how long is
that gonna take the world is gonna be
different for a little bit and I'm
really curious to watch it go because
there are many people taking it super
seriously there are a lot of people kind
of doing the rules and trying to take it
seriously there are people who are
neutral who haven't changed their day at
all and then there are people that are
like I don't give a [ __ ] about this
virus I'm gonna do everything just like
I was so I'm really curious to see how
this evolves I'm really curious to see
what it's doing to the cannabis industry
right now cannabis is selling cannabis
alcohol sex toys things of that nature
are selling ridiculously fast a
recording equipment is hard to buy right
now if you want specific good recording
equipment it's sold out at most of the
music vendors so some industries are
doing very well while many are kind of
at a standstill but right now the
cannabis industry is thriving
unfortunately many facilities have
minimized their staff because they don't
need human interaction in the building
if they can do the job with three people
they've got three people working if it
would be much easier with four or five
they still minimize it to three and let
those people work their asses off that
way it's just those three people coming
and going less people less germs less
exchange of bodily fluid and bodily air
contact that minimizes the risk to get
less people sick and those people can
handle it because they just work extra
hours and right now that's probably the
best thing to do is just be at work or
be at home there's no need to be out in
the public like I said earlier there's
nothing to do everywhere is closed my
town is a ghost town many of the
restaurants are offering delivery only
but we've been so far into this
quarantine that many of my local
restaurants have closed down until the
quarantine is over or they have just
given up for good because they're not
making enough money to pay a staff to be
there to wait for the couple of food
orders they do get but the dispensaries
are swamped with customers the
dispensaries are doing their best to
practice safe social distancing they're
only allowing a certain amount of people
in the waiting room at a time depending
on the size of the waiting room of
course if it's a six by six area you get
one [ __ ] in there if it's a
little bigger we can fit more people in
there then once you're in the bud room
they're actually minimizing your time in
the bud room they request four minutes
per patient or customer in the bud room
I've been shopping at the medical and
recreational dispensaries the protocols
are a little bit different at both
places but it's similar at the Colorado
cannabis exchange they don't let you
pass really you walk in the door to the
bud room and there is a counter and an
ATM just working as a roadblock that's
as far as you can get it's very obvious
they don't want you going past there you
walk in and you're stuck right there
they have a few things inside of the
glass counter on display so that you can
see here are the few concentrates we've
got left and then the flowers are behind
the budtender you can see those clearly
they do have a couple of menus printed
that are in the waiting room so you can
look in the waiting room and get a
little idea of what you want before you
get back there so that's helpful but the
shopping experience is very different
I'm used to being able to grab the jars
and hold them and put the jar of
concentrate or the jar of flowers up to
my nose and give it a smell and kind of
look and see if it looks appealing
smells appealing if it's the right color
and texture and that's how I make my
decisions this time I had to kind of
look through the glass and hope that it
smelled good I shop with Green Dot labs
so it is always amazing concentrates I
was really satisfied with the crescendo
I had to go back for more and then again
for more because it was really delicious
I that's perfect for me is right up my
alley but the shopping experience is
a little bit different but they are
selling so much product even with the
weird adjustments the medical and
recreational dispensaries are selling
there has been a line every time I have
gone part of the line could be because
it is taking a touch longer to help
people because of the different setup
also more people are shopping I've
noticed that I see different people at
the dispensaries when you go to the same
dispensaries on a regular rotation you
start seeing the same people I'm seeing
brand new faces there are more cars
there's more traffic they're the only
places open the liquor stores the
dispensaries very few restaurants
the bank is open its drive-through only
there are very few places you can
actually go to so the dispensary and the
carwash have been very entertaining
lately starting to feel like that weird
guy that just shows up at the dispensary
with nothing to do and like I'm just
here to buy two grams and to see another
human but I'm also trying not to go too
often so I go and I get my limit and
then I'm scary low I go back and get my
limit
but I also want to go because there's
people there and I like people but my
point is the cannabis industry the
recreational and medical and also the
free market cannabis industries are
thriving here in southern Colorado we
are lucky enough that they have declared
cannabis recreational and medical
cannabis to be essential businesses they
also did the same with alcohol and there
are a couple of reasons for that I think
I've talked about this on the show
before they were going to close the
liquor stores they made an announcement
hey liquor stores are to close at a
certain time on this day and everybody
in Colorado went to the nearest liquor
store and got in line and it was kind of
funny to see that when they're like hey
you're not gonna be able to buy booze
everybody was like nah [ __ ] that there
were lines around the blocks and none of
those lines were going to be gone by the
cutoff time where they said hey this is
when you close last call for alcohol and
so eventually our governor said hey
maybe we shouldn't do that they also did
that because they thought about the fact
that people will go into alcohol
withdrawals strong alcoholics will die
if you cut them off cold turkey and that
would just overload the hospitals with
unnecessary problems and if you don't
give us some weed and some alcohol while
you lock us down for several weeks we
may [ __ ] revolt you may see more
problems than you were prepared for so
they decided
you leave the alcohol as essential
business and cannabis is deemed
essential business which I really find
to be a blessing that gave a lot of job
security to my industry friends because
many of my friends are in the cannabis
industry my other friends are in the
service industries and they are all
[ __ ] all of my comedian friends all my
waiter and bartender and staff and
whatever type of service if you bring
something to somebody and expect a tip
many of those people are [ __ ] out of
luck right now so I'm glad that at least
my cannabis industry friends are still
in work and maybe it sounds a little bit
selfish but I'm really glad that I can
still get my concentrates imagine if we
we're all just cut off of all of our
concentrates are flowers our buds our
dabs our edibles whatever you do to
medicate yourself if you use SABS or rub
in if you go to the dispensary and buy
something imagine if they're just like
now we're shutting that down we've kind
of established a lifestyle around having
these products available it may it may
make a few people go a little bit more
than stir crazy you can't go outside
you're trapped with your family and
nothing to [ __ ] lubricate your mind
that would be fun
you guys I just realized I've been
rambling for like a complete 20 minutes
and we haven't covered a subject we
haven't talked about cannabis in any
sort of way it is 4/20 I just had a few
notes written down I wanted to come hang
out do a fun 4/20 show thank you for
hanging out with me I hope you're having
a good time let's do some serious
podcasting it's 4/20 let's talk about
some 4/20 related stuff I like involving
my audience in my podcast my listeners
are great contributors to the show this
is one of the times when I call on you
for some answers I want to know what are
you listening to while you're smoking
it's 4/20 you've got control of the aux
cord what are you gonna put on what are
you gonna play right now what kind of
music what's your favorite band
what song what am I missing is there
something out there I should really be
listening to what are you into what gets
you grooving for 4/20 send me an email
my email address is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com
or you can hit me on twitter at g f YH
podcast let me know what you're
listening to if there's some 420 music
out there I need to catch on to
introduce me if you've got some stoner
music I need to hear some reggae music I
might be into or if you've got some
obscure [ __ ] that you think I might like
introduce me to it or just let me know
what you're gonna play while we smoke a
bowl for 4/20 so
I'm asking I'll share a little bit right
now I would probably put on some tasks
and lionís just because I like listening
to tasks and Linus when I'm taking dad's
at 7:10 then I would probably put on
some routes II feel and reggae maybe
some Iike Mouse or something like that
right now then we may go on to something
a little more modern a little more well
produced cuz I want that low tone in my
ear we may go with some revolution or
something like that for a little bit but
then we're gonna have to go route C
again then we may go some like morgen
heritage or something like that but then
we'll finish the day with fish I like to
listen to fish in the evenings just
smoked down listened to fish it lets my
brain wander a lot just a long fishy Jam
when tre is really lighting it up
everybody that listens knows I'm a huge
fish man I'm also a giant Grateful Dead
fan many of my strains are named after
Grateful Dead songs and Grateful Dead
type of stuff so that is where my
musical taste is of course roots II dub
reggae fish and the Grateful Dead are
always gonna be my top three choices
then I'm a classic rock guy I was raised
with three stoner uncles and of course I
had two aunts and my mom who were also
semi pot heads who liked his good
old-fashioned classic rock rock and roll
so I know all that stuff I love all that
[ __ ] it just feels good I'm also a
drummer I'm a musician I've been paid to
play with a lot of bands I was known
around here as the guy that could fill
in for your classic rock band so I know
all of that classic rock stuff I blame
that on my upbringing the songs were in
my head when I started playing drums
like well let's just learn all of this
stuff and it came out naturally I know
it it's a good time then if you want to
kind of delve into a little bit random
side of my music I grew up with like a
lot of Metallica type of stuff so I know
a lot of Metallica Megadeath Pantera
Pearl Jam Nirvana all that 1995 MTV
stuff that's right up my alley I dig on
that [ __ ] too so that's that's what I
dig on for music when we really need a
change and the trim crew is lagging and
we've been there too long and you can
tell that people are dragging ass and
they want to go home Thursday like on a
Thursday it's not quite Friday and
everybody wishes it was Friday cuz
Friday's got its own vibe on Thursday
that's when I put on that like cheesy
90s pop rock [ __ ] just cheesy white
guy rock music it's poppy it's Rocky
maybe some barenaked ladies in there
that's not by choice I just put on like
a Spotify channel and played that kind
of [ __ ] you're gonna get what are those
guys called Sugar Ray and [ __ ] bare
naked ladies and all that cheesy [ __ ]
what's that other group that I'm
thinking of some body wants Tommy that
[ __ ] is so cheesy but when you get the
crew singing it you're all just laughing
it'll bring a totally different vibe it
refreshes the room so that's like my
last resort things have gone wrong
that's what we put on unites the whole
crew everybody knows that [ __ ] you just
start seeing different people seeing
songs and you're like I had no idea you
would know that one and no idea you
would know that one but that [ __ ] works
for everybody it's cheesy
you only play it for a few songs once
you get everybody going again you let
them pick their music one of my favorite
things is if I run the grow if I'm the
cultivation manager the first grower to
get there gets to select the music for
the grow part of the building the first
trimmer to get there selects music for
the trim part of the building then we
jam their music for the first part of
the day that's just a little reward so
that is where my musical brain is I love
music I talk a lot about music what else
are we gonna do munchies and snacks bro
you got some good music done you just
took a fat dad what are you gonna reach
for to put in your face so you're gonna
have some sort of a snack I honestly try
to not snack too much after I dab
because then I just need more dabs I
catch myself in this vicious cycle of
dabs snacks dad's snacks and you never
really get to enjoy I guess you enjoy
the [ __ ] out of the snacks but you're
always just chasing that high away by
eating snacks so I try to get fairly
blazed and don't eat for a long time
until it's like bro you better eat or
shits gonna go wrong and that's what I
liked it I have food I like to eat good
food I've been really not bragging here
this sounds like [ __ ] for a minute but
I've really eliminated sugar and crap
from my diet and all the snacks have
kind of been switched over to like
hummus and carrots and like actual good
fruit and [ __ ] and since I've quit
eating all the sugary stuff and spoiling
my face with crap fruit and real food
tastes amazing and when I drink kombucha
now the kombucha just tingles and dances
on my tongue since I'm not drinking dr.
pepper that kombucha tastes so much
better I know the kombucha is not for
some people if it's for you you know
what I'm talking about that just sweet
kombucha dance a nice grapefruit
sparkling kombucha oh yeah it'll put a
smile on your face
but when you get stoned what are you
reaching for to eat what are you
reaching for to drink I'm probably gonna
go for like maybe some strawberries
maybe some chopped up watermelon I like
a lot of fruit pieces that really makes
me feel good makes me not feel like a
piece of [ __ ] for spoiling myself with
too much crap I do catch myself eating a
lot of peanut butter and jelly
sandwiches during quarantine I think
that is boredom eating I'm just bored so
I gonna make a PB&amp;J and [ __ ] snack
that [ __ ] down because it takes a
minutes all the peanut butter you can't
just shout it down so that's like my
crappy snack lately I think the jelly is
a little more sugar and junk than really
what I need especially with all the
other fruit my diet and then like I
mentioned I really like a nice kombucha
a nice cold frosty cold kombucha with a
nice fizz to it that's delicious
or I also really dig in Odwalla
the mango madness or a strawberry
protein or almost any of the Odwalla
hook me up with the fruity flavored one
I'll be just happy but that's the kind
of [ __ ] I reach for when it is snacky
time trying to be healthy trying to take
care of myself and do better I encourage
you to do the same thing I feel better I
feel good I know that you guys don't
care about that this is a weed show but
when you take care yourself you feel
better
when you water your plants and feed them
better they act better your brain and
body will do the same thing all right so
we got music we got snacks what else do
you do are you one of the people that
puts on a movie and watches the same
[ __ ] movie over and over again I
can't do that once I've seen a movie
I've seen it I can watch a comedy
special maybe twice because they're
gonna be jokes I didn't catch the first
time but broader and have time to watch
the same movie twice that drives me
crazy so what are you gonna watch once
you get stoned we've gotten stoned we
got good music on we just had a snack
now it's time to sit down are you gonna
watch a movie or you gonna watch
cartoons do you have a favorite TV show
what's your [ __ ] that you put on TV do
you have a Netflix show you go to let me
know what are we watching then here is
the last part that I want to know are
you a gamer what are you playing
maybe you're producing music what do you
do to fidget with your fingers once you
get blazed are you gonna turn on some
video games if you turn on the video
games
what are you playing I just want to know
what my friends are doing after they get
stoned what are you doing to entertain
your mouth your ears your eyes and your
hands after you smoke I would appreciate
if you let me know send me an email my
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail calm and again my twitter is at
GFY
each podcast and now since we're talking
about 4/20 I think the most important
question is what are you smoking I
always talk about what I'm smoking on
the show what are you smoking are you
smoking a bong load are you smoking a
joint are you smoking a blunt are you
smoking dabs are you smoking rosin did
you have to scrape a resin out of an old
pipe I'm sorry if you did tell me what
you're smoking through and what you're
putting in it are you smoking some Jack
Herer
you smoke in golden good you have some
arise let me know what you're smoking
and how you're smoking it and again my
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
and the tweeter is at g f YH podcast
alright ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls pimps and hos friends and foes
smokers and growers clone cutters pollen
chuckers all you bad [ __ ] out
there
quarantine Ian's and caronian 's I want
to thank you guys for joining me for a
4/20 episode honestly all the talk about
snacks put a little rumble in my tummy
so but it's time to get some food going
I'm gonna make myself a little 420
personal buffet over here in the Rasta
Jeff palace I hope you guys have a
wonderful and safe 4/20 don't do
anything [ __ ] stupid you guys don't
ruin 4/20 for the rest of us who are
trying to behave ourselves we will have
a great 4/20 next year we will make up
for this when we are allowed to go
outside again we will have a giant st.
Patrick's Easter 4/20 de Mayo party that
is gonna kick ass like you have never
seen before
I cannot wait I hope to see you there
hopefully it doesn't turn into a
Juneteenth and summer and all kinds of
other stuff all at one time party as
well oh I hope this is over soon hey you
can hang out with me on Instagram live
every Monday I go on Instagram live at
7:10 p.m. my Instagram is Irie
underscore genetics I try to get there
around 7 7 10 I go on Instagram do a
live video I hang out with my friends I
answer cannabis related questions I'll
answer just about any question you put
in the live chat I try to talk to
everybody and answer every question that
comes up I encourage you to join us on
Instagram live every Monday around a 7
p.m. mountain time you guys I am in
Colorado everything I say is in the
Mountain Time Zone
check me out I hope to find you on the
Instagram live feed also I will be doing
live shows with some of my
friends we will be doing stuff on zoom'
we will be doing things on Instagram
life I'm trying to put more stuff
together I've gotten some extra
equipment that I shared with friends so
now I've got more people that are able
to do shows online from their houses
with me we will be doing audio and video
shows more frequently so please look
forward to that and please join me when
those are available all right ladies and
gentlemen boys and girls I have been
rambling for a long time it's time for
me to get out of here and get some food
in my belly and then I'm gonna get high
as giraffe [ __ ] I want to thank you
again for listening I'll be back in a
couple of days with fresh new content
maybe you'll see me today on Instagram
live at 7:10 Mountain time I'll be
taking dabs and celebrating 4/20 all by
myself so look forward to seeing me
there that's all I've got for you I want
to give a giant shout out to my buddy
stone dat trout BOM and until next time
take a phat dad and give your mom a hug
for me
[Music]