all right what's a podcast world welcome
to episode 526 of the growth from your
heart podcast today we are doing
something new today joining me on zoom'
we have got white Mike welcome to the
show bro what's up man dude thanks for
joining me in these weird Co vid times
from the bunker from the bunkers now
what you're gonna call it you got an
official name for your recording spot it
is now a bunker that's gonna stick
that's how it goes
yeah this is gonna be fun man oh we got
Mike some recording gear he's finally
found some time he's got that did you
sedate those kids bro or is that natural
I didn't app today and I ran them hard
this evening just let him run around in
the backyard and go ape [ __ ] right until
bedtime so they're good good hopefully
uh we can do this once a week or so and
get you dialed in I've got at least
three hours so does that mean three
hours show from the bunkers that was you
just said maybe I like this we're gonna
learn how to do this so far I feel like
we're comfortable you may be a little
bit louder actually I'll just turn
myself down a bit and I think we'll
[ __ ] even out ah this would be a good
time dude so welcome to the show makes
weird audio folks we're uh we're trying
something new yeah we are I'm sure most
of the people listening we got to keep
in mind it's a podcast this will live
forever most of the people listening
currently are aware that we are under
stay at home orders from our government
there's a high risk yeah please stay
home help us out there's a virus
spreading and it is causing Asteria and
illness and death and so we've been
asked to stay home Mike lives across
town and he's also got two young
children and a family so Mike doesn't
need to get me sick I don't need to get
Mike and his kids sick we're trying to
be good citizens we're gonna stay at
home so we're gonna do some shows from
zoom I'm sure most of the people are
doing yeah we're gonna get creative here
I'm sure most of the people are doing
[ __ ] from home they're gonna be excited
just to have content while they're on
the home stay so if like Mike said if we
do get any weird audio glitches we'll
get it figured out this is our first
time trying to forgive us our trespasses
I think I'm pretty good at tech gear and
editing so we'll make this sound all
right it sounds great that sounds good
my head but who knows what it's doing in
the recording gear maybe we should look
at that and see that that's happening
dude that looks good too I think we're
doing it we're recording a podcast Mike
Congrats
ah before we get too far ah this episode
is brought to you by our friends at
seeds here now.com seeds here now calm
carry seeds from all the industry's
favorite breeders including miss Jill
genetics Duke diamond and of course I
read genetics seeds everything it seeds
here now is backed by their satisfaction
guarantee and for my friends on a budget
seeds here now.com offers several packs
for under $30 as well as amazing monthly
sales make sure to use coupon code why
h10 while checking out to save a few
bucks
again that is coupon code g fyh 10 at
checkout at seeds here now dot-com or I
pulled that off with no notes I don't
have any cards or anything I think I do
that in my sleep sometimes I wake up
doing a seeds here now at buy seeds Etsy
tier now pretty good what are you
smoking on over there but I saw you take
a big fat dab what you got I've got all
sorts of goodies right now I just went
on a resupply run to apothecary I've got
the last one was some blackberry banana
cush oh that sounds delicious
I went specifically for more the Sour
Diesel ambrosia I've gone through a
couple of grams of that in quarantine
and had to go read up and ended up
coming home with a lot more hash and I
intended by which happens I wasn't gonna
bring ups it you went in today when you
shop bro you went uncharacteristic that
was a hard word for my face to say it
was unlike you how hard you went in your
shopping spree today I I kind of
chuckled and like I've been good for
quarantine I've I've really only left
the house once or twice since the end of
March and run it yeah my birthday I had
to have I wanted a doughnut for
breakfast so I said [ __ ] it went good a
lot of podcast listeners just told you
happy birthday so happy birthday way
late but happy birthday Mike so you went
shopping let's I'm gonna segue right
into that actually let me tell everybody
what I'm smoking I also am smoking
apothecary Farms concentrates I just hit
Malibu pure Kush ambrosia the package
says seventy two point nine percent THC
eighty four point seven percent total
cannabinoids the Malibu pure cush tastes
like cush I know that sounds like a
stupid ass
if you're not a cush smoker but it is
exactly what I expect from a good cush
it's got that earthy funky nastiness and
the Malibu has a little sweetness to it
so that's the cush I was gonna ask about
your shopping experience you said you
went to the dispensary today how well
was that how did it happen and how
different is it for normal I got I'm
shopping med so med still allowed in the
stores basically a normal shopping I was
in a mask which was odd
I was the compliance guy for a long time
for a couple different outfits and so
the different rules we play by here in
Colorado are kind of always in my head
and having my face covered the whole
time it was just alarm bells going off
of my head rule seven rule seven it's
really was not a real no but anybody
who's deals with the they want your ID
checked two or three times in the
dispensary when you check-in the guy at
the door or the gal at the door or the
non-binary gender person at the door
checks in your ID and they go oh that's
you it looks like you the eye color the
height the [ __ ] hair color the hair
color doesn't even matter now we've all
got everyone's got [ __ ] rainbow hair
for the eyes and the [ __ ] height look
kind of like you the picture looks like
you it says you're old enough you can
shop in our store then when you go back
to shop they pass your ID to the person
who is serving you we call them a
budtender and they verify you again just
because if they sell to you and you're
not old enough or you're not a medical
marijuana patient they can they're being
charged with a crime they just illegally
sold a controlled substance to you so
they'll double check that ID shouldn't
be people in jail we've got friends who
have ended up in jail because of weird
things and because of the the increased
penalties the compliance rate is over
90% for comparison with tobacco it's
usually in the high 80s or mid to high
80s and so we're several points up with
with the increase for the cannabis sales
because those girls are harsher so
you're in the dispensary you've got
gloves you've got a mask
I didn't glove up I was however carrying
a disinfecting that's the I remember the
wiping their story it's
but yeah it was other than the mask it
was a pretty normal shopping trip and
it's for 19 as we're recording this so
for 20 Eve bro in 6 minutes it's going
to be for 20 I just looked at the clock
we're recording it's gonna be Zachary
five minutes away till 4:20 now hell
yeah
Cheers so that in this being the first
time I've left the house in my 518 days
19 days I kind of went a little nutty it
was like you know what I came for those
two give me one of them one of them one
of them one of them yes you do today was
just a hash run I've already seen your
flower haha I got to see it first and it
smells really good shout-out to the
grower that got your flower going he
knows who he is and it smells really
delicious we had a friend help me out
with some flowers today and Mike's gonna
get some of the help and he's gonna love
it it smells really great the
dispensaries are different I've been to
uh if you watch the recreational so you
were there I was glad I was shopping
because there was no line the REC line
was substantial everybody in their cars
I didn't count the cars but there were
more than a few so you sit in their cars
they're not allowed to go inside the
store now right yep it's all they're
doing all drive up at the store I was at
yeah so you've got to I had a friend who
went in your order gotta call it in tell
that you go to weed Maps weed map shows
the current menu it's got good pictures
of the product you go to weed Maps see
what you want you write down a little
list you give them a call you say hey I
want this and they tell you come in 15
to 30 minutes and then when you go they
ask you your name and they've got it
bagged up with a receipt stapled to the
bag you give them cash they run inside
they would come out with your change
honestly you just tell them keep the
change you try to map it out right it's
looking a hundred bucks to give them a
120 or 110 you tell them have a good day
and you send them on their way then they
bring out your bag and you don't even
have to get out of the car right now
dude I wish I kinda wish they could keep
it like that forever because that would
just nice there when we legalized
cannabis in Colorado we agreed to a lot
of rules just to placate the people who
were against us
we agreed to a lot of over and above and
I think a lot of that is gonna get
dialed back during this I think that's
gonna be one of the little [ __ ] up
silver lining Oh lockdown whatever good
I think we're gonna slowly you know as
we come out of this some of the rules we
change to deal with this they're gonna
have to justify going back to the way it
was like curbside pickup at dispensaries
is wonderfully convenient as a parent
it's a kind of a pain in the ass because
I've if I'm out of the house there's an
80% chance I've got kids in the back of
the car and I can't take kids into a
dispensary they physically can't enter
the building right and it's not like
there's consumption happening there
because nobody's got a tasting room
permit yet but it's it's always been
sort of an over and above rule we've
dealt with in the curbside pickup gets
around that so well so your kids are the
age now to where you can take them to
the dispensary how long until you think
that runs out depends on the
communication between you and your kids
as things evolve right well I'm not
really like they know about the world
and the cannabis in the world and so
like as they grow up it's just gonna be
like that's the thing that adults do
that's I never thought of I haven't put
my brain in that perspective but the
kids after my daughter my daughter's 16
the kids after that are gonna grow up
with normalized cannabis it's gonna be
just like when whoever used to stop on
the way to the beach or on the way to
wherever and grab a six-pack of beer now
you stop and grab a couple of pre-war
pre-rolls or an eighth or whatever it's
just part of life now that's kind of
great thanks Mike I'm glad you opened my
brain to that my belief on the subject
is kind of based on my interpretation of
when I first found out about pot and I
was like you kept it secret until now
that's weird like there's all kinds of
dangerous [ __ ] you don't want me doing
in the world but like this one was a
secret till now why I've got to get my
hands on some of this [ __ ] and I want to
see what happens to society when that
goes away when it's just like Oh what
are those guys doing oh there's a thing
in the world called cannabis and if you
smoke it
it's fun and adults do it just like beer
just yeah why'd you jumping or whatever
else like [ __ ] that adults do the kids
shouldn't yeah take a weirdness away
maybe that's part of why I wasn't super
I was never afraid of cannabis I grew up
you guys have heard about my uncle's on
the podcast several times they just used
to smoke like it was nothing and so I
just grew up like it was that's just
what you do like before you go to the
baseball game you [ __ ] burn one down
on the car it's so fun we've come so far
since we were kids isn't like things we
can get away with doing around each
other like there's a great picture that
goes around on Facebook of like an eight
year old blowing out the candles on her
cake and there's like six beers and an
ashtray and a cigar like three
cigarettes in the frame
all right around on top of this kid you
couldn't do any of that now but when we
were kids it was comment like oh ya know
senator Burris stories that involve me
getting accidentally burned by a
cigarette just because smokers were
everywhere around kids and being a kid
you sometimes wander into a lit
cigarette yeah used to smoke in the mall
and the store in the restaurant you just
have a smoking section in the restroom
yeah it used to be ridiculous Mike we're
telling everybody how old we are right
now this is button we are son like two
old crazy [ __ ] old stoners also
congrats how long are you on cigarette
freeness since January 22nd so like
three months groans Congrats that's
awesome like close to 90 days that's
[ __ ] rad i switch to tony pops that's
why i said it because i saw you pull the
titty pop out and set it down and what
should be the ashtray but it's now the
tootsie roll pop older dude things got
hairy ferment the shipment was late
[Music]
that's [ __ ] funny
that is funny i'm gonna interrupt the
show because we normally do some
shoutouts to our friends who support the
show on patreon at the top of the show
and i did not do that
but i love them and you're taking a
drink and it's a really good time to do
that um usually i do something silly we
roll up fat digital fonts we pack up
digital bong grips and we pass and do
our friends
so how about we do it like this all of
my friends in this episode are gonna get
a big digital dab so let's start off
with the big shots my buddy Callie
canape let's follow that up with a big
shout-out to my friend freek fish I want
to send some love to our friend Meredith
how about a big high-five in a fist bump
to mark Moskal how about a big high-five
- Gregory Segura maybe I shouldn't be
saying everybody's full names I don't
know why I wrote down full names today
that's [ __ ] awkward I better make
shots - air across let's send some yeah
hope your wife knows you're [ __ ]
contributing to patreon about some love
- NorCal Irie
let's send a big chef to Ryan s onus and
some love this spruce Hill farm and last
but not least how about a big shot it's
all how about a shout-out to Tanner M
sorry I'm I and stumbly and got [ __ ]
laughing at the fact that I read
everybody's full name out there big shot
it's all of our friends who do support
the show on patreon we do appreciate the
support that is how Mike got recording
here you guys on patreon funded Mike's
recording equipment so I say thank you
Mike his unmeaning is here to say thank
you thank you thank you thank you yeah
for sure he's been having fun we took a
couple of zoom sessions and chatted to
get used to this I think we're getting
good at it you guys if you are not yeah
oh there Mike you're [ __ ] good at
this are you like a [ __ ] pro already
if you're not already subscribed to my
patreon campaign and you would like to
learn how to support the show all you
have to do is visit www.reimaverick.com
pod on patreon and also we were going to
set Mike up a patreon campaign so we'll
get that going over the next episode we
should probably just press pause and do
it but we'll keep moving right now
we'll make it real easy for you to find
it'll probably just search for white
Mike on patreon it's something like that
will come up we'll get you going Mike
we're gonna make you some some patreon
funding something like that yeah we'll
get it going but Mike wasn't confident
in doing the patreon but since I've said
it on the show now it's gonna happen
yeah big shout out to all of our friends
on patreon for keeping us accountable I
try to talk about cannabis on the show I
also try to talk about events that are
current man I saw something in the news
and Mike saw something in the news today
and I didn't I want to talk too much
about XII Boyd all this kovat stuff and
I wasn't sure how big of a deal it was
it annoyed me it frustrated me Mike
called me earlier
the first thing he said was you see
these [ __ ] idiots yeah there are
people in Denver surrounding the Denver
Capitol building
protesting be stay at home orders for
the kovat 19 protective orders
protective measures that's kind of silly
yeah don't do that like well my whole
take is like what if you're wrong like
like that's just been one of its like if
you're gonna advocate for major [ __ ]
like I get that it sucks I [ __ ] hate
it too but what if you're wrong yeah
what if [ __ ] wrong and you're out
there getting everybody out there sick
like I know like a lot of people that
have businesses want to get their [ __ ]
open right away but like have you taken
a minute to imagine what it would feel
like to read the headline like my
business in facts 50 people kills three
people yeah that your business can't be
open right now or that you can't do you
think can't go enjoy whatever activity
you take your vacation or yeah yeah if
we don't stay home and stop volleying
the virus the virus will keep bouncing
and they will keep extending the stay at
home orders
I don't know how real this is but my
fear is that if we don't voluntarily
just start staying at home they will
eventually whoever they are I know I'm
smelling one of those Eddie Bravo
conspiracy theorists but there will be
some measures taken to force us to stay
at home and limit our movement right now
they are requesting and if we comply
with requests that's cool
but if we don't I think they may up
their game a little bit in the future
maybe but I'm Way more worried about the
stupid people that I am about like the
government trying to insist we stay home
I agree with that
are they almost out there Darwinian
themselves are they kind of oh for sure
like it's been really hard for me not to
be super mean on social media like if
we'll know for sure in two weeks but
like if two weeks from April 19th
because it was all this weekend if in
about two weeks the the hospital numbers
spike
this is why it's the protests yeah and
it's like it's it sucks but it's so easy
to stay home right now like it really
sucks but it's super easy to stay home
right now
it's really boring but I mean it's free
you chill I know it's not free little
worried anything delivered you can get
I've had the weirdest weirdest thing
you've had delivered what's the weirdest
camping booze ammo hand cream like we
literally made our own America and
sanitizer
we had isopropyl alcohol delivered and
delivered and my wife [ __ ] magic that
[ __ ] in a hand hand sanitizer and so
like we made homemade hand sanitizer you
had all this stuff for delivery fun for
the whole family
I've had a [ __ ] truck load of Tootsie
Pops delivered that's funny I heard your
story about string cheese yeah the my
wife's click the wrong size of string
cheese and we got like an encyclopedia
Encyclopedia Brittanica set sighs ding a
syringe the kids are happy you [ __ ] with
it because this yeah
and less diapers to change I bet after
all that yep but yeah like you can watch
anything I've got Disney Plus so we just
watched all of rescue rangers like three
times through and all of the GI Joe
episodes are up on Hasbro's YouTube
channel you can watch all the old GI Joe
cloud we're working our way through the
old duck tails now duck tails yeah I'm
loving it like just enjoying quarantine
to be over so I can watch cartoons with
you your kids kind of living the dream
over there bro it's really not that bad
once you get used to just being at home
all the time did I'm a grower and kind
of I like social don't get me wrong but
you know me if you say stay home for
seven days I'm like sure okay it's not a
problem daughters and gamers are way
more equipped to handle these
stay-at-home requests
they solutely I caught a Bert Kreischer
new comedy special
it was hot fire I saw Tom Segura's new
comedy special hotter fire I saw Chris
Delia's new special it was pretty good
and fiery but yeah there's new comedy
specials out to watch we've got I got
Netflix and Amazon Prime and Hulu and
dude so many people have been doing cool
live feeds I've been doing more live
feeds with my friends Adam ill is on
live all the time granny kind of lives
on live right now live is just boom and
live is the place
Instagram live you guys that's what I'm
talking about everyone's on Instagram
live zoom doing zoom shows I've done a
couple I did a show at Scottie I did the
cannabis 420 zoom so we've been trying
to put out extra content so we're
talking about that stay at home protests
there are people that we should give
some respect to there were medical what
do you call my because there weren't all
nurses there medical professionals
medical professionals in their scrubs
yeah we were so when how are they doing
it Michael that you'd use you were the
one that pointed out to me the article I
read in the first the first pictures I
saw in social media was two of them they
were just when the red light hit they
were just stand in the crosswalk it was
appropriate for people to be in during
that red light and then when the
crosswalk said stop get out the way they
got out the way okay they basically
cross the street back and forth and that
was their march back and forth yeah a
crosswalk they just kind of went it was
instead of crossing they just stood
there and then when it said all right
stop crossing now there's a little yeah
and they were just telling everybody go
home cuz this is [ __ ] silly and that
people are really sick in my hospital
and I'm trying not to make you a patient
also one of my favorite view they're
extra insulted oh yeah like they're
putting their safety at risk to treat
patient after patient after patient and
dealing with all sorts of fucked-up-ness
on top of it like people dying alone and
having to be there with that and having
to be the conduit of family on the phone
and like on a totally non kovat related
situation I have a family member
in hospital right now and having people
visit and not visit and can visit and
can't visit it's [ __ ] yeah not to my
uncle passed by himself had to pass my
himself a few weeks ago so yeah I'm
sorry we've got that going on bro
yeah their daughter can't leave the
hospital because she can't come back
yeah and she's the last visitor on the
list so she's literally stuck there
until this is over one way or the other
so I don't recall what everybody dude
something that I was doing something I
could have gotten hurt the other day and
I was like nope this isn't the time like
even if I just cut my I forgot what I
was like I could but oops and I was like
no no I'm I don't even need three
stitches right now would be [ __ ] way
more traumatic than it needs to be
because I got to go to the hospital and
yeah yeah I was I've been doing a lot of
stuff there's been a lot of like let's
take an extra second for safety just
because we really it's not 13 stitches
if it's 12 stitches it's happening at
home I got tape in crazy blue mic this
has been a fun podcast I'm glad we did
this
duct tape crazy glue and Vaseline yeah
I've noticed a technical glitch but I
can fix it and I know what I did wrong
so as long as I learned what I did wrong
definitely solve that problem I'm not in
my usual spot and so my microphone
discipline is [ __ ] I've noticed myself
repeatedly leaning way back in my chair
for the most accepting for picking you
up yeah the sound seems good my your
headphones yeah yeah um let's see how
long we've been doing sorry guys if
you're listening to this we're just
meandering today and kind of learning
this and going for 24 and a half minute
less than that because it'll be some
editing at the beginning there that
we'll cut up and go for a little over 20
minutes you got anything else on the
cannabis hot seat that you want to bring
up today micro should I kind of work
into another topic for the show here
[ __ ] those protesters yeah that's just
dumb [ __ ] that is just ridiculous but
other people at risk and you guys we're
gonna stop talking about the kovat
madness
it's just you got to admit it is the hot
topic it's what's on all of our minds
and it's what's got Mike and I do in
this deal like I feel like con I was
listening to one of your older shows and
you did a piece on like content
producers having kind of responsibility
right now to help keep people
entertained and I thought that was a
super legit thing they're sort of kind
of realized and embrace but also like
it's important that we're here and we
should use our our space here to
encourage people to stay home like I
know how much it sucks like I'm [ __ ]
miserable too like I fully fantasized
about like Chuck and one of my kids over
the fence the other day just this is not
getting edited so well no I did it stuff
like it's it's really tough but just do
your best
if you think about it you can stay home
now or you can stay in the hospital
later it's kind of your option that's
that's the thing that I'm so worried
about today like there were a lot of
people out not as many are there
normally out celebrating around the
Capitol this weekend but there were a
shitload of people out and like car
loads of people were packed in together
for hours driving in circles around the
Capitol packed like in heavy traffic
with other cars packed full of people
people walking around on the sidewalks
waving signs and [ __ ] in the parks and
like I get how sir crazy everyone is but
like if the smart people are right a lot
of people just got infected right all
went home tonight and shared it with
their family like in that sucks
and if the smart people are right on
this one in two weeks it's gonna be ugly
yeah yeah if those people have to people
have half of the people got sick today
if a quarter of them got sick I'm not
I'm not an epidemiologist I'm not gonna
play that game I have just described it
and compared it to the virus is almost
and this is just my simple mind to grasp
it uh and and for youngsters I was
talking to somebody much younger ah it's
like a volleyball
somebody threw a volleyball up in the
air and when it landed somebody hit it
and it broke into two and then when that
volleyball came back down somebody hit
those two and they turned in each one of
them turned into two more every time the
volleyball gets volleyed it multiplies
it becomes two more volleyballs and so
we're out there in society just volley
in these volleyballs everyone's gonna
like it's like at a [ __ ] concert in
the beach ball comes by everyone wants
to hit it no beach ball oh and he hit it
up in the air and it goes flying you
don't think anything about it now you're
infected that balls bouncing around just
infecting everybody if we would quit
bouncing the [ __ ] beach ball around
it would land on the ground and they
would deflate they would [ __ ] die and
then we could go out there not have to
worry about beach balls that's kind of
the way I think about it keep your balls
to yourself yeah super quick hey Mike
it's 420 you want to take it bad bro I
just realized we've been talking it's 15
minutes into fours for 15 minutes in the
fourth warning yeah I've got a dad
loaded let's uh let's end the plea to
stay home and like if you need better
weed like that's a good segue also this
is a good time to learn how to grow so
many people are buying seeds I see so
many people on Facebook groups and
Instagram groups about how do I grow how
do I do this now is a good time don't
them to say books and podcasts and
YouTube jacket into cannabis to get out
and clean up your yard clean up your
house I'm lucky we moved houses right
before this [ __ ] like in the middle of
February we moved and our move was kind
of chaotic so it didn't really end until
the first week of March so when they
were like alright everybody tried to
stay home I was like all right finally a
reason in peace the downside of that is
I've got a vehicle that is like bursting
with cardboard right now because I was
getting ready to go take it to the
recycle place and today I went to load
it up and go I see a notice that says
they're not because wherever they said
it is closed due to the virus and so
literally I finished loading up the car
then I checked to make sure they were
open that day and I was like got a bunch
of car
now yep yeah that's one of the fun
things I've been stockpiling if anybody
needs boxes [ __ ] let me know you
trying to build a fort no you guys just
do these boxes were sent to me by
[ __ ] Jeff business [ __ ] awesome
guy got a bunch of Bezos boxes this is
my [ __ ] 4runner is full to bursting
with cardboard dude I catch myself
ordering things online shopping they
come here and I'm like oh cool you
bought new shoes go put those in the
[ __ ] closet because you can't go
anywhere like oops it's not myself doing
that you can place narrow drums during
the quarantine though I've noticed that
all the drum equipment I buy you can
play the [ __ ] out of that during
quarantine it works really well and I'm
sure the neighbors have learned a lot of
Led Zeppelin songs the past couple of
weeks
one of my neighbors they're - they've
got a couple of girls maybe two or three
of them I that are like six eight and
twelve ish and every night at like 7:30
I think it's right after they do dinner
they go out back and scream like I can't
see them I'm just guessing from the
sound that's a local thing bro it's
called howl for Pueblo every night if
they're not howling it's right out it's
not as Wow they're just venting like
okay a lot of cities are doing weird
things to show solidarity some cities
are howling and some cities are
screaming some people are shining
flashlights into the air me and the
family did the Pueblo shines that was
awesome nice like we had fun I see you
loading up a dab what you got I'm going
with the grape Cola and I'm gonna get
myself in trouble dude that's a big dad
for you I'm kind of impressed alright so
there may be a moment of this podcast
where they're just two guys coughing
dude that's our spin-off two guys gonna
[ __ ] steal it no it's ours we're
taking it what copyright [ __ ] yeah
yeah - guys coughing I'm gonna heat
my dad nail you guys thanks for hanging
out and joining us for a zoom video I
know you're not gonna watch the video
you're not gonna see the video I agreed
with Mike that we wouldn't do video this
time we're breaking Mike in slowly but I
want to thank you for joining us for
this awkward episode of the girl from
your heart podcast the main point of
life is to have fun and enjoy yourself
it's been time with your friends and I'm
[ __ ] doing that right now
not just with Mike but all my gang here
listening in Mike's nodding his head as
he's away from his mic well he eats his
nail but he agrees thanks for hanging
out thanks for being the army Irie army
gang gang just getting this now hot and
my setup is not heat the nail from the
microphone friendly sorry warden working
out some kinks it's a skill to work the
microphone and the torch and the gear I
remember an episode and Mike is spoken
of the time that he tried to hit the
microphone he put his mouth on the mic
and then put the dab on the dab meal and
wondered why the smoke didn't flow so
yeah there's there's some tricks to this
madness sometimes I'm gonna talk until
my dad was ready overheated mine
I was just rambling not paying attention
so I made mine into lava we could
reshape the glass if we needed to I am
going to hit more of these and send Mike
a clean bang there we go I know where
there's a place that could be open for
that banger so we may have to send you
there tomorrow I'm gonna hit the Malibu
pure cush because it's what I've got on
the table it's cushy and it tastes
delicious and it's obviously working for
me it's good podcast concentrate your
batter looks really good I'm a big fan
of the batter I just listen I just
raigeki my concentrates in the crisper
drawer and I reached in and grabbed a
jar and what came out was Malibu pure
Kush that's the dad for the day all
right happy 4/20 Mike happy 4/20
everybody I'm gonna hit a dad real quick
it'll be a moment of silence but you
guys smoked with us it'll be just fine
here we go it's her bubbler bubbles and
exhales good podcasting cheers everybody
it is 4/20 we're celebrating properly
yeah Mike just wrecked himself we're
gonna let him cop for a couple of
minutes all talk over here for a moment
it was delicious you're kind of
different colors right now in the video
that's kind of cool yeah you've seen it
yeah yeah now you've seen he's watching
himself in the video guys it's [ __ ]
funny you ever watched when your friends
stare at himself in a video and forget
that he's on video that's pretty good
longtime listeners may remark that
coughing fit was pretty shallow for my
normals that was pretty good especially
for the size dab you took we could tell
that the no-smoking is working for you
bro yeah I've been able to to hit all of
my cannabis products quite a bit harder
lately good are you getting more stoned
from it what I choose to hit a martyr I
hurt myself my dad Penn knew like the
second day or second third day of
quarantine I was just puffing on it like
it's kind of wanting a cigarette and
puffing on it too much and I got up and
I went to get something in the whole
house kind of tilted like it was a boat
yeah oh [ __ ] those pins can be dangerous
just sipping on it sipping on it and
suddenly you're like oh I have been
sipping on it and it's gone and I'm
wrecked and I think your lungs kind of
get used to the pen you're heading to
they get used to the turf setup that
makes sense
I mean when I first started hitting it I
could hit it kind of but I'd COFF a
little if I hit it harder and by the
time I was ready to kill it I could sit
there and rip on it to the white flash
to me and then tap the light a couple
times or button a couple times and hit
that second pool yeah the Pens come in
handy they're not my favorite but they
do come in really handy grape Cola was
tasty all chattering you're almost
sweaty I could see you sweat from the
data so you pull off the Hat and smoking
awesome yeah I've noticed a bit since my
and I don't try to be that guy that's
like I've changed my diet I'm amazingly
healthy you guys eat what you want I can
enjoy life but I have chosen to minimize
my diet I had a birthday recently I had
a lot of things encouraged me to change
my diet I'm healthy and everything at
school I just wanted to be healthier
I haven't had I haven't if you know me
you know that I was a dr. pepper fanatic
I haven't had a dr. pepper since
Valentine's and it is now for 20 oh so
he has two days before Valentine's Day
was my last dr. pepper but dude I get so
lit sometimes now I'm not doing the I'm
not doing the caffeine up and dabs back
down a caffeine up and dabs back down
now it's normal day normal day jabs holy
[ __ ] whoa Thank You dabs like they
really get me so I've noticed and since
I've cut out all the sugary stuff I'm
not eating cookies and no donuts and
[ __ ] like that food tastes so good food
tastes better I can taste my
concentrates better - I'm not having
syrup tongue or whatever I was getting
from the dr. pepper and all the sugary
crap yeah I have to relearn food doesn't
all taste like muted cigarettes
I do miss hanging out on the porch with
you when you would smoke a cigarette
though that's kind of weird I kind of
miss my outside time too and there's no
reason to just go out on the porch and
be weird now yep I stand out back with
my bong every now and again I'm not
comfortable in my neighborhood with my
new neighbors and I'm not comfortable
dabbing on the porch I'll sit out there
and smoke a joint but I'm not down with
the dab rig and the torch on the porch
torch on the porch is our other band
name
- guys coughing and torch on a porch is
our first record we have not confirmed
Avars used to have a house like it's
gonna sound like a weird and way to say
it but it's like a major side street
it's not meant to be a main artery
through our town but it it's the main
way people get from one side of town to
the other and now I mean steady traffic
it's it's only one lane each way but if
you sat out there all day you'd always
have a car in front of you maybe get to
two or three minute gap with no traffic
but usually it's a steady stream just
out there [ __ ] dab and using a
propane torch to heat yeah yeah you guys
did go get a torch go get a vector torch
or a special blue double dragon torch
get your cell phone on crackhead torch I
got its little Ken brulee torch they
last about a year and a half two years
then all of a sudden it goes to [ __ ] one
day this doesn't work anymore of Cova do
you order another one from the internet
yeah yeah good shout out to Amazon for
keeping us safe yep the perfect time
their lives
it's almost suspicious how perfectly
everything was set up for delivery and
then we were all told to stay home but I
am NOT going to be Eddie Bravo and I'm
not gonna go that ivory well like [ __ ]
like this happen before it's just
society was substantially less able to
cope with it right but we're so lucky
right now can you imagine trying to do
this in the 90s where there's you can
get food delivery but it's pizza or
Chinese that's the [ __ ] that's it
yeah or some subway
submarine sandwich kind of place and
maybe if you're lucky a place that that
does like sandwiches or pastas would
deliver but only if you're lucky or live
in a major city yeah I was from kind of
right that's not Long Beach in
California so we could get some good
[ __ ] delivered but not much you're right
and who knows what it would have been
you know it could have been his blonde
sister central oh my god go there touch
all those videos you got HBO Showtime
Cinemax and other basic cable channels
back then my TV never really left MTV at
beavis and butt-head and [ __ ]
headbangers ball and everything you
needed was on MTV yep maybe late at
night you'd put on USA up all night but
try to catch emannuel on Cinemax you
know remember watching the boring
channels remember trying to peek through
the blurry channel blurry channels back
in the day bill that passed like 50 I
thought it was funny because the cartoon
channel was 50 and then the adult
channels were 51 up and I was like I
just go to cartoons and then scroll up
one and I can maybe catch a green boob
on the side or something people that are
our age know we're talking about trying
to watch unscrambled porn for scrambled
porn
that's weird podcast episode this is the
weirdest one of the weirdest podcast
will ever do I hope happy before 20 bro
I got lit off that bad feeling nice and
heavily medicated
yeah oh [ __ ] no no back in the day used
to have I would need so much equipment
would be say 95 I would need a camera
probably the site at least the size of a
shoebox to record this then I would need
a server probably the size of another
shoe box and then 72,000 [ __ ] cables
to make those two things work and then
listeners if you want to laugh go look
up a movie called pump up the volume oh
dude yeah dude wow I love that movie
first on the first podcast concept yeah
I think it was like baby podcasting
pirate radio yeah pirate radio we should
I should go watch that again you guys
watch that it's a great movie it's yeah
it's a really good one you may or may
not be able to pull it up for free on
YouTube there's a cool thing you can do
if you know how to do it if you type in
google docs slash pump up the volume
or Google Docs / movies pump up the
volume you'll find it in somebody's
Google Drive Google drive's or Google
Docs you can find yeah there's a way to
I can't think of how to do it right now
at the top of my head but our listeners
that are tech savvy are gonna figure it
out you can find other movies in
people's google drives that are open and
you can watch it from their Drive I know
the future is awesome Mike I was gonna
say is now old man now yeah yeah now all
we need
I bought Mike I'm not trying to say I
bought Mike but we got Mike about about
130 bucks worth of equipment that's
really well you got the focus right that
was about a hundred bucks the Mike was
like 45 yeah yeah like less than 250
bucks worth the gear we got Mike going
and he's on a video chat with me we're
looking each other face-to-face like
real-time there's no lag this is [ __ ]
awesome I expected a little bit of delay
there zero lag happen and makes it super
nice so yeah we're a yes we didn't get
flying cars but we got the viruses from
the movies and we got all the phone [ __ ]
from the movies we did not get the
flying cars if I had a flying car I'm
afraid of flying cars in our
neighborhood bro people would be falling
from the sky running out of gas on the
way to work exactly yeah so it'd just be
the one dimensional travel than a few of
us would just be like [ __ ] it
wouldn't be cool alright Mike we have
been going for long enough to where I
think we should start wrapping this up
because we're getting way off topic but
it's been fun I want to make sure that
we've got a successful show so they do
like it when we ramble and this is gonna
be a bonus post for 20 [ __ ] episode
dude thank you for hanging out thank you
for finding making time to do a [ __ ]
zoo show with me I look forward to doing
these watch the schedule more because
you're good at and now that you're
comfortable you got a little flow you're
doing I like this we're gonna have to do
some [ __ ] my background before we do
video but they're gonna love it they
like content right now especially with
the the quarantine Ian and caronian
situation hit us up on social media tell
us you
did and we'll do more that's it you can
send us an email I grow from your heart
at hotmail.com you can send me a tweet
my tweeter is @gf wih podcast might tell
the kind folks how they can find you on
the social media you can find me on
twitter @ @ need more Punk 15 or at
Facebook at Puebla for sensible cannabis
laws excellent ladies and gentlemen boys
and girls pimps and hos friends and foes
smokers and growers if you feel like
this episode was educational informative
or entertaining you'd like to support
the show financially you can do so by
visiting www.americanoutback.net here
now calm don't forget to use coupon code
in it checkout save yourself a few bucks
it seeds here now calm Mike I want to
thank you again for joining me bro
thanks for setting up all that gear
thanks for being patient with me getting
etat ah thanks for the family for giving
me some time to do it I did not prepare
a shout out for this show Mike do you
have anybody out there that you would
like to give a shout out to you just
looked at me that's the truth let's just
do it that way big shout out to all my
friends staying home and taking care of
themselves and their families in each
other
Mike thank you again for joining me
everybody else out there until next time
take a phat dad and give your mom a hug
for me
[Music]
yes
music wow
sometimes the things that means the
light maybe that's all the time it's
gonna be easy I solve it for tomorrow
mana and guitar still hope the wicked
side
I'm feeling good
[Music]
love is the harder on Sunday you better
find it
I'm a big man I put my problems behind
me I smoke marijuana I stay up on the
weekends and flower
[Music]
we also say we keep some details some
music on my music will burn up a dance
[Music]
party marijuana is my sacrum and I smoke
the marijuana
[Music]
we got the phone to make your donkeys
make document cell phones we got the
diesel diesel we gots to know for the
people we got the idea to Raisa spoke
and get wiser
Charlie stop smoking smoking marijuana
hundreds upon the wicked
sometimes the things are needed light
may be difficult not all the time it's
gonna be easy
I saw we gonna smoke the marijuana hon
get stay up on the kids I'm feeling very
good about myself big on same feeling
good well and that's the problem I
smooth the marijuana yet boom Dubi kids
[Music]
you gotta find