all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world I'm your host Rasta Jeff
and it is time for episode 527 of the
growth from your heart podcast this
episode of the show is brought to you by
our friends at seeds here now.com seeds
here now.com carry seeds from all the
industry's favorite readers including
miss Jill genetics Duke diamond and of
course I region etics everything at
seeds here now.com is backed by their
award-winning satisfaction guarantee and
for my friends on a budget seeds here
now.com offers several packs for under
$30 as well as amazing monthly deals use
coupon code she fyh ten while checking
out to save a few bucks
again that is coupon code g-f white H
ten to save a few bucks at seeds here
now dot-com you know I like to start
this podcast off by talking about what
I'm smoking today I've been taking dad's
of cowboy Kush full-spectrum extract
from Green Dot labs this is a blend of H
a og and star dog on the package the
flavor is described as earthy fuel and
leather on the back the potency label
says the product does contain sixty four
point eight eight percent THC I am
thoroughly satisfied and impressed with
the cowboy Kush full-spectrum extract
this was a for a gram jar I say four
gram jar because now it is a zero gram
jar it started off with big chunky
diamonds just the right amount of Terp
sauce this was a beautiful presentation
the flavor and aroma were perfect and
the buzz was delicious I feel like I'm
sitting back in the chair I'm kind of
mellow I'd like to go grab some snacks
but that would be a never-ending process
right now so big shout out to our
friends at green dot Labs for the
delicious cowboy Kush full spectrum
extract ladies and gentlemen in this
episode I'm going to read some listener
emails before we get there let's do some
shoutouts to a few of the folks who
support the show on patreon let's start
off by giving a big shout out to my
buddy Tanner M let's send a big shout
out to my buddy sour D I want to send a
giant shout out to my friend farmer John
how about a big THANK YOU shout out to
Keith K I always have a giant shout out
to my friend Black Bird 76 let's send a
big thank-you shoutout to my
buddy Cass Burton let's into big thank
you shout out the big toe grows let's
send some love to my buddy Tommy I've
always got a DAB for my buddy Ned Denver
let's send a big THANK YOU to fat rabbit
I've got a huge thank you and a shout
out to EZ oh five seven I know what that
means bro and last but not least let's
send a big giant thank you shout out to
my buddy oh gee purple thumb big thank
you big shout-out to everybody who
supports the show on patreon if you're
not supporting the show and you would
like to learn how to do so
all you have to do is visit
www.reimaverick.com
thank you guys for all of the support
and I did get a special email from a
listener and this one says yo me and my
buddy THC activator were able to put
some paintings together to finally give
back to you for all the [ __ ] awesome
information and genetics we just wanted
to thank you and see if it would be
possible you could give us both a shout
out that would be awesome but if not I
understand my name is G farms 401 on
cannabis and my buddy is THC activator
thanks again brother
well hey you guys thank you for the
patreon contribution thank you for
listening thank you for the great
message big shout out to my friends G
farms 401 and THC activator for the
patreon contributions and the continued
love and support I can't do it without
friends like you first of all I need
listeners if I'm just up here talking
that makes me crazy you guys listening
makes me not a psychopath so thank you
for that and also the patreon
contributions those go a long way that
is how I keep all of the gear running
the technical equipment lives through
all of your contributions also I pay for
the website I pay for the internet
connection I pay for these little fuzzy
microphone covers so without your love
and patreon support it would not happen
in the words of encouragement and the
thank you that goes as far as the
patreon support that means a lot to me
people reaching out saying thank you
giving me a high-five a digital virtual
fist bump excuse the throat clearing
that was gross
but everybody reaching out showing me
some love that means a lot to me you
guys thank you I do appreciate that so
big shout out once again I'm gonna grab
the paper and make sure I don't [ __ ] it
up big shout out to my friend G farms
401 on cannabis give them a follow on
cannabis and also our friend THC
activator big love big respect big
thanks to everybody who does support the
show and while I'm dishing out
thank-yous let's send a big THANK YOU
over to my buddy Mike for joining me on
Zoom on the last episode that was a
great time I had a lot of fun we had a
great chat we had a good hangout big
thanks to everybody who listened to that
episode I was a good time doing two guys
coughing if you listen to the episode
you've got that joke it was a great time
thank you and also thank you Mike once
again bro let's do that again
and I want to get more people on my zoom
show we will do zoom shows and record
the audio and release those as podcasts
when I get comfortable I do intend to
zoo to do zoom videos I apologize for
the stuttering today we're gonna blame
that on the cowboy Kush full-spectrum
extract it's got me my tongue got caught
on my teeth and I could not see what I
was saying all right ladies and
gentlemen this is going to be a fun
episode I'm in a good mood I'm nice and
stoned about a good day ah it's nice
weather it's finally not cold it was
sixty something degrees today where I
live that may not be warm where you live
quit showing off California where I live
that was super nice it's gonna start
getting super nice really soon and
pretty soon they say they are going to
lift the quarantine restrictions I'm
excited for that I honestly don't know
how excited I am to get back in public I
don't know it's mixed emotions but just
to know I'm allowed to go back outside
and things may get normal again as me
feeling excited once I get out there
we'll see how my OCD and my germophobia
really does with being out there in
public again I'm gonna try not to talk
too much about quarantine and kovat
we're just gonna make a time stamp on
this episode I am recording this on
Friday April 24th we are currently like
several days into a quarantine kovat
situation so if you're listening to this
in the future this was actually recorded
during the kovat lockdown it's [ __ ]
weird it's just as weird as everybody
said but nothing too crazy has happened
to where I am that's your time stamp
that's your historical moment let's move
forward the first email on today's
episode comes from a longtime listener
I'm not
sure if they want their name said but
the email honestly i printed the email
out and this was the last print from
that ink cartridge so there are a few
words missing the email is a little
fuzzy on the paper I can make out what
it says it goes something a little bit
like this it says hey Rasta Jeff I never
miss an episode of The Grove from your
heart podcast and I usually catch the
live feed every Monday night thank you
that means a lot to me every Monday
night I do a live Instagram feed I go
live 710 mountain time I usually hang
out for about an hour I talk about
cannabis and I answer random questions
join me if you're available I'm Irene
underscore genetics on Instagram check
out the live feed this listener goes on
to say I am a caregiver in Michigan and
you have taught then the next sentence
gets cut out I'm gonna hope it says I
have taught you a lot I'm gonna hope it
doesn't say that I've taught you
anything terrible and taught you bad
habits but it does go on to say I have
two quick questions on episode 523 you
mentioned rosin wasn't your concentrate
of choice why is that I'm an old school
flour smoker but literally then a lot of
it gets cut out a full line then I can
read concentrate because the majority
were being made using solvents but it's
hard to read that but the next sentence
says solvent free I thought this was the
best route to go I'm new to all this and
I thought I would really like to know
the difference now I did read this email
before I printed it I think this
listener does not have a lot of
experience with concentrates and they
are considering buying a rosin press
because that is a very affordable and
efficient way to make concentrates at
home it is also very safe so they were
considering purchasing a rosin presses
what I do believe if I'm correct so
they're asking why I have said that
rosin is not my favorite concentrate I
do not prefer rosin I like BHO
concentrates I like full-spectrum
extracts I like batters those are what I
prefer that is not made with Roz and I
think the rosin tastes a little bit
funky to me it always has a hint of a
burnt popsicle sort of a flavor I do
have one friend who makes quality rosin
but it is quite an extensive process he
makes bubble hash out of fresh frozen I
may be inaccurate on some of these
statements some
these details I believe he is fresh
freezing concentrate making bubble hash
out of that then fresh freezing or
freeze drying be concentrate then he is
making pressed rosin from back
concentrate so there are a lot more
steps when you remove the vegetative
part the flower part from the press it
makes thing taste he makes things taste
much better sorry that was hard for my
face to say the process of squishing raw
flower
it makes the final product taste much
better I don't think you get as much of
that burnt popcorn flavor if you
actually press bubble hash if you make
hash out of it then press the bubble
hash it's a full another step it's a
whole another process that's a lot more
work but it really drastically improves
the quality of the concentrate so if
you're going to make rosin I recommend
you follow Pedro's grow room on
Instagram and on YouTube he teaches a
lot of great techniques on making
high-quality rosin it is not my favorite
unless Pedro makes it I would not buy
rosin from anybody but Pedro
hypothetically if you were to make some
available so I am not a huge fan of
rosin that is my personal preference
there are thousands of people out there
who really love rosin it's just not for
me I like to smoke pho I like sauce and
diamonds I really prefer the batters
lately something about a nice batter a
greendot batter a good apothecary batter
just a nice dull up in the middle of the
container it's got a nice texture to it
a good flavor and when you hit it
there's something that does in the lungs
it has a nice expansion to feel smooth I
can get a big fat hit it tastes real
nice I don't have any hatred toward
rosin it is just not for me I think that
um what's the food that I don't like I
can't even think of a food I don't like
jelly freaking anything I'm a vegetarian
so we'll just say steak isn't there's
nothing wrong with it it's just not for
me
you guys didn't eat steak do that rosin
is steak is just not for me I'd prefer
to have something different so that's my
comparison just personal preference I
don't think it tastes good it hits hard
and it gets me high it's just not my
favorite thing so that's a long rent on
that then there is a part two of this
question it says another grower podcast
at a quick video a couple of months ago
about pa-ching and said you always need
to put your
pH down or pH up in water to dilute that
solution before adding it to your
nutrient reservoir because if you dump
it straight in with your newts and then
again the sentence gets cut out but I'm
gonna say there's a risk of a chemical
reaction or that acid or base in your pH
balancing solution and possibly disrupt
the nutrients that you just put into
that mix I understand why they could say
that that is a very um that's almost too
much detail to worry about I don't think
that's gonna be a thing most folks are
going to be mixing maybe a cap full of
pH up or pH down into their solution
you've got a five-gallon bucket you're
putting very little pH a pH down in
there I don't think it's going to be
enough chemical to cause any problem at
that rate the nutrients you've already
added to that water are elated and
buffered they're protected basically
from that other chemical reaction you're
putting in there I'm not a chemist I'm
not a scientist but I don't think that
those products are powerful enough to
cause any damage in small delusions now
in a commercial environment we're
putting a hundred milliliters 250 mils
of pH down in a solution at a time that
may need to be diluted that could be a
good idea to dilute that with a cup of
water then pour that in when you're
going with larger batches that may
really be helpful but for the basic home
grower in a small batch of nutrients
with a small mix I don't think it would
be necessary but if you've got crazy OCD
and you want to be extra detailed that
could be a thing that you could do it
could not hurt but I don't find it to be
absolutely necessary for the small grow
environment keep in mind I did preface
that by saying zero chemistry experience
I have zero chemistry knowledge I don't
have any papers that say I'm good at
chemistry so I'm not really qualified to
give that answer I'm just telling you
that I've never seen a problem and the
thousands if not millions of [ __ ]
batches of nutrients I've mixed so I
want to thank you for sending a great
email I think we've been chatting a
little bit corresponding through email I
think I've answered a couple of your
questions you may have actually
supported me a little bit so I thank you
for all off the love and support I do
know your name I don't know if you want
it set on the show but thank you I do
appreciate the great message if you have
more questions
please send them my way I will get them
on the show if I don't get them on the
show
I'll answer privately thank you for the
support if anybody else out there has an
e as a question my email address is grow
from your heart at hotmail.com
I would love to get your listener
generated cannabis cultivation or
cannabis culture question here on the
show you guys that cowboy pushes got me
[ __ ] up I'm talkative today let's keep
flowing we've got a couple of great
questions which one are we gonna do
first they're both right here in front
of me this one is gonna work well it
says Rasta Jeff I appreciate all of your
knowledge on the podcast I have a quick
question about carbon filters very good
question you guys how often do you
recommend changing the whole filter I've
changed out the dust filter but I've
noticed a little PM and the humidity is
starting to rise a bit I've been using
it for a year they have to be replaced
or just the outer dust filter the smell
has been in check but I'm a little bit
concerned with the PM I just added a fan
in the corner and ordered a new clip on
oscillating fan prior to that I only had
one small clip-on fan maybe I just need
more airflow I'm in a 4x4 and the
relative excuse me the relative humidity
has been 50 to 60 percent you're a
little bit high there we need to lower
that humidity the temps are around 72
with lights on 60 with the lights off
I'm running to Mars ts 1,000 LEDs thank
you Jeff from AJ all right there are a
few things we need to address here in
this question yes you do need to replace
that carbon filter I think the
manufacturer recommends every two years
I don't know how much air you're running
through there I don't know what size
blower you purchased I don't know what
size carbon filter you've got I don't
know how big the room is I don't know
other environmental factors to put into
my brain equation here I don't know how
much stank and dust and dirt and pollen
and powdery mildew and humidity have
gone through that filter most
manufacturers say 18 to 28
I think it's 26 what's the [ __ ] in 18 to
30 months I'm trying to do math in my
head
they say one and a half to two and a
half years they recommend about a two
year change you're saying that so it is
time to change it probably because
you've got a lot of other factors you've
had powdery mildew in there
the humidity is raising the humidity
will lessen the effectiveness and
lifelong the longevity of your filter
you've also had powdery mildew I would
consider swapping out that filter just
because of the powdery mildew I know
it's going into there and then going out
but I don't know powdery mildew that
makes me paranoid I wouldn't want to get
that again so it is probably time or
close to time to changing out that
filter if it's in the budget it is
something I would consider now you said
that you had powdery mildew also you
asked about the the outer filter if that
thing is dirty
give it one clean with oxy clean rinse
it out one time put it back the next
time it gets dirty that is generally
when I say that it's time to replace the
filter if it's getting that much dust in
it it's showing you that it's getting
really dirty on the inside it's probably
gonna stop taking out the smell real
well you say it doesn't stink
that's your grow you also don't think
your armpits stink when your girlfriend
leans on you and goes god you need a
[ __ ] shower we don't notice some
smells we get noseblind to certain
things bring somebody new into the house
and see if they notice that grow that's
how you know if the filter works bring
the landlord over see if they notice
that's how you know if the carbon filter
works now we're talking we've talked
about changing out the filter that dust
cover needs to be clean needs to be
replaced needs to be put it back on run
it again
check for smell if you're confident but
there's no smell you may be okay I'm
concerned with the powdery mildew in
there that may be alright I don't think
you're gonna blow it back out it just
makes me worried keep beings clean it
shouldn't smell if you smell it swap it
out now what has me concerned you said
that the humidity is high and what you
have done to fix the powdery mildew is
to add a fan a fan is a good start but
that is not going to lower the humidity
we need a way to remove the humidity
from the room and that can be done
through an exhaust fan by sucking the
air up through the top of the tent or
that can be done by placing a
dehumidifier in the actual tent but I
don't think that a fan is going to solve
the powdery mildew problem it will slow
it down
and will make it longer it will make it
take longer to appear but I don't think
it's going to be the solution so find a
way to lower that humidity 50 to 60
percent when you get into flour is going
to be ridiculous
and you're also going to have more
vegetation in the room at that time
you'll have big buds you'll have more
leaves you'll be watering more
frequently you're going to have more
opportunity and more reason for powdery
mildew to pop up I recommend some way to
get that humidity out of there
I also recommend maybe a harder
defoliation and that should do it for
you d foliate take some leaves out of
there and then just learn how to lessen
the humidity overall in the room exhaust
at the top dehumidifier something like
that is going to be required so you do
need to replace that filter I would say
about a year 18 months in I don't go
over two years of course I grow super
stinky weed I've got just the right size
filter the appropriate size blower so
that lasts about 18 18 months two years
you're gonna want to reduce your
humidity or that powdery mildew will
keep coming back it sounds like we got
you figured out bro you've got that clip
on fan and another fan and maybe time to
add an exhaust fan to the top of the
grow tent I want to thank my friend AJ
for the great grow question you guys I'm
gonna take a quick drink of some water
here I'm not gonna press pause please
bear with me you folks on the video if
the video ever comes out you get to
watch me take a sip so here we go take
an eclipse it quick sip join me hydrate
motherfuckas
well I needed that more than I realized
that was pretty damn refreshing drink
some water you guys all right I've got
another messenger in front of me let me
get my [ __ ] together this one goes a lot
like this it starts off with hey Geoff
firstly sorry for the loss of your uncle
hey thank you I appreciate the
condolences I appreciate the support
I miss my uncle thank you for the love
it goes on to say I just wanted to share
some pictures of my lemon Geoffrey and
ask you a co2 question I did look at the
pictures and your plants look great you
guys out there in podcast land imagine
some beautiful lemon Geoffrey plants
they're [ __ ] perfect now we'll keep
going it says I'm absolutely loving the
podcast I think you're doing a fantastic
job educating your listeners and helping
us focus on things to help us all become
better growers during these difficult
times that's awesome - thank you
now it says first question is about co2
during the vegetative state is there any
benefit to running co2 during veg yes
running co2 during veg will make your
plants grow more quickly you'll get more
rapid growth you'll get better use of
your nutrients you're feeding the plants
high-quality nutrients hopefully we've
got them under high-quality lighting if
you can afford it and the room is
designed properly yes co2 will
absolutely increase the performance of
your plants right now general
atmospheric conditions are approximately
400 ppm of co2 particles per million of
co2 depending on where you are that
could be more or less about 50 ppm or 50
ppm is less based on your location your
altitude will have something to do with
that but generally we're sitting about
400 particles per million of co2 in the
general atmosphere our plants can eat
much greater volumes of co2 than that
they'll get a much higher performance
environment going on you'll see it if
you do it they'll notice so I'm gonna
keep going cuz I'm rambling I wanna get
myself back on track it says my second
question is how much and for how long do
I run co2 this is my first attempt at
running co2 I've started on day one a
flower okay I would have done it in bed
but you started in a flower you're
putting him into turbo charge that's
cool
my setup consists of a five by four tent
with a high output for evergreen indoor
uniformity Pro LED uh not familiar with
that light sounds fancy if it's working
for you that's awesome I know what size
tent that is it says I'm running two
five-gallon drain science air pots with
Pro mix and nectar of the Gods this is
all making sense so far I've got an
autopilot co2 meter and controller I had
said it 1,200 ppm that is gonna work
well for you that will work my tent runs
around 80 to 85 degrees with RH around
60 you might want to reduce that RH just
a little bit during lights on AC
Infinity fans handle the exhaust I have
two oscillating fans and two stationary
fans in the tent should I run the co2
until harvest or is this a waste and is
1202 much too little or just right
alright there are a couple of things to
talk about in that uh you were doing it
correctly I would reduce the overall
humidity and I think if you've got the
LEDs eighty to eighty-five maybe cool
the oscillating fans and stationary fans
are cool uh should I run it till harvest
yes I would run it right up until the
day of harvest you are not wasting it at
that point 1200 is good 14 is good 16 is
when you're kind of pushing it 1600
PPM's is that's when you're kind of
maybe wasting it 14 you're like oh yeah
1200 is great um there's something that
got my attention though where is it
there's a wine and exhaust fan let me
read back my tail AC infiniti fans
handle the exhaust my question is are
you exhausting out your co2 are you
wasting your co2 with that exhaust
process you've got a very small
environment it's not going to take a lot
of air movement to exhaust out all of
the co2 you were generating so is the
co2 in the tent
are you exhausting that tent into a room
how big is that room how much co2 is
happening in that room are we able to
cycle that co2 back into the tent
if you have got co2 happening and you
can minimize the humidity I may reduce
the exhaust fans and not run them or run
them very minimally because you don't
want to keep sucking out that co2 it's
expensive you don't want to keep going
and buying tanks or whatever you're
doing to generate the co2 I would think
of cost-effective ways to set this up I
don't know what your full environment is
I don't know where the tent is located
but are you wasting co2 by pumping it
right out of the tent every time your
exhaust fan comes on hopefully it's
going into a bedroom and office the
spare room whatever and hopefully it's
just drawing that right back in maybe it
mixes with the atmosphere and the rest
of the room and it can come back in you
get a little fresh air with it I'm not
sure but if you're pumping co2 you can
turn off the exhaust fans as long as the
heat and humidity don't get too high so
that's a juggle a balancing act you're
gonna have to dial in there but it
sounds like you're doing things
correctly you've got the meter the
controller it sounds like you're doing
it right now as long as the co2 goes off
when the lights go off I think
everything will be cool but my advice is
to make sure you were running that
correctly but you're not sucking it all
out with your exhaust because that will
get very expensive it says feel free to
share my pictures if you choose to use
the question on the show I can also feel
free to use my name alright big shout
out to my friend Sauer D bro you're
killing it with that lemon Jeffrey I
hope I answered your co2 question 1200
is good 14 is high 16 is [ __ ] really
high 18 is when people go what are you
doing bro so you're right in the right
ballpark you were doing it correctly do
it while the lights are on
turn the co2 off when the lights go off
and I do recommend using it at the
vegetative stage I generally start co2
kind of low 6 or 800 ppm s in bed and
then about every week I increase a
little bit until we're into that beefy
bloom stage and then you'll notice the
performance increase and take notes
write down how much you're paying for
the co2 and how often you buy it and
then see how much performance increase
you get at the end you get a better
harvest you get more yield was it worth
it do it two or three times and find out
if it's worth that extra trip to the
store the extra equipment the extra
effort see the extra money see if it's
actually worth it
all right sour D I want to thank you for
a great message if you've got any more
questions please send me another email
all right I've got one more message here
and this one says what's up Rasta Jeff
I'm a huge fan of all you do with
breeding and the podcast thank you that
means a lot to me thanks for checking
out multiple aspects of my work
it also says my son kiss is looking
great I'm flipping her into flour today
I feel like we have similar taste in
music and I think that you would love
Fat Freddy's drop let me know what you
think of them or if you already are a
fan stay Irene have a happy 4/20 thank
you brother my 4/20 was [ __ ] Irie when
it is signed from doctor you or Doc
Holliday on cannabis hey doc thank you
for the great email I'm going to wrap up
this episode by playing a little bit of
music from Fat Freddy's
drop that'll be coming right up big
shout out big thank you to my friend dr.
you ladies and gentlemen boys and girls
pimps and hos friends and foes smokers
and growers clone cutters and pollen
chuckers all you sexy cultivators out
there I want to thank you again for
listening to another episode of The
Grove from your heart podcast if you
feel like this episode was educational
informative or just entertaining and
you'd like to make a financial
contribution to the show you can do so
by visiting www.caincarroll.com I would
also appreciate it if you subscribe to
my youtube channel go to youtube search
for the girl from your heart a podcast
click Subscribe maybe even type in some
comments and let me know what you think
about the show ladies gentlemen that is
all I've got for you for this episode I
want to thank you again for listening
I'll be back in a few days with fresh
new content I want to give a giant shout
out to my buddy Papa Roni and until next
time take a phat dad and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]
getting so tired for these big prize
[Applause]