all right welcome back podcast world it
is time for episode 530 of the grow from
your heart podcast joining me via zoom
for his first time on video is white
Mike welcome to the show bro what's up
man what's up everybody dude thank you
for joining me you look good you sound
good this is gonna be a really good time
brave new world folks brave new world
some positive [ __ ] did come out of the
quarantine if you wouldn't again if we
would not have gotten locked down I
don't think we ever would have ended up
doing this but gfy it's on video podcast
brought to you by corona whoa
the virus the virus not the beer yeah is
gonna say clear that is the beer still a
thing ah man I feel sorry for the beer
company we should I don't drink but I
feel like I should just buy a bunch of
Carabas just because ya start drinking
because of the [ __ ] virus would be
like a way to deal with that no don't do
that guys don't that's not a good shut
down temporarily for all of this and
that's just is it because they don't
have people to make the beer they gotta
send the people home or is it just
nobody's buying the damn beer does sales
plummeted yeah that's - it's just like
the toilet paper thing there's no
[ __ ] rhyme or reason to it it's just
people heard coronavirus and they're
like oh [ __ ] dude switched Modelo herd
mentality sheep logic I get it bro me
unzoom this is awesome having a good
time you look good you sound great thank
you being here this episode of the girl
from your heart podcast is brought to
you by our friends at seeds here now.com
seeds here now.com carries seeds from
all the industry's favorite breeders
including miss Jill genetics Duke
diamond and of course I read genetics
everything it seeds here now.com is
backed by their award-winning
satisfaction guarantee for my friends on
a tight budget seeds here now.com offers
several packs for under 30 bucks as well
as amazing monthly sales to save
yourself a few more bucks use coupon
code key wih 10 while checking out at
seeds here now.com again that is coupon
code G F Y H 10 while checking out at
seeds here now dot-com awesome in this
episode of two dudes coughing I am
dabbing some stuff called first matter
premium concentrates this is no
just be viewers today and get to see
what we're dabbing yes yes this is a
good time it's the first time they'll
actually get a view of what we're dad
and on if my sweaty hands can get this
childproof container open it's making
that Skippy sound where it's hard to
open there we go this is first matter
premium concentrates this is a new
company
it says contains marijuana keep away
from children on the back of the package
it says this product contains 94.4% THC
a it's one gram of how come e crystals I
was gifted this by a friend via another
friend shoutout to friends passing
things along for friends when you crack
open this jar this was a 1 gram fat
diamond I'm going to put on a dabber and
show the camera yeah this company
specializes in just straight-up mole
rocks THC a diamonds if you're watching
this on the camera on the video that is
real that is a THC a diamond I've
already dabbed about half of its this is
half of what was left and it half of
what was in the container and it was a
gift an it was specially selected for me
so it may have been bigger than a gram
but that was a very beautiful diamond it
is odorless and it is flavorless but it
is very potent when you dab it ah it
makes your arm my arm hair stand up it
made me get real talkative I got red my
body temperature went up I took a
[ __ ] big dab also ah it was I really
liked it
then the person who gave it to me
recommended she's like I know you you
probably have some turps sauce or
something I really like it when you mix
it with a little bit of Terp sauce of
course you know me I've got some turps
sauce I've got this a little 10 gram jar
of lemon oh gee Terp sauce from our
friends at apothecary farms so I put a
little chunk of that concentrate on the
just on the table and then I dipped it
into a little bit of this sauce try to
get that on the camera there a little
bit that's just liquid terpenes in the
lord
cannabis derived terpenes yeah that is a
high Servius full-spectrum extract
that's probably 7 or 8 grams left in
that jar there but we put some of that
on it and that was tremendous the high
goes straight to the face just Kapow
instantly as soon as you daddy like oh
whoa I might be in trouble and you get I
got real high for a minute um kind of
almost too talkative almost racy
almost a paranoid sort of a thing
but once it settles in I was loving it I
was super high like psychedelic high
like let's go do some [ __ ] good concert
kind of a buzz unfortunately we're just
hanging out here at the house so but it
was a great buzz so shout out to our new
friends from first matter premium
concentrates they didn't pay to be on
the show they didn't ask for anything
like that they threw me a grandma
concentrates and I [ __ ] approve and
that's a really good way to get yourself
on the show I just have to like your
product that's really the way to do it
if I don't like your product I won't put
you on the show because why would I
share it with my friends Mike I feel
like I've been talking a long time about
what I've been smoking on would you like
to share with us what you're smoking
today sure most of what I've been
smoking today is this Sour Diesel
ambrosia nice bed up there is that
coming through folks there's not a lot
of light down here it's kind of coming
throughout the video show though it's
pretty good to me I would dab that it's
wonderful nice diamonds delicious sauce
it's it's doing his damn job I'll tell
you that much just gonna say you sound
stoned not a lot of details just bash
worked yeah alright well Mike is smoking
Sour Diesel ambrosia from our friends at
apothecary Farms um not to be a hater of
your concentrate I am NOT a fan of Sour
Diesel concentrates but I love the Sour
Diesel flowers something about
extracting it doesn't bring that proper
essence in my opinion it loses something
for sure but I was missing the sour deed
and that's what was available the buzz
is still there so if you want that sour
dehy but yeah the buzz the high the met
is the medication whatever the effect
you're gonna get that but I don't think
it's just something about the salary I
want that you can smell it through the
bag in my pocket like who's got that
diesel like that's the kind of diesel
that I love and I missed that when you
smoke it everybody for four miles looks
where'd you go in damn your weed smells
good we were spoiled here for a lot of
the years with good diesel everywhere I
had a couple of friends who grew that
diesel shoutout to those guys for doing
a really good job one of them listens to
the show so big ups dude I hope you're
doing well
yeah we sure do man go somewhere that's
our D I'll take a little bit of it my
legal limit that's what I'll take um
Mike this is the portion of the show
where we do shoutouts to
our friends who support the show on
patreon I was rolling up digital joints
and passing up digital bong loads that
seemed to suck up a lot of time and I
also got really tongue-tied during all
of that [ __ ] so all of my friends from
patreon you all get a DAB a bong rip and
edible and a pre-roll to take home so
let's send them all a shout out let's
start off with giant Mike and the Davin
Queen listen to Big Shot it's a heli
I got a big giant shout-out to my friend
e 205 7 um no it's easy oh five seven
sorry I can't read my own damn
handwriting I know what oh five seven
means bro that's [ __ ] rad big
shout-out to are you lighting up Tim big
shout out to our friend Kurt Z I always
got a big pinche shot that's my buddy
Lobster Bush let's send a big thank-you
shout out to my friend Karen Crawford a
big giant thank you shout out to Michael
W and last but certainly not least I
want to send a big thank you shout out
to my buddy baked p WN big thanks big
shot a to everybody who continues to
support the show on patreon if you're
not supporting the show and you would
like to learn how to do so all you have
to do is visit www.payoor.com it easy
also for the very first time I would
like to introduce white Mike's patreon
campaign all you have to do to support
white Mike is go to patreon.com/scishow
several times he brings a lot of great
and all his information several times
J's I think he's been on a hundred
episodes we were talking earlier take
yeah I'm gonna guess easily you're on a
quarter of the shows for a while you run
a long stretch I'm gonna say you've been
on hundred shows
Mike is very articulate he's well-spoken
he's got really good opinions I respect
his thoughts and opinions his thought
process most of what he says really
makes sense to me it's okay that I had
disagree with you occasionally that's
why we're good friends but most of the
time he's [ __ ] spot-on so that's my
ad for Mike please support my friend
white Mike he is a cannabis soldier a
cannabis
if he's out there doing different things
but we need him on the team so if you're
if you're supporting the girl from your
heart podcast you definitely want to
support white Mike so patreon.com
forward slash white Mike bro I'm proud
of you for getting the video show going
and a patreon campaign
welcome to 2020 yeah it's one it's one
is here baby
you've been in 2015 for a minute so I'm
proud of you for making it this far yeah
we've been on lockdown for a minute I
had to get inventive in patreon and some
video episodes I think it's gonna be no
way to do it for a minute I think it'll
be great and it's a good way to make a
positive out of a negative but people
need some entertainment they want to get
their mind off of things and seeing our
smiley or whatever you want to call it
our pasty faces here on the screen is a
good way for people to escape and also
learn something they're hanging out with
us we could pass them a virtual [ __ ]
joint like this they could grab it
through the screen there you go and then
they can hang out and they can learn
they can get educated and it's [ __ ]
free so that is really cool yeah I'm
gonna I'm missing the flowers man I need
flowers down in my bunker but I've been
keeping the flowers outside at this new
place oh man that's new hash only in the
bunker how effective the no smoking oh
okay all right um I'm this I don't know
if this is anybody else's getting this
but I am very confused by the seasons
and the time of year right now I keep
forgetting that it is spring and going
into summer I keep feeling like we just
got [ __ ] for a summer and we're going
into winter I've been shopping online
and most of my clothes are fall and
winter appropriate that I've purchased
you tell yourself all the way to the end
of the year already know something about
the lockdown
I just I'm like well we got [ __ ] for
spring I didn't see the spring happen
like I normally do and it was cold and
so I guess I'm used to it as being cold
and I thought it was going to continue
to be cold or something I don't know my
brain was you went inside when it was
cold out your body hasn't told you it's
summer yet yeah we haven't had that for
20 well we should have had a 4/20 party
we should add an Easter party we should
add a st. Patrick's Day party there
should have been so many things to tell
my mind and body that we've progressed
in the year instead it's been Groundhog
Day I'm just doing the same [ __ ]
Tuesday every day dude every day is
Tuesday I don't know about you listeners
but the the
Groundhog Day thing that's [ __ ] rude
legit during the lockdown it is weird
um every day the same hopefully people
are listening to this what would be the
future from now so I don't try to dwell
too much on the kovat 19 thing but just
an update we are recording late night on
April 27th 2020 we're currently how many
weeks dude six weeks in the morning on
the 27th yeah yeah we're we six weeks
into the quarantine : 19 situation now
March 26 this were a month okay and it
is been I haven't really I've left and
I've gone a few places I haven't gone
anywhere to go enjoy and be somewhere
since March 12th 12th of March was the
last time I've really gone out I've seen
a few people because there are a few
things that were almost necessary
interactions like like things that just
have to happen I've gone to the grocery
store I've gone to the dispensary I've
seen you once or twice there were brief
interactions but I know she talked too
much about that but they had to happen
we had to get equipment how are you
gonna record it you didn't get equipment
from me so let me teach you there silly
to me that was already mailed to you
yeah I mean there was no way to teach
you it was like to have to see him to
teach him this so there was one good one
one equipment lesson but it's been kind
of strange I'm adapting well like I've
talked about previous times I'm a grower
I'm kind of a hermit I'm good at being a
hermit I've been practicing this
isolation the isolation games since I
was a teenager since high school so this
wasn't too bad for me and Mike I know
you're kind of a gamer and you've got
only an oarsman and then yeah the kids
at home that opes yeah you've got
entertainment or whatever you want to
call it all day long yeah like a couple
days back me and my oldest case for
almost five we went for a drive for the
first time in like three weeks and now
we hit the highway and as soon as we got
on the highway was like dad it feels
like we're flying we were doing like 35
miles an hour just we had just gotten on
highway I just hit the gas he was like
oh wow it's like Oh buddy we've been at
home for two [ __ ] yep there is no
traffic I had to go to the gross store
to get supplies and there
was nobody out and the guy the grou
store he wasn't sleeping not to say that
the guy whose store wasn't doing his job
but he should have been sleeping I was
the only customer his seaford all day
and he wanted to talk he's like so what
are you gonna grow how many of me gonna
girl with it how long are you gonna you
know flower how long does it smell it
was it look like what's your name what
did you eat yours like just talk to me
please I've been here for all day you
can see it on a poor guy but thank you
to all the people who are keeping
businesses going I know it's a struggle
right now I could see it on your face
but I should have brought him lunch or
something maybe next time I love it show
up with food for the guys it's always
awesome um alright Mike we've been
rambling for quite some time I did not
really pay attention to how long we've
been going so 15 17 minutes into this um
and I'm awesome ly excited to have you
here on a video show I think that this
would be a good opportunity to kind of
do the official white Mike interview
you've been around for quite a while
you've been on a hundred episodes people
know kind of who you are they know what
you're about but they don't know much
about you other than what we've talked
about on the show the only I said
earlier the only real credit you've got
is cuz I've given you street cred I say
you're cool so they believe me like if
Rasta Jeff brought him around he's got
to be alright he wouldn't bring too but
too crazy of a person around but but
yeah exactly they know that basically
you're like my co-host or one of my best
friends are probably my best friend my
sidekick is basically what they know and
that you [ __ ] ramble a lot and that
you drink Mountain Dew and you smoke
dabs and that you haven't had a
cigarette and [ __ ] how many days now
dude three months five days see so those
are things that they know about you I
feel like today is a really good
opportunity to learn a little bit more
and share that [ __ ] about my friend
white Mike so in this episode guys we're
gonna do the official white like a mini
Hughie here we go white Mike interview
vol 1 we may do this in the future I'd
like to start it off by talking about
how and where I met my buddy white Mike
I was honoured and privileged to be a
part of the very first dispensary here
in Pueblo Colorado it was called met
amar it's called met amar ministries we
were kind of flying under a radar by
putting the word ministries on there and
it worked but we were met in more
ministries we were ran by a guy named
Tom and his beautiful wife Karen rest
pease Karen I love you and I miss you I
wish I could pass you joint right now
there were a couple of other folks
involved in that dispensary we got to
mention Chris an and tree uh several
other folks but I was mainly the dude
running the show I found a dispensary
that was kind of operating in an
apartment and I was like how about we
open an office and do this for real and
they're like if you're brave enough to
go set up a counter and do this we'll do
it and I was like we're doing it kind of
sketchy let's just [ __ ] do it for
real if we're gonna do it we're gonna
get in trouble up here or down here
what's doing this was in what 2009 I
think 2008 is when we got it going when
I started doing it a winter of 2008 is
when I met the guy in the apartment
I believe cuz I got my medical card
around before Christmas around
Thanksgiving that year I believe if I've
got a brain injury Mike so you gotta
give me some credit on my timelines that
timeline sounds about right she does got
an A - mm early 2000 yeah so I think
winter of 2008 is when I met the guy in
the apartment by early 2009 we had moved
it downstairs to the retail place and we
had opened up like a full on retail
dispensary I was working 6 days a week
from open to closed in the dispensary no
I'm not bragging I'm not complaining
that was my position it was awesome no
problem with that
I would [ __ ] and that was a great time I
learned so much I had so much
interaction I got so much calm at this
time in at least in Colorado selling
weed over the counter was a little bit
like being a Space Ranger it was awesome
I was people thought I was a superhero
it was snacks and food and lunch and
stickers and gifts all the time and also
the owners this was the thing yeah if if
you couldn't decide if you wanted to buy
jar a or jar B I'd pack up a bowl a jar
a and a bowl a jar beer we [ __ ] smoke
him see which one you like better than
he could make your decision like it was
real weed smoke him right there in the
[ __ ] office so eventually that
dispensary got hot got super popular
we were bangin and I couldn't keep up by
myself and Mike kept coming in with
another person um his father-in-law not
sure how much detail I should convey
here but Mike came in with his
father-in-law I made four I had already
known his father-in-law his
father-in-law was a cool cantankerous
old guy came in several times without my
and then he came in a few times with my
and Mike and I just made friends then
one time I'll remember this forever ah
Mike and his old man came to my house to
hang out it is we just became smoking
buddies and the doorbell rang and it was
the first time it your old man really
introduced us he's like Jeff Mike Mike
Jeff and I go and you must be I said you
must be the see and I was calling your
old man the old man the old man and
receive the book and you got my literary
reference [ __ ] spot on without
hesitation and you laughed and we were
we I was like being this guy our friends
I'd already liked you from coming into
the dispensary you speak well you're
articulate you're [ __ ] smart we're
the similar lines of music we like to
argue about the music but deep down our
roots are the [ __ ] same all right and
we're just like the herb we both loved
ganja yeah and we wanted to put ganja in
a positive light so we became friends I
got the opportunity I was the manager at
that dispensary I got the opportunity by
the owner to hire another budtender and
an assistant manager Mike was honestly
the first person to come to my mind
he's well-spoken he's a smart guy I
trust him he knew about cannabis so I
was like I know this guy Mike let's
[ __ ] give him a shot I interviewed
him I think they probably hired you on
the spot knowing Tom yeah yeah so this
is one of the stranger days my I was
like do you want to work here and I was
like yes tell me a little bit about
yourself I gave him like a little five
minute here's what's up with me he was
like cool I guess could do this for me
and then he laughed and I went to work
yeah that's basically that place didn't
have a lot of order it didn't have a
paperwork no he was Brahma he was from
North Carolina and he was an older guy
and he had the exact attitude you think
an older weed grower from North Carolina
would have as long as the weed grew
landed on the Shelf turned into money we
got paychecks I think everything else is
gonna be all right
yeah that's he didn't give too much of a
[ __ ] so eventually unfortunately that
dispensary was closed by our city I saw
it coming we knew was gonna happen [ __ ]
was evolving city came in politely
closed us they could have done it much
more aggressively we could have all been
arrested yeah they came in and said hey
please quit and we were given the
opportunity to close the doors
our smartass answer was what about all
the people in line they were kind enough
to let us serve the people in live when
they came in a few
people got up and booked as soon as they
saw a cop come in they were gone but a
few people were like I've got a medical
marijuana card they can't [ __ ] with me I
know the rules those people that stayed
I gave them most of the product we had
on hand I split all of the remaining
products with the permission of the
owner and the manager I split all of the
product up amongst the last customers
and the last employees in the building I
was like it's our last day here here's
all of our bonus checks we can't sell it
let's have a good time so there's been
three points yeah
drunk edibles that did yeah did we all
load it load it up and it was all legit
you guys we didn't steal anything the
owner was standing there next to us so
um at that point Mike kind of became my
helper he was already one of my best
friends he [ __ ] earned his spot of
being my bro he was in the passenger
seat of my van he was [ __ ] my video
game buddy we had a good time Mike and I
ended up hanging out a lot he became my
helper uh
in my personal grow and anywhere else
that we went Mike would just be in my
van he kind of became my main trimmer
I could be there if I was trimming herb
I could count on Mike being there
he was my girl helper he could build
[ __ ] uh most importantly he became one
of my very best friends I don't talk
about that enough bro we've got a
business relationship but bro you're
always [ __ ] my count on you I love
that [ __ ] so thank you uh then also this
is not official but mike is my lawyer
Mike is my I know that's not right if
you're not my lawyer he is not his
lawyer but mike is my freelance lawyer
he's my free lawyer the other lawyer
costs like two thousand dollars an hour
I can call Mike and go hey can you
answer this or do I need to call the
expensive the screening questions yeah
do I call the Italian guy or do I
[ __ ] talk to you about this and so
Mike can answer have a question I call
and that ladies and gentlemen is how
Mike got his name
white Mike um it's a joke I made it as a
joke because uh it's just such a white
guy dude he's from parkour he wears a
Jen cause he listens to [ __ ] 311 and
if I have weed in the car and I go fast
he says buddy decide if you want to have
weed or go fast one lot break one lot of
time look if you're gonna break a loved
one at a time
let's see those are the reasons that
make you white Mike like and I have no
problem with it I love it every guy I'm
kind of a rebel I'm kind of a loose
cannon I forget sometimes that I'm
smoking a joint driving 90 talking on my
phone
but all of this should I shouldn't be
doing it Michael go slow down put the
phone away or put the joint out we can't
do all of this buddy and I'm like oh
thank you Mike I'm really glad you're in
the passenger seat because sometimes I
get a little [ __ ] carried away
so Mike became white Mike for that
reason if it bothers you that I call him
white Mike is all in love it's all in
good fun look how [ __ ] pasty he is we
got him on a video here you could see
his right mr. pasty uh he's from
Colorado he says bro he's wearing a
beanie he's goes on yeah he's qualified
is white Mike it's nothing racist I
think it's all in good fun so that's
where white Mike the nickname white Mike
came from I gave that one to him because
if I needed somebody to research
something tell me about a law fill out
some paperwork some white guy [ __ ] Mike
would do it for me I'll do that [ __ ]
that's my gig so that is a little excuse
throat clearing guys I'm gonna blame
that on our friends at first matter
Premium concentrates shout out for the
fatty dabs so I'm crossing off all the
[ __ ] that I've covered here because we
do have an extensive interview I'm
trying to be a good interviewer uh Mike
we've covered up to the point where I
met you and you became my bud tender and
my bro and there's a little interest
that's our origin story also I got a
mention that in that same time period
Mike got me involved in the cannabis
community going to City Council meetings
that's what I'm trying to say City
Council I would have never gone to City
Council meetings I would not have gotten
put a politically active that would not
be part of my repertoire if it weren't
for Mike so I feel like that's where
Mike shines is on the paperwork
the activism the well-spoken side I do
this jamriang [ __ ] bro talk and I do
the grow in the cultivation I'd be the
cartoon character Mike does the white
guy [ __ ] so um he introduced me to the
City Council part and kind of taught me
how to tighten up my game a little bit
so that's where Mike came in in my world
hmm sorry about that that was gross now
where I want to jump to is can you tell
us what you were doing before you got
into the cannabis game you don't have to
reveal too much there's not comfortable
with what were you doing before the week
game bro how far back should I go as far
as you're comfortable man let's do the
day you were born what were you thinking
when he looked up and saw the bright
lights I'm just kidding
yeah what Mike was born alone maybe
let's start it what got you smoking weed
what got me smoking weed yeah where did
you go wee man I just remember every
everybody was obsessed with it in school
like I grew up in Jeff mentioned at
Parker Colorado in 80s and 90s the
parents movement at the time the
anti-drug parents movement was a big
thing drugs and schools were a big thing
gangs and schools were a big thing I
mean none of this [ __ ] really existed in
Parker but they were [ __ ] super
paranoid about it and so there's a
little suburb outside of Denver just a
few miles outside of Denver it's really
suburb II it's real nice Douglas County
Colorado for most of my childhood it was
the fastest growing County in the United
States that's pretty cool why I liked it
I like to joke that we didn't have white
people in my town when we didn't have
non-white people in my town when I was
growing up that's why the cops [ __ ]
with the teenagers so much because there
were no minorities to screw with it's
actually true and it's weirdly trooper
true about Parker like I remember in
middle school we used to make the one
black girl stand up and talk about what
it was like to be black in February and
the one Jewish kid get up in December
and talk about what it was like not to
have a Christmas tree I think it was
really [ __ ] up the 80s were a weird
time if you're a lot younger than Jeff
and this sounds insane
it's just what we did to people back
then but all the way through school they
kept bringing it up marijuana people are
gonna offer you marijuana every time I
went to Denver with my parents I was
like where the drug dealers at like why
aren't they trying to sell me drugs
would give me free drugs you get me
hooked on drugs I'm confused
they're lying to me in school or
something it's waiting for those guys
and then I was sitting in the hall it's
school working on a group project and
this kid that lived up the street from
me comes whipping around the corner of
the hallway like power walking and as he
came around the corner he pulled his
hand out of his pocket and threw
something at me and it hit me into my
chest and I didn't know what the [ __ ]
was happening but I had the presence of
mind to flip my shirt
or whatever just hit me and two teachers
came running around the corner right
behind him and were like hey not so fast
like stay where we can see you and we're
kind of like marching him off to the
office or something and after they
passed I looked down and the two kids
that were working on the project myth
with me we're like what the [ __ ] just
happened and I looked at it it's like I
know enough from house class know that I
just got hit the chest with a bag full
of weed like a deal from whoever you
believe in a kid with Allah or JA or
Buddha yeah true story my first guy GUI
was [ __ ] thrown at me it's perfect it
was meant to be dude David I'm really
glad I asked he knows who he is bro he
knows who he is
yep I ended up taking that home and
trying to smoke it like I think it was a
pop can with whole smoked in it and I
just burnt myself a couple of times then
was like is this what being high as like
and it was God years later two three
years later before I actually got good
and stoned in someone named Mandy's my
camera which parent I think her mom's
garage now your snitch you're not Mandy
to your [ __ ] does name-dropping on
everybody dude dropping names on
everybody this is 30 years ago if you
can find these people tell them I said
hi
all right so you get hit in the back in
the chest with the bag of weed and then
you go smoke with some young innocent
girl named Mandy yep there's a couple
times I introduced weed all right that's
high school time right yep you go to
college
eighth grade and then maybe eighth grade
I got hit in the chest we may be seventh
grade
okay and mandy's garage I wasn't driving
yet side of you in 15 sophomore in high
school friend oh wow
alright that's about the same time most
of us start smoking I went a little
younger but then I had a break because I
moved away from home and to find my new
crew and all that find a new plug yeah
yeah well where I'm from dude everybody
[ __ ] smokes weed so it's just it's
easy
yep did not smoke weed it's more
challenging all right so we got you
smoking about [ __ ] 15 years old you
smoked all the way through high school
yeah
from the time I was 15 through now all
right so college all that good [ __ ] all
right that puts me back to where were
you right before the industry what kind
of I know you're well educated so we
kind of education you guys what sex we
in college I studied sociology in
psychology so I took a lot of drugs
classes drugs in society type stuff drug
policy type stuff history a drug policy
one of the things that blew my mind one
of the first drugs classes I took the
class started the history of drugs with
salt and pepper like that's where it
started out and if you look at the
history of the spice trade it's exactly
like the modern marijuana market like
it's fun makes total sense to mom but
when I graduated college the goal is to
go work with at-risk youth I wanted to
go help teenagers that kind of had a
shitty run of it get their feet back
under him so they didn't turn into
shitty adults and I went and worked with
locked up teens for a couple years and
got injured and as I was trying to
figure out what I was gonna do after
that a friend of mine came down with
what eventually we learned was a mess
and we just sort of trial and error he
uh he was miserable he had to do like
four weeks straight the hospital where
they did tests after tests and blood
draw after blood draw and he was living
with me at the time and I I called him
today was before I went to go pick him
up in the hospital and I was like dude
what do you want free cut your
homecoming and he was like I'm [ __ ]
miserable I just want to be home I want
to take a shower and he's like I want to
get
like clean the bong and have some good
weed waiting for me and this was 2004
maybe 2005 at the latest
okay so Colorado went medical in 2000
but nothing existed yet there was no
dispensaries there was two or three or
four doctors across the state signing
paperwork time but it existed but it was
real quiet nobody talked about it nobody
knew where to really get it yeah
and so my buddy comes home from the
hospital and he's 24 and he needs a
walker to walk to get around not a cane
but like the foreleg metal half box
warrior yeah you weren't injured at work
too so were you hurt at the same time or
my neck was messed up and it was giving
me weird pain signals down my left arm
okay and so my left hand kind of always
hurt and I was always massaging you
still do that yeah it's I slit my next
not fixed and when I haven't been
keeping up with my CBD THC regimen and
the stretches that I do and the
inflammation builds up the pain comes
right back oh I see you and word we're
hanging out when you get the fidgets you
start pulling on your thumbs and
stretching your hands out I see you go
right for it when after a couple dabs
you start scratching I'm sorry I
couldn't that off so Mike needs a walker
Dave comes home and he's got to use a
walker to get around and we get stoned
that night and I mean it was rough he
was having trouble talking he he'd think
this think of a sentence like I went to
the store and bought cheese and he'd go
to say it and his brain would just pause
and it wouldn't want to say store and so
he'd go I went to the any kind of look
at you for a minute
and have to look down and the place
where you buy things and it's like the
store and he's like yeah if I can went
to the store and I bought cheese it was
just brutal seeing my buddy kind of
pulled back like that because he is like
picking up girls in the military and
athletic and in fast cars and [ __ ] like
that and all of a sudden now he's a
walker and he's struggling to talk and
struggling to talk it was rough to see
and he takes a couple of bong hits and
stands up to go to the bathroom and just
walks to the bathroom and he didn't
fetch it either until he opened the door
and he saw his walk or sitting next to
the chair and he looked at his feet was
like what the [ __ ] he's the first time
in six weeks that I've been able to walk
ten feet without tripping over my own
feet and falling down without my Walker
that is [ __ ] horrible and he sits
down and he goes did you notice that I
didn't need my walker and I go did you
notice she didn't stumble over that
sentence and we both just sort of stared
at each other for a minute going dude
dude look with more bong hits we need to
test this and after like three or four
days it was crystal clear that cannabis
was medically beneficial for him that's
awesome to put it mildly and then became
we began like a year-long journey of
getting him a medical marijuana card
right because I said earlier you know
dr. Ochs yes
you couldn't just google pot doc there
was no weed maps there were no
dispensaries there were no Sanjay Gupta
specials nothing you had to file
something to know what is this card on
your you are something weird like that
there were weird ways of finding
dispensaries back in the day yeah I
spent I've cut probably 50 hours digging
through forums and I found some doctors
name and a couple of lawyers names and I
was able to get him an appointment and
back then it was a couple hundred
dollars for the appointment it was a
couple hundred dollars for the card and
once you got the card all it meant was
after the cop arrests you and you end up
in front of a judge you've got some
paperwork to help try to
you out of trouble because all it meant
then but I was able to get him that far
and you could job store there was no
stores right nothing existed then if it
was just you got caught with purely
black-market herb you were allowed to
have it I'm you could grow your six
plants and a story there were no rules
back then none whatsoever
other than the original framework of
amendment 20 took minutes remember a
minute one yeah I saw you searching for
us let's say 64 20 so is it took us
about a year to get Dave his card and
about the same time my now wife then
girlfriend and I started to get more
serious and we started to come down here
and spend more time with her family and
her dad is sick and [ __ ] it always has
been in a couple of those his ailments
are on the list for amendment 24 a
medical marijuana card and he's been you
know 10 joints a day keep the doctor
away since he was in his 20s and I said
you're [ __ ] nuts why don't we get you
a card he was like what what what are
you even talking about and so I started
a process of getting him a card cool and
that took another six or eight months
and by the time I got him a card I had
found two or three more people that
needed help doing that
so my first job in the industry was
helping sick patients get a proper
medical marijuana cards that's pretty
cool
you said I'd come down here we're in
Pueblo so wasn't Puebla so I was coming
down for yeah
driving down from Denver it's about 130
miles to come spend time with the wife's
family the girlfriends family at the
time and the old man he's talking about
is the guy that I met him through so
that's our buddy can I say his name dude
like yes years later he would introduce
me to Jeff yeah yeah um so that's how
you got into it you were helping Dave
out then you got Steve his card you got
a couple of your friends their cards you
got yourself a card oh how is Dave now
bro wonderful man just had a beautiful
baby girl excellent I like hearing that
bro yeah you helped him get right right
for the pandemic that a kid perfect
timing dude something to keep them
occupied right something to keep them in
their proper gonna make another one
during the [ __ ] pandemic - ah so a
lot of people are we got up - when you
started coming down and hanging out with
Steve how long until you run into me at
the dispensary when you start hanging
out with Steven coming down here to get
medicine so I started coming down here
for medicine and regularly like maybe
2000 gotta be six or seven ish for the
listeners and they would have been sorry
it would have been i'm listening my baby
monitor just started going off so i was
Lucy with that while I was trying to
count back in years it would have been
2006 2000 2007 okay
I knew a couple of medical patients down
here that I had met through Steve that
it had pretty solid we might have to hit
pause bro we need to take a break we can
tackle bottle no worries yep good
Britain's calling a break hold on
right buddy welcome back to the show
how's everything going in family life
well you're still muted
pretty good man I hope the little man
goes right back to sleep yeah I no
worries if he doesn't bro it's a family
time and we can take another break if we
need to I'm good at editing him I might
not even edit out that middle section
there cuz I just talked for a moment so
if the listeners heard all that
gibberish I didn't edit and if they
didn't hear a bunch of gibberish I did
edit and we'll just keep going now I've
got a good reason to listen to this I
was live but yeah see what she was
rambling about you're doing a good job I
was talking about how good of a job we
are doing as an interview team together
well we're uh where were we when Ethan
cried see I made it a point not to see
your kids names on the show started
coming down here back in two thousand
six or seven yeah yeah coming down
teamed up with steve-o we could just
jump to the part where we kind of met
right we ended up [ __ ] becoming
homies through met amar yeah it met amar
my father-in-law came home like like
giggly schoolgirl excited like he healed
every guys's [ __ ] weed stores man
back it's such a we're so used to it now
yeah I have to check in with prohibition
landed to kind of ground myself and and
get a feel for what it's like in
non-medical non recreational places now
cuz I can Colorado's the future bro oh
dude I know you're spoiled and I forget
the so spoiled so spoiled it wasn't long
ago I was in Texas in the airport I
asked the lady at the newsstand for a
recent copy of High Times and she was
like we don't carry that here like we
can't carry stuff about illegal
narcotics this is my twenty eighteen a
yeah we're in the future here in
Colorado and we have to remind ourselves
that [ __ ] sometimes like Steve comes
home with there's a weed store downtown
you got have you're never gonna believe
the car we got to go this is how [ __ ]
you're going now you're never gonna
believe this like you got to go before
the cops show up you got to see the [ __ ]
in action and
I was blown away that the quality was
just as good as anything I'd been by and
if not better anywhere else thank you
because I was growing a lot of that that
means a lot to me but I think the price
was also a little bit better and you
know we got death threats and all kinds
of problems because the combo said
that's that price here in this area
people were angry bro like we were
worried for a minute we're like we may
have [ __ ] up people get to experience
this in every state that goes legal but
the the the price on the black market is
fixed and that's a beautiful part of the
market because everybody gets to pretend
that product is scarce to the point
where the price is the price or [ __ ] off
and as soon as there were stores where a
customer could you know without a lot of
bravado go all right then I'll just go
to the other one like if home people
don't want to treat me good I'll go to
Lowe's yep as soon as that's the thing
the pricing at the price cause [ __ ]
scarce no more and by the time met amar
had opened up there was a dispensary or
two in Springs and then one or two in
Denver in two or three around the Front
Range and then one up at Fort Collins
and by the time we had real competition
down here the price had dropped to what
300 an ounce or something out good
hundred dollars well 280 or 320 yeah man
our store loved the $400 an ounce
standard black market price at the time
and I mean by then the game had changed
and that number sounds crazy high now
when I said it yep yeah but it used to
be 280 if you were a member or 320 if
you weren't and that was that's a whole
another topic we'll talk about in
another day when I was making the bottle
just now I was remembering the grows
back then there'd be a binder where had
like comic book plastic sheets in it
yeah and it was people photocopies a
full page
the full medical marijuana application
yeah have your application your card
your ID just said that if something did
go wrong look we've got their picture
their doctor recommendations and rose
when law enforcement showed up and you
had to be like all right officer like
please don't shoot yep like let's go
through a notebook
we were trimming somewhere and law
enforcement showed up and all we did we
all pulled out on Medical Marijuana
cards and they go it looks good too and
they all left they didn't care it all
had a card you know I'm gonna take this
dad you got to cover me for a moment um
but that was like two thousand six seven
eight ish and then when the city shop
met him are down my wife is a lawyer and
my family is in law so when the city
shut us down saying we were violating
zoning rules that the City Council
hadn't passed yet I got pissed and I
told the owner of met amar we've got to
fight this and for various reasons we
said I'm not in the mood to fight right
now so no so I decided [ __ ] it I'm gonna
go fight this myself and if they're
gonna pass crazy rules like this
somebody from RN needs to stand up and
at least have our voice heard because at
that point it was very much City Council
and County Commissioners begrudgingly
passing rules for something they didn't
want yep and when you've got a group of
people making rules for something they
don't like the rules get asinine quick
and I mean it was terrifying the first
couple times I went and spoke I think
the first time I spoke up at a meeting I
was on the front page of the paper the
next morning I'm just as an extra little
like by the way the nail that stands up
gets hammered down first yep um and then
maybe a year later I was in a meeting
that City Council put together
where's people from Planning and Zoning
and people from the Sheriff's Office
City PD and people from like the water
department and the Health Department all
got together to work on what rules do we
want for home gross and before the
meeting got started the the sheriff's
deputy and the city narcotics cops
started talking about funny [ __ ] that
had happened with legal pot and they
mentioned the closing of met amar and
that they had a surveillance camera on
the back porch the whole time and I just
started giggling because I'm sitting
next to these two listen to the
conversation I was like oh man there was
a camera there yeah like how many of my
smoke breaks did they get yeah they got
me rolling joints on there for hours of
footage to better now my camera was a
that's funny all right so you said screw
it just time to go full force and start
hitting city council with that whatever
I felt they needed to get smacked with
and you went for zoning you went for
rule changes you go for any sort of
hearings or proposals but new
discussions are coming solid years in my
life yeah yeah you got me going to
meetings dude I took other dreads to
meetings like there were a little
section of dreadlocks at the city
council meetings we all tried to put on
a decent shirt show up it's kind of fun
I would have never gone and done that it
can work for you so that's what some of
you when they realized that I could get
10 or 15 people to show up if I wanted
to then they really started listening
because that's what small town
politicians for the most is a little bit
of crowd making a little bit of noise
because then the press shows up and then
it's a real issue that they've got to
deal with whether they want to or not
and we were lucky enough to have a
friend in the press and so they would
always make sure to put our faces on the
camera on the news they're had friends
multiple friends yeah yeah we used to
have a reporter who if we had a cannabis
story you must text her and she would
drive up to the house and you could give
her the weed story if she needed weed
details she would text Mike and I hey
tell me about weed tell me what's going
on we'd fill her in so the news reports
are almost close to accurate because of
that stuff if for a while man you've
done a lot of great [ __ ] in cannabis ah
like dude from getting involved to get
Dave a card from being my bud tender
assistant manager whatever you were at
madam our that was a stressful
challenging we didn't have an
Johnson bud tending then yeah we were
inventing the rules and the systems as
we happen so it's really interesting and
fun to watch we had MMJ menu first like
nobody had that [ __ ] before us we were
doing it on the black market kinda I
remember like sort of inventing the
smell jars and display racks and pre
rolls and we had awesome displays that
dispensary always looked so good we had
nice good systems in place so I've
always trusted working with you and we
worked at that dispensary then we got
kind of out of the there wasn't a
dispensary to work at and then we teamed
up again for another place and then we
kind of worked in another place together
we've been through three facilities
together me working in the back and you
working up front it's been a lot of fun
where I always try and anytime I get a
place or an opportunity to bring
somebody on board if I'm in charge or do
hiring you're always I put your name at
the top of the list location always goes
in yeah yeah we've been a good [ __ ]
team so fist bump across [ __ ] zoom
bro um you've accomplished a lot of
great [ __ ]
do you have a favorite accomplishment in
the cannabis industry cuz I know them
two little gremlins you got over there
better be your favorite accomplishments
but in cannabis what's your favorite er
you can take the time I saw you pause or
the video froze um getting honestly when
we got Dave his card that was in every
day couple hours a day year long
struggle when that first card showed up
that pay off that like dopamine kick
that sense of accomplishment was [ __ ]
massive yes you can have it in the house
you can have it the car it's not gonna
go to jail and have a mess at the same
time right yeah I couldn't imagine him
him having to go to to jail for
possession that would have been cruel
and stupid beyond words
and sort of have have that protection in
place even back then as flimsy as it was
was was it just astronomical and felt
really good to have achieved and then
it's a silly rule and it don't matter
anymore because it's been overwritten by
the state but I got Pueblo County or the
city of Pueblo not to limit plant counts
and that was like a three year long
fight where they wanted to limit it and
they needed to limit it and just slowly
and with reason like the city doesn't
want to get in between patients and
doctors was my whole argument you know
and little by little I won over every
heart and mind one at a [ __ ] time and
that felt really good still to this day
the city of Puebla is not a blank
element they limit you by square footage
and a state highway that's huge yep the
state limits you but not the city
I'm always bitching about that state
limit thank you bro for trying to keep
me cos for a while I was able to grow
quite a few plants but now I'm known and
people know where the [ __ ] I am and they
whoever they is I say who are they got
another email address or they don't
exist another email address where I've
talked to they know where I am and they
know what I do so I got a state one
plant under the count just in case they
break off a branch try to tell me it's
another one like so that's not a fun
game to play anymore I miss the good old
days when you could try to explode the
basement try to make the house [ __ ]
fly by putting grow 899 s the number
buddy let's grow six recreational and
five on the medical card yep five don't
go six don't no don't do it
so getting Davis card is your proudest
accomplishment that's cool yeah they
[ __ ] adrenaline rush when you get the
first one not two down I'm not trying to
steal your interview but I remember you
get my first car walking into that
dispensary the first time and it's like
wait you're gonna weigh it in front of
me and it's the price on the menu and I
just order off the menu and I get to
smell you're gonna whip and you're gonna
wait in front of me and it's gonna wait
twenty eight point three five grams when
I buy an ounce like holy [ __ ] I don't
have to wait the parking lot for 45
minutes at one rate if I'm just gonna
get in my face I don't have to sit on
someone's couch and listen to Tupac for
[ __ ] three hours while they [ __ ]
play [ __ ] Pfeiffer FIFA yeah get eyes
you just bought a gram [ __ ] basil
stuff in a bag yeah did I have a dream
that somebody sold me bunk weed [ __ ]
come on you just get my weirdest [ __ ]
dreams dude
other memories that's yeah legal is a
beautiful thing if you don't have legal
work on it yeah yeah ah man what keeps
you inspired now you've done a lot of
[ __ ] you got Dave settled in you got
kids now what keeps you inspired in the
cannabis industry just seeing what's
what's next
I love seeing what's new it's been so
much fun watching Colorado evolve like I
remember going into history class as a
teenager and being like well hopefully
we don't have a world war three and I
mean our Great Depression or a
prohibition that's close to all three of
those right now dude that's [ __ ]
scary but up until cannabis legalization
there wasn't an obvious like this is
gonna be in the [ __ ] history books
guaranteed there's gonna be multiple
chapters on what we're living through
and when I really started digging into
like wait a second Colorado has legal
weed I kind of remember that from when I
was a freshman in college but it didn't
mean anything other than like good job
hippie like you're still going to jail
and that evolved to what we have now I
remember the first set of rules that
came down and how we went from a
thousand to retail dispensaries to 500
overnight
I remember what you're just watching the
glass evolved like I've got this
beautiful little rig right here nothing
like this had ever been seen when I
started doing this the concentrates we
so now yeah I showed you this in 2008
I'm gonna bust out this diamond again
just because it's that pretty maybe not
because the containers fighting with me
and nose on the camera so doesn't want
to open rewind the video watch that
diamond at the beginning but if I showed
you this in 2008 you'd think I was
giving you drugs we would kick people
out of the house for using I really
can't get it open so I don't get to
smoke this it was a one-time deal I I
had to dispensary the day before 4/20
and I got six grams of hash and it was
in a little paper bag and I drove at
home but in 2004 6 1 gram jars a hash
meant you were a drug dealer looking to
distribute six cribs and yep
and in a lot of places like if you're in
Texas one gram of hash and one gram of
heroin are legally equal you know just
as [ __ ] and they weigh the container
yeah a little glass jar would it take
this whole glass jar and they go that's
17 grams of hard drugs enjoy life in
prison with [ __ ]
it's just Colorado's on a different
plane now and watching us go from where
we were to where we are now has been an
amazing journey as involved in it to be
a part of it I maybe I'll find a hash it
inspires me to finally write the book
about it but I wasn't gonna ask about
the book in this interview bro but the
book is it really you're gonna do that
happen it's it started so many times but
I get to like page 30 and I just stopped
writing for a minute and I take a little
break and then I never go back to it
let's just put your book together the
people deserve it and I want my chapter
so I'll help you write it I was gonna
ask where do you see yourself in five
years but I'm just gonna say write the
[ __ ] book dude right the
look ya I'm booked to her we'll say on
book tour yeah so the other part of that
was where do you see cannabis in five
years and also the B part of that is how
long do you think until we see national
cannabis legalization so cannabis in
five years and how long until it's legal
everywhere see I had a better
guesstimate pre-pandemic oh yes mmm
nothing's gonna be the same after this
folks like I mean every little facet of
life is gonna get tweaked to some
degrees slightly different 2% different
everywhere
at least the minute the stuff that
almost stays the same is gonna be two
percent different personal greetings
no more handshakes bro oh yeah those are
gone yeah people wearing masks at the
bank that's cool now and in the
dispensary buying weed in the parking
lots again is cool at the dispensary we
got go cups now in Colorado we didn't
have go cups before coronavirus now we
got go Cubs go cups for those of you who
don't know is you can go to a restaurant
and get a margarita in a plastic cup
with sulfate around the top is your I
promise not to drink this time home
officer seal just sort of like when we
buy a joint now it comes in a little to
help me promise not to let that [ __ ] up
so we you know as long as you serve food
you're allowed to sell alcohol to go as
well now yep for right now though there
was a rumor that the state was going to
take that privilege away already and
they clarified that as long as the sales
transaction happens inside the
restaurant
meaning you ordered your [ __ ] through
the app on your phone and the payment
was technically processed inside and
you're not handing someone a 20 from
your car window sales still legit
awesome oh it's so [ __ ] arbitrary but
a lot of those are getting worked on
including there's a whole bunch of them
for cannabis that they dialed back right
away so that we could do curbside none
of that shit's going back the way it
used to be none of it
you need to take a break roll em you
know I hear the monitor going you just
finished that bottle I made him we'll
see what if he goes back to sleep now
already will cool I'm probably not gonna
edit out the last break it was
interesting that's fine
just maybe yammering for a minute so to
continue with that how long do you till
you think we have legalization or do you
think we'll see that we should see that
in our light in your lifetime I don't
know which one of us will live longer
but I also see that in our lifetimes
right now I mean my take is Trump is
truly terrified and panicked about
re-election and so between now and
November I think
cannabis legalization is it has out of
nowhere potential more than it's ever
had before because the person in top who
can really push to make it happen is is
panicked as they've ever been and is
incompetent as they've ever been if you
disagree with me you know or my twitter
is and if you agree let's calm
forward-slash way Mike exactly but I
honestly think that there's a maybe
10-15 percent chance that Trump tries to
throw marijuana legalization is a way to
come at Biden from the left right
towards the end of election season and
honestly it's just attrition now still
wouldn't starts then down have yeah I
still wouldn't vote for me that more
states then don't have medical or reckon
Al and it's gotten to the point where
the DEA the FDA NIDA are all being
forced to reevaluate their positions on
marijuana and like if we catch you with
it we'll throw you in jail is slowly
becoming there's a lot of medical uses
we need more research and I mean little
by little we're winning and I mean the
prohibition latticework is crumbling
it's just how long until it crumbles and
and it's so hard to guess that now
especially during this chaos society
tends to swing like on a pendulum left
to right conservative to liberal and if
you look at the last hundred years the
roaring 20s like sexual liberation music
lots of liberal social advancements and
then at the end of the center at the end
of the decade with the economic crash
things went super conservative again and
they stayed that way for a long time and
we slowly work our way back out and then
same thing happened again in the sixties
the summer love happened and that led us
the [ __ ] Reagan era
like we could fully be going through
that again
and honestly cannabis has been on a big
liberalisation push for a long time and
I don't see the pendulum swinging back
on this one but it could it fully could
got a watch right now the anti pop
movements never been as ginned up and is
quick with messaging as they are now
they were a lot more powerful in the 80s
and 90s than they are today but the
remnants still have plenty of month yeah
and they started the full weight and
backing in federal government so a lot
of that generation that doesn't approve
is on its way out like they're too old
to keep fighting us you know what I mean
that's the generate two generations
above us a generation above us the older
crew doesn't approve people our age were
in so not that I'm excited for old
people to pass but I mean that's the
opposite that's where we're headed but
on a way yeah the batons got to get
passed and then what are we gonna have
to deal with what are the kids behind us
gonna be into legalized everything
pretty soon we'll see with but that's
the thing is with prohibition once you
like it's especially ridiculous when it
comes to cannabis there's there's no
logical reason why cannabis products of
any kind should be prohibited but
prohibition is a policy is terrible
it's just bad social policy and if you
want to get down to it the most
dangerous [ __ ] in society isn't
prohibited it's highly regulated and
restricted and under that model its
controllable like frighteningly kind of
creepy so like you can order the parts
for a nuclear bomb on the Internet
there's a really creepy story of a Nazi
in Maine who did it and finished it and
the only reason the terrible [ __ ] didn't
happen is because he was also abusive
and his wife killed him called the cops
on herself and when the cops showed up
there
what's in the sink and she was like oh
that's a bomb
but it's it's highly regulated and
restricted and then you look at stuff
like narcotics and they're prohibited
don't Google that because your Google
[ __ ] search history will be [ __ ]
forever but then if you look at like
when drugs were legal
how were they used in and whatnot and
when heroin was legal housewives were
drinking laudanum
a load potency oral consumption I'm if
you rent Tombstone Wyatt Earp's wife
that's the drug she's have gone and it
was sort of like meth in the 50 is when
housewife's were taking it to stay perky
and skinny it's it's a much lower dose
it doesn't have the overdose potential
the [ __ ] teeth weren't falling out
like no Breaking Bad nonsense happening
it was just pharmaceutical pure clean
specific dosage specific timing to take
it
dosage recommendations same thing with
laudanum and when you really start to
look at all this [ __ ] kind of as a whole
picture thing the idea that cops are
gonna stop people from doing heroin if
they feel like doing heroin like it just
doesn't make any sense of doom
if people's families don't stop them
from doing heroin the cops are gonna do
it and if if you look across society
right now we've got things like safe
injection sites methadone clinics
marijuana dispensaries psilocybin
legalization and decriminalization
measures are hitting the ballots all
across the country Denver just
decriminalized psilocybin California
before Co vid was working on signatures
to decriminalize across the state like
the the framework that put prohibition
in place is all slowly starting to
crumble more and more people are waking
up to the idea that these are terrible
[ __ ] policies they'll lead to all
sorts of destruction that we're not
intending when you really get into the
dollar amount and we're
it's going and what we're funding with
our moral high-ground it's just [ __ ]
nuts you know just put people in jail to
keep them in jail to [ __ ] up their lives
to [ __ ] up their futures to [ __ ] up
their lives again yeah exactly like
where do you see yourself in the future
of cannabis we've come a long way but
we're getting old things are getting
weird where do we go next
I'm in a weird place man I don't know
what's next
I'm on pause right now I was doing a
bunch of consulting before covin but
nobody wants to fly me to their grow to
teach their [ __ ] trimco I don't have
to be idiots right now so I'm mostly
just hanging out with the kids at home
waiting on waiting to see where all this
goes but most of the [ __ ] planet is
doing right now chillin out what the
kids waiting to see where this goes yeah
all right Mike I've got one more really
important question for you and we're
gonna wrap up this interview dude by the
way you've done an amazing job thank you
for making your first resume video thank
you but I appreciate that I'm not the
best interviewer in my opinion so it's
really comfortable having my best friend
as my interviewee I had this
conversation with myself a moment ago I
don't know what to call you but the guy
on that end I was an honor to have you
good job he did a really good job for
your first video I keep it up um the
most important question of the night bro
and I already know the answer because
we've been friends for so long but I've
got to include this into my interview
here what's your favorite strain to
smoke you gotta go with the Grateful dog
oh man that puts a smile on my face not
some something that's not yours it's
gotta be Kem dog or Sour Diesel
that's a closed City sour really close
to the Grateful dog The Grateful dog is
bred by myself the Grateful dog is
honestly a Deadhead og
inbred project deadhead OG is a chem d2
or no it's the chem 91 to San Fernando
Valley OG Kush f4 and then I got a
Grateful dog select phenotype a Deadhead
phenotype and I reversed it I called the
seeds that came from that were known as
grateful dog I took another seed from
that and grew it out and then I reversed
the original grateful dog and put that
pollen onto that seed and it made more
seeds the seeds that came from Matt
won't reverse like they come out real it
yeah that there's a lot of weirdness
going on but I can't
verse number 77 either I call that one
77 to select that one doesn't reverse I
could treat it with silver thiosulfate
it won't cross but it's really cool
knowing bit your favorite strain is
something that I bring then yeah that's
that's awesome is when I grow it you
always kind of drool a little bit so
that's pretty awesome I know it's not
just the potency like it's it's
something in the genetics that plant
just that herb and my head were meant to
go together it's something those are two
amazing genetics you got OG Kush and
chem dog the chem gives you that sweet
stank funk and the OG Kush gives you
similar but more earthy and then they
both have a yeah it's just a beautiful
combo wasn't my original idea I worked
with it I kind of inbred it I did some
stuff so that's my story and I'm
sticking to it Mike I'm glad that's your
favorite
dude we should start wrapping up before
one of your kids starts going before it
gets much later here how can the fine
folks find you on the social media you
can find me on Twitter it's at Nemo punk
hit me up on Facebook its Pueblo for
sensible cannabis laws and now you can
find me on patreon at patreon.com slash
web mike that's awesome I'm so excited
you've got a patreon you guys if you are
only able to help us out one of us if
you're doing like a 420 contribution to
me go ahead and throw me two bucks and
throw Mike two bucks I want to share
that funding with Mike he's been doing
it for a while so he can do that yeah
let's stack of his patreon for a minute
you guys and then come see me again you
come see me again when cove is over
let's help out Mike for a couple of
months while he's trapped at home and
helping us out Mike thank you for being
on the show
dude most importantly thank you for
being my friend thank you for being my
friend that's super important we don't
talk much about that because we're just
bros we don't get all mushy but like 11
years let's keep it going
hell yeah thank you bro I appreciate it
ladies and gentlemen boys and girls
pimps and hos friends and foes smokers
growers clone cutters pollen chuckers
seed hoarders and snowboarders I don't
know what the [ __ ] else I got Fred tried
to go on with that one I want to thank
everybody for listening most importantly
thanks to Mike for being here thanks to
Mike's family thanks to the little ones
for giving them some time to hang out if
anybody else out there feels that this
episode was educational informative or
entertaining and he liked to make a
financial contribution to the show you
can do so by visiting WWE
grow from your heart also don't forget
patreon.com forward slash white mic
let's load up
white mics patreon be sure to visit our
sponsor seeds here now.com make sure you
use coupon code gen while checking out
to save yourself ten percent at seeds
here now dot-com once again big shout
out to Mike big shout out to everybody
for watching and listening I myself will
be back in a few days with fresh new
content hopefully I've got a cool guest
with me I make no promises during the
quarantine sometimes I decided to record
it like 3:00 in the morning Mike you
look like you got something to say at
the end if you want more more of these
video podcasts hit us up tell us he
likes it on social media yeah go check
out the updates I did to the patreon
contribution tiers there are some more
tiers available on my patreon go check
that out there may be something that
gets your attention alright ladies and
gentlemen boys and girls pimps and hoes
friends and foes that is all I've got
for you I want to give a giant shout out
to my buddy James but erson and until
next time take a phat dad and give your
mom a hug for me boom good show bro you
did a [ __ ] good job