all right here we go welcome back
podcast world it is time for episode 531
of the girl from your heart podcast this
episode of the show is brought to you by
our friends at seeds here now.com seeds
here now.com carries seeds from all of
the industry's favorite breeders
including canner otto genetics DJ short
seeds miss Jill genetics and of course I
read genetics everything at seeds here
now.com is backed by their award-winning
satisfaction guarantee and for my
friends on a budget seeds here now calm
offer several packs for under $30 as
well as amazing monthly sales make sure
to use coupon code Chan while checking
out to save a few bucks
again that is coupon code G fyh 10 while
checking out at seeds here now dot-com
you know I like to start this podcast
off by talking about what I'm smoking
today I've been taking dad's of banana
orange cookies full spectrum extract
from Green Dot labs this is a big 4 gram
jar on the package it says it is a blend
of banana cush and orange cookies the
flavor is described as banana orange
smoothie I'm going to say that is
perfectly accurate is like a banana
orange smoothie with a hint of pepper at
the end of it I think that is coming
from the cookies ah there is the orange
cookies in here that peppery dark
undertone at the end comes from the
cookies the orange banana smoothie is
dominant and I really enjoy it I'll show
you the jar here on the screen if I get
this open there you go that is the
banana orange cookies from our friends
at Green Dot labs on the back of the
container it says that the product does
contain sixty nine point three seven
percent THC and non detectable amounts
of CBD alright ladies and gentlemen in
this episode I'm going to read a couple
of emails before we get there let's do
some shoutouts to a few of the folks who
support the show on patreon let's start
off by giving a giant shout out to our
friend norske I want to send a giant
thank you shout out to growing granny
I've always got a giant shout out for my
buddy Bobby C let's send a big thank you
shout out to learnin and burnin I want
to send a big thank you shot it's a big
toe grows how about a big fist bump and
a thank you to Ryan em I've always got a
big thank you shut up for sefirot we
need
a special thank you to HD cha and last
but certainly not least let's send a big
girl from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to my friend Paul T big thank
you big shout out for everybody who
supports the show if you're not
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit w-w-w dot patreon.com forward
slash grow from your heart all of the
information you need will be right there
on the screen and I did include a link
in the show notes for all of my stone to
friends just to make it easy
thank you guys click on the show notes
click on the video description you will
find a link to the patreon campaign I do
appreciate all of your support all right
before we go much further I want to send
a big thank you to my buddy Mike white
Mike spent some time learning how to
work some audio equipment he learned
some time he took some time setting some
stuff up he found some space some quiet
time and we have been recording shows
here on zoom' and they will be appearing
on YouTube but they will also be in the
Apple podcast and stitcher podcast feed
but Mike did a great job on episode 530
I want to send a big thanks to Mike for
the [ __ ] great show 5:30 was awesome
good job bro you did a really good job
also thank you to everybody who listened
and for all of the comments we got a
great response to episode 530 people
really seem to like seeing Mike on
camera so you guys send him a lot more
words of encouragement send me a lot
more thanks let's get him on a lot more
shows all right big shout out to Mike
and if you missed it episode 530 I did a
full interview with white Mike we
learned a lot about Mike it was a really
good time I had a lot of fun so check it
out
learned some stuff about my friend
all right what else do we need to talk
about I am also in the process I like to
give you guys garden updates I've got a
quick garden update for you I am in the
process of reversing a male know excuse
me I messed that up let me say that
correctly I am in the process of
reversing a female golden goat plant to
create female pollen which will only
contain female chromosomes so I can make
more feminized seeds from the golden
goat cross yes of course I will be
making more feminized golden goat I'll
make more Lemon Geoffrey
there will be more orange gasm in there
and there will be a couple of new things
and a couple of things that have been
made and were put out and were very
sought-after
and I did not have enough to release it
I made testers this time I'm going to
make a production batch of a couple of
very popular things so we're using the
golden goat reversed female to create
the pollen I also mentioned that I've
got the lemon Geoffrey coming up the
orange gasm coming up and of course the
feminized goal and go amongst that mix I
am going to add a Strawberry Fields
plant so we can make more of the red
pill and I will also add a blue berry
cookies plant to make more of the blue
pill both of those names were tentative
stress-test
names they will be changed those strains
will not be marketed as the blue pill
nor the red pill they will have a
different name when they come out you
guys will know it I've got the names in
my head I have not announced them I have
not made anything official I like to do
a lot of research and make sure I didn't
steal any names before I label a strain
but I've got names for those they will
be remade when they are available the
new names the permanent names will be
announced and the packages will be
available of course at seeds here now
dot-com so I'm working on reversing that
goat it has been sprayed its first time
I generally like to spray one time
before I go to flower then I wait and
put it into flower about seven to ten
days after that
sprayed the day which it goes into
flower then it will get sprayed again
every three days until I see pollen
sacks forming depending on the strain I
may continue to spray this is a golden
goat it needs continuous sprays after it
shows pollen sacks
I've been around day most plants will
show me pollen give me pollen a little
bit earlier the golden goat is kind of
stubborn it makes me wait until about a
30 day 32 I will have pollen production
shortly after that I will have the
females pollinated I will put them in
there when I see that the male plants
are developing well on the golden goat
that's how I time that up when I see oh
this female is now making balls they're
gonna start opening I see those real
male plants forming it's time to put the
girls in there that's the way that I
time that don't put the girls in there
until you know that reversal is actually
reversing then the that reversal will
keep going it's gonna take a minute to
turn it's gonna change sexes then it's
gonna make pollen and then by the time
you get those females in there and get
them flowering about 14 days in
everything will work out it is beautiful
so it's all about timing but that's
where I am I have begun the process of
reversing the golden goat it has
received its first spray it is not yet
into the flower room but it is getting
ready so that will get reversed will
pollinate some elite cuts I like I said
will remake some things and there are
also a couple of things you guys don't
even probably know I've got in there so
new stuff may be coming here in 2020 or
2022 cranking through this year you guys
it feels like this this has been a long
february or a real long [ __ ] i don't
know it's been a long tuesday or
something like that is what it's felt
like quarantine is messing us up i hope
you guys are going outside getting some
exercise doing something i take off your
sweatpants and put on your jeans make
sure they still fit see how many uh belt
holes you've extended your waist make
sure you're doing alright with your
health and with yourself check in on
somebody if you haven't called your mama
you haven't called somebody cool call
him check in on him it's not it's not
weird to call somebody to check on them
during quarantine time take care of each
other take care of ourselves all right
that's enough quarantine talk that's
enough plant update talk oh the leds you
guys i talked about growing under led's
I continue to be impressed by the LEDs
the plants want to eat a little bit more
but I like that that means I'm getting
more growth probably getting more
production the roots are probably
expanding quite rapidly
I am feeding them more I have recently
started giving them dark I give the
seedlings and the brand new clones get
24 hours of light I have recently given
them I've started giving them 3 hours
I'm going to give them 4 hours of
darkness here on Monday that will be
it's probably the day that this episode
comes out so they'll be clicked into
four hours of darkness and 20 hours of
light they are going to be some of the
clones in that room will be flowered
some of the clones in that room are
intended to be mother plants so once
they get separated out of that room the
light cycle will get changed again and
then the plants will get arranged into
their final spots they'll get cloned
then once we determined sex then we will
trellis them and there's some steps to
go but I'm impressed with the LEDs
that's my point
I love the LEDs I am seeing amazing
growth I don't think it's as hot as the
six hundred watt light that I replaced
that could be two three hundred and
twenty watt Canon LEDs in place of a six
hundred and a 600 HP s and it doesn't
feel as warm in that room of course
we're not to the middle of the summer
yet that's when we will really know I
know how hot it got been we'll compare
then but that is my rambling update on
the grow room we've got LEDs going the
plants in there look great I've got Jack
the Ripper's seedlings I don't know if
I've revealed that before I've talked
that I've got seedlings in there they
are Jack the Ripper from sub cool
they're from TGA genetics they are Jack
the Ripper's they look fairly uniform
there's one that grew it looks like it
topped itself it grew two main tops ah
that one's interesting but the other
four they all look fairly similar if I
were to pull off that extra side branch
that makes it have two tops that other
one would match the others very well so
quite uniform except for that one weirdo
that's kind of what you expect there
Jack the Ripper's they [ __ ] love love
love the LEDs they're in three gallon
pots soilless mix they've been getting
fed new millennium and bedroom and
recharge and they seem to love it you
guys that's what I got for you on that
okay I did say we were going to read
some emails I've got two emails lined up
we may pull out a third depending on how
long this episode goes depending on how
rambly I continue to be the first email
in this episode comes from our friend
Papa Roni and it goes like this it says
hey Rasta Geoff I've been listening to
your podcast for a few months and I love
it thank you bro I love hearing comments
and compliments like that and thank you
for listening I say this all the time
but it's really true if you guys weren't
listening it were just me talking this
would be a problem this would be [ __ ]
weird so you guys make this a thing I
would just be a psychopath or something
if I decide her and spoke into the mic
and stared at myself like this hey Jeff
they'd just be [ __ ] really weird so
I'm glad I've got a good audience I'm
glad you guys are so supportive and I've
been really loving and enjoying the
interaction that I've been getting
through social media through email just
during this quarantine we've all been
keeping each other company so thank you
I do appreciate that
so this says I am way overdue for
finally becoming a patreon country
patron it says patron but it means
patron I was gonna say patreon
contributors but it just says from
becoming a patreon but I am here finally
man don't worry about taking a long time
to join us on patreon it takes a minute
some people don't know it exists and
you've got to put in a credit card
number on the Internet that's sketchy I
understand and dude not everybody's got
a few bucks and I'm not I don't expect
money from everybody if you can you can
and you can now so thank you I do
appreciate that I don't want anybody to
feel bad for not helping me out on
patreon plenty of people do so thank you
to the people who do and if you don't
keep listening the way that you can help
me out is tell a friend how cool the
show is or just do your best in the grow
every single day when you're in the grow
think what would Rasta Jeff do that's
what that's the rules you should follow
in there do the Rasta Jeff method any
[ __ ] that can be done today
do it today don't wait till tomorrow
anything you can do a little bit better
do it a little bit better anything you
can clean up [ __ ] clean it up be the
best cannabis grower and cannabis
advocate and spokes person you can be
don't be a [ __ ] in public when you're
lit that's the way you can help me out
for free mmm you guys I told you I'm
rambling let's blame it on our friends
at Green Dot labs for the banana orange
cookies that [ __ ] is delicious and
potent alright there is more to this it
says for now you can refer to me as Papa
Rooney on the podcast their rhymes with
pepperoni just begins with a Papa don't
ask an old friend came up with it but
don't worry I'm never gonna ask why we
call one of my friends Papa Roni but big
shout-out to my friend Papa Roni I've
seen your name pop up and the patreon
contribution feeds several times I do
appreciate you thank you for helping us
out on patreon and it says I'm looking
forward to talking with you as soon as I
upgrade my patreon tier I'm sure you'll
be able to pass on a lot of
wisdom thanks a million for all you do
signed again from Papa Roni hey bro
don't be afraid to ask me some questions
you've signed up for patreon you were
part of the squad you're part of a gang
send me an email if you've got questions
we'll get them going anybody else out
there if you've got questions let me
know my email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com of course I do get
to those patreon questions a little bit
more frequently and sooner
so the patreon may be a way to get your
question moved up to the top of the
ladder or have a really good question if
your questions interesting I will read
it on the show I try to help everybody
I've got a stack over here I was
probably a hundred emails in there I'm
gonna read them all it just may take a
long time let's refocus and put me back
on the rails here you guys I'm going
away fast today and I got a lot of [ __ ]
to say this one comes from I don't know
if they want their name said but this
one comes from a friend down there in
Albuquerque shout out to my friends in
the 505 I'll go crazy in the house I
hope you're doing well
but you guys aren't going to Alba crazy
during the quarantine but the message
goes a little bit like at this it says
good morning my friend good morning to
you as well I hope you're listening in
the morning it says I write you with a
curious problem about some product I was
given I recently flowered five blue OG
Kush origin allegedly from we're not
gonna say who they came from allegedly
from this place in California my friend
had many other seeds and strains from
various other breeders my friend
happened upon the stash of flour and
seeds after the feds broke up the grow
in California so you found some flowers
and seeds from a raided grow in
California these plants were left
unattended and eventually seeded yes
that if where they just let's see I want
to read more I want to read that again
friend other seeds and strains what
happened to stash of flour and the feds
broke up the grow so there was stuff
that was left unattended ah there were a
number of strains in the room that
seated up my question to you is a number
of these female plants harmed out to
create oh if a number of these plants
earned out to create seed throughout the
whole greenhouse there were thousands of
viable seeds and they were labeled
accordingly to the plant they came out
of blue genetics allegedly tout
stability but all fiy knows were wildly
vastly different my question is are
these seeds blue og backcross or when
they herm
as the pollen get bad enough that I have
a bunch of crazy random crosses that now
need to be stabilized okay that's a
really good question I took your advice
and I'm waiting around or two to start
breeding I'm keeping some amazing fruity
gas and purple Finas alive until I can
afford a small tint to either stress the
female form or b.x seeds or to pop a
male so I can collect pollen any advice
or expert knowledge would be appreciated
I don't want to tell people this is OG
Kush if it was really crossed with candy
land or some Clementine or Lucinda
Williams and I still want to stabilize
this strain in the future and possibly
start breeding once since no one wants
to take initiative in Albuquerque to
breed bro there are a couple of people
doing really wonderful breeding projects
down there in Albuquerque if you do a
little bit of research you can find them
on social media very easily shout out to
my friends down there doing breeding
projects in Albuquerque I go down there
and do some consulting for some other
grows I'm not involved in any of the
breeding projects down there but I do
know what's going on going on down there
and the cannabis scene in Albuquerque
very interesting stuff happening right
now especially with the quarantine
they're gonna run out of herb if they
don't step it up ah but there are
breeders in Albuquerque so uh but still
don't be afraid to do it this is a
really interesting question um you said
you're gonna try to find a male out of
here you won't find a true male I don't
think if this was a grow a commercial
cultivation that was raided and taken
down
I'm going to assume and this is just me
making an ass of you and me that all of
the plants in this cultivation were
females they probably did not want males
around in a commercial cultivation
they're trying to make money if they got
raided they're going after money they
probably weren't breeding was probably a
big setup on so you got a bunch of
plants that seeded out they were all
females they seed it so there are a
couple of ways that this could have
happened they probably I'm gonna guess
they harmed out or they did a thing uh
where when the plants go too long they
make seeds and I'm not sure if those
seeds are going to produce
hermaphroditic seeds or if those seeds
are going are hermaphroditic progeny
with intersex trades or if they're going
to produce feminized seeds you said
you're looking for a male I don't know
that that's gonna come up if they came
from female plants there will be no male
genetics in that gene pool so you should
not find any males if you find a male
plant it is actually a hermaphrodite it
is going to express male parts but also
it will have female parts but there was
no male pollen in this room hopefully
allegedly I'm assuming so so you've got
a couple of good questions in here are
these blue og backcross or when they
termed as the pollen get bad enough that
you have a bunch of crazy random crosses
we don't know where the pollen came from
we don't know if that one of the plants
freaked out and harmed and made pollen
we don't know if two different strains
in that room freaked out made pollen we
don't know if every room or every plant
in that room turned into a hermaphrodite
and made pollen and pollinated that room
the pollen from plant a and B could have
landed on plants C so now you've got
seeds that are a B and C so it's really
hard to identify exactly what you've got
out of that room um then a bunch of
crazy random crosses yes you've got a
bunch of crazy random crosses um if
there is something in there that you
find what you can do is grow them
yourself your if this is a personal
breeding project you can grow them
yourself don't don't let me slow you
down don't put these to market these are
not for anybody else these are for you
this story is a cool story for you to
tell behind some seeds but these seeds
aren't for anybody else they're going to
be mutants or mafart i'ts and question
marks coming out of
seeds you don't know what's there you
can't ask for money for seeds with
question marks you've got to have you
got to know parents of parents of
parents and how they were bred and where
they were bred if you're gonna ask for
money for seeds ah that's just like
throwing up just like saying it make me
some food and we'll open a food truck
and I just go to the fridge and I get
seven random ingredients and put them in
a blender and I go there you go it's
what I can get you hope I got ice cream
and peanut butter and not like pickles
and peanut butter and you know so you
got to know what's going into there and
so I'm rambling cuz I'm high as [ __ ] now
we're talking about ice cream but jeez
let me get back on track you don't know
what made those crosses and if it hummed
out then you've got hermetics also
you're gonna carry on that erm trait so
if you grow them out see what you've got
and you said you're gonna find a male in
there there's not gonna be a true male
you're gonna have and don't stress the
female form or BX you're going to make
hermaphrodites by doing all of this
stress find something that is a solid
female that has the traits you like if
you really insist on working with these
to further generations find a female it
expresses full female traits that has
all the other traits you like aroma
potency color structure whatever you're
looking for find that in one of those
plants from seed then stress test the
[ __ ] out of it put it in many different
environments see if it I'm Afra nights
on you in there then here's another
trick this is what I do with a plant
before I breed with it give it a stress
test
put it on 12:12 for about three weeks
once you see bud sets forming you got
nice fat pistols you got dandelions
going up the branches [ __ ] with the
timer
put it back on eighteen six run it for
about two weeks see what it does is it
freaked out immediately does it act okay
does it not freak out at all then put
that timer back on twelve twelve and
give it give it ten days see what it
does
now you're what two four or five weeks
in maybe six weeks in let's [ __ ] with it
again let's put the timer on 24 hours
for two days let's just see what happens
this plant may produce seeds if it
produces seeds on its own that's okay
but if it produces hermaphrodite signs
if it shows you male flowers popping up
we've got to get rid of that plant or do
not breed with it
you've got to breed with one it will not
hermaphrodite on you you need to get
very very careful to not have
hermaphroditic intersex traits in your
breeding project
to identify a solid female because you
only want a female out of this batch
then what I would do personally I would
whip up a batch of silver thiosulfate
and I would reverse that female and make
pollen out of that female and put that
pollen on a clone of the same plant and
make reversed seeds out of that then
grow those if you did a good job by
selecting one that is not hermaphroditic
which it's gonna be scarce in this batch
because that is a trait that is in there
these plants reproduced without a male
in the room there is a sexual
reproduction that happened there had to
be pollen production somehow I don't
know I can't identify what did I wasn't
there but we've got asexual reproduction
in this room so hermaphroditism or
intersex traits is very common or very
likely somewhere in this gene pool so
find a solid female find the female that
is what you want stress test the [ __ ]
out of her reverse her by using silver
thiosulfate don't do it with light don't
do it with heat go do with any of that
silver silly [ __ ] use silver thiosulfate
reverse it instead of causing a
hermaphrodite let's cause a chemical
reaction in the plant this is a little
bit different people are gonna say I'm
crazy but we're doing it chemically it's
controlled I know what I'm doing it and
with it this isn't a trait that's just
in there I'm using some science behind
my understandings of doing this to the
plant so then reverse it and pollinate
of a clone of the same plant now you've
made s1 you've got self seeds grow those
you'll find many phenotypes that look
just like that mother plant you just
reverse and then you'll find some
phenotypes that lean a little bit
towards whatever the pollen came from I
don't know and you'll have more that
lean a little bit towards or whatever
the pollen receiver was it sounds like
you could have Lucinda Williams crosses
you could have Candyland you could have
Clementine you could have blue og you
can have all kinds of random crosses in
this room but I don't know what seeds
you're working with because I don't know
which planet came from well I feel like
I really went on a good ramble on that I
think I covered it though you've got
random pollen in a room I don't know
which plants the pollen came from I
don't know what caused the pollen you've
got a lot of variables don't try to make
money off this batch of seeds you did
say that you're waiting before you
started doing some breeding uh advice
and expert knowledge and don't take
money for these because you'll make
people mad it will ruin your reputation
and don't share them if you do share
them make sure you only share them with
people you know that you can tell them
this
story all right I want to thank you for
the great email this was a good one it
got me going on a good rant I do like
talking about breeding and breeding
projects I look forward to an update
this came in this is a fairly new email
so I look forward to an update what did
you decide to do with these seeds have
you done any research have you grown any
more out if you found any keepers what's
the next step I'm really curious thank
you that's my friend out there in
Albuquerque and if you've got any more
breeding questions if you've got any
cannabis cultivation or cannabis
community or cannabis culture questions
my email address is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com you know that I would
love to hear from you alright ladies and
gentlemen boys and girls pimps and hos
friends and foes smokers and growers
seed hoarders clone cutters pollen
truckers all you sexy [ __ ] out
there I want to thank you guys for
listening to another episode and for
watching another episode of the girl
from your heart podcast if you're
listening to this on stitcher radio or
on Apple podcasts or wherever you have
happen to listen to your podcast this
episode is available as a video make
sure you go to youtube search for the
girl from your heart podcast click
subscribe maybe leave some comments on
the videos let me know what you think of
the new show format I'm going to be
doing changes and upgrades randomly here
over the next couple of weeks I hope you
follow along and let me know what you
think of the changes that come from the
show alright if you feel like this
episode was educational informative or
entertaining and you'd like to make a
financial contribution of the show you
can do so by visiting
www.azcleanelections.gov on Kochi fyh
tennant check out again that's coupon
code g fyh 10 at seeds here now dot-com
ladies and gentlemen that is all I've
got for you for this episode I'll be
back in a couple of days with fresh new
content I want to give a giant shout out
to my buddy Jesse James and until next
time take a phat dad and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]