[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis Community
it's time for episode number 53 54 of
the grow from your heart podcast your
source for Cannabis News education and
conversation if you're a new grower a
professional grower if you're a new
smoker if you're a veteran and Dabber if
you're a cannabis activist or even if
you're just someone who's curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you welcome
roll up a fat joint grab a Dabber I'm
your host roster Jeff we are joined
today by King Colo once again welcome
back bro thanks for having me man his
real name is Sean we'll call him King
Colo we'll call him Sean we'll alternate
between the two he's got an alter ego
he's like a superhero and [ __ ] over here
it works for me he's the organic as [ __ ]
superhero rasca sitting across the table
from me is our good buddy Jesse welcome
back bro hey thank you man dude thanks
for coming we're going to let Jesse talk
a lot on this episode a [ __ ] uh well
yeah you have a lot of good [ __ ] to say
you showed up with the sheets man yeah
Jesse brought notes and [ __ ] this is
going to be good so thanks for coming
you guys on time and everything I
appreciate it uh as always I need to
give a big shout out to the Mystic Roots
man for letting me play their music on
the show big huge thanks to cat and coup
and the Mystic Roots crew um I usually
do an ad but sea just said something
that really got my attention here uh he
said that NPK value no longer matters to
him uh would you like to elaborate that
now that I've got some microphones
turned on yeah so uh I think mpk uh with
Organic true organic gardening isn't a
necessity that's something that is in PK
value is all synthetic it was invented
for synthetic fertilizers okay as a way
to sell them exactly um you know you're
you're just giving the plant what they
need when they need it uh and the reason
I brought this up to you is actually saw
a post earlier today and it was uh out
of a publication I'll just read it for
you quick do it give credit to who it is
okay so uh this is plant and prosper uh
you he's a really cool guy if you don't
follow him on Instagram it's plantor
inore Prosper sweet I saw him throw this
up earlier it's uh Justin Von liebig
he's actually credited with creating
synthetic fertilizers so here's a little
excerpt that plant Prosper posted from a
book that he was reading NPK gardeners
owned their practices to the great
scientist Justin Von Li big the father
of artificial fertilizers what most
don't know is that later in life Von Li
big acknowledged a grave mistake in
relying only on chemistry in fact he saw
negative impacts of artificial
fertilizers on life in the soil and his
own vegetable garden and thereafter
preferred organic matter to inorganic
chemical fertilizer he invented to quote
Von Li big after I learned the reason
why my fertilizers weren't effective in
the proper way I was like a person that
received a new life understanding how
nutrients will make us work will make us
all see the light and then ultimately
make us better gardeners with no with
more sustainable Gardens sorry kind of
buered that at the end oh no that's uh
that's pretty much been your message the
whole time anyway yeah is it the uh the
synthetics are disrupting the E life the
organic life in the plants and that we
need to get away from that and uh have I
said on the show that you brought me a
bokashi bucket have I said that yet uh
no I last show I mentioned I was going
to bring it to you but yeah okay well I
got to give you a big thanks for that
one uh big thanks and shout out to the
Rocky Mountain worm company Sean brought
me a Bashi bucket so I'm one step closer
to becoming organic as [ __ ] hell yeah I
ordered one last week too sweet let me
know how it goes we Bashi together yeah
we'll be Bashi buddies Bashi Bros and
don't don't say that out loud little
we all the Growers are like sounds fun
everybody else is like what the hell are
those guys doing I'm going to Bashi with
Jeff we got to go
class that's like the purple kangi
purple kangi Club wi and purple too I
took a lot of pictures today shout out
to the kangi Kush that's a sweet strain
so what were you saying about the NPK so
yeah basically NPK was created uh with
synthetic fertilizers is kind of you
know the basis behind it you you give PL
nitrogen when it needs it you give the
plant phosphorus and potassium when they
need it or when you think they need it
and you byass this natural process and
by doing that when you when you bypass
this process basically you're just Le
leaving the salts the mineral salts and
everything that's left over from the
fertilizer that's not immediately taken
up by the plants Roots you're leaving
that in the dirt because you've bypassed
all natural chemistry it's not being
digested it's not being broken down it
stays there it's like what you were
saying about uh CO2 in synthetic rooms
in the last episode yeah exactly there's
yeah there's nothing that you know I'm
going to have some numbers on that here
that's basically if I just drank uh
Gatorade all day or something salty all
day I can't say cuz they'll sue the [ __ ]
out of me but if I drink some if I just
put salt water all day that's
essentially what we're feeding the
plants by feeding them synthetic
nutrients exactly like you'll you'll pee
out the water but the salt stay in there
you know I mean it's you it's not good
for you it's not good for the plant
someone's going to say but I flush
heavily but you don't flush often enough
I don't think even if you get run off
that salt is still binding to your
because your plant has to metabolize it
and what it does metabolize is still
coming out of the roots as well so
you've got the extra buildup you put in
there you got the part that was never
used used and then you got the part that
was metabolized you got a lot of salt
stuck in there using the synthetics well
and then it also forms the plant too so
it's in the plant materials as well yeah
you got to smoke those salts right yeah
salts what are you rolling up dude
because you're a couple feet away from
me and that [ __ ] smells delicious over
here I swear it's getting stronger I
think that I brought the Wi-Fi Tahoe the
Wi-Fi Tahoe smells delicious did you
grow that uh no no I picked it up from a
local shop up in the springs nice shout
out to that local shop in the springs
good work yeah but uh yeah so with the
mpk uh we don't rely on the numbers we
rely on more of what it's called The
nutritive Cycle Theory so it's you know
the plant it's kind of like a person you
know the plant's a baby it's growing it
needs things to Aid in you know its
vegetative growth so that's where your
nitrogen comes in that's
where the those your potassium comes in
to help strengthen those cell walls as
your plants get bigger to make sure you
know that everything's going properly
instead of giving the plant directly
what it needs what we'll do is we'll let
the plant decide for itself all of those
things will be available in the soil and
not in the sense that we're going to
load it down without falam meal or bone
meal or blood meal but we'll we the soil
will have an mpk value usually you know
I calculated last time and just with the
real basic mix of like neem and Kaja and
Kel meal and things like that I think we
were running around like a 324 is kind
of what the fertilizer quote unquote was
coming out at that's fairly low but I'm
sure you got I'm sure that plant got
everything it needed yeah and that's and
that's where we come from is you know
that's the reason that when you go to
the grow store you'll see that organic
fertilizers are like zero or you know
1.23 or these extremely low numbers and
people see that and they're like oh
that's the other one says 0 60 like
that's going to yield me way more and
that's that's an that's a common
misconception you it's
not I mean you will get bigger buds
using that they're not going to be the
tastiest or the cleanest in the world if
I ate a bunch of pennies I would feel
full but I just [ __ ] out a bunch of
pennies exactly and I would yeah I
wouldn't get anything from it I'll argue
that you're not necessarily going to get
bigger buds from it um right a lot of
the like the you know 00 60 that sounds
like a a powdered uh Bloom booster and
uh those things can really [ __ ] your
plan up in a hurry if you uh try to go
too crazy with them they're
yeah yeah I like I said I as far as the
whole mpk thing I I wouldn't stress it
I'd make sure that when you you go into
your cycle make sure your soil's amended
properly and then is you know make sure
that you're feeding it it beneficial
bacteria that it's getting everything it
needs if you
know it'll have alphalpha in it it'll
have kelp in it if you need that booster
you can always top dress with like a
fish bone meal or make a nettle tea or a
Yaro tea there are many different
options and
those while they may not be high in mpk
that's what they're predominant with and
that's going to you know that's going to
get the you enter that into the soil
that's going to get the bacteria and the
fungi cycling whatever nutrient you just
ingested you know you entered into the
soil so they're just going to keep
carrying on that process and keep
delivering it to your plant as your
plant needs it does your plant know when
to stop eating at that point if it's it
it'll be like oh so you can't you're not
you don't run as much risk of burning it
with the Organics is something I've
noticed yeah I well when I was when I
really kind of first got into it I kept
getting a lot of nitrogen deficiencies
at the beginning of flour I mean like
every ran I did organic it would just
for some reason I would just get these
yellow ass leaves you know week three
and it just it
sucked trying to F your feed to keep up
and try to do everything you can to
chase it yeah but in week three if
you're already yellow and it's yeah it's
a lost race and I thought that it was
because yeah I wasn't feeding the plant
enough nitrogen and that wasn't
necessarily the case where I really saw
the Improvement was when I dialed my
amendments back you know when I really
slowed things down and was like okay I'm
not going to pound it with stuff I'm
going to make sure that the you know
soil food web's alive that everything's
cycling how it needs to that everything
is working and will let the plant decide
for itself and yeah I mean I haven't I
haven't seen you know any more I haven't
dealt with the deficiency in a while I
will say that I
don't I haven't ran comparisons I don't
run when I I don't run traditional
growth so I can't say that this is what
I'm you know you're going to yield
compared to this I only do my own thing
yeah um sorry I uh just trans um I just
made the switch back to full Organics in
my indoor grows um I had been using
bottled
nutrients um
and my my first I took the Clones my
first uh set of plants that we uh
transplanted into a good soil and
everything um we never fed them any
bottle nutrients or anything like that
so there wasn't any uh flushing involved
but I used the soil mix that was pretty
much what I'd been using previously um
when I grew indoors and I nitrogen
burned some of them I think uh the the
first half of the plants I transplanted
um
used one amount of uh all the inputs and
I got yellowing instantly and you know a
lot of people could have been like oh
that's lack of nitrogen but I already
knew there was a [ __ ] ton of nitrogen in
there so the next night when we
transplanted the other half of the
plants I uh just cut the the amount in
half and used the half amount of
everything and those plants just
exploded instantly um and they're still
out growing you know this been 3 weeks
ago and they're still out growing uh the
plants that we transplanted the first
night so go easy with the Organics
because they're bioavailable the plants
are that's right there the plants can
eat it you don't have to yeah they don't
have to do as much work to eat that so
you can speed them up too much by
overfeeding them with a lot of these
Organics and that's something we're
talking about with one of our favorite
products is ogt and Sean was teaching me
how ogt can kind of speed up the
metabolism of your plants a little bit
too much so go easy on the ogt guys I've
been recommending that a lot um replace
that with Rocky Mountain worm castings
if you're able to I was wondering uh
when I heard I listened to the podcast
last night um but uh uh was wondering if
that could be useful and flushing in any
way yeah you know it can it actually
absolutely could that makes a lot of
good sense I know you're a super huge
fan of OG bowar I started using them
here recently I am so impressed with OG
bowar holy hell I mean I'm talking just
from the standpoint of the plan
overall health I mean I haven't seen a
damn Yellow Leaf I haven't everything's
green and waxy it's it's pretty cool I
mean but the that goes to the new pack I
I had read somewhere that somebody had
actually mentioned hitting it because
you're only supposed to use the nutrient
pack I believe three times throughout
the whole cycle but I heard him about
introducing it a fourth time into yeah
about like or not even into flush I
think they were saying like around like
week you know a couple of weeks before
flush actually like really start cycling
in but yeah I mean that's definitely
something worth looking into it's a
great idea you guys are going to have to
start taking a lot of notes on these
next few episodes I'm GNA have Shawn
back Sean wants to do a full episode on
recycling soil and re amending your soil
we had a listener ask specifically about
that we're going to get to that one
that's always been yeah thanks fastberry
uh I don't know who you are but uh you
follow you're an awesome person we
really appreciate you listening your
input and I do want to let Jesse talk a
little a little bit or a lot actually
about he wants to talk about um light
deprivation my brain is blank today he
wants to talk about light deprivation
and getting a head start on the outdoor
season um Sean's got a a a bomb he wants
to drop I'm not sure do you want to drop
in now or do you want to put people in
suspense and give this new uh new idea I
I think that we'll we'll we'll bring it
out on the next episode on the next time
that Shawn comes over he's going to talk
about re amending recycled soils and
then he's got a a bomb to drop on the
ire growing world yeah you're going to
you're going to either you're going to
hate me or you're going to love me but
we're going to change the way you think
about a certain item that most people
are using regularly in their lineup
everybody everybody that I know is
everybody's using regularly in their
lineup I use it regularly in my lineup
so don't think that you know what I mean
I just learned this too so you know I'm
guilty of it as well all right then you
got probably we'll probably give you two
weeks to study up on it probably skip
you on one episode just because we don't
want you too many times so you don't get
stale and expected and then we you just
Ash right on the table bro yeah perfect
it fell
anyway I'm too lazy to get up and get an
ashtray but then we'll have you back and
we'll let you drop that bomb on the show
and disrupt everybody's uh growing
methods sounds good um I've got to do a
couple of commercials because I did not
do them and we're about to let Jesse
talk a lot um our first
ad first ad is from Natures green
remedies.com visit Natures green
remedies.com for gauge green genetics
llata lab Sin City rare dankness mile
high can Aventure the Cali Connection
MTG iy genetics and many many more
trusted Brands um I'm not sure what the
coupon code is for this month I'll try
to update you in the next episode but
make sure you check them out I saw a
coupon code sorry to interrupt you for
that no go for it let's hear it um I
can't remember what it was but it was
25% off and that's a hell of a [ __ ]
deal yeah it is if you can find that
coupon code man someone on Instagram was
talking about it there you go make sure
you check out Nature's green remedies on
Instagram it's like green remedies
nature or Nature's green or something
because uh Instagram is kind of a [ __ ]
and they've been killing people pages so
all right check them out uh shout out to
Yankee I'm sorry I don't have a coupon
code for you I got to figure out the
date that this show posts because if
this goes out after February which I
think it does then I need a new coupon
code that's all I'm doing here I'll try
to post one up at the end of the show
I'll make a note code is what I'm
writing uh since Jesse is here this
podcast is also brought to you by our
good friends at hro indoor growing
supplies check out H gr indoor growing
supplies they have two locations to
serve Colorado visit the Denver store at
6271 Beach Street or my favorite the PUO
location at 618 East 4th Street drop in
and say what's up to burn maybe Maddie
will be there maybe Jesse will be there
say what's up to my friends check out
hyro maybe I'll be there lately I've
been there a lot check out hyro for
competitive pricing and a great
selection of indoor grow supplies hyro
runs a special for the podcast listeners
all you have to do is tell them that you
listen to The Grow from your heart
podcast and they will give you
commercial pricing I wish I had some
cool effects for that under your entire
order yes there you go your whole order
you'll get commercial pricing uh that
saves you a few bucks dude it definitely
saves you some money if you're buying a
big bag of soil it definitely chops down
the price I used it today myself save
save myself four and a half bucks on a
bag of soil see four and a half bucks
counts it's make makes it cheaper than
everywhere else yeah that uh that coupon
code is actually better than the uh
employee discount I'm supposed to give
myself sweet also big shout out to Rocky
Mountain worm company if you're looking
to move to Organics more sustainable
gardening a better way of growing a
healthier safer way of farming a way
that will last forever you'll be able to
eliminate those plastic bottles
eliminate a lot of water shipping a lot
of waste uh you'll be self-sufficient
check out the Rocky Mountain worm
company uh if you have questions about
that check out uh it's King Cola on
Instagram how do you spell it actually
it's uh uh
kingcore C I knew there was an there's
an underscore under between the words
and at the end so make sure you check
that out but big shout out to the Rocky
Mountain worm company they're now an
official sponsor for the show I will
write them a really super ad I'm just
not sure how to advertise that yet all
the ads sound the same to tell you the
truth and they're great guys too they're
great dudes we're going to get them back
on the show in the future we're going to
have the guys from uh I shouldn't even
tease you yet uh the dragonfly Earth
medicine people are going to be on the
show pretty soon also so we got a lot of
cool stuff hunt Grammy Gatsby I hope
you're listening dude it's time for you
to come be on the podcast you got to
come everybody send the grimy Gatsby an
email and tell them tell them they need
to be on the gr from your heart podcast
all right lot lots of love to all the
sponsors for making the show possible it
does help out if you guys want to
sponsor the show just send me an email
it's grow fromy yourart hotmail.com I'll
get you all the information that you
need also don't forget that there is a
donation button on the website go to the
iry genetics.com website click on the
podcast tab on the top right there is a
donation button if you feel like
donating a few dollars for the time that
I spent putting the show together you
can do that I'm not begging you I just
want you to know that it's there do that
do that do that thanks so um I think
it's time to let Jesse talk about light
deprivation he's got a lot of notes over
there
um do you want me to just let you go
about it or do you want me to ask you a
couple of questions I had written down
how do you think is cool you got a good
starting point yeah I got a good
starting point well then get started bro
Here Comes Jesse I actually don't have
as many notes as it looks like I haven't
even read most of this stuff this is
just it's really big print it is pretty
big this top paragraph or three is the
important part um this was written by
um either either Eric or Jonathan from
uh forever flowering green houses sweet
I was going to shout them out yeah yeah
they're great guys great products um and
I found it on a website called the
gan.com which is also a great website
um joint
break so light deprivation this is just
a definition that weat tastes good I uh
yeah I can uh taste the Tahoe in there
for sure yeah um I was having trouble
and I've always always had trouble uh
explaining light depth to some people so
I would use someone else's definition of
it light deprivation AKA light dep is
the process of forcing plants to flower
with sunlight in a time of year that is
not normally the flowering period of the
sun's natural light cycle similar to
controlling the light cycle with the
grow light by turning it on and off with
the timer farmers can control the
budding cycle by blocking the sunlight
and making the plants think it's time to
flower um typically this is done with
the hoop house or Greenhouse of some
kind um however it's not actually
necessary
um and um [ __ ] I forgot what I lost my
track all right so I'll recap a little
I'll recap a little while you catch up
uh basically what we're trying to do we
want to grow outside but we want to get
a little bit of a jump on the outdoor
season before the police and thieves go
look for the outdoor crops so our trick
is to build a greenhouse outside or a
hoop house which I'll let Jesse explain
how to build a hoop house he's our
construction guy he's got a beard um and
a hammer and a truck so uh basically
what we need to do we want to put our
plants outside and outside we'll put
them out early before we get to our
flowering cycle that nature gives us
with the sun the sun cycles the photo
period is what makes these plants flower
so we are going to trick them we're
going to cover up our outdoor Greenhouse
or hoop house house we're going to cover
that up every day at the same time and
let them sleep for 12 hours and then
uncover it every morning at the same
time so that these plants are tricked
into thinking that the season has
changed to fall and it's time for them
to flower so maybe we can do this with
the if you schedule it right you can get
these going four weeks maybe three or
four weeks before everybody else is in
flower you can pull off one crop before
everybody else and that [ __ ] won't get
stolen here you can uh [ __ ] I have it
all figured out cuz I'm doing it myself
um if you put your plants out April 25th
here you will harvest um July 30th I
want to say wow that's early yeah yeah
because nobody gets a harvest till SE
late September early October mid October
yeah and that's with the 65 day strain
um you know so and you're not going to
worry about any cold you're not going to
get that freeze that everybody worries
about but you know in our region
possibly a little bit in the early
season you can put Plants back in there
and reflower them couldn't you you can
actually um you get two runs out of that
yeah two run easily um I've seen three
runs so actually I've seen four runs but
that was with a forever flowering
Greenhouse yeah forever flowering you
guys so a hoop house or a small
Greenhouse is the way to go if you guys
are trying to do this on a small level
the smallest level of light deprivation
I think you could do put a couple of
potted plants uh try to use a seven
gallon or bigger at least yeah at least
but I mean some people you know this is
for the guy that's just trying to do one
plant for himself or whatever put your
seven gallon a lot of guys are going to
use a 5 gon Bucket from Home Depot you
know that's what they're going to go get
44 what's up 44 so 44 you take your and
44 was kind of doing this last year you
take your 5 gallon Home Depot bucket
with your big ass plant in there and
every day at 6 o00 or every day at 7
o'cl whatever time you choose you got to
pay attention what time the sun goes
down uh get that plant and go put it in
a closet in the house just put it back
in your grow room yeah yeah put it in
your grow room or whatever a small
operation yeah just put it in the room
for the night and let it sleep every
night at the same time and then it has
to go back out outside under the Sun
every night at the or every day at the
same time as long as you give that plant
12 hours of consistent 12 hours of
Darkness uninterrupted every night you
can do a light depth like that and use
the sun and a closet for your grow area
here's a trick too um you don't actually
have to uh put it back out at the same
time just have to wait for um you know
10 11:00 at night you know safe time uh
Sun completely down no
lumens genius and then use a uh use your
Farmer's Almanac to find out what time
the sun goes up that morning there you
go yeah and typically you're probably
getting your first actual this is from
uh Jonathan a forever flowering actually
I'm not this smart but um you get your
first lumens probably before the sun
actually comes up yes so you know take
20 minutes off that time um but yeah
that's uh I've done it before the old
fash or the the other way of you know
Seven and Seven
and it's very tedious yeah yeah so you
can take it back outside guys bring it
in if the sun's going to set at 8:00
bring that plan in at 7:00 let it chill
out before you go to bed at 11: or 12 go
put it back outside cuz it's night time
or you got to find out what time the
sun's going to come up you know it's
going to be 630 7:00 in the summer
probably exactly depending on where you
are yeah yeah so that's a good good idea
right there and that's basically free
yeah you got to buy a pot of big ass pot
you got to buy some soil you got to buy
some Rocky Mountain worms you got to buy
some gr Kashi you need some drag fly
Earth medicine uh a lot of cool other
[ __ ] some azomite a little bit makes
that up Sean's going to teach you what
to put in your soil in a couple episodes
put all that [ __ ] in a in a pot put a
nice clone of some Grateful Dog in there
throw that sucker outside yep you can do
it that's free weed um you could I mean
you could use a garage a shed you know
anything if it's just a couple plants
old grow tent I've seen uh people take a
big ass trash can if you got a little
plant you take a little big 30 something
gallon trash can drill some holes in the
bottom of it so that you got air flow
and just set that [ __ ] right on top of
it yeah I've seen him do that for hail
storms but also seen him do that for a
shitty light dep it'll work I mean I'm
sure it work it'll work it's not going
to be you know it's not going to be the
most amazing but it's what you got so uh
do you want to teach these guys how to
do uh a hoop house yeah just like a
quick since you're since you're the man
with the hammer and all uh real simple
one is just you need a gravel pad or an
elevated area um I mean you don't need
it but you need drainage uh it keeps it
from being a muddy mess Jesus I'm ston
again um I made the mistake of not
smoking all day before coming at Jeff's
com to Jeff when you when you show up at
my spot it's dab time too you got a
pregame yeah you got to warm up um but
yeah I mean take two by fours lay them
down on the ground uh screw them to each
other make a big rectangle um 8 foot by
let's say 12T um so you need two 8T 2x4s
two 12T 2x4s
um make a rectangle pretty much handful
of screws um build that stake it to the
ground um lots of different ways to do
that uh piece of rebar or something and
then nail the you know nail the rebar to
the uh
um to the 2x4 with a fence staple or
something like that um and then take you
let's see 8 or
12T he's counting he's doing he's doing
construction I'd say at least six uh
pieces of
um at least 2 in
PVC um would need to
be at least 12 or 14t long I think to
make the entire hoop over okay um and at
the front you'll screw basically you're
just going to bend the the PVC into hoop
yeah into a half circle where you're
making kind of a it just looks like a
really cheap Greenhouse yeah yeah and
then you you'll use some clamps
um uh like some conduit clamps you can
even just screw straight through the PVC
into the but I mean you got to secure it
to the 2x4 somehow so um for a 12T
Greenhouse I'd put
up four of those pieces of PVC or four
hoops and then use one as a skeleton
beam down the middle that that would be
at the peak um attach it with zip ties
or something like that um if you're in a
really windy area um you'll probably
want to beef up your material a little
yeah um like the Front Range
Colorado but um and then you you know
just throw some plastic over it and uh
boom you got a greenhouse uh it's pretty
simple some Thin see-through plastic
right over it yeah yeah now you've got a
weatherproof a weather resistant
Greenhouse yeah and then so now you
basically built this big rectangle you
secured the rectangle to the ground uh
then we took VC and made arches and then
you just made one two three four or so
arches you got one at each in and then a
couple in the middle then you take that
one right down the center yeah and then
we just drape plastic and secure the
plastic at each on the bottom on each
side mhm and then uh do you let it
hanging you get make some on the front
and back too or do you just leave the
front back open if you're wanting to do
it cheap I just really recommend leaving
them open okay airow you get some air
flow in there yeah you're not going to
get unless it rains totally sideways you
should be legit right yeah I mean okay
you can have the plastic uh now that
Greenhouse is good all year right like
you can use that for if you don't want
to do light depth that's a perfect cheap
little hoop house you can a bunch of
cannabis in there 8 X 12 you can put a
lot of pots in there a lot fu yeah [ __ ]
yeah so guys get get some seeds going or
get some clones cut now because you're
going to want to get these suckers
outside pretty soon yeah like this is
real time stuff uh vegum inside uh we
haven't actually addressed this uh but
vegum inside to the size that you would
normally flip a plant um or even [ __ ]
bigger um top them a few times fim them
if you can our light dep plants are
[ __ ] G gigantic I mean um and they're
turpy they taste good they're as big as
an outdoor plant um when it's start
starts flowering Outdoors you know an
inground traditional or natural uh light
cycle plant so that's I mean the yield
is uh I'm not going to say numbers but
it it it's it's very much worth it okay
do it right yeah this will definitely
pay for itself definitely and that
outdoor cannabis is so good it's
definitely good it tastes good it's well
grown and then uh sun does amazing
things Greenhouse cannabis uh you know
has been protected from the wind and
rain so it's a a lot more frostier uh
looks a little more like indoor weed
green I think Greenhouse weed is my
favorite mine too yeah for sure yeah I I
honestly prefer it to indoor Sun turps
exactly you can't match that sun yeah
that controlled environment all right so
we've got this hoop house and it's
pretty much weather resistant it's 8 by
12 uh how tall does it usually end up
about 78 ft tall is usually about where
we are yeah yeah the uh the one I was
thinking of in my head would be about 7t
tall I've been in the one that I've
pretty much been in one that you've
built I've been in two they were side by
side I know exactly what we're dealing
with here you can get some big ass your
points can finish 7 feet tall in here
you can get gigantic with this I've seen
some guys in NorCal um I mean they have
scissor lifts to uh pull the plastic
over and [ __ ] like that they're I mean
just all right so that's the part we're
going to have to talk about now we're
trying to make this light dep so we're
going to put our plants out there when
they're waist highish maybe a little
higher maybe I'm tall so I can't really
judged by that I guess when they're
about 36 to 42 in tall you want to start
inducing flour and now we can't just
flip the light like we used to indoors
to 1212 now we've got to do it like
Jesse was saying we've got to use some
sort of cover we got to use some kind of
tarp so you need if you've got if your
Greenhouse is 12T long and 8T wide
you're going to need like 12 x 12 at
least to cover it because that Arch is
going to take a lot more space probably
12 x 15 or so right yeah yeah yeah so
just get a 15 x 15 tarp just that you
have plenty of coverage um yeah and make
sure it's actually um it actually blocks
out the sun yeah you might have to use
two layers um I have used I get green
tarps um because of the green Spectrum
uh supposedly you know
that's pretty um I don't know if that's
yeah I don't know actually yeah I don't
know about the science behind that
that's just I was standing there and I
was like H green t so the point is to
keep out all of the light because you
need it dark so whatever time you pick
every night if you pick 7 o'cl you got
to figure out what time the sun's going
to come up but if you pick 7 o'cl you
got to go out to this hoop house every
night and cover it up with the tarp so
it's completely dark the first few times
you do it go in there and hang out wait
for like
just lay down and hang out for a little
bit close your eyes and adjust to the
dark and if you can see any light if you
can see any light in there it's too much
light you got to make it darker I
continuously do that through the season
um yeah so it's um with tarps and
cheaper material I mean forever
flowering makes really nice stuff yeah
if you've got if you've got some money
to spend and some land to put it on
check out forever flowering green houses
well yeah that's not your backyard setup
though you can get just the greenhouse
Fabrics from them and sweet and they're
actually not too expensive uh I'm going
to do it this year um and they also have
a blackout tarp that's breathable so um
you know that's and it's not too much
just order the tarp from them um so if
you can afford that that um otherwise
sent you yeah yeah
please we want
hats I'm trying to close a deal for you
man
sweet um but uh uh damn I lost my train
of thought thinking about their bigeon
hats covering it up getting dark oh yeah
the cheap plastic it it's going to tear
throughout the season um so you know uh
continuously check it have extra plastic
um I put plast I put the tarp and then
plastic over it so um to make sure I get
a Total Blackout okay yeah yeah so you
can't have any light in there that's our
Point guys so every night this is the
whole time you're doing this every night
somebody hopefully you hopefully you've
got the dedication somebody's got to go
out there every night and make this [ __ ]
dark and then every morning you have to
go out there and turn the lights on by
uncovering it yeah and you're going to
get some air you got to have to get air
flow in there while it's covered up so
think about a way to to get air flow in
there while you're covered you might
need a fan towards the floor to get some
air in and out uh trick I use for that
is um this also helps keep everything
secure Sean's dedicated he just pulled
out forever flowering stickers oh nice
and a business card there you go yeah
help you get in touch with them for sure
tell them yeah
we do yeah yeah um I met him once kind
of so yeah but yeah and a dab session um
it was uh when they were Through The
Greener site one time no smoking allowed
there yeah oh yeah of course um but uh
uh uh [ __ ] I lost my train of thought
you're good at that dude was that like
some sativa or something in those dabs
uh yes that was actually some lemon
Jeffree Sour Diesel dabs you got to warn
me about that [ __ ] man I'm not a sativa
smoker you are today I'm sitting here
losing my [ __ ] man he kind of wiggling
around yeah yeah it's so hard to sit
still you guys would be uh proud of me
that's that's why I couldn't sleep last
night I was dabbing this stuff just
going I'm trying to get tired and it's
not working yeah dabbing it dabbing hard
yeah I'm totally an indicia guy okay
I'll remember that um [ __ ] I lost my
train of thought that's going to be the
name of this episode Jesse lost his
train of thought um but yeah know just
uh I'll remember uh light dep is awesome
you you were just kind of talking about
what fabric and stuff you were going
ventilation um I'll take a booster fan
like a 10in or 12in one um and hook the
ducting to it um tie it to the side of
the greenhouse so it's up off the ground
it doesn't suck any dirt or anything
into the fan um set that on the floor of
the greenhouse uh plug it in pull your
tarp uh hook to that have like a six
foot chunk of ducting and pull that out
wrap the plastic around it there you go
and make it do a couple s's on the
ground and all that good stuff so the
light comes in you got to bend your
duting to keep the lights out I know
everybody tells you to keep your ducting
straight but at this time you got to
bend it that's how you keep light out
and that puts a um negative pressure on
the greenhouse too helps suck the tarp
nice and tight yeah if you've got it
sealed up good okay yeah that's a good
idea uh use some uh some Timbers rocks
whatever that is or whatever um to hold
the tarp down um you know once you pull
it over uh you can have sandbags um but
that'll be on the edges on the ground
something heavy enough to keep wind from
lifting taking your tarp away giving you
sunlight when you don't need it and then
like squeeze clamps from Harbor Freight
like uh big old alligator clips um like
a jumper cable yeah yeah um use those to
uh help secure it all to the PVC frame
um um and also close up the ends uh wrap
to plastic real tight and clamp the uh
clamps on them yeah all right we got a
sweet structure we got some cover we've
got some air
flow um you can do the exact opposite we
got some big ass plants to go in there
hopefully you got some good iy genetics
or some gaug green genetics or something
to put in there that'd be pretty sweet
um you can do the opposite with this
also you guys if you're trying to keep
your growing season going longer you can
put lights in this greenhouse too mhm uh
which sounds strange but sometimes your
plants are going to flower earlier than
you want them to in some areas if you're
in a warmer place and then you can keep
it going and then you may have to add a
heater later in the season but if you're
trying to get two grows out of it like
we were talking about you can pull off
that light depth grow hang up a couple
lights veg some plants in there all you
have to do when the Sun goes down at
night just turn on one or two lights and
those will keep your plants awake so
that they don't go into flower and when
you're ready just take the lights down
then you can get that whole other it can
just be CFLs too it doesn't have to just
enough to keep them awake they don't
have to stay on all the time you can
just walk through every couple hours
with the light and it'll wake them up
for sure and just disrupt that and they
won't hurm out cuz they're out in the
sun like that they'll be cool so that's
a good way to get two full harvests out
of this cheap uh you're going to have to
put a heater in there by the end of the
season if you do it that way but you'll
get two full crops out of this and if
you're doing 18 by what are we doing 12
by 8 yeah 12 by8 you can fit quite a few
plants in there we don't want we don't
want to get you hyped up on numbers but
well it depends on your container size
and your plant size right but if you're
8T wide you can do either two or three
pots yeah I mean cram them in there
there's no need to have a walk space if
you need to get in there just pull the
plants out I mean it's freaking Outdoors
so um you know that's uh you like to
army crawl through your rooms yeah I'm
big and clumsy I leave a little bit of
dreadlock space or I'll get a dreadlock
hung up on a branch or something and
that's 96 square foot of biomass if you
do it right so toing lots of training
get the plants going all right 96 Square
ft of tops feel like that's a decent
start on light dep yeah I'm sure you
guys will have question
so that's what you got to do you got to
email me or Facebook or something me
Twitter me uh I grow Co no it's grow
from your heart at hot I won't say that
anymore I'm sorry that's a bad habit
it's grow fromy heart at hotmail.com uh
it's gfyh podcast on Twitter it's grow
fromy heart on Facebook uh you can
Instagram me you can call me if you know
me it's funny because I'll get like text
messages just listen what's up and I'm
like oh you gotta you should email me or
something it feels weird getting it this
way uh Jesse grow on Instagram yeah um
I'm kind of bad about answering direct
messages but uh me too I'll ad I swear
I'll do it one of these no I I normally
get to them I'm just not very timely so
it may take me a week but I'll get to
you yeah I got to sit down and answer
just all of my emails and Facebook and
Instagram Direct messages one of these
days just go right through it and empty
out the inbox takes work though yeah
yeah and then then you assign yourself
tasks when you do it yes I can do this
for you and then you're like oh there's
more work I'm already kind of I'm
already working light light Deb takes uh
a lot of dedication and commitment so
yes it's like ninja status but for the
cost of the supplies the time you're
going to do it uh you don't have to pay
for any electricity and the Sun is free
as long as you're reliable with getting
out and covering and uncovering every
day and not letting uh keeping the airf
flow in there not letting it get
stagnant in there you should be cool I
think yeah um I think when Shawn comes
to talk about his soil recycling we'll
talk a little bit about keeping bugs
away unless you guys want to talk about
bugs in the outdoor right
now I mean prevention yeah prevention
spinosad let's go for it talk about yeah
how are we going to keep bugs away
actually okay I had a friend ask me um
about caterpillars last night so um and
there's not a lot you can do about them
um once it happens just you know manual
labor pick them out um cut away the rock
you got to call Manuel and have him come
pick them up for you that's a p thing
that is a local joke sorry I actually
used to know a guy he uh he told
everyone that was his name and his first
name actually was manual but so how do
we keep the caterpillars from getting
into the
grow um I believe I was told those
little [ __ ] lay their eggs about 3
weeks before you actually see them um so
that's when it's still pretty early Bud
growth um you know it's especially
Outdoors they're still stretching a lot
at that point Point um there's just
little popcorn nugs on
[ __ ] um so uh spinosad is something I
had great success with last year um I
got it in a montere spray yeah Monterey
bug
spray supplies no actually we don't have
that one I think I bought it there oh oh
well we have the Captain Jacks now too
which um actually has more spinosad in
it than montere I believe so um
uh neem oil although um I mean ne ne oil
works great so yeah how do you feel
about spinosad it's a it's actually a
bacteria found in the bottle of rum uh
barrels yeah I think it's it's good to
be used it needs to be it's something to
be used strategically Like Jesse was
saying it it needs to be well planned
thought out talk to other people figure
out when they usually see these prob way
to put my thoughts on neem oil too
strategically you don't just spray
willy-nilly I mean you want you want to
apply for reasons at certain times you
you want to get in tune with your
environment that's where I feel about
that I mean you yeah you want to utilize
everything that you can there's you
don't have too many options especially
here in Pueblo with our extreme weather
and we get a huge variety of pet it's
amazing yeah well as you're high and dry
was if I was a spider M I'd want to live
here um Outdoors is the only one don't
say those words bro here I mean I've
seen crops here completely wrecked by uh
here goes Organics again I've seen crops
here completely wrecked by spiderm sand
powy mold and I've never had an issue
with them personally um I've found that
you know occasionally you'll have some
when the plants come out in the spring
and they're very easy to deal with um uh
a little neoil um maybe some uh uh like
lemongrass based something uh water uh
this you you know very easy to deal with
most of the bugs just don't like water
yeah um moisture the gardens I've seen
wrecked by them are new or bottle fed um
they're pouring [ __ ] chelated
nutrients into the Earth you know yeah I
think the the the big problem is is it's
usually in it comes in two situations
either a they don't do anything about it
and then they just get the infestation
and then that's usually where they want
to come in and treat with Like an Eagle
20 or tetran or something like that um
or the other situation is is that
they'll actually use those things on a
regular basis as a preventative uh the
plant builds no sort of self-immune
system you know you're all you're doing
it for it the second that you forget the
second that that insect builds up a
resistance you've lost the war so yeah
the trick is prevention you want to go
at it really you want to go out it you
systemically you want to add in neem
cake and crustation meal things like
that into your soil mix you want to
plant out spray regiments of NE oil uh
essential oils like he was saying uh
lemongrass uh peppermint oil uh Rosemary
Rosemary kill spidermite eggs on contact
um so if you see a little bit of an
infestation your first thing is to go
and remove any stippled you know
anything with stippling and then go back
through and hit them with some uh
rosemary oil what's your thoughts on
this um I have Rosemary growing in my
yard um
how would I go about just taking the raw
plant and utilizing that into a so you
can go a couple of ways so there's
either a you can make it like a
traditional essential oil which is I
have no idea how to do yeah that's just
that's just a quick Google search it's
really not that hard it's just kind of
like you you know you mix it sit and
forget it you know you might have to
apply some heat to it or things like
that the other option would be like a
cold process kind of like a ferment to
kind of extract those essential oils so
that would be more like a fermented
plant juice so then you would go that
would go back to like the Korean natural
farming that I kind of do where you
would take the Rosemary or whatever
plant you would want mix it in basil
yeah basil honestly you could do
mixtures of them all I do uh personally
I do ginger garlic cinnamon sticks and
then I'll grind all of that up mix it in
with the indigenous microorganism and em
one and yeah that's usually how I I'll
create a little you know spray off of
that also have a damn I bet that smells
amazing it does like like my girlfriend
actually likes that when I spray it in
the house um but yeah
so yeah damn I'm like forget what I'm
saying too man we got to smoke different
dabs next time I'm sorry we only took
one or two dabs and everybody looked at
me like I'm high let's
podcast uh so preventatives the stuff
you mix up so yeah you just want to uh
preventive preventatives are key so you
want to plan out your neem sprays your
essential oil sprays uh your spin ofy
anything that you're going to use you
want to make sure that you have it
planned out on a calendar when you're
going to use it before you go if you're
going to make things like I was saying
you want to make sure that you give
yourself a month or two in advance so
you can make them and they'll be ready
cuz these are you know 30day ferments
right and making worm casting tees and
things has taught me to plan several
days ahead now exactly you have to start
it you know 12 to 48 hours before you're
actually going to apply it yeah before
it's even useful yep get that foamy
layer which when you when you get used
to it it actually is kind of turns out
to be a lot easier cuz you know you're
like well I'm on your way out of the
garden you start this tea up and you'll
hit it the next day with it so yeah it
works out like that I'm getting away
from the bottles thank you you guys are
doing it for me so we got some hoop
house action kind of got some ideas on
how to keep away the bugs uh what was
the one thing you talk about a lot
karanja meal so yeah so there's neem and
then there's Kanga they're the same
thing you hear a lot of people talk
about like a neem and Kaja 50/50 mix
it's really unnecessary the big
difference is that like neem oil
technically has uh like uh what's the
word I'm looking for uh almost like
birth control style uh properties to it
okay which for human health reasons and
karaja oil doesn't okay so that's kind
of my basic understanding is that
they're the same thing basically kage
oil is a hell of a lot cheaper to Source
or at least karaja meal uh I can't I've
never personally used karaja oil
specifically but the uh it's basically
the same thing as NE okay you got me
curious about these birth control
properties now yeah I won't
ask oh if you really want some birth
control properties go use Eagle 20 I'll
make you ster oh yeah it'll make you
it'll make you twitch you won't get laid
at all because your eyes are twitching
yeah definitely birth control right
there all right I want to see if I got
over all the stuff we wrote down because
we're coming up on 50 minutes I'm trying
to keep this about an hour I've noticed
we get a lot more listens when we go
like 50 instead of uh 70 like we're all
Stoners we ran out of our attentions so
what are we going to say part of my
problem is I'm over here making notes
and reading [ __ ] you guys are just
High Let's see we got over that we got
over all the stuff that I wrote down on
this page I promise you guys I'll get
you a coupon code at the end of the
episode I'll throw that in right at the
end um man one of the cool words I
learned today nutritive Cycle Theory I
like that it's good I wrote that down
I'm gonna have to do that again read
more about that I said do that again
what am I going the good old NCT yeah
exactly no I just made that up I'm
that's new to me too I've got a couple
of post up about it on my feed and then
Rocky Mountain Natural farming's page
I've got a little post about it up guys
make sure you check out the Rocky
Mountain natural farming and the Rocky
Mountain worm company check those guys
out all their internet stuff you will
learn so much put on the podcast put in
some headphones and go type in Rocky
Mountain worm company and just find just
click on links and see where you end up
and see what you learn anything you read
on there is useful so just read it all
and then when you have a question just
comment and ask yes and I'll bring Shawn
back I'll be like this guy asked this
question and Sean will come and he'll
say this is the answer young Jedi and
we'll all learn to grow like a pro here
organically and every bit of this uh
applies to your Gardens too um corn
Tomatoes uh all that good stuff too yeah
yeah use warm castings on all yeah this
is not just pot yeah I'm glad that and
you don't have to buy everything at the
hydro store either there's there are
other store and I hate to say that since
you know the hydro shop is a sponsored
but you can go to the farming store and
the the regular grow store there's a
nursery around here that sells uh Grow
Supplies but they don't have any grow
lights or anything but they've got lots
of great amendments in things it's a
garden supply store you can go to those
places too you guys don't be afraid uh
agriculture horiculture stores supply
stores support your local economy yeah
they know why you're there don't rub it
in their face that's just a a garden
store man so well if you're on that
level buying that stuff you know the
etiquette by now anyway I hope I hope if
you're listening to us we don't have to
remind you to not walk into the garden
store and be like my weed plants need
more nitrogen bro no go in there and
just be at our local one I've seen more
than one person get kicked out of the
completely make you leave and I'm like
man I'm here for the exact same thing
but you know I'm not a dick so yeah they
know we smoke the joint in the car on
the way so we smell lovely and they're
like oh what's up man um before I forget
I wrote down this uh big shout out to
Lind big shout out to Judy big shout out
to Dreadful Jay and also everyone to or
shout out to everyone from bong TV you
guys been listening to the show I
appreciate that um that's something
important that I wrote down cuz I'm high
and forgetful today um we're going to
wrap it up do you guys have have any
final magnificent words of wisdom
towards the end of the show here uh grow
meeting March 6th at March 6th I'm gonna
write that down because I'm forgetful
today and I lost my pen how did what's
going on I got one be sure to be there
for that one for sure yeah let us uh I
don't have a topic um I did have a topic
but um I don't know how yeah uh give me
a new one uh throw throw us a nice deal
so yeah all right yeah so new grow uh
the next grow meeting at high grow
indoor growing supplies in Pueblo March
6 2015 I will be there I'm pretty sure
I'll be there I don't see any reason why
I wouldn't be unless fish comes to town
or something I'll be there Jesse will be
there Sean will be there uh we'll get a
lot of cool people there come meet us
you guys Armando vill this is your
personal invitation we wanted to hang
out and meet you for a while come down
bro all the people that have been trying
to hang out with us uh us Growers can't
leave we're kind of nerds and uh Hermits
and we stay at home and grow weed all
day and then uh we do we got to do at
work and then we go home and grow more
weed but uh so come hang out with us at
these grower meetings because we've just
committed to being there we'll all be
there all at once we're going to teach
you a bunch of stuff we're going to
learn a bunch of stuff it'll be fun and
just added it into the calendar man it's
set oh it's official now it's official
Jesse will put it on Facebook and
that'll make it super official Facebook
official uh February 27th we're going to
do another free tea day uh cool we had a
great response from that so and request
to do it again so I was like hell all
right I saw the TB and brooded it looked
perfect it was marvelous did you mix
that yourself yeah good job bro good job
Rocky Mountain earthworm castings and
molasses it's all you need oh I put a
little alphalpha in it like minuscule
amount so yeah make it bubbly yeah make
it bubbly show me what you're worming
with yeah that [ __ ] was
yeah oh this is going to get out of hand
if we do the worm puns again all right
you got any shout outs dude uh I mean as
always shout out to Rocky Mount worm
company uh you know everybody who's
helping us out over there Allan the big
toker Nick you know coming on last time
and obviously you for having us really
appreciate that thanks for coming on and
giving me great content uh you two are
probably you guys and Clint are my most
listened to guests so this one's
probably going to blow up since you're
both here it's like superhero status
what's up Clint come do a show with us
sometime yeah uh Clint keeps he's like
training wheels because he's he doesn't
know anything about can well not like
I'm not even being a dick he does not
know [ __ ] about weed he's like weed
ignorant so we'll be saying stuff and
he'll look over at me like what does all
that mean and then I got oh yeah you're
right we should tell everybody what that
means cuz we just talked like pros and
they're still learning with training
wheels let's have them come ask us
questions about Organics beginner you
know from a dude who doesn't even you
know come quiz us come ask us the stuff
that we've talked too quickly over and
lost people come remind us to slow down
we'll give you six questions and then
after that we'll give you six
dabs he's never taken a dab before so I
don't want to know if I'm not ready to
give a dude six dabs though my friend D
said that he's coming to Colorado he
doesn't live in Colorado and a friend
told him that his first dab he's going
to take is a Graham dab and I've been
trying strongly to discourage that from
happening but he's insisting on taking a
Graham dab for his first try dude don't
do that de listen to my friends here
they don't know you and they advise
against it you're just going to hurt
yourself yeah yeah I told him he was
going to [ __ ] up his whole day yeah and
then everybody's going to laugh at you
you're going to look an [ __ ] uhhuh
you're going to have to eat and then go
lay down and then wake up like 10 hours
later and eat again and you're going to
cough for 30 minutes you're going to
look like an [ __ ] don't do it D
you're feel like [ __ ] for probably 30
hours yeah see and that's coming from
three people that really smoke a lot of
dabs yeah I've I do gram dabs and a
grham dab is a big ass dab for me that's
my limit half gram is a little more than
I want three is comfortable like that's
and that's a big dab most people do
about 0.1 it's just dick waving I'm
sorry but yeah there there's no need to
do that um yeah I mean Jeff has his
reasons and and he's very aware that
it's just dick waving and I like to take
big dabs I just like pretty good at
waving his dick I like it when when that
dab when you're not sure if you're going
to come have a stroke a little bit of a
heart attack or if you want to jump up
and high five all your friends all at
the same time from a dab I love that
feeling that's and that's what a0 five
does to you cheerleader dab cheerleader
dabs cheerleader dabs guys it's when you
take a big dab and your arms just start
moving give me an a give me a b and
you're not even
trying similar to the Josh Blue that was
a straight from Facebook oh no he'd left
his ass yeah that's true shout out to
Josh Blue I've seen Josh a few times
he's hilarious hilarious guys I hope you
PID attention to all I hope you learned
a whole bunch of stuff today I hope you
learned how to build your own outdoor
hoop house I hope you're going to build
a hoop house in your backyard I hope
you're going to grow a whole bunch of
can I hope you your neighbors their
neighbors their neighbors and all your
other neighbors are going to be like
damn whose weed smells so good because
everybody is growing a big plot of
outdoor cannabis this summer that's what
I want happens on a county road I hang
around on overgrow the government they
can't bust us all they can't take down
every crop y grow grow grow grow grow
grow some more teach a friend how to
grow while you're teaching your friends
how to grow teach one of your friends
teach no teach two of your friends about
the grow from your heart podcast cuz if
you teach one person they'll get high
and forget if you tell two people the
chances are one of those people might
come in listen to the show so teach more
people about the show while we're
teaching everyone to grow weed I think
we're make your mom listen make your mom
listen that's funny grab your mom make
her listen to the podcast she might be
she might think that weed's a devil and
she'll listen to us the only problems we
had today was we all forgot what the
hell we're talking about Jesse needed
extra water yeah I could I already have
ADHD but I could barely sit um having
very hard time uh sitting still right
now that's why you're like the
construction guy that's why you build
[ __ ] all day cuz you're like I got to go
I got to do stuff I got to build things
Mar that's why I smoke hand theut dude
all right I will do that to you next
time no it's all cool I made these lemon
Jeffrey dads someone had some Sour
Diesel the other day and um it was very
good uh cousin Tater there shout out
cousin Tater good girl cous he's killing
he's got a bunch of my genetics and he's
been killing it with my stuff he does
well with my seeds um I'd give him a
best new grower of the year that I know
so there you go and then Adam let's get
Adam that award this year let's make
Adam the best new grower of the year
most dedication you got to earn it bro
we're not giving it to you yet but
that's what we want from you we want you
to be best new grower that we know
you're part of the grow crew now like it
or not he does what he's told to do he
puts the lotion on the
[Music]
skin no more whip for Adam again all
right I'm going to close the show at
that with all that nonsense you guys
thanks for listening you guys thanks for
coming dude uh I called Sean at like I
was like can you be here like a half
hour for a podcast and he's like sure no
problem so that was kind of cool Jesse
thanks for coming dude I know you're a
super busy guy I appreciate you guys
being here teaching the world how to
grow great cannabis organic and
sustainably uh guys thank treat mother
right that's right I treat your mother
right
too uh thanks for listening to the
podcast everybody um I promis the
episode's is getting better and better
I've got more cool guests people are
reaching out to me to be on the show uh
I hear the guys from can adventure and
sour seeds want to be on the show uh the
dragonfly Earth medicine people want to
be on the show we're going to get Allan
from the worm company on here like it or
not we'll duct tape him and drag him in
here make him talk I'm sure if I say
tell me about worms he'll just start
going and that's all I need to do is
just get him here um keep listening guys
they're getting better I appreciate you
for sticking through the weird winter
episodes when things got chaotic uh now
that the show is over please go to
iTunes or Stitcher go to the iTunes
Store or Stitcher is weird it's hard to
find where to make comments but just
figure that out uh search for grow from
your heart find the review section give
me a festar rating after that type in a
comment let me know what you think of
the show and will read your comments on
the show stit keeps changing the way
everything's done on there uh I don't
know why they keep doing that it's hard
to find a spot for comments sometimes
it's hard for me to read the comments if
I can find them I'll read them for you
don't feel bad if I skip you on Stitcher
it's just that place is a pain in the
ass it's free so I can't complain that's
where I listen to it at most of the time
we get a lot of good ratings on Stitcher
we were ranked there are you know I kept
saying 255,000 there are only 15,000
shows on Stitcher but we were ranked 888
for a couple of episodes around 50 in
that time period we were really kicking
it I haven't looked lately because I
don't want to get too excited or
disappointed but 888 out of more than
another podcast that's on there that's
more than uh yeah we for that week we
may have been the leading cannabis
podcast I bet for that week and I'm not
even dissing anybody I'm just saying
holy [ __ ] we've done that thank you guys
for listening you made you made that
happen yeah um don't forget that every
show is available on iTunes Stitcher and
uh every show is archived on iry gentics
colorado.com once again I'm going to
remind you that we added a donation
button to the podcast page if you feel
like the show is worth a few bucks you
can go to the website iire genetics.com
click on the grow fromy heart podcast
tab at the top right is that donation
button that goes directly to my Paypal
account guys I will never charge you for
the podcast this is always a free show I
do this I grow from my heart I give you
this show from my heart I feel like I
know a lot of [ __ ] I can get you on a
better path to grow better cannabis I
have a lot of friends that want to help
you do it this is free but if you feel
like making a contribution I would
appreciate it I'm not trying to beg for
you to give me anything I'm just saying
that it's there uh make sure you follow
me on Twitter search for grow froms G
fyh podcast uh find us on Facebook
search for grow from your heart make
sure you follow iy genetics on Instagram
that's a lot of stuff you guys I'm just
begging for you to pay attention to me I
guess uh if you're interested in
sponsoring the podcast or if you have a
product you'd like us to review send me
an email grow from yourart hotmail.com
I'll get you all the information you
need once again huge thanks to all of
the sponsors High gr indoor growing
supplies the Rocky Mountain worm company
and of course Nature's green
remedies.com big huge shout out to my
ninja Spence thanks for forting words
are hard when you're high thanks again
for listening everybody until next time
take a big fat dab and give your mom a
hug for me