this episode of the grow from your heart
podcast is dedicated to my friend steven
brody stevens happy birthday brody
welcome back podcast world i'm your host
rosta jeff and it is time for episode
540 of the grow from your heart podcast
this episode of the show is brought to
you by our friends at seeds herenow.com
seedshearnow.com offers seeds from all
the industry's leading breeders
including duke diamond miss jill
genetics and of course irie genetics
everything at seeds herenow.com is
backed by their award-winning
satisfaction guarantee
and for my friends on a budget seeds
herenow.com offers
several packs for under thirty dollars
as well as amazing
monthly sales make sure to use coupon
code gfyh10 while checking out to save a
few bucks
again that is coupon code gfyh10 while
checking out at seeds
here now dot com you know i like to
start the podcast off by talking about
what i'm smoking
today i've been taking dabs of garlic
banger number six
live batter from our friends at green
dot labs on the package it says this is
a blend of headbanger
and han solo burger the flavor is
described as garlic
cookies and sour i think i agree with
that when i crack open the jar i'm
punched in the face with a pungent
garlic aroma
when i take a dab i get that garlic
aroma on the exhale i get a little bit
of sour
and then as it sits on my tongue i do
get a little bit of sweet cookies and
garlic
on my tongue as an aftertaste so i find
that description to be perfect
on the back of the package it says the
product contains 69.97
thc i am loving the flavor i am loving
the buzz
this is delicious concentrate big shout
out to our friends at green dot labs
for the delicious garlic banger number
six
live batter all right ladies and
gentlemen in this episode
i'm going to talk a little bit about
leds we may read a patreon question
but before we get there let's do some
shout outs to the folks that support the
show on
patreon let's start off with the big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to my friend miss mel
let's send a big thank you shout out to
meredith i've always got a big thank you
shout out to my friend og purple thumb
let's send some thanks to stone to trout
bomb let's send a big thank you shout
out to grim
bull the druid i've always got a big
thank you shout out for lefty's farm
let's send a big thank you to learning
and burning i've always got a big thank
you shout out from my friend tim
let's send a big thank you shout out to
fat rabbit how about a big thank you
shout out to my buddy ned denver
and last but certainly not least let's
send a big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out
to my friend tommy big thanks big shout
out to everybody who supports the show
on patreon
if you're not already supporting the
show and you'd like to learn how to do
so all you have to do is visit
www.patreon
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need will be
right there on the screen
once again big thanks big shout out to
everybody who has continued to support
the show all right before we get to the
led talk
i need to mention music somebody has
asked me to post a list of the songs
which i have played at the end of the
podcast
i'm going to update that and i will post
that to social media so you guys can get
a good list of the songs i've played
though if you've enjoyed some of those
tracks you can download them you can
listen to them
hopefully you support those artists the
music industry is a pain in the ass
show some love to the artists that i
introduce you to you probably already
know who half of them are but there will
be some reggae bands in there that are
slightly obscure to some of you
so i will post that list something i'm
going to have to do in the future is
stop
putting in other people's music if i
want the podcast to grow
if i want it playable on other platforms
i want it to
expand i'm going to have to quit using
copyrighted music
every time i put somebody else's music
in the show i do get a
copyright notice from youtube they
aren't mad about it but i think over
time eventually they'll say hey you've
used
500 uh of 500 instances of somebody
else's songs we're gonna have to [ __ ]
with you for that eventually
it may limit me in growing down the
future so i'm going to
shy away from using other people's music
in the future probably another 10 or 12
episodes before we can
uh stop doing that we can get away with
it but if i want the show to grow it's
something i need to do and i would like
the show to grow i'd like to make the
video show uh go further i'd like to
make the audio show go further some
platforms will not take it with other
music
so uh the short version of this story is
if you are a producer if you make music
out there
i would like a short intro track just
about something
uh 30 45 maybe a minute and a half at
the longest
uh of course you know i like reggae i'd
like something that kicks in the door
with a big fat beat
uh something that lets you know you're
listening to the grow from your heart
podcast hosted by rosta jeff
um something about cannabis culture
cannabis community
um stay positive in the [ __ ] wording
if you put words in there
um reggae is best you know i like reggae
but i'm open for whatever
if you would like to charge me for a
song send me some samples of your work i
will see if you are doing what i'm into
i'm picky when it comes to music
especially if i'm paying you for it
uh if you'd like to trade for seeds
that's always an option if you'd like to
be paid in
cash or paypal that is always an option
if you're a producer out there doing
music doing production
especially some some sort of a reggae
project let me know i'd love to get some
music on the show
the catch is it has got to be 100
original music i can't use a remix i
can't use a dub
i can't use anything that has ever been
put on youtube or copyrighted
before it's got to be for me you can
copyright it but you've got to give me
the rights to that music it is mine once
i buy it from you
i guess that means i own the copyright
right so i'll be copyrighting it but
what happens is once somebody puts a
track on youtube youtube
has an algorithm that can find that
track and any other music
especially popular [ __ ] so if i put an
obscure song on there it takes him a
couple of days to flag me if i put a
popular song on there the minute that
[ __ ] uploads youtube goes hey
you just played metallica we know
metallica real well you can't do that
so it has to be something that has never
been heard by youtube something that has
never been copyrighted played in a video
before
uh original music so if you've got some
music contact me
uh the email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com i'd love to get
your music on the show if you'd just
like to send me
uh just donate a track i will definitely
play it give me
uh all the artist info you need so i can
give you a shout out give you credit for
your work
um maybe i'll send you some beans or a
shirt or something like that you'll
definitely get a shout out on the show
but
okay that's enough of that i've been
talking for a long time i need music you
guys i can't keep borrowing music i need
original tracks
help a wookie out thank you uh where are
we going next
led talk you guys holy [ __ ]
i have been very hesitant to switch over
to led lighting a lot of people tell me
led
is the way it's more effective it's more
efficient it's more affordable
uh the plants seem they say the plants
seem to like it i am a commercial grower
i'm known
my reputation is for running commercial
grows and also for being a breeder
in a commercial environment i rely on
numbers and we're going to talk about
numbers in the future but i rely on
weights and potency and scheduling
and i know that the double-ended gavita
lights the double-ended hps lights which
i've been using in a commercial
production
they hit all of the numbers i need i
don't know that
i would ever switch my commercial grow
away from double ended hps bulbs
in talking with a few friends they've
convinced me to give
led lighting a try i've made good
friends with a guy who owns an led
company shout out to my buddy keith
keith and i were talking and he said bro
why don't you run a couple of these leds
in a tent and let me know what you think
he honestly gave me two canon
lights from black sail market so i've
got two cannons from black sail in a 5x5
tent
i've been running them for um i'm
looking at the date i'm going to say
uh all of april and most of may uh most
of april and all of may i messed that up
but they've been going for almost two
months now
and i'm honestly completely impressed
with
the growth that i am seeing from these
led lights
i was really hesitant to spend money on
them and change my setup but when
somebody gave me two of them i put a
tent in a spare room i put some lights
some plants some seedlings under there
my tongue is tied up today but we'll get
a podcast going don't worry guys i put
plants under the lights is the way that
worked um and they've been growing for a
while and i am seeing
amazing growth i also put a cloner
on the peripheral edge of that tent it
was outside of the tent just
on the outside of the tent on a little
uh little table and those clones rooted
super quickly they loved that led
lighting so the clones
showed me right away when i cut clones
they never drooped they never did
anything weird they went into an easy
cloner
there was at the edge of the tent and
that light from that uh
cannon light at the middle of the tent
shone out enough to make those clones
grow
super happily they never drooped they
never skipped a beat that told me
something right away
i've been watching the plants that i put
in there grow they're staying
super short and super squat the node
spacing
is super tight most of the time i would
get i'm going to guess about an
inch between nodes and right now we're
about a half maybe three quarters of an
inch between nodes
so normally i would veg under t5
lighting was my go-to lighting for veg
i've edged under leds and i see much
more
rapid growth i see much more nodes
tighter node spacing i see more
branching so i've got my node spacing my
branches are growing out and off of
those branches i am getting
more shoots the plants are in veg they
are still what i would consider small
plants i have had to
defoliate them two times and i've
bottomed and cleaned them up because
they are so bushy and so branchy
that they would survive the way they are
but being a commercial cultivator i like
to go in and take off
excessive leaves and excessive branches
that makes my plants grow
more at the top it encourages growth to
the top excuse me it also allows for
more airflow
throughout the canopy throughout the
plants so i did some defoliating because
these leds are making the plants grow
rapidly i'm not used to this fast of
growth in my bedroom so
i think i'm really impressed um they're
growing faster they're growing very
healthy
they are eating like a champion i've
noticed that i don't see any nutrient
burn and i am feeding the [ __ ] out of
these plants usually by now
uh what i call getting the nails done
the little tips of the leaves would have
browned up a little bit that is not
happening to these plants i think they
love it
also uh it is not as hot i replaced
a so in that normal room there would be
a
600 or a thousand watt hbs depending on
the season in the summer i would run the
six in the winter i'd run the thousand
that's just things we do in colorado to
adjust it's colder in the winter run
that thousand keep the house warm
uh it gets a little bit hotter in the
summer take that thousand out put a six
in there
so we don't have to compete with it as
much but so in flour i would have a
thousand in there
and veg or a six in veg i would have two
t5s in there
right now i've got two 320 watt canon
leds from black sail and the room is not
too hot i don't have any air
conditioning running i don't have a
swamp cooler running i've just got the
lights running in the room with the
ambient uh airflow from the house
and the air exchange i've got a fan
blowing the air out of the room so that
we get a little air exchange
other than that there's no special
arrangements and it is not too hot in
there
the plants really seem to be thriving
they're not stretching
they're not doing anything weird they're
not having any nutrient deficiencies
i think i am impressed with led lighting
especially these canon leds from our
friends at blacksail
they did not pay me to say this keith
does not know this podcast
is happening right now i'm just so
excited about the lights that i wanted
to honestly come on here
and talk about it with you guys the part
i really wanted to talk about
that was kind of a setup it made me
think about by watching these plants
they're growing differently than my
plants in the past have grown because of
the lighting i've got brand new
seedlings in there that i've never grown
before plus i've also got familiar
plants in there
that i'm very familiar with which i've
grown lots of times for
years 10 years some of them three years
others some of them are not as old but
i'm familiar with them
i'm seeing different growth i'm seeing
different leaf shapes i'm seeing
different structures
not completely different but as a
breeder i am noticing differences the
plants are squattier they're not
uh branching the branches aren't as long
the apical tops the dominant tops aren't
as
uh dominant they're not as ridiculous
everything is staying a little bit
shorter and tighter
the canopy is more even without as much
manipulation
i am wondering uh if i would have chosen
different phenotypes in all of my
selections in the past if i had been
growing with led lighting
i may have seen different traits i may
have seen different features i may have
seen different colors i may
i haven't flowered under these lights
yet i may discover that i'm getting
different aromas
i may have discovered that i'm getting
different buzzes from these finished
flowers
i'm wondering uh if i've been growing
under leds maybe
my breeding would have gone different
directions i'm wondering if my growing
would have gone a completely different
direction
had i been using led lighting in the
past because my plants are acting
completely different
was there a phenotype in the past they
got too stretchy that i eliminated
but maybe under these led lights it
would have stayed nice and squat and it
would have been a [ __ ] champion
that's just some weird path that my
brain went down did i select
wrong plants i know i didn't select
wrong plants you guys are breeding with
them you guys are growing them i'm
having fun you're having fun they're
definitely successful
but it's got me second guessing
selections now it's got me
wondering like did we make mistakes in
the past it's also got me thinking about
going back and getting old batches of
seeds and growing them
and looking through them again to see
let's just take
a rise for an example you guys know i've
grown tons of rye seeds i grew up
probably 500 seeds looking for king
solomon just for that male
so i got to see 500 different plants of
that grow what if i grow 500 more under
leds am i going to see different [ __ ]
i probably am just that one variation is
going to
give me such different [ __ ] so keep that
puts me down a lot of other paths
keep that in mind when you're shopping
for seeds uh most of my stuff i send out
to a lot of people and let them test it
so we get to see what it does
under leds under hps under ceramic metal
halides
under t5s we also get to see some
experimental [ __ ] that crazy people do
out there and i love it keep doing that
but keep in mind you're going to get
different results i say when i grow it i
get this
but until now i've been growing under
hps's now that i'm growing under leds i
may
my flavor profiles may expand i may see
completely different things
out of my breeding out of my growing
this may change
a lot for me and keep that in mind when
you're selecting that what i have said
is based on my hps lights i do use
feedback from
a lot of other growers i've got testers
i've got friends they're they all get
the seeds they grow them
i use their input but obviously my
descriptions and things are mostly from
what i discover because i can rely on
myself
when three people say it tastes like
strawberries the word strawberries goes
into the description if one guy says it
tastes like a dog fart i don't put the
word dog fart in the description
if six people said dog fart that goes in
the description but ultimately i make
the description decisions
um so keep that kind of stuff in mind
you guys i was just kind of
i thought it was really profound i had a
lot of deep thought maybe i was baked
but i was sitting there thinking man was
i [ __ ] up for all these years
growing under hbss and selecting
differently making a switch really
triggered thoughts in my brain then
there's another path that my brain went
down
um i'm gonna call them our forefathers
the guys before me the guys before them
and the guys before them
the guys that were growing cannabis in
the 60s and or 70s i don't know exactly
when people started doing home grows
around here
but in the states when people started
doing home grows we were very limited on
equipment we didn't have a growth store
what was a grow light nobody was growing
indoors so we didn't have a grow light
and if you had access to a grow light
you weren't going to go buy it because
people would say what the [ __ ] are you
doing with the grow light
they would expect you to have a
greenhouse or show up with tomatoes or
cucumbers in a few weeks and that shit's
not going to happen
so there were no grow lights back in the
day also
there weren't websites with very
detailed
strain descriptions and seeds available
for people to work with so
people back in the day were very limited
on
equipment uh products and everything
everything knowledge especially but they
were relying on
the lighting they had a lot of people i
know older growers that would tell us
about stealing street lights or older
growers they would talk about stealing
the lights at the gym
they were using whatever lights were
available to them and experimenting they
didn't know
that certain colors would do certain
things to the plants they didn't know
that
certain lights made certain color
spectrums they did not have any clue of
that [ __ ] yet they were still trying to
figure out
indoor cultivation from the beginning so
the pioneers is what we'll call them the
cannabis indoor pioneers
were getting whatever lights were
available they were getting whatever
dirt was available we didn't have a lot
of studying we didn't have a lot of
access if you lived in
rural arizona you were using probably
rural arizona dirt you didn't have
a growth store you may not have a
nursery and if you did like i said
before you didn't have an excuse to go
buy the [ __ ]
so you may have to drive an hour away
buy something that works you know
whatever
grandma betty's potting soil from
whatever local farm store that was near
you and then
drive that back home an hour away so
that nobody knew what you bought
and then put your hopefully get some
seeds from somewhere that's
another thing where are we going to get
seeds from back in the day you either
had to know somebody that had some seeds
you had to buy some weed that had seeds
in it and grow those and hope for
success
or what a lot of people were doing is
our military members were
traveling overseas or a lot of
adventurous folks were traveling
overseas and they were acquiring seeds
from farms
where the cannabis was originated and
they were bringing those seeds back here
then they would get here with seeds who
knows where they came from well the
soldiers know where they came from but i
mean we had seeds coming from everywhere
we had seeds coming from thailand we had
seeds coming from afghanistan we had
seeds coming from vietnam we had seeds
coming from
uh brazil we probably had seeds from
morocco there were seeds coming from
mexico
there were seeds coming from everywhere
all over the place
and we didn't know what we had we
probably had colombian gold seeds we
probably had
uh panama red seeds we probably had some
jamaican seeds probably some colombian
something of everything but who knows
what it was unless you knew which buds
it came from
you were just growing seeds at random
there was no you couldn't google it and
say i've got
arise seeds a rise is across a golden
goat and daybreaker it should take nine
weeks it should taste like
this we can [ __ ] look at ross to
jeff's podcast to know exactly how to
grow it they didn't have that [ __ ] they
were all experimenting
and flying by the seat of their pants
while they were getting stoned
so a lot of what we've got now a lot of
the selections
were done through the shittiest
equipment through
the shittiest sources like the where
were where did the seeds come from what
equipment were they using
what kind of nutrients were they using
we didn't know much about nutrients i
mean there were a few
guys i mean people were studying people
were advanced there were horticultural
specialists back then but nobody was
advanced as we are now
and you couldn't dial [ __ ] up you
couldn't just click on the internet you
had to go to the library and read
books and people wouldn't go do that
back in the day especially potheads if
they caught a pothead at the library
reading a cultivation book they already
know what you're doing
and you don't want to go there anyway
you stink like weed you don't fit in it
felt weird
so a lot of our selections came from our
forefathers they had to select [ __ ]
from random seeds from random lighting
with random nutrients with random grow
equipment they were probably grown with
rocks and five gallon buckets under a
street light in the basement just trying
to figure it all out
i don't know i really got my mind
thinking uh so now we're using all of
that stuff
as our breeding stock now all of the
[ __ ] that those guys selected
uh in the 60s and the 70s maybe even
before that because cannabis has been
around for a while
i've heard stories of way back in the
day jazz musicians
would come into town let's just say that
i know jazz musicians they play at the
club down the street after the show
they all come here we smoke a little bit
of weed we hang out they crash on my
couch they get up the next day
they go to the next state to play
another gig while they're here we're
gonna smoke right that's just what we do
this was way back in the day before
everybody had herb they would leave me
some seeds they'd say hey jeff
these seeds came out of our herb i know
you like to smoke we like to smoke we're
gonna come on tour next year because
we're traveling musicians it's what we
do
we want you to grow this grow these
seeds produce this herb
and then next year when we come back
you'll have more seeds and more herb for
us we can smoke with you you can
give us you could probably sell us some
herb if you grow it i don't know how
that worked i don't know the
arrangement but you give them herb you
give them seeds and then you end up with
herb and seeds
and then they travel around and they
take that herb to the next state maybe
i'm in pueblo colorado we'll say their
next gig is in [ __ ] santa fe
they drive down to santa fe they leave
some of my new seeds that i've made with
those people in santa fe and some weed
with them and they say grow this next
year
so everywhere they travel they dropped
off weed and seeds if they had it
and then every time they came back next
year weed and seeds and they expand
every year they got bigger they did more
gigs they didn't have to wait till
albuquerque to get to the next gig they
got to play in trinidad next year so
that was pueblo trinidad
albuquerque santa fe and they've got
weed growing everywhere that's just some
stories i've heard about how people used
to
start getting people growing weed and
having a supplyable a reliable supply
of cannabis for when you're traveling
around old jazz musician story
that was told to me by some old jazz
musician cats but
man think about those guys were the ones
selecting your cannabis
breeding strains they just dropped off
some seeds somebody grew it
and then those guys had to select from
that from that gene pool was what they
got to work with
so we've got to either i'm not sure do
we thank or do we blame
our forefathers for the selections which
we're working with now there were a lot
of guys like mel frank out there doing
great selections
but also there were a lot of guys out
there in basements just doing random
selections
and then all of that became our future
gene pool what we've got now
so all of the stuff we're working with
now was based off of
just really archaic equipment archaic
selections
i don't know really makes my brain think
would selections have been different
would we work be working with different
cannabis plants today would different
ship be popular would it have taken a
totally different route
i also think that they didn't have lab
testing nobody was looking for
other secondary cannabinoids everybody
was focused on high thc because
the only thing they had as a test was
them they could smoke it and go
i'm high as [ __ ] or they could smoke it
and go man i didn't get high
that was the lab test for them so we
tossed out everything that didn't get
you high as [ __ ] if it didn't have the
red eye head buzz to it that we were
looking for
it went away so basically i was just
daydreaming and wondering
how cannabis would be different if we'd
done different selections if we'd had
different
equipment different technology uh
different seeds
uh just i don't know my brain went down
that path and i thought it was a fun
ramble to share with you guys but that
is my rant on led lighting big shout out
to my buddy keith
at black sail market for hooking me up
with two canon leds
i honestly was so impressed with the
first two but i ordered three more
already
uh they're here they'll be hung up very
soon they're going to go in
the mother room and the small veg space
and then
once i see how this first room flowers
out if i'm as excited as i think i'm
going to be i will replace
all of the lights in my personal flower
space
with led lighting that's right i'll
switch my personal grow
from hps all to led lighting the
commercial grow will stay the same
trust me i'm not ready to make that leap
maybe when the technology evolves a
little a little better
and maybe but i'm a little more
impressed with it but not yet but so far
the homegrown
is going to make the switch all right
ladies and gentlemen i did say i was
going to read a patreon question let's
jump right into that part of the show
if you're not supporting the show on
patreon and you'd like to learn how to
do so all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need is right
there on the screen today's patreon
message goes
just like this hey ross to jeff refer to
me as smoke what
because there is a possibility i could
be in prohibition land but who knows
i don't know nothing bro it goes on to
say i heard on your show that a few
people were unable to continue their
patreon subscription
and lately i've been blessed so i
thought it is my time to step up and
help a brother out hey thank you i
appreciate that
um if you guys aren't able to help out
on patreon during this weird covet time
please don't stress on that but i do
appreciate all of the people who have
stepped up during this weirdness
thank you and big thanks to our friend
smoke what for the new patreon support
his message goes on to say i'm starting
to experiment with creating some
personal seats but i battle temps with
my leds in small spaces and i have
trouble running over 400 watts and
summer is right around the corner yes it
is my friend you better figure out how
to cool that off
it says i don't have any questions but
the project i am starting is going to be
a fun one and i cannot wait to update
you in a year or so
bro i look forward to the updates i
cannot wait to see what you do
it says since i might have to wait until
winter to produce any seeds
it could be an uphill battle reaching
some of my goals until we find some
legalization here
and i can stretch out a bit bro don't
get yourself in trouble and my advice is
if it's going to be an uphill
battle wait until the winter because you
don't want to make struggle
seeds now there is another paragraph
here and it says
one thing i thought might be a good idea
is to collect genetics for when my state
opens up to the legal markets
what would you suggest for strains that
are either overlooked in the legal
community or ones that possibly never
made it into the legal cannabis markets
i have the most i have most of the
popular ones in your collection but i
don't know much about
other strains out there despite there
being epic strains everywhere
i'm thinking of something that i can
bring to the groves that lack the
product the product to fill them when
legalization passes
i says anyways until next time stay irie
hug your mom and take a fat dab for me
emphasis on the dabs because
concentrates are too illegal here
and i don't want to risk the 10 to 20
year
lodging they offer for having them holy
[ __ ]
that puts life into perspective dude
this person said
10 to 20 years for possession of
concentrates where they are
and i have got 4 8 12 and there is at
least 20 grams of concentrate sitting
here on the table
bro that puts [ __ ] into perspective i am
blessed i'm thankful to be here to be
able to take these dabs
i will for sure take a fat dab for you
my friend smoke what
now let's focus focus on the question
here uh smoke what asked
uh they want to start saving genetics
they want to have genetics ready
for when legalization happens in their
area they want to be able to put quality
genetics into a dispensary
and they want to know what i would
suggest for strains that are either
overlooked
or possibly never made it into legal
cannabis
markets that's a really good question um
strains that never made it that are
often overlooked are kind of some of the
older strains that people ask for you're
going to get
if you open a dispensary and you start
getting traffic you're going to get
an older demographic that will ask for
uh stuff like acapulco gold
and uh colombian gold and the panama red
and stuff like that they're gonna want
that stuff the older uh like the veteran
age guys are gonna want that [ __ ]
then there's gonna be another crowd that
comes in and they're gonna want
durbin poison and white widow and train
wreck
that is a generational thing then after
that you're going to get people that
come in and want sour diesel
and chem dog and og kush that's another
generational thing then right after that
you're going to get people that want
all of the wedding cake and cake balm
and [ __ ] girl scout cookies and all
the girl scout cookies out crosses that
shit's gonna happen also
it is really hard to fill all of the
needs for a dispensary
for the shelves um you kind of asked
me to mention things that were
overlooked or things that have been
forgotten about
like i said before the panama's the
acapulcos the colombians those things
missed the dispensary they never made it
into the dispensary but there's probably
a reason
um in a commercial environment you've
got to meet
goals you've got to reach production
goals and that has to be a schedule
if the plants take 11 or 12 weeks to
flower they're probably not going to
make it in a commercial grow i need 9
weekers
if it takes 8 to ten weeks i'm going to
run it nine weeks
to fit into my schedules and that plant
if it wants to go nine if it survives
if it makes everybody happy that
qualifies for the commercial grow
it's got to put out weight it's got to
hit harvest goals
most of my plants hit certain weights if
they don't hit enough weight i'm not
going to reach goals i'm not going to
get bonuses we're not going to have
enough medicine for the shelves nobody
will be happy
i cannot keep that plant in the facility
it's got to go so it's got to reach
the weight goals that has also got to
reach potency goals
if it puts out a whole bunch of weed in
nine weeks but when people smoke it
nobody gets high
that plant's got to go so it's got a
flower on time it's got to put out
weight it's got to be potent
it's also got to sell when i put it on
the shelf does it go anywhere
there are probably 70 strains in a lot
of my commercial
production facilities we have somewhere
between 50 and 70 mother plants
per commercial cultivation facility
there's a reason for each and every one
of them
if one of them slows down or doesn't
have momentum on the shelf if it sits
there for long enough
toward the time i grow the next batch if
they've still got some of that i don't
grow it anymore that plant gets cold we
remove that from the system
bye bye it doesn't work for a commercial
cultivation facility
so there are a lot of things to think
about when you're trying to
select genetics for a commercial
cultivation facility
um everybody every dispensary should
have something fruity
whether it's like a i'm saying fruity
you want fruity flavors if it's blue
dream or golden goat that qualifies as
fruity
everybody needs a berry flavor if it's
blueberry if it's cherry
you need some kind of berries in there a
berry mix you need fruit you need
berries
uh you need floral i think every
dispensary needs something floral it's
gotta smell like sweet flowers girls
love that floral smell and [ __ ] some
guys love it too
so you need fruit berries and floral
that could be
one strain that covers all of those and
hopefully they don't catch on but if
you've got three strains to cover fruit
berries and floral you're in business
also every dispensary needs something
that smells gassy
and or fuelly sour diesel uh chem di95
something in that
fuely funky gassy kind of range we also
need some earthy smelling [ __ ] something
like og kush
something like a bubba kush a pre-98
bubba something in that realm
something like the gmo we need stuff
like that so you need fruit
berries floral gas and earth is
something that i think all dispensaries
require required to have on their shelf
that is your basic shopping area right
there
uh then after that people are going to
ask for your highest
lab tests it's all about the lab test so
if you've got something that tests real
high in the labs
that is a really good thing to put on
the shelf put that 35
thc sticker on there they'll walk in
they'll be drawn to that sticker they'll
buy that [ __ ] they won't ask any other
questions that's what people want
people want something with a really
strong head buzz when i walk in i want
the thing that's going to make me go oh
[ __ ] i'm having a panic attack
that's the weed i want so have something
with a really strong head buzz
have something with a really strong body
buzz you're going to find people that
want to relax
people that want to take a nap people
that are high strung and need to chill
the [ __ ] out
they need something with that body buzz
you may find people that want something
with high cbd i mentioned before they
want high thc one they want that lab
test that's really appealing to people
also cbd is very popular right now so
you may want to find
a strain that is high in cbd those lab
tests go a long way
in a retail market so put the lab
numbers on the jars have the lab numbers
available to where people can see them
they'll see that number they'll forget
everything they were talking about or
saying or thinking and they'll go i want
that 35
jar and then they'll buy that and you
make money so uh lab tests really help a
lot something high thc high cbd
also think about the other cannabinoids
which are becoming popular thcv
is really popular right now people are
looking for thcv products if you can
find a strain
inv put that on your shelf brag about it
advertise about it because it is not a
super popular trait right now but people
want that
uh something else you're gonna need to
have on the strain og kush and og kush
crosses
everybody wants some sort of a kush we
need that stanky
og kush aroma whether it's uh an og
cross
a straight up og if you've got a kush on
the shelf people will be drawn to that a
lot of the
the younger kids the gangster guys they
heard cushion a rap song they're gonna
come by kush
uh diesel i mentioned before diesel is
popular you need a diesel but
don't embarrass yourself and grow
something that says diesel and does not
smell like diesel at all because we will
call you out we'll say that's not
[ __ ] diesel that smells like berries
and fruit
we want [ __ ] diesel so get a real
diesel
if not don't waste your time because it
will be embarrassing mdi95
sour diesel something like that will
make you real happy uh
chem we need some chem dog genetics on
every shelf at every dispensary
you've got so many options for kim you
got chem 91 you got kim d you got chem
four you got kim's sister put some chem
dog
on the shelf everybody loves chem dog
that [ __ ] will sell
uh also it'll make you stand out not a
lot of people can grow some really fire
chem dog if you've got the chem
and it's doing the job right it will
make everybody happy
then here are some things you need to
think about what kind of and i'm
thinking that you're opening a
dispensary and i'm kind of thinking down
the road for you
what type of vibe do you want your
dispensary to have
if you stock the stuff like the acapulco
gold and that panama red and the
colombian gold and [ __ ]
you're gonna bring in an older veteran
type of crowd if you've got the og kush
and the sour diesel you're going to
bring in a younger type of crowd
do you want to cater to medical patients
do you want to cater to
the hype crowd you kind of get to decide
that by the atmosphere the ambiance the
environment and the products which you
stock at your dispensary
so do you want to carry the hype [ __ ] do
you want to have i don't even know the
new hype [ __ ] do you want to have gelato
44 and cake bomb and
cherry cake and wedding pie do you want
to have all that [ __ ] on the shelf
that's going to bring all the youngsters
in there that's gonna bring all the hip
kids all the hypebeasts
all the youngsters all the instagram
kids they're all gonna come in for that
stuff you can have a shop like cookies
where you just got flow in all day or
you can have a little quaint shop that
is kind of up to you
so do you want that hype [ __ ] uh you can
get that if you want it
it will bring the hype crowd do you want
that older stuff the acapulco gold the
panama red that is going to bring you
that older crowd sometimes you may
notice that young hype crowd
and that old veteran crowd they don't
blend perfectly well together it's not
the best marketing strategy that may
sound crazy because they've both got
money in their pockets they're all
buying herb
but you've got to set the environment
that you expect for your dispensary
it you'll see what i mean it's a niche
thing if you've got the acapulco gold
and
the [ __ ] cake bomb you'll get a good
crowd it's hard to keep it balanced out
of what stays on the shelf
you've only got so much shelf space
you've only got so many plants there's a
lot of thinking to do
so which kind of crowd do you want to
bring what kind of atmosphere do you
want to invent
what type of products do you want to
offer that is all up to you um i said
before everybody's going to want a girl
scout cookies cross
especially right when you open up in a
new market everybody has heard about
girl scout cookies they're going to come
in they're going to want cookies
the same as i said about sour diesel if
you've got a real
girl scout cookies cut if you've got the
form cut if you've got the thin mint cut
put that [ __ ] on the shelf at the
dispensary if you've got a knock off
girl scout cookies if you've got a bag
seed
if you've got something that you bought
from seeds from somebody and it came out
questionable not 100 girl scout cookies
don't put it on the shelf because
a an experienced connoisseur smoker will
come in there
they'll look at it and they'll go that
is not girl scout cookies your place is
whack
they will leave if you're trying to say
you got sour d and it's not sour d
i'm leaving if you try to say you got
girl scout cookies and it's not girl
scout cookies i'm [ __ ] leaving make
sure
if you're selling and displaying a hype
strain make sure it is grown and
displayed
properly and it is really what you're
saying it is a lot of us can tell
i can look at girl scout cookies buds
and tell you
nope or oh yeah i can tell by the look i
can tell by the smell
i can crack it open i can tell by the
texture i know girl scout cookies very
well
most connoisseurs do know the cookies
very well and we will call you
if you're [ __ ] with us so people are
going to want girl scout cookies they're
going to want train wreck
they're going to want anything with the
word cake in it cake bomb
wedding cake a rise cake that doesn't
exist but i'm sure it would [ __ ] sell
if it existed
the gelatos things like that biscotti
all that popular stuff is going to sell
it is all about kind of what you want to
put on the dispensary shelf
kind of all about what you want to put
in your cultivation what goes in the
trays what goes in the rooms what grows
well for you
it's got to grow well it's got to
produce it's got to hit numbers it's got
to be
not a pain in the ass to trim if it
slows down the trim crew too much get
rid of it
if it messes up any of your flow it
needs to go if it works well for
everything from the beginning to the end
if it goes from the
seed to the cash register without
problems put that [ __ ] on the shelf put
that [ __ ] in the grow
but it also has to make all of the
consumers happy so
you have to kind of decide what ends up
happening as people set up dispensaries
kind of based on like my breeding is
based on what i enjoy
my dispensary would be filled with
strains that i enjoy i would attract a
crowd similar to myself
that smokes and enjoys things that i
enjoy the demographic would end up being
probably 25 to 45 year old dudes that
listen to reggae and have dreadlocks
that would be a big part of my
demographic at my dispensary but that
that would be cool with me because
that's who i hang out with i want
everybody to come and shop but i mean
the main core
would just be 25 to 40 year old dudes
with dreadlocks listening to reggae
music on their way to band practice
probably who would stop by all right um
so it's all up to you what you want to
put in the dispensary it's got to work
in the grow it's got to work on the
shelves it's got to work for the the
consumers
i think i gave you a pretty good rundown
of all the basics fruit berries floral
gas
head buzz body buzz thc cbd maybe some
thcv
i need og kush sour diesel chem dog you
want those old things for the old guys
if you can get it in there
or maybe you don't if it doesn't work in
the garden maybe there's a reason why
that [ __ ] is not around
do you want to work with the hype [ __ ]
and how do you want your menu to look
all right i think i really covered your
message uh let me make sure there's
nothing i'm missing in here because this
did come from patreon
i think i got it all for you hey my
buddy smoked what i want to thank you
for the great patreon message
if anybody out there else out there has
a question i would love to hear from you
my email address is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com
also don't forget to join us on patreon
that message did come from patreon that
is a very good way to get your question
up to the top of the list all right
ladies and gentlemen boys and girls
pimps and hoes friends and foes
smokers and growers clone cutters pollen
chuckers
uh seed hoarders and skateboarders that
is all i've got for you for this episode
i want to thank you guys for hanging out
for another episode of the grow from
your heart podcast if you feel like this
episode was educational informative or
entertaining and you'd like to make a
financial contribution to the show
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need will be
right there on the screen once again
big thanks big shout out to everybody
who has been supporting the show
also don't forget to visit our sponsor
at seedshearnow.com and use coupon code
gfyh10 while checking out
save yourself a few bucks if you get a
small order that will at least save you
shipping if you get a big order that
will really add up
quite quickly don't forget that the
episodes are now available on youtube
i'm now putting out video episodes if
you're listening on apple podcast or
stitcher radio
i invite you to come join us on youtube
and see my smiling
fuzzy face it is time for a shave but i
think we're going to be all right
uh youtube.com or no youtube what do you
do go to youtube search for the grow
from your heart podcast that's more like
it i found my rhythm
uh click subscribe maybe click on that
little bell so you get a notification
every time i put out a new episode you
get a notice and you do not miss any of
the new
content uh please subscribe maybe also
leave some comments on the videos let me
know what you think about the show
i think that is all i've got for you for
this episode i've ran out of notes i ran
out of stuff to say
i think that is it i want to give a
giant shout out to my buddy cass burton
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you