all right here we go welcome back
podcast world it's time for episode 541
of the girl from York our podcast
joining me today is white Mike welcome
to the show bro thanks ma'am what's up
everybody
Oh baby I hope you're doing well bro I
hope the audience is doing well I hope
the audience is smoking something
delicious this episode of the show is
brought to you by our friends at seeds
here now calm seeds here now calm offers
seeds from all the industry's leading
breeders including Duke diamond miss
Jill and of course I read genetics
everything at seeds here now is backed
by an award-winning satisfaction
guarantee and they also offer packs for
under $30 and they have amazing monthly
sales make sure to use coupon code GFY
h10 while you check out to save yourself
a few bucks
again that is coupon code g fyh tenet
seeds here now to save a few bucks I
really [ __ ] that add up but we're gonna
keep rolling through it does it felt
natural the next order of business Mike
is to ask what you're smoking on what
are you dive in today bro I've got a
little assortment of apothecary stuff
but what I've been hitting most is the
Malibu Malibu pier cush talkin is harder
than it should be today it is we're
gonna get it figured out - is that
Malibu pure cush from apothecary I love
that Malibu pier Kush that [ __ ] tastes
so good it's pretty tasty better you're
all slow and mellow - I'm over here
dabbing the guava papaya live batter
from Green Dot labs it's a blend of
camphor and papaya the package says sour
fuel and soft fruits okay I'll agree
with that it's uh it's like a sour
fruity candy I don't know about the fuel
on there I don't really get the fuel
most of the time I agree but sour fruity
candies almost like a sour patch with
the powdery sugar on the outside where
it's real crispy he get the crumbly
sugar it's kind of got that kind of a
flavor in my opinion guava papaya live
batter loving it
Mike is showing his package that's not
what I meant to say the package of his
concentrate there's this concentrate
there's my concentrate you guys - you
don't get too excited
it's so audio listeners that's a good
segue Mike if you were listening to the
show on audio I invite you to come join
us on YouTube I've been putting all of
the shows up in a video format on
to beYOU could see my smile on face you
can see Mike's pasty semi-smile on face
you can see the concentrates we just
showed join us on youtube search for
girl from your heart click subscribe
click that notification bell that way
you can get a notification every time a
new episode comes out check us out on
YouTube also we have upgraded we are on
Spotify we approved this show to not
move we have added to Spotify I had a
couple people ask if I'm gonna Joe Rogan
them and if I'm going to disappear on
other platforms no we're going to
Spotify also because a lot of people
only listen on Spotify I'd like to
expand the podcast get it out there I
want everybody to be able to listen it
was silly to not have it on Spotify
there was a technical glitch it was not
allowing my service to work with Spotify
mine comes from my website I had to make
a correction I thought of a very easy
solution it took me a night of
brainstorming it actually took about six
dabs and then I went oh that's the
[ __ ] solution I did it and everything
seems to be working so we were on
Spotify from 500 on up is on Spotify
some of the episodes won't load into
Spotify I do not know why they have
rejected them the files are the correct
files the shows are good shows I don't
know if it's copyright and music that I
have selected I don't know why but a few
of them got rejected
Spotify simply won't accept them to the
feed they won't play so I apologise if
you're missing if you want Spotify the
solution is to come over to YouTube and
check us out on the YouTube channel um
yeah that way you get to see Mike's
smiling faces looking at me like Mike or
Geoff just rambling right now I've got a
way that if you're not yeah come hang
out with us on YouTube it's it's a it's
a more interactive experience um so we
are not gonna leave any platforms you
guys just cuz we're on Spotify doesn't
mean we're going away I want you to join
us less than offers like they don't care
about our little weed show bro if they
want to make me rich I'll help you out
talking so um we're gonna get to getting
rich in just a minute what else was I
gonna say
oh speaking of Spotify Spotify may be
rejecting some of my episodes because of
copy written music and the start and end
of certain shows so once again I will
politely calmly and very cordially
request that if any of my friends out
there make music if you're a producer if
you're a recorder if you're an artist if
you're into making beats bro I need
eat a good opening track maybe a closing
track for the show you guys know I like
reggae I'm a reggae fan I used to play a
song called the doggy dub it comes in
with a big fat beat just burnin tuna
just starts it doesn't [ __ ] around
something about 30 seconds 45 seconds
yeah the good old days maybe a minute
and a half long just some music so I
could say what's up guys it's this
episode of the show welcome back all
that good fancy [ __ ] seeds here now calm
get all that in there if you want to
make me some music if you were a
professional and you require payment
send me a sample and if I like your
sample I will pay you for the full track
if you were if you're just trying to do
something for out of the kindness of
your heart that's kind of what I'm
looking for I would appreciate that you
still may get paid you will definitely
get a gift of some sort in return I got
to figure out where you are and what you
want I will take good care of you um
Mike said getting rich ah speaking of
getting rich big shout out to all of our
friends who support the show on patreon
Mike this is the portion of the show
where we should say thank you to the
people that support us on patreon you've
been doing pretty well fairly well for
your new patreon campaign you have any
people yeah you have anybody you want to
give a shout out to while we're doing
patreon shoutouts I'll let you have a
moment I know I didn't prepare you this
but off the top of my head oh gee purple
thumb thank you you're the latest
subscriber big shot to og purple thumb
and I think the Kanak rat was the first
one right so it was the first and oh gee
purple thumb was the most recent big
shout out to our friends helping cracker
Mike out over there Thank You patreon
and the folks who've been supporting the
show let's give them a shout out let's
give a shot a to Steve Smith let's give
a giant shot at the prospect let's give
a shot at - Helly i've got we've got a
big shout out for todd kay i've got a
big girl from your heart podcast shot
it's a big toe grows about a big shout
out to canna organic illinois also got a
shout out for black bird 76 okie grows
720 red beard and keith kay big thanks
big shout out to all of the folks who've
been supporting the show on patreon if
you're not already supporting the show
and you would like to learn how to do so
all you have to do is visit w-w-w dot
Petrie on comm forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and of course I did include a link in
the show notes to make it easy for the
stoner friends if you would like to
support my friend white Mike it is
really simple there just go to
patreon.com/scishow
bird / white Mike nice and easy white
Mike all one word he'll pop up show my
some patreon love give him some support
and thank you guys for the support yeah
it makes it it's kind of fun when you do
a podcast that you enjoy doing and then
people send you contributions for it
you're like well that's kind of cool
like I did something I love I helped
people out and now they're sending me
some love in return for it right it's
definitely very cool thank you so much
they help keep all the equipment running
smoothly I've talked about all the gear
that I've got going on we bought I
replaced the MacBook with patreon
contributions what time the MacBook
started sparking and making [ __ ]
smoke so I replaced it with patreon
contribution so that's what the patreon
money does i pays for the web connection
it pays for the website i covers quite a
few things there's we've got to back up
fun in case anything goes wrong or if we
try to do some upgrades so thank you
guys you really are helping out next
purchase here is gonna get me out of the
void so if you don't like the black void
behind me chip in if you do comment
that's pretty good they won't know what
you mean until a couple episodes away
but get Mike out of the void yep we
covered all the stuff I think all the
important business stuff patreon killed
it I think it is time to work into the
the the email portion of the show yeah
yeah I was gonna say they did very well
the folks did very well on my patreon
this month we're almost to another level
my number thinks my brain thinks in
number of levels and increments are you
guys if we get to the next level I would
consider another podcast episode maybe
at least one more every other week but
if we could get it to the level I'm
thinking more content more content I
would add another episode I think or I
don't give me faster yeah I would have
to focus less on other things and I
would just be able to fill out free up
some more time for more podcast content
so if we get up to that next level I may
do another episode and Mike was like bro
what are you gonna do for another
episode every week where are you gonna
come up with content I said have you
seen the stack of emails Mike we have
got emails the people are waiting so I'm
rambling today I took that dab of that
guava papaya it's been a long [ __ ]
day truth be told it is 1:00 in the
morning row yeah your dad crush
sigh that's good yeah uh it's 1:00 in
the morning and we're here recording uh
but we're gonna kill it let's get to the
email portion of the podcast Mike let's
uh let's help some people out I've got a
stack of emails here in front of me the
first email on today's episode goes just
like this it is from somebody who called
themselves IRA vibes and it says hail up
Russ to Jeff I wanna thank you for the
great information I received from
listening to your podcast I've been
growing everything from the late 70s in
my homeland in Jamaica not just the holy
herb but the food that I eat
that's awesome big respect for that big
shout out to my friends on the island of
Jamaica it says the only difference is I
grow natural and no salts but now that I
have moved to the USA I find it hard to
do the same because the soil is not the
same here yeah we've we've kind of
destroyed the soil we don't have any an
agricultural mindset like in Jamaica and
Jamaica they're thinking about the
future all the time we're thinking about
right now and maybe tomorrow so the soil
has been kind of tore up here a little
bit it's all urban also notice the soil
is different can't grow the same so they
decided to grow outdoor and use cocoa
and canna newts but was not kidding I
would I know the plant could produce
wall oh I was growing in Jamaica
I was on a mission to get information
from the top readers and growers to see
what they were using I until I stumbled
across the DG see there we go so they
found me on the dude grows show oh did
you see that's where they mentioned
Rasta Jeff so naturally I because I'm a
fan of the island of Jamaica
I had to browse your podcast and thank
Joe for the blessing yes give thanks I'm
glad you found me ah I'm glad you are
learning from the show big respect but
here's the part that we've got to cover
it says ah I have switched my nutrients
from what I was using I said Canada in a
minute ago I wasn't gonna say that but I
did say the reason can I switch from
Canada and I am using veg bloom and my
herb is on fire I'm sorry for the long
words but job bless ah so we did the
episode on my nutrient mix episode 405
hour listen for listener friend here
switched their nutrients up to the bed
bloom they did the mix that I said and
other herbs are on fire they wanted to
send some thanks for that so I
appreciate that thank you big respect I
don't know where you are now but I do
hope to get to sample some of that
rusta herb big thanks I always love
getting compliments and getting feedback
from the listeners especially people who
we improve their garden that's good to
know
my favorite part of the show yeah yeah
we're helping people I just wanted to
share that big shout out to our Rasta
friend this one comes from patreon I
found this one on patreon if you are a
patreon supporter and you've got a
question go ahead and send those to me
via patreon so I know you are a patreon
contributor and I'll try my best to get
to those messages as soon as possible
don't forget that right now we are
recorded ahead I'm a few episodes ahead
of myself so if you feel like you sent
me an email today and I said I was going
to read it on the show we're ahead of
ourselves it's probably coming up I
wasn't lying
but nation yeah come on were we I knew
that things were going weird in the
world and I was learning video recording
so we recorded ahead I've got them in
the bank in the vault is what we call it
here in podcasting so I'm ahead of
myself in case I do get sick I in case
something goes wrong I need a week off
to recover
I've got shows you guys won't miss
content planning ahead trying to be
smart for you guys this one comes from
patreon Mike I'm [ __ ] stone and
rambley today this could be like a seven
hour podcast tonight alright so this one
comes from patriotic comes from our
friend Xavier it says hey Rasta Jeff
thanks for being an extremely positive
force during these times we all face
much appreciated hey thank you for
noticing that I try to stay upbeat um
man thank you it goes on to say I have a
few questions for you I recently
listened to episode 4 Oh for grow less
in part 4 I heard you talk about shine a
few times uh and I have questions about
the shine I'm wondering what weeks of
bloom you recommend using shine that is
a really good question shine is a
product from veg bloom it's a product
from they're called hydroponic research
is the name of the company I like the
product shine if you're growing and
hydroponics if you're growing in Coco
soilless mix I think shine is a great
product for adding bulk flavor density
trichomes it is a really good bloom
booster um it is kind of based on your
plants and your budget and the
availability of the product some people
have a harder time getting it based on
their location if it is in the budget
start it early if it is not in the
budget started
a bit later so if you can afford to use
it a week one or week two a flower do it
if it is more cost-effective for you to
wait two weeks start it at week three
but I'm sure you want it in there by
week three by day one of week three you
want to start putting it in there if not
you definitely need it by week four and
I would use it all the way through the
bloom phase especially the bulking weeks
like five six seven eight then I stopped
using it around flush in most cases
sometimes I'll use it for if I'm
flushing for fourteen days I'll use the
plus of the shot of the shine for about
a week of that because it's not gonna
build up in the plant it's gonna it's
gonna you're not gonna taste it it's not
gonna get stuck in there we're flushing
out mostly other things we still got
seven days to flush that out I think
it'll really bulk up so I use it early
week two if you can if you can use it a
week one use it a week one if you can't
I'm not saying you can't afford it but
it's an expensive product you've already
bought a lot of things maybe you don't
have it week one's a good idea week two
is great week three really get it in
there by week three week four you better
have it by now if you haven't gotten it
by week four you can still add it at
five and six but it would have been much
better if you did it earlier so that's
when I would start adding it this person
says oh you can use it can you use it to
help stop the initial stretch yes if you
do use it early use it before flower if
use it a few days before you go into
flower it will help slow down the
stretch that in a combination with
popping and twisting the branches that
will definitely help slow down the
stretch and give you big fatter plants
um it says I also heard you mention some
kind of enzyme what a kind of enzyme
would be good to add at the end with my
shine and then it says I'm using
advanced nutrients so what I need to use
since e-zyme as my enzyme that is a
really good question um just because you
were using the advanced nutrients
product line does not mean you need to
stick with their enzymes you can use
whatever enzyme product is going to work
with your nutrient regimen anything
since he's I'm slf 100 hydros I'm any of
that stuff is going to work for you the
thing you have to pay attention to
mostly when you're mixing nutrient
companies is if you're using something
like a base or a cal-mag or something
like that you don't want to use a base
nutrient that's got a bunch of nitrogen
but they also put some phosphorus and
potassium in there and then you use a
bloom booster from a nut
company it's got the potassium and
phosphorus but they also put nitrogen in
there just because in their recipe would
have worked but now you've got two
different companies with two different
recipes they had two different game
plans the quarterback threw the ball
they thought that in their game plan
that the [ __ ] runner who's the who
catches it the [ __ ] catcher what's
his name the wide receiver they thought
bad dude was gonna go out and left but
he's using a different company he went
out and right so nobody caught the ball
so now you got [ __ ] a dropped ball
and you don't wanna drop balls when
we're growing so I just think about if
you're using two different companies
that's when you have to pay attention to
blending products and product lines but
if you're just excuse the throat you
guys I'm talking about those dad's
really ER that's what did it
ah if you're using just enzymes I think
any enzyme will work I really like slf
100 it's a great product hi gross I'm is
a great product
since he's I'm is an okay product if
you're using the advanced and you want
to stick with a brand specific line go
for it but it is not necessary they said
what enzyme would be good to add any of
those would work for you it's a very
good idea to add those enzymes at the
end it helps clean stuff up it helps
break down anything that may be left in
there ah I'll repeat the three again slf
100 it's pricey but it's a good product
hi crews I'm it's pricey but it's a good
product but you're using advanced
nutrients that since e-zyme is probably
the most expensive enzyme out there so
those are three that are readily
available
kanna's i'm is available there are a lot
of great enzymatic products out there I
find the one that fits your budget
something to think about
they may look really expensive when you
go to buy the bottle but it may say use
one milliliter per gallon so if you're
using one mil per gallon as opposed to
something that takes 10 mils per gallon
you have to do the cost effectiveness of
the milliliter cost per mil in that
container at that time don't get sticker
shock because one is super expensive if
you only use one mil but half of
whatever it's gonna last you a long long
time if you have to use 10 mils of it
it's gonna go much more quickly so you
may be paying more right up front but
it's gonna last you a lot longer mm-hmm
all right Xavier I think I helped you
out with that one I hope I gave you a
good answer um well let's talk about how
much shine to use ah that's probably a
good thing to recommend I start off
lightly if you're going to go if you're
gonna go early just do one gram if
you're gonna go before a flower or a
week one or two a flower start off with
one gram
her per gallon thank you Mike one gram
per gallon and then yeah per per
whatever per can of Mountain Dew a 1
gram again one round per nostril yeah no
don't say that
uh-huh people are wonder what kind of
show we've got don't snort the shine who
knows you may get all kinds of trichomes
but one gram of shine per gallon then at
week two increase it to two and stick
with that until week four then slowly
increase it as needed
if you want to you can stick with two
grams you can get all the way up to more
than two I've done a lot I don't want to
give you numbers cuz you guys gonna [ __ ]
your plants up pay attention to the tips
of the leaves when the tips of the
leaves get a little little brown a
little bit yellow that's as much as they
need don't go any more than that you're
pushing them as hard as they need to go
they're starting to get their nails done
they're about to burn so start off with
one slowly work your way up to two maybe
work your way up to three pay attention
what the plants do if you're really
happy with what they're doing maybe try
a little bit more don't go much past
three and a half you guys don't do that
they'll get [ __ ] sad they'll get mad
okay angry they'll cook up on you but
increase it slowly and pay attention to
what they do if you're in cocoa you've
really got a lot of opportunity to
increase slowly during soilless mix you
gotta just water as you can but pay
attention so start off with one gram
work your way up don't go more than
three and a half the guys have bed bloom
are gonna email me and say three and a
half [ __ ] grams dude maybe I was
fired oh he was so good but everything
else has to be in line also you can't be
overloading anything else are under
loading everything else has to be in
line you can't just think I'm gonna
throw three and a half grams of shine in
here it's gonna be the magic bullet if
everything else has to be in line for
that shine to work it's like building a
body builder if if my I've got chicken
legs bro I'm six foot five I weigh like
a hundred and ninety pounds I got
[ __ ] chicken legs I'm not I'm not
ashamed of that if they don't grow I
could do I could go do leg day every day
Bron I'm just gonna get more chicken
legs and it'd be like if you took my
chicken legs and put Brock Lesnar's
shoulders on there and he told him go
ahead and Bend go ahead and [ __ ] lift
all that weight not a benchpress I know
I need my legs so some kind of standing
lift lifts all that weight my legs are
gonna crumble so if you just have a
shitty plant and you think you're just
gonna go feeding it a bunch of shine
it's not prepared for that it's not
gonna be able to take it it's got
chicken legs bro you got to work the
whole plant everything has to be
in harmony her doll to work beautifully
like that you look like you had
something to say Mike nope just try to
plan your new feeds out from the start
so that you're not rushing to add [ __ ]
in the middle that's where people get
into trouble yeah I forget that people
don't plan ahead very well if you were
on week 6 you should know what you're
feeding all the way up to the day you
flush and you should know the day you
flush when I put a crop into flower I've
got a general idea of what day it's
coming down like it may be my first run
with a plant but I know it's either
gonna take 9 or 10 weeks I've chosen
that I'm gonna give it 9 or 10 weeks and
then I'm gonna pay attention to it I'm
gonna cut it down so I know that the
week 8 I need to flush I already know
what I'm gonna feed it week 1 2 3 I
already know I've got the recipe figured
out the the biggest thing with really
good cannabis is is a plan and sticking
to a plan when people start changing
[ __ ] in the middle or trying new [ __ ] in
the middle or I wanted to start that
nutrient this week but I didn't have it
so I'm gonna start it next week and next
week becomes to timeline and then you're
telling people I wanted to started shine
I start the shine on week 2 I meant to
get it out by week two but I missed week
two and then week three kind of got away
from me so I started it kind of and a
week for ya and then you say that shine
wasn't the product you expect it because
you didn't get it in there you missed
two and a half weeks worth of shine
opportunity and it's not just newts
either like I've talked to people that
are they got to their harvest moment and
they went to grab the the plant cutters
bolt cutters to chop their plant down
and thought where am I gonna hang this
girl yeah what oh and now they're
scrambling and hanging clothesline and
it gets weird just cuz they didn't plan
yeah and all of a sudden they're they're
a quality cannabis is a c- because they
didn't plan out one step because amazon
took an extra week because they didn't
deliver something that they should have
ordered during week two like you guys
know you're growing cannabis you know
you're gonna have a harvest in a few
weeks start think
had yeah good idea Mike so I have all of
your nutrients if you're in veg and
you're going to flower next week
order your flowering nutrients get them
here go to the store and buy them if
you're waiting on Amazon if you're
waiting on something go get them things
are super weird in the world right now
yep it's getting a lot harder to do that
right now so the planning becomes even
more and more vital yeah and things are
gonna start running out you guys so I've
done an episode before on being prepared
to be prepared you leave the gross
stores alone I'm trying to avoid all the
pandemic and kovat and weird talk but
leave the gross stores alone all right
Mike let's move forward I'm high and
rambley and so are you so we could
really get far off the rails tonight oh
we've got another yeah those are our
friends you guys this up this uh what
does it call this is an email right yeah
this email comes from somebody who calls
themselves Edward and it goes hey Rasta
Jeff what's up Edward thank you for the
support it goes I just heard episode 535
and I cannot wait anymore you have to be
one of the best shows in podcast land
thank you
I just noticed that every email I read
starts off with the people thanking me
and saying I'm the best I don't pick the
emails that say that they all say that
it's not a selection thing that's just
how they start thank you guys I love
that but it looks like I'm picking a
based on that I'm not trust me or please
trust me that goes on to say if anything
I can't talk can't stop talking about
your current flower
uh you were making the listeners in
Prohibition land said oh they said don't
stop talking no they said do stop
talking about if anything stop talking
about your current flower they're upset
and sad that we're over here smoking the
guava papaya and telling them about it I
like to check in on places like Reddit
and check out what people are smoking
around the country and every now that I
see some my god yeah Scotty real has a
little bit of brick weed on his shelf
behind him in the show and it's funny
just to see the brick weed sometimes
like hey bro wanna smoke a joint he's
playing with it you're like oh no dude
no but our friend Edward says seriously
I love the show and I did my best with
my monthly contributions hey thank you I
appreciate that I will have to associate
the name in the email with the patreon
so I can see what you're contributing
and send you a special thank you it goes
on to say my question
I have some new seedlings they have
reached about five inches only the top
four leaves have appeared and they are
falling over uh so we've got that's
about four inches I'm picturing GI Joe
GI Joe is like three and a half three
and three quarters so they're about five
inches and only the top four leaves have
appeared and then they fall over then it
says why I put some toothpicks next to
them but they are not strong enough to
support the weight what should I do
so this is what we call getting its
leggy yeah they're stretchy and leggy
youyou don't want to put some popsicle
sticks you don't wanna put pins in there
to keep them up um are you can that may
be what you have to do at this point but
that's not the idea um what should I do
those plants want a little bit light
they want a little I was gonna say one a
little bit more of everything except
water they want more life they want more
air ah yeah B needs a little bit of wind
on them but I think they're reaching for
the light
you've probably got them under a low
quality light a low power light
certainly not be correct spectrum light
so they're going hey the main thing I
want out of life right now is light I'm
looking for it I think it might be up
there I'm gonna try to keep growing
until I get to it and it's not gonna get
to it because the light is not the right
light so you need more to light then you
need a little bit of wind a little bit
of wind will prevent them from getting
so stretchy
yeah just a tie don't go [ __ ]
breaking them and destroying them but a
little wind makes them kind of struggle
and they kind of think about Mike wood
what's the first thing you do if I were
just to shove you punch me back right
you spread your feet to get your balance
when you get pushed you spread your feet
so if I when you blow on the plant it's
gonna get rattled it's gonna spread its
roots to try to hold itself up and get
stronger so then in my pleasure about
the stock a little bit yeah then I'm
going to assume it's been over watered
also you're probably over watering if
it's not getting enough light it's not
growing it's not doing anything it's not
it's probably a little bit over watered
and that is probably because it is not
in the appropriate soil you need some
aerated soil for a seedling so think
about lights air water and soil and make
sure that all of those are correct but
it sounds like light is probably the
main culprit here put some more light on
it that should keep it a little bit
tighter I've noticed if you listen to
the previous episode
I switch to the LEDs my growth went
crazy so that is a huge testament to
different light I went from T fives to
LEDs and saw double the growth really
quickly so the light is probably the
culprit then it goes on to say have you
helped anyone with an aquaponic system
there are many YouTube videos and
write-ups out there but no one gives a
real concise answer let me know your
thoughts I have built one with love and
I would love to share my progress with
you uh so yeah I do not grow
aquaponically but I do know the guy
named aquaponics Steve and he's got a
podcast called growing with fishes and
they specialize in growing with fishes
so I think potent ponics may be I think
potent ponics Steve is the way to find
him on social media and the podcast is
called growing with fishes so that's the
what you should look for also check out
the dude grows show it may not be about
aquaponics but if you like my show and
you're growing aquaponics uh Steve dread
from the growing with fishes show is
also a good friend with the embracing
organics crew and the dude grows crew so
make sure you check out the dude grows
crew I think you'll enjoy that show or
the dude grow show that's on YouTube
it's on wherever you're listening to
podcasts the dude grow show is on there
if you're hearing my show you can find
that show there and embracing organics
also that is on YouTube they talk about
organically growing we talk about
cultivation and all kind of aspects so
if you want to learn more about growing
growing with fishes it may be called
potent phonics ah growing with fishes
we'll get you to the show the do grow
show and embracing organics are both
great avenues to expand your aquaponic
and cultivation uh uh organic
cultivation knowledge boy Mike we should
dab something different on the next
episode does that [ __ ] papaya guava
shake I mean stuttery and weird today
exactly yeah going with the last email a
lot of people when they're first
starting to get into growing they they
say I want to start growing herb and I
want to grow and then there's a very
difficult way to grow that comes after
that either with fish or column or with
gonna steal a train car and bury 80 feet
of water sprayers Oh air apana CLE upon
yeah all right grow underground and
train cars and I mean honestly if it's
your first couple of grows just focus on
getting good growing in your space yeah
understand it managing the environmental
controls of your space and learning how
to manipulate it successfully for what
you're trying to do yeah Linda the gear
learned basically the plants learn that
what light cycles do like what happens
when I trim a plant here one of the
basics of plant growth the cycles the
nutritive cycles and then learn how to
make all that happen with fish but if
that's really the way you want to jump
in I'm no one to just sway you from
living the [ __ ] dream but it is
really a challenging way to jump in I've
seen some really beautiful in Theory
setups that they use fish but they all
scare the [ __ ] out of me because fish
plus an environment that's good for fish
plus water pumps and hoses in my brain
equals a night
lots of clogged hoses I just keep
picturing Brian cleaning out the little
sprayer nozzles oh yeah the facility you
know I'm talking about and just man
instead of that stuff it's fish [ __ ]
that's just what I picture yeah yeah
being cultivators to work in a [ __ ]
SeaWorld no yeah I'm sorry no [ __ ]
SeaWorld but anyway the more that it's
right now you tell me dude
environmentally sustainable growing is
killer and so if you can keep us
thriving grow going based on a fishpond
like by all means do it it's gotta be
fun yeah cuz you get to take care of
fishies and you probably get to name the
tilapia that are swimming around or
whatever but that's I don't know that's
a whole new ballgame fish food is way
[ __ ] cheaper than bottled news well
maybe what do you feel because you got
to think about that fish food is going
to turn into fish feeding a mistake it's
gonna turn into the nutrients for my
plants so I may totally change up my
fish food diet at that point they may
get caviar or a steaks and whatever they
want at that point
ah this episode are this [ __ ] I keep
calling his email and
episode geez how high are we gonna get
those brought to you by too much ash yes
this episode of two guys coughing is
brought to you by ya seeds here now calm
this up the mail says to try to do it
again again I'm a new grower and I want
to use aquaponics to support my grow be
good to talk soon from your friend
Edward a shout out to Edward I hope we
did not discourage you from aquaponic
growing it's going to be a lot of extra
work but if that's your passion follow
your dream dude do that just an extra
learning stem man by all means dive in I
see ya just get the book first yeah and
definitely talk to aquaponics Steve
Steve rassner Steve dread he's got a lot
of names eyes awesome dude's got
dreadlocks down to his ass a big ol
fuzzy beard he's been on the dude grow
show he hangs out at all the dude grows
parties he's a friend of mine trust him
respect him I think he will steer you in
the right direction
and I think you'd enjoy his podcast also
shout out Steve I hope you're listening
brother hope you're well also um if
anybody else out there has a question
we'd love to hear from you the email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com don't be shy send me an
email
Mike I've got one more email here in
front of me we're gonna do four in the
sample show just cuz one was super quick
ah
this one says hey Rasta Jeff I hope
things are going well for you my name is
I don't know if they want their name
said in their food so we're gonna skip
it and we met briefly at the endo Expo
this year and I grabbed some double
dragon seeds from you thank you for the
support I think I remember meeting you
and I'm glad that you've got some double
dragon seeds I look forward to seeing
you at the next endo Expo whenever that
may be and these weird times in which we
live now ah I need a wee diesel Expo
zoom Expo stop it Mike it goes on to say
I recently saw an Instagram post of
yours where you posted your reverse
spray yes I posted a big leader of
silver thiosulfate that I had freshly
mixed up it says I've been working with
SDS spray for some months now and I've
always been under the impression that it
should come out clear after it is mixed
in your Instagram post it appears
slightly colored do you use or be use a
surfactant or do you think this is what
happens when we use expired product
because that has happened to me before
or is the color of your spray normal as
it comes out thanks for taking your time
to read this and
okay fat dab for me dude I've got a fat
dab on the dabber so that as soon as
this show ends I'll hit this dab for you
this one is gonna be dedicated to you I
do know the picture for you yeah yeah
we're gonna do it properly I do know the
Instagram poster speaking of I made that
jar of silver thiosulfate I shook it up
i diluted it I applied it to some plants
I remember that day I remember that
batch I remember that photo
uh the Silas silver thiosulfate solution
in that jar is quite clear what's not
clear is the wall behind me I took that
photo in front of this wall right here
it is sort of an off-white color that
came through in the photo so it looks
like the photo the solution of dabbed at
eggshell paint behind it yeah yeah yeah
it's off white bro it's from supreme
it's off white I'm just working on but
it's not pure white it's kind of yet is
eggshell II back there it's been too
much dab smoke so it made the solution
look like it did have some color to it
but no it is completely clear it should
be clear sometimes you may see little
flakes in it that means that your stuff
didn't dissolve you should have
dissolved it shook it up more tea
probably shake it more it'll break up in
there ah but it should be clear if it
turns dark colors when you're mixing it
that means that your solution has
probably been exposed to too much light
or that there's moisture or something
went wrong in either the silver or the
sodium powders is what that probably
means one of the companies has stopped
sending me fine fine powder and they
sent me bigger chunks those chunks don't
dissolve very well and sometimes I do
see colored particles floating around so
what I've begun to do is I put those
chunks in a baggie and I wrap that
baggie in newspaper and I crush it with
a hammer to make those chunks smaller
and I don't get that problem anymore and
the solution works better so that's a
little tip for you if you're buying from
the same company as myself and they've
started sending you the pellets instead
of the powder crush the pellets it's the
same [ __ ] you just have to crush down
their big crystals um they think they're
doing any favors by sending a big the
big buds and we just want the shake so
no I do not use a surfactant I soak the
[ __ ] out of the plant to the point of
runoff I don't only spray the leaves I
make it a point to spray the the branch
of the plant the main meristem the main
branch of the plant also gets sprayed
with silver um I think that is
everything that we need to cover on that
one the spray was clear I don't
use a surfactant on if you've got colors
probably contaminants yeah
say that again Mike nice easy question
nice easy question yeah I'm glad you
asked because that means you're paying
attention this stuff was clear bro it
was just the wall behind me would you
read the question I smiled because I was
hoping personally that it was like an
Instagram filter now just just the wall
behind me needs a little bit of repaint
and even better answer yeah there's a
lighting or the wall something gave it
some color but it is clear it is
completely clear you'll be happy to know
that all of that thiosulfate has been
applied to a plant and now that female
looks totally like a male and it is
about to produce pollen here in the next
five to seven days and should have a
nice uh big tray of pollen to play with
that'll be a good time all right Mike I
think we've been going for a little over
30 minutes maybe unless we make an edit
or two here so I think we got enough
content to call it a quality podcast
it's kind of weird now that I'm not
[ __ ] baked out of my brain the show
is over and I feel like I could do a
podcast now just downshift into reality
yeah I got landed in the middle of that
show somewhere let's fix that yeah we're
gonna we're definitely gonna fix that as
soon as I do the catchphrase we will
take some dabs together just one man
then I got a go if you know a movie
that's from hi-5 and [ __ ] shout out
you're cooler than [ __ ] ah a weasel
stole the B [ __ ] note all Mike do
have anything to add at the end of this
show before we start doing all the
business parts again I just want to say
that Jeff knows how to curb and
everything everything man
I did not exhale if you feel like this
episode was educational informative
and/or entertaining you would like to
make a financial contribution to either
the show or to white Mike all you have
to do is visit patreon.com forward slash
grow from your heart or forward slash
white Mike helped out my friend Mike
white Mike get his patreon loaded up get
him going so I'll come do some more
shows with us we do appreciate all of
that support don't forget check out our
sponsors at seeds here now calm and use
coupon code gen while checking out
there's a new strain available called
free
the Duke if there is any free the Duke
available please get a pack of free the
Duke help free my friend Duke diamond
we're not gonna go too deep into what
happened to Duke but free Duke please
help my friend out gotta get back home
with this family um also please support
the show on youtube if you're listening
on an audio format
I invite you I implore you to come check
us out on the youtube channel you know
how to find YouTube once you're there
all you have to do is search for a girl
from your heart podcast we will pop
right up click subscribe click on the
little Bell then leave some comments on
the videos let us know what you think
about the show we do appreciate that
sort of stuff I want to thank Mike again
for hanging out hey Mike thanks for
staying up late and for hanging out with
me was a good time dude yeah man thanks
for having me
I think the audience loves having you
here I get a lot of great messages a lot
of good feedback when you're on the show
looks like Mike is gonna dab some jam
band I'm gonna hit more of this guava
papaya
it's obviously doing something to my
brain so why not just keep this
weirdness [ __ ] going ladies and
gentlemen boys and girls pimps and hos
friends and foes smokers and growers dad
kids and flower children I want to thank
everybody for listening to the show
thanks for tolerating my [ __ ] rambles
in this episode I know I was a mess Mike
knows I was a mess we had fun that's
what matters I hope I helped you out in
some sort of a way Mike tapped his head
I don't know what that even means I know
you were a mess together we were a fun
mess we were a hot mess some episodes
are gonna be that way some of them are
gonna be [ __ ] gems this means they do
like it when we ramble the best part
about part about podcasting is nobody
got hurt nothing bad happened as much as
many times as I fell in my face I got
back up and kept running damn Skippy
girl damn no skip and I might fall down
if I skip yeah I'm so high I don't know
about that all right you guys we're
gonna end the rambles here we're gonna
take some dabs um I want to give a giant
shout out to my friend Michael Harper
and until next time take a phat dab and
give your mom a hug for me