greetings from podcast ville this
episode of the grill from an art podcast
is brought to you by our friends at
seeds here now.com check it out you're
stuck at home
you're on quarantine they [ __ ] looted
the dispensary you know what you got to
do you got to grow your own [ __ ] herb
you got to do it from seed where do you
get your seeds at seeds here now dot-com
that's right seeds here now calm carry
seeds from all the industry's leading
breeders including miss Jill Duke
diamond and of course I read genetics
everything at seeds here now calm is
backed by their 100% satisfaction
guarantee and for my friends on a tight
budget seeds here now.com offers several
packs for under $30 as well as amazing
monthly sales make sure to use coupon
code Jeff wih general checking out to
save yourself 10% again that is coupon
code g FY age 10 at seeds here now
dot-com if you're joining us on video
I'm sure that you could see white Mike
is here
welcome to the show bro without man
thanks for having me okay thank you for
being here thank you uh for putting up
with my ridiculously fun intro that was
a good time ran myself out of breath
trying to be so enthusiastic yeah just
to buy myself some breath catch in time
what are you smoking on over there bro
so I smoked and flowers Aria awesome
shout out to the local home grower for
doing the good work well I think it's
fancy I wasn't gonna diss the guy it's
no it's just
alright he's gonna listen to this so
shout out to the local homegrown ok that
dude is he cool I love seeing people get
happy over gifted herb I am smoking
since you replied enough to ask I'm
smoking purple starburst live batter
from Green Dot labs this is a blend of
purple punch skittles and starburst OG
on the package the flavors described as
spun sugar I think that is cotton candy
right grapes and shampoo I know it
sounds weird I
enjoy that shampoo flavor it's good it
sounds kind of weird I really like it
the shampoo is what stands out the most
for me uh cotton candy and shampoo
almost like strawberry shampoo I think
it's that old cheap strawberry swab
shampoo I dig it on the back it says it
contains fifty four point eight four
percent THC and non detectable amounts
of CBD I'm diggin the purple starburst
starburst spelled with a Z so nobody
gets sued Z ta r bu rst purple starburst
from Green Dot labs so obviously got me
stoned and it's doing that [ __ ] to my
throat that passes through the show yeah
it's got me going Michael when you're on
the show something just makes us [ __ ]
ramble together I bet if we were in
school they would have separated us we
would not have been a lot of classes
together like those two guys we got to
keep those two guys coughing separate
them we're bad influences on each other
ah this is the point of the show where
we should do some shoutouts to a few of
the folks who continue to support the
show on patreon let's start off with the
big giant grow from your heart podcast
thank you shot at to the hardest working
man in cannabis let's end up giant thank
you shot up to James Brown I've always
got a big think you shot up for
Godfather Kush let's send a big a high
five and a fist bump to Bret G I was
want to send a big THANK YOU shot up to
Jacob W about a big THANK YOU to Curt Z
about a giant shout out to Captain mojo
we've always got a big THANK YOU shout
out for everybody busting their ass out
there at Hogan's farms big thank you to
my friend Melvin eight one eight big
fist bump and a thank you shout out to
day Ron got a big thank you shot and a
high-five to Josiah I've got a big fat
thank you shout out and a big fat dab
for giant mic and the dab in Queen big
thanks big shout out big fist bump to
everybody who continues to support the
show if you're not already supporting
the show on patreon and you would like
to do so all you have to do is visit
w-w-w dot patreon.com forward slash grow
from your heart all of the information
you need will be right there on the
screen and also let me encourage you to
support my friend white Mike on patreon
it's really easy go to
patreon.com/scishow him some love he's a
great contributor to the podcast he's a
great contributor to the cannabis
industry and community so help out my
bro thank you Mike I do appreciate you
and thank you for everybody that's
contributed so far yes thank you to
everybody who helps out Mike and myself
we do appreciate it and I am working on
freeing up more time so I can make even
better and more content and the patreon
contributions money does buy time
sometimes so it's really helping that's
yeah that is helping out so thank you
guys and it keeps all this fancy
equipment going you guys bought Mike's
recording equipment through patreon so
thank you guys for that appreciate it
something I should mention about patreon
questions and comments and shoutouts I
do promise to give people shoutouts if
they continue to contribute to the
patreon campaign I also promise to read
their emails and answer their questions
a lot of people have sent me a lot of
great questions and emails they do not
realize that we're recorded several
weeks ahead at this time I think we are
three weeks ahead of ourselves in
podcasting so I need to take a break and
let us catch up so that the emails are
fresher but your messages are coming I
did not forget you you just got to be
patient I only read like three or four
per show and I probably get 25 per week
so the math means that I'm always going
to fall behind I'm not complaining that
means I've always got content when the
apocalypse comes still got emails to
read it's not a it's not a Beth and we
just please yes quality takes time and
I'm going to get to your message I'm
going to get to your patreon shoutouts
we're just ahead
so if you sent me a message in June I
just now we haven't even gotten you were
already
I'm already recorded almost halfway
through June so it's gonna be I don't
think you understand what I'm trying to
say my brain got ahead of my mouth but I
think my mouths got ahead of my brain
either way we're recorded ahead so don't
feel offended if I skip your question
haven't gotten to your question yet
haven't given you a patreon shoutout
it's coming
I don't feel slighted don't feel
offended don't cancel your patreon
subscription that shit's coming up be
patient and that means that you got a
whole like a whole month of patreon
shoutouts coming up if you've paid for a
patreon shout out I think that covers
that part of the business another thing
I wanted to mention is today I had the
honour of recording on the grow cast
with Jordan from the grow cast that was
a really good time I had a [ __ ]
really fun chat a really fun chat pre
recording and recording with him I think
that dude is a great recorder a great
podcast or not a good time so in the
future make sure you guys look forward
to myself on the grow cast with Jordan
River if you're not already listening to
the grow cat
to make sure you download that I think
it is on Spotify I know it's on Apple
podcast and I think it's on most of the
other podcast servers he did agree to
come be on my show on a video format so
in the future look forward to myself
interviewing Jordan River Mike if you'd
like to tag team and join in you're
always invited so that'll be a cool show
now that we've got the zoom recording
mastered man the sky's the limit right
yeah I think we're really doing a lot
better since we're talking about podcast
servers thank you Mike also for the
compliment I didn't mean to glance right
over that we are doing a lot better
zoom makes a lot better show we're a lot
you're a lot more comfortable it makes
it a lot easier for me as well so good
job to you bro ah let me get myself back
on track I didn't mean to gloss over
your comment trying to stay focused here
and not Scotty reel myself shut of the
Scotty I love you bro um I mentioned
patreon a moment ago are not patreon
what's this thing called what is it
stitcher on stitcher a lot of people
have notified me that episode 371 is
errored on stitcher and it's only a
minute long bro I have [ __ ] deleted
replaced edited updated [ __ ] kicked
and cussed at that [ __ ] file and that
upload serviced it I don't know why it
won't work it is the same RSS feed that
works on iTunes or Apple podcast it's
the same RSS feed that works on Google
podcast or Google Play
it's everything except Spotify runs off
of that RSS feed everything else is
accurate and correct except stitcher I
don't know why stitcher won't [ __ ] do
it dude I don't I can't figure it out
stitcher than this one episodes is ever
gonna be friends and they you can email
stitcher and it takes them like three to
17 weeks for them to reply they don't
really care because I don't pay them
anything they're hosting my [ __ ] for
free they don't make any benefit from
contacting me or not so they're not
gonna fix it so that episode if you're
listening today on stitcher radio you
know like hey bro I would have loved to
have heard 371 it's a great episode you
did want to hear it it's available on
Spotify and also I encourage you to
check it out on YouTube because it is
Jesse and myself sitting at the table
many people have not seen Jesse they
don't know what he looks like seen come
see what Jesse looks like missed the
Jesse episodes yeah those are some gems
he actually messaged me today on
Facebook and he said hey do you want to
do another outdoor up
so I was like [ __ ] come on over so I got
to get that recorded and don't say an
episode number at the start of it so I
could sneak it in whenever and try to
fit it in the flow yeah that way I don't
have to make everybody wait too many
weeks for that but if you missed that
one on stitcher radio I want to call it
patreon every time the two logos blend
together in my head um if you missed
that one I apologize thank you to
everybody who emailed me messaged me I
got a lot of messages my replies were
short yeah dude I know I'm trying to fix
it I [ __ ] fixed it I was trying to be
I try to reply to everybody but after a
while I was like dude I know and I am
I'm trying to fix it I just can't
[ __ ] they won't fix so that's we're
just gonna have to live with that
nobody's gonna die nobody got hurt we
can all live the podcast another day but
it's not gonna be fixed so check it out
somewhere else I think you'll like the
video let me make sure I haven't skipped
any other notes I was on the grow cast
ah dude people like the music that we've
been playing I've been playing at the
end of the show I don't know if you
watch the shows cuz you're on them and
sometimes it feels weird to watch it
we're on at the end I'm running like a
clip of it's a slideshow of strains of
just weed pictures and also sometimes I
take a DAB and the other day I think I
danced around to a Phish song or a
Stevie Wonder song for a couple of
seconds and somebody asked me to show my
dreadlocks - I forgot about that I'll
show my dreads in another episode
they're bundled up super tightly today
but I'll show them in another episode at
the end but people are impressed with
the music that I'm playing at the end of
the show unfortunately we've got to quit
doing that Spotify doesn't like the
music YouTube doesn't like the music
we're getting the this no no no finger
at us the bigger the company the less
cool and the bigger the podcast we've
increased the listens
audio and video listeners have totally
increased by a large amount so we're
getting more notices which is getting us
higher up in the rankings which more
algorithms are seeing us and now they're
messing with our stuff so um I'm no
longer going to be able to put cool
music at the end of the show unless
somebody makes me a kickin theme song if
you send me music that is original I've
said this before I'll play your track at
the starter at the end of the show and
you'll get compensated based on how cool
your [ __ ] track is and how many times
I decide to play it if you're a
professional and you need money for sure
send me a sample if you're kind
send me some tracks so [ __ ] give you
a shout-out I'll say your name and I'll
send you gifts in return
but what I was getting to is somebody
asked me for a list of the tracks
multiple people have asked me what was
that track what was that track I'm going
to read a couple of short ones because
the list is really long I'll read a few
of the most recent tracks I've played
then I'm going to post to social media
the full list of tracks because I've got
it written down since uh 446 I started
writing down which songs I was playing
so I've got the full list of every track
it's gonna take me a while to tweet that
it may be like [ __ ] 20 tweets how
many songs can I fit and suck if you've
really got the list handwritten take
photos of the list and post that [ __ ] to
Instagram just save yourself years with
the tweeting see the thing about that is
this handwriting is kind of it looks
more like book code and for some people
it's not gonna do you any good people
like The DaVinci Code it's still not
gonna it's just gonna be an artifact
that doesn't mean [ __ ] they're like so
what are those four letters in a row
mean those are just initials for a Phish
song that nobody else understand so
they're gonna need they're gonna need so
I don't even know are HM is red hot mama
from widespread panic yeah that was one
that I put on there and then through
five oh five through 507 it says [ __ ] I
made because those three [ __ ] shows
were tracks that I made so let me just
read will start at five on the back
we start at five twenty seven so 527 was
called Fat Freddy's drop
I didn't write down details guys so I
may not know either the artist or the
track I just wrote down enough to give
myself a reminder so that I don't play
that song again for like another ten
tracks or whatever so Fat Freddy's drop
that was recommended by a friend 528 was
a Pearl Jam song don't remember which
one 529 was government mule that is
Warren Haynes mat apps cannot remember
the bass players name I feel like a dick
for that Matt's one of my favorite
drummers super awesome track five thirty
was the white Mike interview I didn't
put music at the end of that because I
think we high-fived each other at the
end or something it sounded cool so I
cut that out
5:31 got a lot of notice 5:31 is a song
called bloodshot eyes sorry for my
bloodshot eyes I did not write down the
artist I want to say through the roots
but I could be completely wrong with
that don't hold me accountable for that
but if you google reggae song bloodshot
eyes
it will come up there a current reggae
band they're popular right now I found
it on Sirius XM us cruising home one
night and that song came on on the
reggae channel on Sirius on the joint
and I was like that's a [ __ ] good
tune ah 532 is the Beastie Boys because
I [ __ ] love the Beastie Boys um 533
was Damian Marley 534 was fell on black
days you better know fell on black days
bro um 535 was here comes trouble and I
think that is chronics and protege is
who think sings that together 536 was
saying Timmy Santos by Phish I think
that was the live track from dicks at a
show that I went to recently
5:37 was brass monkey by the Beastie
Boys because jesse was here and he made
a comment about uh the Beastie Boys
taught him that every picture is cooler
if he pointed the camera and so when he
said Beastie Boys at the end of the
video I left that part in he thought I
would edit that out cuz the show is
technically over but I left that short
clip in and then I played the Beastie
Boys just to make it fun 5:38 was boogie
on reggae woman by Stevie Munn Stevie
Wonder 5:39 is a track that I made and I
just call it some reggae it doesn't
really have a real name but those are
the tracks most recently that I put on
the show hopefully I got the one you're
asking about
I will it's gonna take a while for me to
tweet all of that [ __ ] but I'll tweet
out the list or something show you guys
the rest of the tracks like I've been
talking for a long time we haven't even
gotten to any cannabis content let's
talk about weed I want to talk about
growing weed we should I like to give
garden updates what's growing on I think
we might have borrowed that from another
podcast but that's okay I'm marking off
the things that we've already done cuz I
went out of order check on that list
homie yeah um I like to give garden
updates dude um I have a garden people
know I'm a [ __ ] ganja grower I really
like to give updates when I've got
something cool going on recently we lost
a very important cannabis soldier uh
some cool is no longer with us some cool
past a while back we cried over that I
did an episode about it but I still love
sub still miss sub so I'm still on my
mind sometimes um I wouldn't be the
breeder grower [ __ ] talker podcaster or
social media thing I wouldn't be that
guy without a lot of sub cools influence
sub cool Tommy a lot of what to do
I jokingly say that some cool also
taught me a [ __ ] whole lot of what
not to do mmm that guy was [ __ ]
cantankerous and a loose cannon but I
[ __ ] love the [ __ ] out of him dude
wouldn't have been here without him so I
got some Jack the Ripper seeds from a
good friend who was very close to some
cool who actually thanked me for my
podcast about subby mmm he sent me some
Jack seeds Jack the Ripper I German
aided them right around 4:20 they are
now under some cannon LED lights and a 5
by 5 10 that is my tester area is what
I've called it now it's my breeding
chamber for today I have got a stellar
stellar look in Jack the Ripper male
dude mm-hmm let's Jack the Ripper male
is what I wanted I planted five seeds
and I found a killer male out of that
pack I've got a female that looks really
well they're gonna breed very well
together the photos look sick
thank you I'm glad you've seen that they
are under Canon LEDs I've spoken about
canons on a previous episode those
plants grow so vigorously under canons I
should have flipped to flower like a
week earlier because they're just taken
off dude but the canons are killing it
I love the canons nice yeah yeah so I've
got that new lights and a new male plant
in a new environment and it's got me
super excited I'm always passionate and
stoked about growing but right now I'm
like whoohoo new [ __ ] and I also changed
my mom and vege space to Canon LEDs so
I've only got one more flowering area to
go until we're all kin and out in this
place so it's gonna be cool hmm and I
think I may need to get some cannons and
my friends to get them growing to ah but
I've got this Jack the Ripper mail I'm
super excited about it bro it's dumping
Colin it looks great it's right about
pollination time for the females I do
have I haven't talked about the females
that are in there too much I like to
keep my stuff kind of not super
secretive but yeah well I feel like
sometimes I've talked about projects and
then they failed and I was like oh
that's cuz I talked about it I gave it
too much like too much energy too much
hope I put it on a pedestal and I [ __ ]
it all up but I do have a Jack the
Ripper male a Jack the Ripper female and
there is an arise female in there
amongst several other females not
several a couple were limited by plants
here but ah yeah half my count is
dedicated to this breeding area so there
will be some Jack the Ripper f2
that's just for myself to like make more
Jack the Ripper seeds cuz we got to make
more Jack because subbies gone and then
I crossed there also my there are other
things in there like you'll be happy
with what I put in there one of your
favorites is in there so there will be
some I read genetics classic yes yes
some I read genetics classics crossed to
one of sub cools classics this will be
not the first time that I've worked with
sub stuff but the first time I've used
his pollen I was a serious Jack Tripper
fan and it's just it disappeared it's
not like I stopped being a fan it's just
it's not being widely available yeah I
cannot wait to see where this project
leads all the commissioners are as
psyched as I am all the yeah yeah I get
they are because I get messages every
time I say it they want testers you guys
the pollen is just now starting to drop
I need weeks to get the seeds done
harvested packaged then I will grow them
if they're worth a [ __ ] when I grow them
that's when I'll look to giving them out
to testers mmm I'm gonna interrupt
myself because I said something a minute
ago you said that the Jack the Ripper
disappeared and then I said it got over
ran by like cookies and stuff like that
they triggered her memory in my head an
episode or three ago I don't know when
gives were so far ahead mmm I called a
few strains hype strains and apparently
I offended a close friend and I don't
want to offend anybody I said the a
strain I listed off strains then I was
just rambling I was putting words
together and I was like this sounds like
a hype strain I said two words together
and my friend bred that strain and I
don't want to dis my friend so no
disrespect to you bro you're listening
to the show right now I hope or somebody
will relay the message to you he's a
really popular girl right he's on a
youtube I don't need to I didn't mean to
offend you bro but it was all I'm just
running names off the top of my head and
I said this sounds like a [ __ ] hype
strain your shits fire i apologize bro
nothing about love and respect I really
don't have any beef with any breeders
out there I think all that [ __ ] is silly
but when you when I thought of cookies I
just thought it would be polite of me to
[ __ ] him go ahead and apologize to my
buddy I said cake bomb was all hype uh
cake bombs not a height bro cake bomb is
[ __ ] all gasp no brakes so [ __ ]
sorry bro I apologize just rambling I
picked a strain out of the [ __ ] thin
air I pissed somebody off doing it I'll
be more careful I'm sure
wasn't pissed off I'm sure he's like
[ __ ] you just call I'd be like if
somebody called a rise after like a bro
or rises [ __ ] hype meds I don't
oh ouch [ __ ] stop that's my kid it's
like calling one of your kids a [ __ ]
you know the wrong word look at that
little R word like hey wait bro can't
say that word anymore especially got my
[ __ ] kid right kids bro yeah exactly
sorry I picked on your child bro nothing
but love and respect mmm keep killing it
on [ __ ] patreon the person I'm
talking about kills it on patreon and on
twitch and on [ __ ] but patreon I'm
impressed with your patreon by the way
okay I'm rambling myself [ __ ] all day
long my throat's gonna be too dry to
even cover in a cannabis topics these
rambles are brought to you by dabs big
shout-out to dabs and also big shout-out
to our friends at seeds here now calm um
so stitcher Eric covered that make sure
you find the show on Spotify I really
prefer you check the show out on YouTube
I'm just trying to get most of the
audience to youtube I understand you may
be driving and unless you've got YouTube
ready you can't lock your phone and
close your phone and put it away or in
your pocket or something and hear it so
I understand you may need to listen on
Spotify or stitcher or Apple podcast but
if stitcher fails you again those there
are backup options Spotify is free it's
available um there are other services
that I will try to get the show on it
just takes I had a technical issue and I
do and I didn't know that I knew how to
make an RSS feed and solve issues I
[ __ ] did it Matt was sitting here
he's like why aren't you on Spotify and
I think this is my excuse and I was like
I could do this I could do that oh I
could do that and within 20 minutes my
[ __ ] was on Spotify I just had to take a
couple dabs and get the idea think about
it yeah so I think we've covered all of
the news and all the crap and the first
start of the show running like 20
minutes in now we got caught up with the
do list yeah I think they call it
housekeeping in the podcast business now
we can actually move on to the
educational and entertainment part of
the podcast I like to take questions
from email if you've got a question the
best way to get it to me honestly the
best way to get it to me is through
patreon um go for the appropriate tier
I've changed the pricing but go for the
question answering tier sign up throw me
a question on patreon the patreon
questions go first obviously that's an
expensive ticket to riot you get to the
front of the line
the next
best way is to send me an email it's
grow from your heart at hotmail.com yeah
laugh at me cuz it's a hotmail [ __ ]
but all the other ones get hacked and
broken into and gmail failed me once and
now I'm scared so it's hotmail bro grow
from your heart at hotmail.com we'll get
you right to me I don't remember where I
found this question because I didn't
print it which makes me think it came
from YouTube I love the people comment
on YouTube but it's more challenging for
me to print them off because it wants to
print the entire YouTube screen unless I
catch it in the email it's difficult I'm
not complaining third world prompt first
world problems white people problems but
if you really want me to get it I
YouTube isn't the place to send it grow
from your heart at hotmail calms the
best I did find this one on YouTube I
believe and all I wrote down was do I
question somebody asked me hey Ross -
Jeff why are my plants drooping toward
the end of the day cycle a little bit
before the light cycle might start my
plants my leaves start to droop down do
they need water right before they go to
sleep that I do something wrong they
were really worried about their plants
Mike you look like you might know what's
going on with these do you have any
input on this nope oh you look like you
really [ __ ] I try because I've seen
this before and I'm waiting do you start
to get droopy but toward the end of the
day I do the plants are doing the same
thing I think they'd be pissed if I gave
them Red Bull though and that's yeah
yeah don't do that give them a nap so
what's happening is they have reached
there he's got that mountain dudes going
strong for you people only listening on
audio it's my daily light integral is
that means the daily light integral
they've had their amount of light that
they want for the day your light is
however far away yeah that's basically
it bro they go hey I only want this many
you moles per Joule today and that is a
measurement of light don't worry about
pars don't worry about photons what
matters is you moles per Joule and
they've gotten enough so they're
starting to shut down
they're going yeah there's no reason for
me to keep [ __ ] photosynthesizing I'm
just gonna let my leaves hang I'm gonna
kind of take a rest and start doing the
functions that I do during the night
cycle and then when the lights shut off
it's a beautiful night time for them so
that is why the plants are drooping they
could be thirsty but most if it's
happening like 15 20 30 minutes before
nighttime they've reached there there'd
be the other symptoms of thirst
yeah exactly be easier to diagnose than
this now one thing that does happen in
strains bred from my day breaker if
that's something they came from the day
breaker line cuz I cross stuff straight
from day breaker I made a break or f2s
and a few day breaker things I rise was
made in that batch so things that come
from a rise also have the potential to
make if you get the big leaved
phenotypes of crosses that come from a
rise those do have the potential to be a
little bit droopy just because they're
so big then like the plants don't have
enough energy to keep that giant leaf
turgid and upright so it hangs a little
tiny bit all the time yeah that [ __ ]
got big in the pre 98 bubba kush used to
make ruby yeah and it was just tired
it was just like nah bro these leaves
are the leaves are longer than my
[ __ ] foot so they're like I can't
even keep the tip going anymore I was in
needed a little bit of plant viagra on
the leaves was just tired bro who's just
getting a little plant edy I guess but
what I think is happening for the person
who asked me this question is the plants
basically need a nap so you could and I
don't know the condition of your plants
I don't know how long your lights are on
if they are on for 24 hours a day and
you're seeing droop toward a certain
period of the day give them some night
time start introducing some dark to your
plants if you're on an 18-6 maybe not
because then they may be telling you I'm
ready to start flowering so be careful
start paying attention if they're
starting to droop at the end of that day
time they're starting to tell you hey
bro it is almost time for me to start
flowering unless you either put me in a
bigger pot or something changes they
could be starting to get root bound it
could be one of the reasons they'll do
that but it's the daily light integral
that is mainly doing that if you put
them into flower you also see that
happen toward the end of the flower or
toward the end of the day and flower
they will also start to droop you can't
really change the light cycle so you got
to keep them on twelve twelve they're
just keep giving them that light they'll
pump out those big old fat buds but
they've already processed as much as
they can so nothing wrong with your
plants but if they are in small pots and
your vegging it may be time to pop
that's the only thing I could recommend
but if everything else is in line just
enough light you're cool
next question let's move right on this
one came from patreon like I said before
patreon is the best way to get your
message onto the show that is the ticket
to the front of the line patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart also
help out my buddy white Mike patreon.com
forward slash white Mike this one came
from patreon it comes from our friend um
I'm gonna straight-up say his name
because he signed it there's a lot of
stuff in I think his name is Craig
Compton and he said hey Ross - Jeff I
ran across your podcast and YouTube
channel about a month ago and I wanted
to tell you that I am hooked thank you
bro glad you took the bait I says I
really appreciate the way you present
your knowledge your passion and your
dedication to the plant and the industry
they are all a 10 out of 10 so we're
getting 10 stars today bro thank you for
the compliment Craig it goes on to say
I'm a new grower I'm a commercial grower
and I love to listen to people who can
elevate my game and you are now one of
my favs thank you bro I like to I like
to educate and inform and what I really
like is knowing that somebody is getting
educated and informed and in light that
feels good like I threw a dart and it I
didn't know where my bull's eye was but
I [ __ ] hit it so that feels really
good as somebody an educator a podcaster
a producer a passionate person those
compliments all mean a lot of [ __ ] to me
a lot of good [ __ ] so here's where this
message gets really fun it says I almost
spit my coffee on my windshield the
other day when you said you had to stop
listening to your guru because you
started talking like him um I don't know
if it was on this podcast or in a live
feed or on embracing organics or in
another platform for a while I was
listening to a guy who was very
educational and informative I feel like
I've got to educate myself with more
knowledgeable people so that I can keep
you guys educated I got to get a lot of
education sources so I try to fill my
brain with knowledge I had a [ __ ]
bromance in a man-crush on this [ __ ]
weed cultivator that I found you're just
filling my brain with so much great
information and I started he's got a
East Coast accent I wasn't talking like
the East Coast accent but I was using
his terms and his ideologies way too
much like I caught it infecting
affecting my brain affecting with an AI
was affecting my brain and my my speech
and my thoughts so I had to stop talking
like i listening to him
to cut myself off from it I was like no
no more to him for a minute it's like if
you listen to the same rapper for a
while you probably if you listen to
Eminem you probably start doing that how
many men start doing the Eminem [ __ ]
eventually if you listen to [ __ ]
whoever use if you listened to Metallica
you start playing [ __ ] chin chin chin
chin chin chin just too much of that so
I had to quit listen to this guy but
this guy says I knew immediately you
were talking about keV because I am the
same way and it made me bust out
laughing that he has the same effect on
you as he does me he's talking about
Kevin Joe dree I had to quit listening
to Kevin Joe drew for a while you guys
because I started saying all of his
words his glossary his dictionary it all
spilled into my brain it wasn't a bad
thing but I wanted to be me again and
stop being Kevin Joe dree it was [ __ ]
me up so this guy knew right away who I
was talking about he says he has the
same effect as he does on me I'm very
fortunate to have crossed paths was keV
about five years ago and became very
good friends with him and over that time
I've spent many hours and days with him
learning and laughing and smoking some
grape flour he's my mentor and friend
and I think God every day for people
like him and you who make me a better
grower and person thanks again I signed
up for patreon just to support you thank
you bro that means a lot you are worth
it and I look forward to the day we can
hang out as well as bust out a fat dab
or a fatty piece love and understanding
and he signed with his real name I
follow him on Instagram he's Robert
gnarly on Instagram and let's see where
else can we find him um he doesn't give
us another spot to follow him so that's
enough spots we gave him a good shout
out
Craig Compton thank you for the cool
message it means it dude this guy
listens and supports us while he's
working alongside the walking talking
cannabis encyclopedia like Kevin Joe
dree Kevin is if I can't figure
something out Kevin is who I would look
to for answers and this guy's standing
next to him all day this person still
chooses to listen to us on our little
podcaster so that's flattering
that's a huge compliment that's a huge
uh try not to let my ego swell too much
I'm getting older and trying to deflate
and understand that ego but it has got
pumped up a little bit you just put some
[ __ ] some pump to my ego bro so thank
you not a bad thing bro yeah I'm right
when the show helps people grow better
like that's the whole point of the show
exactly the point of the show I was
recently i subjected to some online weed
forums and holyfuck the advice is just
as bad as it was in 97 it's still [ __ ]
you must have seen some comments I left
on a Facebook forum it's still it still
seems like it's a whole bunch of
mediocre growers giving people advice
they know is shitty in hopes that
they'll still have a market for their
meds right the advice is that bad and
it's okay that there's people putting
out the right information and it's
reaching its target it makes me happy
yes yes it's okay to be a mediocre
grower dude I sucked it growing when I
started I sucked at playing drummers
someone I sucked at podcast yeah we
always say I sucked it I I don't take
karate I'm not a [ __ ] ninja when I
was a kid I took karate it sucked at
karate I was a white belt my kicks were
sloppy my form was terrible dude after a
few years it's thrown [ __ ] head kicks
and tournaments like you gotta suck for
a little bit and everything you do it
feels good to suck it stuff like I've
got such a good grasp on podcasting
growing [ __ ] playing the drums that
when I try to pick up a guitar it's like
this is hard and it makes my brain go
yeah and I want to [ __ ] get good at
it and figure it out it's okay to suck
at [ __ ] what you shouldn't do if you
suck at stuff is tell other people how
to suck at things also you don't have to
have an answer Mike if I go other people
how to do it worse to make your second
appear better what are what notes do i
tune my guitar to Mike see you could
have said F R T and Q if you really
wanted yeah but it's seven bro you
[ __ ] adult it you manned up and went
I don't know
hey Mike how many states have legal
cannabis I should know but see you can
you see you're qualified enough to do
the research and give me a ballpark
answer yeah I could check and be sure
but how legal you talking you know you
should answer questions on forums about
your kids you can chime in about legal
states shut the hell up when it comes to
tuning guitars yeah
more people took that advice there will
be a wave yeah and that's the only thing
that I can't say that's the only I'm
sure that's not the only thing that is
the real issue that bugs me on social
media grow platforms people will say my
uncle's brother tried to put this in his
soil and it worked for him so that'll
solve all your problems and I'm like you
just told them to that's gonna kill all
the plants like I hope you didn't do
this yet can I reply quicker and get my
word in before you do this and yeah but
it worries me like all social media is
pretty toxic right now but the grow
forums I got I think it's that the
financial incentive because everybody
sort of understands that there's a
limited number of cannabis consumers out
there and everybody's selling the same
product and if somebody asks you for
advice you're like now set it on fire
take it out back and kick it like that
makes your [ __ ] even if it's mediocre a
little bit more I don't know it's just
the advice is so bad it's insane the
advice on other topics is usually bad
but it's not and I'm trying to be a
positive person folks but it's a good
time to vent this drives me crazy
somebody posts a picture of a plant it's
got a minor problem the first person
says spider mites they don't have spider
mites so now they're paranoid about
spider mites second person says thrips
third person says bad soil fourth person
says wrong light now this person is
spraying for mites and spraying for
thrips and changing their soil and
buying new lights when really it was too
hot well their plant dies because they
did 11 things to it on the same yeah and
so I'm like please be careful so guys my
bottom line my point here if just be
careful when you're [ __ ] looking
online for advice like there are a lot
of things that people will say go look
at the pictures of their garden go look
if they if they can't smell leaves with
a V if they put an F in the word leaves
don't [ __ ] take their advice like
that's it's uh it's easier with other
topics with with cannabis it's it's
still fringy enough that sometimes it's
hard to tell like proper grammar is not
always indicative of proper knowledge
it's not quite as obvious it isn't like
in politics with politics it's quick
when people start talking about
in law's you're like do you mean repeal
[ __ ] yeah it's a little bit more
obvious than it is in the cannabis world
but usually if you pay attention you you
take a minute and check two or three
reliable sources you get the info you
want but just be super careful if it's
you're asking the social media forum
about a cannabis screen question because
eighty percent of those answers are
designed to [ __ ] of your plants I don't
know if they're really designed that way
or if they're actually that misinformed
like I would like to hope they're not
targeting - thank you fail I should move
forward from ranting about social media
honestly dude social media people
talking about feminized seeds ah
and such an I think ignorant is the
appropriate word ignorant means
misinformed it's not an insult
they're very ignorant about feminized
seeds they have frustrated me enough to
where I am going to do a full Episode on
feminized seeds and detailed on how I
make them so that it's understood so
that people aren't using the wrong terms
and wrong assumptions I want to correct
it so that's maybe it worked for them
giving all this terrible advice
frustrated me enough to go okay children
here's how it works it's like if you if
I know that the best way to get one of
my comedian friends to tell a joke is to
start telling his joke wrong yeah yeah
like if you're you know I hang out some
of the comedian nerds right so start
telling it's a good analogy start
telling one of their bits bro nobody
you're [ __ ] it up it goes like this
and I just watch them tell their joke
like thank you and I get to hear you do
comedy now yeah alright Mike we're super
rambley I've got no deadline today so
let's get right into another message
this one comes from what did they sign
it with no they're writing from
prohibition land so we're not gonna even
if their name and somebody sent me an
email the other day and I said I am in
PL and I was like bro
I don't where's peel my prohibition land
[ __ ] and I was like sorry I'm
I'm hi I'm [ __ ] it's stupid if I didn't
get that I apologize from prohibition
land says like this Rasta Jeff I love
everything you do brother I'm riding
from East Coast pearl abyssion land I'll
keep it short since you're busy thank
you I do appreciate that first if you
think your perpetual grow lesson was
worth money
in your breeding lessons was priceless
dude that's awesome thank you I think I
made a joke one time about my perpetual
grow lesson being worth a million bucks
or if I wrote a written a book that
would have been the cash cow right there
that was old school so you've been
listening for a while and I'm glad you
enjoyed the breeding labels lesson I
kind of went over that on to other
podcasts today we talked about that on
embracing organics we also talked about
that on the grow cast with Jordan River
so fun topic that keeps coming up I'm
gonna get myself back on track it says
dude I listened to it twice back-to-back
just for the a and B line lesson and I
will listen many more times for a
refresher I love that keep clicking on
it bro listen on YouTube give me more
lessons and views that episode is my
absolute favorite and I will spread the
word about your podcast to anyone who
will listen my friend I love that ya
don't run off your friends by rambling
too much about it but encourage them so
it goes on to say I grew in a basement
for about ten years and I had to stop
for six I started again then I started
again I says why he had to stop but I
don't know if I'm supposed to read that
cuz it's in parenthesis I says now I'm
allegedly in week two of my week to a
flower on my third attempt I've got four
New York diesel in a four by three tenth
everything looks good for this one bro
I've seen your past and I hope this one
is much more successful nice cross yeah
toes crossed Jah love I am fairly
experienced but this is my first trellis
grow so they've got a trellis a netting
system I just installed my second
trellis so they've got a first one
hopefully spreading it the second one
kind of given it support it says I
listened to all of your scrog lessons
but I have a quick question all right
this is where the questions come in is
it okay if some of my buds are woven
through the trellis or should I only be
weaving so only the branch material is
touching the trellis I hope this makes
sense I'm trying to keep the canopy
super low I'm just worried that I'm
keeping some of the buds caught in the
trellis I work on a 2500 acre fresh
produce farm but I come home to a four
by three tenth row that is passion right
there I wish every day that these rows
were golden goat or a lemon Geoffrey
thank you bro I wish you much love shout
out from our friend out there an east
coast prohibition land let's talk about
this for a minute Mike one of the first
thing I thought was yeah it's okay
you're gonna get your buds are going
grow into your trellis occasionally um
you get the little nodules the stick
comes up and the bud branches off of
there and instead of it just growing
straight it happens to catch the part of
this trellis and it just grows around it
that's fine you're just gonna have to
cut that out at the end of flower be
careful something that did catch my
attention though you said that you're
still weaving it through and you're in
flower be very careful doing that if
you're in flower far enough to have
chunky bud set you should have already
be woven up through there that's part of
what got my attention so I'm gonna read
it again I'm only I only be weaving or
should I only be weaving so only the
branch material is touching the trellis
um I I read that or I would listen do
you read that it sounded like he was
talking about his setup okay should he
weave it through so that when it starts
to flower out heavily all of the
flowering material is off and it's
mostly stick hitting trellis okay most
of the time shoot four on the bottom one
we're going to clean off most of the
branching and sucker shoots and [ __ ] on
the bottom net that's we clean all the
way that's I kind of use a rule of thumb
I kind of lean off a lot of there at the
end of flower because it's too hard to
get it out before flowering right but
there shouldn't be buds on the bud
starts right above that like that's I
tell the guys bottom it to the first net
that's kind of the first net goes about
18 inches high and we bought them up to
there so you got however tall the pot is
and then the rest of that gets kind of
cleaned up so there's no bud down there
ah maybe maybe tiny buds may grow into
your net but that's fine just pull them
right out they're gonna fall off when
you start pulling it you know when the
guys run through the grow rooms mic and
at the end of the day we got a bunch of
little popcorn buds on the floor those
are the ones that got caught in the net
those are the little tiny buds that grew
on the wrong side of the fence so your
second layer a trellis um that is there
to support the buds so they're gonna be
leaning against that they've got to go
somewhere but I'm toppling over they're
tall they're gonna and so that is when
you get the opportunity for that stick
to go straight the blood starts growing
up the fences around it and they were
gonna go on the wrong side of the fence
yeah that'll be okay that will happen
that's gonna be hard to prevent you see
where the buds are gonna develop cuz
you've got a chute there but sometimes
you just can't aim it it's the [ __ ]
happens in a tent you've got a little
more chance
to control it to need you in a larger
facility yeah
and when you're talking for six plants
it's it's easier to to micromanage each
Cola it's not possible to do it on a 20
yard table yeah when you cut them down
you're gonna cut them down to small buds
anyway nobody wants it's really fun to
look at big old donkey dick buds big old
bananas big old dildos a weed but I
don't want it like those business
there's a stick down the middle there's
a drum stick down the middle I'm not
trying to buy a five hey drum stick
along with my weed I'll go to Guitar
Center when I need sticks actually I'll
visit my friends at dope sticks shout
out to dope sticks I gotta show love to
local drummers and people that support
you back that's my friend Eric Moore's
got a drum company that make sticks now
got a Shum Love but I don't want the big
buddy you got to cut it down make it
smaller so in the end of the cycle
you're kind of down making it smaller
anyway don't be too worried if it's
stuck what you can do at harvest time
you can cut the branch low and so if
your trellis is at one level and the
buds growing up through it cut below
there and just slowly slide down and get
the trellis net out of there the string
the plastic line whatever just slowly
get it out of there go downward and pull
it out hopefully you got like twelve or
fourteen inches worth it he won't
I'm just exaggerating and hoping you the
best of luck but it's only gonna be a
couple inches you got a slide down pull
it out of there maybe that way you won't
break that bud off of this stick and it
will still dry and cure properly but
yeah it's not a big deal it's not a
major issue it's not a problem
it just makes uh harvesting is a little
bit more challenging once you get it
that way if you can when it comes
harvest time cut the plants out of the
net don't cut the net down all at once
just as a commercial grower with a lot
of experience Mike's not in his head
because he's seen it so like your net is
hooked to some supports on the side of
the table if you cut it free of those
supports so that the net flops free all
in one piece it'll [ __ ] up your harvest
all of your buds will flop free all a
triple triple your I understand it's
easier to cut the buds out of the net
than to cut the net out of the buds to
tell you the truth and it's yeah it's
super easy to go piecemeal and be
patient don't don't get rush working
with that net I've seen growers cut
other growers I've seen growers
themselves that is when wind [ __ ] goes
rogue I fall off a ladder once they were
both holding but this dudes working in a
ladder and his 4x4 tent he's already
going crazy so we're gonna drug testing
problems we're gonna drug test you if I
catch you in a ladder in there buddy
that was a really good piece of advice
bring the net down little by little
around the plants knot or if you can get
the plants out of that top layer then
cut the net out and then take out the
bottom layer then cut the net you may
want to recycle that net bro it's like
eight bucks please just [ __ ] get a
new one yeah reusing that in the pots
those are the two most brutal things
three is I reuse the pots I take them to
the pots oh don't you you can run the
cloth pots through the washer at the
laundry machine don't do them at your
wife's or your mom's house because she
will [ __ ] at you but do them at the
laundry machine at the industrial
washing machines and you can run those
cloth pots through there and get one or
two uses out of them they're cheap and
affordable but some of you guys are
using the more expensive ones with the
zippers go wash those take your plastic
pots too if you're in a legal state and
it's not sketchy take them to the car
wash just spray em down yeah if you can
get that thing that holds the floor mats
in place on the wall clip them into that
spray the [ __ ] out of them and clip them
in and spray em yeah because when you
put them on the floor they're gonna
slide away put them up against the wall
or put your foot on them or something
guys cuz they will that sprayer spray
the [ __ ] out of them and don't use any
detergent just do the hot water rinse
and spray for a couple seconds before
you start uh so in case there's soap in
the wine spray for a few seconds until
the water unclear yeah spray the line
clear until the water runs hot and clear
yeah you don't want car wash in your
plants and if you are in a sketchy area
and you need to wash them out the car
wash put them in the back of the truck
face-up like you're gonna load them and
then drive up to the car wash and then
to stand on the bed of the truck and
hose it looks like you're hosing the bed
of your truck down but you got enough
pots and they're packed after you just
doing the bed of the truck Mike how long
have we been at this [ __ ] these are like
[ __ ] secret tricks right here I was
telling somebody about the old you can
rig an electric car door opener the
little key fob openers you can rig those
to block like a bedroom door so that if
your landlord comes by
unexpectedly they can't get into that
second bedroom I was telling somebody
about that trick last night holy [ __ ]
where'd you learn about that it's like
okay that was a high times trick when I
was in high school
allegedly I saw one of the coolest most
stealth grows in a Denver apartment
allegedly maybe recently that was
[ __ ] I was him I was impressed yeah I
was like oh that's in here like I didn't
know I was sitting on the couch on the
opposite side of the room and didn't
know it existed so nice shout-out to my
friend who knows what he's doing we've
been going for a while but we've got one
more message from patreon and uh this
person is a girl from your heart podcast
supporter they're an IRA genetic
supporter they support Rasta Jeff and
all things I do
there are also members of the DGC so
I've been shout out to this person for
being an awesome cannabis soldier big
supporter of the cannabis community and
shout out to Rasta Kaye we've got a
message from patreon from rustic a shout
out to Rasta K anybody who calls himself
Rasta whatever is a friend of mine it
goes like this I'm waiting for sex on a
rise yeah I don't think I've ever sent a
message with the words waiting for sex
in the subject good luck with your
google searches in the future bro anyway
waiting for sex it says what up grow me
is I have a quick question though this
community I thought this community could
help I switched over and a rise five
days ago two twelve twelve so they've
put it into flour they're twelve hours
on a twelve hours all our it's in it's
in the flowering cycle because the
question is is there a specific point
specific that's the word specific point
not Pacific I meant to say specific is
there a specific point that would show
sex first I did top it so with the
pistols are sacks Chilam higher on the
plant or lower or is this all random
thanks guys um how long ago did you top
it before you put it in the flower I'm
hoping you gave it 7/10 maybe 14 days to
recover so that the auxins and
cytokinins can run back to the tips of
the plants and [ __ ] choose I try to
fight over apical dominance I hope you
did that too late to [ __ ] worry about
it at this point I'm not gonna make too
big of a difference would have gotten
bigger fatter bloods had you let it
recover um
at first I thought they were asking what
time frame it will show sex and I was
going to say ten for location and what
yeah location what specific point on the
plant will it show sex look at the very
tops I think the tops are going to be
the most indicative points of the plan
to find sex so you'll start seeing if
it's a female you'll start getting the
little pistols coming out if it's a male
you'll start seeing little nubs and
eventually those nubs will turn into
little ball sacks so the top is probably
the best place to look or if you've got
an area that's getting really shaded
that area may develop into flour more
quickly sometimes the male plants will
show you a little lower down they'll
start popping off just one or two sacks
that are really extended because they're
trying to reach for the light but
typically the tops are going to be where
you're going to see sex first because um
the male plants grow taller here's a
weird thing in my opinion what I've
experienced the male plants generally
grow taller than all of the females um
they'll get to-- so if you've got a
batch of the same strain a batch of
whatever seeds golden goat seeds that's
not a good [ __ ] selection cuz that's
a feminized we needs a blue raspberry
truffle we got blue raspberry truffle
the males typically grow just a ratio
taller I don't know what size pots are
using but it's gonna be noticeably
taller because they're gonna make pollen
now Paula needs to fall down on to the
females so the tops are usually where we
start getting that that's the one where
they want to put their pollination parts
their sex glands go up to the top so
they can catch that Paul and if it was
down lower it would get intercepted by
leaves or get blown away by the wind by
the time I got to it so the tips or
that's where their vaginas are the
vaginas are on the tips mainly it's
where they start off first so wants to
get pollinated up there so ah that's
that's something to think about if you
guys are checking for males and females
quite often not a hundred percent true
sometimes it's Fino typical sometimes
you get some mutants and some freaks and
some champions but usually if you run a
pack of seeds those plants they get
super tall right away or generally gonna
be boys don't get to it so I was the
urban legend and the more we ran I
thought that was funny that one held
true yeah I kind of believed it from the
beginning because it's got a reason
there's like a reason in nature in a
sense yeah it's if that's not actually
true that's
it's true as [ __ ] he's true in my
experience for sure yeah oh the boys
want to get up there and drop Pauling
down if the boys are lower you can't
pollinate the top bud you and the short
guys ever get to [ __ ] the tall chicks
the first couple times I pop seeds I got
really excited over the you know the
super vigorous one yes in each time it
was like oh man
one you know ten days in the flower you
come in it's like oh man that plants got
a hard-on I tell a lot of people like
that when you're excited about it's
gonna be a boy like don't say that I can
already it's not I'm not jinxing you
it's it's a [ __ ] dude that's why it's
a foot taller than the rest it's why
it's more vigorous yeah I'm gonna move
on from that it's 2020 Mike this was a
fun podcast we've been going for like I
think close to an hour dude I wrote it
down on another page of notes and I
don't know where it went
yeah do we've been gone for close to an
hour so yeah yeah let's start wrapping
up this show brought a good time with
you yeah the people deserve this I think
uh the last episode I was off my game
dude I watch it again and as like it's
not as bad as I felt like it was but I
was just a little bit off my crackers we
might want to look at the last episode
we recorded we talked about being a
little fair a little recorded ahead in
this episode so I don't feel like we're
giving away any movie magic secrets but
we were in rare form for an episode
folks if you enjoyed it there wasn't
much editing to be done but we were I
think we may have had too many dabs for
a podcast that night dude
mind if we got we we got carried away
before the show a little bit and it was
also like 2:00 in the morning so that
should always has an effect on us yeah
late night podcasting from the bunker
it's been a good time dude the blade
Navy bunker sessions man so yeah well I
don't know they didn't pay us [ __ ] I
gotta pay them so [ __ ] that yeah brought
to you by seeds here now words like you
yes thank you guys thanks to everybody
on patreon who helps us out ah Mike I've
never given you the warning that I'm
gonna do this but I think you should
expect it right now do you have any
Mike's moments here at the end of the
show
a mykes moment now just be good at each
other people all right sounds good to me
where can the kind folks find you on
social media find me at Nemo Punk 15 on
Twitter or Instagram and at pablo for
sensible cannabis laws on facebook or
you can hit me up on patreon at
patreon.com forward slash white my
beautifully done bro you're doing that
like a podcasting professional at this
good Pro like I was expecting you to do
that [ __ ] yeah thanks again for hanging
out dude oh yeah thanks for having me
it's time to say go for it go let me
interrupt you I was gonna say keep
leaving YouTube comments keep sending
emails keep sending tweets
I love the interactions and want more so
yeah we want more just like you want
more we want more interaction will keep
nachos you keep responding will keep
interacting keeping them coming for you
be safe while you're in quarantine or
while you're doing whatever you're doing
feel like pretty soon man we make it to
go play again and see some comedy shows
and high five people and I'm itch and
there's a couple of bitchin don't go
outside well just it's you to get out
again like I'm it's weird cuz I'm a
shut-in anyway but I've kind of reached
the end of my limit I need to get out
and see some people to do some things i
frickin agree ladies yes yes I take care
of yourselves behave yourselves I'm not
gonna talk any conspiracies you're an
adult do what you want to do I love you
for it
Mike thanks for hanging out ladies and
gentlemen boys and girls pimps and hoes
friends foes smokers growers seed
cutters clone cutters pollen chuckers no
seed poppers there's so many of them
that I don't even know anymore I love
you guys I want to thank each and every
one of you for hanging out I feel like
you're like my own adopted pets and I
want to scratch all of you right behind
your ears so thank you for being here if
you feel like this episode was
educational informative and you're
entertaining and you'd like to make a
financial contribution of the show I'm
sure you've heard it plenty of times
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart I cannot thank you enough for all
of the love and support and of course
the funding helps as well speaking of
funding make sure you support our
sponsor at seeds here now.com a lot of
people ask me when are they getting a
fresh drop of this now they've got it
now
go check seeds here now calm use coupon
code gen save yourself a few bucks
somebody also asked if that coupon code
is good
other brands yes you can use that store
wide website why you can buy miss Jill
genetics assignment you can buy ethos
and that will work on your full order
GFY h10 I should work on the full order
at seeds here now calm I so go load up
yeah scenes here now calm Tom Ross Jeff
sent you coupon code gfy H 10 Mike that
is all I've got for this episode this
was a fun show - thank you for hanging
out for - taken some post-show dabs with
you anywhere yeah I like this there
might be an extra dude I'm glad you said
that now don't you have to ask you when
we're done you guys I'm gonna change my
shirt and we'll be back for another
episode if things go my way I want to
give a giant shout out to my dear friend
Benny's in the veg and it's all next
time
take a phat dab and give your mom a hug
for me