are you ready I'm ready welcome back
podcast world
I'm your host Rasta Jeff and it's time
for episode 543 of the growth from your
heart podcast this episode of the show
is brought to you by our friends at
seeds here now.com seeds here now.com
offers seeds from all the industry's
leading breeders including miss Jill
genetics Duke diamond and of course I
read genetics everything at seeds here
now.com is backed by their award-winning
satisfaction guarantee and for my
friends on a tight budget seeds here
now.com offers several packs for under
$30 as well as amazing monthly sales
make sure you use coupon code 10 while
checking out to save a few bucks
again that is coupon code g fyh 10 while
checking out at seeds here now
dot-com you know I like to start the
podcast off by talking about what I'm
smoking today I've been taking dad's of
sex on the beach
live batter from Green Dot labs this is
a blend of Paradise Island and Han Solo
Berger the flavor is described as
strawberry piña colada you know I think
I agree with that it's very tropical
it's very fruity it's very delicious I
think I tasted pineapple and coconut
maybe in there maybe that's the Pina
Colada part very delicious made me feel
like I was on a beach on an island I can
almost feel the wind blow through my
dreadlocks as I dab this one so big
shout-out to our friends at Green Dot
labs for the super delicious sex on the
beach
live batter alright in this episode I'm
going to do a long rant about feminized
seeds I'll talk about how they're made
I'll talk about labeling but before we
get there let's do some shout outs to
our friends who support the show on
patreon let's start off with the big
girl from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to Karen Crawford let's send a
big thank you shot at the Greg s I've
always got a giant thank you shout out
to my friend sour D let's send a big
thank you to Tanner M we've always got a
giant thank you shout out to spruce Hill
Farm let's send a big thank you to freak
fish I've always got some lovin for
Tobes McLovin and last but certainly not
least let's send a giant grow from your
heart podcast shout out to our friend
farmer John big thanks and big shout out
to everybody who continues to support
the show on patreon if you're not
already supporting the show and you
would like to learn how to do so all you
have to do is visit
w dot patreon.com forward slash grow
from your heart all of the information
you need will be right there on the
screen and once again big thanks to
everybody who supports the show and I
did include a link in the show notes and
the video description so that you guys
can get there almost forgot that part
there's a link in the description click
on that it will take you right to
patreon all right I did say I was going
to do a rant about making and labeling
feminized seeds um something I should
say before I get into this is this is my
method this is how I do it I'm not
saying that your method the way you were
taught the way you learned the way you
read the way somebody else should you
had to do it is wrong I'm saying this is
how I do it and I personally have seen
great success I think the people who end
up with my seeds see great success I
think the people who've end my seeds are
very satisfied with me and I do not get
any complaints so with that disclaimer
let's talk about how I make feminized I
read genetics seeds um the first thing I
want to cover something that really
frustrates me I see it on social media
people have this assumption this idea in
their head that feminized seeds are
hermaphrodites they are not Herms
they're not hermaphrodites they're not
Hermes I don't like the word hermie it
sounds very immature
it's a hermaphrodite or it's an intersex
plant if you want to chop the word
hermaphrodite down just say herm
Hermey sounds childish to me maybe
that's just weird to me that's not a big
deal let's continue the plants are not
hermaphrodites they are not intersex
they are true and trusted female plants
the females that I use have been stress
tested and specially selected for
breeding if I have a female plant before
I even consider breeding with it I beat
the [ __ ] out of that plant and how do I
do that there are a lot of ways to
trigger a plant to show a hermaphroditic
trait or a intersex trait if it's in
that plant the easiest way to do it is
to disrupt the light cycle during flower
so when I am working with new plants if
I intend to breed with them I will put
that female plant into flower for about
two weeks everything is normal I'm on
I'm feeding it normally we're going into
flour things are starting to look good
as soon as the plant is comfortable in
twelve twelve I'm gonna [ __ ] it up and
put it on eighteen six now the plant
goes wait a minute
it was the fall now it's spring again
I'm still alive I don't know what to do
some plants will freak the [ __ ] out some
plants will show signs of intersex
traits of hermaphroditism within a few
days they will pop up little male
flowers they'll pop up full-on pollen
sacks they will show you problems you
get rid of those plants or do not breed
with them if you want to grow those in
your own private garden that is cool
you're not breeding you're not passing
on that trade just know that that's an
option
one day when you [ __ ] up if you get a
light leak if something goes wrong that
plant could turn into a hermaphrodite
and that plant could express that trait
and that plant could pollinate your
garden I get rid of those I don't grow
them I don't breed them they're not
allowed in my grow I've got very high
standards for my breeding for my
cultivation if it shows any intersex
traits it goes bye-bye I don't want it
we're not hanging out it's not my friend
nothing personal I'm in it for business
I can't have problematic plants so the
bottom line is these are solid tried and
true tested females other ways that I
abuse them so I said then I'll change
that light cycle to eighteen six then I
may still not see problems so I'll put
it back on twelve twelve after three to
five days now we're three weeks in we
either see some problems or we don't
I'll put it back on 1212 finish out
weeks three and four on 1212 then at
week six or seven let's just [ __ ] up
that light cycle all again let's put it
on 24 hours a day and see if those
plants her/him out see if they have any
signs of stress if they freaked out on
me those plants better not freak out if
they do guess what chop chop bye bye see
you later they don't get to play with my
friends anymore they're gone so I am
stress testing these plants also many of
the cultivars the plants the clones the
selections that I am using have come
from commercial cultivation facilities I
love all my bros and uh female grower
friends that work in these commercial
cultivation facilities but many of them
are young I love you guys they're 24 25
26 years old some of them are in their
early 30s a lot of them like to have fun
on the weekends a lot of them
maybe sometimes may take a couple too
many dabs on their lunch break so [ __ ]
happens in the commercial cultivation
facilities and when [ __ ] happens the
plants get seriously abused sometimes
also sometimes equipment fails HVAC will
fail watering irrigation will fail
something will go wrong I get to see a
myriad of abuse and problems given to
these plants via the grow tax somebody
may be stoned and forget to pH a whole
batch of nutrients somebody may be
stoned in overwater a whole [ __ ] room
somebody may just forget to even show up
to work that day sometimes [ __ ] happens
in a commercial cultivation facility
there are ramifications and
repercussions for the staff but also the
plants have issues that we've got to
deal with I get to see the plants get
abused as what I'm saying you guys I've
seen them tortured in all sorts of ways
you can and cannot imagine so I know
what the plants are going to work with
many of the plants I work with I've seen
them in a commercial cultivation setting
and I've gotten to watch them in ah the
commercial cultivation in Pueblo West
and the one in Springs the one in South
Denver the one in northglenn I get to go
to these different facilities and
they've got the same cultivar in these
facilities so I get to see it grown by
four different leave growers I get to
see it abused by four different HVAC
systems I get to see four different bug
infestations whatever happens in a
facility I get to see it four different
times in over hundreds of plants so I've
seen what will handle problems what will
not handle problems what is good for
growing under high stress conditions
that's where I've selected my females
that I'm using for breeding so they're
not hermaphrodites they're able to take
abuse they take stress very well they
grow with good vigor and also I think
they're good plants since they work in a
commercial environment where we I would
love to say we can pay attention to
every single plant sometimes [ __ ] gets
overlooked like I said earlier we got
young people who are having a good time
working and they're the music's loud
we're going fast
[ __ ] happens I lost train of that
thought but [ __ ] happens I may need to
[ __ ] press pause and figure out where
I was
I'm selecting these plants from a
commercial cultivation facility so I've
seen a lot of problems I know they're
gonna grow well since the grow techs
that show up late and stone and have a
lot of plants to handle some of them are
overloaded and I'm bombarded with work
if they can handle hundreds of these
plants I know that when I breed to them
a grower who is new it growing will
definitely have good success with a
small batch of these plants they're good
successful plants is what I think I'm
trying to say with the good they've been
vetted by myself and by several other
commercial growers so they're verified
qualified plants they are not
hermaphrodites they are not males they
don't have problems those are the plants
that I start with the main most
important thing I think is starting with
trusted breeding stock you can't make a
good cake with shitty ingredients you
can't have champions without good
[ __ ] champion stock I don't know what
I'm saying but you need good plants to
begin with so let's say we've got to
qualified plants let's say we've got one
qualified plant we're gonna start with
one that we want to make feminized seats
from um let's kind of go through the
process of how I do this the selected
cut is I would take two clones if I just
want to make a small batch of FEM seeds
I've got one plant I take two clones I
grow them I vege them they get about the
size where I'm ready to flower here's
where the feminization process kicks in
the one of the selected cuts is treated
with silver thiosulfate that is a blend
of silver nitrate and sodium thiosulfate
those are two products that are
available for purchase on the internet
if you know where to look they are not
very dangerous if you're safe with them
you can cause problems if you inhale
them just be careful follow the safety
precautions on the containers and you
will be fine wear a mask wear some
gloves you'll be okay you're probably
wearing a mask today anyway don't worry
about it so I mix up my own silver
thiosulfate solution then it is diluted
to specific dilutions then it is applied
via a spray I spray it directly onto the
plant by itself without a surfactant I'm
applying diluted silver thiosulfate
solution onto a plant at very specific
dilutions and very specific intervals
what does that mean the strength of my
solution varies based on
the plant I am trying to reverse some
plants want really strong solutions some
plants really freak out if you spray
them too strong they need a lighter
solution more times it is kind of you
have to learn the plant so what do I
mean by intervals I spray it in a very
very carefully scheduled time I know
exactly which day those plants are
getting sprayed I can tell you how many
times each plant that I reverse will get
sprayed if I've worked with it a couple
of times excuse me I'm choking on my own
words if I've worked with the plant
reversing it several times I have
already got a good idea a notebook a
recipe in my head somewhere I've got it
written down and marked down but I know
it needs this dilution it needs to be
sprayed this many times for optimal
pollen production if you spray with too
hard of a solution too strong of a
solution sometimes the plants will
produce pollen sacks but they will not
produce any pollen you'll get a really
Paul and Sachi plant nothing comes out
of it if you don't use a strong enough
solution obviously it doesn't reverse so
you've got to find the balance some
plants want to be sprayed really hard a
couple of times some plants want to be
sprayed really lightly a bunch of times
some plants want to be sprayed really
hard a lot of times it's all about the
plant and what it takes to reverse that
plant and the only way to learn that is
by doing it to that specific plant and
watching the plan sometimes the leaves
will crinkle up and it looks like you
just shocked that plant with a [ __ ]
laser you've gone a little bit too hard
but often times those plants make a lot
of great pollen we're not going for the
looks we're going for pollen so it's all
about pollen production is the main goal
so I mix up silver thiosulfate i dilute
it to specific delusions and I spray at
specific intervals when I spray I spray
the [ __ ] out of the plant I remove the
plant that is going to get sprayed out
of the grow space so it is the only one
to get sprayed I soak it to the point of
runoff that plant is dripping there's a
puddle on the floor around the plant uh
I really soak it I also make sure to
spray the sticks and the main stalk
I don't just focus on the leaves I want
to get a lot of silver into this plant
so I'm using silver thiosulfate the
thiosulfate acts as a carrier the silver
cannot penetrate the leaf surface and
get into the plant the
sulfate makes it more bioavailable for
the plant I guess you want to say is I
don't know if that's the correct word it
makes it more I gives it better
penetration for the leaf surface that
gets this silver into the plant the
silver is the active ingredient that is
going to work the magic so I've selected
proper plants I have mixed up a solution
I have made a schedule and I've applied
my solution at the proper schedule I've
applied to runoff we've gotten silver
thiosulfate into the plant that silver
is into the plant now let's talk about
how and why this feminization process
works I've just sprayed the plants with
silver silver stops the copper movement
within the plant there is copper moving
in the plant we feed the plants lots of
minerals lots of elements copper is one
of the things that is abundant and
moving within our plants I don't know
that abundant was the appropriate word
it is present and moving within our
plants when I disrupt disrupt the copper
movement by spraying the silver
thiosulfate that disruption triggers an
ethylene response ethylene is a hormone
that triggers and I just wrote down a
lot of different reactions in different
species of plants and if you research
what ethylene does in plants it has a
lot of different functions and triggers
in plants it makes some plan to ripen it
has a lot to do a lot to do with
ripening and senescence in cannabis it
makes cannabis think that the end is
near because I'm ripening for some
reason and I wasn't ready to ripen I'm
not sure what to do cannabis is main
goal is to reproduce just like a lot of
us all it wants to do is reproduce so a
female cannabis plant it's only instinct
is to survive it wants to make the only
way it can reproduce the only way it can
survive is to make seeds so that next
year those seeds can grow and it can
carry on its generation so when we freq
this plant out it kind of panics and it
goes I don't really know what to do I
may die my hormones are all [ __ ] up
I'm scared of life right now here's what
I'm gonna do and it makes pollen sacks
because it's already got the female
we've got a female plant it's already
got the female sex part so that it can
breed it makes pollen sacks to where now
it's got the part of the breeding that
it was missing now that plan is
self-sufficient
people are gonna say you've got pollen
sacks you've got a hermaphrodite you've
got a male no there are no male
chromosomes present because I have
selected a tried and true solid female
and we have proven that by my stress
testing earlier by messing up the white
schedule by overfeeding it by giving it
too much cold I didn't talk too much
about stress testing but light is the
main way I do overfeed I give it cold I
give it heat give it too much co2 I
don't give it co2 I withhold waterings
stress him out let [ __ ] the guys at
the grow grow them they will stress them
for you and tell you what stresses those
plants out so it is not a hermaphrodite
it is not a male it is not showing
intersex traits this is a female that
has been treated with a chemical that is
now hormonal e reacting by producing
pollen sacks those pollen sacks contain
pollen but the magic part is there are
no male chromosomes within that pollen
there's no male pollen all of the pollen
in here is female our friend mr. soll
made a great analogy he said just
imagine if you put your female plant
here and your pollen donating plant here
in this case it's a reversed female and
we put a filter between them it would
only filter out male pollen that is
basically what we have learned to do by
creating feminized pollen there is no
male pollen no male chromosomes
available in this exchange so now I have
created
female all female pollen eckesachs
pollen there's no wise no males allowed
no boys allowed this is all girls club
in this situation if I have done my
selections properly and I think my track
record shows that I am pretty damn good
at selecting female plants for feminized
seed production so at this point we have
got female or feminized pollen
that is the basic beginning of making
feminised seeds that is where it all
starts it's all about the female pollen
so I've taken silver that I've taken
selected plants made my solution applied
the solution and that silver has created
an ethylene a copper disruption which
created an ethylene response which
triggered the plants to create pollen
sacks that is kind of the short
condensed version but for you guys to
understand that's really all you need to
know if you want to read more I
encourage it because it's really fun
learning about hormones and ethylene and
plants you'll really open up your mind
to learning more so at this point we
have got a female plant that is now
dropping feminized pollen that is the
first half of our breeding combination
remember earlier I said we were going to
take two clones of the same plant now
we've got one it is reversed when we
treat it with the silver thiosulfate and
it starts changing its sex we have now
reversed the sex it's kind of gotten a
sex change but we just call it reversed
to be polite so now we've got the one
reversed plant we've got the remaining
clone that we have not done anything to
it is growing just like it normally
should maybe we've bottomed it and
cleaned it up a little bit maybe you
topped it to get more tops whatever you
want to do to keep that plant growing
happily and healthily now it is time to
put the plants in to flower you've got a
couple of options here things you can do
you can either collect the pollen from
the reversed plant and store it and then
apply it later but what I would prefer
to do is just put that plant in the room
along with the females that are going to
get pollinated so
in this situation you need if since I'm
choosing to put the mail in the plant
with the girls I need to get him
pollinating get him started ahead of
time for the females he's going to take
a while to produce pollen reversed
plants tend to take about two weeks ten
to ten days to two weeks longer to drop
pollen in a standard true male plant a
male plant will start putting out pollen
sometimes day 1012 but hopefully around
day 14 17 he started getting pollen
around 8 23 to 30 you're really
pollinating with a reversed plant I
generally don't get pollen until days 25
to 32 ish sometimes a little bit later
depending on the cultivar and how well I
reversed her sometimes if I'm learning
it'll take a little longer and I
honestly don't get a lot of pollen from
reversed plants that's why they are a
little bit more pricey than the regular
seeds so the normal male plant will
pollinate much earlier the reverse plant
pollinates around day 26 to 35 ish
hopefully somewhere in that area so what
we've got to do is we've got to get him
going in flower and starting to produce
his pollen way before the females here
is a trick that I usually charge money
to tell people but I love you guys
and if you've listened to this this far
you deserve this tip when I am making
feminized seeds the way that I time it
properly I do not put my females in the
flowering chamber until my reversal has
begin to solidly show me some male parts
once I've got some pollen sacks and some
balls popping up and I'm certain that my
reversal is working that's what I'll
move the girls into the flowering room
sometimes if you move them into there
too early
the females miss their peak pollination
point and then it takes too long for
that reversal to start dumping pollen
you get very little pollen you also get
very little pollen reception you get
very little seed production and it is
not worth your time and space I'm a
commercial seed producer I've got to
time it out very well so as soon as I
see that guy not as soon but I know when
when I see the guy making his balls the
girl making her balls I know that that's
[ __ ] gets confusing when he got these
things going on but it's 20/20 we got to
accept this [ __ ] when my female starts
showing her balls I said
that think about that my female plant
starts showing her balls that's when I
move my other females into the room to
receive the pollen now that plants going
to drop pollen onto my girls that
happens just like a male and female the
I guess you can consider the pollen is
the sperm and the pistols and the ovules
are the female parts the ovaries inside
of a lady so we just got to get the jizz
in there so we get the reversed pollen
on to the female plant I keep saying
female because there is no male that's
how we are making feminized seeds
so we're pollinating we have now taken
the pollen from the reversed plant and
put that pollen all over the at the
right time at the appropriate time
somewhere probably around day eighteen
to twenty three twenty five on the
flowering plant is when you want that
pollen to hit day thirty-two is probably
like around when it's way too [ __ ]
late so get it around eighteen twenty
three twenty five somewhere in that area
depending on the cultivar colony now we
have pollinated now this is where we
have two different options of course in
my example I said we're going to use the
same cut so let's talk about that well
we have now done is called selfing a
plan the best way I can say this for you
to remember is that plan just [ __ ]
itself it [ __ ] in itself and it made
clones of itself it didn't make clones
and made seeds of itself I shouldn't
have said clones that's the wrong word
disregard the word clones I'm gonna move
forward it made reproductions of itself
it made offspring progeny of itself we
self that plan there are a lot of
reasons why we could do this and a lot
of benefits um I've got a lot of
favorite plants but I cannot keep every
plant so right now I would like to cycle
a couple of plants out and a couple of
plants in let's just say that I want to
I'm not gonna do it to nobody freak out
let's say I want to get rid of the
grateful dog because I don't have space
I want to get rid of it I want to coal
to plants bring in two more if I want to
get rid of grateful dog but I'm afraid
to lose it forever one thing I could do
is sell fit take two clones make Paul
and put the pollen on the same plant now
I've got self seeds there is no
adulteration of genetics so I have
preserved my grateful dog when I want it
later it's over there in a bag in the
vault all I got to do is grow some seeds
and find the one that I really like
grateful dog is back in the rotation
I've got seeds for preservation so
that is a really good way to preserve
across and not adulterated what do I
mean by adulterating it we want a lot of
people want golden goat seeds but there
is not a golden goat mail available also
here's something I want to touch on
briefly there is no golden go there's no
gorilla glue for male available so if
you say you've got gorilla glue for
seeds and they're regular seeds you do
not that is fake that's not a thing
gorilla glue for was a clone only
phenotype so you cannot have regular
seeds of gorilla glue for there's no boy
it is adulterated there's something else
crossed into it it could be a back cross
it could be a FEM seed GG for purely not
a possibility
golden go purely not a possibility there
was not a male of those released so
nobody's making pure unadulterated seeds
so now we can make unadulterated golden
goat feminized seeds we can make
unadulterated greatful dog feminized
seeds and store them for preservation in
the future also if people want to grow
that golden go they've got a really good
opportunity of getting the phenotype
that they see me post because I haven't
added any other ingredients into the
[ __ ] the recipe it's still golden
goat if I wanted to make seeds of it and
not feminized it I would have to find a
male of something else and now it is
golden go across to whatever not pure
gold and go kind of [ __ ] it up for you
so that is called selfing when you take
one plant reverse it put the pollen on a
cultivar of the same type it's got to be
the same plant golden go to Gold and go
Grateful dog to Grateful dog
whatever that's as far as blueberry
cookies - blueberry cookies now there is
another thing that we do with feminized
pollen we put the feminized pollen on
different cultivars so if I put the
golden goat pollen on Lemon Jeffrey
there on the lemon skunk that makes
lemon Jeffrey golden goat pollen on a
lemon skunk female makes feminized lemon
Jeffrey seeds
that is called a reversal or an r1 that
indicates the difference between selfing
and using the pollen on another plant
what we have done there is we have
created a brand new hybrid we have made
a new line and we didn't have to use a
male plant in that so we've got a
feminized brand new hybrid so instead of
calling it an f1 or an s1 which is what
we would call a self project this is now
an r1 to indicate to my customers and
people reading about it that this is a
reversed feminized cross there was not a
male used it was an R so the S indicates
self and if I say s1 that's the self
first generation if I say R that is the
reversed first generation r1 is a first
generation reversal so I think that
covers the basics of FEM seeds really
quickly important is selection the most
important part is selection select solid
females then make your silver
thiosulfate solution the next important
part is learning the delusions and
application intervals and rates apply
your silver silver thiosulfate then
you've got to time out your males and
females get the mail dump and pollen get
the females ready to receive pollen at
the same time then you've got to
pollinate then everything else if you're
breeding if you're growing seeds
everything else happens just the same as
it did with regular seeds your Rapala
nating just like you are any other crop
um we're going to make self seeds or
we're going to make reversed seeds there
is no reason why you cannot put so if I
wanted to reverse gold and go I can
reverse the golden goat put a clone of
golden goat in the room put a clone of
platinum tangi in the room and put a
clone of lemon skunk in the room and now
I can make golden goat films lemon skunk
our lemon Geoffrey films and also
platinum it's the Sunkist fans I got a
lot of [ __ ] my brain right now I'm
trying to keep it all straight but I can
make three different lines of FEM seeds
from that one golden go reversed plant
and that's why you see me making
multiple crosses the red pill the blue
pill is a golden goat feminized cross
lemon Geoffrey platinum tangi the golden
goat there are several of them the
garlic goat which was kind of rare
that's I've been going out those are all
feminized golden go across
many of them happen in the same room at
the same time I don't have to breed just
golden goat two golden goat I can put
multiple girls in there and make a lot
of great crosses so when I do golden
goats a golden goat just to recap and
keep it in your brain that is a self it
is [ __ ] itself I know that's crass
but you're not gonna forget if I
pollinate anything else with that pollen
that is a reversal and those will both
be feminized and here's where I'm going
to reiterate they are not hermaphrodites
99.9% of the feminized seeds I produce
are true feminized seeds there is 0.1%
that gives me the opportunity for
complaints and error I don't get the
complaints and [ __ ] problems you guys
nobody sends me emails saying I bought
FEM seeds and I've got hermaphrodites or
I've got problems because I feel like my
process first of all I keep reiterating
that selection process I feel like that
process is solid I feel like my reversal
process is solid then here's something
the next step for a breeder for anybody
making FEM seeds here is the next most
important step for you to do you have
got to grow them your self do not give
them to friends do not sell them don't
donate them you may be setting people
you may be giving them [ __ ] dynamite
for their grow room you may have just
given them a big batch of hermaphrodite
seeds if intersex seeds they're gonna
put them in there grow they may not be
experienced growers they're gonna have
it growing you told them feminized
they're not even looking for males then
guess what first day a week three Kapow
everything is pollinated because you
done [ __ ] up so your responsibility as
a breeder a pollen chucker a cannabis
community member somebody who's trying
to help is to grow the seeds you made
yourself grow them see what you've got
if you get one hermaphrodite one
intersex plant out of that batch of
seeds you need to reconsider what you're
going to do do you want to put that out
there to the community one batch of herm
seeds can ruin a seed company's
reputation for the entire future you can
be on top of the world and if you
release one line of Herms you may have
just ruined your seed company for the
rest of your career she'll still sell
some seeds but people will be very
reluctant very hesitant they will
I'm looking at me for my fem seeds
because I've got a better reputation I'm
not trying to brag I'm just saying
that's how he goes I've seen it done in
this industry there's a breeder who was
[ __ ] killing it for several years
putting out Femmes I don't know what
went wrong he got a lot of complaints
about problematic [ __ ] plants now I
don't see him it events I don't see his
booth anywhere he kind of disappeared I
know he's still online selling seeds but
he doesn't go to the events he doesn't
want to put his face out there he would
probably get a long line of people
yelling at him and another line of
people trying to buy seeds so he just
stays at home and clicks on the internet
does his sales that way so be careful it
is your responsibility to make sure that
the seeds you created are worth a [ __ ]
grow them they have to be better or as
good as the parent plant if you're
making self seeds make sure they look
like the [ __ ] plant you're promising
people they're gonna look like you will
see this is a good way to segue into
this you'll see a little bit of
variation we're not introducing another
cross into there but golden goats got
parents it's got a mom it's got a dad
it's got two grandparents on either side
you may see recessive traits you may see
a little bit of variation when it comes
to your Femmes that depends on the
parent plant that you choose to work
with when you're making selfs there will
be little variation hopefully but it is
possible when you're working with the
reversals you are going to see a little
bit of them female and a little bit of
the reversal come through you're gonna
get mostly 50/50 s but you'll find a
really dominant phenotype in that mix so
if you don't make a phenotype that is as
good or better than your starting parent
stock you did not do a successful
breeding project you have not done
anything improving you just [ __ ] made
a copy or you just kind of made a bunch
of seeds you've got to improve cannabis
to call yourself a breed or have a goal
have an intention and make improvement
don't take us backward and the evolution
of cannabis please move us forward and
once again they're not hermaphrodites
there is no if the her word herm is
available in this situation he [ __ ] up
don't breed with Herms don't make herbs
don't sell Herms
if the seeds are hermaphrodites if you
get more than if you grow a hundred and
you get two harms out of there you're
getting 2% and that is beyond the
threshold of allowance for
hermaphroditic seeds you
got to cross that back again get a good
female and then reverse your original
mom and [ __ ] redo it now you've got
like a femme [ __ ] bat cross thing
going on which would it'll work but I
would abandon the project all the way
because that means that there is
hermaphroditism present in that line of
jeans
I wouldn't even [ __ ] with it or maybe at
least try a different phenotype of that
but if you've got a different female why
are you making trims so abandon it that
is my idea don't be ashamed or afraid to
abandon a breeding project it is more ah
admirable respectable to say this batch
of seeds is [ __ ] flush or feed them to
the bunny or whatever you got make hemp
seeds out of it make some seed sprout
tea maybe you can make some [ __ ]
Korean [ __ ] natural farming sort of
stuff out of it but don't sell them
don't give them to people don't expect
people to put that in their gardens
because as a breeder we want to our I
want to I think our job our goal our
purpose our mission ah we should be here
setting people up for success we should
be making cannabis better we should be
making growing easier more enjoyable
more successful more pleasant for our
clientele our customers whatever you
want to call them our [ __ ] friends
our community our family the people that
buy seeds for me keep me alive keep me
afloat they keep [ __ ] food in my
belly and Nikes on my shoes and [ __ ]
they help my kid eat you know what I
mean I got a [ __ ] daughter I got a
drumset addiction I got dabs to smoke so
I really respect and appreciate my
customers my clientele they're my
community they're my friends I don't
want to rip off my friends I would feel
like a [ __ ] bag of a person if I sent
out a batch of seeds and anybody sent me
a message gone bro your seeds [ __ ] up
my garden these seeds you made
hermaphrodite it and put pollen on my
[ __ ] girls and I needed medicine and
I don't have medicine dude I would I
would probably grow a crop for them or
buy them medicine if I did something
like that like that's how bad I would
feel I I [ __ ] feel things ah people
work really hard for their money first
of all they work hard for their money to
buy this seeds seeds are not cheap even
if even if you get them directly from me
at an event they're still expensive
that's several hours at your job slaving
away doing some [ __ ] you didn't want to
do for someone you didn't want to do it
for in a condition you didn't want to be
in I get that I under
stand back so when you give me that
money I want you to have a smile not
just be satisfied with the seeds you got
for the price but you need to be
satisfied with the outcome you've got a
lot to do with it if you're just [ __ ]
pouring redbull and miracle-gro in your
plants don't ask me for help or do ask
me for help I'll [ __ ] help you but if
you [ __ ] them up by doing that that's
your fault but if you get a shitty
outcome on my fault I feel really bad
for it ah I think I made I think that
comes by in my tone of voice and if you
see the show you don't definitely know
I'm sincere so I want people to have
great success with cannabis that's why I
breathe that's why I do the show this
show is free because I want everybody
out there to grow the best ganja they
can we need to medicate we need to write
create we just need to feel good feel i
reinforce honest make sure you're not
making it worse because I'm doing a lot
of work and a lot of our friends a lot
of our cohorts will call them colleagues
may be a better word we're out there
doing our best to make it better so if
you're gonna breed please do your best
to improve on cannabis you guys I feel
like that went by quite quickly it looks
like we're at about 35 30 ish minutes
maybe if I do a couple of edits in here
um I hope I covered everything I hope I
was clear and concise I know I repeated
several things not hermaphrodites FEM
seeds are not my femme seeds are not
made through hermaphrodite um
hermaphroditism there is a method that
some people use old-school dutch methods
we've kind of moved on from that those
companies don't last they're not around
any longer because they weren't
feminizing properly I think we can trust
most of the major companies that are
available now making FEM seeds so part
of my mission here was to dispel the
myth that their Femmes that frustrates
me because I work hard to make quality
films or that their harms are e they are
not Herms I worked very hard to make
quality films and also uh I don't think
that we need to be afraid of feminized
seeds anymore and we need to quit
bashing people who choose to grow FEM
seeds um they are very useful every
plant you grow will be a viable plant if
you get it to fruition if you take care
of it if it germs would probably get
fruits out of it if you're growing reg
seed you got to cut down probably 50 to
60 maybe 70 percent of your [ __ ]
plants before they even get to flower so
there is an advantage if you're in an
area with a limited plant
or if you're in a small tent and you
really rely on everyone if your system
if you've got a six plant setup and you
need all of them those fins are the way
to go you don't want to have an empty
pot empty pots are expensive if you
think about it that pot should be
producing something and if you don't
have something in there you're running
lights you're running your system that
empty pot is costing you whatever you
would have produced so feminize do have
a place
they're not [ __ ] hermaphrodites
please quit saying that I think that's
all I've got for my feminized episode
it's time to wrap it up it sounds like
my voice has given me the same hint so I
want to thank you guys for hanging out
I'm a lot of people ask about where they
can grab my feminized seeds I would
highly recommend seeds here now.com of
course use coupon code in it check out
that will save you 10% if you're getting
a small order that will cover your taxes
if you're getting a big order that will
cover that should help you out quite a
bit at least cover shipping um yeah
seeds here now calm also support the
show on patreon if you feel like this
episode was educational informative or
entertaining I would appreciate your
support on patreon all you have to do is
visit w-w-w dot a tree on.com forward
slash grow from your heart all of the
information you need to sign up on
patreon will be right there once again
big thanks to everybody who supports the
show on patreon thank you you guys are
[ __ ] killing it uh what else do we
got um you can check out the show on
YouTube please visit the show on youtube
go to youtube subscribe to the grill
from your heart podcast click on the
little bell so you get a notification
every time I put out an episode you will
not miss any of my content also check us
out on Spotify Apple podcast stitcher
radio Google Play just about anywhere
any quality podcasts are available
ladies and gentlemen boys and girls
that's all I've got for you for this
episode I want to give a giant shout out
to my friend Gro man Stan and until next
time take a phat dad and give your mom a
hug for me