this episode of the podcast is dedicated
to my friend Zack Hayes happy birthday
bro welcome podcast world it is time for
episode 545 of the grill from your heart
podcast this episode of the show is
brought to you by our friends at seeds
here now.com seeds here now.com carey
seeds from all the industry's leading
breeders including top dog seeds apply
to labs and of course I read genetics
everything at seeds here now.com is
backed by an award-winning satisfaction
guarantee and for my friends on a tight
budget seeds here now.com offers several
packs for under $30 as well as amazing
monthly sales make sure to use coupon
code g fyh 10 while checking out to save
a few bucks
again that is coupon code g fyh 10 while
checking out at seeds here now
dot-com you know I like to start this
podcast off by talking about what I'm
smoking today I've been taking dabs of
sour best lemons live batter from our
friends at Green Dot labs this is a
blend of SBS
E and lemon tree Northern Lights I'm not
sure what SBS e means but it smells
[ __ ] amazing
on the package the flavor is described
as lemons lemons and more lemons
sometimes the descriptions are spot-on
sometimes they're questionable this time
it's [ __ ] lemons times lemons Plus
lemons squared that is accurate
sour best lemons just opening a package
and holding it a few inches from my face
I'm getting lemon candy lemon pledge and
in a stringent lemon punch there's
something real citrusy and kind of sharp
getting to my nose I'm putting it a
little closer it's got a gross delicious
lemon aroma and flavor to it it is
abundant and ridiculously lemon I can't
say lemon Terps enough when it comes to
this concentrate it is delicious when I
take dabs of this it makes my brain spin
around in my head for a minute there's
something about the lemon turf in this
it just makes my brain spin and then the
remaining buzz after that is tremendous
it keeps me nice and talkative on the
back of the package it says it contains
64.6 1% total THC and zero CBD I really
dig this one it is going to be a great
concentrate podcast because it has got
me stoned and rambley and that always
makes for a good
alright ladies and gentlemen in this
episode I am going to talk about a thing
I get asked quite a bit in the last
episode we talked about feminized seeds
so in this episode I'm going to talk
about male selection selecting a male
plant for breeding many of the things I
say when it comes to male plant
selection also applies to reversing a
female plant I'll touch on that a little
bit when it comes to the conversation
before we get there let's do some shout
outs to a few of the friends who support
the show on patreon let's start off with
the big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out to my friend Mason
six-six - I need to send a giant fist
bump and a giant thank you shout out to
my buddy lemur priest bro thank you
again for the giant contribution a giant
fist bump I'm glad I could help you out
thank you for helping me out
let's also send a big giant girl from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to my friend Rasta kay let's also send a
big THANK YOU shutout and a fist month
to grow man Stan I've always got a big
thank you shout out for totally white
tops let's send a big thank you shout
out to smoke what
let's also send a big thank you shout
out to my friend Craig Compton also got
a big thank you for North North Terps
we've always got a big thank you shout
out for Vincent and last but certainly
not least let's send a big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to my friend Shawn 23 big thanks for all
of the support if you're not already
supporting the show on patreon and you
would like to learn how to do so all you
have to do is visit www.opm.gov/life
you're busy just click on that link it
will get you right to patreon it will
make it very easy for you to support the
show while we were talking about patreon
I should make a short announcement a
disclaimer patreon is changing many
things on their service one of the
things they have changed is taxes I
don't understand completely how the
taxes are going to work on patreon it is
a really long thing that I need to read
through and understand before I agree to
anything but it is something that is
going to happen I'm not going to stop
being on patreon I have to pay them
taxes they've got to pay taxes when
money moves Uncle Sam wants a
somebody wants a piece of that pie every
time a pie gets cooked somebody wants a
bite so there will be some things
happening on patreon
you need to read on your contributor and
and I will read on my creator and and we
will read together and be clear of
what's happening on patreon so that
there are no surprises at the beginning
of the month they are making adjustments
while they were making adjustments I
adjusted some of the tiers and benefits
to patreon honestly I was getting a lot
of 420 contributors and people when I
say you contribute 420 they are
expecting a shout-out on the show I had
to raise that tier I moved everything up
one tier because I could not keep up
with the shoutouts I feel like I'm
falling behind so I did increase the
tiers everything moved up by one I will
continue the shoutouts until I am caught
up and then I will change all of that
next month I'll get caught up you'll get
what you paid for but in the future some
of the tiers will increase in price I do
apologize for that it's fair to the
audience because I couldn't keep up with
all of the patreon shoutouts I was going
to fall behind if people were going to
give me money to say their name on the
show it was gonna be 8 episodes before I
can give you a shout out that doesn't
feel fair to me so I've just simply
increased that cost that will
automatically slow down the amount of
shoutouts I have to give maybe
maybe people will pay extra which in
turn that will mean I have to do more
episodes so either way it's gonna work
out for us you guys I don't want anybody
to feel short-changed since patreon
added taxes and I adjusted some things
on patreon I felt that it was my
responsibility to come and be
straightforward about it
I edited some [ __ ] go take a look there
are new tiers available there are new
options and thank you once again for all
the patreon contributions I do
appreciate it you guys that's how I'm
able to keep the show afloat that's how
I'm able to make sure that if this
equipment goes weird I've had to replace
a few pieces of my equipment the
headphone amplifiers they go out quite a
bit I try to make sure to have brand new
microphone covers if anybody it's Co vid
times right now so I don't have guests
here on the show but ah the patreon pays
for the zoom account the website account
my internet connection that is the sort
of stuff we're covering with patreon
plus these little fuzzy microphone
covers so that I'm not spinning into the
same one week after week so that if Mike
comes over Jesse comes over they're not
spinning into the same one anybody you
have on the show gets a freshie I don't
like to recycle those I've had a couple
of pieces of equipment
take a [ __ ] on me we've replaced that
with patreon contributions this computer
the old MacBook started making funny
noises and I couldn't render video on
that thing anymore I cleaned it out I
refurbished it as many times as I could
handle it was frustrating it was making
the show not as fun and easy to produce
so I used patreon contributions to
upgrade I've got a fresh computer this
was about a year maybe two years ago but
I've got a good firing up computer that
works very well we're on zoom right now
I'm recording via zoom it's way easy for
me to record and edit using zoom that's
the Tech Talk you don't care about but
that's really easy using the new
computer so the patreon contributions
are what keep the show moving smoothly
also sometimes you may help me out
getting the extra for a gram jar so that
I can get nicely baked and produce a
really good podcast I think I do a good
job on a nice and stone some people and
they don't work super well when you get
them high I've had some people that I've
worked with them and I've taken him to
lunch and allegedly given them a couple
of dabs and I've had to take them back
to work and set them and a chair and
tell them sit there and no [ __ ] moved
you're gonna break something it might be
you or it might be some equipment but
don't touch anything something will get
hurt today some people like myself and
like white Mike and like most of the
crew that hangs out we take a couple of
dabs and we are able to function so I
think keeping me stocked up with good
dads and good equipment will keep this
podcast going boy that turned into a
long [ __ ] ramble about patreon ah
thank you that's the bottom line there
will be changes uh and I'm not trying to
abandon you or insult you or pull a fast
one on you I edited some [ __ ] so go take
a look if you're contributing on patreon
check out what I did I simply moved the
scale over one for most of the lower
level tiers if you're thinking you're
gonna get a shout out for 420 now
there's 710 if you thought you're gonna
get your message read for 710 now that's
$10 just trying to keep up with myself
so that I can provide the things I'm
promising and not fall far behind that's
part of why I'm doing that all right
thank you guys let's move forward I said
that we were going to talk about male
selection Oh before we get there um I
also mentioned I am looking for music
for the podcast and I've mentioned that
I'm willing to pay and or trade or
compensate on artists and/or musician or
a group for some music I've gotten a
couple of wonderful submissions and
contributions I've gotten so many that
honestly I can't sort through all of
them right now and check which one I
like the best a couple of them got my
attention there's one guy that sent me
like three or four options
I kind of like your style bro but keep
them coming because I can use intros I
can use outros I can use mid show stuff
I could be playing music right now if I
had a cool little just something subtle
it's not too much behind me just a
baseline or reggae drumbeat maybe some
chucking if you're a musician you know
what kind of Chuck and I'm looking for
ah but keep the great music submissions
coming I will go through them I've got a
long appointment to get my dreadlocks
worked on ah this week and I intend to
take an earbud and just put that on
while they're working on my dreads and
listen to a bunch of [ __ ] answer a bunch
of emails while I'm sitting in the chair
I paid for three hours to sit in a chair
and get my dreads twisted on also random
side note a listener or a viewer on
YouTube asked to see my dreadlocks bro
these dreads are a [ __ ] mess right
now
I've been in quarantine I can't get them
maintained I can't get them loved on I
can't work on him on the top of my head
very well by myself by the time I record
another episode maybe two I will have
been to the dreadlocks salon I have a
very good dread stress I don't know what
to call her she's a very wonderful
person she does a really good job
working on dreadlocks she's gonna do a
great job fixing on my dreads after that
I'll bust out the dreads and show you
what they look like ah they're a [ __ ]
mess right now they're real long they go
past my knees it's tremendous but it's
worth waiting for let me get them fixed
up that was random what else we'll be
talking about here music has come in
dreadlocks breeding update this is where
we are um I like to share with you guys
what is happening in my grow if you've
been following along you know that
recently I acquired some Jack the Ripper
seeds you know that I found a beautiful
Jack the Ripper male within that pack of
seeds then you also know I found a
couple of select Jack the Ripper females
they are in a room they are successfully
pollinated the pistols have curled up
the pistols are brown
it looks like seeds are developing there
are a few others select females in that
room um there's a golden goat I think
I've revealed that there is of course I
put on a rise and there I've got to
pollinate the arise with the Jack the
Ripper what would I be doing if I didn't
take one of Subs best maker made
creations one of his best breeders and
put that's one of my most known
creations that was kind of the idea of
the project across those two together
that was the initial idea then of course
I loaded the room up with a few others I
think I've revealed a couple on other
episodes excuse me I'm trying not to
burp into the microphone here I feel
like I've revealed a couple of the
other strains I in other episodes
there's a golden goat there's an arise
what else should we talk about today I'm
going to post a photo of it so there is
a blueberry cookies female that has been
pollinated by Jack the Ripper that will
be very promising both of those strains
of a very beautiful shape a very
beautiful structure create aromas
tremendous buzz this should be a winner
are there a couple other things in there
maybe I'll trickle out more names more
ideas as the show goes by also I've said
this before everyone's gonna ask me for
testers chill out bro they're they're
just being made the seeds are just
forming within the calyxes I can see the
calyx is swelling up with seeds just
getting going so be patient I've said
that before
I need several weeks several several
weeks they've got probably four to five
more weeks to go chop them down harvest
we've been over this I'm not gonna
repeat all that but be patient testers
will be coming what I do like is
excitement and eagerness for names what
do we call Jack the Ripper two blueberry
cookies what do we call Jack the Ripper
two golden goat if you've got name ideas
I would love to see them you can send
them to me um
a great way to do it would be to just
send them to me on an email at grow from
your heart at hotmail.com
or leave them in the comments on the
YouTube video I would love to see
comments of strain names in the YouTube
video so it would be a blueberry cookies
female pollinated by a Jack the Ripper
male a golden goat female pollinated by
a Jack the Ripper male um and that's as
far as we'll go we'll just go for those
two now if you got name ideas throw them
in the comments in a future episode I
will talk about how I choose stray names
because I'm sure you've noticed I've
been a little bit of a theme a schema an
idea around my strain names they aren't
all consistent but you can see where my
mind is where my brain is and if you
can't I'll talk more about that in the
future all right now so in my breeding
ten I've got that going on I think now
it is time to talk about selecting male
plants for breeding cannabis I think the
most important part about selecting
plants for breeding is having a goal
sure maybe you grew some seeds and you
ended up with the male and a female and
he thought I'll breed that's fun that
will work you're gonna have success
you're going to make seeds the question
is are those seeds worth a [ __ ] if
you're just a hobby grower if you're
looking to supply yourself with some
seeds to play with that's a beautiful
project have fun doing that there's
nothing wrong with that
if you want to be a little more serious
about it if you're somebody like myself
who is putting seeds out for a market my
seeds are available at seeds here
now.com they're available at several
other vendors so I need to make sure
that my seeds are reliable that they
have a reliable outcome that they have a
good germination rate I need to have a
goal in mind when I'm making seeds
otherwise you're just pollen chucking
which is fine if that's your goal if you
want to [ __ ] around it we're not all
setting out to be professionals at
everything we do some people just want
to have a little fun making some seeds
growing seeds doing it over again your
self sustainable that way it's a
beautiful project but if you really want
to walk down and get into the breeding
game if you really want to get serious
about breeding there are a few major
steps you need to take first of all I
really recommend I didn't write this
down this is off the top of my head
something I thought I should include
read some books there is a lot of
knowledge just hidden in pages of books
and it's mostly free you can get a lot
of books available in PDF form on the
internet now if you type in breeding
books by Greg Greene or Mel Frank or
Robert Connell Clarke any of those books
will be filled with enough knowledge to
blow your mind and make you a decent
breeder decent a well-educated person
who could have a good idea of breeding a
lot of those books give you a lot of
wonderful ideas but you have to do this
[ __ ] to actually understand it then once
you've read some books about breeding
read about a lleol charts and Mendel
charts understand what Gregor Mendel had
in mind understand what his goal was
understand what he was doing that will
really give you more intuition on
breeding so read some books about
breeding read about Mendel charts read
understand aliens understand chromosomes
understand the basic biology of plants
that will really give you a head start
then once you understand all of that
stuff and it comes time to breed forget
all of that [ __ ] and go with your
intuition and take two plants that you
know are going to make a positive
outcome I know that sounds like a lot of
silly steps cuz I just told you learn a
bunch of [ __ ] then forget it I am a
musician I'm a trained musician this is
a side rant that will make what I'm
saying relevant I understand how to read
and write music I can read a chart and
play it while I'm reading it I can turn
the page with one hand and keep the
groove going and keep playing I'm not
bragging about my musical skill I'm
saying I'm so comfortable at reading a
chart
that I can play it very well when it
comes concert time we don't take the
charts we don't take the music that's
embarrassing you got to remember the
songs on stage you don't see any of
whatever your favorite band is they
don't have music on stage that are
rocking so I learned the music
I studied the music I've got a very deep
understanding of what each note means in
that song it's so engrained in my heart
that when I get on stage it's intuitive
and I don't make the wrong decisions
because I've got the proper training for
my instincts and my education take over
and the music comes out honestly
sometimes I [ __ ] up on stage but that's
the beauty of music sometimes you can
fall on your face and nobody gets hurt
you hope to catch the one when it comes
back around and you keep [ __ ] going
so now I compare that to breeding read
all your books get a solid education
have a solid foundation and then get out
there and freestyle when the time comes
and it should come out beautifully grow
from your heart breed from your heart
things will come out successfully but
have some sort of education and
understanding what you're doing so with
all of that being said we need to have a
goal when we are breeding what is your
goal and the goal and the traits you
were seeking have a lot to do with the
male plant you select for your breeding
project your male plant is going to
contribute at least 50% of his stuff to
your breeding project so if you're
making a cake the male is 50% of your
ingredients you got to have good [ __ ] to
start with or this cake will never taste
good so let's talk about some good
traits that we want to find in a male
plant the only way to find these traits
is to grow the male plants you've got to
get some seeds ah get a population of
seeds I don't know how many seeds you've
got I recommend a lot if you can grow a
lot grow a lot a minimum of 10 if you're
looking for a male a lot more if you've
got the space the time and the legal
means to do so so grow a bunch of seeds
then we're gonna select a male out of
that population of seeds how are we
going to select a male right away I
don't want so if we take 10 plants we
pop 10 seeds let's just say 10 it's easy
to get your hands on a 10 pack of seeds
a 12 pack a lot of breeders offer that
at a fair price so you've got a 10 pack
of seeds we grow them out most likely
we're gonna find at a 10 we're going to
find somewhere between four and six
males we're gonna remove the females
from the room that's another grow that's
another episode that's another strategy
do whatever you want with that party or
brain right now I'm gonna play with the
males in this grow room I've got four to
six males the first one that shows me
it's a male is probably not going to be
a breeding male the one that is the
tallest and the stretchy ax stand the
proudest to get up there is probably not
going to be my breeding male sometimes
they're the same plant sometimes those
are the first two males that I get rid
of and I'll tell you why they don't
qualify a minute ago I said I want my
male to be 50% of my breeding mix those
big boys they get too big right away
those guys that start to pollinate
immediately in my opinion they dominate
the recipe too much and they don't show
enough of the female that I use in my
crosses when I do breeding so let's say
we took this male and I put it on a
strawberry fields plant we're gonna say
that I took a chocolate plant I'm just
picking two things that are different
chocolate and strawberry when I breed
those my goal is chocolate strawberry
right I mean as a hypothetically as a
breeder I'm partly cheffing this I want
chocolate strawberry if my male plant is
too dominant in his genes if he's too
[ __ ] or if we got a big caveman
that's at the gym all the time that guy
is going to over dominate my mix and I'm
gonna make more chocolate I'm not gonna
get enough strawberry out of there it's
gonna look like this guy and maybe if
that's what you were looking for as a
breeder maybe that's a success but
that's not what I started out for so I
want to find a male did flowers a little
bit later I want to find a male that
doesn't show me flower right away and
doesn't get real tall immediately the
reason the males are getting super tall
is so they can get up above the canopy
and drop pollen down on all of the
females and they can be the dominant
male that wins the group and there are
generations get to continue so I don't
choose the first or second male it will
show me flower now we had somewhere
between four and six now we're down to
about four or two maybe three males left
to play with I'm going to watch these
guys grow I don't want any weirdo plants
if I've got a weirdo plant that's doing
in veg doing weird shapes weird
structures that's not going to set
myself up for success in future breeding
I don't want more weirdo [ __ ]
he's got to go just think about it like
people if you see people out there
unfortunately if you see some weirdo
can people walking around scratching
their head yelling at the [ __ ]
telephone pole you don't want to breed
with them if you see people that look
like they got their [ __ ] together their
body is in line they're healthy or
[ __ ] smiling they got a good
presentation you want to breed with them
right plants should be the same way if
you're looking at a plant going I don't
know things kind of [ __ ] up you don't
want to breed with that why do you want
to continue that gene we're looking to
make more tents we don't want to make a
bunch of [ __ ] sixes there are six is
out there your goal is to take maybe a
six and a seven and make them into a ten
or make two eights into an eleven you
got to improve when you're breeding so I
don't want weirdos I don't want mutants
I don't want problematic plants we'll
talk about problems in in a moment but I
want something a male plant that isn't
the tallest not the first to flower and
doesn't show me any weird growth if he's
got problems from the beginning if he
was a struggler I may not use that one
I don't need struggles in my offspring
so before we get too far make sure or I
recommend to take a male or take a clone
of your male plants before we go into
flower I found a really great male I
call him King Solomon I've also got a
Jack the Ripper male that I'm playing
with he doesn't have a name I just call
it Jack the Ripper male I have got
clones of them so that when I make
successful crosses with these I can use
them again and again and again because
I'll keep cloning and having a father
plant same as a mother plant but it's a
dude I'll have that plan around for
continued production so I can keep
producing pollen from him and keep
making more successful crosses so I
recommend that you get a clone of your
favorite male now here are things to
look for traits that we want to seek in
our male the shape and the structure do
you want squat and bushy plants do you
want tall and skinny plants do you want
plants that make one main cola because
that is an option if you're running a
whole bunch of plants on a table and you
just want to turn them in burn them you
can put 64 plants on a four by four
table they grow up to make one main
stock you flip them real early
you get sixty for ten grand buds it's
640 grams from one light not bad at all
in my opinion you can breed plants to do
that do you want tall plants do you want
skinny plants do you want bushy plants
do you want big wide leaves do you want
little skinny leaves you can breed that
into your plants it's all about the
selection that you make with your
parents you want branchy and sturdy
plants do you want brand
in sturdy plants I want branchy plants
with lots of good structure close
internodal spacing nice beefy branches
that will hold up big buds I want male
plants that are going to make big fat
male clusters that will translate to big
female buds when it comes down to the
progeny in the future so something I
don't like is a hollow plant if I've got
a male plant and I top it and that
sinner is hollow you can feel them when
you're working with them I can look at
them and see them from across the room I
do not select a hollow male plant that
is just something I don't like I prefer
it to not be the Super Hollow plant so
all about the structure and the leaf
shape do you want short squatty plants
do you want big branchy plants some
people I like those taller longer branch
to your plants I get a lot more
production out of them I work in
commercial groves where we trellis I'm
gonna work them around I can manipulate
those plants to give me a lot of flowers
so it's all about what you want find a
male that represents the structure you
would like to recreate because that male
is going to give at least 50% of its
structure to the offspring so keep that
in mind
also think about odors aromas what does
it smell like it's only going to be half
of the mix and keep in mind think about
when you grow plants and veg you rub the
stem it smells kind of weird but when
you dry and cure it it doesn't smell
like that but there is consistency in
the way those aromas change if it smells
like puke when you're rubbing the stem
it's gonna have gassy skunky aromas for
the end of flower if it smells like
sweet feet and berries it's gonna smell
like fruit and blueberries and [ __ ]
toward the end of flower these are just
things that you'll experience as you go
along I like to rub the stems I like a
male personally that smell smells a
little bit like puke I know it sounds
horrible but they make great breeders I
like a male plant that when I rub the
stem early in veg or late and veg it
smells a little bit like the bar trash
can that fermented funky disgustingness
always translates into a good breeding
male in my opinion also a little bit of
sweetness a little bit of CAM and a
little bit of skunk I love that male
plant for breeding it's going to make
wonderful [ __ ] offspring but that is
my goal maybe you want something that is
the complete opposite maybe you want
something that smells like peaches
maybe you want something that smells
like watermelons I don't know what
you're into find the one that works for
you that is a big part of breeding a lot
of breeding is science I talked about
read all the books learn all the charts
do all that [ __ ] then I said forget it
all because that is where it comes to an
art form also we are making a lot of
decisions they have to be educated but
they also have to be artful with a goal
there are a lot of things to keep in
mind you guys so we're talking about
aromas let's talk about colors I really
like a colorful male plant if your male
plant is making purple he's probably
going to make purple offspring if that
male plant is making reds and golds and
oranges and you've got to let them
flower a little while a lot of people
cut down the male plants way too early
let them go seven eight nine weeks see
what you've got there because that's
when you're gonna see the true traits of
that male plant you'll see colors that
you never ever imagined would be
produced by that male plant when he cut
it down at week five and six you know
when you start flushing your females
they start turning gold they get the
yellow on the outside of the leave they
get the red and the orange down the
center of the leaves they start making
beautiful purples and [ __ ] your male
plants will do that and if you don't
give them the opportunity to grow that
long you'll never ever know it so look
for colors reds pinks purples different
shades of greens what do you like some
of those different colors will translate
in the offspring you may get 25% of your
offspring may show that color maybe 50%
maybe up to 75% of your offspring will
have that color depending on the traits
of the female depending it out dominant
and recessive that trait is so look for
colors off you've got something that
puts off some Purple's it is very very
good to breed with that plant in my
opinion if purple is what you're going
for here is something you should really
look for if one of your male plants is
putting off trichomes that's a bad
[ __ ] you should use him in
breeding the male plant is putting off
tracks that's kind of it's not rare but
it's not super common you'll find that
in about three out of ten keepers
they'll put off trichomes if you've got
a boy that's putting off resin the
female that he pollinates will put off
resin the seeds I mean the seeds that
come from that they will put off resin
if you got a good resin producing female
and a good resin producing male you put
those together guess what double resin
you just made a double resin oreo right
there so if you've got a trichome to
male use that guy
because it is going to work very well in
my opinion something else we should
think about when it comes to selecting a
male plant is flowering time how long
let's also talk about veg time how did
the plant grow in veg did it explode
with growth was it slow and shitty and
lanky was it problematic that he give
you any issues did it need support too
early or the stalks nice and robust but
we should think about flowering time and
veg vegetables did this plant keep up
did it was at smaller was it bigger was
it average think about that then when he
put it into flower how did it react how
long did it take to show you that it was
a male did it try to show you that it
was a male way before you flowered it it
had become rootbound and started putting
off male flowers
I would not breed with that so think
about flowering time how long from the
time you induced flower to the time you
started seeing male parts then how long
until those male parts started opening
up then how long until peak pollination
time pay attention to that stuff because
that is going to correlate and relate to
the flowering time of your offspring
that's why I like to let the males go
for quite a while 7 8 maybe 9 or 10
weeks if that male plant keeps growing
and stays nice and healthy and keeps
getting huge towards 8 or 9 weeks your
offspring could take eight or nine maybe
ten or eleven weeks so pay attention to
that male plant grow it out I know a lot
of breeders and a lot of growers do not
grow out male plants far enough to see
what they've got to work with so please
do that try it you may be amazed at what
you see how long does it keep spinning
out pollen as a breeder it's got to spit
out if you're gonna breed commercially
and put the seeds out it's got to spit
out enough pollen to make it worth your
time that's why feminized seeds are so
damn expensive when you reverse a plant
you've got to be very careful about how
you do it and you don't get near as much
pollen as you do from a well selected
male plant so that's a big difference
there make sure you're getting enough
pollen how long does it continue to spit
out pollen and do you get enough pollen
to make it worth your breeding time
let's talk about issues things that
would make me not select a male plant I
mentioned before a hollow plant I don't
like a hollow a male plant I don't like
a slow shitty grower if it takes a long
time to veg if it's got issues if it
doesn't handle some abuse I'm not gonna
breed with it if it's weak and spindly
it cannot hang out also I mentioned
earlier if it's too robust if it's too
dominant if we got [ __ ] Hulk Hogan or
The Ultimate Warrior in there I may not
choose that one for breeding so I'm just
gonna make a bunch more Ultimate
Warrior's bunch more Hulk Hogan's a
bunch more testosterone ridden [ __ ]
super beasts that's not what I'm looking
for also does this male plant respond
well to feeding and pH issues I kind of
abused my pill mail plants a lot like I
do the females feed them poorly see how
they react [ __ ] up the pH see how they
react see if they get p.m. see if they
are attracted to pests some plants the
bugs just love to come around as soon as
you start growing some plants the spider
mites go what's that new smell Larry
this thing smells good let's go invade
and they all go get it so see if it
brings bugs something I mentioned
earlier does it auto flower does
anything cause this male plant to go
into flower before you have flipped the
lights to 1212 if it got a little bit
rootbound and decided to Auto flower
don't breed with it
if it got a little bit um underfed and
it decided to go flower on you get rid
of it don't breed with it if it's
autoflowering on you that is going to
continue over into the progeny and your
customers will not be happy like I said
earlier if you're breeding for yourself
you can do whatever you want as long as
you were aware of what could happen you
were making your own creations you're
not gonna share them with anybody but if
you're putting them out to market they
need to be reliable they need to be more
consistent let's make sure I'm still
recording because my computer just did
some weird [ __ ] not even gonna edit this
out yeah we're still going we're cool
all right I just got a notification I've
got my notifications turned off so that
was whack but you didn't hear it we'll
keep moving I apologize for the
distraction where are we
auto flower you don't want one that auto
flowers another thing to think about is
were there problematic plants within
that seed stock did you grow out females
and find problems in the females because
it's most likely that you grew a
population of girls you were looking for
that keeper what you see in those girls
was there a hermaphrodite were there
intersex traits amongst the female
population which you found from the same
seed pack if so that gives me a little
suspect a little question a little
apprehension to breed with that plant
that tells me there is an
sex treats within the seed line
somewhere in that DNA it is possible I
don't know that I want to pass that it
could be a recessive trait it could be a
dominant trait it may pop up in the next
generation it may pop up two generations
from now it may not pop up at all I
don't know that I would set myself up
with that time bomb that's kind of a
problem waiting to happen so were there
problems in the rest of the seed stock
did you have any trouble or they're
hermaphrodites where they're freaks
where they're mutants in the other seed
stock that's just something to keep in
mind is a breeder that's something I
like to think about I also really like
to know the parents of my breeding stock
like I know what made King Solomon I
made King Solomon and I know what made
the parents that made those parents so I
know far down the line I know the
grandparents of my breeding stock I know
the great-grandparents of some of my
wines that are out so I just really like
to know what's going on then I there are
many surprises then I have less I've got
the more data you have the less
surprises you're going to have is what I
think I'm trying to say so um where are
we now in my list Herms
pollen II the next step to do I think is
to select qualifying females um briefly
females that are not hermaphroditic
females that are not problematic females
that are resistant to pests and problems
and pathogens and molds and mildews and
issues plants that can take a beating
plants that you've got a goal for
breeding them to UM maybe you just want
to make some new seeds but if you notice
in my breeding I am using things that
are very dominant in flavors and then
I'm using a male that is very dominant
in potency so I put my potent male on
flavorful Oh terrific
oder river as females and I get potent
and tur P plants out of that so select
quality females then pollinate earlier I
mentioned that a lot of this talk would
work on a reversed plant as well if
you've got a female that fits this
criteria that grows well has a good
structure doesn't hermaphrodite smells
great branches sturdy has the node
spacing in the shape and leaf structure
you're looking for you can reverse that
that is a very good candidate for making
a candidate for making feminized seeds
make sure it's not a hermaphrodite beat
it up abuse it stress it light stress it
in the last episode I talked about how I
stress test my femme seeds my female
plants we
or I make femme seeds do that see if it
homes if it doesn't give you any issues
that plant will work very well as a
pollen donor plant to be reversed so
we've got our male or we've got our
reversal our next step is to get the
plants to the right stage and pollinate
the females are going to need to be
around day 18 23 25 depending on the
cultivar I've got one plant that wants
pollen like 27 day 30 sometimes so it's
all about the female when her pistols
are nice and ripe when she's ovulating
and wants to get pollinated the male
plant depends on the male plant you've
selected probably around day 14 17 21 up
to day 32 wish you're gonna be getting
pollen pollinate um keep documentation
of palling pollination times write down
when the pollen starts I flipped on day
one on day seven I saw male sacks on day
12 pollen was coming out write that down
then write down peak pollination time
when did this plant really start dumping
pollen then also if you can keep it
around long enough document when the
plant stopped dumping pall and that's
also important to know your window how
long do I get to make pollen so document
that then also document the day you
pollinate your plants so that you know
how long you've got to grow these plants
and how long those seeds take to develop
the more data the more success you will
have in the future you can set patterns
and you can set expectations and you can
make corrections based on your data
write down a lot of [ __ ]
so get your females at their peak point
for pollination pollinate them um it's
very easy if you don't do much the male
will pollinate the room on his own if
you've got a fan in there every night
his [ __ ] flower is open up in pollen
II because this little dust the pollen
fly out everywhere if you haven't
pollinated everything already turn off
the fans take that male to the center of
the room and just shake him and it's
[ __ ] it'll be ridiculous if you've
got a nice male there will be a lot of
pollen and there you're gonna have to
clean yourself up you're gonna get green
boogers from all the pollen you'll
sneeze for a couple of days it's well
worth it so we have pollinated continue
to feed the seeds of feed the plants as
normal I don't give them big bloom
boosters I reduce the bloom boosters I'm
not trying to make big fat buds I
increase my Cal mag a little bit I
continue with nitrogen and I do add a
little bit of amino
assets when I'm making seeds amino acids
are really good for starting life and
getting those seeds nice and healthy I
also make sure to just take really good
care of the plants overall their overall
health is really important make sure
their pH stand fed and watered and D
foliated and [ __ ] love for properly
and you'll have happy seeds I do a few
other tricks that I've talked about in
other episodes but we're not gonna delve
too far into that we're gonna keep
talking about selecting a male so now
the seeds are ready for harvest right
time goes on we've got seeds we chop em
to cut them the next important thing to
do is to grow these seeds we don't know
if this male plant we have selected is
worth the [ __ ] until we grow these seeds
and I'm gonna branch off some people are
going to want to try multiple male
plants to the same female plant for
breeding I don't like that idea I
honestly don't see a way that you're
going to stop pollen from male plant a
and male plant B and male plant C from
cross contaminating your female plants
so when you grow the offspring you never
know which male plant was the champion
you just wonder who - baby daddy and you
don't know which male plant to breed
with again and it's kind of a waste of
time in my opinion pick one male plant
breed with him at a time that is my
advice in my opinion I think I've been
successful and so my words may may have
some way that may show I've been
successful with that advice you guys
it's all I'm saying but run this run the
seeds that you've grown you've got a
batch of seeds from either one female or
multiple females run them see what
you've got
check the germination rate how many
seeds if you can germinate ten of them
how many pops when you put them in your
germination method did you get nine out
of ten you get eight out of ten or are
you champion all ten germinated check
that out German germination rate is very
important then grow them watch them grow
but they look like [ __ ] mutant plants
that they look like they're gonna have
struggles the entire time do they look
like good plants flower them do they
make good buds are the plants that you
just created better than both of the
parents that you started with because if
not there's no point in continuing this
line unless it is doing something
magical for you and you smoke it if you
feel perfect keep it but the goal is to
improve upon the two lines that we
started with so you've got to grow them
out look
hermaphrodites look for intersex traits
look for problems are there mutants is
it worth the [ __ ] does it take to long
to flower are they very inconsistent are
they very uniform you can have positive
and negative things to document at this
time but we've got to be sure that we
have improved on the quality of the line
of cannabis that is our main goal here
as a breeder if you haven't made it
better there's no point in breeding so
you either need to excuse me you either
need to f2 these seeds to make them
better or abandon the project altogether
if you're giving them out let your
friends know hey these aren't the best
seeds that I've ever made but they are
free so you can have them you can give
them away you can share them but set the
expectation when you give them away
don't say these are [ __ ] amazing
seeds go hey these are they're okay
they're good I mean be honest with
yourself
I have made some okay seeds you don't
see them at any of the vendors because
they are okay I only put out the champs
and if they don't show to be champs
after I put them out for a while if I
don't see a lot of great success
I will discontinue them for sales and I
will give them away as freebies I'll
pass them out to my friends if you stop
by the booth when I'm out somewhere in
public and you say hey what's up maybe
I'll just pass you a pack of them for
freebies but I don't sell them I don't
make a profit off of the bees or the
nines I put out tens in eleven you guys
and that should be your goal as well as
a cannabis breeder
if you're listening on audio I apologize
I just took a long drink I was getting
real dry if you're watching the video
big up thank you for sticking with me
all right so the main important part is
have a goal have something in mind do
you want to make indica dominant plants
do you want to make sativa dominant
plants are you aiming for a certain
cannabinoid are you aiming for a certain
terpene are you aiming for a certain
growth structure what is your goal have
a goal in mind when you're crossing
select a male it will fit your criteria
for your goal I understand we don't all
have unlimited seeds find something that
works the best out of the pack of seeds
you've got pay attention for dominant
traits or positive traits pay attention
for negative traits decide if that's the
plant you want to breed with do the work
breed with it Chuck bat [ __ ]
pollen let those plants have their
action then you've got to grow the seeds
that is where the real test of your work
comes in see if your progeny if your
offspring if your children are worth a
[ __ ] or if you just need to get rid of
that mail and start all over again
that's not a bad decision that is a very
respectable and reputable decision if it
doesn't work it doesn't work
get rid of it don't do that some things
just won't work that is the way the
numbers work sometimes you get amazing
crosses sometimes you get a whole bunch
of [ __ ] so it's all up to you it's
all about your goal ah try your best to
reach your goal and if you don't reach
your goal don't be afraid try try again
like I said before when we're growing me
when we're growing plants when we're
playing music if we crash and [ __ ] up
the best part is you don't get hurt it
may cost time and money but you get to
get up and try it again alright I think
that concludes my mail selection podcast
episode if I left anything out if you've
got any more questions I do encourage
feedback questions criticism send it my
way you can leave it in the YouTube
comments if you'd like to be more adult
about it you can send me an email grow
from your heart at hotmail.com is the
email address I do look forward to
hearing from you also if you've got
questions concerns Corrections or if
you've got something to say that is the
email address again grow from your heart
at hotmail.com I look forward to hearing
from you alright ladies and gentlemen
boys and girls pimps and hos friends and
foes clone cutters Colin chuckers all
you bad [ __ ] out there I want
to thank you guys again for listening to
another episode of the grow from your
heart podcast if you feel like this
episode was educational informative or
entertaining and you would like to make
a financial
to the show you can do so by visiting
www.hsn.com right after this episode I
believe so all the new [ __ ] will happen
by right after this episode comes out so
with the first there will be new changes
on patreon don't be surprised I've got
to read about it you read about it too
so we're both well informed and again
thank you for the support
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart also make sure you visit our
sponsors at seeds here now calm and use
coupon code wih 10 that is the letters G
fyh and the number 10 to save yourself
10 percent at seeds here now dot-com
also I encourage you to follow the show
on YouTube you may be listening on a non
on an audio format at this time I just
want to remind you I am putting the
shows out on YouTube I would appreciate
it if you come join me on YouTube come
check out my smiling face ah sometimes I
get mic on here sometimes I got some
other folks come see what we look like
join us on YouTube simply search for the
girl from your heart podcast click
subscribe click on that little bell that
will let you know every time I put out a
new episode you can see a new episode
and not miss a thing
also I apologize for Spotify I'm putting
all of the episodes in Spotify sometimes
they don't allow some episodes to go up
it goes up on iTunes it goes up on
stitcher I don't know why Spotify is
blocking some of my episodes I do
apologize once again every episode is
available on YouTube I do my best to get
everything there on the YouTube channel
alright ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls that is all I've got for you for
this episode my throat is dry it's time
to get high on a thank you for hanging
out I'll be back in a couple of days
with fresh new content I'm gonna send a
giant giant shout out to my buddy Lemur
Priest and until next time take a phat
dad and give your mom a hug for me