yeah welcome to the show podcast world
I'm your host Rasta Jeff and it is time
for episode 546 of the girl from your
heart podcast this episode of the show
biz brought to you by my friends at
seeds here now.com seeds here now.com
offers seeds from all of the industry's
leading breeders including Melvin etics
Duke diamond genetics
miss Jill and of course I read genetics
everything at seeds here now.com is
backed by an award-winning satisfaction
guarantee and from my friends on a tight
budget seeds here now.com offers several
packs for under $30 as well as amazing
monthly sales make sure to use coupon
code Chen while checking out to save a
few bucks
again that is coupon code GFY h10 while
checking out at seeds here now
dot-com you know I like to start this
podcast off by talking about what I'm
smoking today I've been taking dad's of
headbanger live batter from Green Dot
labs this is a blend of Sour Diesel IBL
and biker Kush on the package the flavor
is described as sour and fuel they
should have followed that up with
[ __ ] delightful I love the flavor of
this concentrate the sour the fuel it is
perfect it's funky it's delicious and
when I dab it I get goofy high from this
concentrate I'm gonna crack the jar open
and let you see what it looks like that
was the four gram jar of manna for my
way about halfway through you can see
that's a beautiful golden texture nice
and smooth beautiful color I really
enjoy the live batter from our friends
at Green Dot labs on the back of the
package it does say the product contains
sixty three point nine seven percent
total THC and non-detectable CBD once
again big shout-out to our friends at
Green Dot labs for the delicious and
tremendous headbanger live batter
all right podcast roll they do have a
fun show lined up for you before we get
there let's do some shoutouts to a few
of our friends on patreon I do need to
remind you that they have started adding
taxes to patreon I don't think any of
the things I offer on patreon are
taxable since all the things I give you
as patreon tiers as rewards our
they're all like thank yous and
shoutouts and I read your question I
don't think those things will be taxable
it is based on your location not my
location is based on where you are when
you contribute to patreon I tried to
adjust all of the tiers to keep things
tax free I also have to be honest and
legal I did my best to keep it the same
for everybody I did however increase the
price of a few tiers I did talk about
this on a previous episode I just want
to talk about it again because this will
take effect by the time this episode
comes out there are new tiers on patreon
I moved everything up I was getting I
make promises that if you contribute to
my patreon I will do things for you to
say thank you I was getting overwhelmed
I'm not complaining I love the support I
loved the contributions but I wasn't
able to keep up with my end of the
agreement people were contributing they
were not getting their shoutouts and
their questions read to slow that down I
raised the prices normally when you
raise prices you sell less of something
ah hopefully you guys just continue you
keep sending me the extra funds that
will result in me doing extra podcasts
I'm already trying to find scheduling
time and energy to do another show every
week so there will be some changes in
the patreon and there may be changes
coming up in the podcast if the patreon
continues to kick ass the way that it
has been thank you guys for the kick-ass
patreon contributions I am stone and
rambley once again shout out to our
friends at green dye labs for the
delicious headbanger live batter
it's [ __ ] working alright now here's
the part where we are going to do some
shoutouts I have invented a new club
ladies and gentlemen this is the 710
club the following folks have
contributed seven dollars and ten cents
is a monthly contribution to the patreon
campaign so welcome to the 710 club
ladies and gentlemen let's give some
shoutouts the leader of the 7/10 Club
gets a shout out first let's give a
giant shout out to my buddy lemur
priests to thank you for all of the
support bro I do appreciate it that does
not go unnoticed thank you fist bump big
respect I appreciate that
then we need to follow that up with the
big giant dab and a high-five and a
thank-you for my friend Papa Roni then
we need a big thank-you shoutout for my
buddy godfather cush then we need a big
thank-you shout out on a high five for
easy
oh five seven for twenty then I want to
follow that up with the giant thank you
shout out to my friend Blackbird 76 I've
always got to thank you
and a high five for my buddy fat rabbit
let's send a giant thank you shout out
to my buddy
Lefty's farm thanks for all the support
of lefty I also want to send a giant
thank you to my buddy Cass Burton hey
bro thank you for all the work you're
doing with cannabis
oh you're learning a lot but you are
also teaching a lot and that means a lot
to me so thanks for sharing the
knowledge I also want to give a giant
thank you shout out to my friend Rasta
que big fist bump big thank you for all
of the continued support if you have
more grow questions please send those my
way Rasta K I'm more than delighted to
help you out also let's send a big girl
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out to our friend Gro man Stan also we
need to send a big thank you shot out to
zoso Jay so so Jay keeping up the
awesome cannabis photography running
some of my genetics doing wonderfully
posting beautiful photos thank you and
last but certainly not least I want to
send a giant grow from your heart
podcast
thank you shout out and a fist bump and
a virtual dad to my friend John K big
thank you big shout out again big thanks
to everybody who is supporting the show
on patreon I do appreciate the support
and I could not continue to do the show
the way that I do it without you and if
it continues to go the way it is I will
put out more content so look forward to
more content in the future because I've
got faith you guys are not going to stop
what is the next order of business the
next thing I should cover is musical
submissions I am not ignoring you I get
a lot of emails every day I get a lot of
questions every day I focused a lot of
my time on catching up on patreon
messages and questions so if you've been
waiting for an email or a reply via
patreon I should have caught up with you
by now if not you are probably next um
the emails and musical submissions are
also being caught up I've gotten a lot
of great musical submissions you guys
good work there are some out there that
were a little bit too much for an intro
keep in mind if you're sending me music
I've got to talk over it so it can't
sound like trash cans and trash trucks
and it can't be dubstep is what I think
I'm trying to say if it is dubstep
mellow it down in a part where I could
talk don't make the robots battle all at
once
I think dubstep sounds like the toaster
in the microwave having a fight but if
that's what you're into do your bad
thing um but I'm still reviewing the
musical submissions there are a couple
that I
enjoy there are a couple couple of guys
really get my vibe and I've sent a
couple of emails out I asked for
permission to play one on the show
tonight but it's a little bit late it
was spontaneous when I do have
permission to play the samples and I
know what is expected of me and once
we've worked some things out I will
debut some really cool music there's
some really cool digital music some
really cool live music that has been
produced for the show even if I don't
select the tracks as a permanent
start-stop commercial type of track that
I play in the show it still may end up
being played on the show at least once
so that you guys can hear these people's
hard work because people put some time
into it I make music myself I know what
it's like I stay up all night long you
don't realize that the Sun is coming up
and you've just got to get this [ __ ]
sound perfect you need this one sound
panned over to the left just a little
bit more then you got to go here at the
car and make sure it's right I know what
it takes so I appreciate all of you
folks who have made and contributed
music and tracks for the show also keep
in mind it's got to be an original you
can't just remake another song you can't
cut and paste other pieces but thank you
guys I'm reviewing it and I will share
some on the show when I've got
permission once again shot at the green
dot cuz they got me rambly where else
are we we are charting in Jamaica that's
right I get uh statistics from a couple
of sources on the podcast and right now
in it's not called I can't say the wrong
terms cuz they've changed it and Apple
podcast is that the correct word yeah I
can't call it iTunes anymore it's Apple
podcast in the Apple podcasting app in
Jamaica we are ranked very high in the
education category we keep moving up and
down every couple of days but we are
ranking in the top 50 and top 25 in the
education category in Jamaica that means
a lot to me big up to everybody on the
island of Jamaica big up to all the
ganja farmers all the ganja learners all
the upcoming ganja growers everybody out
there on the island who is dedicated and
involved in the legalization and the
ganja movement big respect keep
listening to the show I would love to
hear some emails if you folks out there
in Jamaica have any questions anybody
has any questions but I'm here for my
Jamaican family send me some email some
questions to grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
of course if anybody has a grow question
a cultivation question
a cannabis culture question grow from
your heart at hotmail.com is the way to
reach me
of course patreon puts you at the front
of the line patreon.com forward slash
guru from your heart I don't think I
even said that part when I did the
patreon rant if you're not already
supporting the podcast and you would
like to learn how to do so visit
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart that should pop up on the screen
right there
of course I did put a link in the show
notes for all of the stone friends and
for the people who have their hands full
if you're working if you're driving just
wait so you get home you can click on
that link it'll take you right to
patreon you can support the show alright
I think that puts us back in rhythm back
on track where are we Garden updates I
like to update you guys on what is
happening you guys in gals and binary
folk I like to keep you updated on what
is happening in my personal garden most
of you know that I am running a Jack the
Ripper mail to make it Jack the Ripper
f2 experiment of course I was heavily
influenced by sub cool big up big
respect to sub cool rest in peace bro I
wish you were still Eric's I've got some
[ __ ] questions some cool had a lot of
answers he was uh miles ahead of me in
this industry he was doing the same
thing I'm doing but he's faced a lot of
the trials and tribulations and had a
lot of the questions so he's got a lot
of the [ __ ] answers that I need right
now
ah so wish some of you was around but I
have got a Jack the Ripper mail plant in
a room I have got for Jack the Ripper
females in a room I have narrowed down
my selections to where I know which
three Jack the Ripper females I'm gonna
keep maybe two I've got a good idea
numbers two and four that doesn't make
any difference to you though when I drew
them I labeled them one through ten um
number one happened to be the [ __ ]
best male he was a stud from the
beginning I was like that one right
there I liked it labeled at number one
it's what I was looking for this whole
project was based on finding a jtr male
so I labeled him number one and I
labeled an ex plant number two the next
one number three the next one number
four down the line up to ten uh as they
grew and look shitty I got rid of that
not not shitty but not up to my
standards for breeding I eliminated that
not keepers i shun the non-believers
then I was left with five oh there's a
male and four girls I think I've
eliminated
number five doesn't root well ah and I
think two and four are the keepers and I
think seven is the one that's
questionable that might stick around
we'll grow
but one two and four are the keepers
those are the champs so I've got some
Jack the Ripper Jack the Ripper male
some Jack the Ripper girls the Jack the
Ripper male has successfully pollinated
I said in a couple episodes ago it
looked like the pollination worked that
room is seated those pistols are brown
they're crinkled up the calyxes are
stuffed with seeds the plants look
amazing they're nice and pregnant what
have we pollinated I've been hinting
slowly on the show at the strains that
I've got in there that are getting
pollinated by the jtr of course I think
I've mentioned there is an arise plant
in that mix part of the idea of making
the Jack the Ripper cross was to cross
sub cools plant to one of my popular
plants which of course would be the
arize so there's a female arise we will
have a rise X Jack the Ripper you always
list the ladies first when you're
listening genetics so it'd be a rise
cross to Jack the Ripper also I put a
golden goat female in there we've talked
about that previously on the show people
are sending me name suggestions I'll
reveal some of those on the show I'll
share some of those I of course will
reveal the names of these crosses on the
show as well there's a golden goat in
there lots of great name suggestions in
the comments thank you guys
there is a blueberry cookies female in
there so we will have blueberry cookies
cross to the Jack the Ripper
um I think with the blueberry cookies
we're going to get the blueberry cookies
flavor and potency but I think the Jack
the Ripper is going to give it a more
bubblegum sweetness the Jack the Ripper
that I have selected the phenotypes I'm
finding in the room have a bubblegum
strawberry sweetness maybe a watermelon
sort of a thing so I think out of the
blueberry cookies we're gonna get like
strawberry blueberry skittles II uh
I smell Laffy Taffy when I think about
it my brain smells the pink and purple
Laffy Taffy so that's what my brain
thinks I also put a platinum tangi in
there that platinum tan she's a great
plant it's a very good breeder but I've
noticed all of its offspring are not
major monster growers I'm wondering if
this Jack the Ripper will make it bigger
that's what I'm going for four there so
there's a platinum tangi there's
blueberry cookies there's golden goat
and of course there is a rise there are
a few more other ladies in there I will
reveal more of those as time goes on
there's no need to spill all of the
beans on one show I got to keep your
attention got to keep you coming back
for more somehow so that is a garden
update
of course all of those plants are
underneath a cannon underneath two
cannon LED lights in a five by five 10 I
am loving the cannon LEDs after vegging
one round under the cannon LEDs I went
back to Keith and I bought three more so
now I've got five cannons running the
entire veg space myclone area my mom
area is all cannon LEDs I'm going to
finish this flower run in a small room
with cannons and see how I like the
finished product and if I completely
approve with the seed production and the
way that everything goes and grow so far
we're half way in and I'm [ __ ] happy
so if that continues I may I probably
will replace all of the lights in my
personal flowering space with cannon
LEDs or I'm gonna try to be really
patient and get to be a tester for some
of his new [ __ ] because I heard there's
new things coming down the pipeline
probably not supposed to say that
shout out Keith getting you some hype
alright what do we want to move forward
from here I think this is a good time to
segue into the patreon question for this
episode I've only got one email for this
episode I thought it was a really good
question it also works with another
question that another podcaster and
fellow grower asked me so let's start
with V email part that was sent in by a
listener then I'll also add on the other
part that my friend attached and then I
will get on a nice little ramble here
about this topic so this one comes from
a person let's see they did not sign
their name I don't think they want their
name said easy enough for me let's get
to the point it goes hey hey just was
high as hell and wondered if growing
commercially has taken the fun out of
growing for you bro that's all for now
I'm waiting on my new canon to pop some
orange chasm seeds take care
PS here's my favorite part PS kombucha
makes me poo and that's how the news
goes they didn't sign their name but I
think this is a great question they're
asking if growing commercially has taken
the fun out of growing for me then they
also said they're waiting for their
Canon LED so this person's got some
canons and some orange gasm seeds you're
gonna have a good time with that I have
seen the orange gasm under canons they
do vary
well I think with that one cannon you
probably want to run about a 3x3 maybe a
4x4 space at the at the most
keep that uh that light a little bit
above that ceiling and as the seedling
grows it that light closer and closer
we're off topic I'm just excited that
you've got my genetics and a like run by
my friend I made by my friend now I
recommend you get some new millennium
nutrients and you do the trifecta bro
you can't go wrong that way also you
need a peel grill minder unit in that
temp to make sure everything's Irie she
can't go wrong if you got I read
genetics a peel minder unit if you've
got a canon light and you've got some
new millennium nutrients you were
setting yourself up for success you've
got the [ __ ] Ferrari the keys the
fast tires you got cool paint you're
ready to shred it let's get my high ass
back on track cuz there was a question
here also kombucha makes me poo that's a
good thing bro you don't need that stuff
sit in there for too long I probably
needed to come out it'll fix your your
guts right up now as commercial growing
takin the fun out of growing for me um
no because I won't let it
I live to have a good time I look like a
serious I don't look like a serious dude
I got [ __ ] dreadlocks to my knees I
got a scruffy beard today I wear a
backwards hat and I'm [ __ ] 41 years
old ah I come across fairly serious I
get [ __ ] done people can rely on me I
like to give the yep the appearance the
presentation that people can rely on me
I can get [ __ ] done that's what I like
to give off I even be in a stoner with
dreadlocks and whatever I still like to
give people confidence that I can get
[ __ ] done so I seem kind of serious
especially being uh in charge being the
boss peon whatever the lead grower the
team leader the cultivation director at
a facility it can become stressful there
are a lot of things to worry about I am
the person between upper management and
the employees so when they employees
[ __ ] up I gotta yell at them and it's
hard I don't like yelling at people
they're my friends or my they're my
buddies we dab after work we hang out
and [ __ ] but I also don't like getting
yelled at by management so it's a
[ __ ] it's a weird place to be I don't
I don't like being I don't like being
the disciplinarian kind of person so I
don't let it suck the fun out of it
because we are there to have fun
I let the first person that shows up to
the grow select the music for the day so
if you're the first grow tech there you
get to go in the back and you get to
select music if you're the
first tremor there you get to go up
front you get to select music there's a
big divide between the two parts of the
building
I can't hear tremor music when I'm in
the back I can't her grow her music when
I look toward the front so the first
person in each part gets to select music
that gives a person a little bit of
groove they're there they're first there
kicking ass that makes it fun I put the
music up loud I don't care what you want
to play I'll give you like 45 minutes of
whatever you want if it's gangster rap
if it's hip-hop if it's [ __ ] Swedish
country folk death metal I'm in if
that's what you want to hear and you
were first let's do it but we're gonna
switch it up throw the turd there before
a break we're gonna change it when we
come back from break it's definitely
gonna be different when we go to break
we'll know after we go take a dab or two
we'll come back we'll know what to put
on after that ah but I don't let it suck
the fun out of it
I walk through the grow I make sure that
all the guy I assigned tasks for
multiple guys I get them going they're
doing their thing right I know that this
guy doesn't really enjoy doing this job
so I'm gonna walk by him every couple of
minutes and tell him he looks [ __ ]
good doing his job he knows I'm [ __ ]
with him he knows I'm just [ __ ]
patronizing him but it's fun it keeps us
he knows he's doing a job that sucks but
the boss is acknowledging it and I go
check on every guy so say I've got five
guys growing I've got them all doing
separate things maybe two guys are
putting up trellis one guys doing
transplants one guys cutting clones and
one guys doing some [ __ ] I'll bounce
through all the guys and make sure
they're all doing something that they
need to be doing make sure they don't
need help if they need help I'll help
them ah the guy's putting a trellis I'm
six five if they need a guy to go run
[ __ ] zip ties down the poles I'll zip
tie the [ __ ] out of it keep him up catch
them up while they're doing it I'll
[ __ ] I shoot and holler like Ric
Flair if we accomplish something and we
get lunch ten minutes early you'll hear
me go whoa
cuz we get to go to lunch 10 minutes
[ __ ] early we're gonna go have a good
time we're gonna that means he get two
more dabs in is what that really means
so a hoot and holler I [ __ ] scream
and yell I had nothing bad I'm like
let's get it done by the [ __ ] we're
gonna grow some [ __ ] weed today and
you just gotta have a good time in there
I think keeping morale up really helps
so I go check on the guys hanging
trellis then I'll go look at the guys
transplanting when they're transplanting
I'll walk by if they look like they've
fallen behind I'll catch them up I can
do something I know how to do all the
[ __ ] so I get my hands dirty I do a
couple of the things ah then as I'm
leaving I go man you guys look [ __ ]
sexy pot in all these plants
you guys keep it going if it's just a
couple bros if it's a lady I won't say
that so I'll get myself in trouble but
you know what I mean I'll say you guys
are kicking ass you look [ __ ] great
doing it I like your shoes something
random they know what I'm doing but it
still feels good we're bonding
they're not just sucking at work all day
so then I go find the other guy who's
cleaning something or whatever and I
clean up a little bit for him just catch
him up so now his cleaning job doesn't
suck as much he's like girl you're a bad
[ __ ] you're the boss you didn't
have to clean that but you did ah I'm
not above anything I started off as the
budtender is the tremor I started off in
the bottom now I'm [ __ ] it's
everybody starts somewhere you just
gotta [ __ ] earn your spot so I've
just been there longer than a lot of
them I respect all of them I keep it fun
I help them
so keeping it fun with music and just
being I'm just a [ __ ] jolly dude um
I've kind of got a unspoken rule that if
I can't tell you're high in the facility
nobody else can and just shut up and be
high but the minute we can tell you're
high
go [ __ ] take a break get some water
drink some sodas or eat some cookies get
your [ __ ] back together whatever you got
to do to get it going but if you're if
nobody can tell you're high but I don't
know I don't know you're high I can't be
mad at you so that's an unspoken thing
be blazed if you can be blazed uh we
take a break every couple of hours
sometimes I just buy pizza if the guys
are kicking ass and I see that a couple
I know that we get paid every two weeks
I know that around the end of that
second week a couple of the guys we go
to lunch breaks and their car doesn't
leave the parking lot it's cuz they
don't got no weed or no money I'll buy
pizza the next day just to keep those
guys [ __ ] fed one meal will get your
[ __ ] crew back back on your team it
prevents a mutiny so I'm Ric Flair in
the [ __ ] girl I go whoa all day long
[ __ ] you know I'm coming I cannot
sneak up on you I'm loud we have a good
time we're bros I love growing so it
hasn't sucked the fun out of it because
I make it fun part of my job is to make
it fun I get to do different tasks every
day I was saying I get to help all the
guys at different stations that means I
get to do different [ __ ] every single
day and I learn new stuff by doing that
I love learning I'm passionately curious
is what I think the term is I love that
so it has not sucked the fun out of
growing for me because I just simply
won't let it um I make it fun I love it
and it's never gonna stop being fun
el-amin segue into the second part I was
on a live chat with my friend Scottie
real and a few other folks
and Scottie real dropped a question he
said man with all of the technology and
all of the things we have learned as
growing become easier or harder for you
and there are a couple of good answers
from me for that question
um I am at a level where I call myself a
black belt grower I don't try to be
egotistical about it I don't try to
boast I just know that I'm confident and
if there's a grow issue a plant issue a
commercial cultivation issue a small
grow issue a breeding question I can
probably cover and answer the question
without much research sometimes I gotta
go I don't know let me check a couple of
resources so I don't give you wrong
details but for the most part I know the
answers so I'm like a black belt grower
with being a black belt grower there's a
lot of information I know how to do a
lot of [ __ ] hypothetically I know how to
throw a lot of kicks and a lot of
[ __ ] blocks but that also gives me a
lot of decisions to make which kick in
which block do I throw sometimes you got
to make a decision on the fly you really
hope you block that right punch and you
don't get hit with a [ __ ] left punch
on accident ah I hope you guys follow my
karate analogies it's [ __ ] simple for
me I'm a black belt grower you know
where I'm going so
is growing harder or easier now that I'm
a black belt grower I've been given not
given but I've got the controls the keys
the driver's seat and the codes the
launch codes to several large commercial
cultivation facilities I could make
those facilities and those jobs as hard
as I wanted to make them there is a lot
of [ __ ] to go wrong in a commercial
cultivation facility when I train new
people and agro the first it usually
they start in the middle of the day we
hire them they come in about lunchtime
the second day they meet me at the door
to go in at 8:00 or 9:00 in the morning
or 7:00 in the morning wherever we are
as I'm turning off the alarm I go okay
here is the fun part the first thing we
do at every grow after you turn off the
alarm and clock in is find what went
wrong last night I know it sounds shitty
but there are a lot of moving parts
there's more to break there's more to
maintain there's more to take care of
there is more to find what the [ __ ] went
wrong last night some of my facilities
have five to seven hundred lights
something went wrong there are pumps
there fans there are a lot of moving
parts something went wrong so every day
we got to walk in and find out what went
wrong sometimes that's the hardest part
of commercial growing also
commercial growing is everything you're
doing at scale mixing nutrients you can
really make a mistake if you put in if
you do the math wrong if you're trying
to add 450 gallons you accidentally do 7
milliliters times 50 instead of 5 you
just did a lot more nutrients on
accident your mistakes can be much
larger so it's easier but it's also
harder but I don't let it get too
difficult I try to keep it simple stoner
ah the more parts you add the more [ __ ]
that can break so I try to keep a
commercial grow reliable and
self-sufficient I don't like to water by
myself by hand I like an auto watering
system but it's not harder because I can
see the issues I've learned to read the
plants that makes things a lot easier
I've learned to calm the [ __ ] down
my grower panic button is much pressed
less much often when I was a new grower
and I would see something weird in the
plants I call it the panic button you
just go oh [ __ ] I have to flush I have
to spray I have to defoliate I have to
call 6 friends and find out what they
think I should do now I go huh those
leaves look like [ __ ] I wonder what we
did and I just think about it I solved
the problem so in the sense of my
knowledge growing is much easier with
all of the technologies [ __ ] can become
way difficult we've got controllers and
watering controllers and light
controllers and climate controllers and
gigantic HVAC systems I don't understand
some of the J I don't understand most of
the giant HVAC systems so when they
break that's hard for me that's the hard
part is maintaining all of the gear the
hard part is maintaining the staff the
hard part is maintaining scheduling for
rooms employees vacations plants
transplants [ __ ] inspections that's
the hard part it's not really the
growing I'm a black belt grower I can
handle 99% of what you throw at me as a
grower now most of what I've said is
relating to a commercial grow let's talk
about a home grow in a home grow you
would be surprised at how much of a
caveman grow I run I have got vented
lights with a carbon filter and a blower
blowing air over the vented light out of
a window
that's my light setup thousand watt HBS
lights for my breeding in my main area
like I said they may switch to be
cannons but for now that's what we've
got the lights are plugged into a the
blue one what's it called the blue
control box power box I've got the one
controls for lights with the two
accessory switches on there and that is
set on 1212 what else is in there a
couple of fans everything is lifted up
off the ground uh very low-tech is just
so the plants aren't touching the floor
because I don't like my plants on the
floor floor gets cold I like them lifted
up very low-tech three gallon pots
[ __ ] some sticks sometimes I do
trellising in that room I move the
plants a lot so I prefer the sticks in
there but my technology for my personal
grow is very simple keep it simple
stoner that keeps it really easy
the only things they can really die I've
got an air conditioner the things that
could really break in the room the
ballast could burn out the light bulbs
could burn out the fan could die the air
conditioner could die or the power box
could die but those are about my major
pieces of equipment that I would have to
replace or the pl minor units and
they're telling me what's going on also
I've got a high temp shutoff switch my
power box plugs into so I've got a piece
that plugs into my main plug the power
box plugs into that the piece has a
thermometer that hangs in the middle of
the room if the temperature exceeds a
hundred degrees it cuts the power to
everything in the room everything shuts
off not everything the fans in the air
conditioner may stay on depending on how
I've got the plugs configured but my
cooling will stay on the lights will go
off that way the lights don't continue
to roast the room mainly I've got the
lights plugged into that most of the
time so the lights will turn off I'll
rescue the room then I'll get a
notification from the PL minder unit it
will say bro it's a hundred and five
degrees in the room the lights went off
we don't know what the [ __ ] happenin I
can either drive home or I can walk to
the grow room and see what's going on
and solve the issue so I mainly like to
keep it simple stoner in my personal
grows that keeps it easy nothing can
break it makes it easier to grow when
I'm spinning and the commercial grow we
spend a lot of time cleaning filters
cleaning nozzles cleaning sprayer jets
ah cleaning the dehumidifier there is a
lot of cleaning to be done so it's not
harder but it's more maintenance and a
personal grow I've got an air
conditioner I don't have a dehumidifier
or a humidifier in that room I let the
plants and the [ __ ] rest of the
equipment kind of do that part it's
Colorado it's kind of easy in my room to
dial that in ah I let you
we do all the work for me I think I lost
track of my [ __ ] train of thought
there but I don't have a lot of
equipment so I can spend more time not
so much time cleaning filters cleaning
[ __ ] I'm just cleaning one air
conditioner filter and that's about
really all I got to clean in there I got
a mop the floor occasionally I got a
[ __ ] spray things down and cleaned
[ __ ] up and change the bulbs and I
cleaned the glass the glass between the
bulb and the [ __ ] plants there's a
little glass bulb in there so the heat
stays in there and the air moves it out
I cleaned that quite frequently
but there's not a lot of moving parts to
take care of so that gives me so much
more time to play and focus on the
plants I don't have to touch so much
working parts and machinery less [ __ ] to
break Lester a place that keeps it more
fun um does commercial growing suck the
fun out of it was the original question
that got me triggered on this sometimes
it's stressful but I keep it fun in
there then I know that I get to come
home and do whatever I want and that
grow if I want to run in and run around
in there with no clothes and no shoes
and just my earbuds in my ears and
listen to Joe Rogan talk about aliens I
can do that if I want to wear my full-on
clothes just to get that other image out
of your head and my shoes and still I
have Joe Rogan in my headphones I can do
that if I want to sit on a five gallon
bucket and smoke a joint I don't smoke
in the grow room but if I wanted to I
could sit on a five gallon bucket smoke
a joint listen to uh the fighter and the
kid in my headphones or on their [ __ ]
radio nice and loud I don't have to
worry about anybody in there it's my
personal grow if I want to cut down all
these plants cuz it looks like fun I
could cut them all down if I want to
light him on fire we could do it ah I
got my own personal gross so I'll never
quit having fun and my personal grow I'm
a breeder I find two plants and I make
them [ __ ] I'm gonna make seeds and then
I get to grow those seeds I'm like
making packages of baseball cards and
looking for Mickey Mantle's all day but
I'm printing the cards so that's a lot
of fun fino hunts are fun breeding is
fun watching what you do with my seeds
is a lot of fun I send seed packs out
you guys post them up on social media
I get to see what you did with my
creations that is really fun to me
so commercial growing can be stressful
but I handle stress with a big smile um
I don't take [ __ ] like it's [ __ ] I take
[ __ ] like it's life because shit's
always gonna keep coming if you let [ __ ]
bug you
it's like if you show the dog you're
weak the dog is gonna bite you more I
feel like life is the same if you're
like I'm losing life cuz you thought you
were losing before [ __ ] watch this but
if you go man I'm crushing it you stay
on top of your [ __ ] life cuz you've been
crushing it dude we're gonna just make
sure you keep crushing it we're gonna
put you on the path of crush crush crush
alright I think I've rambled for quite a
bit for a Thursday episode thank you for
the great email I want to thank
everybody for all the patreon support if
you feel like this episode was
educational informative and/or
entertaining and you'd like to make a
financial contribution of the show of
course you can do so by visiting
www.unityhouston.org and seeds here now
calm use that coupon code gfy age 10
while checking out that will save you
10% off your entire order if you're
getting a small order that will cover
the cost of shipping if you're getting a
big order that can add up quite quickly
don't forget that the podcast is now
available on youtube if you're listening
on an audio channel i appreciate you but
i encourage you to check out the show on
youtube go to youtube search for the
girl from your heart podcast click
subscribe also click on that little bell
that is the notification bell every time
I put out new content you will get a
reminder you will never miss an episode
you'll never fall behind I will
appreciate you also leave some comments
on the YouTube channel I've been getting
so many comments my favorite comment was
why does this guy only have 3,000
subscribers that's my favorite comment I
agree why do I only have 3,000 I'm not
complaining I appreciate all 3,000 of
you let's get batshit up to 10,000 I'm
just joking you guys I appreciate you
each and every one of you but leave some
YouTube comments let's push it let's get
some more viewers the more comments you
leave the more people will see the
videos the more people see the videos
the more subscribers we will get then
more people will be growing better
cannabis it'll be more available we will
over grow the entire planet all together
let's do that alright don't forget about
the email you can send me an email it
grow from your heart at hotmail.com if
you've got any cannabis culture or
- Bayesian questions I would love to
hear from you and of course patreon is
the quickest way to get your questions
on the show ladies and gentlemen that is
all I've got for you thank you for
listening to me ramble
I had a good time on this podcast I hope
you had a good time too I'll be back in
a couple of days with fresh new content
I want to give a giant shout out to my
friend mr. Sol and until next time take
a phat dad and give your mom a hug for
me