all right what's a podcast world I'm
your host Rasta Jeff and it is time for
episode 547 of the girl from your heart
podcast this episode of the show is
brought to you by our friends at seeds
here now.com seeds here now.com offers
seeds from all the industry's leading
breeders including aficionado seeds
exotic genetics miss Jill genetics and
of course I read genetics everything at
seeds here now.com is backed by an
award-winning satisfaction guarantee and
for my friends on a tight budget seeds
here now.com offers several packs for
under $30 as well as amazing monthly
sales make sure to use coupon code wih
tin while checking out to save a few
bucks
again that is coupon code g FY aged 10
while checking out at seeds here now
dot-com you know I like to start this
podcast off by talking about what I'm
smoking today I've been taking dabs of
garlic Grove live batter from Green Dot
labs this is a blend of GMO cookies and
Loa f2 on the package the flavor is
described as General Tso's garlic and
orange soda I think I really agree with
that flavor description there is not a
potency label on the back of this
package for some reason that sticker did
not get put on here it does not need
that sticker what it should have is a
fist there should just be a logo with a
fist right there because this was the
most pleasant punch to the face I have
had in a long time when I dabbed this I
was immediately punched with this orange
flavor this orange zestiness hit my face
overwhelmed my mouth then as I exhale
that is when the garlic really kicks in
it's garlic and orange that's why I get
why they're call why they're calling it
General Tso's it is really garlic and
orange e on the exhale then that garlic
and a little bit of funk just hangs out
on your tongue on my tongue at least for
a couple of minutes and I really enjoy
it
I'm obviously super heavily medicated
from the garlic Grove to be quite honest
with you this is not the first take that
I have tried to do this intro to be
quite honest with you I set up all my
recording gear I had my headphones on I
took a DAB I thought I was gonna record
and I found myself on the couch
scrolling through social media trying to
get my [ __ ] together so this is a
quality concentrate
big shout out to our friends at Green
Dot labs for the garlic Grove live
batter all right I do have a great
podcast lined up for you before we get
to the email portion of the show let's
do some shout outs to a few of the folks
who support the show on patreon let's
start off with a big grow from your
heart podcast shout out to the leader of
the 7/10 Club let's give a giant thank
you shout out to my buddy lemur priest
let's follow that up with the big girl
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out to my friend Karen Crawford let's
follow that one up with a big girl from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to my buddy Vic Anna crap let's in -
thank you - Helly
let's send a big fist bump to my buddy
learning and burnin let's send a big
high-five - okey gross 720 let's give a
big hug to my buddy net Denver let's
send a big THANK YOU shoutout to big toe
grows let's send a big thank-you to
Tommy and last but certainly not least
let's send a big grow from your heart
podcast - thank you shout out and a fist
bump to my friend Shawn 23 big thank you
big shout out big respect to everybody
who continues to support the show on
patreon if you're not already supporting
the show and you would like to learn how
to do so all you have to do is visit
w-w-w dot reincarnation you need to
support the show we'll be right there
on the screen and of course I did
include a link in the show notes to help
all my friends get to patreon if you're
watching on YouTube click on the video
description there will be a link in the
description if you're watching on one of
the audio formats tap the screen it
should bring up the show notes then
you'll find the link right there that
will get you right to patreon also there
is a link for seeds here now in the
video description I do my best to make
things easy for you thank you guys for
your support all right now I think it is
time to move into the question and email
portion of the show the first question
I've got lined up for today's episode
actually came from YouTube I'm looking
for the screenshot on my phone I
generally do not take questions from
YouTube
I prefer to get the questions off of
patreon or email of course patreon is
the first option that's where I go for
questions if I get all those questions
caught up then I go to the email but
sometimes I
good questions on the YouTube I'm not
necessarily looking for them but I found
a good comment there and this one has
been coming up on social media quite a
bit so I thought I would address this
one it says Rasta Jeff can you tell from
looking at a seed and see if it is male
or female I know that people are passing
around a chart on social media it shows
that if there is a volcano shape at the
end of part of the seed or if there's a
dimple or a nipple shape or a bottlenose
dolphin shape on part of the seed that
it's a female if it's got another shape
it's a male that is total [ __ ] if
that was accurate sea breeders would be
fishing through every scene with the
magnifying glass and we would pull out
all the seeds that we wanted and give
you all the seeds we didn't want I
wouldn't do that but that would be a
thing that happened nobody can tell a
seeds sex by looking at the seed if
you're going by that chart that you see
on social media you're going to be
poorly sadly sorely disappointed don't
do that I do not believe in that chart I
don't know any other breeders or growers
that believe in that that rely on that
so no I do not believe you can tell a
sex of a seed just by looking at the
seed thanks for the great YouTube
comment thank you for following me on
YouTube big shout out to my friend Lance
hope you're doing well bro looks like
you got a kitty in your picture think
that's a cat or is it a dog I don't know
bro but I like a person with pets in
their picture so big shout out thank you
for the great comment I hope I answered
your question next time send me an email
grow from your heart at hotmail.com or
even better support us on patreon
patreon comm forward slash girl from
your heart all right let's keep moving
the next message came on the email this
one came from the this one's actually
from the I read genetics email and this
is an update and/or a correction and it
says hey brother I wanted to ask about
your comments on bTW so in a previous
episode I talked a Bennet talked about a
beneficial bacteria I called it bacillus
thuringiensis I think I'm saying that
correctly if not I'm saying it close
enough I've never really had to say it
out loud I've only read it on packages
and in books it's not a word you throw
out in conversation I think I'm saying
it right if not correct me
I don't mind Corrections in fact we've
got one right here so
says I think BT treatments are actually
BTK which killed Caterpillar type
critters then it goes on to say for
fungus gnats I think your listeners
should try using BTI so I've been
educated today that there are different
strains of bacillus thuringiensis is how
I think it said bacteria there's a bt k
and a bt i i can pronounce the BTK it is
the K stands for curse tacky and the I
is Israel insists Israel insists it's
close enough you guys we're learning in
public today
um just all about sounding it out but
there are two different bacillus BT
bacterias and I did not realize this so
one is better for Caterpillar type
critters and the other one is better for
fungus gnats so that'll make it easier
to shop for a more pest specific product
if we are applying the right pesticide
we will have more success getting rid of
the pests and we will do less damage to
the plant because some of the pesticides
and soaks and sprays they do cause
slight problems and irritations to the
plants although they get rid of the bugs
sometimes they piss the plants off a
little bit if we don't have to apply
something or if we're applying something
that's unnecessary or the wrong thing
we're causing more problems than we're
doing good so if we can dial in the
absolute perfect correct pesticide we
can eradicate our problems and not cause
any extra stress on the plants that's
what I'm rambling toward at this point
um so it says I hope that makes sense
and you definitely have more knowledge
than me so I just wanted to ask you to
make sure hey you sound like you were
well educated on this subject so I am
ready to learn from you as well don't
feel like I am better than you smarter
than you I've been growing more maybe
longer I don't know but I've just got
experience and I've got a big mouth so
I've got a show that doesn't mean you
can't teach me something I've got to
keep learning constantly that's how I
stay on top that's how I stay ahead how
I stay active it's how I stay
entertained I wasn't learning I would
just lose my mind imagine this brain not
absorbing knowledge and doing something
with it oh that's scary so thank you for
educating me and then it wraps up with
stay Irie brother then they signed it
with baked Baker on cannabis so if
you're not already on cannabis join up
on kin
if you're already there go ahead and
give my buddy baked Baker a follow on
cannabis and of course please give me a
follow - I'm Irie underscore genetics on
cannabis hey baked Baker thank you for
the great message I called this one an
update in a correction you guys there
are more than one strain of bt
beneficial bacteria there's the BTK
which is better for caterpillars and
there's the BTI which is better for
fungus gnats so we all learned something
today big shout out big thank you all
right I want to keep it moving because I
do have a couple of more emails and I
don't want to run out of time I don't
want my throat to burn out too quickly
you guys know that if I talk too long I
will run out of my voice so let's keep
going
this one says hey Rasta Jeff thank you
for answering my question on the podcast
regarding carbon filter so I'm sure you
guys remember a few episodes back I
spoke about carbon filters it says that
was cool for some reason I heard that in
a beavis and butthead voice that was
cool
ah then it goes real quick one of my em
dog plants has sprouted a pollen sack
and germinated I think you say me mean
pollinated some buds on the lower branch
near the stem so you've got an EM dog
plant it sprouted a pollen sack so I
think it is gone hermaphrodite on you
it's shown us some intersex traits and
it is spread pollen so it's pollinated
some buds on the lower branch near the
stem the top buds seemed fine I've run
this girl many times with no herm issues
um my first question is why did it herm
this time then do you know why it harmed
on you this time did I have a light leak
did you overfeed it did you stress it
did he get too hot what's the issue they
caused it to her that's the first thing
I want to know ah then it goes on to say
question is should I top it in case
another one sprouts of pollen sacks oh
you should Utah should you chop this
plant down in case it sprouts another
pond sack you're worried um that's a
good question or do you think I could
let her finish with no problems it's
kind of late for that you've already got
problems
how do I feel about that it depends on
how big the plant is do you need it do
you need that that finished product that
seeded finished product or can you live
without it is it gonna hurt your budget
budget is it gonna hurt your medicine
supply is it gonna hurt your stash
it's a risky plant it's a problematic
plant but is it worth the reward
that's when you've gotta weigh the risk
reward the problem - the payoff is it
worth the [ __ ] that it's gonna give
you it's kind of late in already so
you're worried about uh trying to finish
it without problems broad already
pollinated your crop I'm not sure what
the rest of your problems could be um
then you say that it in the previous
part you said that it pollinated the
lower parts and you don't think the tops
got it I hate to burst your bubble buddy
but a lot of times when you see a couple
of seeds that means there are a lot of
seeds you do not see as a breeder I know
that the outside seeds are just the tip
of the iceberg so to speak and once you
break open those buds there's [ __ ]
seeds in there so you may have a lot
more seeds than what you're thinking
you've got you want to know if you
should chop it in case it gets more
pollen sacks um in
they may do that it could make more
pollen but is it too late to pollinate
the rest of the room are the plants that
are in the room already past their
pollination point have the UH the
pistols that they curled up or the hares
are they brown and nasty looking at that
point they're past peak pollination I'm
not sure how far into flower you are
wait we can find out because it says I
have about ten more days to hit eight
weeks so that means you're seven more
days three you're in week the end of
week six now you're at a really critical
part here um you're gonna have a lot of
seeds and the seeds that you made are
probably gonna also and they could
possibly be hermaphroditic you could
have some gems in there but that's not
what you're worried about
um you're wondering if you should cut it
down you're a week six by the time I
read this um you've probably gotten
close to the end of harvest right now
but I would almost just cut that [ __ ]
down cuz it's stressful and make sure it
doesn't cause me more problems but also
keep in mind there are probably a lot of
seeds happening in your crop so it says
I'd be happy with one more week or do
you think it's a gamble and just chop
her now um do you have a perpetual grow
going if all of your plants are at the
same cycle the ones right around this
plant are gonna have some pollen are
some seeds in there hopefully the rest
of them aren't to seeded but if you've
got more plants in a earlier stage and
you've got more plants that are coming
in and staggering you do have the
opportunity to keep pollinating your
future crops so if you've got more [ __ ]
going on I would get rid of it because
you're just gonna continue the problem
the plants that are in there have
probably already been pollinated or are
past their peak
pollination point they're past ovulation
they probably can't take pollen any
further at this point but you're at like
week six week seven so I'm not sure what
they look like maybe they can receive
pollen right now I would cut this plant
down I would think about what caused it
to hermaphrodite why did it flip on you
what it's probably something you caused
I don't want to point a finger I don't
want to blame you but you say it ran
fine a couple of times now it's hurting
on you what did you do was there a light
leak was there an issue like I said
earlier did you overfeed it we need to
figure out what caused the herm
then you need to think about do you want
to risk this same problem in the next
grow we know this plant is problematic
like this dog bites do you want to keep
putting it on a [ __ ] leash and taking
it to the dog park and having to pull it
off other dogs I don't think so I would
[ __ ] get rid of it dude that's what I
would do I would just chop it right now
I've got a very different approach to
gardening than a lot of people I also
have access to a lot of genetics when I
cut this one down I get to grow
something else in its place something
that is not a hermaphrodite something
that does not give me problems something
I don't want to kick if this plant
accidentally pollinated my crop only
kick it I'm mad at it so it would be
gone it would already be in a [ __ ]
trashcan if this were me so it depends
on how much you love this plant how much
you need the medicine off of this plant
and how much you want to give yourself a
headache I think I decided halfway
through reading this that cut that
[ __ ] thing down get rid of it stop
fighting yourself and set yourself up
for success that's what I want to say
that's the answer that I would go with
but I don't know how bad you need the
medicine or the product so um that is my
advice cut it down cut your losses quit
[ __ ] up the rest of the grow with the
problematic plant and replace it with
something that is not problematic all
right let's see if you put your name in
there you did not say your name so you
know who you are man ah thank you for
the great message and let me know how
this goes send me a follow-up and I will
read it on the show I want to know what
you chose to do and how the outcome came
and how many seeds did you get and what
are you gonna do with the seeds please
don't share these seeds until you've
grown them yourself until you know if
they're problematic or if they're
amazing you know what I'm talking about
don't share crappy seeds and since they
came from a crappy plant I'm not calling
your plant crappy but it hummed on you
that's crappy since they came from a
questionable crappy plant they're
questionable crappy seeds in my mind I
think I covered all the notes I wrote on
that one why did it herm figure that out
probably a lightly probably over feet it
they're probably more seeds than you
think it may keep making pollen it could
pop up more pollen sacks um but it could
be too late to pollinate the rest of the
room if you've got a perpetual cycle
going on the rest of its gonna just keep
getting pollinated um I would call that
[ __ ] and get rid of it alright that
wraps it up thank you for that one let's
move forward to another email this one
starts off with good
morning good evening it is definitely
not morning time here I hope you're
smoking a fat bull whatever time it is
wherever you are it goes on to say funny
story I came down to write you an email
and noticed the new podcast I love that
when people go to write me a message or
send me a tweet or something and there's
a brand new episode for them to check
out always puts a smile on people's face
it goes on to say I just so happened it
just so happened you answered my last
question oh oh that's [ __ ] awesome
you went to write me a message and as
you were writing it I answered your last
question I love stuff like that
synchronicities you guys there is no
that that stuff's supposed to happen it
goes on to say I had a small chuckle at
the way things work sometimes yes me too
my friend one thing I will clarify about
the last email when I was talking about
ro and calcium buildup I meant ro water
in humidifiers oh yeah it says I know if
you put tap water in them they will
start to build white powder on the walls
from the calcium in the water or so that
is what I had read not only will it
start to build up calcium on the walls
possibly but you will ruin the filters
the filters will get clogged up with the
calcium quite quickly so it goes on to
say where were we where were we aha
okay the cutting out of the root ball
and living soil was Borah long the lines
of what I was looking into and actually
found a way with these rapid stack pots
so apparently there was another part of
the question about living soil but here
is the part that we need to address on
today's episode it says anyway here is
my problem venting from my ceiling into
my basement
unfortunately the excess heat has caused
my house to heat up too much yes
sometimes those grow lights will heat up
the house quite a bit it says I have
attempted to move it around within the
same circuit and use my dryer exhaust
but then it started to blow breakers
that puts off so many things I want to
talk about in my head um if you're
flipping breakers you are definitely
putting your house in danger you're
putting everybody in risk be careful
doing that I shouldn't have to preach
too much about that what's happening is
the breaker is heating up so much that
it goes huh I gotta quit running because
I'm pulling way too much electricity and
this could cause a problem so the
breaker flips but every time that
happens the wires are heating up hot
enough to flip that breaker eventually
the coating on the outside of the wires
the polyurethane stuff will melt two
wires will touch you'll have a fire um
that'll take a while but eventually that
sure will happen I don't know how old
your house is I don't know what kind of
wiring you have if you've got old wiring
in a really old house you've got a much
more potential for starting a fire if
you got a new house still run a risk but
it's not as bad so be careful if you're
flipping breakers another thing that
comes to mind is you said you tried to
run it through the dryer exhaust which
makes me think you were tying in your
Gro exhaust into the dryer vent exhaust
that's not a good idea either it doesn't
sound like a big deal but never really
modify the exhaust system in a home
whether it comes to the dryer exhaust or
the HVAC system those systems were
designed very specifically for the flow
of the house and the heating and cooling
equipment if you go tying in another
duct that was not planned for you're
going to create opportunities for
backflow air they shouldn't go a certain
way should have never gone a certain way
will now go a certain way you'll disrupt
the airflow of everything you've either
got the opportunity of blowing the warm
air from your grow into cool spaces or
blowing the cool air into warm spaces
it's gonna go the wrong way because it's
not how it was meant
to go also ah you'll end up with dryer
lint in your grow if that [ __ ] goes
wrong
nobody wants a dryer lint in the grow
you don't want to be picking that [ __ ]
out of your buds
I don't know that that'll really happen
but don't tie those in and don't [ __ ] up
the electricity you gotta be safer than
that so let's keep going where are we I
also now can use my I also now cannot
use my dehumidifier as that pumped out
too much heat um and you're cranking up
a lot of heat in a little space it says
so now my room is running at 28 degrees
Celsius and 45% relative humidity
daytime and nighttime is about 23 or 24
degrees Celsius with about 52 percent
relative humidity so you're not dropping
too much for your night temperature but
you're getting a little bit more
humidity and they're not extreme it's
gonna be okay um you're gonna have to
remove the heat you have to ducted a
different way I would duct it outside or
add an air conditioner you're either
gonna have to move that duct did you
tried to tie into the dryer you're gonna
have to run it outside somehow um I
don't know what your opportunity is do
you have a fireplace so we're gonna into
the fireplace and we'll go up the
fireplace and out the chimney or use a
window seal up the window put a hole in
a board or a piece of insulation or
however you can seal the window then
make a six or an eight inch hole we run
a blower out through there and make sure
to use a carbon filter but you're gonna
have to get rid of the heat or add an
air conditioner you're not just gonna be
able to blow heat around um you're just
gonna heat up the whole house I don't
know how big your house is I do know
that it's going to come up and tell me
how big the grow is so let's keep going
it says I've done a bit of reading on
co2 I know with extra co2 they can
handle higher heat so I believe this is
the route I'm going to have to take
before I read too much further I just
want to say that this is probably not
the best solution this is more like a
band-aid you're not really fixing the
heat problem you're just kind of
covering it up with something else that
cost more money and is an experiment you
don't want to rely on co2 bags those
little make your own co2 mushroom bags
and [ __ ] those aren't going to provide
enough co2 to supplement the to fix the
heat problem it's not gonna band-aid
that [ __ ] enough you're gonna have to
get the co2 bottles in a system and turn
it up a real high to get enough co2
there to mitigate that heat issue the
issue the solution is to correct the
heat
don't go create more problems and spend
more money on the wrong [ __ ] by just
buying a mask and a band-aid we want to
actually solve the problem or at least
that's what I would do you can do
whatever you want but I wouldn't I
wouldn't go that route um
then it says how much would I need for a
four by four and a two by four tent that
kind of set off some weird bells in my
head how much light are you running in a
4x4 and a 2x4 that is heating up your
entire house I've got questions I would
like to see your setup a little bit I
would like to see how you've got the
tent set up how you're running the
ducting where you're running it I want
to see what's going on I can give you a
lot of guidance and advice that's a
really small area of grow space and you
shouldn't have an extreme amount of
light in there that the biggest in that
4x4 may be you've got a thousand which
is pushing it and in that 2x4 what do
you got in there like a four hundred
maybe a six you shouldn't have
mm that's a lot of light for that little
bit of space you shouldn't have a whole
lot of bang and light this shouldn't be
too hard to cool I'm sure with a little
bit of uh knowledge from an experienced
grower or someone who has set up a lot
of rooms I'm sure we could cool this
down quite a bit without doing the co2
idea then it says would it be better to
exhaust my flower tent into the lung
room or keep the whole thing and closed
um I don't think that the co2 is the way
to go but if you're gonna do co2 I'll
put the two tents in one room and fill
that whole room with co2 and just keep
the co2 moving or put the co2 straight
in the tents but it's gonna duct out of
there if you've got the tent in a room
so just do the hole you're gonna have to
augment the entire room is what you'll
have to do so um
yeah you're gonna have to I would reduce
the heat don't even do the co2 reduce
the heat work on removing the heat or
adding an air-conditioner the co2 in my
opinion is a band-aid and if it gets a
little bit hotter
how many more band-aids are you gonna
put on there you can't just keep adding
co2 the correct thing to do is to fix
the problem in my opinion you can keep
trying to battle the heat or you can get
the appropriate equipment to correct the
heat now it says that you're flipping
breakers you're gonna have to be really
careful how much lighter you run it dude
I'm really confused and I'm not trying
to disrespect your grow that's a four by
four and a two by four
you can't have too many watts going on
in there so I'm really curious please
send me an update let me know what's
going on in this grow so I can give you
more guidance more advice get you a
little bit more dialed and cool down
your room a little bit um maybe we can
figure out how to run your equipment
more efficiently off of the electricity
that you've got because I'm pretty sure
most people can't augment the
electricity in their house but I look
forward to oh this one's from Tonto also
yeah I look forward to a follow-up and
it also says PS if any of this is
unclear please let me know and I will
clarify do not want pictures if you can
send me a video just walk through and be
like this is what's going on that would
really help me out that would help us
both out and I will follow up with some
updates alright a big shout out to my
buddy Tonto thank you for the great
message again if you've got an email
question a cannabis culture a cannabis
cultivation question my email address is
grow from your heart at hotmail.com I
want to keep it moving I'm having fun on
this episode here is another message
this one came from this one came from
the CRO from your heart email it says
hey Jeff I'm the French dude that you
answered the question about the light
leaks on your show a few months ago I
think I remember that it says it was
October I think I remember answering a
lot of questions about light leaks but
it goes on to say Here I am again still
listening to your awesome show almost
every day thank you I appreciate that
says lately because of this Kovan
locked-down [ __ ] I was happier than ever
to listen to your show because it is
good to have your positivity and
enthusiasm in this time you have helped
a lot dude that means a lot to me thank
you I know as a content provider that
people kind of turn to us for just an
escape a getaway not only are you
getting some sort of knowledge but
you're just escaping you're not thinking
about all the the Co
[ __ ] or the dumb [ __ ] that's going on in
your life I won't bring any of it up so
you don't think about it right now but
thank you for noticing and thank you for
the for mentioning that but I was
dealing with kovat and Quarantine and
all that [ __ ] as well but I was using
podcasting as an outlet to communicate
with people and keep myself occupied so
I'm glad you guys were using my work as
something to entertain yourselves that
worked out very well for both of us um
it goes on to say my question today is
about lighting I've said it so many
times I'm not a lighting expert lighting
is where I am the most uneducated when
it comes to cannabis cultivation I am
NOT a lighting expert there's a lot for
me to learn when it comes to lighting
keith has taught me a little bit about
lights a couple of other people have
tried to teach me a lot about lights my
brain doesn't absorb that stuff the way
that it absorbs the plant stuff so
hopefully I can answer your lighting
question but I just wanted to be
completely honest it goes on to say I
grow in a 2 by 2 foot tent with a
hundred and twenty watt LED and it says
actual power 120 watts I am pretty
satisfied with it for both flowering and
the growth phase but I'd like to add a
little boost because sometimes you just
want a little bit more light more growth
and more bud yes we all want more growth
in more bud and a good way to get that
is more light it says I'm aiming for
something like a 200 watt for the whole
tent even though I know that talking in
watts is not really accurate I'm really
glad you said that there are many ways
to measure
lights and I don't think that watts are
the way to measure them accurately for
plants I don't think plants know what
watts even are they don't care they want
on the right spectrum I think you moles
per Joule is the proper measurement all
right let me quit talking out of my ass
and we'll get back on track here it says
do you have any advice on supplemental
lighting I thought about adding some
heli D bars something like one bar for
grow and one bar for flowering or maybe
a CFL full-spectrum bulb I wouldn't do
the CFL I would prefer the LEDs but it
is pretty difficult to know which
direction to go nowadays with all the
information on the web I tried the
forum's but I remembered what you said
about Gro advice on the forums in
general
there is a lot of [ __ ] on there yes
the people that own light companies go
and they comment like they're just users
and consumers and then people that don't
know anything about growing they say
that they had a problem or a great
success with the certain light and it
was just a fluke because something else
in their grow was what was magical or
what was wrong so you have to be really
good at fishing through [ __ ] when
you were getting advice on forums so he
says I figured why not simply ask my
buddy from overseas Rasta Jeff it says
so if by any chance you read this email
I'd be really glad to get some help from
you stay safe your buddy Rick from
France what up Rick from France thank
you for the great message it's great to
know that I've got people over in France
listening to the podcast let's talk a
little bit about some grow light advice
for my friend Rick it sounds like you
are close to having enough light in that
2x2 tent it sounds like you want to
almost double up the amount of light I
would if you're gonna do it I would
double up during veg and flour there's
no reason to have certain amount of
light at one point and then not have
full power for the whole cycle just go
full power the whole time so whatever
you're gonna buy make sure you've got
the electricity to run that light both
lights all of the lights make sure
you've got enough power like our
listener before they're flipping
breakers in their house when they try to
run all their gear make sure you've got
the electricity the next thing make sure
you're able to cool it like our listener
before it's too hot in their house they
can't cool it make sure you're able to
cool it with those two things being
thought about and heavily considered
let's talk about a couple of lights
you've got a two by two I would put one
Canon LED from black sale market in that
two by two and it would be [ __ ]
awesome it would be more light than you
need that's a 325 watt light and I think
it would light up your 2 by 2
beautifully I think a cannon is perfect
for a 3 by 3 it is going to light up
your 2 by 2 and your plants are going to
go kaboom Kapow
um so I would shred I would recommend
about 300 watts and that 2 by 2 maybe a
little bit less I think 200 Watts total
will be right about where you want to be
the cannons you can dial them down
they've got a little not Inaba it's
hidden but it's there Keith will show
you where it is and maybe in the
instruction
I didn't read the instruction book I
apologize and I admit it but there is a
little knob you can use a screwdriver
and you can turn down the wattage so you
can get it down to 200 watts I think it
goes that low you can play with the
wattage and you can get it dialed in for
your plants the only thing to consider
is ceiling height as long as you've got
enough height I think a cannon would be
wonderful for you if not I would find
something with a good reputation I would
do a lot of research and I would find
something around 200 watts for your
space it sounds like 200 watts would be
just about perfect for your square
footage I honestly do not know enough
about LED lights nobody pays me to
recommend lighting nobody pays me to
talk about LEDs I'm not sponsored by an
LED company I do have Canon LEDs I grow
with them and they work beautifully my
plants are [ __ ] happy the growth is
beautiful I should have flowered earlier
because they took off in veg I wasn't
prepared for that they got kind of tall
and flower that was my fault
those lights made the plants grow super
super quickly so I recommend the canon
LED from black sale I think you can get
them you said friend from overseas err
in France I think they are available in
France Keith if I am wrong please send
me an update I'd like to give accurate
information about your brand I recommend
you check out black sail market they
have got a website just google black
sail market black sail LED you will find
them on Keith is a great dude he's
really easy to work with
um I don't work with companies if
they're not easy to work with like I've
got a lot of opportunities there are a
lot of products there are a lot of
vendors a lot of brands and if your
product has to be [ __ ] top-notch
that's the most important part but if
your product is top-notch and you're a
dick I still may not use your product if
your product is top-notch and you're
cool as [ __ ] I'm buying your [ __ ] and
talking about you on my show so Keith's
big fist bump bro I approve of your
product you guys black sail market
cannon LEDs they're [ __ ] awesome big
thanks to my buddy Rick from France I
appreciate knowing that I've got friends
out there in France and I appreciate
knowing that I'm helping you out in your
garden and I look forward to hearing
from you again in the future if anybody
else out there has any cannabis culture
or cannabis cultivation questions you
know I would love to hear from you my
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com also if you want to get your
message right to the top of the
go check out patreon.com
how to get your email right to the top
of the list via patreon all right oh
I've got one more thing to talk about I
almost forgot I got a question on
YouTube let's get to this when I got to
find it here in the phone this is my
version of being organized it says I got
more than one message like this where I
would have ignored it but I think it is
time to address this one it says man I'd
like to see your dreads sometime and I
know it's a pain to get long dreads in
the camera but maybe just for a minute
at the end of an episode I just like to
see the texture size and shape that is
kind of a weird odd request but it's
been asked so many times that I think it
is time to bust out the dreadlocks for
you guys
feels a little bit weird it's a gross
show but so I've got them tied in a knot
tight untie that part and then I've got
a hair tie it's actually a [ __ ]
headband that works as a hair tie but
I've got that tied up in here pull out
the hair tie and here's some dreadlocks
you guys this hat is too big but it's
comfortable as [ __ ] I'm showing you the
dress trying to get it going you guys
that are only listening on audio I
apologize you're gonna have to watch the
YouTube channel I'll go to youtube
search for the girl from your heart
podcast and check out this episode and
see the dreadlocks if you're interested
so I've got them all they're down there
hanging down I'm gonna show you the what
did you want to see me the texture size
and shape so I got a couple I'm gonna
say there's a couple of different
textures these are more uniform the
smaller ones that's the texture and size
and shape I guess these are like my
common size ones and then I got a couple
this one that comes from let me get
natural direction some of this may get
edited more I may just leave all this in
the show I'm getting real comfortable
with the video show you guys if you
haven't noticed you got a couple of
thick ones like this chick let me get
this gone this one's real thick here
this one is almost the diameter of a can
of butane I guess it's it's thinner but
I mean you know it's comparable so and I
measured as a joke I don't know if I'm
supposed to say this cuz a friend is
doing a giveaway based on the length of
my dreads but I hope your giveaway is
done before this podcast comes out my
longest dread was 49 inches long we
measured with the tape measure 49 inches
so I'll stand up and show you I'll also
trying to get somebody to snap a photo
for me so that I've got a good stand-up
from the back kind of a picture sorry to
do it right here with this camera just
on the MacBook but I'm stand up show you
the dreads you won't be able to hear me
for a moment but if you're listening on
iTunes or Apple podcasts or stitcher I
invite you to come check us out on the
video here we go show the dreads real
quick
[Music]
you
also I'm six five and they go to my
knees hmm so there's a lot of stuff to
work with that's why you see him tied up
almost all the time
I let him down at concerts and I'm when
I'm not doing stuff you know but it's
hard to have all this hanging from your
head all the time and you're trying to
work in a garden or something so they're
mostly tied up but I appreciate the
question I was time to address that it
was a little bit awkward felt a little
bit weird as I was swinging him around
there but a lot of people asked about it
so I guess it was time to show off the
dreadlocks that's the length the texture
the color the size the shape all the
[ __ ] that you wanted to know not shy
about it can't be shy haven't rocks her
this long you get all the questions
eventually so I hope that wraps that up
for now if anybody else out there has
any I guess dreadlock questions as well
feel free ask away ah yeah that was fun
um also while I'm thinking about it
please check out my friends at Operation
grow I'm part of a thing called
Operation grow sponsored by pl grow
systems is also sponsored by new
millennium nutrients and Auto pot
systems and of course it is sponsored by
I read genetics I'll tell you briefly
about what operation grow is on
operation grow I was I gave mmm let me
correct myself and catch up with my own
thoughts I'm trying to read my notes and
my notes threw me off
what operation grow is I donated packs
of seeds to six growers I think six
growers got the same pack of seeds they
all got orange gasm seeds they were all
given an auto pot system they were all
given new millennium nutrients they're
all growing on the same schedule we are
all talking about our progress and
documenting our grow on operation grow
on YouTube I think you can find it under
Operation grow 2019 because of course it
started in 2019 we know it's 2020 now
but it started back then so what I'm
doing here is I am inviting you to check
out the show operation grow on YouTube
every Saturday ah Mountain time at 2:00
p.m. we go live on YouTube and we talk
about the grow everybody that is
involved in operation grow shows their
progress with the orange gasm plants
they all got seeds they all germinated
at the same time they're all using the
auto pots they're all using new
millennium nutrients the only
differences are the lighting and the
environments and some people got sample
of cocoa as well so I think everybody's
using cocoa there are very few variables
in this experiment everybody also has
APL grow minder unit so we're able to
see the the temperature the humidity the
fluctuations the VPD in these rooms
we're getting pictures we're getting a
lot of documentation it's a really fun
experiment project series that is
happening you can join us I invite you
every Saturday like I said 2:00 p.m.
mountain time I am in Colorado it's a
2:00 p.m. my time I don't know where you
are use your iPhone to let you know what
time we need to tune in or if you missed
the live show it is YouTube and they are
magically left up there forever so you
can go watch them on operation grow 2019
all right I'm glad I caught that note
before I wrapped up the show because
I've gotta give a shout out to my buddy
Pete Pete thank you for letting me be
the breeder to donate the seeds for the
operation and just for being involved
it's fun I'm having a good time I'm
learning about my own genetics I'm
getting data that I never would have had
access to before and in today's modern
world data is everything and I just got
to figure out what the [ __ ] to do with
the data all right so it is time to wrap
up this podcast ladies and gentlemen
boys and girls pimps and hos friends and
foes smokers and growers clone cutters
pollen chuckers all you bad
[ __ ] out there in podcast world
thanks again for listening to another
rambley episode of The Grove from your
heart podcast um if you feel like this
episode was educational informative
and/or entertaining and you'd like to
make a financial contribution of the
show all you have to do is visit
www.reimaverick.com use coupon code g FY
h10 while checking out to save yourself
a few bucks at seeds here now dot-com
once again I got to remind you about the
YouTube channel I invite you to
subscribe to my youtube channel
I appreciate you if you're listening on
one of the audio podcast Foreman per for
the platforms that's the word audio
podcast platforms I couldn't think of
the word platform there I appreciate you
if you're listening bear however I do
invite you to come listen to the show on
YouTube simply go to youtube search for
the girl from your heart podcast
subscribe click on that little bell that
little bell will give you a notification
every time I put out a new episode you
will never miss a show also leave some
comments on the YouTube channel I love
finding cool comments it makes me smile
every day alright ladies and gentlemen
boys and girls that is all I've got for
you for this episode I'll be back in a
couple of days with fresh new content I
want to send a giant shout out to my
friend William law and until next time
take a phat dad and give your mom a hug
for me