welcome back podcast world i'm your host
rosta jeff and it is time for episode
548 of the grow from your heart podcast
this episode of the show is brought to
you by our friends at seedshearnow.com
seeds herenow.com offers seeds from all
the industries
leading breeders including miss jill
genetics duke diamond
and of course irie genetics everything
at seeds herenow.com is backed by an
award-winning satisfaction guarantee
and for my friends on a budget seeds
herenow.com offers
several packs for under thirty dollars
as well as amazing
monthly sales make sure you use coupon
code gfyh10 while checking out to save a
few bucks
again that is coupon code gfyh10 while
checking out
at seeds here now.com
that music you just heard was by our
friend danks for nothing
big thanks and big shout out for the
perfect podcast intro tune i love it
just the right tempo
it's got a great vibe to it i'm really
digging the feel of that for the start
of the show
that one may stick around i will play
more musical submissions as the episodes
progress
i want to stay on track on this episode
because i have got a lot of ground
to cover i do like to start the show by
talking about what i'm smoking
i am still smoking through this jar of
garlic grove
live batter from green dot labs again it
is a blend of gmo cookies and loa
f2 on the package the flavor is
described as general soa
garlic and orange soda i said i
completely agree with that on the last
episode
i also mentioned that this should have a
warning label on it that it has got a
punch in the face it's like a
jack-in-the-box i feel like when i
unscrew this lid
just a fist should come out and just
punch me right in the face but also give
me a hug
it's like the most pleasant punch in the
face you could ever imagine well i've
got the jar open i'll show you
uh beautiful color i like the way the
light shines and reflects off of there a
little bit of sheen a little shimmer
a really delicious concentrate it is
like a a thick cheesecake batter
or maybe a real thick butter i'm really
digging the texture and flavor and
consistency of this it dabs very nicely
obviously it's got me nice and rambly i
did get another jar of this i had to
visit the dispensary to get some
supplies
this one does have a potency label on
the back of this one it says
it contains 68.24 thc and
non-detectable amounts of cbd big shout
out to our friends at green dot labs for
the
tremendous garlic grove live
batter this is the part of the show
where we do a shout out to our friends
in the 710 club how appropriate this is
the 710 episode
big dab big fist bump to everybody in
the 710 club those are the folks who
support us on patreon at the 710 level
or above
let's start off giving a shout out to
the 710 club with the captain
and commander of the 710 club how about
a big thank you shout out to my buddy
lemur priest
bro thank you uh looking you straight in
the face giving you a big thank you bro
big fist bump i appreciate it much
respect let's follow that up with the
big heartfelt thank you to our friend
north north terps thank you bro i love
reading your messages
thank you for the support also i want to
send a thank you shout out to stephen
smith bro you kick ass just because your
name is the same name as one of my
favorite drummers
you get points in my book for that also
today i had the honor of meeting
giant mike and the dab and queen really
cool people got to spend a couple of
moments with them
uh we properly socially distanced
allegedly uh that was a good time
good to meet you guys i hope we hang out
in the future when all the social
distancing and stuff is uh
cleaned up and we can hang out and
actually take some dabs and spend more
than a couple of minutes together
uh hanging out just meeting each other
you guys it was a pleasure it was an
honor look forward to next time shout
out to giant mike and the dab and queen
let's move forward with the big giant
shout out to kurt z kurt i know who you
are bro thank you for all the continued
support i see you out there bro thank
you
i've always got a big thank you shout
out from my buddy og purple thumb keep
killing it bro i love your photos
also i've got a giant thank you for grow
man stan thank you big shout out big
fist bump
also how about a big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out to
totally
white tops thank you for all the love
and support i also need to send a thank
you
to pac north west dan thank you and last
but certainly not least
let's send a big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out and a fist
bump
to my friend shawn23 big thank you
i do appreciate all the support you guys
again if you're not already supporting
the show on patreon and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit www.patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need to support
the show will be right there on the
screen and of course i did include a
link in the show notes and the video
description
to make it easy for all my stoner
friends and all of my working friends i
know a lot of people may be driving
you may be in the cubicle you may be
even in the garden working right now
can't really go type patreon.com a whole
bunch of [ __ ] don't worry
all you have to do is open up the
podcast on wherever you're listening
click on the description or the notes
there will be a link in there hit the
link it'll take you
right to patreon you can support the
show i'll stop smacking the microphone
we'll all be friends forever thank you
guys i do appreciate the support
uh you guys contributed heavily to
making today's episode a success
and possible i've got a large plethora
of concentrates on the table
uh that was probably paid for by patreon
contributions i don't know that i would
have gone and done this if i didn't get
a very
generous patreon contribution at the
start of the month so
that helped you guys out i'm going to
use that funding toward the show so it
paid off immediately
i've got a plethora of concentrates here
i'll try to go through each jar or at
least most of the jars
and i will post a picture of this table
on the grow from your heart podcast
instagram page i'm going to write that
down to remember that
i'll try to do it as i'm editing the
show but post
ig 2 ig that's going to be a better note
so i know what that means but then you
can see what this table looks like
it is beautiful chaos um
2 4 6 8 10 12 14
15 16 17 17 jars
but many of them are four gram jars and
then we've got a 10 gram jar of terp
sauce here
there's a nice collection of
concentrates on the table then we're
going to top off that with a whole bunch
of equipment we'll talk about rigs and
dabbers
maybe a little bit of evolution of
equipment but let me keep myself on ta
on track here patreon thank you guys
where are we going from there
it is the 7 10 episode this episode will
come out on
seven nine that is close enough uh we'll
we'll dab it seven nine i'm dabbing
every day but
7 10 is officially dab day
dab time you can take a dab whenever you
want guys but let's talk about
what is 710 what does 710 mean why am i
celebrating 710 why am i excited about
it
in short 710 is the new 420. look at
that dreadlock here sneaking out gotta
tuck that one back in there for the
camera
uh 710 is the new 420 you guys uh if you
look at the number 710 write the number
710 on a piece of paper and turn it
upside down it says
oil so what do we do at 710 we smoke oil
what kind of oil we smoke
hash oil what kind of hash oil butane
honey oil bho
butane processed honey oil um
i'm not going to go too far but in this
episode i'm not going to teach you how
to make concentrates that is not
something i will cover i'm not a
concentrate maker i am a concentrate
consumer a concentrate connoisseur if
you will we're not going to talk too
much about making it
uh but butane honey oil is made with
butane i know that sounds dangerous if
you don't know a lot about the
concentrates the butane is
easily removed we've figured out systems
to remove the concentrate we'll talk
more about that
but butane honey oil is what bho stands
for that's where the oil
in 710 comes from you turn 710 upside
down it says oil
we're smoking butane honey oil bho if
you've seen bho around
those letters some of this may be old
info for some of you
but i want to start at the beginning
we're going to do the evolution here
this is page 1 of the book
so you've got bho we're smoking butane
hash oil
that's the oil in 710 i really believe
that the phrase 710 was coined by
task rock of highly educated titanium
i'm going to give task
most of the credit i know he was on a
chat with other folks i believe the guy
from healthstone glass was in there and
i'm not sure who else
if you were in there please send me a
message i'll give you some credit for
being in the room
but i've heard the story from task and
him and another guy maybe other guys
were in a chat
they wanted to upgrade 420 they're like
bro we've moved on from smoking weed
we're smoking oil all the time
uh let's come up with a new word and
task was like 7 10 bro so 710 became
the new 420. at 420 all the stoners like
to pack a bowl and smoke a bowl
smoke a bowl of 420 celebrate 420 all
day long on 7
10 we're gonna get dabbed the [ __ ] out
dtfo you guys dab the [ __ ] out
on 710. so shout out to taskrock for
coining the phrase 710
shout out to the 710 movement there's a
lot of a lot of people behind all the
oil movement the concentrate movement i
was lucky and blessed to be here in
colorado where a lot of it happened i
was at the uh
i said i think they say at ground zero
at the forefront of the
evolution of a lot of this stuff so i've
been around since a lot of it started
um so i think i want to talk about some
of the different
types of concentrates and uh different
ways of dabbing and then we'll talk
about some of the
uh gear that you need for a proper dab
sesh so uh
in short dab time is 7 10 and this
episode is all about 7 10
so let's talk about some of the
concentrates we're going to smoke
on 7 10. to the best of my memory most
of it started
with old school shatter i'm going to
bust out some shatter here i've got a
fresh gram of shatter i picked this up
at apothecary farms it's still sealed up
it's brand new
this is a gram of crescendo og shatter
shout out to our friend colin gordon
uh ethos collective at ethos genetics
for the uh
what did he breed here the crescendo i'm
pretty sure that comes from colin
i'm gonna try to bust this open they
make them child proof it is
wookie proof yeah i may need scissors
you guys
got teeth though there we go i got that
[ __ ] open all right we're gonna bust
out some chatter show you what some
shatter looks like this is uh the
container that it comes in
it's got all these state regulations uh
printed on the side here
it's got a bunch of just store stuff
retail stuff uh potency 66.7 percent
uh thc and zero cbd for seventy seven
point nine percent total cannabinoids so
there's thc and something else in there
maybe thcv
uh thc a they didn't list it very well
but
there's other stuff in there other
cannabinoids in there it says
there may be long-term physical or
mental health risks from using
from use of marijuana including
additional risk for women who are
or may become pregnant or are
breastfeeding use of marijuana may
impair your ability to drive a car
or operate machinery this product was
produced without regulatory
regulatory oversight for health safety
or efficacy
this is an inhaled product uh so it's
just got all the regular safety [ __ ] on
the back there that it needs to have
got the fancy apothecary logo on here
shout out to our friends at apothecary
farms
so this is shatter you guys i'm gonna
show you it comes in
customized this is just uh it's like
parchment paper basically don't use wax
paper for your shatter the wax comes off
you want parchment paper
uh get the good shake get the organic
[ __ ] or get your custom-made stuff with
your logo like our friends here at
apothecary
so i'm going to unfold this i'm going to
try not to drop it while i show it to
the camera
sometimes it sticks to the paper
sometimes it slides off the paper this
one's stuck
so this is what shatter looks like it'll
be in different
um colors and consistencies but mainly
this is what you're going to find this
is close to the right color that
is the right color it may be lighter or
darker in color that's not a huge deal
this is right in the middle
this is kind of the color that you'd
expect a little bit lighter would be
better a little bit darker i wouldn't
have bought it
but i got this for the show this is
shatter if it were not
warm this is a warm day in colorado so
right now
it's more uh bendy than it should be but
if this were warm when i did that move
it would just break it would just be a
piece of shatter that's where it got the
name shatter
so this was kind of the uh the start of
the bho oil movement this is the [ __ ]
that got it all going
um i could probably dab this whole thing
right now and not be amazingly high i
would not recommend you do that
but i have moved on to uh we're gonna
show the evolution and show you where we
are now but this is old school
i don't buy this stuff anymore uh but
this is available this is shatter
i should show you uh if you were going
to dab some shatter i've got a
dab tool here i'm just going to show you
what the end of it looks like without
any concentrate on it
i'll put a little dab on here this is
what i would recommend
for a beginner dabber and you're going
to think i'm crazy because
it is a tiny dab that may be more than
enough to make somebody cough and get
them really high
you guys what i put on the dabber is
less than
0.1 of a gram of a dab you can't tell
that i took anything off the dab
i could still give this gram to matt or
mike and say here's a gram and they're
thinking they got a full gram this
you'll never notice that is missing so
that
if you're looking at the video that
little tiny piece is what i would
recommend
you take a dab of it is smaller than a
grain of rice
if that's your first dab do that you can
always take a bigger dab
you can't un-dab the dab that you just
took when you take your first dab
it may be tremendous you may get a heavy
feeling in your lungs
you may get the sweats uh you may cough
you should cough i like the cough that
comes with the dab that
rush that redness your face turns red
you get the sweats you cough a little
bit
sometimes that'll give some people a
panic attack write it bro that's what
you're there for that's what i'm there
for i just took a giant dab i paid money
for it i just [ __ ] myself up i want to
feel something
i don't want to take a dab and feel the
same that's that's a ripoff so
take a little dab and if you don't get
what you want from that first dab take
another one
and if you don't get what you want from
that one take a bigger dab next time but
don't go in like i do
and take a monster dab on the first rib
that's my advice so this is
shatter this is what basically started
the game i showed you how big of a dab
that you should take
i'll show you how big of a dab i would
take i'm not trying to show off i've
just been at this for a while
i'll show you how i go in on some
shatter i would probably do
at least that big of a dab right there
that's how i would get the party started
for some shatter so probably do the
whole gram and cough a couple of times
if that's what we had to do
but i think i'm going to pass this on to
a couple of friends who
smoke more shatter than me now the next
thing i want to talk about
is also shatter but this is the new
fad and shatter technology this is a
gram of strawberry milk shatter this is
one gram i don't know who made the
strawberry milk i apologize
uh the potency label says it is 82.1
percent total thc and 93.4
total cannabinoids so we do have more
potency
in this one on the label than we do in
the other shatter
but this one is what is known as crc
shatter so it has been color it is color
remediation
column and i think the c could also be
chromatography
because i am not a concentrate maker i
am not a scientist
this is not my area of expertise what
i'm talking about right now
i posted to social media please teach me
about crc
i got a lot of feedback a lot of it i'm
trying to open this pack there we go a
lot of it was straight up
bickering and [ __ ] between
concentrate makers and smokers
from what i understand
color remediated concentrate or color
remediation
columns or color remediation
chromatography all of those were typed
in my responses
in in social media when i asked to be
taught about it
basically there are two sides of the
uh opinionated forum here some people
say that it is
polished turds they think that the
color remediation was required because
the starting product was not up to par
so when they ran the material that came
out dark or kind of funky or
smelled bad or tasted weird so then it
is color
remediated to take out all of the crap
then it comes out different
and it is cleaner now there are two
sides two schools of thought here like i
said some people think that that is
amazing
you're cleaning up all product you're
making it safer you're making it cleaner
for patients and consumers
which is a good thing a lot of people
also say that that is
allowing growers and producers to create
a sub
par product because we're just going to
clean it up anyway
so there's a very fine line in crowds uh
on how people
feel about the crc excuse me for the
throat clearing i took a lot of dabs i'm
not even going to edit that this is a
real 710 show um i'm going to show you
oh this is pretty i just now opened this
i should have showed you more of the
opening i'll refold it that's all i did
i pulled the package out of the uh the
main package and then i've got the
parchment the customized apothecary
parchment here
i've got to be careful when i show this
to the camera because this
is more shatter like and it is also
falling out of the parchment because of
the way that i'm tipping it
i'm going to pick it up with my bare
hand that's a bad idea it's going to
melt and stick but this is for the
show's case
that's what the crc looks like if you're
looking at that on the podcast
it is on the video it's much more clear
than the non-remediated product i'll
show it again
and then i will take a photo side by
side and post that
so here's the non-remediated and then
here's the remediated product you can
see
obviously see color differences uh this
one's bright bright yellow this one has
got an amber color
nothing wrong with the amber shader back
in the day the amber shadow is what we
all wanted
is what we were going for now we've got
this crc like i said you guys there are
two camps
people love it or hate it it is polished
turds in some people's mind
it is also a really clean and refined
product in some people's mind
i am not going to go too far down that
rabbit hole i will take a dab of it
after this show or maybe later in the
episode i may leave the video running
i want to develop an opinion on this
myself i should smell it
i should smell it because i hear a lot
about it doesn't have any smell or
flavor or it all smells and tastes the
same i'm going to lean away from the mic
and smell it
yeah there's no smell i don't smell [ __ ]
it smells like the paper and my fingers
that's all it smells like
but that is the crc you guys i will
leave the decision making up to you i'm
not trying to be biased here
i'm telling you that there are two camps
uh some people say that it's great
because we can clean up a product we can
take things out they got left in in the
extraction process
what may have gotten left in i'm not
sure what it can take out but i read
chlorophyll
i also read pesticides they argued that
it could take out pesticides
so i'm not sure you guys there was a lot
of bickering and a lot of uh
controversy in the group when i asked
about that so
that is color remediated shatter we
started smoking shatter
then eventually appeared a product
called wax
wax happens um when so when you make
shatter you want it to sit still while
it purges you put it under a heat source
over a heat source you put heat
underneath it
or in a vacuum oven and you let the
shatter
purge so that the residual butane comes
out of it
we've learned that if you disturb the
shatter while it's sitting there
if you whip it and put air into it it
would make a fluffier consistency and
that would also
in some people's mind it was speeding up
the process of getting that butane out
of the mixture
because we wanted to remove all the
butane wanted a proper purge if you left
butane in there you got told you had
tane soup or poop soup
but eventually we learned how to whip
the product and by whipping shatter it
put air into it
and it turned it into what is known as a
wax
i was trying to pick some of this up but
it's real crumbly i'll try to get this
big chunk
you shouldn't touch your concentrates
with your fingers you guys but this is
for science
so here we go this is wax you can see
it's a little bit dark in color it's not
as
clear as the remediated stuff not quite
as dark as the shatter
it's got a little bit of air in it i
liked back in the day i really liked
clean shatter i thought the clean
shatter
hit well and tasted good i liked
some wax it depends on how it was made
and what the consistency was and what it
tasted like
back in the day we had not mastered the
art
of um removing and removing
uh the terps and processing things
properly and getting the or not not
removing the terps i apologize removing
the butane
preserving the terps my brain was
tripping i had so many thoughts we
weren't pros at it yet so it didn't
taste amazing yet proper wax
was [ __ ] delicious so something i
think i should note about
this wax and the shatter is these are
made from
dried products these can be made from
dried buds
or dried trim once you harvest and you
cut off the sugar leaf
that dry stuff can be used to make wax
and the shatter
so um we got through wax we got you
through shatter
i'll show you this is a white widow wax
i should give a shout out to the people
i got it's white widow wax from
apothecary
the label says 64.1 percent thc
and 76.5 total cannabinoids i'll show
you in the jar without my
grubby fingers on it so you can see what
it looks like uh try not to spill it
there we go
that is the wax for you so it went
shatter and wax
and then we started seeing another
product
called batter batter was kind of between
the shatter and the wax it was
softer and it didn't wax up like the wax
but
it didn't shatter like shatter and it
looked more i'm gonna show you
just so you can get a view of it it
looks like just a little dollop of
cheesecake batter or cake batter or
maybe some thick butter in the bottom of
the jar
you can see at the if i turn the jar
just right you can see how they doll up
to that right into the container
it just has like a little like a thing
of whipped cream or something
it's got that cool little whip at the
top of it the tail it's got that looks
like a hershey kiss in there
so that is batter this is black water
batter from apothecary farms on the
package it says 67.6
total thc and 79.9 percent
total cannabinoids i like batter i like
the batter because
i feel like it expands in my lungs a
little bit i get a big fat dab out of a
little bit of batter
and i feel like it's super terpy most of
the time
terpy flavorful terps are flavor when
i'm talking about terps i'm talking
about the flavor you guys
i usually find the batter to be the most
uh preserved
terps of this type of concentrate that
we've reviewed so far so we started off
with the shatter
then we moved to wax i'd show you let's
show you how big of a dab of the wax to
do because i showed you the shatter
just again little tiny dab of the wax
gonna show you
that that's enough wax to do a fat dab
you guys that's a big dab of wax right
there
that's bigger than you should do that's
going to get you going so
that's the wax now i'll show you how
much batter that you should dab
if you're new at dabbing i'm going to
bust out some of this batter this is
black water dabber from apothecary farms
i'm gonna throw the dabber around just
for good luck then we'll put a dab on
there
just gonna go kind of light just want to
just dip it into there that's why they
call it a dab you guys you just need a
dab not you don't need a [ __ ] dollop
or a glob
you just need a dab that's enough that's
more than enough now that i hold it up
to the camera
that would make mike cough that's enough
to get matt or mike
plenty stoned and they are dabbers you
guys so maybe half of that
and this is again about the size of a
piece of rice i'm going to knock it in
half
it's just hard for me to it just feels
silly the way that i dab it feels silly
to offer
somebody that much concentrate but it's
about half of a piece of rice
that's all you got there so
that is how much of a dab i think you
should do of wax or batter so we've
covered the first three basics
uh those are the first three things that
we kind of fell in love with
that we were dabbing on that was
available that were really popular here
for dabbers that were available
uh in stores then people started
developing new technology
um there was a company i talk about
apothecary farms a lot they did a little
bit of
pioneering in the industry they came up
with their own product
that they called ambrosia ambrosia is a
blend
basically a blend of two different
concentrates in my opinion from my
experience
they made a product called hcfse and
that stands for
high cannabinoid full spectrum extract
i'm going to show you some tropicana
tropicana cookies
full spectrum extract um this is
79.1 percent thc 91
total cannabinoids this is what we call
diamonds you guys i'm going to try to
get this on the camera
that is diamonds basic diamonds
trying to move my notes out of the
screen here so you guys can't see what's
coming up next on the show
those are diamonds you can see that it
looks they're hard i'll touch them with
my finger they move around they're not
soft and squishy
i shouldn't pick them up but i will uh
that's a that's falling apart on my
fingers but that's a diamond for you
that's a good size diamond right there
so that's what we're talking about when
we say diamonds i like diamonds diamonds
are a dabbers best friend
so those are the diamonds then you hear
us talk about
sauce diamonds and sauce the sauce is
the
high terpene full spectrum extract so
they've made a concentrate
and i don't know the science behind this
i'm not claiming to be a concentrate
maker i like to dab
they make a concentrate and they leave
it in solution under pressure that's
enough details there when they do that
the diamonds
sink to the bottom the terps float to
the top right you got the heavy diamonds
on the bottom the liquid up top
so this is the terp sauce i'm tipping
this jar toward the camera the best i
can
it is mostly liquid just pure terps this
is 10 grams of liquid terpenes
not just liquid terps but is mostly
terps uh let me see if there's a potency
label
this is uh 68.2 percent thc and 79.3
total cannabinoids the rest of that is
just terps you guys this is the terp
sauce from apothecary farms
try not to spill it but i want you to
see down in that jar
it's uh thicker than water but not as
thick as honey
almost maple syrup almost as thick as a
maple syrup you guys i don't want to
spill it
but i want you to see what i got going
on in there so
our friends at apothecary made the ht
and the hc but when they introduced
these things
they had mixed them together in what
they were considering the perfect
homogenized blend and they call it
ambrosia
and what i'm going to show you here is
the lost
tribe ambrosia and that is diamonds and
sauce
together you can see the diamonds in
there and you can see the sauce in there
now what i like about this when you dab
the diamonds by themselves
they are very high in thc excuse that
they are very very high in thc but
they're a little bit harsh
and they don't have a lot of flavor and
the high is not
perfectly desirable so in my opinion
the the thc diamonds the high
cannabinoid full spectrum extract the
thc diamonds
that type of concentrate makes you go up
the thc
makes your high go straight up like a
firework fourth of july just happened
makes your brain go up like a firework
then i think the terps
are what give your fireworks colors that
decides if you're gonna get
paranoid if you're gonna get giggles if
you're gonna get [ __ ] munchies
if you're going to get a panic attack so
the thc is going to make you get high
and the terpenes whichever terpenes are
present in your concentrate
are what are going to dictate the type
of high you experience and those
that buzz could be different for
different mind types different
chemistries
uh different people just different
different people get different effects i
really like limonine i think limonene is
good for my brain
limonene gives some people a [ __ ]
panic attack i enjoy it so
um that is the ambrosia that is high
terpene full spectrum extract and that
is
high terpene full spectrum extract i
don't know if i told you that was lemon
g
high chirping full lemon og it smells
like
lemons and gas it's like lemon pledge a
lemon pledge and a skunk punched you
right in the face it's delicious
then we've got the tropicana cookies hc
diamonds and then we've got the lost
tribe ambrosia which is the blend
the homogenized blend of both together
so
we've gotten through the shatter the
batter the wax we've gotten all the way
up to the
terps and the ambrosias something that
a lot of people are into this is not my
thing
not my flavor not for me i'm not hating
it i've just decided that i like other
things better this one makes my lungs
feel heavy
i really like batters but when i smoke
the
sho which stands for solventless honey
oil
uh it is really heavy to my lungs this
one is a
jam band premium ambrosia show from
apothecary farms i'm going to show you
what it looks like then we'll talk about
it
you can see that we did smoke most of it
just because it's not that bad i mean i
paid for it and want to get high so we
smoked it but
again it looks like a little dollop of
cheesecake it's a little lighter in
color than all of the other
uh concentrates like this that i showed
you but
this came from rosin this was pressed
into rosin flowers were pressed into
rosin and then that rosin
was made into bubble hash they made
bubble hash out of the pressed rosin so
there's a big process to this
this is one of the more expensive
products on the market right now
these solventless concentrates are
definitely more expensive they're very
sought after
there's a big crew of concentrate heads
that just loves solventless concentrate
they will pay the premium
and they're they're after it all the
time so this sort of stuff sells out
uh this one is 82.1 percent total
cannabinoids
i love it i get really blazed from it
it's a heavy high you feel like you just
want to sit down and chill the [ __ ] out
it's a video game concentrate
but that's not what i'm going for and
it's also really really
heavy on my lungs um
something else i should talk about rosin
i just said that that came from pressed
rosin let's talk about
original rosin what i've got here is a
piece of parchment paper
what's inside is rosin i'm going to show
this to you
this was made with no chemicals no water
this was made with heat and pressure so
i've got a friend who takes buds and
there are several different methods of
doing this
i've seen it done with a hair
straightener i've seen it done with a
hydraulic press
i've seen it done with everything in
between uh shout out to my buddy pedro
for making the best [ __ ] rosin that i
have ever smoked
um this came from a local friend so they
take a bud
and they put it in something with heat
imagine the hair straightener it's got
two hot plates you press it together
whatever goes in the middle there is
going to get squished and get hot put a
bunch of pressure on it heat it up to
just the right temperature
fold up a bud and parchment paper and
put it in between there and press it
this is what comes out we call this hash
rosin
just flour rosin i'm sorry this is flour
this came out from a squished and heated
bud it just dripped right out into the
parchment paper
you guys i don't make the product but i
do know what it looks like and i do know
how to smoke it and i am kind of excited
about this
it is not my favorite concentrate but to
see people able to make their own
concentrates at home without any
dangerous products because making bho
and all this other stuff you can put
yourself in danger this was done with
hot with just [ __ ] a hot [ __ ] hair
straightener
or maybe a hydraulic press so you're
just squishing buds and some
there's a lot of tech to it if you're
gonna make your uh your roster make sure
you do the research don't take my advice
but
this can be done at home for very
affordable prices you just need to
squish nugs you need nugs
and a squish source they pressed it and
there it is
rosin is not my favorite because most of
the time i think it tastes like a burnt
popsicle stick
or a popsicle stick or a burnt popcorn
and it just doesn't dab right for me
it's not what i like
a lot of people love it don't let me
sway you because i don't like it you may
[ __ ] love it so
that's how much roz and i would dab if i
were going to dab a dab of rosin that's
all you need if you're a new dabber
if you're an experienced dabber you know
how much to take for yourself go in but
if you're new i want you to go light
like i said earlier you can't un-dab the
dab you just took
you gotta deal with it you gotta cough
you gotta have that panic attack you
gotta do all that [ __ ]
i'm looking at my notes to make sure i
covered all this stuff that i wanna
cover
um something i did not buy any of is
distillate distillate is um it's
distilled [ __ ] concentrates they make
a concentrate
and sometimes concentrates are not up to
par or sometimes they want to do
different things with different
components of the concentrate they can
separate each cannabinoid the thca
the cbd whatever cannabinoid you're
looking for they can pull it out in
separate columns then
they can take uh the terpenes and
separate them into different columns
when they sell just the thca or just the
cbd in a liquid form after it's been
distilled that is a distillate
a lot of times we refer to that as hot
dog water it's quite the same as the crc
tech people think it is polished turds
you were taking concentrate that was not
up to par
go ahead and distill it clean it out
separate all the [ __ ] then you can put
your own very specific blend of terps
and thc
into the pens into your rigs into your
vape carts and you can sell that however
you'd like
so that is distillate i did not buy any
uh
it is clear and it looks a lot like the
uh terp sauce that i showed you
i'm not into it didn't spend any money
on it i used to really like it
then companies started when it first
came out i think the companies were
using quality material
as time went on it got funky it got
worse it's like the bottom of the barrel
we call it hot dog water now
sorry if you're making distill it and i
just [ __ ] all over your stuff hopefully
you're making good stuff but be careful
with the distillate
all right um so most of what i showed
you
is made can be made from dry products a
lot of things have to be made from a
fresh
frozen product um i didn't go over live
resin i don't have any live resin
live resin has a lot of different
textures and consistencies that is made
from fresh frozen concentrates you have
to cut down or fresh frozen plants
you have to cut down your plants take
off the big leaves then freeze it
then you run that through a butane
extraction machine and it comes out
super turpy and delicious you get the
essence of that fresh plant because
heat and light destroy terpenes when you
cut it down and freeze it and then
extract it
you've just preserved all the magic and
it tastes so delicious
so that is live resin now i'm going to
show you
what i believe to be live batter this is
batter that was made
from fresh frozen plants this is the
garlic grove i'm going to crack it open
and show you that one again
this is the live batter from yeah it
says live batter so that means that
gives me the
opinion that it was made from fresh
frozen plants so that's the live batter
it's very similar to the non-live batter
the other batter i showed you
may have been a frozen batter as well
and they don't indicate that on their
package this one i know was fresh frozen
um just because i showed you the
apothecary diamonds and sauce i want to
show you some green dot labs
we call this full spectrum extract this
is the
high terpene full spectrum extract and
the
high cannabinoid full spectrum extract
sold together
from another company instead of using
the proprietary ambrosia term
at green dot labs they call it a full
spectrum extract we say
fse um i want to show you this one had a
nice diamond in here this is the garlic
banger
i really love the chunky diamonds in
there you can see those diamonds if i
tip it too long the terp sauce will run
out
but there's the diamonds in there uh
that is the green dot labs i also want
to show you this holy [ __ ] just because
it's beautiful
and it's called holy [ __ ] look it really
says that on the jar holy [ __ ]
from con from green dot labs full
spectrum extract
got a really cool logo i want to show
you the
concentrate see that that's a nice ratio
of diamonds to sauce
so that's what the diamonds and sauce
the full spectrum extract looks like
i think i've showed you most of the
concentrates on the table i do have
some head banger and some sexy peach but
there's consistencies that you've
already seen
so i think now it is time to work our
way toward talking about
the equipment that we need and use when
we are dabbing let me read my list to
make sure i got it all shattered crc
wax batter diamonds and sauce ambrosia
fse show distillate rosin yeah we got it
all you guys
i feel secure moving on to the gear
section um in the gear section of the
podcast i want to start by showing you
what has become my favorite dab setup
this is nice and easy
uh not super expensive this is something
everybody has access to
a lot of people like a really colorful
fancy rig from a glass artist that they
know
i love that i like a rig that i know
hits like a [ __ ] truck
ran my face over this is my favorite rig
it has got a big fat
flared out mouthpiece so that when i put
my mouth on it it fits perfectly
my mouth goes in there instead of on the
outside it's more like i'm blowing a
trumpet instead of sucking a peepee
it fits better uh when i take a giant
dab
if i've got a really small peepee shaped
mouthpiece or something with an awkward
hole in it
i get a bunch of concentrate built up on
my lips because i take big dabs
this big flared out mouthpiece doesn't
concentrate my dab my smoke into one
tiny spot
i really like that it's good for a
mustache guy i got some some sort of
facial hair all the time
so i like the flared out mouthpiece
you'll notice this rig
is fairly small this is probably three
and a half inches tall in the main
can piece we don't need a big
rig this is not a bong when you're
smoking a bong
you want to fill a big section with
smoke and then pull the carb
so you can get that all that smoke to
your face we're not going to carve the
dab rig
you're going to put the dab on there
you're going to put a cap on it you're
going to spin it around and that smoke
is going to go through the water to your
face there's no chamber to fill
there's no space you don't need that big
dab that pull you don't need that i like
a small
rig you'll notice my nail or banger of
choice today
is just a basic this is called a banger
just a basic banger it's a 90 degree
banger
uh we'll talk more about bangers in just
a moment this is my
weapon of choice when it comes to
dabbing i heat this piece up until it's
the desired temperature i set my i've
got a dabber
i place the dab in here using my dabber
but dapper's got a hair on it beautiful
timing couldn't have been better
there we go put the dab right in there
once the dab is in there i put a cap on
it we'll talk about the cap and what it
does in just a moment
and then i just inhale slowly until i've
got my dab um so that is my
favorite rig right now i like the
smaller rig better it's better than a
bong in my opinion i like the flared
mouthpiece
um well let's talk about the perk i
don't need a lot of water it's kind of
dirty in there sorry i should have
cleaned that but this is reality it's a
[ __ ] 710 show i've been dabbing
i like this one it's got a stem that
goes straight down to the water then it
splits off two directions they call that
a hammerhead
this is a hitman hammerhead sidecar is
what this is known as
but that two-way perk in there gives me
plenty of good filtration
just enough to cool down the smoke and
make it not super hot by the time it
gets to my lung i'll inhale through the
rig and you can see the bubbles on both
sides
i'm not sure how clear that comes up on
the camera but that is the hitman
hammerhead sidecar my rig my weapon of
choice
let's talk more about some other
equipment when i first got into dabbing
the first real dab i started by dabbing
by putting concentrates in a bowl and
smoking it in a bowl
and that was a waste it got me really
high but it wasn't efficient and
effective
my first real dab off of a real dab rig
came from daniel desai at the broadway
wellness booth
at the high times cannabis cup in denver
colorado at the
expo uh the endo what was that called
[ __ ] expo mart expo
i forget the name of the place a little
tiny shitty place
uh not the big place not the denver mart
but x dough it was x dough is what i
think the name of the place was
but shout out to big d he gave me my
first real dab i took that dab off of a
device
known as a skillet i don't have a
skillet anymore mine was donated for
science or history
with the skill it was it fit inside of
your bong or your rig
your existing smoking apparatus and it
had a piece that came up
out of the the female part of the bowl
wherever your bowl would slide into your
bong
it would slide into there just like your
bowl and then it had
it went straight up and then it curved
down and hung upside down it looked like
an upside down or a right side up bell
actually the bell part flared
and pointed down then it had a piece of
like aluminum wrap wrapped around it
looked like a hippie made it made you a
wire wrap and i had one piece that
extended to underneath that bell then
underneath that bell would go
a round piece of titanium and that was a
skillet plate
so you'd be able to swing it up since it
was on the it's wrapped around
the curved piece [ __ ] i'm messing this
description all up
so it goes up and it curves straight
down so you got a [ __ ] 180 degree
angle goes straight up
goes it does a u-turn you turn peace at
the middle of that u-turn you would wrap
the titanium [ __ ]
twine or wire and then you could spin it
up and down to where you could move
the plate in and out from underneath the
bell i think that makes sense now so you
got a u-turn the bottom of the u-turn
is a bell at one end and it attaches to
your bong at the other
i've got some resin on my finger if you
see that in the video
just resin don't worry so you got your
u-turn bell on one side goes into the
rig on the other
then they've got the skillet that swings
up and down so you can swing it up
heat it swing it back down it goes under
the bell you would swing it up and heat
it long enough
then you would slide it under the bell
and then you'd put your dab on there and
then when the dab melts
your bell is basically right above it
and it would just go right into there
when you inhale i think that makes sense
that was the original way to dab i saw a
lot of people put their dab on the
skillet and tip the rig and the [ __ ]
dab would run right off the skillet
i saw a lot of carnage from that we were
heating
that [ __ ] skillet till it was glowing
orange and then hitting it we've learned
that that is not the way to do it
we've evolved a little bit since then so
the first dabs were coming
off of a skillet i wish i had one here
to show you like i said i donated that
one to history
but the thing we got right after that
was the
domed titanium nail i'm going to take a
little sip of this
water and then i'll show you a domed
titanium nail
so this rig is a little tiny rig from a
local glass artist called solomino glass
shout out to solomon i don't know if
he's still around i think he may have
gone to denver
hope you're well bro haven't seen you in
a minute but
this is a little tiny rig known as a
mini rig it's got a 14 millimeter
male joint this joint is a male so you
need a
female dome to go on your male rig but
what we would do is we would put this
piece in there this is called a nail
and if you're not watching the video
i'll try to describe it it kind of looks
like a screw
it's got a long piece and then a top to
it like a head of a screw
but it's also would have a nut on it and
you would use that nut
to uh adjust the height so you put the
long end of the screw
into the rig and adjust the nut to where
the head of the nut is sticking out
and then you would heat it up you would
heat up the head of the screw part i'm
pointing at it on the video here we
would heat this part up
and then we would put the dome over it
so that your dab doesn't get away
and then you put your dab on the dabber
and put your dab onto the nail through
the dome so you've got
your nail would basically sit where your
slide would go into your bong but it
fits inside of there
this goes into the hole and rests on
that this the nut part
holds it in place so it doesn't go too
deep you heat that part up so now it's
nice and hot
then you place your dome over it and
then you put the dab onto the nail
and now the dab doesn't disappear it
doesn't just fly off into nowhere
because it's got the dome
then as you inhale if you choose to you
can kind of cover the dome a little bit
with your fingers and regulate the
airflow
and we'll talk about carb capping and
that stuff here in a moment but
that is where we evolved we went from
the swing arm skillet to the
domed nail a big shout out to taskrock
for the nail that he made here i think
this was called the flux nail this is a
14 millimeter
flux nail from highly educated big shout
out this one is
chased and burnt to [ __ ] it's time for a
new one but i don't use this anymore
just had it around on the shelf for a
good experiment so you throw this bad
[ __ ] in here heat it up with the torch
put that on there drop your dab in there
then hit it cap it with your fingers
that is how the dabbing evolved from the
skillet
then i think everybody got tired of
taking the dome off and losing domes and
dropping domes and having to carry a
dome around
also the dome would get stick stuck if
you would take a dab
and the dab would drip down a little bit
it would get [ __ ] stuck and you'd
have to heat it up a little bit with
your torch to get the dome off
uh we got tired of the domes you guys so
that is when
we found domeless nails big shout out to
our friend taskrock once again
highly educated for the domeless dab
nail this looks like a rook from a chess
piece
it's got a tapered bottom it's got two
heat sinks so that the heat doesn't get
too much to your rig
then it has got a big top with a big
moat
type dish in there and then it's got a
cylinder down the middle
so where your dab doesn't fall right
down the middle hole it's got a
cylindrical piece that sticks up
kind of a chimney if you're watching the
video it will all make sense to you
this is a domeless nail this one is a
female this one fits on the outside
if it's right over there on the outside
of that just like the dome does
then you would heat this part up you'd
use your dab tool to put your dab right
in there cha-ching
then that is where the carb cap comes
into play
the device i've got in my hand is known
as a carb cap this is from highly
educated titanium also
it's got a couple of tips available i
like the flat tip you can pick up some
shatter
then you put your shatter onto the
dabber after you've heated it up
then the carb cap fits right over the
top of the domeless nail
i know we didn't have a dome now we're
just using a cap right but what you can
do
you can use this and turn it and it's
got one hole inside of there
i'm trying to get the hole on the camera
there's the hole you turn this while
it's on top of the nail and that will
move the oil around
on that nail to disperse the oil better
and get it to fresh heat because
sometimes the nail will cool as the oil
hits on there
if you take a big dab like i do it will
cool over time so that is a carb cap
uh we didn't have to take the dome off
every time you could scoop up your dab
heat it up drop your dab on there put
the cap on it and be ready to rock
wasn't as much work very convenient that
was the evolution
so where do we go from uh domeless nails
where am i where am i
uh skillet dome domeless oh that is
where we moved into
bangers and carb caps let me get some of
this stuff out of my way try to keep
myself
organized and on track bangers and carb
caps these have become my favorite way
to dab
i'll show you a couple of different
examples i showed you this one here
this is a female banger
it's got a the hole is on the bottom it
fits onto a male rig that's a female
banger that's a 14
a 14 millimeter is the size of the hole
this is a
male banger it's slightly stuck in the
rig i may have to apply some heat there
we go
that's just resonating it gets stuck
this is a male this one goes into the
hole does that make sense to you guys
the male goes into the hole the female
receives the piece so the joint is a
female the nail is a male
this is a 14 millimeter banger as well
uh neither one of these are very
expensive bangers if you want to be the
guy that buys the expensive stuff go for
it if you want to buy something not
overpriced
go for that try to find something
american-made that's my biggest
recommendation but those are
your dab bangers uh where do we have to
go from there
a bubble cap a banger isn't a banger
without a good bubble cap so let me show
you a carb cap and we'll talk about what
a carb cap does
and why we're using these things also
big shout out to blissful glass
for the grow from your heart podcast dab
rig you did a wonderful job i [ __ ]
love it
thank you big shout out make sure you
guys follow i'm 99
sure that was blissful glass give them a
follow so a carb cap
i've talked about taking a dab you're
gonna heat this up drop your dab in here
we'll do that in a moment
uh then you're gonna put a carb cap on
it why and what
what the [ __ ] does this carb cap do when
you put the cap in here
you'll notice it restricts the airflow
when i inhale watch when i inhale
without it
now watch when i inhale with it
you can hear and see the restricted
airflow the hole is smaller not as much
air can get in here
that creates a vacuum and it creates
a it requires that's what i want it
requires
less heat to make my dab uh
vaporize or volatize whatever the word
is it takes less heat to get my dab to
turn into a vapor that i can get through
the rig
so without the intense heat i do not
burn my dab off
i don't burn off the terps i don't burn
off the cannabinoids i can get a little
lower temperature
and i don't burn my throat my lungs my
esophagus it's a smoother dab
and it tastes a little bit a lot better
honestly when you cap it so that's the
reason of a carb cap
i'm gonna veer off of my notes here
because i forgot to talk
about um cold start dabs some people
will put their concentrate in the banger
and then heat it up that's acceptable as
well i like to heat the banger and then
drop the dab in there
the reason for the cold start dab and i
didn't talk about inserts either let me
make a note on this paper to talk about
inserts i skipped that
inserts hopefully i look down and see
this um cold start dabs
cold start dabs are closer is what some
people prefer that way you don't scorch
the dab you don't fry it up
you're actually getting it as it's
heating up instead of dropping it onto a
hot surface
imagine if you drop something onto a
scorching hot surface you just sing it
right away
if you bring it up to temperature and
then smoke it as it reaches temperature
you get it at that perfect boiling or
volatizing or vaporizing point i don't
know the correct term
so a lot of people do cold start dabs um
insert dabs i don't have my inserts set
up here in front of me i should have
grabbed that
an insert looks like a little tiny
thimble and you put your concentrate in
the glass
thimble then you heat the banger and
drop the insert
into the banger and put the carb cap on
it
this is a very similar approach as a
cold start dab
you're not singing the dab right away
it's sort of like a double boiler like
if you're trying to melt chocolate
if you put chocolate in a pan and turn
up the heat the chocolate is going to
burn and stick to the pan
if you put a pan of water on the stove
and then put your pan of chocolate
inside that water you'll slowly heat the
chocolate and it won't burn itself and
it doesn't scorch that's the same idea
as doing an insert dab you're catching
the dab as it heats up instead of at the
scorching temperature
so that's an insert dab i had to make
sure to include that because i did
leave that out on my notes and shout out
to my new mexico crew
who's always killing me with those
[ __ ] insert dabs love you for it but
god my lungs are hurting
uh where are we gonna go from there
banger and bubble cap showed you the
male
and the female banger um now this is
something fun you guys
i've got a really fun device here in
front of me that i may be able to move
it a little bit but i don't want to get
too crazy
eventually we got tired [ __ ] potheads
we got lazy
and got tired of heating up the dab nail
constantly between dabs
uh waiting for it to cool to the right
temperature you heat it up you let it
cool down
then you put the dab on there you take
your dab you set it down next guy scoops
up his dab [ __ ] heats it repeats it
it takes a little bit to get a couple of
dabs in you
and if you want to have a nice dab
session you can go through a little bit
of butane
also some people didn't want us using
butane in some places we were allowed to
consume but we couldn't have a torch you
couldn't be blasting the [ __ ] butane
torch
so that is where we became uh [ __ ]
techno
technologically advanced and we got
something called
an email what i'm showing you here is a
ceramic
dab nail some dab nails were made out of
ceramic some people feel that the
ceramic
preserves the flavor better than the
titanium or the quartz
i think the quartz is definitely better
in flavor than the titanium that's why i
liked it so i switched
the ceramic is great but it's not my
favorite i'm not 100 sold but you can
see that i do have it and i do
enjoy it it does give a nice flavor but
it takes maintenance
and it will break eventually i think but
this is a quality ceramic nail
and a quality ceramic email shout out to
our friends at b nail
a big shout out to ollie at b nails for
a great hookup on the email
i love this thing uh this has made
quarantine easier
i'm not bitching about the ceramic nail
it's just not my favorite i'm honest
with you guys
if this was a quartz banger on this
email i would be hitting this
all of the time but the ceramic is
simply not my favorite
just being honest with you um it doesn't
cap as well
and it's just not for me i like the the
banger with the bubble cap so
this cord this is a heated element there
is heat coming off of this right
now you can't see it but this is hot
this cord is running to a box right here
i'll try to show you the box
it's plugged in and it's also attached
to this so i've got to be gingerly with
this
uh this box right here this end plugs
into the wall
this end right here is plugged in to
here and you can see it's got the number
715 on it it's set at 710 but it's
about 712 sorry i'm dyslexic it's a 713
now 714
this is keeping a constant temperature
on the top of this dab nail
so right now if i decided to which why
the [ __ ] not
i could scoot myself a dab of this
garlic grove live batter
and this is always hot there's no
maintenance there's no prep
all i got to do is get a dab put it on
the dabber and i'll show you how we hit
the email you guys
just because why wouldn't i do it right
i'm gonna move the mic out of my face
we're gonna take a dab it's already hot
it's ready to go i'll put a cap on it
take a dab and we'll talk more if you're
dabbing now's the time
cheers
you guys if you are new at dabbing do
not take a dab that big
that is a professional dabbers dab and
i'm sure you noticed that when i dropped
the cap
on that nail the smoke got even thicker
i've got the temperature to that nail
set kind of low
and the concentrate just bubbles when
you set it on there it doesn't volatize
but as soon as you put that cap on there
it's like putting a lid on a pan it just
traps that heat just cooks it a little
more quickly
it really gives you a solid dab that
tasted delicious by the way shout out to
our friends the green dot labs for the
garlic grove live batter
it's been some of my favorite [ __ ]
lately i'm just gonna ramble for a
minute and get my [ __ ] together
we'll get this show moving again trust
me that was a delicious dab
so i've showed you the ceramic nail i've
showed you the titanium
i've showed you the quartz crystal
banger
showed you a lot of great [ __ ] where are
we going to go from here oh i know
where do we go now we will go to the
terp pearls
something that came really popular for a
little while was a device known as the
terp
pearl i'll show you what a tert pearl is
it's real simple it is
these are little glass balls it's hard
to show you on the camera without
dropping them
just little exactly what they sound like
round perfectly round
glass balls try to pick them up here
there you go two round glass balls and
what we do with the dirt pearls
is you get your banger and you gently
they're gonna make a tinky noise that i
hate the sound of it but
you drop them right in there and then
when you take a dab
the idea is that those terp pearls will
spin around
under the pressure of the carb cap and
they move the oil around
in your banger to where they touch more
of the surface of the banger to where
your oil doesn't sit in one spot and
cool down one area
it'll move it all over the place and
keep the they also hold heat so they're
melting your dab while they're doing it
instead of your dab puddling up in one
spot it just makes you get a longer
cleaner better draw out of a dab and
i'll show you what happens
uh there's a certain you have to use a
certain kind of carb cap to make it work
uh here's the cap that works when you
put it on here and then you draw through
it if you watch on the camera
i don't know if you could see it through
the uh the murky part of that nail but
those
little balls in there were rapidly
spinning around the edges of that
banger so if you suck at the right
temperature and you've got oil in there
it'll just keep that or not the right
temperature the right pressure it'll
keep those balls moving around that'll
just keep your oil moving over the heat
you don't burn the dab you don't create
a puddle you get a bigger fatter dab for
people who take big dabs that is
definitely a good thing to do
i don't do it i just use the bubble cap
i take a big fat dab
you've got to clean the turf pearls
often i just more [ __ ] to clean it was a
fad for a little bit
uh give it a try if you're into it you
may love it some people love it just for
the novelty
some people are into it i'll show you
one more time see if they spin in there
you can definitely hear them oh it's
intense when you take a dab with no dab
and you're just sucking
and sucking all right let me put these
pearls away where are we gonna go from
here
i think that covers most of the dabbing
equipment if you feel like i've
forgotten any uh
legends that should have been included
in the list please send me an email the
email address is grow from your heart
hotmail.com now let's talk about some of
the other things
that are required for taking dabs oh i
almost forgot to show you also
i've got a titanium nail for the e-nail
system this
just a different cord you just plug this
one in it's got a titanium nail
this one again is from highly educated
titanium so if i decided to switch up to
the tie
i can do that but i do prefer the
ceramic over the titanium but i prefer
the quartz
over everything just my personal opinion
you guys
nobody really pays me to say any of this
stuff so let's move on to
the extra parts that we need for dabbing
something you can't dab without
the torch bro uh without an email you
definitely need a torch
so you're gonna have to be able to heat
up your banger somehow so let's start
from the beginning you got a banger
you got a rig you got a rig with a
banger you need that part then you'll
need a torch
you'll need a torch to heat up the
banger then you will need
a dabber to put the dab into the banger
then i highly recommend
a carb cap i like a nice bubble carb cap
if you're going to go with terp pearls
make sure you get the appropriate carb
cap that will make the turf pearl spin
uh when you're shopping for your pearls
the appropriate carb cat probably will
be right next to them if you've got a
good reputable reputable reliable
head shop or if you're shopping online
they should pop up in the same
should be like people that bought that
also bought this so your basics are
uh your rig your torch your dabber your
carb cap and a quality concentrate
after that you're gonna need a few
extras we're gonna need to fill
the torch because a guy like me goes
through a lot of butane
and while we're talking about torches
let me back up
i love you guys i love all of you i want
you all to take dabs
but please just go get yourself like a
cigar torch or a little torch like this
that doesn't look like a big crack head
torch
you guys that are dabbing with the
[ __ ] big blue torch on your front
porch or at the campsite
that [ __ ] looks terrible dude i don't
know it just looks crackhead ish
to me i love you guys just go get a
torch bro just take some butane they're
not that expensive
uh just just it looks better it looks so
much better than that big [ __ ]
canister torch that you're using come on
crackhead magoo
i love you anyway either way you're
going to need some butane to fill your
torch
butane is not expensive you don't need
any fancy kind of butane don't let them
really upsell you
if you've got a normal torch the cheap
butane is going to be fine if you buy an
expensive torch you may want to get a
little pricier butane
they claim there are additives and other
[ __ ] in the cheap butane i don't know
i'm not an expert there but it could
clog up your torch it could [ __ ] it up
so if you get an expensive torch get
good butane
this thing was like 30 or 40 bucks i
don't know if that's expensive or not to
you
it's got two flames and it says the name
of the brand and it says the name of the
brand they better work together
these came from uh this one actually
came from new mexico this one came from
a local shop
so you're gonna need some butane to keep
the dab torch moving
uh something else i recommend is a q-tip
why do i recommend some q-tips i've
always got a
thing a glob mop sitting around because
most of the time you can see that this
banger
is a little bit cleaner than the other
one after i take a dab once it's cooled
off a little bit i'll take a q-tip or
two
and just mop out the crap right out of
the banger just mop it up just
clean it right on out so that the next
time i dab it it doesn't taste like [ __ ]
these q-tips have a pointed end and a
rounded
excuse me and get that pointed in down
in there into the corner then use the
round end to clean it up
i also have another little container
over here that acts as a trash can
every couple of days i gotta dump that
out get rid of all my uh my
dirty ass q-tips so q-tips are very
useful if you're gonna use a banger i
also q-tip
out the uh quartz or the uh what's it
called again the ceramic banger
if i remember i didn't do it this time
wasn't paying attention was just keep
keeping the show moving so another thing
i recommend
it will come in very handy in your dab
life which right now during the covid
situation
is kind of a commodity but some sort of
isopropyl alcohol some
91 or better rubbing alcohol
when you're dabbing life will get sticky
i just set this dabber down right here
on the table
and the back of it is sticky from my
dabs and i got a sticky spot
my carb cap rolled across the table now
i got a sticky spot
now i'm gonna move it over here out of
my way and now i've got two sticky spots
uh everything is sticky and it's only
been a few minutes since i've cleaned
the table i cleaned up before i did this
podcast
everything is sticky over here now a
little bit of isopropyl alcohol will fix
that right up it'll be your friend
i also like to have alcohol wipes i
don't have them out right now because
i'm here by myself but the little square
packets of alcohol wipes i like those if
you happen to be dabbing with friends
before and or after a covid situation i
would still clean the rig with those
just clean the mouthpiece i got a
mustache girls wear a lipstick
just clean the [ __ ] mouthpiece
occasionally every couple of dabbers if
you don't know the guy before you don't
feel bad about cleaning the [ __ ]
mouthpiece even if you do know him
don't feel bad about cleaning the
mouthpiece here see we're seeing why
covet is why we should clean mouthpieces
you can't trust anybody's
spit or anything now you got to take
care of ourselves but the little alcohol
wipes
are always handy i like to have those
especially at events where we're smoking
in a
community fashion uh what else do we
need to talk about
an oil slick pad um
most of this entire table is covered in
a slick pad i'm gonna try to tip the
camera down and show you what i'm
talking about
this green and white pad here is a slick
pad
nothing sticks to it uh it doesn't it's
got a couple of burn marks on it from
cleaning nails and [ __ ] but
it's it keeps the table safe so that my
table doesn't get real super sticky
this part the stickiness wipes right off
real easy with a little bit of rubbing
alcohol
i recommend a couple of slick mats or
slick pads somewhere to store your
concentrates keep your computer desk or
your dab in space
sticky free don't get your mom's table
all sticky whatever you're doing
uh they're just a really good investment
keeps it nice and clean for you
um also some paper towels put them right
next to your rubbing alcohol because
you're gonna need to
need to clean the table quite often uh
you'll see me sometimes doing a podcast
reach my arm up and rub my forearm it's
because i just stuck it in a [ __ ] dab
so clean the table a lot
all right i think that covers most of
the concentrates i covered most of the
gear i'm looking at all the [ __ ] on the
table i think i covered that
um a couple of different rig styles i
should talk about this is your normal
perk type rig it's got the down stem and
the hammerhead we talked about that
um i hit out of this one here this one's
got like a honeycomb rig if you notice
the smoke goes down and then through
this then there is a disc in here
with holes on the top that make the
smoke go straight up so that's a really
cool filtration system this bubble here
prevents the water from going too high
and splashing me in the face
i'll give a little pull of that you can
see the honeycomb style perk
i don't know if you can see how that
water just goes straight up gives it a
whole lot of filtration a whole bunch of
micro bubbles in there
uh we've got of course the grow from
your heart podcast rig just got a little
down stem with two holes
call that a two hole diffie could be
more than two holes now that i'm looking
at it
but it's got some holes in there uh nice
and simple i like a nice i like this one
because it's nice and small
fits maybe it fits in the cup holder
allegedly perfectly i don't know what
i'm talking about
i like a little mini rig these used to
be all the rage this one went to a
couple of cannabis cups because it's
easy to carry around and it doesn't
topple over
then this one is a little bit unique
this one uh
it's known there's a company that makes
rigs like this they call them a klein
uh this company calls it an in-cycler if
you look at it
the smoke would go down this way then it
would go in through here
then it goes up like the other rig
through the honeycomb
but then as it goes up the water
falls into these holes i don't know if
yeah you can see there's a hole here
there's a hole here in another hole
on the inside of this rig there's a cone
so the water would fall into the holes
of the cone
then it swirls like a tornado goes down
then out of this drain on the back of
the rig
then back toward the bottom so the water
is going up and then recycling through
the
condular shape then through the funnel
then through the drain
then back up so the water is moving as
well it's known as an
end cycler it's a recycler but inside of
ourselves inside of itself
i'll give a little pull so you can see
what it does watch for the water to fill
the holes at the top and then fill the
cylinder on the inside and swirl back
down
that's the neat part just a lot of cool
filtration is why i like this one big
nice smooth dabs
but here we go i'll give it a pull so
you can see
you can see where the water drains back
down in you guys i do encourage you if
you're listening to this on an audio
format this is one that you're going to
want to catch on video
i encourage you go to youtube uh search
for the grow from your heart podcast
even if you can't watch the videos all
the time please subscribe check this one
out leave some comments
uh this is a the 7 10 2020 video i hope
you're digging it
all right where are we going to go from
there you guys i showed you a bunch of
cool rigs
let's talk i talked a little bit about
dab size do small
dabs like i keep saying you can't undo
that dab
if you get too high you're not going to
enjoy it you're not going to want to dab
anymore you may get paranoid you'll get
uncomfortable
i'm not trying to discourage you take a
small dab and enjoy yourself
take seven little dabs and enjoy
yourself then later on in the week take
a bigger dab
then work your way up you guys see me
doing monster dabs don't try to be like
me
i'm not saying i'm cool i'm not saying
i'm robocop i'm saying if you're new the
dabs i do are gonna [ __ ] your whole day
up and you're not gonna enjoy it
i've been doing this for a long time i'm
a [ __ ] pothead i've been training i'm
a black dog say that a lot
not only am i a black belt and growing
i'm a [ __ ] dab in black belt so
be careful um that's not from my ego you
guys that is from
my heart caring about you i'm not trying
to say i'm a monster dabber it sounds
like i'm bragging or something
it's i'm not i'm saying i do heroic
doses and i don't want to watch you try
to be a hero and hurt yourself so
do small dabs now let's talk about dab
temperature i do kind of big dabs
so my dabs are hotter than the average
bearer
when i heat up the nail i usually heat
it up until it's almost to the point of
glow
right now you don't need it to glow but
i know right to where it's about to glow
then i'll put my hand by it i hold my
hand about
it's probably a half an inch maybe yeah
i'm going to say a good half an inch
away from the nail
i want to feel the heat of the nail kind
of i don't want to touch it i know if i
touch it at that temperature it's going
to breath it's going to [ __ ] suck
but i can get real close it's not going
to cook my hand if i touch it
but i want it to feel you can feel the
moisture being cooked out of your skin
when you get close to it i know that
sounds bad but
it's just a pinch it's not a burn it's
not a hurt but you can feel your skin
kind of contract
and go oh that's hot give me away from
there and it's your skin it's the
moisture in your skin just going i don't
think you should do that bro
so kind of experiment with your dab heat
my advice is to go too cool before you
go too hot
if you think it's not gonna melt then go
a little bit hotter
put the cap on there and draw through it
if you think you could have gotten a
bigger dab if there's a puddle left you
probably could have gotten hotter
but i want you to start nice and cool
don't go roasting your [ __ ] lungs
something i should talk about emails
they've got a number on the box
that's an arbitrary number i do not
believe that they have
some of them may they're affordable and
i don't think that they're using this
technology because we can afford it
i don't think there is a sensor running
up the cord
saying oh the surface of your nail is
this temperature i will adjust
i think we are sending out an arbitrary
number worth of
heat a worth of electricity uh kilohertz
or something down this
cable to heat up this element and then
that heat has to travel to the head of
the nail
so that is kind of an arbitrary number
find the perfect setting on your email
don't rely on
my email number don't rely on anybody
else's email number
the manufacturer or who sent it to you
may have a recommendation
start there or a little bit lower and
work your way up
it's better to start with a dab that
won't melt you may have to waste a
couple of dabs
but that is all about the learning
process just blow a couple of dabs off
let them evaporate let them [ __ ] melt
let them waste
but once you get to that perfect
temperature it'll be magical every time
you reach for the email
you'll be able to get that [ __ ]
perfect perfect dab and then clean it
every time
give it maintenance make sure to turn it
off when you leave you have no
idea how many times i've walked in the
house and [ __ ]
saw those numbers lit up on the box and
went oh [ __ ]
i don't think anything will go wrong but
that's that's a hot thing just sitting
here on the table while i'm away
i don't have a cat but if i had a cat a
cat i know a cat would come knock that
over just to be a [ __ ] cat
and then you'd have [ __ ] dab nail
fire all by the kitty
so uh dab temperature go low don't go
too hot we don't want you to roast your
lungs roast your esophagus
don't burn your [ __ ] out you can go
hotter don't take too big of a dab you
can go bigger
uh where else are we don't hold your
dabs in
i see a lot of people try to take a big
dab and then hold it in it's not
necessary with the dab with a bong rip
with the pipe rip there's no need
to try to hold in your hit that will
give you oh
see no copd chronic obstructive
pulmonary disorder
that causes problems in your lungs that
pressure is not good for your lungs
your lungs work like a filter when you
breathed in that smoke
it got all of the cannabinoids all the
terpenes it got all the [ __ ] that it was
gonna get
on the way back out it probably took a
little bit more i'm not a super
scientist
but then you blow it out all the [ __ ]
you don't want went into that cloud all
the [ __ ] that you want
stayed into your lungs don't hold it
it's not good for you
you'll give yourself lung problems heart
problems chest problems
you'll get a head rush out of it but
it's not worth it in the long run so
uh do not hold your dabs in i don't find
it necessary
it's not good for you um i think that is
most of what i had written down we could
cover
um some etiquette when you're done
dabbing
take the carb cap off of the nail
because you don't want to pass it like
this to me and have it fall off on my
table and break
or if we are somewhere carpeted like a
lot of cars
allegedly have carpet i don't want you
to drop that carb cap onto my leather
seats or onto my floor that's carpeted
and then get it all furry and we gotta
[ __ ] clean it
so when you're passing it take the carb
cap off
uh pass them as two separate things be
careful that way
especially with an e-nail do not leave
this cap on top of the email let's look
at what's gonna happen here you're going
to take your dab
like a [ __ ] stone bro and you set
these two down together and you just
leave it there what are we doing
we're heating up this carb cap the
heat's going to climb up to here
mike is going to come over and be like i
need a dab he'll grab this and burn the
[ __ ] out of himself because it's been
sitting here all day heating up
let's not do that to our friends take
the carb cap off of the rig
also if you dab out of somebody else's
rig and you're not
familiar with how to q-tip that [ __ ]
out ask them politely
hey bro will you show me how to q-tip
this thing because i don't want to leave
your banger all dirty and chased
feel free to ask for help with somebody
else's equipment a lot of the rigs
a lot of the bangers we're using are not
cheap you guys i buy
production glass because i'd rather get
the hit than the art
i want the punch to the face more than a
colorful rig but a lot of our friends
make
beautiful colorful custom art don't
don't break it don't be disrespectful
with your friend's glass that's another
thing i should mention when you've got
your buddy's expensive glass
don't be boisterous and expressive and
too much like like this rig here
i wouldn't i wouldn't want you doing
that with my rig right there i know it's
there it's mine
but if that's your buddies maybe move it
over here before you start [ __ ]
talking with your hands and [ __ ] so keep
[ __ ] like that in mind
uh some of our rigs are quite pricey i
wouldn't be uncommon to be at a sesh
in denver in colorado in la wherever you
are and come across a 10
15 20 000 dab rig that people just pass
around so keep that kind of [ __ ] in mind
uh don't break people [ __ ] have respect
for it
um i think that is all i've got for you
guys
showed you all the gear gave you some
tips we talked about all the
concentrates
i think now it is time to take some
[ __ ] dabs
uh let's wrap up the show and then i'm
gonna take a couple of dabs out of the
banger i'll take a dab out of the banger
and that'll probably be the end of it oh
i should hit the crc
also i got some homework to do so i'm
gonna do this part i'll keep the video
recording while i take some dabs
maybe i'll play uh some of the music or
something at the end of there i'm not
sure how this will work but
we'll make it happen [ __ ] it we'll do it
live um
ladies and gentlemen boys and girls
thank you for hanging out in the
grow from your heart podcast first ever
video
710 podcast i hope you learned a lot i
hope i taught you a bunch of [ __ ] i hope
i gave you a lot of questions also if i
inspired any questions
please contact me you can send me an
email my email address is grow from your
heart
at hotmail.com also if you feel like
this episode was educational
informative or entertaining you'd like
to support the show financially
you can make a financial contribution by
visiting www.patreon.com forward slash
grow from your heart all of the
information you need to sign up will be
on the screen
of course i did include a link in the
show notes once again shout out to the
captain of the 710 club i want to send a
big thank you to my good friend
lemur priest can't wait to see you in a
couple of months when all this weirdness
clears up bro
i'm gonna get you so high dude um
what else do i got don't forget to visit
our sponsor at seedshearnow.com and use
coupon code gfyh10 to save yourself a
few bucks
at seeds here now.com
uh don't forget about the youtube
channel if you're not watching the
youtube video
i invite you to check this out on
youtube go to youtube search for the
grow from your heart podcast
click subscribe also click on that
little notification bell then every time
i put out a new episode you will get a
notification
you'll never miss an episode of the show
stay up to speed come hang out with me
at least twice a week we may have to
increase the podcast episodes
uh because of all the generous patreon
love
thank you guys once again if you've got
any questions concerns comments or
corrections
you can send me an email the email
address is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com that is all i've got for
you
happy [ __ ] 710 you guys i'm
going to hang out and take a couple of
dabs
i'll be back in a couple of days with
fresh new content i want to give a giant
shout out to my friend
task rock and until next time take a fat
dab
and give your mom a hug for me i'm going
to hit the crc
first because i've never tried this and
it's new to me
and then i'll probably hit some batter
all right here we go
all right my first review of crc here on
the show uh it doesn't have
uh any desirable flavor it was kind of
uh it was like dabbing hospital product
it felt very sterile
it didn't have much flavor the high got
me immediately but it already feels like
it's wearing off
it punched me and then it was like
exhale high high
i'm not high anymore i don't know if you
can tell it didn't really do much and
took a good dab
so that is my review of the crc i'm
gonna take a dab now
of the garlic grove live batter off of
the email just because it's convenient
and then we will say goodbye for the
evening and i will go find
some food thank you for watching you
guys let's take a dab together if you
were dabbing
now's the time uh please leave a comment
and let me know what you're dabbing for
7.10 go to the youtube comments and type
in i am dabbing this
for 710. i am dabbing garlic grove
live batter dab with me guys and gals
you