[Music]
welcome back podcast world
i'm your host rosta jeff and it is time
for another episode of the grow from
your heart podcast
this episode of the show is brought to
you by our friends at seedshearnow.com
seedshearnow.com offers seats from all
of the industry's
leading breeders including miss jill
genetics duke diamond
exotic genetics and of course pyre
genetics
everything at seedsharenow.com is backed
by an award-winning satisfaction
guarantee
and for my friends on a budget seeds
herenow.com offers
several packs for under 30 as well as
amazing
monthly sales make sure to use coupon
code gfyh10 while checking out to save a
few bucks
again that is coupon code gfyh10 while
checking out
at seedshearnow.com
i'd like to start the podcast off by
giving a giant thank you shout out to my
buddy thanks for nothing for the perfect
podcast intro track
thank you bro that fits very well and i
appreciate your work
all right this is the point of the show
where i talk about what i'm smoking
today i've been taking ridiculous dabs
of holy [ __ ]
full spectrum extract from green dot
labs this is a blend of
sex on the beach and halo on the package
the flavor is described as pina colada
and fuel
that is a very unique description but
i'm going to agree
when you inhale there's a fruitiness
that pina colada coconut kind of
pineapple taste
that tropical flavor overwhelms my mouth
then on the exhale
my tongue goes dry and it tastes like
fruity fuel so i completely agree with
the pina colada and fuel flavor on the
back of the package it says the thc
level is 59.29 percent
and non-detectable amounts of cbd
big shout out to our friends at green
dot labs for the delicious
holy [ __ ] full spectrum extract and
speaking of holy [ __ ]
holy [ __ ] you guys it is super hot today
it is the hottest
day that we have experienced here in
southern colorado this summer
and i am feeling it that has led up to a
bunch of great
podcast questions it sounds like a lot
of other people across the country
across the world are having
heat issues in their grows so in this
episode we are going to talk about air
conditioning we're going to address a
couple of air conditioning questions
before we get there let's do some shout
outs to a few of the folks who support
the show
on patreon let's give a giant shout out
to the members of the 710 club these are
folks who support the show at the 710
level or higher on patreon
let's start off with the big shout out
to the leader the captain and commander
of the 710 club let's give a big thank
you shout out to my buddy lemur priest
let's follow that up with a big thank
you shout out to my buddy kurt z
i've always got a thank you shout out to
ez057
also let's send a big thank you shout
out to my friend zoso j
i also want to send a big thank you to
our friend helly we've always got a big
thank you shout out and a fist bump to
canna organic i want to send a big thank
you to jacob w
let's send a shout out to godfather kush
let's send a big thank you to learnin
and burnin i've always got a big thank
you for redbeard part of that red beard
crew
also let's send a big giant grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to my friend keith k big thanks and big
shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon
if you are not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need will be
right there on the screen of course i
did include a link
in the show notes to make it easy for
everybody who's got their hands full
all right you guys i don't want to waste
a lot of time today uh let's jump right
into the
patreon question part of the podcast
i've got a question here that comes from
our friend karen crawford
karen thank you for the continued
patreon support and also thank you
for the great question this one goes a
lot like
this it says hey ross to jeff first off
can i just ask
how the hell you manage to do all you do
growing breeding consulting
multiple podcasts emails social media
sales dabbing and somewhere in there you
got to have some sort of a personal life
i don't know how you do it but i do know
we all appreciate it so
thank you uh thank you for noticing
karen this has become
uh my life this is not uh something i do
it's something i do for fun it's not
just something i do as a hobby this is
what i do you guys
i breed seeds i do consulting i do
podcasting this is my life i am
in it i am not just playing i'm not just
hanging out in the cannabis world i am
[ __ ] immersed in it i wake up and
it's cannabis time i fall asleep and it
was cannabis time all day
uh being a seed breeder owning a seed
company is not a hobby it's not
something if you want to breed
and put seeds to market at the level
which i do
it is not a hobby it's something you
have to run like a business it's a farm
and a farm business it has to be
operated as such i don't get to take a
lot of days off i'm not complaining i'm
just saying
this is a lifestyle and i'm dedicated i
love doing it if you want to be
successful as a breeder
successful as a content provider you
have got to stay relevant you've got to
be on top of [ __ ] you've got to be there
if i don't put out a show i disappear if
i don't put out a new strain
i disappear so it's constant work it
never stops it's always evolving
if you think you're gonna do it uh know
that it's going to be a lifestyle not
just a job not just a hobby
um let's see growing growing is what i
have to do
if i didn't grow none of this would work
growing is uh growing and playing the
drums are two things that i have to do
if i didn't do those
something would go wrong with me
mentally and physically a screw would
come undone
springs would pop out somewhere it would
just be terrible uh breeding
i love to breed i love making new seeds
and growing them
and then i love seeing you guys have
success in your garden with the great
things i breed so that's awesome
consulting
um i love going to big grows it keeps me
up to speed it keeps me up to tech i get
to see what all these other people
bought and then i get to play with it
learn how to make it work owners get
these big ideas somebody told them to
buy some crazy [ __ ] so they bought it
because they had money
and the investor was like we don't know
what we need so they bought it the
person that told them to buy it
disappeared it was just some
[ __ ] dude they knew and they need
somebody to work it so they call me and
i get to go play with so many great toys
so that keeps my
uh my sword sharp so to speak uh
multiple podcasts
uh yes i am here on this show a minimum
of twice a week i'm working on improving
and increasing the amount of shows
i do the embracing organics show i
appear as a guest on quite a few other
shows
shout out to scotty real and the dude
i'm on their show quite often i try to
do as many
uh social media appearances as i can i
was held back by a couple of uh i needed
some dental work and i got it done so
now let's do some [ __ ] shows you guys
i'm not so shy about the face anymore
um also where are we in this emails
social media
that is the first half of my day i wake
up and answer emails
and then i try to catch up with them
before i go to bed once more social
media i've been slacking on social media
but i do try to keep a presence there
dabbing i'm always dabbing you guys
always dabbing and somewhere in between
there you gotta have some sort of a
personal life
uh i try to have a little bit of a
personal life i got mike around he's my
buddy
dab and matt comes around uh quite a few
people come and
hang out when it's not quarantine time
we do zoom and [ __ ] but a lot of times
this social media stuff my instagram
live
and the things like that that is a lot
of my social interaction because i don't
get a lot of time to go
explore and do a lot of [ __ ] so you guys
that i do interact with
uh you are my social interaction so
thank you that [ __ ] means a lot to me
now i'm rambling from that holy [ __ ] dab
i think i've got a brain bake from the
heat and then also i'm [ __ ] extra
baked from the holy [ __ ]
so i'm going to move into the actual
important part of this message karen
thank you for noticing all of the hard
work i'm doing
it goes on to say i'm a caregiver in
michigan and a couple of months ago you
were kind enough to answer a question i
had about extracts and why you don't
prefer rosin i definitely remember
it says this time i have a grow room
question that i definitely need your
expertise on
i am here to help it says indoors i have
a 20 bike
or a 12 by 20 flower room in a basement
with heating and cooling vented in
however
over the past couple of weeks [ __ ] has
been hot as hell outside and the ac
house uh the house ac isn't cooling the
room enough
i feel your pain it is ah it's 10
o'clock at night as i'm recording and it
is still 91 degrees outside
so i'm sweating it's hot i've had the
cooler on all day it is finally
uh cool in here it hasn't been cool
until right about now at 10 o'clock so
i feel your pain it's hot the whole
country is getting hot right now
um you're running six to eight plants
under four hlg 550s
and two best of a 2000 watt reflector
series budget purples uh to vary the
spectrum
and even though i run my lights at night
uh from 5 pm to 5 am with it being in
the mid 90s every day temps are raising
between 85 and 88
even with my hurricane 20 inch pro
velocity fan on them and the
dehumidifier set to 60
all right so it's getting hot in there
um she told us what kind of light she's
got we know what size the space is
um she's got the right idea running the
lights from 5 pm to 5 a.m
it's cooler at that point you don't have
to fight the sun it's easier to cool the
grow room
also electricity is cheaper many
electrical companies will charge you a
premium price for the electric during
the day because everybody's functioning
all the businesses need power
it is cheaper at night so you're off to
a good start
the hurricane 20 inch pro fan uh guys
here's a note you need to keep in your
brain
fans do not create cool air they move
the air around they circulate air
if it's getting too hot from a heat
source you need something to battle the
heat source
the fan doesn't battle it it moves it
around it makes it comfortable
you need something to fight the heat if
you're making heat you need something to
make cool
so here we are at this point we have got
58 to or 85 to 88 degrees
uh 60 humidity it says i'm afraid my
girls are going to get
very unhappy soon if this continues so i
have purchased a winter it's
w-h-y-n-t-e-r that's
said winter if you guys have seen those
when you're shopping a winter 14
000 btu arc sh portable ac
unit but i have no clue how to vent this
properly
uh these units are great if you were in
the right environment if you don't have
access to a window unit if you don't
have a window to put a unit in
these will work beautifully i think
you're on the right track uh just a
little bit of guidance to install it
okay i can help you there because i do
have a room with
uh it may be the exact same air
conditioner if not a similar model i've
got a winter 14 000 btu portable air
conditioner
um yeah so let's talk about uh some of
your questions i have a small
11 by 30 inch window that i could use
but i'm nervous about number one
bugs number two light leaks and number
three odor those are all
valid concerns it says i've had 10
different people
uh give me 10 different answers on this
and i don't want to [ __ ] this up
what would be the best possible way to
do this keeping all these things in mind
and with the knowledge that i have a 70
year old woman living
very closely to the side that it will be
vented out who has already complained to
me about the smell of marijuana
oh that crazy old lady is going to be
the bane of your existence i'm sorry
she's over there
it says i apologize for it you know what
you got to do you got to burn one with
her and if you saw me spit on the
microphone i apologize you gotta go burn
one with her and make her your friend
give her some topicals make her feel
better i apologize for my lack of
knowledge when it comes to hvac
uh don't apologize for lack of any
knowledge i'm sure you know plenty of
[ __ ] because you've made it this far in
life
this message is well typed you know
enough you're okay don't apologize
and this may be simple uh but for
someone with varied responses as sure
i sure as hell i'm concerned and i want
it done right i like that
i get it right the first time we don't
have to keep overdoing it one solution
was to remove
the window replace a piece of plywood
pre-cut for the hoses okay you are on
the right path let's just start talking
about how i would do this
i have got a very similar window set up
with a very similar air conditioner in
the window i did not use plywood i opted
to use
i'm not sure what it's supposed to be
for i am not a construction guy i'm not
a handyman
ah that is not my realm i'll admit that
[ __ ] you're not good at hvac i don't
know what the [ __ ] at lowe's is called
i point and grunt we get what we need uh
i use
some blue insulation board it's blue
it's foam it looks like it's for
insulation i think it's got a diamond
shape and it may say dupont in the
middle of it
uh i don't get the one with the silver
reflective on either side they offer it
with the silver reflective i do not buy
that
by the foam board i think it is one and
a half to two inches thick they make it
in different thicknesses
in my basement window the window well is
quite wide it's as wide as the basement
foundation as wide as the house was
built
so i can press i take out the window i
took it the glass and the frame are gone
they simply popped out of the [ __ ]
the square where the window goes
i popped that out i cut a square of that
blue foam insulation and i popped it in
there as tight as it would go
then i used gorilla [ __ ] it's a spray
foam
you can put it you're going to ruin your
clothes wear some clothes you can
destroy wear some gloves tie up your
hair
if you got dreadlocks get that [ __ ] out
of the way the gorilla [ __ ] is a mess
and it gets
everywhere it is hard to clean up it's a
pain in the ass karen saw photos
of the area where i applied the gorilla
[ __ ] all that spattery stuff
that's what i could not clean up it
sucks to work with be more careful than
i was
seal all the way around that window with
the gorilla [ __ ]
then make multiple layers of duct tape
over it uh don't do the duct tape yet
we're gonna do that next
uh but seal it with duct tape then take
your
ducts from the air conditioner and trace
the size of the hole and make a hole
and cut that hole out now what i choose
to do is i went to the grow store
and the ducks i am using are six inches
in diameter the air conditioner i
purchased has a six inch duct
i grabbed a six inch metal flange it's
just a piece about this long and it's
sick i'm holding up my hands probably 10
or 11 inches
maybe 12 inches long just a piece of
sheet metal ducting wrapped into a duct
it's
six inches in diameter and 10 to 12
inches long
and i push that through the foam board i
measure it cut a hole push that through
the foam board tape that securely into
place
the foam board is taped into the wall
also held in with gorilla [ __ ]
then i put the metal in there then i
attached the ducting to the metal just
to give it something
to attach to something strong to support
on then i duct tape
the [ __ ] out of it i want to catch up
into your message and see where we
are um i've kind of lost my spot
uh window replaced with a piece of
plywood pre-cut for the hoses
um yes you can do that you can pre-cut
or you can post cut it was easier for me
to cut once it was up there
i just hang the thing and measure it was
easy but cut it as you need
uh then you want to screw the window
into the frame and caulk it
that would work i use the foam
insulation because it's easier to cut
uh and it's uh it's insulated it's
already insulated
but the good part about the wood is it's
going to be light proof i have to duct
tape the inside of my room to make sure
no light comes through
when i use this so where are we here
uh cocked but how do i filter it to
ensure bugs and or light can't get
through the intake or outtake hoses that
is a very
good question and a very good challenge
one of those hoses
spits out heat um i usually put
black pantyhose over the end of that
just put pantyhose just like a condom
and duct tape it in place
it'll blow and you'll see that flap in
the wind a little bit but the pantyhose
prevents anything from coming in
put it on both sides i do not use
the um the duct in i only use the duct
out that way i'm not pulling the air
from outside
it makes the air conditioner struggle a
little bit because you're using that
humidity in the room
but when it's 120 outside and it's only
85 in my room i feel it's easier
for the air conditioner to use that air
that's already in the room and then it
just blows the heat out it's less
circulation and cycling going through my
machine
less ducting that i've got i don't use
that second hose i just leave it open
and i put a filter over that
so a pantyhose is the cheap way to do
that uh if you're confident that it's
not going to heat up enough to cause a
problem on the pantyhose by the time it
gets down that far it should be okay
but make sure you put your hand over and
check so that's how i filter it
pantyhose that is
super high tech um it's really cost
effective that's a million dollar trick
pantyhose bro uh where are we or ma'am
sorry i shouldn't call you bro you're
one of the bros by now oh
you're one of us come hang out one of
the grow bros nothing but respect either
way
um i don't want to say this out loud but
mites are
the only grower problem i haven't dealt
with well uh you'll get mites eventually
where else are we on this
and how do i go about this smell venting
out and blasting the intake out of the
hoses
i do not think it cycles much air from
your room you've got the two hose models
so you are going to be pulling
air in through that it's going to go
over the compressor and out you may need
to use both hoses
and then it creates a loop and that air
doesn't touch or grow you aren't pulling
air from the grow and pushing it out
you're just pulling out it's a loop
and that should work for you i can't
make any promises that way use the two
hoses
and you create a continuous loop and the
air doesn't get sucked from your grow
the odor doesn't get sucked and blown
out
you may need another carbon filter in
the grow room just put a carbon filter
with a blower in it
right in front of the air conditioner uh
that'll help stir the air around also
that'll suck out a bunch of aroma and
odors
but if you do the loop i don't think
you're going to get much aroma
where i am i don't worry too much about
aroma the neighbors know who i am by
now goes on to say i've emailed you a
few pics i did check out the emails and
i did reply i'm sorry for holding the
email paper in front of the camera
that's rudolph wasn't paying any
attention if you're watching the video i
do apologize
trying to be a better podcaster i did
check out the photos i did reply with
the video i was kind enough to make a
quick video of myspace
and show that to you i hope it helped
out then it says mites are the only
problem i haven't dealt with over the
years and i don't want to have to
uh the way to not deal with mites is to
have a
solid integrated pest management system
have some sort of security so that those
mites cannot arrive don't allow them to
even show their faces
either sprays or predators however you
choose to do it
in your message you were concerned that
maybe they'll come in the cracks it
feels like maybe they'll come in those
little holes where you just hung up that
board
they're going to come in through the
miniature cracks in the walls in your
house anyway they're
if they're there they're coming in uh
just make sure you've got a pest
management
system um another good point you bring
up is also with a unit on the floor the
hoses don't quite reach without being
fully stretched
well i need additional six inch venting
or five inch they're using five inch on
that one different model than i've got
so the hoses are working properly or
would it be better to prop it up on
cement blocks
that is a very good question i love the
way you think i've got mine
raised up on three cinder blocks i've
got it up kind of high
the heat blows at the canopy are the air
the cool blows at the canopy of my
plants right across the top it kind of
goes between the lights and the canopy
that's where the hottest part is it just
pushes that heat right away
also up on the buckets i am allowed to
these air conditioners will create
condensation and runoff there's a drain
in the back
it will pee a little bit occasionally
run that tube into a bucket between
those uh
cinder blocks that you've got it raised
up on or however you raise it cinder
blocks are my recommendation
i probably weighs about 130 pounds so be
careful lifting it up make sure it
doesn't roll off of there
i put duct tape flaps on the wheels
uh the cooler is sitting on four cinder
blocks uh is it four is it two
uh it's two there's it's only this wide
so there's two cinder blocks are stacked
up three high
but i took just little mounds i made
speed bumps out of duct tape on the
cinder blocks
so that the thing cannot roll also the
wheels pivot
so i turned it to where the wheels are
facing different directions so that it
doesn't have an easy way to turn
just be safe be careful it weighs 130
pounds it could fall on you it could
fall on your plants
when it falls that ducting that it's
attached to is going to yank the window
cover off and now everybody can see
right into your grow room if the lights
are on if it's hot outside
everyone's seeing your grow lights
they're seeing your grow room
make sure that [ __ ] thing doesn't
fall but yes do raise it up off the
ground it's going to make condensation
hopefully it came with the drain tube if
not it's got a little spout in the back
lift up the cover on that i just leave
it uncovered all the time
mine's got a tube that hangs into a
bucket uh fills up about
five gallons maybe every week or so i
never let it get full because i can see
it when i go in the room
just dump it occasionally a lot of
people say you can use that water to
water your plants
i don't like that there could be [ __ ] in
there there could not
but there could be [ __ ] in there let's
see if there's any more to this message
it says again
thanks for all you do ross to jeff karen
thank you uh for noticing thank you for
the support you've been helping me out
on patreon for quite a while it does not
go unnoticed
that's part of why your message got
moved directly to the top of the list
also it was perfectly timed it's hot as
[ __ ] outside i'm sweating everybody's
rubbing their forehead all day today
everywhere i was
so perfect timing it also says i popped
some lemon jeffree and orange gasm seeds
that you were kind enough to get to me
when seeds here now was sold out
allegedly i'm not sure what you're
saying
they look gorgeous uh it's so cool
you're doing operation go
grow with the orange gasm uh she is
referring to
operation grow which is sponsored by
irie genetics pl grow systems
new millennium nutrients auto pots and
possibly another company which i have
forgotten
but we are all they are all growing
orange gasm
and they are all using a po grow minder
unit to monitor the room
everybody has an auto pot system to feed
the plants and everybody got
a box of new millennium to provide
nutrition to the plants and we're all
meeting every saturday
it is 2 p.m mountain time for me i'm in
mountain time i don't know where you are
but
convert that uh whatever time it is
wherever you are join us on youtube
i go on at 2 p.m we talk about operation
grow
this time we are growing orange gasm
there are six growers that all started
at the same time
they are all on the same phase of growth
we flipped into flower
on saturday so the coming saturday will
be the first
grow report of the plants being into
flower uh
karen i'm glad you are following along
with that i hope you're learning a lot
about the plant there was a lot of
interesting information on the last
couple of episodes
and i love your uh your enthusiasm about
growing so keep it up stick around
please and if you've got more questions
please reach out
i would love to hear from you it says
i've been learning about her alongside
the boys and i'm stoked to watch her
grow
i'm excited that you're joining us it's
good to know that more people from this
show
are watching that show so thank you you
guys i invite you come check out
operation grow
it maybe operation grow 2019 because
that is when it started
but don't get fooled we are still up to
date and staying current all right this
says
feel free to use my name if you want to
include it on an episode i'm a medical
caregiver out here
and i am proud in or out and proud in
michigan big shout out to all my friends
out there in michigan michigan is
killing it
uh it's kind of the wild wild west out
there and i like that style
karen you keep it up keep crushing it
and if you've got more grow questions
please
send them right my direction all right
i'm going to keep moving because i do
have another great message this one also
is about air conditioning
this one comes from um
monsoon moon 420 shout out to monsoon
moon 420
the message goes a little bit like this
it says
hey ross to jeff i'm a long time
listener and i love your show because it
gets me through the day and teaches me
things at the same
time perfect you have found the catch
bro
you are learning you're laughing you're
getting a good time and it's getting you
through the day
you're at the office you're in the truck
you're doing whatever you're doing but
you're not thinking about that crap
because
i'm teaching you something and you're
having fun so thank you for noticing bro
it goes on to say i'm just wondering if
you can give me some advice on my mini
split acs for my grow space
i've got to uh speak up before we get
too far i am not an hvac technician
everything i say is bro
science uh this is all from what i've
seen and heard
uh i am not a pro in this department but
we're gonna get through this together
it says i have framed up a veg and
flower room my flower room is five by
five
they're in a normal bedroom and i have
an active air take an active intake and
exhaust in both of my rooms
so you've got active in and active out
on both of them
the intakes pull air from the room
outside the grow area
and the exhaust go to an empty space
under the house
all right so you're pulling from the uh
outside the grow area
and then it's going through the grow
space and then under the house
i'm really only worried about cooling
the flower room
uh then it says the bedroom doesn't
matter so much yes it does that's the
first correction i'm gonna make
i don't know how hot your flower room
your bedroom is getting but so many
people
overlook the importance of building a
quality veg room
that their grow is not as successful as
it could be
your veg room is equally as important
if not more important than your
flowering room
without a proper veg cycle your plants
will be weak and spindly
and not prepared for a proper flowering
cycle i'm not saying that monsoon moon
is doing anything wrong they may have a
perfect set up they don't need to make
any adjustments i want to make sure that
everybody knows
that veg is very important i often see
people
invest a lot of money in the flower room
and then i'm like cool let me see your
veg space and like oh i bought a five by
five tent
and i'm like so you spent thousands of
dollars on this fancy flower room
and you're gonna start everything off in
a five by five tent
okay that's that's cool but i think you
should have
veg is the foundation that is the start
you want the best lights the best
ventilation the best
co2 you want all of the best in veg
that's like training
you want to train the best you can
before you go into battle and battle is
the flower phase
i want them tough i want them strong i
want them prepared i want them to
be ready to flower and give me what i
need before i put them into flour so i
think veg
is just as important and that matters as
much
if not more uh so i don't know if you've
already got a dialed in veg space and it
doesn't matter that you
upgrade it but i want to make sure that
you understand it does matter as much
now
let me keep going it says do you think
it's better to have the head of the ac
inside the flower room or outside of the
flower room blowing near
an intake all right so you've got your
veg space in your flower space
inside of this bedroom you're bringing
air into the tents
if you put the head of your mini split
inside the room
you cannot have different temperatures
in your veg tent
and in your flowering tent because
you're cooling the room
and sucking that air into the tents so
whatever temperature you get the room in
the middle we call that a lung room
whatever that lung room
is temperature to that's what
temperature is going
to go into your flower and your veg
spaces
if you put the head of your mini split
inside the flower space you can dial in
the temperature
in the flower room you've got a mini
split you should have two heads right
can't you put one in
each i'm not sure what unit you bought
many of them have two heads that's why
it's a split split over here split it
over here
or is it a split because the heads
outside are in here and the units
outside i don't know
like i said bro not an hvac guy but um
so that is your main thing to think
about do you want to climb and control
the room and move that air into both of
the tents or do you want the
flowering room to get the focus of the
air conditioner
then it goes on to say if i go ahead and
install it straight into the flower room
will i still need to use my
intake or exhausts um yes because you
are not replacing
the fresh air the co2 the humidity
there's no airflow because of that you
still need
unless you seal up the room and
supplement co2 you do still need exhaust
and intake because you'll stifle the co2
and oxygen in that room
if you're running co2 and you've got
enough co2 to supplement to keep those
plants happy you can seal it up and not
use those intakes but
if you don't have supplemental co2 in
there and i mean like 14 to 1600 ppm if
you're not supplementing high
don't seal it up and do keep using the
intakes and outs
uh what i need to exhaust the smell out
of the room at certain intervals
i hope you've got a carbon filter hooked
up to your
outtakes all of your outtakes your
exhaust even if they're going under the
house i would still put a carbon filter
on all of your outtakes and just run
those exhausts 24 hours a day
to keep that air moving you may be able
to turn off the fans on the
intake because that outtake the exhaust
will passively pull air in through the
intakes you'll get enough replacement
air through displacement
hopefully i don't know your space but
most of the time typically that's what
will happen
so make sure you're running your carbon
filter on your exhaust to keep that air
out of there
i think i covered most of that then the
last part of the question says
also um what material could i use to
make a good seal on the doors to my room
i recommend weather stripping dude or
the flaps that they sell
use that flap that goes on the bottom to
cover the light lower that as low as you
can
then also use weather stripping on the
inside of the door to where it seals
real tight up against the wall
then they sell other flaps um i can't
remember what they're called they're
near the weather stripping if you go to
your local hardware store
there's they're like six foot sections
of weather stripping that'll screw in
so the door will close and fit right up
against that you put this one stripping
on one side you put this [ __ ] on the
other side and they fit up perfectly
together
that's a little bit overkill in my
opinion the weather stripping does very
well in any facility any grow that i've
worked in
so that is a great question if you want
to cool that flower room drop the head
in the flower room if you want to cool
both rooms
uh put the head of the air conditioner
in the middle
where else are we use those exhausts
with carbon filters
if you're not running co2 you may not
need to use the intake fans but you can
if you want to
think about the amount of air you're
putting in and the amount of air you're
taking out are the fans the same size
um do you have any sort of displacement
do you want negative or positive
pressure in that room those are things
to think about things you can adjust at
this point
and then smell always use a carbon
filter and put
those uh weather stripping on your door
all right how long have we been going
just about 30 minutes i think i didn't
write down the start time
we're going to keep going i do have a
couple of more messages these can be
quick
this one came from somebody who we don't
need to mention their name they know who
they are
but it says what's up dude i'm coming to
you for some advice
bro um we spoke last a little bit about
getting in the industry
well i'm sure you get hundreds of emails
from growers like this but i hope you
consider this one different
anyway i've been growing cannabis for
close to two years consistently
i've been for off and on a little bit
longer due to being in an area where it
is illegal to grow
but decriminalization for possession
puts me at risk for dail uh daily for
myself and my family
kind of going fast i want to get to the
point um so this person basically
they're in an area where they have
commercial facilities but they cannot
afford
licensing and they kind of want to get
to growing legally it says i wanted to
get a backstory to you
but then it says do you know of any
facilities that are looking
to hire my wife and i have already
discussed and she's fine with me having
to travel
if you know of someone or anybody who
needs help or wants help trimming
propagating transplanting should all
even sweep the floors uh basically this
person is looking for a job here
in colorado and i hate to be this guy
but
there aren't any cannabis jobs
excuse me there aren't any there aren't
many cannabis jobs popping open
at this time we're in the middle of a
pandemic we're in the middle of covid
most of the big facilities have gone on
a skeleton crew
if they used to have six guys now they
got three if they used to have ten dudes
now they've got four
we've really minimized staff so that
we're not getting as many people sick
the trim crew is minimized everybody is
cut down
the stores are down to minimal staff so
unfortunately
there is not much hiring happening in
the colorado cannabis
industry irie genetics specifically is a
very small operation
people seem to think uh and i love that
we've built this illusion that it's a
giant company
iriegenetics is me it's just me
sometimes i get
a couple of people to help me package
things one or two people have
volunteered and been paid to put seeds
the bubbles into the
the cardboard packs but i touch all the
seeds i do all the packaging
i get very minimal help i have some
shipping help and some packaging help
but that's about it shout out to my
helpers you guys know who you are
not ignoring you but 99.9 of irie
genetics is me so i don't need
uh too much more help i don't i couldn't
hire anybody to give them a reliable
income or anything like that so
unfortunately i don't have any good
advice for you on the hiring part i do
need a quick drink my throat is parched
that's why i was stuttering a moment ago
let me take a drink and i'll keep going
all right now i'm ready for another long
ramble um
you said that there are producers in
your area getting licenses
my suggestion is you said you cannot
come up the money to get your own
license go to one of those people and
apply there
uh get a good background in a commercial
cultivation area where you already are
you've got a family you've got a lady
you've got a baby on the way let's not
uproot you for a hopeful career when
maybe you can find a career right there
in your own backyard that's my advice
go to one of those facilities that is
producing go to the dispensaries go
everywhere and apply all you have to do
is make a good resume
make a resume just like you would apply
for any other position also add that you
were a passionate cannabis cultivator
be professional be on time speak well
dress
decently it is a grow position it is a
cultivation position
but you're not showing up to grow weed
at the interview you're showing up for
an
interview at the interview be prepared
for that all right
i think that is my rambly advice for
that one i wish i had more advice for
you
uh you know who you are keep listening
if you've got more questions please
send them my way and thanks for all the
patreon support
this one this last email from
this show is very a very very important
message i've got to make sure to say
this one nice and clearly
uh this one comes from our friend thor
and it says
more white mike that's all it says more
white mike so
mike the people have requested your
presence more white mike please
mike i love having you on the show i've
just been recording at random [ __ ]
times you've been busy
you guys we will get white mike back on
the show i'll message him as soon as i'm
done here
and i'll just say podcast with a
question mark and we'll work it out
it'll happen
that's my bro uh i apologize for not
having him here for a while
just been trying to get podcasts cranked
out um so i know you guys love white
mike
i've been trying to get better at being
an interviewer
i'm not the best interviewer on a
podcast i feel like i run people over
because i've got a lot to say i've got
an agenda i know how i want to say it
i just talk so i'm trying to become a
better interviewer a better podcaster i
want to have more
guests on my show via zoom people that
aren't just my good friends when jesse
comes over it's easy that's like hanging
out with my bro
when mike is here that's just like
hanging out with my bro there's no work
to that
but i want to be able to interview and
hang out more comfortably with other
people
the only way i can do that is by
interviewing and hanging out
comfortably with more people so i would
like your recommendations and
suggestions
who you would like to see me have on the
podcast who do you think would make a
great guest
send me your recommendations via email
or twitter the email address is grow
from your heart at hotmail.com
on twitter it's at gfyh podcast let me
know who you would like to see on the
show
once i'm comfortable i'll work my way up
to more intimidating guests and we'll
get some people on the show
look forward to some guests on the
podcast in the future
all right that is all i've got for you
for this episode i want to thank you
guys for hanging out big thanks to
everybody for all of the
great emails again if you've got a
question a cannabis culture
a cultivation question or even a
correction for the podcast
the email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com
you know i would love to hear from you
also if you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
and you would like to make a financial
contribution to the show you can do so
by visiting www.patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need to support
the show will be right there on the
screen
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who supports the show
also don't forget to visit our sponsors
at seedshearnow.com
use coupon code gfyh10 while checking
out
that will save you 10 if you're getting
a small order that covers the cost of
shipping
if you're getting a big order that will
add up quite quickly
go ahead and get a couple more packs
since you saved a few bucks
also find me on cannabis cannabis is a
cannabis friendly social media
application
you cannot buy sell or trade cannabis on
cannabis
but you can post your cannabis photos
you can post your dab videos you can
post your grow room pictures
and you don't have to worry about your
account being flagged or shut down
because we invite you we encourage you
to share your cannabis experience on
cannabiz
cannabis is a free social media
application available in your app store
if you're using an apple phone if you're
using an android phone whatever type of
device you've got
go ahead download cannabis give me a
follow i'm irie underscore genetics on
cannabis come join the cannabis
community that is all i've got for you
i'll be back in a couple of days with
fresh new content i'm going to give a
giant shout out to my buddy jaren
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you