yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 55 of the
grow from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation if you're a new grower a
professional grower if you're a new
smoker or a veteran dabber if you're a
cannabis activists or even someone who's
just curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you thanks again for joining me
I'm your host Rasta Jeff as always I
want to send a big huge thank you shout
out to the mystic roots band for letting
me use their music on the show
big thanks to Kat coot and the whole
mystic roots crew right now you're
listening to a song called the doggy dub
check that out it's on their album the
constant struggle before we get too far
this podcast is brought to you by hi Gro
indoor growing supplies hi grow indoor
growing supplies has two locations to
serve Colorado visit the Denver store at
62 71 Beach Street or check out the
pueblo location 618 East 4th Street in
Pueblo Colorado check out hydro for
competitive pricing and a great
selection of indoor growing supplies get
your favorite nutrients at Highgrove
indoor growing supplies a gross store
ran by folks who grow hydro is always
running a special for the podcast
listeners when you check out high grow
tell me you listen to the grill from
your heart podcast and they will give
you commercial pricing on your entire
purchase also the organic portions of
this episode were sponsored by my
friends at the rocky mountain worm
company visit the rocky mountain worm
company in Colorado Springs for fresh
worm castings African nightcrawlers red
wigglers and all of your organic soil
amendments the Rocky Mountain worm
company has dragonfly earth medicine
products in stock right now Rocky
Mountain worm company will ship to your
door you can get the same worm castings
that I use and many of the same
amendments that I use through wwr Aki
mountain worm company comm check them
out today if you're in Colorado Springs
drop by the store at 4:11 Tijuana Street
in Colorado Springs Colorado and make
sure you tell them you're listening to
the grow from your heart podcast big
shout out to Jay and Alan and Sean and
Nick and everybody involved down there
the
Rocky Mountain warm company really
appreciate you sponsoring the show and
huge thanks for the gift package you
send me home with we'll talk about that
in a minute
this podcast is also brought to you by
my good friends at nature's green
remedies com visit nature's green
remedies calm for gage green genetics la
plata labs Sin City rare dankness
mile-high canna venture the Cali
connection MTG I read genetics and many
more trusted brands nature's main
remedies is running a special for the
podcast listeners use coupon code spring
15 for 15% off any order and you always
get free priority shipping at nature's
green remedies calm that coupon code
spring 15 is good for any brand in stock
but it does expire at the end of this
month so take advantage of that offer
before the 31st big thanks and much
respect to nature's green remedies for
the promotion and the continued support
big thanks to all the sponsors if you
guys are interested in sponsoring the
show send me an email it's grow from
your heart at hotmail.com and I'll get
you all of the information you need to
sponsor the podcast I want to take a
quick second and read and iTunes comment
we got a 5 star rating again it says
thanks from fat ankle-foot the comment
was left on February 26th it says love
to listen getting better with every
episode as someone whose influence is
mainly from sohmas book it's nice to see
things turning to more organic based
been using worms for years please keep
doing what you're doing and keep up the
great work well thanks a lot for the
sweet comment fat ankle-foot I
appreciate that I'm glad that soma
inspired you and started a lot of your
teachings because uh I was hanging out
with a friend who grew weed for several
years and we were talking about my crops
and he said dude you know who you really
remind me of was a guy named soma and at
the time I'd never heard of soma so I
went home and of course I googled soma
and uh someone I have a lot of the same
philosophies a lot of the same practices
we agree a lot so I've learned a lot
from soma I kind of used some asuma's
methods but mostly his ideals uh he
almost treats plants is like a religion
sort of you know he's his religion is
growing pot and I took that spiritual
aspect of growing pot I had that before
I ever knew about soma so I kind of I
multiplied on it or expanded on it once
I found soma so I'm glad you knew soma
and glad your soma fan
and dude thanks for using worms in your
garden and thanks for trying to go
organic and thanks for listening and
super thanks for the comment and the
five stars you're part of the crew now
so welcome to the crew fat ankle-foot we
appreciate it
I think I read this uh this comment on
the last episode but this one is from
buzzer yeah I read that it says thanks
for making this for us again dude you're
super welcome thanks for listening
so if you guys want to send us a comment
I'd love to read your comments on a
future episode
thanks for the commented for everyone
that sent a comment for the new comments
and the old ones thanks to everybody if
you want to leave a comment on iTunes or
stitcher or if you don't want to leave a
comment on iTunes or stitcher just send
me a tweet it's grow from your heart so
it's actually @gf wih podcast send me a
tweet there or find me on Facebook and
I'll respond to you if you want to say
something anonymously you can send me a
personal message and I will keep your
name private I just tell me not to say
your name and I won't say it on the show
or make up a fake name and I'll say that
one you can also send me an email it's
grow from your heart at hotmail calm you
can let me know if you want your name
said or not I try to be respectful I
know how it is you can't always tell
everybody that you grow cannabis if you
don't live in Colorado alright that
feels like enough intro stuff I'm gonna
do a solo episode I want to talk a
little bit about the Rocky Mountain worm
company the Rocky Mountain worm company
was kind enough to give me a tour of the
worm farm I'm also going to talk a
little bit about my company I read
genetics and I'll also talk a little bit
about feminized seeds I've gotten a lot
of emails about feminized seeds I'll
explain my method of making those a
little later in the show now let's start
with the Rocky Mountain worm company
last week I was invited to go visit the
Rocky Mountain worm company and they
gave me a little tour of the building
and I got to see where the worm castings
are made they don't have a giant
facility but what they do have is super
clean and super organized and I was
pretty impressed I got to hang out with
J and Sean and Alan for a few minutes
and they taught me a lot about worms and
worm castings and why they use specific
worms that they use to make the worm
castings some worms you guys only eat
the top layer of if you put them in a
big thing of dirt like if it's a field
of dirt or if it's just a bucket full of
dirt they will only eat the top layer
and they don't dig down these guys
actually know which worms eat the top
which worms at the bottom they know that
some worms will eat every layer some
worms
travel through all of the dirt or
whatever you're putting them in and they
will eat and digest all of that these
guys these guys knew a lot about their
worms they showed me worms in every
single stage of growth every single
stage of life they have to kind of keep
the worms and five gallon buckets and
they let me open the buckets with the
worm farms and them I get to feel the
texture of the medium in which the worms
live in it's kind of Airy its kind of
fluffy it feels a lot like the soil that
I mix for my plants one thing that I
thought was really cool is what they're
feeding the worms this is really cool in
my opinion
parts of the worm diet is ah dried and
ground herb from a company called
o.penvape open vape makes vapor pen
cartridges so they're using their
extracting the CBD or THC from a plant
and making oil out of it and then they
send all the leftover material to the
worm company to feed the worms so the
worm company is using ground-up plant
stocks and leaves and whatever else was
left for the plants after harvest after
the making oil part happened and they're
feeding the ground-up plant matter back
to the worms and then the worms are
making castings at vat and those
castings are being used to grow my
cannabis and probably those worm
castings hopefully make it back to
o.penvape and go back into their
cannabis so we're kind of doing like an
in-house recycling sort of thing it goes
full circle uh without us creating more
stuff without something being tossed
into a dumpster for the trash guy to
find imagine when you harvest you have
every plant has a stalk and stems and
leaves imagine if you let that dry grind
it up and had some worms to feed that to
you wouldn't have to throw all that away
and you wouldn't have to make so many
trips to the dump or wherever ah that's
just super efficient I was completely
impressed so let's see I want to give a
huge shout out to Jay and Sean and Alan
and Nick I really like hanging out with
those guys the worm Factory is a cool
place I'll definitely be back there soon
those guys threw a handful of products
my way and I'm kind of starting to
implement them in my grow I have to
slowly adjust from the organic or from
the non-organic bottled stuff to the
organics because I don't want to ruin
the organic stuff so I'm learning what I
can switch out and what I can use
together and these guys are definitely
definitely definitely moving me along
quickly
I've been feeding the my plants worm
castings for about a month now and I can
definitely see an improvement in my
crops the first thing I noticed I would
say that after introducing worm castings
and grow Kashi is that my plants are
just simply more active they look more
vigorous they look happier they're
greener I see more growth and they also
seem to want more water which tells me
they're growing and taking nutrients
more than before so I definitely
encourage the use of grow Kashi and worm
castings as a nice way to just start
leaning toward the organics yeah so I
feel like I've been talking about them
for a little bit let's see if you want
to learn more about the worm company I
definitely recommend you check out their
online presence is wwr Aki mountain worm
company comm they're also on instagram
at Rocky Mountain worm company dude you
will learn a lot from them if you can
stop by their store check it out tell
them I sent you I said that at the
beginning but go there check it out it's
a great place so big huge shout-out to
the rocky mountain worm company I love
you guys can't get enough of that place
another thing I want to talk about is
Irie genetics I've got I get a couple of
emails every week about I read genetics
with questions about I read genetic
stuff and somebody just asked me why I
don't talk about IRA genetics on the
podcast um the show isn't really about
IRA genetics the show is about canis
cannabis in general so I not try not to
focus too much on my own company but it
seems like you guys are interested so I
guess it seems fair that I talk about it
a little bit I turned out to toot my own
horn gonna take a sip here sorry hold on
alright um so let's talk about IRA
genetics I guess let's jump into this um
I read genetics is of course my seed
company I breed regular and feminized
cannabis seeds right now I read genetics
is pretty much sold out of seeds for the
most part nature's green remedies is my
main distributor and they got most of
what I had left over after I hooked up
most of my local friends with my latest
harvest I really like to get the locals
ah all my friends all my Colorado I mean
my company is called IRA genetics
Colorado Colorado is what allowed me to
become this breeder I feel like the
local people should get the IRA genetics
products first and that way I get to see
what they grow and I get to take
pictures of it I can take clones of it
so I'm not trying to be rude about it
but the locals always get served up
first
after I feel like everybody's gotten
their seeds make sure nature's green
remedies gets what they can what they
can do so I really can't make enough
seeds to meet the demand lately honestly
I'm going to make more golden goat limit
geoffery seeds here really soon
the boys for that project are actually
in flower when you make femme seeds or
seeds in general you got to start the
boys off a little bit ahead of the
females so the males aren't flower now
the girls will go on flower and a couple
few days those should be ready in about
90 days from now I think this episode
will come out March 1st or 2nd and 90
days from then I should have lemon
Geoffrey and um golden goat seeds
available I actually wrote down the
wrong screen and I will set the wrong
strain and teach you guys but yes I'm
making more lemon Geoffrey and I'm
making more golden goat right now they
should be ready in about 90 days the
locals will get them first there is no
waiting list there's not a way to get on
a waiting list right now after my locals
get served up they will be dished out to
nature's green remedies and nature's
green remedies calm will sell out
quickly I promise you that I'll make an
announcement on this show before they go
there so when I make those lemon
Geoffrey and the golden goats I'm also
going to put a new cut called Kalonji
cush in their Kalonji cush is the
Grateful dog pollinated the Tahoe og and
I call it Kalonji cush after a reggae
artist named sizzla Kalonji if you're
wondering where my weird names come from
Kalonji is a reggae artist Sizzla
Kalonji so I'm gonna cross the golden
goat to the sizzle of Kalonji and I want
to call that sunshine girl which I is
actually a Sizzla song so I think that's
gonna be pretty cute um I have a couple
more ideas that I'm going to put in that
room I have two more females that are
going in there for sure but I don't want
to talk too much about them until I've
got some seeds in my hands from those
because um man let me tell you weird
side story one time I reversed a golden
Goa plant a female golden Goa planet I
treated it I turned it into a male and
I'll talk more about that later in the
show how he do that but I turned this
female plant into a male right and it
created pollen and I put that pollen on
a roomful of plants and that's how I
created the lemon Jeffrey that's how I
made golden goat seeds there was another
cross in the room that's never been
released or shown to anybody because it
only made a few seeds and those are mine
I also sprinkled that pollen on another
plant arm the strain was headband it was
a headband cut that I got from my good
buddy hankie B he gave me that headband
cut I sprinkled pollen on it and when
that plant took the pollen the plant
died within 24 hours that plant was dead
every other plant in the room was
healthy and happy took the pollen it
showed signs of being pollinated just
like it should have I don't know what
went wrong but that headband plant died
within 24 hours of taking feminized
pollen I've never seen that from a plant
I've never heard of that from a plant
I've talked to other breeders nobody has
an explanation for that the plant was
healthy everything was cool I don't know
what the hell happened so I'm gonna put
another headband in there and I'm gonna
hit it with golden goat pollen again and
I've got a name for it but I'm hesitant
to say on the show because people are
gonna rip me off but if I say it then no
one can steal it from me Rex I'm saying
it the golden goat is going to pollinate
the headband plant and I will call it as
a halo you know right you see you got a
headband and now it's gold it's above
your head
that's the halo bro so that's what I
think I'm gonna call the headband to the
gold and go the halo the Kalonji cush to
the golden goat will be the sunshine
girl those are coming up you guys about
90 days so pay attention I'll need some
testers but I didn't say that on the
show
let's see more about IRA genetics I
recently started my work on making black
cherry Kim f2 seeds f2 is finial
generation so I made the F ones right
that's plush berry was pollinated by a
Daybreaker plant and the seeds that came
out of there were called f1 the first
finial generation of that cross so now I
grew a bunch of them out and I found the
male that I want and I've recently found
three females that are good candidates
for breeding so I'm waiting for these
plants to finish before I commit to
which females I'm going to use to
continue the line into f2 but once I
choose one I'm going to I'm going to
choose two of them actually and I'm
going to hit both of them with the male
pollen and then I will keep all of the
seeds separate so that its phenotype
number seven and eight or the two that
I'm really eyeballing for my females so
I'll keep black cherry chem seven and
black cherry chem eight separate and
pull all the seeds out and I'll grow a
hundred of each one of those and see
which one shows me what I like and it
will keep that one to continue working
with so I went for these plants to
finish I got to smoke them I got to dry
them I got a
turn some of it into ABS I got to smoke
some of it is flour I got to see which
one I really liked the best and then
that will be used to make the f3 and I'm
really trying to stabilize the purple
trait in that strain is what I'm trying
to do so I really want right now I'm
getting about a little more than 50% a
purple when I run a pack of 50 I'll have
25 purple plants I want to make it up to
closer I want to get like 75% purple
plants out of this and then by the time
I'm done I'd like to see that purple
plant come out almost every time is what
I'm aiming for I plan to take it to f5
over the next few years
I'll breed the f2 s this summer one
thing I've seen out of it that's really
cool is some of the phenotypes look done
and there are only 55 days into flower
so I've made a purple strain with a Kim
flavor that finishes in about 55 to 65
days which is pretty cool so that's my
black cherry chem project that's going
right now you can check out pictures of
those I put them on Instagram and I also
put them on my forum on my website if
you go to I read genetics Colorado comm
go to the forum it would be really cool
if you join the forum sign up and join
the forum it doesn't cost anything
nothing weird is going to happen you're
just a member now and you can
communicate with us and participate but
every week I go and post a weekly grow
journal of my own gardens up there and
the black cherry Kim has been
highlighted quite a bit so you can see a
lot of great pictures of black cherry
cam on my website right now in the forum
I'll go there and check it out if you
can and all if you ask me questions
there and you talk to me I really that's
my favorite place to go and communicate
with people because they can't censor me
because I own that Facebook can't shut
that down or anything so do what you
want to do there if I think you're a
dick I might tell you to quit being a
dick but then grow weed and post your
weed pictures there I'd love it alright
um one thing I can talk about is I'm
looking for and a rise mail a rise is a
golden goat that was pollinated by
Daybreaker and I really love that strain
it makes a great smell it makes a great
flavor the high is amazing the plants
put on super resin they grow in a good
amount of time ah they're real stout
plants you don't need a lot of staking
on it if you find the right phenotypes
so I'm looking for a rise male I want to
use a rise in a long term breeding
project he will be my law
turn breeding mail um I see some
beautiful things from the strain and I'm
sure that a good male will make some
more amazing crosses the resin
production from that plant is so
impressive but it'll be a few months
before I select in a rise male I've got
the feminized golden goat lemon Jeffrey
project ahead of that I've got the black
cherry Kim ahead of that and then after
that will be the arise male selection um
I want to find a good over eyes male for
my permanent breeding stud but I plan to
make like 15 to 20 f1 hybrids with their
eyes to see what works when I do find
that one um then I want to see what can
be improved on or what I need to abandon
um guys when you if you breed if you
take a male plant and you hit six or
seven female plants with it
don't be afraid to throw away a bunch of
seeds when you you have to grow those so
you take male plant in a room with like
however many females you're gonna put in
there five six maybe twenty females
you're gonna make that many new crosses
you have to grow some of each batch of
seeds yourself before you can do
anything else with them unless you give
me like your friend and you say these
are untested dude because you don't want
to put out seeds that you don't know
what they're gonna do so get the seeds
and grow at least ten I would say a
hundred if you can I know you're limited
on space and things I like a Fino hunt
of a hundred plants it really shows you
the what's going to happen but grow some
of those and if they totally suck throw
them away I know that sounds crazy but
there are enough strains on the planet
to where if you just made some [ __ ]
that doesn't improve the genetic line
throw it away why do we need that don't
be so attached to your new creation that
oh it's a great strain it does this it
no it sucks
throw it away I've thrown away more
strains than I have kept um we all talk
about the lemon cush everybody had high
hopes threw the lemon cush that I worked
with that strain sucked it tasted
amazing and it grew big fat donkey dicks
four buds but you couldn't get high off
of it it would not make resin none of
the phenotypes on that planet made resin
and I don't know why it's just that
cross did not work so all of the seeds
are gone all the clones are gone that
project has been abandoned I realized
that's a failed project it wasted some
time but I don't want to waste more time
or more people's time with the same
project by sending out shitty seeds so
um that's a rant on a not being too
attachment it's in a lesson an
attachment if you're too attached to
that strain then you're wasting your
time growing something that sucks and
you could have been grown something way
better you could have been breeding
something that was way better just let
it go sometimes you gotta learn to let
things go remember that lesson I talked
about my rig that I dropped you just got
to sweep it up and move on sometimes
alright so when I do get all these new
strains made I will need help testing
these like I said I like to run a
hundred myself but I will also send out
a bunch of seeds to reliable testers the
way that I know you're reliable tester
is you've joined my web forum and you
have posted pictures of your previous
grows on my forum and you stay in
contact with me and you show that you're
serious about it that's a lot of how I
find my testers is off of my own website
so in the future if you're interested in
testing IRA genetics seeds that would
help you a lot to join the forum I do
play favorites that way it's my choice
all right let's see I'm not sure what
else to say about IRA genetics
I'm the head breeder I make 99% of the
decisions with help from my friends I do
let the people around me kind of give
their input because their cannabis
consumers growers smokers they have a
lot to say but that's me IRA genetics is
all Rasta Jeff I have trim friends that
help me shoutout to everybody that's
ever came and helped me trim some IRA
genetic stuff or shoutout to all the
people that have helped me package seeds
or whatever so in the future I am going
to get away from the feminized seed
market as much because feminized seeds
are a pain in the ass to make and I
think that we should all eventually step
up our game and learn to just grow
regular seeds if we didn't have male
plants we wouldn't have more plants
anyway so it's my responsibility to put
out more regular seeds I think than I do
feminized seeds and I see um I see
better [ __ ] come from the regular
crosses than I do the FEM seeds honestly
feminized seeds are stuck you can't
improve on them too much the cross that
you make that's what you got like I see
when I cross like if it's feminized if I
cross plant a and plant B they come out
a little bit better than a and B were
but you can't make them super better if
I take a regular male plant and a female
plant and cross that I see much
her stuff come out of that much more
improved plants transgressive
segregation my offspring will outperform
each parent and that only happens when
I'm using regular pollen I can't make
that happen with my feminized pollen so
there are a couple reasons why I will
eventually abandon the feminized seeds
that's eventually I'm not saying soon
but one of these days I will stop making
FEM seeds I don't know what else to say
about IRA genetics that's a there's so
much I could say but I feel like I'm
just stroking my own ego over here
talking about I real ah um support IRA
genetic student it's a Rastafarian seed
company by her Asda man so instead of
having mass-produced commercial seeds
you've got seeds every seed was touched
by me every plant was touched by me by
my Rastafarian hands so it's got a
little bit of Rasta love in there I
think that means something to me I'd
rather buy products from a small company
that cares about their products than the
Walmart of whatever industry you're in
alright let's get on to another topic
here I mentioned that I want to talk
about feminized seeds a little bit um a
lot of people seem to have
misconceptions on what feminized seeds
are on how they're made on where they
come from and on what they will do um
people think that feminized seeds are
straight-up hermaphrodite seeds which
I've got a pretty popular seed company
that only sold feminized seeds for two
years and we came up pretty good and I
don't know how I read genetics would be
popular and/or reliable if we just sold
a bunch of damn perms so let's start
with some basics here what does it mean
to have feminized seeds I took a few
random notes feminized seeds mean that
the seeds will produce all female plants
I can only say 99% female plants because
this is science and nature and [ __ ]
happens but they'll be 99% females this
is helpful because new growers don't
know how to identify male plants in
their gardens so if you're growing
feminized seeds you don't have to watch
for the boys it also makes things easier
for growers with limited space because
the grower knows that every seed planted
will be a usable female and none of
their space soil nutrients water
electricity none of that's going to be
wasted on growing a male plant that had
to be chopped down 10 days into flower
so feminized seeds mean that all the
seeds will produce female plants now
here is where some people are confused
or feminized seeds made pay close
attention because honestly you guys I am
I'm amazed with myself that I'm giving
out this information is one of my
biggest secrets and I don't usually
share with anyone um I want to take a
DAB in a drink before I share this but
I'm gonna take a quick dab in a quick
drink and then I will teach you guys how
I make reliable feminised seeds on a
semi large scale for nature's green
remedies and patience throughout
Colorado give me a quick second I'm
gonna take a DAB in a drink all right
guys I am back and heavily medicated
after that dab I want to tell you how I
make my feminized seeds first of all I
got to warn you that the chemicals that
I will describe here are a little bit
dangerous and you need to follow the
safety rules for these I am NOT
responsible for you hurting yourself or
making yourself sick with these
chemicals okay I'm simply telling you
how I do this if you do this follow the
instructions wear gloves
wear goggles do everything safely so the
way I start is I order silver nitrate
and sodium thiosulfate from a scientific
supply company um I get powdered
versions of silver nitrate and sodium
thiosulfate and I mix I'm not even gonna
tell you the delusions or the rates but
I mix the silver nitrate into an amount
of water and I mix an amount of the
thiosulfate into an amount of water and
then I mix those two in another
container into another container and now
I've got 100 percent silver thiosulfate
in that third container and I will
dilute that to a certain dilution now
some plants will take will need stronger
delusions of the silver thiosulfate and
some plants will need lighter delusions
of the silver thiosulfate what I've
learned as some plants I can treat some
plants one time with the silver
thiosulfate at a high dilution just
before flout the day before flower and
that will work for that plant some of
them I have to make the dilution much
weaker and spray it multiple times and
some plants I have to make it stronger
and only spray at once and the only way
you'll learn this is through
experimentation by trying plants by
trying different delusions so
I put the silver nitrate into one
container of water and put the
thiosulfate into another container of
water I shake them up to where it
dissolves I mix equal amounts into
another container and then I take that
container and dilute it to the proper
dilution for the plant that I'm working
with
then I will I'm going to use golden goat
because I'm I just did this to golden
goat about seven days ago I took three
golden goat plants and I put them in a
small space where there aren't any other
plants around there's no wind to where
my spray is not going to randomly land
on other plants because I don't want to
reverse other plants on accident in this
process so I took my three golden goat
plants I put them in a small confined
space and I sprayed them with my silver
thiosulfate mix at the proper dilution
and I sprayed these plants to the point
where they are dripping from top to
bottom these plants were covered in the
silver thiosulfate solution be careful
because if you use the silver
thiosulfate at a strong dilution it may
turn things purple like the floor where
the spray lands on the wall behind it it
may turn it may leave little purple
marks so be careful or a little shiny
purple mark like shiny
iridescent looking marks I think is the
word it's gonna need the way it looks
but it'll screw some stuff up if you
don't want your things purple be careful
so spray the plants then I let them sit
and dry because I want them dry before
they go in a flower room so I let the
plants dry then I carry those plants to
the flower room where they will go into
flower and I try to spray them right
before the lights off for the flowering
cycle so they get sprayed they dry and
then they go into the flower room and
the lights go off and they have now just
gone into flower and with the golden
goat I can spray it one time on the day
of flower and in about ten days that
plant will show me male flowers no
people are saying how does that work I
gotta explain this to you kind of slowly
so pay attention because I'm trying to
explain it to myself I don't have any
notes on this im just freestylin right
now so bear with me what happens is when
we spray a female plant with silver
thiosulfate solution the thiosulfate
acts as a carrier for the silver the
silver isn't really absorbed by the
leaves easily but the thiosulfate makes
it get in there a little bit better so
we're tricking the plants into taking
the silver by a
the thiosulfate now when the silver
reaches the plants the silver disrupts
the copper movement in the plant system
there is copper in your plants yes the
silver will disrupt that when that
copper movement is disrupted in the
plant system it responds by triggering
an ethylene production or I'm sorry an
ethylene it triggers an ethylene
response it's not an ethylene production
it's an ethylene response and that
ethylene response tells the plant that
something is seriously wrong and it's
time to go into survival mode so that
plant survival method is to create male
flowers that will create pollen because
now all that plant wants to do is shoot
pollen and reproduce to keep the species
alive
so I've disrupted the copper the plants
freaking out
it panics the panic causes ethylene to
move through the plant in a weird way
that ethylene triggers the plant to
throw out flowers that are male flowers
that produce pollen now since those
plants that female plant is all female
it does not have any male chromosomes
the only reason it is showing male sex
parts is because I've stressed it and
manipulated it so it will now throw out
male parts that contain pollen and
though that pollen will be all female
excuse me my throat's clogging up here
from the dabs let me take another drink
of water alright that should help so now
we've got female plants that are
spitting out all female pollen and we're
taking that pollen and of course putting
it on female plants you know we've never
introduced any male pollen here so like
I said before 99% of those plants should
come out female and the only reason I
can say 99% is because like I said it's
science and nature and [ __ ] does happen
and also your grow room can cause issues
as well your gross style can I'm not
blaming it on you I'm just saying that
environmental factors and all that stuff
plus science and nature will lead to
some screw-ups and I'll take credit for
part of those screw-ups because I'm the
one that made the seeds but when this is
done right we get quality reliable
feminized seeds so I hope that makes a
little bit of sense um
I make the psilocybin sulfate and I
spray the plants with it and magically
that makes the plants turn into
transsexuals they're not male plants
they're
reversed females is what we call them
and that basically is how I am making
feminized seeds so these are not
hermaphrodite seeds I'm not taking
hermaphroditic plants and using
hermaphrodite pollen I'm not doing
anything crazy ridiculous this is
reliable science um the reason a lot of
people are afraid of feminized seeds is
because when it was started there were
other um less reliable practices used to
make phem seeds um soma does another
method since we talked about soma
earlier in the show soma does not use
the silver thiosulfate method as often
as I do
what soma does is he lets his plants
grow too long so if he's got a 10-week
flowering plant he'll let it grow about
12 weeks and when a plant goes that long
it kind of stresses itself and then it
hums out and creates pollen that way and
that's what soma is using I've also
heard of soma taking a mature plant and
this sounds completely crazy to a lot of
growers but it'll make sense
he takes a completely mature plant and
then he will light a small fire and he
will put his plant too close to the fire
the plant panics and the plant feels
like it's a forest fire coming so that
plant starts to create male flowers and
it's a female plant it's freaking out
it's triggering that survival instinct
so it makes those male flowers which
make pollen and then soma collects that
pollen and sprinkles it on to other
plants and maybe this explains why
feminized seeds are so damn expensive
because there are more steps into making
feminized seeds there are to making
regular true breeding male female seeds
that's why it's hard for me to keep up
because I have to reverse plants and I
don't get as much pollen from reversing
these plants as I do from a normal male
and it takes a little longer
alright I feel like I told you enough
about reversing plants I think you
should have caught on by now like I said
you're gonna have to experiment with the
delusions and the application rates um
in n Rosenthal's book I don't have it
next me the Oaksterdam course guide they
had wrote the most like not even sure
that it's the most current but ed
Rosenthal wrote an Oaksterdam course
guide and in that book there is a recipe
to make your own silver thiosulfate that
recipe does work although for some
plants it will need some adjusting
that's just my advice alright I am going
to take a phat dab and take a drink and
try to get this frog
my throat so that I can sound like an
actual podcaster I'll give me one second
I'll be right back guys and we will give
some shoutouts and wrap up the show
alright guys I'm back I apologize for
taking so many breaks on you this
episode usually I have some guests that
can cover me while in coffin and taking
a drink or whatever but today was just
me so you had to bear with me I
apologize I hope you enjoy the show
I just took a big old fat dab of some
Jack the Ripper
shatter made by my good friends at Terp
X I picked that up at the green and
healthy wellness in Colorado Springs I
don't shop in a lot of dispensaries
because I'm self-sufficient but I was
low on shatter I uh I'm just between
harvests right now so I had to pick up a
few grams of shatter um dude green and
healthy wellness on to 12 South 21st
Street Colorado Springs has the hookups
on tour packs shatter if you have to be
a medical patient so if you have a
medical card and you were in the
Colorado Springs area [ __ ] if you're in
Pueblo or Denver it's worth the hour
drive to head to green and healthy
cannabis and pick up your terp X shatter
it's a great price I can't tell you how
much it is because I have member pricing
we have non-member pricing and they have
quite a few tiers of pricing I don't
want to get you pumped up because
sometimes they run out of the low
pricing stuff but dude go to green and
healthy wellness in Colorado Springs and
get some turf backs big shout out to
John and John and Jordan and Jordan
nothing like a dispensary with two
John's and two Jordans in it
alright also I want to give a big
shout-out to my friend Claude the
Candyman Claude if you're listening to
this show bro big thanks much respect
guys support sweet stone candy if you
are in California you can get your sweet
stone candy I don't think it's available
here in Colorado anymore but much love
much respect to Claude the candy man big
shout at the sweets no candy also a big
hug to Melissa and a little scratch on
the head too sticky the dog shoutout I'm
also big huge shout out to my buddy hunt
I always owe you a big shout out bro you
need to come on the show grimy Gatsby on
the podcast that's what I'm saying um we
are having a growers meeting you guys we
do these growers meetings in the back of
hydro indoor growing supplies Jesse gets
a topic started and then I will jump in
and help him give a little grow lesson I
think we're gonna talk about um oh no
that's all I don't even know what the
topic is this week I should text him and
find out but we're going to have a
meeting the meeting is on March 6th at 6
p.m. at hydro indoor growing
supply's grabbing the paper with the
address right now because I don't
remember the address I do remember but I
don't want to say it wrong it is 618
East 4th Street and Pueblo Colorado you
were invited that's right you were
invited if you're listening to this
podcast I think you have to be 21 and
over it's a 21 and over event if you're
listening to the show and you're 21 and
up you can come to this event it's a
high grill indoor growing supplies March
6th at 6 p.m. I will be there Jesse will
be there there's a good chance Shaun
King Cola will be there sometimes cement
shows up garden of Weeden comes there
will be a lot of cool people there
sometimes we give away prizes they give
away prizes it's not my event I just
help out but big shout out to hi growing
or growing supplies for that it sound
like I'm to start coughing again I feel
like I have a big coughing fit coming so
I'm gonna try to wrap up the show pretty
quickly just a short episode you guys
seem to pay more attention in the
episode they're shorter I honestly get
more lessons more completed listens to
episodes under 45 minutes so we might
start doing that um if you have a show
idea message me I'd love to hear your
show ideas this show came all out of
emails that I received from listeners I
made this show just for you because of
your questions so if you want to hear
something let me know don't feel shy
don't feel like you're begging I will do
a show based on what you want to hear
because this show is for you not me
alright so I'm gonna close the show up
thanks for listening to another episode
I'll be back in another week
hey I said that the Dragonfly earth
medicine people were coming it turns out
uh our schedules kind of missed each
other they are in Washington up near
Canada right now I may set up a Skype
interview but I never went podcast do
Skype and phone interviews I usually
don't listen because it sounds like [ __ ]
so unless I can get a really quality
recording out of it I won't do it to
tell you the truth I'll wait for them to
come to Colorado and I will interview
them in person so i heiped you guys up
that the Dragonfly earth medicine people
are coming there was a miscommunication
they are currently in Washington I am in
Colorado yeah you heard me if I can make
it happen through a good phone interview
I will if it's not quality I will never
play because I hate it when I hear a
crappy phone interview on a podcast but
um I'm gonna try to get Sean and Jessi
back for a soil recycling episode really
soon I've got a lot of cool stuff lined
up the cannabis cup is coming up here
pretty soon
actually it's my birthday right now so I
got a lot of fun
happen in this week um if you're
interested in sponsoring the podcast or
if you have a product you'd like us to
review send me an email it's grow from a
hard hotmail comm and I'll get you all
the information that you need also don't
forget to check out our sponsors the
Rocky Mountain worm company and hi grow
indoor growing supplies don't forget
about the new coupon code at nature's
green remedies calm that coupon code is
spring 15 well as I was saying that
Yankee from nature's green remedies just
messaged me to confirm that he got the
new coupon code I gave him that is
pretty neat so that coupon code is up
and active you guys spring 15 at
nature's green remedies calm now that
show's over please go to iTunes or
stitcher go to the iTunes Store or yeah
go to the iTunes Store search for girl
from your heart or on stitcher you got
to find the review section do it on the
individual episodes I guess because
stitcher sucks for leaving reviews give
me a five star rating after that type in
a comment let me know what you think of
the show and I will read your comments
on a future episode
like I said stitcher keeps changing the
way the comments are done on there just
leave a comment and I will do my best to
find it if you have some design you're
not into the social media thing you can
always email me grow from your heart at
hotmail.com don't forget that the show
is available on iTunes stitcher and
every single episode is archived on I
read genetics Colorado com we did add a
donation to the podcast page on the
website if you feel like the show is
worth a few bucks you can go to my
website I read genetics Colorado com
click on the girl from a heart podcast
tab at the top right there's a donation
button that goes directly to my personal
PayPal account
I'll never charged anybody anything for
this podcast this podcast will always be
free this comes from my heart for you
I'm not asking for anything but if you
feel like you want to make a donation
don't be shy just click on there you can
throw in $1.00 there's no limit on what
you can throw in one listener emailed me
- excuse me one email one listener
emailed me and told me that he would
actually donate to it if I put the
button up there and I had my web guy put
the button up and he has not contributed
yet so I'm hoping that he hears this is
my web guy spent a few minutes putting
that up there for me I'm just being a
smartass you guys find me on Facebook
search for girl from your heart follow
me on Twitter search for its GF wih
podcast fall I read genetics on
Instagram let me give a huge huge shout
out to a ninja Spence
also big shout out to my friends that
were in town visiting from Mississippi
this week what's up Jeff what's up John
hope you guys listen to the podcast
great time with you this week I had a
great dinner last night he has her
kicking ass um yeah everybody thanks for
listening until next time take a big fat
dad Kingdom on the hug for me
we aim for the sky now we hire them all
of the rides till we shine like the
fiery star son I create to admire it all
ride a line from my rhyme from a wire
jaw check it out
Linus keeps coming out with the slammin
piece makes the whole house wanna bounce
like static sheets we've attract elite
world star athletes you can't compete
cuz your rap is we have a seat my
numbers game isn't contained by a data
sheet I run the game while you drag your
feet I understand with my love of angels
my life was Monday now it's feeling
magnifique first place and we moving the
ball fluent in love under the influence
of drugs you speak a we could ruin your
ball
oh the balls I just wash it like a ball
do it again do it again
you