[Music]
here we go welcome back podcast world
i'm your host rosta jeff and it is time
for episode 550 of the grow from your
heart podcast
this episode of the show is brought to
you by our friends at seedshearnow.com
seeds herenow.com offers seeds from all
of the industry's leading breeders
including duke diamond miss jill
genetics and of course irie genetics
everything at seeds herenow.com is
backed by an award-winning satisfaction
guarantee
and for my friends on a budget seeds
herenow.com offers
several packs for under thirty dollars
as well as amazing
monthly sales make sure you use coupon
code gfyh10 while checking out to save a
few bucks
again that is coupon code gfyh10 while
checking out
at seeds here now.com i want to give a
giant shout out to my buddy
thanks for nothing for that sweet rhythm
you hear in the background there
thanks a lot for the contribution to the
show make sure you guys follow danks for
nothing on cannabis
ladies and gentlemen if you're watching
the video i'm sure of you you have
noticed by now that white mike is back
in action welcome to the show
bro thanks man what's up everybody thank
you for being here dude
uh before we get too far would you like
to shout out how people can stalk you on
social media
uh you can find me on twitter at nemo
punk 15 you can find me on facebook at
pueblo for sensible cannabis laws
and you can hit me up on patreon at uh
patreon
forward slash white mike there you go
patreon.com forward slash white mike
help out white mike for helping out the
show as patreon is building up we do
appreciate the support mike is a major
contributor
not only to the podcast but to the
community yes you are bro you are
getting it going
i'm glad i encouraged you to get the
patreon going and thank you to everybody
who's helped out mike thanks very much
patreon
um this is the point of the show where i
ask you what are you smoking on today
bro
everything i get my damn hands on man
you seem like that today
it's i've been enjoying 7 10 so much i
haven't gotten around to posting about
it it's [ __ ] like 7 17 now
yeah it is well don't reveal too much
we're actually recording on 7 15 yet uh
my voice
still sounds raspy bro it's been five
days and
i dabbed myself into a throat thing so
if i sound weird on the show
we're uh we're pleasantly politely
blaming 710 it was my fault i didn't
hydrate properly i took away
just enough too many dabs had a
wonderful 7 10. i hope you had a good
weekend too bro we didn't get to hang
out
we're both doing our own thing so much
lately cove it sounds like a jay-z
song covid it's just that's
the reason for everything in 2020 man
that is the reason for most of
everything right now i'm gonna fade that
music out
710 was spectacular had a lot of fun uh
consumed a lot of good product
didn't get to go anywhere or see any
buddy that's not family but it's
not fun kind of different this year huh
not going out and uh
kind of different not going to an event
and being at the booth for
7 10 i've usually got a booth at some
event we've got people coming up and
saying hi from all over the place
i usually take a plethora of
concentrates and we dab out with
everybody
that was kind of a bummer not to get to
see everybody um going to need
go ahead i keep cutting off i was just
laughing i've got a sore throat but i
know it's not cup throat like we didn't
pass around
our own little stoner plague this year
no cup cough this year
uh i wish we yeah i wish we could i
would give i would take cup cough just
to have a cup right now
i think i think i say that now but i've
tried i wish we could be that normal
again man
that would be nice me too uh shout out
to all the people that i would have seen
at an event i can't wait to see you
we're going to need a big uh what did we
miss we missed easter
we missed uh st patrick's day we missed
4 20.
uh we missed earth day we missed a whole
bunch of good [ __ ] then cinco de mayo
and then summer and then 7 10.
and then august is going to be fall
we're going to get screwed on um we're
already wearing a mask
yeah no fish hit dicks this year don't
break my heart bro but the good part is
i've already got tickets for next year
the hardest part about going to
officials getting the damn tickets so
i'm set up for when they
hopefully get to go next year wow
we're set up for halloween dude we're
already wearing a mask yeah
it's it's been a strange [ __ ] year
and it's only getting stranger man
it's the ride ain't over it feels like
you're on a roller coaster and we're
still going up
like it hasn't tipped over yet i don't
think
i don't know how i feel about that
statement mike i don't know get a
[ __ ] helmet people
i like to hope that we're maybe trying
to make some progress at this point but
you're right um i'm gonna put this back
on track as a weed show
obviously mike is smoking some [ __ ]
ramble box concentrates over there well
i saw him
consume something a minute ago and it
was a bigger cloud of smoke than i'm
used to seeing
lemons sour ambrosia it's looking good
bro
um can we see the concentrate is there
any left in the jar i'm working on there
you go
see if i can get it yeah but tip it back
because you're going to spill it now so
get it back to
upright i mean like put it down normal
because you're going to spill it there
you go yeah we saw it good shot dude i
just know what you just spilled the
terps weren't about to leave
i
hitting us up on youtube to get a good
look yeah thanks for watching on youtube
good reminder bro
um we are on youtube also a lot of
people are used to us being on the audio
formats we're available
on spotify of course apple podcast and
of course stitcher
and many other audio formats but we're
also available on
the youtube so check us out on youtube
search for the grow from your heart
podcast of course
click subscribe press on the little bell
that way you get a notification every
time i come out put a new episode
sometimes mike is with me
i'm going to have more guests in the
future but join us
i invite you to find us on youtube um i
am smoking since somebody was polite
enough to ask i'm smoking garlic grove
live batter i've got a four gram jar of
the garlic grove
on the label that says gmo cookies and
loaf f2
the flavor is described as general sews
garlic and orange soda
i've mentioned before the thing they
lack to put on the jar here
is just a punch i just have a fist
because when you open it up it's like a
pleasant jack in the box it's like you
open the jar and
kapow right in the face it is delicious
it's tremendous
uh it has got me stoned but talkative i
love this concentrate for the podcast it
tastes really good i like the buzz
i like the way the batter hits uh for
710 i smoked
shatter i smoked crc concentrate i
smoked wax
i smoked a little bit of everything and
you can hear it in my voice right now
my favorite is always this green dot
labs alive batter
something about the way that it just
rips it makes big clouds it feels good
in my lungs and i'm always
heavily medicated from it on the back it
does say it contains
68.24 thc and non-detectable
amounts of cbd i like that blend but
seems to be working for me that's the
amount of thc i needed today
big shout out to our friends at green
dot labs for the garlic grove
live batter um i feel like we've been
going for a long time we haven't covered
much ground yet today bro we got
talkative right at the top of the show
uh keep it up bro please don't stop i
love it hashtag they love it when we
ramble
last episodes there was uh one of the
messages right at the end was more white
mike so
you wanted it you got it folks
abracadabra i told you if you didn't
want it that's at nemo punk 15 let me
know
you guys uh we got him at just the right
night too he's on he's on one tonight
good job mike
i'm in a good mood too it's just i
needed this so
two guys coughing let's do it here we go
this is fun bro i love hanging out with
you and doing these kind of episodes
what's on deck bro the
on deck is the 710 club this is the
portion of the show
where we give shout outs to the people
who support us on patreon at the 7
10 level or higher i call them the 710
club
um i wish i had some sort of like drum
sound right now i will get one that's
what we're missing so it'd be the 710
club
more equipment oh it's just a button
we'll make it happen
ah we'll do it in post i don't know
maybe i'll get stoned and forget
it's a good idea uh anyway let's move
forward and give some shout outs to the
bad [ __ ] who support us
on the 710 club let's start off with the
big grow from your heart podcast thank
you shout out to the captain
and commander of the 710 club let's send
a big thank you shout out to my boy
lemur priest
thank you bro uh there's a rumor that
lemur may be looking at
uh plane tickets and [ __ ] and when this
mess clears up there will be a irie
genetics lemur priest hang out it'll be
a good time but we gotta wait for all
this [ __ ] to go away and then
proper social distancing but there's a
rumor that we're thinking about
getting something together so we're
gonna hang out we gotta get back to
normalcy he's just gonna take a minute
yeah big shout out to you we got our
that's the truth bro and zoom shout out
to zoom uh big shout out to we're
rambling we're gonna get to a podcast
you guys we're gonna have fun today
uh big shout out to kent big shout out
to papa z big thank you to david h
always a big thank you to captain mojo a
big thank you to brandon
as always a big thank you to kimatic
i've got a new one for you let's send a
big grow from your heart podcast thank
you shout out and a fist bump let's send
a high five
and let's also roll up a big stinky
skunk joint to our friend
god dat skunk bill bill got that skunk
what up bill i want some of that skunk
buddy let's [ __ ] smoke i'm from socal
i grew up in socal smoking that socal
skunk
let's get high bro uh let's also send a
big shout out to just a smoking i'm just
a smoking i want to be just a smoking
some of that skunk
let's also send a thank you to xavier c
and last but certainly not least let's
send a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to girls
grow too big thank you big shout out and
thanks for all of the support
to everyone who supports the show on
patreon if you're not already supporting
the show on patreon and you'd like to
learn how
to do so all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need to
support the show will be right there on
the screen
of course please support white mike on
patreon as well patreon.com forward
slash white mike real easy i'll put
those links in
uh the podcast uh notes and in the video
descriptions
click on the link it'll get you right
there sorry for the face rambles you got
a brand new tongue i'll learn how to use
that
all right in this episode we are going
to answer listener emails
i've got a really interesting first
email
let's get to it we're getting to it
brother uh most of the time
when somebody sends me a grow question i
am filled with wisdom and answers i feel
99 confident this time i was like oh
[ __ ] i don't know what to say
i'm gonna have to reach out to mike and
some other people and see if we can come
up with some ideas
so this one is very interesting it says
hey ross to jeff thank you so much for
the
awesome am i holding this paper in front
of the camera no i don't want to block
myself out it says
ross to jeff thank you so much for the
awesome information and for your videos
i am totally blind and i am currently
teaching myself to grow marijuana
i live in the state of oklahoma and i
have a medical card i have smoked
marijuana for the majority of my life
uh 25 years now and i remember what
mature plants look like but i never had
any valuable
hands-on experience while i could see
now i'm trying to teach myself to grow
blind and i'm using the resources you
suggested
in the 401st episode of your podcast
there are things that i'm running into
though and i don't really know how to
handle them
wow this guy got further than i ever
think i
would if i were blind and trying to grow
this guy
has made success he's gotten somewhere
that's way further than i feel like i
could have gotten i'm proud of this guy
i'm impressed
oh for sure it's that's tricky there's
so much stuff that's
i'm automatically go well like you just
check the meter
my kind of stuff um like how you look
for light leaks
problem solving all the little pieces in
this is gonna get tricky
but like in a fun way if you like
puzzles right
he does have i've read this message and
he does have somebody that helps him out
he's blessed with somebody that
helps him out so we're gonna keep going
it says there are things i'm running
into that i don't really know how to
handle
i'm lucky that my wife can see and she
helps me with what she can
uh man uh big thanks for having an
amazing wife
however much yeah however i am dead set
on learning to do this with my own two
hands
if you were willing to toss me any
advice uh and share your wisdom it would
be greatly appreciated also
my situation is a unique one but i am
only i'm not the only blind person out
there growing
once i have stuff figured out and i have
a firm hold on a solid grow i will start
putting up videos
until then i have to conquer each aspect
of growing
and make sure that when i distribute
information regarding growing blind
i'm giving information that is useful
and will help other blind people love
and enjoy
cannabis um dude that is
such a [ __ ] awesome aspiration goal
uh well thought out plan i love that uh
that's
that's ambitious and i love it i love
ambitious stories i love people
who face adversity and they're gonna be
a bad [ __ ] because of it
like i don't know yeah thriving with
with a struggle that's awesome
uh and bless your wife for helping you
out because you're gonna need a little
bit of coaching to figure things out i'm
trying
so i spent like a day you kind of sprang
this one on me i'm trying
to wrap my head around it and that's a
big
question mark right now like there's so
many different things where my brain's
like well how are we gonna do this
yeah i as he as
the as a person who is often in charge
of large commercial cultivations
my main job is to oversee
[ __ ] ninety percent of what i'm doing is
seeing what's going on i just walk
around and look at [ __ ]
like is this room where it needs to be
are the temperatures i guess i feel that
part but i look at meters
uh do the plants look good does the
equipment say what it needs to say are
the lights doing within i go to another
room and then i
and i look at the crew are the guys
doing within the gals are they doing
what they need to do is mike doing what
he needs to do are the computers working
properly
because you guys are running computers
in part of the building are the trimmers
do i'm visually doing 90
of my job uh so yeah
the reason i wanted to read this is
because i had very
minimal useful advice i have never
i don't have any experience being blind
more about the
the growth set up before i could even
let's keep going let's keep going it
says we are currently
uh curing some lemon jeffrey i did not
really participate in the grow i was
just a cheerleader and a smell tester
so it sounds like the wife has probably
got a decent grasp on growing uh thanks
for all you do i hope to hear back from
you i understand
you're a busy man and you already have a
full plate thanks again and keep it up
kind regards uh they signed with their
full name i'm not going to say that but
uh we're going to call them uh inspiring
[ __ ] grower will be their new name
um so i don't have any like i said any
useful advice i don't i didn't ask a lot
of questions about
what kind of products you're using what
your setup is uh that that was more
technical than i was even ready to get
i thought there may be other blind
people
other blind growers other growers who
are losing their sight and slowly lost
their sight over time that have learned
how to adapt and adjust
yeah so i'm hoping they're listening
that's the other odds we've got to have
them listening
also so hopefully they're listening then
also hopefully
they're able to reach out to us and
reach us my email address
is grow from your heart at hotmail.com
if you send me an email and tell me that
you've got advice and ways to help out a
blind
grower or somebody who is losing their
sight i would love some advice to help
our new friend because this is a great
story
and big props to the wife but i
understand that you want to be
self-sufficient and do it yourself
that's really cool
and i want to see you do that but i've
never been blind so i don't have any
good advice for that it's
everything if you put if you blindfolded
me and put me in the grow room
i would hurt myself like there's so many
things in there that i'm just afraid of
without
sight and well it's
neither of us have had to operate
without it so we're both so heavily
reliant on it i'm just
like i'm thinking about a couple of
different
like nutrient stations that we've
managed
um and some of the different caustic
cleaner
agents or so we did talk a couple of
times
and he said that his biggest issues are
mixing and sexing so you're right the
nutrient station
like all the bottles look the same you'd
have to get different shaped bottles for
each nutrient
i was thinking about cloning and i'm
like well
you you can do a lot of that with feel
but when you go to check the roots and
you'll know this better than i do
so i've got the the plant and a plug i
pull that plug out to
to visually inspect if there are roots
but if i can't visually inspect how
sensitive are those to
to touch personally i never interact
with them
really until i go to transplant them and
then it's only
to gently set them in their cup right
and coat them with dirt can they handle
can you give them a gentle a gentle rub
to feel
how your roots are developing yeah i
think i think a little squeeze would be
okay but there's some situations that
can you squeeze to tell if the buds are
ripe like that's
um no but you can otherwise
um it's an eight week plant
you and i have both run schedules where
we would prefer
to check every plant with a scope
or a loop and look for
amber versus not amber versus white
versus cloudy
but we can't because we have to harvest
this [ __ ] on wednesday
because the next crop goes in on
thursday morning
so that it can be in flower by next
monday
yeah um you both know we both know how
that is so yeah
so pick a nine weeks straight yourself
up for success finding a strain that
you can hope will be relying on a
timetable and
um there's gonna be a lot of those
little tricks that you and i just can't
wrap our heads around yet because we're
not used to thinking with that
perspective exactly that's why i'm
reaching out and asking for
our other hopefully we've got a blind
audience a blind community that can help
us out and give us
some tips and tricks that they have
learned i look forward to hearing back
from
not only our new friend the blind grower
uh the inspiring grower but also
uh more listeners who have got some
ideas for us i wish i had more tips
this is something i've never that's like
yeah i've never played
you say that doesn't sound right as you
go looking for what piece of gear isn't
operating correctly
because you've got that [ __ ]
musician's ear so
you're they're so much more sensitive
than mine like i'll hear if
the ac is not running or some [ __ ] but
you'll catch all sorts of tiny little
pieces of equipment that i never even
hear
so i'm sure that's even more amplified
for somebody who's relying on that
sense more than their site can hear that
[ __ ] dehumidifier leaking all the
time nobody said nobody believed me
thing was leaking bro it's filled with
water
yeah i'm sure that especially with
the wife to help practice stuff
that we we can 100 figure out how to do
this yeah
shout out to the wife all right we're
gonna move on to a next message uh to
the next message
hopefully we can give a more solid
answer to this one yes
um i'm pretty sure we can i'm good at
this one uh this one comes
from let's see they want their names
said
uh yeah their name is miles this one
comes from miles what's up miles you bad
[ __ ] thank you for the good
message
it says hey bro love you love the show
love you too bro big fist bump up you're
watching on youtube
my name is miles i'm a patient and
caregiver and a grower
i'll start off by saying you have made
my skills as a grower sharpen over the
last year
i stumbled on onto your podcast after
seeing you on the dude grow show
i'm glad you found us on the dude grow
show big shout out to the dgc
and thanks for mentioning that i have
made you a better grow right uh
major skills sharpen that's awesome i
appreciate that uh since then i haven't
missed a new show and i've listened to
probably 200 podcasts
oh yeah you've heard a lot of this
[ __ ] terrible voice
thank you man yeah thank you bro keep
doing what you're doing for us
and to hone our trying to hone our
skills
excuse me for the throat clone you guys
i got mike too at the same time
there we go i just had a question for
you and it would be great
for the show and miles i do apologize
that it took me a minute to get to your
message
ah but here it comes buddy it is time
for your message on
the show it says my reason for writing
is seed
banks i know you have your own seed
banks you work with
and all like uh and then he put a couple
he listed a few of them
seeds here now at dank store are pros
i've recently had a rash of bad
seeds i've gotten them all from europe i
think we all know who that
is and then he says uh shh and then he
mentions the company we know if they're
coming from
uh from europe we probably know who they
are oops uh and it says
i've gotten from some from us breeders
and then he mentions a couple of us
breeders and i don't want to say their
names because i know some of these
people
and i know that some of them offer great
seeds and i know that some of them offer
not so great seeds
it goes on to say what is the deal with
quality control
why so many bad seeds out there and what
companies take care of their customers
i've gotten replacements
from some but others are anything but
friendly
uh he lists a company and he says this
company for example told me they do not
replace
freebies um let me back up and touch on
a couple of things because you did ask
what's the deal with quality control
it depends on like everything else bro
yeah there's no standard that's part of
the problem there's no standard
mini breeders are a name on a website
you click on [ __ ] i don't want to
single out any website i'm gonna make up
something
seeds.com you click on this website and
then you find a breederfuckingx and you
read his strain you go that sounds like
awesome description i want to buy it
that's your only connection between you
and breederx they can put
popcorn seeds in that [ __ ] container
the vendors that sell it
vet them good vendors vet their breeders
and don't allow that to happen
where you bought from they carry
everybody on the planet and things i've
never heard of before
uh they they're not gonna send you
popcorn seeds but there's no quality
control on the seeds that go out
what's the i pack the seeds for ire
genetics are the packs they go out
some breeders hire other people to pack
the seeds
and it's up to that person to select a
grade seeds and not give you b
or c grade seeds so that's part of the
process who packed them was it the owner
of the company was it one of his
flunkies was it his wife
was it somebody that knows is it was it
somebody that cares
so it's all about did they pick [ __ ]
quality seeds
there is no quality control it's all
about each company's own quality control
the quality control comes on the
consumer end on things like you're going
to go to the internet and you're going
to say
you're going to say all of the names i
blanked out on this you're going to say
all that [ __ ] on the internet
on the correct forums in the appropriate
places that's how quality control
happens in the seed industry
unfortunately so uh quality control
why so many bad seeds out there because
people can sell you seeds and never have
to face you again
i put my face out here i am irie
genetics i represent my company
if you come to our booth at an event
it's going to be probably myself
mike and one or two other people helping
us out but it's always going to be me
unless i'm talking or doing something
but i'm at the booth that's my job i'm
supposed to be there
they want to come talk to me you're
going to see me if you've got a problem
with my seeds you can politely say hey
i had an issue let's talk about it we'll
sit down and talk about it you'll
probably get a replacement if you've got
a real story
mike will probably be there too we put
our faces out there
so many people don't and if you don't
have to put your face out there
who knows what bad [ __ ] and
there may be a seed company called bad
[ __ ] seeds at this point
but whatever it's just an ad in the
paper as far as
yes it's a clicky thing on the internet
and you don't know who you're
interacting with or who you're talking
to
and so that's why people are able to get
away with it uh so that's the deal with
quality control that's why so many bad
seeds
uh what companies take care of their
customers
i know that and this is not advertising
or a sales pitch i know
that everybody at seeds herenow.com has
been personally
selected by james bean james b knows the
maker of all of the seeds on that
website
you have to shake his hand you have to
have a meeting with him you have to hang
out with him
he's a lot like me you could make him a
lot of money but if he doesn't like you
he will not put you on his website
that's simply how he works like no i
don't like your business that business
ethics
something about you makes me kind of
uneasy i don't need to do business with
you and he'll pass on you
so you got to be a good breeder to get
on seeds herenow.com
after that everything on the website is
backed by a satisfaction guarantee
if you've got a problem you contact
seeds herenow.com and let them know what
went wrong
most of the time you will get a
replacement pack of seeds if seeds are
now.com does not replace an irie
genetics pack
i will that's part of my my [ __ ]
quality control customer services if
you've got a problem with the pack of
seeds
i can afford to lose it more than you
can i'd much rather replace it and make
you happy
i'd rather eat a pack of seeds than eat
a customer eat my reputation
it's that easy for me and i know the
next pack will be good because there's
not going to be two bad packs in a row
that's very unlikely
so i don't know who takes care of their
company their service other customers
on a seed breeder level i know that the
vendors that seeds herenow.com has top
shelf customer service
i can highly recommend them um let's see
where are we gun replacements from some
but some are anything but friendly yeah
keep in mind though a lot of people will
just send breeders an email saying hey i
bought a pack of seeds they didn't
germinate give me replacements
and you can tell by the wording of the
message if they're scamming you or if
it's real ninety percent of the time i
can tell by the words
um so they're they're dealing with a lot
of that then
one company said they don't replace
freebies
uh they were freebies i don't know i i
don't know how to feel about that
i don't know uh paid money to be
eligible for that seed oh yeah because
you got to buy so many to get the
freebie so it was like a bait and switch
and then you gotta
so yeah they should replace that [ __ ]
for you um
and if it's bunk wouldn't you stand
behind your product
yeah i stand behind my [ __ ] so uh what
does one seed cost
um varies wildly yeah that varies wildly
how big is your production facility how
many people work for you and i know i'm
giving
vague [ __ ] politician answers right
now um
seeds are not expensive you guys like on
a wholesale
level at the level that the vendors are
buying seeds seeds are not expensive
it's the i don't know i don't want to
disclose too many like i don't know i
may have signed
paper saying i won't tell that part with
a lot of stuff you're not necessarily
paying for like
the pro can come over and fix what's
wrong in 30 minutes
but like you're not paying him for the
30 minutes you're paying him for the 15
years it took him to learn how to do it
in 30 minutes right
it's the same thing with breeding like
you're not paying for the cost
to produce a single seed you're paying
for the time thought energy effort work
dedication love that it took to breed
both those parents
then cross them then test them then
re-test them then stabilize them
and market them their packaging
lab testing each individual seed is no
it's not super pricey to produce
people [ __ ] up and produce seeds for
free all the time
yeah but those seeds nobody knows what
they are nobody knows who they came from
so those seeds were they're not worth
anything
but i think we've got that those ones
that didn't germ
like it's all perspective so that he
wraps it up with so i thought who would
be the best to ask about this stuff and
rasta jeff anyway i hope all is good in
your life and keep
growing g uh my friend miles i hope i
answered your question
customer service is all based on the
breeder
it's all about what the breeder believes
is quality i think everything should
come in a
pretty well labeled package i don't like
too much handwritten [ __ ] if you get a
package for me directly and it's
handwritten
it's because i actually had to package
that pack of seeds up for you and i
didn't have a whole sheet of labels made
and i just hand wrote it for you
but it always comes on the folded card
it looks real good i try to keep them
super professional
like good quality packaging just make it
look professional make it look sharp
stuff like that
uh good seeds in there i try not to put
shitty seeds in the packages if i
wouldn't plant that if i wouldn't be
excited to open that if i bought it
like i don't put it in the package i
keep in mind i know that people
money is expensive people [ __ ] work
their time their energy their effort
they're away from their [ __ ] people
they're away from their family
they're away from the air conditioner
bro it's so hot right now
for eight hours ten hours at a time
doing [ __ ] that sucks
listening to some [ __ ] yell at them
about [ __ ] that they're doing wrong that
is really not even their fault
i get it and they're giving me that
money that they made for a product
i understand uh i don't want them to
think [ __ ] i busted my ass and got [ __ ]
out of this i want them to think yeah
but i spent my money on is [ __ ] doing
it for me that always makes you feel
good
so uh that's my quality customer control
approach i want people to be happy
uh a lot of times there's six seeds in a
five pack that's not rare when it comes
to me
so miles thank you for the great message
dude if you've got any questions
uh send me a message i'd love to hear
from you grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
mike you ready to keep moving we
certainly should all right all right all
right
uh this one where are we it says
hey ross to jeff it's me again so
apparently this person
yeah this person i feel like i may have
read this message on the show before
i'm not sure if i read it uh enough
times
yeah yeah well it seemed familiar now
that i'm reading this but it says i'll
try to make it short fair warning it
won't be
when i was a teenager in the mid 80s i
was schooled by three old hippie vietnam
vets
they used to use they used to pirate
grow sorry for that
in the national forest shame on you guys
i was the gopher for two seasons
anyway they had an afghan they ran
exclusively in mile long rows
on south southwest facing slopes it
sounds like a great [ __ ] growth so
far
we would sew in a single row of 100 or
so plants
all right i can visualize this when they
started showing sex we would call every
male
except the best looking male and give
him only a day
to start spewing anyway it would
pollinate enough to ensure enough seeds
for the next
season that sounds about right so i was
gifted a coffee can
full of seeds yeah right
that was their that was 10 years into
their business
so i think that's an s 10
uh no not it says i think that's an s10
which has been
self for 10 generations uh no i want to
jump in right there before i lose my
train of thought it is not an
s10 it was not self it is an f
10 open pollination um
so f is for filial generation self would
be if we reversed one of the plants
you've got a male
so that is not a selfing that is an f
you're going yeah you're going further
with a filial generation so what
happened was
and who knows what f generation what
filial generation they started with so
they had a handful of seeds this is
presumably because you said every year
they planted a hundred seeds
did the hundred so yeah probably from
years before so you've got a hundred
seats they planted them
uh they picked a male so they took one
male and open pollinated up to 99 other
plants and gathered the seeds from there
that's an open pollination because who
knows which female
those came from it's the same uh plants
but it's an open pollination it's the
same genetics but
that way you get a lot of diversity you
see a lot of great phenotypes that male
has now hit every female phenotype in
there they're probably
somewhere between 4 12 16 maybe 32
different phenotypes
available in that female just because of
genetics and that male could possibly
pollinate
all of those and then we get to see what
that male does to all of those females
for the next generation so
he did that 10 times the first time it
happened
the first ones you planted that was f1
then you took those seeds
planted a hundred cold all the males you
got one boy
probably oh we're going to say there
were 50 girls because they probably
called 50 males
uh 49 males kept one male got 50 girls
left just because of the
math and numbers there so that one male
pollinated 50 girls
and now you did an f2 open pollination
and you just repeated that f3 open
pollination
it was not self because there was no
selfing there was no reversal
there was an actual male used in
pollination so it was a filial
generation moving forward
in an open pollination style because
you've got multiple females
which is a really good way to find
genetic diversity
all right so that catches us up a little
bit right there
uh where are we gonna go from there i
grew them for personal reasons only
until my divorce in 2010 and then uh my
genetics were mysteriously lost imagine
that
uh scotty would say hmm that's [ __ ]
funny we got a dgc listener here
then it goes on to say anyway my point
is i want to find something as close to
that as i can do you have any
suggestions or ideas
i was completely out of the game for 13
years and damn it's a different world
now
i feel like rip van winkle sometimes i
am forever grateful for you
from apical meristem also known as they
put their real name i'm not going to
read that out loud but big shout out to
our friend apical
uh atypical meristem sorry i read that
wrong the first time
um the last part of that question
they're looking for
genetics like with these old hippies
used to grow they had afghan
um man i would recommend look for some
pure afghan seeds you could probably
find some pure
seed banks yeah yeah some pure affy some
l-a-o-g-a something like that
i think dna genetics may be a good start
they are harder to get into the states
than a lot of other brands
but some of that uh l.a kush og
kush l-a-o-g affy that's the stuff
you're gonna be looking for
um i don't know if it's gonna be
anything like what you were smoking 13
years ago bro but
um keep chasing that dragon that's like
the growers [ __ ] thing that one thing
we smoked that one time
i've i've been looking for that p91 for
so long but i think
i think she's here we'll see we'll see
yeah it's everybody's got that one in
their head that they're still looking
for still chasing i think i got mine
dude and i'm excited but
i'm i'm i'm always skeptical until i
flower it
but it looks right it looks right and i
wouldn't know if it's
flowered right or not because i never
saw the plant i only got the buds
delivered in ounce and pound packages
so i don't know what the plant the
[ __ ] flowers and the plants even look
like
right yeah the
the old school stuff i think uh
unfortunately a lot of it's been lost to
time everything's been crossbred
but you never know because everything's
still half
or more underground uh there are who's
got what seeds in their sock drawer
and luckily some of the uh later states
to come into legalization and activism
they're still way behind so some of
those old genetics are still there
they've still got some of that old [ __ ]
so maybe somebody's got it
maybe some old war vets got some [ __ ]
from afghan that you know
like um put it out into the universe
that you're looking for this old afghan
do some research on the internet
put it out there it will come to you my
friend it will come to you that's how
ah that's how these things work i've
been looking for this one strain for
years i said something in the right chat
room and someone's like i've got that
i'm sitting on it you want one of them
here
and i was like huh what so that's how i
ended up with one of the strain that
i've been looking for for
since uh 2002 2001-ish i've been trying
to find a clone of this
i've got it now yeah so be patient when
the time is right
that [ __ ] may just [ __ ] land
right in your lap
or in your mailbox it's a strange time
to be alive i [ __ ] love it
it's a beautiful time to be alive bro it
is a beautiful time uh those were the
only emails that i had selected for this
show i feel like we burned right through
them quite quickly today
mike i had a good [ __ ] time hanging
out with you oh yeah
we uh we put these off for a minute we
got through some stuff
um i'm actually glad i stepped back
because holy [ __ ] did you step up the
level of content buddy
that's uh last couple shows have been
stellar thank you bro i appreciate that
i hope everybody else enjoyed the shows
too the feminized seed got a lot of
notice the male plant selection got a
lot of notice and the ones in between so
thank you guys episodes were amazing
and uh i laughed really hard at the air
conditioning episode because i've been
dealing with that stuff too
i think we're all kind of everybody's
head's in the same place like [ __ ] it's
hot right now how do i get half of
half of my social media thinks i'm
psychic like that's what i was thinking
about and i was like bro it's
every email i get is it's too hot help
yep i uh was starting to scout out a
place
at the new house where i could put a
tent and
immediately as soon as it got hot this
summer it was one of the things i was
waiting on
i wanted to see what the air flow in
this house does in the summer
and already i'm like nope not growing
needs modification yeah yeah you notice
quickly when the heat comes
yep yeah yeah yeah not running as many
lights this summer
holy [ __ ] dude no i uh it affected
everything i remember arguing with
owners because i couldn't get them to
understand that trimmers can't work in a
100 degree building for
and and be the same level of productive
as they are in a 75 degree space it's
just
the heat'll [ __ ] you quick yeah yeah and
that
we're talking about local weather [ __ ]
now but uh we are in the
high desert mid desert area and where we
were the wind would come by
and you could feel the water just leave
your body
like this dry hot wind would come by and
you'd be like huh it just took my
moisture oh [ __ ]
like all the water would just go out of
your whole body you need a gallon of
water to replace it immediately
well it's i mean it's not just we got
high instead of talking about local
weather it's just
this is what the cannabis world's
dealing with right now you got to
mitigate those [ __ ] high temps and a
lot of people
um a lot a lot of people started growing
for the first time or growing
for the first time in a long time
because everybody's on lockdown we're
bored as [ __ ]
like i've got a massive vegetable garden
going right now and i'm
dying to put some cannabis seeds out
there i can't
i'd [ __ ] love to come on i got extra
clone
i got two or three perfect [ __ ] spots
for him too i've got uh
a patch of corn where a couple didn't
sprout so i've got some gaps
that i'd love to fill but uh
i can't do it i got to stay legal but
there are a lot of people where
they can grow outside or they're going
to grow outside regardless and
got to mitigate that heat man no matter
where you're at yep
i did a consultation for a good friend
who uh shut up bro who uh was building a
grow indoors and he's like it's hot and
humid help
and i was like yeah that's [ __ ]
that's the story dude
hot and humid right now yeah we get
lucky in colorado because it's
it's so dry here so we can usually find
a way around the
the water we produce but [ __ ] dealing
with that heat in the high desert
[ __ ] this is a new sun bro i haven't
this is not the sun i went to [ __ ]
school under
yeah sounds like the globe is warming or
something
all right on that note we're going to
start wrapping up the show uh make sure
you follow white mike
yeah punk 15 y'all uh
on all of the social medias and also
don't forget about his patreon at
patreon.com forward slash
white mike um ladies and gentlemen boys
and girls pimps and hoes friends and
foes smokers and growers clone cutters
pollen chuckers indoor growers outdoor
growers
greenhouse guys and gals all you bad
[ __ ] out there
i want to thank each and every one of
you for listening to this show if you
feel like this episode was edumacational
and or informative maybe also
entertaining
maybe you'd like to support the show you
can do so by visiting
forward www.patreon.com grow from your
heart all the information you need to
support the show will be right there on
the screen
once again big thanks and big shout out
to my boy lemur priest for all the
[ __ ] patreon support you're a
bad [ __ ]
um i want to thank mike once again for
hanging out make sure you visit his
patreon campaign at patreon.com forward
slash
white mike uh also support our sponsors
at seeds here now dot com get yourself
some great seeds
use coupon code gfyh10 while you're
checking out
to save yourself ten percent also i
think i can officially announce it here
i always talk about the seeds for under
thirty dollars at seeds here now dot com
guess what
there is irie genetics for under thirty
dollars at seeds here now go click under
the
under 130 tab scroll down until you find
the irie genetic strain
they've got a pack of irie genetic seeds
for you for under
30 bucks go check them out um and you're
welcome i love you that's because i love
you guys also
like i've said before if you were
watching listening on an audio format if
you're listening right now on apple
podcast if you're listening
on what else is there stitcher or uh
spotify
i encourage you i invite you to come
check us out on the youtube channel come
see what myself and cracker mic look
like
come have a good time with us on the
youtube channel go to uh youtube search
for the girl from your heart podcast
uh click on the little uh subscribe
button also click on the notification
bell that way you never miss an episode
when i come out with a new episode um i
think that's all i've got for you mike
you got any final words for this episode
none man all right keep living people
see you next
uh next tuesday see you next tuesday
all right i get it i get it uh mike keep
taking good care of yourself and your
family over there bro looking good
i was exciting to get you on here i want
to give a giant shout out to my buddy
buzz bros
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me