[Music]
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me ross to jeff and it is time for
episode 551 of the grow from your heart
podcast
this episode of the show is brought to
you by our friends at seedshearnow.com
seedshearnow.com carry seeds from all
the industry's
leading breeders including miss jill
genetics duke diamond
and of course irie genetics everything
at seeds herenow.com is backed by an
award-winning satisfaction guarantee
and for my friends on a budget
seedshearnow.com offers
several packs for under 30 dollars as
well as amazing
monthly sales make sure to use coupon
code gfyh10 while checking out to save a
few bucks
again that is coupon code gfyh10 while
checking out
at seeds here now dot com
you know i'd like to start this podcast
off by talking about what i'm smoking
today i've been taking dabs of halo live
batter from green dot labs
this is a blend of headbanger and
infinity og
on the package the flavor is described
as deconstructed sour diesel
i'm not sure what a deconstructed sour
diesel is supposed to taste like
i do know that this concentrate was sour
and gassy
and fuelly and funky and i do know that
it got me
heavily medicated so big shout out to
our friends at green dot labs for the
delicious
halo live batter all right in this
episode i am going to do a strain review
we are going to focus on my strength
dark hollow before we get there
let's do some shout outs to a few folks
who support the show
on patreon at the 710 level or higher
these are the folks i call the 710 club
let's start off with the big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to the
captain and commander of the 710 club
let's send a big thank you shout out to
my buddy lemur priest
let's also send a big thank you shout
out to brendan p i've also got a big
thank you shout out to my friend
the restaurant i hope that's how you say
that bro if i'm saying it wrong
send me a correction i'll give you an
appropriate shout out
i also have a big thank you shout out to
my buddy david h let's send a big thank
you to totally white tops
i've always got a big thank you shout
out to my buddy gramps richard memmel
thank you for all the support bro
let's also send a big thank you shout
out to my buddy the canon craft big fist
bump thank you for all the continued
support
i've also got a big thank you shout out
from my friend john kaye
let's send a big thank you shout out to
okiegrow 720 keeping it real down there
let's also send a big thank you to homie
d and last but
certainly not least let's send a big
grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out to my buddy fat
rabbit
big thank you big shout out to everybody
who has continued to support the show on
patreon
if you're not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need will be
right there on the screen
and i did include a link in the show
notes and the video description
to make it easy to get there for my
stoner friends and i did
start to include the https colon
backslash part of the link so the link
will actually work now
i was typing in www.patreon.com i was
not making an actual link in the youtube
video description i have corrected that
big thank you to the person who gave me
that little tidbit of advice
i am very open to constructive criticism
and corrections and
updates please send me anything like
that don't be shy that helps me out that
helps you out helps us all out
thank you once again big thank you and
big shout out to everybody who continues
to support the show
on patreon i do appreciate that support
now i did say we were going to do a
strain review in this episode and we're
going to talk about
dark hollow let's jump right into that
part of the podcast
stream reviews are always some of my
favorite episodes and it seems like you
guys really enjoy them too
i get to talk about something i created
this is like showing you pictures of my
kids so this is a really good time for
me
and at the same time you guys get to
learn a lot about the products i create
you get a little bit of insight into my
brain of what my goals are and what i'm
trying to do
so with a little less rambling let's get
right into it
dark hollow dark hollow is one of my
newest releases
i am mostly known for making kind of
candy fruity real terpy
real high thc uh thc sativa dominant
hybrids and crosses i've got a male
known as king solomon who puts really
high thc
into most of his offspring i have
selected
very candy flavored very distinct
terpene profile rich
female plants to breed with so a lot of
what i make comes out very candy
flavored very sweet very head buzzy
a lot of people have been asking for
more of an indica buzz more of that
garlic flavor more gassy flavors more
gassy aromas more fuelly funky sort of
[ __ ]
i don't particularly breed for what
everybody else wants i'm breeding for
what i love that's why it works i feel
like i'm kind of an artist i'm making
art that comes from my heart
it works for me in turn that makes a
quality product that
the market wants so it sells to the
consumers as well
i'm sure you can tell by listening to
the opening of the show all of the dabs
i dab
i give away a lot of what i enjoy i talk
about i give good hints on what i enjoy
at the start of the show when it comes
to my dad's recently i have been not
just recently lately
since probably the fall i've been in
love with
funky gross garlicky kind of turps if
it's real savory
garlicky funky body odory maybe some
armpits
ah i don't know it's got maybe a little
bit of hints of vomit in there i have
been
in love with those types of aromas and
so
i acquired a cut of the gmo a while back
and i loved it i was growing it i was
smoking it it was amazing
what's the next step for a breeder to do
to breed with the cuts that he has
acquired so i took my prized
king solomon male let's talk about
solomon briefly
uh arise is golden goat and daybreaker
it's a golden goat female
pollinated by a daybreaker male so i've
got a real sweet
tropical flavored female that i
pollinated with an og
kush chem dog cross of a male that made
my
arise that arise is very well known
for putting out high thc offspring
there are tests uh near 35 there's 35.84
uh there are a few other 34 and 33 thc a
test that come from a rise
so it very consistently puts out high
thc numbers
i found a male in there that i call king
solomon there's a lot to that if you
want to study king solomon you'll
understand why
solomon's got a lot of wives he's bred a
lot in my room
he's made a lot of quality offspring so
i know that king solomon is a champion i
know he makes
tremendous thc i kind of call him the
fixer if i've got a female plant
that doesn't grow the way that i would
like it to grow it doesn't produce the
way i would like it to produce
pollinate it with king solomon find a
phenotype that comes from there
it will be perfect it will correct the
problem and make it better it'll be the
original plant you had
plus better structure faster growth
hyper vigor
and more potency so solomon is my fixer
plant i call him
the king he is the [ __ ] king i have
not found a better male plant than that
so
i took my male king solomon plant and of
course i pollinated
the gmo let's talk a little bit about
gmo
um gmo i should the first thing i should
say is gmo does not
stand for garlic mushroom onions we'll
talk briefly about
the gmo name here gmo is a chem cookies
cross
and it was never meant to be garlic
mushroom
onions it has got chem dog in it it's
got girl scout cookies in it and it
smells
really funky there is a phenotype that
goes around colorado the phenotype that
i bred with
it came from a guy known as skunk master
flex what up skunk i hope you hear this
one day nothing but love and respect for
you
skunk called this plant the gmo
because it smelled funky and it is bred
to the girl scout cookies now at the
time
that this strain became popular the girl
scouts of america
were under scrutiny because it had been
discovered that their girl scout cookies
were being made
with gmo products and they weren't
quality cookies i'm not gonna even go
down that route
but that is where the gmo came from it
smells crazy
it smells funky it smells like chemicals
so that gives you a weird gmo vibe
already
it's got girl scout cookies in it so
that leads us to
the girl scout cookies being discovered
that their product was filled
with gmos and non-desirable [ __ ] for us
to put in our bodies
and they're selling it to us at a
premium so it was
the gmo and the girl scout cookies is
what sparked
the idea to call it gmo it is not garlic
mushroom onions
it may smell like garlic mushroom onions
to some people i had a concentrate of it
that smelled like mushrooms and swiss
cheese it absolutely did
but that is not why that name came about
so i want to dispel that myth that rumor
i want to put skunk masters real story
out there he called it gmo because it's
got girl scout cookies in it
it smells like chemicals and the girl
scouts were under scrutiny
for being discovered that their product
was laden with gmo so that's where the
gmo
name came from let's talk more about the
plant a little bit now
the plant grows really tall and lanky it
is kind of a problematic plant it is a
pain in the ass of a plant
it would not do it will work in a
commercial environment but it is not
going to be the one that makes the boss
happy
and it's not going to be the one that
gets the grower a bonus check
it does make big giant buds but it grows
very slowly
it's kind of lanky it's kind of stretchy
and it has
issues it likes to get calm ag deficient
it's got some other problems to it
it's kind of a finicky little [ __ ] if
you don't feed it right it doesn't give
you what you can get
so i took the gmo female
and of course i pollinated that with
king solomon what was my goal
my goal was to get those garlic turps i
love that
savory it's like mashed potatoes and
with garlic garlic mashed potatoes or
it's almost like you're dabbing or
smoking a savory thanksgiving meal
i wanted that garlic terp but i wanted a
better
flower a better plant structure and a
shorter flowering time
the gmo takes a little bit too long to
flower the buds aren't very big
it's super potent and super tasty and
it's very effective but it could be
better so my goal was just to improve it
keep that terp
but improve on that lanky shitty
structure and improve on the flowering
time and also
improve on the harvest weight because it
does not put out big fat buds
so of course i pollinated the gmo
with king solomon and now we've got dark
hollow
um i'm going to skip a few things and i
want to tell you why i call it dark
hollow
dark hollow of course is a grateful dead
song it's one of my favorite grateful
dead songs
one of my favorite versions is off of
bear's choice best of the grateful dead
volume two it's an acoustic version i
know that's a lot of weird info you
probably don't care about
maybe you do if you're interested in
that i want you to be able to find it
dark hollow by the grateful dead another
really good version
of that song is on reckoning another
live album they put out
anyway that's where the name came from
dark hollow
um it makes big dark leaves there's a
phenotype that will make
nearly black purple leaves and they
start to get this weird velvety texture
toward the end when you start flushing
so the dark colored leaves it had that
dark flavor to it
savory flavors dark hollow it stuck for
me
i am going to do a full episode on how i
name strains but right now i just want
to give you an idea
the grateful dead song the grateful dead
means a lot to me i love their music
they just feel good
so dark hollow the song name the leaf
color
it all worked out for us with the flavor
that's how he got the name it makes
big fat dark color leaves dark hollow
so um let's talk about some of the
aromas
and flavors that you will get from dark
hollow i keep saying garlic
the garlic aromas come through very well
there are also hints of rubber like car
tires
there are also hints of if you've ever
popped open
a fresh jar of tennis balls that's kind
of what it smells like fresh tennis
balls
or sometimes it smells like new shoes if
you ever get a brand new pair of nikes
and you open up the nikes that
leather and rubber smell kind of comes
out it sort of got that sort of a smell
to it
it's also got uh gassy aromas there are
gassy
gassy aromas in some of these phenotypes
there is one phenotype
that makes a disgustingly amazing
sour vomit aroma and i love it i cannot
get enough of that phenotype i know that
sounds terrible
but it's like that's gross oh i love it
that's so gross let me smell it again
it's just so disgustingly pleasant that
i cannot stop smelling it so
it's real savory uh i say bottom end
lower sort of notes of smells not the
high sharper stuff
lower stuff real savory uh garlic gas
rubber tires uh stabby says it smells
like leather boots
so i will agree with that because of the
shoe factor it kind of smells like a
pair of fresh
leather nikes it's got that rubber got
the leather like you just opened up a
fresh pair of jordans or you're walking
through the nike store
kind of does have that sort of aroma now
let's talk about
the buzz i call dark hollow
deep thinking weed most of what i breed
uh
puts me uh i purposefully love to smoke
myself and do a panic attack i want to
smoke right at the edge where i'm like i
don't know what's going on man
i want to smoke right to giggles right
to that point
the dark hollow i can smoke myself
into the couch i usually don't breed
things that make me go into the couch
this one i can turn off my entire body
and go numb
i can get into a little bubble and i can
just think
and i just end up in a it's meditation
weed you're just
nothing's going on around you you could
you could burn down the entire house
you can move all the furniture out as
you as long as you don't touch the couch
i'm sitting on i'll never notice
if i've smoked enough dark hollow it
puts you in this little puts me
in this little just a bubble i call it
thinker wheat or bubble weed or
meditation weed
or it just feels like you're just
isolated in a good way it's not a scary
way
it just shuts everything off around you
so if you're one of those people that
has a hard time
shutting things down this may be good
weed for you if you need to go to class
and kind of be able to just shut
everything off and pay attention to the
professor and just take notes and learn
this may be the [ __ ] for you it's not
multi-task weed it's not
[ __ ] do the dishes and listen to
music weed
this is lock in and [ __ ] be in your
brain kind of weed so
it tastes real good it's got a real nice
buzz to it now let's talk about this is
a grow podcast so let's talk a little
bit about growing
dark hollow that's my favorite part is
growing i don't know that's a tough
choice do i prefer to grow it or smoke
it
ah i don't want to make that decision
we'll keep moving shout out to our
friends at green dot for the halo
concentrate got me thinking down
down that path uh you tell me if you had
to make a decision you can either grow
weed or smoke weed for the rest of your
life but only one which one are you
picking
send me a tweet at gfyhpodcast on
twitter
now let's talk about growing these
plants i keep saying it
in most of my strain descriptions but
these plants will get
tall they're going to get tall on you
uh the gmo plant is known for being very
tall it's got that chem dog kind of a
structure it's got that cookies kind of
a structure
it gets real long and lacy it'll it'll
grow rope vines on you if you let it so
you've got to keep
it a lot of light to keep it nice and
compact i do a lot of cracking of the
stems
i talk about popping stems a lot i grab
the stem with a couple of fingers in one
spot a couple of fingers on my thumb
i grab right above it with a couple of
fingers on my thumb and i simply twist
in different directions until you hear a
little pop
just a little snapping sound you have
now broken the cellulose structure of
the plant
instead of that plant growing vertically
straight up it's going to send some
energy to healing that broken part of
the plant
it won't get taller it will get thicker
we like them nice and thick we want them
nice and wide
so go ahead and crack those stems
because they're going to get very tall
there will also be plenty of distance
between your nodes
for some reason this cross likes to put
some distance between the nodes if you
give it plenty of light
you'll minimize that but it will get
some space between the nodes
that does allow a lot of very easy
trellis work if you're a person that
does trellising
this plant will weave into the trellis
very easily because of those long
branches
let me keep myself on track talking more
about the growing
uh it's going to get tall it will do the
21 day stretch on you
it is probably going to get really tall
during that then the stretch
slows down and all that part where it's
stretched fills in with
big fat thick chunky buds uh this will
make
just giant chunky colas the whole way
through but it looks like you're gonna
get big stretchy plants at first just
give them time to fill in
and like i keep saying it wants a lot of
light
a lot of light these plants really seem
to like a lot of light
so you're going to get some big leaves
on some of these plants
you may get some big giant black leaves
big giant bright green leaves
big giant purple leaves later in the
flowering phase
they may start to turn like a champagne
pink sort of a color as they fade out
that is a good thing there is no problem
there that's what you want
also some of the larger leaf
phenotypes may be droopy that is not a
problem
the daybreaker grandparent on the arise
side
had very large leaves sometimes that
male would droop
he wasn't thirsty he hadn't met his dli
he just had such
big leaves that sometimes they would
just hang down like he was like bro
these leaves are huge
i'm not holding them up all day i'm just
going to kind of let them droop a little
bit
if you see these plants drooping a
little bit and you know that your water
is fine you know that your dli is up to
speed
don't stress that is a trait of these
plants that comes from the daybreaker
grandparent i think it comes from the
joseph
og grandpa to tell you the truth so
if you see some droopy leaves and you
know you have watered
that is okay uh you may see some really
long
pedials um the leaves will stick really
far
off of the plant that is okay many
people think that's a problem
that is a trait coming from the
daybreaker also the girl scout cookies
so long pedials is to be expected
purple pedials are not a problem you may
see some purpling in this plant
it's not a nutrient deficiency that is
not a cold issue
that is what this plant does it will
make colors like that
so you're gonna see long purple pedials
and big colorful leaves
you're gonna get long branching a lot of
long
long branching not many side shoots but
really long branches it's going to grow
kind of like
og kush you guys if you're familiar with
growing og
it just gets long and switchy but then
once you put it into flour that long
switchy [ __ ] will fill in with nothing
but colas
so be ready for kind of stretchy long
pain in the ass plants this is not going
to be the easiest plant to grow but in
the end it will be well worth
all of the work i keep saying it grows
kind of like og
kush anyone who's familiar with og knows
that these plants will need extra cow
mag
cookies often needs more calmag og needs
more calmag
be on top of the calmag for this plant
if you see
the little spots forming in the middle
of the leaves that is probably unless
it's spider mites pay attention
that is probably your earliest sign of
calmag calmag is going to be
the most common deficiency with these
plants
uh they're going to get tall they're
going to get kind of stretchy they're
going to double in size
you will need supports you will need
some sort of sticks
tomato cages or trellises i like to grow
these plants with sticks a lot of the
times i do trellis and tomato cages i
prefer sticks with these plants because
of the way they grow
top it one time you'll get four big tops
use those four big tops put sticks in
there
then you can kind of put them in the
room real close together
that's the way i do it with this plant i
don't do the cages
with the dark hollow i prefer sticks
if you're going to trellis trellis early
because it does get stiff and woody i've
noticed that
these phenotypes something in the
genetics it tends to get stiff and hard
toward the end of life it won't be
really easy to work so
um my i wrote it again calmac i must
really
mean calmag these plants are gonna want
extra calmag you're going to notice a
couple
of different very distinct phenotypes
there will be a black leafed phenotype
the black leaf phenotype you'll notice
it early in flower about week four or
five it'll start turning darker on you
the pedials will get black
the black leafed phenotype has a
tendency
to look angry later in flower this is a
trait from the girl scout cookies late
in flower the leaves will go really dark
in color
and maybe they'll just start doing weird
claw shapes or the leaves will start
doing weird [ __ ] to you
that is a trait from the girl scout
cookies and it just happens
i cannot keep that plant happy all the
way to the end no matter what i have
done
i've noticed the blacker leafed
phenotype
prefers lower ph and cooler temps
so if you've got that dark colored
phenotype lower your temperatures
lower your ph it may make that plant a
little bit happier
if you have got the green leaf dominant
phenotype and you'll be able to tell you
guys this plant makes really dark
and really light phenotypes and it
indicates early that lighter
green colored phenotype is going to like
your standard
temperatures and your standard ph uh
when i say standard i'm talking like
77 to 82 84 whatever you guys are doing
in the grow
and your standard ph like five nine to
six four or whatever
but when it comes to the darker leaf
phenotype you're gonna wanna get like 72
74 degrees it can take a little bit
colder it can certainly take a colder
night temperature
and you want to drop that ph down to
like six six two and stay
there with the dark leaf phenotype of
course i'm giving you advice based on my
experience
your room your nutrients your equipment
your plants everything is going to have
a variable your style will play a factor
into this
so anything i say is from my experience
what i've seen through testers
what i've seen in my rooms your
experience may vary
listen to the plants the plants are the
boss
you may want to give them more calmac
you may have a schedule that says
this is going to happen who cares if the
plants say don't do this
don't do that if the plants say please
do this please do that
we need to be we need to have a good
strategy we need to be in control
but we also need to be open to
suggestions from the plants the plants
are the boss our goal is to make
quality product in the end and if we
don't pay attention to the plants you
don't have quality product in the end so
take everything i say very seriously but
also know
that your room your plants your
phenotypes
everything are going to play a factor
and you may have different experiences
so pay attention to the plants but from
what i've noticed
those green the bright green phenotypes
like a little higher temp
and a little a higher ph of course the
darker colored plants like the cooler
temperature
and the lowered ph uh what else can we
talk about i've got a few
few more notes here oh harvest times the
darker colored plants they will take
less time than the bright green colored
plants i say that the dark hollow
takes somewhere between 9 and 11 weeks i
mostly say 9 to 10 weeks there will be
outliers you'll find an 8 week phenotype
you may find one that grows really black
leaves really wide black leaves with
purple pedials
and it makes really dark buds that is
almost a copy of the girl scout cookies
that one finishes in the end of week
eight
56 55 days she's ready to chop down and
smoke
she's ready to go so you may find that
eight week phenotype
the nine week phenotype is a beautiful
combination
it's got that cookies aroma and flavor
and funk and stank
it's also got the garlic in there it's
got just enough darkness to give it some
really beautiful colors on the buds
and it doesn't take 10 or 11 weeks to
finish you'll find another phenotype in
there
that is very bright green i think this
one
is kind of it's more like the 50 50 mix
it's got the arise in there
it's got the the gmo in there it's got a
sweet garlicky thing to it
but that one's going to take you a
little bit longer to flower
so we've got our girl scout cookies
dominant phenotype
we've got the one that i think is kind
of a 50 50. that one's going to take
about 10 and a half weeks of flower
probably
then we've got our the dark hollow that
it looked like
token nailed this phenotype you can see
it was
bright green but right where the leaves
are sticking out of the buds they were
starting to turn purple you can see
the sugar leaves were turning purple as
they were coming out of the buds
i think he took that one nine weeks and
it looks perfect you guys it looks like
a giant menorah of buds
when he hung it upside down it was
nothing but bud from the base
all the way to the tip big fat chunky
buds and i'm pretty sure he took that
one nine full weeks big shout out to
jrtoken
you can see his photos on cano buzz uh
shameless plug for cannabis it's a
cannabis friendly social media
application uh where you can post your
cannabis photography
check out cannabis on your iphone or
your android
device i'm going to take a sip here and
get my voice and myself back on track
all right so we've got a few distinct
phenotypes to look for we've got the
girl scout cookies looking phenotype
that wraps up around week eight
we've got that sort of 50 50 looking
phenotype that's going to take a little
bit longer 10 and a half maybe 11 weeks
then we've got that beautiful phenotype
that gets dark
it makes purple leaves it grows really
big
big fat chunky colas it smells like
garlic and sweetness and a little bit of
gas and some dirty feet
that is your nine-week phenotype that's
the one you were looking for
you'll start seeing the greener buds
start making purple leaves around the
edges when you flush it
those purple leaves start turning gold
that is a beautiful
phenotype i really love that one i want
to talk about some of the aromas
the phenotype that smells like rubber
early on
turns to gas once you dry and cure it
that's what i have noticed
the rubbery tennis balls fresh nikes
when you cut that one down trim it dry
it and cure it
it tends to turn very garlic that is
when the garlic
appears as later in the dry and cure and
then when you extract that
if you make a squish that's when the
garlic really
really comes out of that one there is a
phenotype
that smells sour it's got a gross
sour smell to it i think it's a longer
flowering phenotype
this one i didn't find this phenotype
this one was presented to me
it smelled sour and gross this is the
one that i kind of say smells like a bar
trash can or a little bit of vomit
it had when i smoked a bowl of this one
it had the most
intense eye buzz um
i don't know how else to explain it
other than my eyes got really heavy and
kind of vibratey and bloodshot red
it went straight to my eyes so if you
get the phenotype
that smells acrid and sour and has a
little bit skinny or longer
super serrated leaf that one is going to
be
a crazy high buzzer it was really
intense on the eyes
straight to the head i felt like i just
wanted to stare at the floor i was so
high i felt like my eyes
wanted to water um a couple more notes
that i've said
leaf droop i've talked about the leaf
droop i don't want you guys to freak out
when the leaves get droopy that is a
trait that comes
from the daybreaker male i've said this
before a lot of the crosses
more of the indica dominant stuff that
comes from the daybreaker
will get these droopy leaves it is not a
problem with your plants it's not a
problem with the room it's not a problem
with the water it's not your fault
that's what these plants do pay
attention make sure she's not too dry
as long as it's not too dry that's just
what the plant does
also when the plants have reached their
dli when they've had enough light for
the day
they will droop just to show you i've
had enough light i'm not gonna photo
photosynthesize anymore today i'm gonna
take a little break just like a person
when they've done their work for the day
and they're done they just go lean
against the wall
your plant is leaning against the wall
just put its hat in its face it's taking
a little break
uh purple stems i don't want you guys to
freak out if you see purple stems that
is not a problem
with these plants sometimes you're going
to get purple stems
that is a good thing
you may see purple pedials you may see
straight up purple
branches you may get purple stems that
is not a problem
those plants will turn into the black
phenotypes the darker leaved phenotypes
they'll smell gassy and garlicky and
delicious you'll have that girl scout
cookies dominance in there
i think that those will be great plants
for you
uh let's see there's one i said it
smells
like a problem there's one that smells
like something's wrong
if you've ever left a pot of soil
in water too long and it got sort of uh
it's almost crappy it's moldy it's funky
it's like dirty water uh it almost
smells like it needs to be flushed or
wiped it's got a really bad
sour disgusting smell to it uh that's
not a problem
with that plant that's just an aroma
that one of the phenotypes make
so one of the grandparents is joseph og
or it's uh it's josephogee and kim d
makes the daybreaker and i think the
joseph og in there
is what is giving us that funky
it's it's really gross it makes my nose
go oh it makes my whole body go
oh but it smells terrible when it's
growing it smells
anaerobic it smells like you've got some
sort of anaerobic fungus going on
and i have never found a problem in the
pot i've never found a problem with that
plant none of the other pots or anything
had an issue
but this one plant just made this
terrible
barfy [ __ ] disgusting aroma
and then when you dry it and cure it and
smoke it it is so
dank you can smell it down the block
it's like uh garlicky dirty feet
but when it's growing if it smells like
it's disgusting
don't don't be worried uh i don't think
you've got a problem like i've said you
could
you could it smelled like there was
something dead in the pot it smelled
like a mouse
climbed into the pot dug a little hole
and died in there
and that's what we were smelling but it
was the [ __ ] plan you guys so if you
get that aroma
you're welcome and i apologize that i
did that to your grow
up grow it finish it out dry it and cure
it let's smoke it see what it does
call it that [ __ ] dead mouse
phenotype i don't know but that exists
that is an opportunity i just want to
make sure that if you get that you don't
freak out because there is one
that really smells horrible in the best
way
i hope you get it send me a clone all
right ladies and gentlemen i think that
wraps up
my uh notes that i took for the review
on the strain
dark hollow there are phenotypes that
will finish up in eight weeks there's a
good phenotype that wraps up at nine
you'll find some that take ten i know
there are a couple phenotypes that go
longer
you'll be able to tell them by their
skinnier skinnier
leaves the more desirable phenotypes in
my opinion
have wider leaves the skinnier leaf
phenotype you get
start getting more told toward the
golden goat i've got plenty of other
offerings that give you that golden goat
dominant flavor and style
so i really look for the wider leaved
phenotypes when it comes to dark hollow
that's where you're going to get those
garlicky
more savory aromas it's going to go
sweeter
the taller the plant the skinnier the
leaf i feel like the sweeter
and the more tropical flavors you're
going to get so i like those
broader leaves i like the dark colors i
really like the pukey
uh crappy gross kind of smelling
phenotypes early on
um feeding it give it calmag it will go
macro deficient early
make sure you give it calmac if you
start seeing issues early on it is
probably
calmag if you see those leaves curling
up and twisting up
that's just something that the
phenotypes do sometimes they look like
[ __ ] by the end
but they really harvest well and they
taste amazing and smoke well
so just treat them the best you can
alright ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls pimps and hoes friends and foes
smokers and growers clone cutters and
pollen chuckers that's what i've got for
you for this episode if you've got any
corrections
questions or concerns i would love to
hear your feedback send me an email
my email address of course is grow from
your heart
at hotmail.com if you are looking for
any dark hollow seeds or any ivory
genetic seeds for that matter
i highly recommend seeds here now.com
make sure to use coupon code gfyh10
while you're checking out to save a few
bucks
and i recently added a strain to the
under
30 tab now if you go to seeds here now
click on the strains for under 30 bucks
you will find an irie genetics offering
in the under 30 tab doing my best to
help out my people
thank you guys for all of the support
once again seeds here now.com
coupon code gfyh10 also if you feel like
this episode was educational informative
or entertaining and you'd like to make a
financial contribution to the show
you can do so by visiting
www.patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need will be
right there on the screen and i did
include an
updated link in the show notes to make
it easy for all of my stoner friends
don't forget that the show is now
available on youtube you may be
listening on an audio format which i
enjoy
but i invite you to check us out on the
youtube channel simply go to youtube
search for the grow from your heart
podcast click subscribe
also click on that little notification
bell that will let you know every time i
put out a new episode
you'll never miss anything that i put
out
um i think that's all i've got for you
once again send me an email if you've
got any questions it's grow from your
heart
hotmail.com i want to thank everybody
again for listening
i'll be back in a couple of days with
fresh new content i want to give a giant
shout out to my buddy john bendit and
until next time
take a fat dab and give your mom a hug
for me