[Music]
heidi ho neighbors i'm your host rosta
jeff and it's time for episode 555 of
the grow from your heart podcast
this episode of the show is brought to
you by our friends at seedshearnow.com
seeds herenow.com offers seats from all
of the industry's
leading breeders including ms jill
genetics duke diamond
and of course irie genetics everything
at seeds herenow.com is backed by an
award-winning satisfaction guarantee
and for my friends on a budget seeds
herenow.com offers
several packs for under thirty dollars
as well as amazing
monthly sales make sure to use coupon
code gfyh10 while checking out to save a
few bucks
again that is coupon code gfyh10 while
checking out
at seeds here now.com
you know i like to start this podcast
off by talking about what i'm smoking
today i've been taking dabs of
gunslinger
remix live batter from green dot labs
this is a blend of star fighter and star
dog
on the package the flavor is described
as sour fruit
and fuel i think we've talked about this
concentrate on the podcast before
i am really a big fan of the gunslinger
remix live batter
on the back it says it contains 65.83
thc and non-detectable amounts of cbd i
do know that it gives me a perfect
buzz for a podcast so big shout out to
our friends at green dot labs for the
delicious gunslinger remix live
batter all right in this episode i'm
going to read a couple of messages from
patreon
before we get there i'd like to do a few
shout outs to some members of the 710
club
of course the 710 club are the folks who
support us at the
7.10 a month level or higher on patreon
so let's start off with the big grow
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out to the captain and commander of the
710 club let's send a big thank you
shout out to my buddy lemur priest
thank you for all of the support bro
let's follow that up with a big thank
you shout out to my buddy ty blacklock
i've also got a big thank you shout out
for my buddy darian smith
i want to send a big thank you shout out
to my buddy kurt z i've also got a big
thank you shout out to zoso j
i also want to send a big thank you to
brett g and jacob w
i've also got a big thank you shout out
for my buddy keith k
and also a big shout out to tim i always
want to send a big thank you shout out
to my buddy godfather kush
i've also got a big thank you shout out
from my buddy prospect let's not forget
buzz bros
and last but certainly not least let's
send a big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out to my buddy
terp burglar i'm loving the name big
thank you
big shout out to everybody who continues
to support the show on patreon
if you're not already supporting the
show on patreon and you would like to
learn how to do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need to support
the show will be right there on the
screen and of course i did include that
link
in the show notes and in the video
description to make it easy
for all of my friends all right ladies
and gentlemen let's not waste too much
time
let's jump right into the patreon
messages for today's episode
the first patreon message comes from
girls grow two big shout out to girls
grow too
the message goes like this it says that
dabbing video was bomb
as [ __ ] man i'm pretty sure they are
referring to the 7 10 episode
where i took a couple of dabs and shared
my dabbing equipment showed you guys how
to take a proper dab
i did take a big fat chunky dab i got a
lot of comments on that
couple of people said that dab would
kill me that was more concentrate than i
smoke in a month
that was my week supply of dabs got a
lot of great compliments thank you guys
for watching that
it goes on to say thank you for doing
this you are very welcome thank you for
enjoying and learning
and thank you for the patreon
contribution and thank you for the
feedback
it says i'm still new to this so that
video was
really helpful the comment i got the
most was that people
got answers to questions they were
embarrassed to ask so
people were taking dabs at places they
weren't sure how to handle some
equipment or maybe they were watching
their friends take dab somewhere and
they wanted to join
but they were intimidated or afraid by
gear afraid of
gear now they knew how to jump in
because they watched me do it i showed
them how to use the gear
now they're dabbing like a pro they're
right up to speed they're getting blazed
with their friends
this message goes on to say i can't wait
to meet you someday
me too as soon as all of the
restrictions are over and we're allowed
to play with our friends again
i cannot wait to meet you take some dabs
give you a big fat proper dab
out of my rig from my concentrates get
you so high you're uncomfortable it'll
be a really good time we'll get some
food or something after that so you're
not too blessed for too long
it wraps up with take it easy stay safe
stay stoned bro
love from missouri a big shout out to
all of my friends out there in missouri
uh working in the new medical and or
recreational cannabis market i'm not
sure if it's medical or recreational i'm
pretty sure they went medical out there
they do have cannabis in missouri one of
the last places i ever assumed imagined
or thought would have
any access to legal cannabis uh i'm
impressed
keep it up keep kicking ass down there
and if you ever have any more questions
please reach out patreon is the best way
to do it all right ladies and gentlemen
let's jump right into the
patreon message portion of today's
episode the first
message from patreon came from our
friend north north terps what up north
good to hear from you again
the message starts off a lot like this
it says
what's up my diggity dog [ __ ] uh
then he called me a bad [ __ ]
uh dude you listen to too much joey diaz
take a break bro i'm just kidding gotta
love joey but settle down
it goes on to say anyways for the pg
version
i love you dog what's up i just had a
grow hack
question what works for me is i have a
portable air conditioner with an
insulated ventilation going out of my
tent
with a fan and a dehumidifier and the
portable air conditioner working against
each other for humidity
i found that the balance works in there
and there's a lot of waste water that
comes from my dehumidifier
uh the waste water does not read on my
ec so can i recycle this water into my
system
that is my question all right so our
friend's got
a system that's got a dehumidifier and
an air conditioner in the room and
they're finding that the
dehumidifier is creating a lot of
condensation and it's gathering a lot of
water i've seen this happen a lot that's
very common
it's pulling the air from the air or the
water from the air gathering it into a
little container
you've got all this water this north
north terps is going to say this
listener but it's north north trips we
know who they are north
wants to know if they can use that water
if they can recycle it into their
watering system
and it's not measuring anything on the
ec meter you put an ec meter and a ppm
meter in there
it shows zero there's nothing in that
water for now
i would say that that water is safe but
what could happen
is gunk and [ __ ] i don't know exactly
what
but build up could build up in your
dehumidifier
build up could build up gunk build up
mildew calcium who knows i don't know
exactly what
but random [ __ ] could build up inside
the dehumidifier you could get things in
the hoses you can get things in the
filters
i'm sure you've had a water filter i'm
sure i'm sure you've seen what
just basic water can do to filters and
pipes it makes things really grody and
really dirty so that stuff will build up
over time possibly
i don't know what's in the air i don't
know what's in that humidity that you
are getting
into those filters into those parts so
my advice would be you can use it
probably but continue to test it make
sure that it's always testing at zero
maybe don't use that water right away on
all of your plants maybe test it out on
a couple of plants
it is testing it zero now but like i
said maybe stuff will build up maybe
gunk
mold junk dust who knows what's going to
build up in the filters
and what will build up in that thing if
you don't keep it super clean that water
may have something in it in the future
so at this point while the machine is
new yeah you can probably get away with
it but i don't know that i would do that
in the future
uh make sure it's clean that's my best
advice that i can give you i've had
uh varying opinions from different
expert growers on this
a lot of us say go ahead and use it a
lot of us are also very paranoid that
there could be other [ __ ] in there
in the future so that's my uh my final
answer
you can use it but pay attention keep
testing it pay attention to the plants
maybe dilute it
maybe you do like 10 percent this water
and 90 the other water that way you're
kind of spreading it out but not wasting
it
maybe use this water for cleaning or
something like that maybe
um but i think you can use it as long as
it stays clean
and as long as over time your machine
doesn't get dirty and get
junk developing inside of there [ __ ]
crap dust
dirt grime goo whatever can build up in
there boogers it's air boogers dude it's
machine boogers
you don't want that part going to your
plants all right so i think i've
thoroughly disgusted everybody so far
let's keep moving with these patreon
messages
if anybody else out there has a question
that was harder to say than it looked
you'll catch on
if anybody else out there has a question
i would love to hear from you the email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
of course the quickest way to get your
email to the top of the list is to
join the patreon campaign you'll find a
tier there that gets your email your
message right to the top of the list
contribute to that campaign campaign
level then send me a message and i will
read it
on one of the next shows i'm trying to
do two episodes every week we may have
to increase it to keep up with the
incoming messages
we'll see how that goes let me get
myself back on track
this message came from our friend ez057
what up easy good to see you bro
hope you're doing well out there the
message goes when you decide to keep a
mother plant
you ever top pop crack twist or just
grow it naturally
uh there are multiple parts to this
question so i'll stop and handle this
part
a mother plant when i'm growing a mother
plant it is mainly
for preservation i don't have room for a
lot of plants in production so i don't
need to produce a lot of clones
so i keep a very small mother plant and
i try to keep them growing very slow
just keep them alive i don't need them
doing too much i don't need them racing
i don't need them too excited
i do top them because i don't need that
one big top bud touching the light i top
them make a little canopy
and get a nice little bush going on so i
will top it
but then as it grows i'm taking but
branches from the top to keep that
branching going
oftentimes my mother plants become my
flower plants also they become a mother
plant i get a few clones i shape them
the way that i want them i keep them for
a while
then once they're big and they're shaped
the way that i want i take a couple
clones off of that
those new clones then become my future
mother plant and that big plant that's
been getting worked on
goes in the room and gets worked with it
either gets flowered out or pollinated
but i need small mother plants if i'm
just keeping a plant for preservation as
a mother plant i don't require a lot of
clones i don't require a lot of
production from my mom's
so i keep them small i keep them under
minimal light they're not even under a
whole bunch of light just enough to keep
them going keep them alive
keep them on a 19-5 cycle i do not
really
pop crack or twist my mother plants i
just let them grow naturally
take the top out so that they start
bushing out that's my first call that
first clone right off the top
that's my next production i run that
this one veggies for a while gives me a
couple clones then i flower that one
generally
so not too much work on the mother
plants unless they're being groomed and
trained and manipulated to be future
flower plants
so there's another part to the question
it says in your experience
how long does it take a plant like lemon
jeffrey to go from 20 to 30
perfect trichomes to over ripe um you
picked a very specific plant you said
lemon jeffrey
most plants i'm gonna say that's a
window of seven to ten maybe seven to
fourteen days when
so there's like a three to five day
period when they're perfect you're like
ooh tomorrow will be just the right day
and you look and they're perfect
then you got like three to five days of
perfection then about
i don't know seven 10 14 days then you
start going oops i probably should have
cut those down a couple days ago maybe a
week ago
so it's about a week of a week window of
prime
cut down time and then by day seven
you're going oh they're starting to get
a little more amber by day 10 you're
like that's a lot of amber by 14 you're
like oh i should have cut that [ __ ] down
so i'm gonna say it's a five day window
of good cutting a seven day window of
you better get it done and then by day
you've kind of missed your opportunity
then it says could i go into that 48 to
72 hour darkness right when i get to 20
to 30 percent and then harvest
thank you for everything you do and the
information high five
love the new instagram live feeds and
youtube videos awesome man thank you
um they mentioned the instagram live
videos i haven't mentioned that here on
the show in a while
every monday at 7 10 ish don't hold me
to it it's about 7 7
10 7 15 every monday at 7 ish
mountain time i go on instagram live my
instagram account is irie underscore
genetics irie
underscore i hope you can spell genetics
iriegenetics
and i ramble for about an hour on
instagram live i let the chat throw me
questions
anything they ask i do my best to field
the question they're live in the chat
and answer your grow
questions so if you've got a basic grow
question that is a good place
to catch me instagram live i hang out i
take dabs i get lit up i talk to my
friends it's much more informal than the
show
just to relax hang out so i'm glad you
were enjoying the instagram lives
i'm glad you're loving the new youtube
videos they take a little bit more work
a little bit of editing but i'm glad
you're checking those out
now let's address the question can i put
it into 24 to 72 hours darkness
right when i get to 20 to 30 and then
harvest yes that would work
the lemon jeffrey is not a big fan of
that long
dark period i've ran this plant a lot of
times more of the
uh wider leaf shorter squatty plants
prefer that dark period
the taller thinner leaf plants are not
as much of a fan of that type of
treatment but it will work
your plan your strategy will work you'll
see a lot of dead leaves when you take
it out of there they'll be all yellow
they'll fall off
but it will work for you that will not
be a bad strategy
uh get them to 20 to 30 that's about
where you want them anyway
throw them into that 48 to 72 hour and
then chop them down that should be
just about perfect for you uh maybe cut
down one plant on one day and do that
cut down the next one another day and do
that if you've been growing multiple
plants in the same area
just see how much they differ see how
much which one you like that's the way
you dial it in perfectly
for your setup but you're not going to
notice too much difference cutting down
two or three days apart and then that 48
to 72 hour darkness that should harden
them up it
may make them beef up a little bit at
the end but uh lemon jeffrey
is not a big fan of that sort of
treatment i think the uh
the sativa dominant cultivars are the
things that want to be
uh put in the or not put in the dark the
indica dominant sorry i messed that all
up but you know what i mean now i'll say
it correctly the indica dominant
cultivars are the plants that seem to
prefer that extended dark
the sativa plants they just go a little
bit crazy get kind of angry
all right now there is another part to
this question easy followed up a few
days later
it says when you are ramping down ppm
and you go into flush
do you maintain the same distance with
your lights
when i started to ramp down and go into
flush it seems like my plants act like
they are too
close to the light much love and
appreciation for everything you do i
wish i could attach pictures
as always my lemon jeffrey is killing it
bro i am excited to smell and smoke some
of that lemon jeffrey let's hang out one
of these days
and talk shop but let's address this
question here
when we are ramping down ppm's and going
into flush do i maintain the same
distance with my lights yes
because at this point my lights are
probably raised as high as they go
because the plants have grown all the
way into the light i don't waste any
space i get the plants as tall as they
can go
in my spaces in a lot of commercial
environments the lights stay at one
height
they're 12 or 16 or 18 feet high they
stay there they don't move
that's where they go i can't move them
they're on a trapeze with 100 lights in
one thing
they're not movable so the lights stay
there in a personal grow like i said the
plants have grown so tall that there's
nowhere to move the lights
you are saying that it looks like uh the
plants are starting to act as if they
are too close i followed up with a
backup question
i said what gives you the idea that it
looks like the plants are too close and
he said that the leaves start doing
funny things and the pistols start
curling
i think that is just the plant being
done there's no more nutrient left
the plants like hey you were feeding me
and now there's no more nutrient
i'm kind of hungry i'm gonna freak out a
little bit the leaves kind of curl up
it's sucking all the nutrients all the
sugars all the energy from those leaves
i think that it's just the end of the
plant's life i think it's done
and it knows it and it looks a little
bit upset about it but
the good thing is we're not growing to
smoke leave consume leaf if those leaves
look a little shitty at the end
that's okay we want big fat trichome
covered buds that taste delicious
if your leaves are kind of yellow and
crispy and fallen off that's a good sign
that you possibly
probably flushed and there's nothing
left in that plant it's going to burn
nice and smooth
it'll burn clean it'll taste real well
all your friends will be really proud
be really impressed you won't choke you
won't cough it should be
a grade product so um i don't think
you're too close to the light
if you feel like you're too close if the
plants are too close raise it up a
little bit
if that's not an option maybe you can
turn it down i'm not sure your situation
i don't know if you're in a tent
if you're in a room i don't know if
you're limited on height i don't know if
you can go any higher
i don't know if you can turn down the
ballast but the only way to find out is
to experiment and do it but honestly
i think that last little bit is when the
plants want the most white so i wouldn't
stress too much
i think they're going to be okay uh but
experiment like i said the only way
to learn is to experiment all right you
guys
i've got one long message let's see how
long is this one this one may take us a
minute to get through so i'm going to
take a little bit of a drink here
and then we're going to journey into
this message that comes from our friend
blue
but let's take a drink you guys sing the
jeopardy song in your head or something
while i do this
all right i feel much better about my
life and about myself now that i'm
hydrated
let's get into this message from our boy
blue
this one goes hey ross to jeff i've been
listening for some time now
and i've been meaning to give you some
support hey thank you i appreciate the
support
don't ever feel like you have to
contribute to get help from me but it is
a good way to get you to the top of the
list
says i listen to your show at work
regularly and it really helps me get
through some of the long
tedious hot and mundane work days and
thank you i love knowing i'm getting
people through work when i
was working in the commercial grow and i
was getting all sweaty and had joey diaz
in my ear
i felt the same way joe diaz joey rogan
just getting me through life
it feels real good so thank you i'm glad
i can give you that feeling then it goes
on to say
the production quality is excellent and
the advice is even better thank you
i'm sure you noticed i went back to the
big mic and the big headphones today
just trying to put out a super quality
show while i learned the other
microphone
i was more comfortable with this one i
goes on to say on one of your recent
episodes
you said everyone thinks you are a
psychic because you knew to answer the
air conditioning questions
but you've been dropping the exact
episodes i have needed at the perfect
times
i love hearing that i love knowing that
i put out an air conditioner episode
right when everybody's room got hot i
love knowing that i put out
an episode about whatever you were
thinking about right at the right time
you were thinking about it that is
awesome
that means that life is happening as it
is supposed to and i'm able to help
people right at the right time so
that feels good it goes on to say i've
recently purchased a couple of packs of
your seeds
i got a rise and double dragon great
selections bro
i plan to purchase many more build that
collection bro like pokemon you gotta
catch em all
then it goes on it says i decided to pop
the double dragon seeds first and was
very happy to get a 100
germination rate on them ah a minute
says that he's got some
less than satisfactory results with
other breeders uh then it says i was
even more excited to see that four out
of the five turned out to be female
that is awesome dude full germination
and a lot of girls that's always fun it
says the girls are growing beautifully
and are approaching week seven of flower
currently
i will email you with some pictures very
soon as i know
you would enjoy seeing them yes please
send me some emails on my kids
i'd love to see what they look like what
they're wearing what they're doing how
they're doing in school
send me pictures of those seedlings
those [ __ ] weak seven flowers now
can't wait to see them now let's get
back on track it says
so back to you being a psychic yes
psychic jeff here at your service
uh call me now for your free reading
says a couple of days after starting the
double dragon seeds i thought to myself
i wish rasta jeff had a strain review
episode on double dragon
so i went to check and it was like two
weeks earlier you had dropped that
episode
um so i was psychic and ahead of you i
put it out there for you all right
moving forward i decided i was probably
going to self a couple of these girls
and create some
s ones something i've done before with
success
and that was right about the time your
feminizing episode which offered me a
plethora of additional
knowledge on the subject so our friend
got some seeds
then i put an episode out about the
seeds then he wanted to self them i put
out an episode about selfing this is
working out pretty well for you bro
um then it says i am rambling as i'm
sure you understand so i will get to the
topic
at hand hey no worries about rambling if
anybody knows
rambling that is me welcome to the rambo
club hashtag they like it when we ramble
if you guys notice i do keep checking my
phone cause i'm hoping to get some
rambling in with white mike today
just waiting for him to text back and
make no promises now let's get
to the rest of i apologize for holding
this email right in front of my face
also if you guys are watching on the
video i just blocked the whole camera
with this paper
i apologize trying to be professional
here it goes on to say
my question now is how does female
pollen react with different genetics
if i throw some other girls of different
genetic background
in with the plant that i'm selfing what
traits and characteristics
should i expect the offspring to keep
from the plant producing
pollen and the plant-producing seeds if
they are not the same
genetics that's a very good question
says i assume they will
still mostly be female now if you were
making
if you used a reversed plant a reversed
female to make pollen they should
all be female if you did it correctly if
you selected properly if that plant is a
true female if it doesn't have intersex
traits
then you should have all 100 female
offspring so
i know they should all be female but how
does an f1 no it's not an f1 which you
were working with
is an r1 and an s1 when you take that
reversed pollen
and put it on a plant of the same
cultivar that is an
s you are selfing it i think i've
described this in another episode
the selfing the s1 that is when a plant
basically
[ __ ] itself that is a crass way to put
it but you'll never forget it
if you take pollen of golden goat put
pollen of
golden goat on golden goat it just self
itself
it [ __ ] itself it made s1 seeds it's
all golden goat
now let's talk about if we take that
pollen and put it on
other cultivars if we took the golden
goat pollen and put it on a
lemon skunk plant we have now created
lemon jeffrey that is an
r1 a reversal one we took we took i said
tooked i'm not even going to edit that i
want you guys to hear me say tooked
it happened all right we took reversed
pollen
and put that reversed pollen on a female
cultivar
and that made reversal seeds r1 so
s1 when it [ __ ] itself that's self r1
reversal pollination r1 reversed pollen
onto a different cultivar
so i'm sure you're never going to forget
that with those terms in your brain
so let's continue it says ah they'll all
be female but how does
r1 and s1 differ when using male and
female pollen
additionally if a plant is hemp and i
breed it to a plant that produces almost
all thc i assume i would find phenotypes
that express cbd dominance thc dominance
and some that are mixed ratios your
input would be very valuable on this
you don't need to read this on the next
episode uh i
wasn't the next one but i got you up
there pretty quickly bro and it says
thank you for keeping me entertained
thanks for super charging my girl with
excellent advice i love your style
and thank you for breeding fire genetics
bro this is a great question
gives me an opportunity to talk a little
bit about breeding and everybody knows i
love to talk about breeding and i don't
do it enough on the show so
um if you take the pollen from your
reversed female
you want to know what traits to expect
if you put that
on different plants if the plant
producing seeds and the plant-producing
pollen
are not the same plant and then you want
to know about thc
and cbd ratios from different uh ratio
plant parent plants
that's a very good question if you take
that reversed pollen and put it on
other cultivars depending on the
dominance of traits of those plants you
are most likely going to see
basically 50 50 crosses if you take
golden goat and lemon skunk and you
reverse that golden go
we've done this before put that reversed
golden goat pollen
onto the lemon skunk it makes lemon
jeffrey
if you look at those two plants if you
were able to grow those two plants i've
never released the lemon skunk that i've
got
it's kind of a very unique cut if you
look at that plant
and you grow it and you know it and then
you look at the golden goat you grow it
you know it
and then you see lemon jeffrey you can
see exactly which traits came from which
parent i can see it very clearly
so when you take that pollen and you put
it on other plants
most commonly you're going to get 50
plants that look like 50 the mommy and
the daddy
then you're gonna get i should say
closer to 30ish percent because there
are going to be some outliers but
in the main main scope of things we're
going to get 50
that look like 50 50 of the mommy and 50
of the daddy then we're going to get 25
percent that look like the original mom
plant
then we're going to get 25 that look
like the original paul and donor which
we'll call
the dad plan so those are the three main
phenotypes you're going to see now
depending on recessive traits of the
parent plants we use we may see signs of
the grandparents popping up whatever the
grandparents of each of those plants
were
you may see some of those phenotypes pop
up so
you're going to get the main three then
maybe a couple of others
so there's probably going to be three
dominant phenotypes one major phenotype
a couple of secondaries and then two
outliers that kind of come up is
generally what i think you're gonna see
in a feminized cross that you're putting
pollen on other plants it's very similar
to crossing uh non-feminized stuff
very similar you're gonna find very
similar uh punnett squares
charts results so now let's talk about
the second part of this
if a plant is hemp and you breed it to a
plant that produces thc
and by hemp we're just uh indicating
that that plant contains 0.3
thc or less that is a hemp plant so it's
got high in cbd
not very little to none thc in it now
we're going to breed that plant to
king solomon who is very high in thc
what's going to happen there
we're going to find plants that are rich
in cbd
we're going to plan find plants that are
rich in thc which one did i say first
we're going to find the other one i got
stone and forgot you're going to find
thc rich plants you're going to find cbd
rich plants
you're going to find plants with crazy
numbers either direction
now the beautiful thing that will happen
is hopefully we will find outliers
hopefully we find something that
surpasses both parents
maybe we find something with way more
cbd than the starting parents maybe we
find something with thc
that far surpasses the starting parents
that would be our goal here
that number will be in there the
cannabinoids
in my opinion in my experience the
cannabinoids don't
breed as solid as a lot of the other
traits if you want to focus on just
cannabinoid breeding
you kind of have to line breed for the
cannabinoids you can't look for
growth and vigor and flavor and
structure you got to go for the
cannabinoids that is my
experience that has not been my goal is
breeding for cannabinoids but watching
and seeing
that is what i think you got to do so
you read one line that you go straight
up that line breeding for
cannabinoids if it's cbd or thc then you
breed your bee line
and you breed that one for whatever
you're looking for flavor
structure whatever else you're missing
from the other one then
once you've got those both solid how you
want them you breed those together
and that's how you make a true f1 that's
exactly what you want
that's a long way to get to it but in my
experience from what i've read and seen
it's a little more difficult to breed uh
you got a line breed to get the
cannabinoids exactly how you want
but you're gonna see a lot of different
uh combinations you'll see
thc you'll see cbd you'll see them down
the middle but then you're gonna find
outliers on each direction and then
hopefully you find some
skyrockets uh what's that called
transgressive segregation that might be
what it's called when you find some
plants that are
way better than the parents that surpass
the performance of the parents
all right blue i hope i answered your
question um i feel like i went over that
one pretty well it was kind of quick but
i feel like i covered it quite well
i want to thank everybody for all the
patreon messages again if you've got
corrections questions or concerns i
would love to hear from you my email
address is grow from your heart
hotmail.com once again the way to get
your message or question to the top of
the list is to
join the patreon campaign at patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need is
right there on the screen of course
please do visit our sponsors at
seedshearnow.com and use coupon code
gfyh10 while checking out
that'll save you a few bucks if you're
only getting a pack or two that will
cover the cost of shipping
if you're getting a larger order that
will add up quite quickly you may be
able to get
even more seeds while you're there make
sure you check out that under 30 section
because there is a pack from ire
genetics in the under 30 section
go check it out spoil yourself enhance
your garden
all right ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls pimps and hoes friends and foes
smokers and growers clone cutters and
pollen chuckers
all you sexy [ __ ] out there i
want to thank you once again for
listening to episode 555
of the grow from your heart podcast i'll
be back in just a couple of days with
fresh new content
i want to give a giant shout out to my
buddy j.r token and until next time take
a fat dad
and give your mom a hug for me
you