[Music]
all right get it together mike it is
time for episode 556 of the grow from
your heart podcast
this episode of course is brought to you
by our friends at seeds herenow.com
seedshearnow.com offers seeds from all
of the industry's leading breeders
including miss jill genetics
duke diamond and of course irie genetics
everything at seeds herenow.com is
backed by their award-winning
satisfaction guarantee
for my friends on a budget seeds
herenow.com offers several packs for
under 30.
as well as amazing monthly sales make
sure to use coupon code gfyh10 while
checking out to save a few bucks
again that is coupon code gfyh10 while
checking out
at seeds here now.com i'm sure you heard
at the beginning
but let's welcome white mike to the show
welcome to the show bro
thanks man what's up everybody oh you
sound good on the microphone today
just make sure to check that microphone
right up on this sucker tonight
yes we got a couple of comments on uh
mike being too quiet last time i
apologize that is my fault my
responsibility
sounded really good in our headphones
that episode as soon as i hit play that
next day after it posted i was
disappointed too sorry y'all
i wasn't our fault it was my fault
technically i'm the one responsible for
that but it sounds really good in the
headphones now
uh it sounded really good in the
headphones last time when i played it
back it was real quiet so we're just
going to keep you real loud this time
i think it'll be cool for the people
that are listening we apologize if mike
was too quiet last time
we're going to fix it we're going to do
a good show this time uh this is the
part of the show where i ask you what
are you smoking on bro
that's some local flower man local
flower i like that is that incognito for
gray market
free market is that what local flower
means it was just a gift from a buddy
all right we're gonna move forward it
sounds like you're trying to be vague on
purpose
i myself a nice hybrid um
locally grown um colorado it's legal to
grow your own
you're allowed to keep and gift your own
harvest man that's the truth hell yeah
gotta love legal land free freedom uh i
am smoking on gunslinger remix live
batter i've been talking about this one
on a lot of episodes lately
i may have bought several grams because
i bought a gram of it
came home dabbed it drove back to the
dispensary and was like i will take my
limit my remaining daily limit on that
product please
rest yes and then i may have gone back
the next day
and repeated that process because i
really enjoy the gunslinger remix live
batter from green dot labs real quickly
it is a blend of star fighter and star
dog it's supposed to taste like
sour fruit and fuel i agree with that
the back of the package says
65.83 thc and non-detectable amounts of
cbd
uh great product great flavor great buzz
can't talk enough about it
shout out to green dot labs all right
mike at this point of the show i usually
do shout outs to people who support my
patreon campaign
uh you've got a brand new patreon
campaign make sure you follow my buddy
patreon.com forward slash white mike but
before i do shout outs would you like to
do
shout outs to the people who are
supporting you on patreon
yeah man i've got a partial list of
supporters right here
um the i like your idea of doing 710
so the the white mic 710 club as it
stands right now
ez057 thank you man appreciate the
support
og purple thumb and prospect seriously i
appreciate
everything you guys are doing for me
farmer z and learning and burning
did you guys rule thank you so much for
supporting what we do here
yeah big shout out to those guys a lot
of familiar names there i'm looking down
at my shout out list making sure we do
army is supportive yes they are thank
you guys uh
thank you for supporting white mike
again if you want to support white mike
on patreon
it is patreon.com forward slash white
mike he is a huge contributor to the
show to the community to the industry
so show my buddy a little bit of love
and once again thanks to all those folks
now i'm going to do the shout outs
to the folks that i owe some love to my
710 club
uh let's give a big shout out to darius
from cerritos that's the coolest name
ever
shout out to darius from cerritos i
wonder if we ever hung out if we bumped
into each other at the cerritos mall
when i lived in california
what's up bro making me miss the coast
also let's send a big [ __ ] thank you
shout out to nurse geek
also a big thank you shout out to xavier
of course let's send a big thank you to
grim bull the druid what's up graham
hope you're doing well brother
also let's send a big thank you shout
out to bong breath anybody named bong
breath is my friend
also let's send a big thank you to
stabby mc [ __ ] stab dude what
up stabby good to see you brother hope
you're doing well
good to hear from you didn't see you on
embracing organics tonight hope i catch
up with you next week
also let's send a big thank you to baked
pwn that's baked pone
i like their opponent [ __ ] old
school internet slang i asked him what
the pwn was about
that's like when you pone people so big
shout out to baked keep honing them
also i haven't heard from you in a
moment i'm glad you're doing well i got
a recent update big shout out to my
buddy dick
goals what's up bro good to see you're
doing well hope you're doing great again
also let's send a big thank you shout
out to andrew g and last but certainly
not least on my long list of thank you
shout outs i want to send a thank you
shout out to our new friend
maroney big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who supports the show
of course if you're not already
supporting the show on patreon all you
have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all the information you need
will be right there on the screen and of
course i did include a link in the show
notes and the video description to make
it easy i almost got through that one
without having to clear my throat
big shout out to green dot labs um let's
see where are we now
mike i think this is the part of the
show where we should just segue into
reading emails and listener questions
because people know that we will get
rambly on accident at some point in this
show
all right how could it happen i wish i
would have just clipped out you going
segway and just play that all the time
when i need just a smooth transition
segway all right today's uh first email
again if you've got an email or a
question a question a correction or a
concern my email address is grow from
your heart
hotmail.com you know i would love to
hear from you today's first message
goes like this it says if this makes it
on the show refer to me as
senzu so what up senzu good to hear from
you the message says
hey rasta jeff i hope all is well with
you and yours i'm just dropping in to
say
the audio quality is great with the
lapel mic thank you because i got
mixed feedback and mixed emotions it
says i feel like the standalone mic had
more crisp audio quality but regardless
it sounds great
and i would imagine it would be perfect
for indulging during the show yes it
makes it easier
to dab it makes it easier to just move
my arms around i smack this mic a lot
just more comfortable you take up a lot
of desk space yeah and if you don't stay
on it right here like i keep reminding
mike then you can't hear us and we start
sounding like [ __ ] so
um but yeah the lapel mic is a new
experience it's more comfortable
there's nothing in my face i can talk
with my hands i can definitely dab a
little bit more it makes it more
conversational if there's somebody in
the conversation with me but thank you
for the compliments there
it goes on to say um also i really
enjoyed the fade in
mellow outro music and 552. i don't
remember which track i played on the
outro of 552.
that may have been some music i made so
that's really cool compliment if it was
something i did
if it was the song from thanks for
nothing it was that reggae track
big shout out to thanks for the amazing
music thank you there is more music
coming i did say that i was going to
play more musical submissions on the
show
i've just been so happy with that one
track that i play that that is the new
theme song for the show
that is like permanent that is it
it doesn't get any better than that it's
pretty perfect
yeah thank you so thanks again to thanks
for nothing uh it was well worth the uh
the request so it goes on it says i also
have another question for you was there
a first question in here
okay i have a question i didn't miss a
first question i hope because i have
another question for you
just out of pure curiosity what other
breeders and genetic companies do you
feel are creating really quality strains
i know there are a lot of breeders out
there who just crank out fire strains
but i'm curious to know from experience
who else is really breeding from the
heart
and why you respect them thanks for
everything you do
i'll be supporting you on patreon as
soon as i am able
uh senzu thank you for the great message
uh don't stress too hard over patreon i
know i say that i will read patreon
contributors messages first
i do read other random messages on the
show with that i like that pop up in the
list
uh it is covid times life is weird right
now bro
i cannot expect everybody to contribute
to patreon i am grateful that you are
listening
i'm grateful that you were contributing
and i'm grateful that you sent me a
really great question
so let's jump into this part uh this
person wants to know
who i respect as a breeder in this
industry i wrote down a lot of names and
a lot of breeding companies
but mainly the people that i i'm gonna
miss people that's what i'm afraid of
i'm gonna skip people i can't list
everybody i appreciate and respect i am
stoned
i took dabs and also i just didn't
prepare well enough to think of
everybody that i respect and trust in
the industry so
i want to start it off by saying i
respect and love
the work of people who are doing it for
the passion of the plant
of moving the plant forward of moving
the community forward
of moving medicine forward of moving
recreational cannabis forward
those are the people i love and respect
and appreciate the guys that are
thinking about healing
and thinking about making people feel
good and when they're in the grow
they're just beaming and smiling i'm not
impressed with the people who are
growing for their wallet the guys that
are walking around going
i'm sure there's four pounds here and
i'm gonna sell each pound for three
thousand i've got twelve thousand
dollars i'm gonna buy this
those guys haven't earned my love and
respect sometimes we all fall into that
you get excited you get a little bit of
money your heart starts pumping
get out of that get out of that grow
from your heart go back into that grow
room and think about
how many people are going to feel better
when they consume that product
that's what i think it's all about we're
making people we are improving the
quality of people's lives if it's our
own
if it's medical patients if it's
recreational patients if it's
those people's families mike are your
kids lives better because you consume
cannabis
much yeah yeah so it's a change much
better
it's a ripple effect so those are the
breeders that i've got the most love and
respect for the guys that are
uh growing with love and thinking about
healing not the guys growing from their
ego
or thinking about dollars and their
wallets if you're growing uh
from your dick to get chicks if you're
grown from your wallet to get cars
like that's the wrong approach think
about cannabis if you're breeding
especially think about
improving cannabis that's our goal it's
like art it's like we're chefs we're
artists we're
all kinds of different things rolled
into one as breeders so to give kind of
a generic answer
and a kind of a disclaimer that i'm
gonna miss a lot of people in this
list but that is what i look for a
breeder that uh contributes to the
community a breeder that's been around
for a while a breeder that has put out
strains that are worth something not
people that come and
chuck pollen and say here's the most
popular candy flavored strain and the
most popular whatever flavored strain we
put them together we put them out we
didn't test them
we're gonna sell a [ __ ] ton of seeds and
guess what next year you'll never know
who we are
that's a whole different group of people
so let's talk about people that i've
really
got some respect for in the middle of my
list i want to go ladies first i just
realized i wrote her down in the middle
of the list but she's going to deserve a
top spot right now let's give a shout
out to miss jill
miss jill is uh not only it doesn't it
shouldn't even count that she's a badass
woman grower but there aren't enough
badass women growers the women get
overlooked it's kind of a boys club
so shout out to miss jill i've got a lot
of respect as for miss jill
as a grower and a breeder when subby was
in prison
shout out to subcool subcool taught me a
lot when subby was in prison
jill was getting cultivation books about
cannabis
and substituting all of the words that
weren't allowed in prison with the word
blueberries or whatever else so that she
could get those books
to subby while he was incarcerated to
keep his cannabis education growing
if that's not contributing to cannabis i
don't know what is that's being
a badass partner a badass cannabis
person just that's being a bad
[ __ ] in general so
jill deserves a little shout out and
recognition for that
then on top of that she is a badass
breeder
a lot of us smoke jelly bean we see a
lot of crosses with jelly bean actually
this jar right here orangutan funk is
jelly bean number 13
cross 2 grease monkey and the jelly bean
gives it
such a delicious flavor a lot of people
are chasing that jelly bean terp
i know a guy who's got a breeding
company based off of jelly beans so jill
created jelly bean
jill was a big part of tga team green
avengers it wasn't just sub cool
so jill gets a lot of credit for that
jill is also now making more crosses
with
the jelly bean and other crosses so she
deserves a big shout out she is a
breeder
that i appreciate and trust and respect
as a person and as a grower and a
breeder
she's got reputable lines she's
contributed to the industry
and she's not full of [ __ ] she's still
here longetivity
i think shows a lot in this industry
like i said a moment ago people come
they do [ __ ] at a booth for one year you
see them bang it out next year they're
not there
and they they made enough money in that
one year to kind of cover that year but
you need longevity to have a business
one year isn't [ __ ] in a business that's
just coming and going that's a one hit
wonder
so miss jill really stands out on my
list the next folks mike you're gonna
love these guys
i really love appreciate and respect
dawn and aaron from dna genetics
i've grown a lot of their strains
they've got a lot of that cushy la stuff
that everybody was after when i first
started buying seeds from the attitude
seed bank
dna genetics had a lot of the hot fire
uh they're good dudes they're chilled
out dudes they run a solid business
they've got good customer service
and they've been doing it before it was
a big money thing they went to amsterdam
they left la and went to amsterdam to go
do this they abandoned their lives and
[ __ ]
to go start a new life for cannabis and
they've always had quality products
they're always moving the industry
forward so big shout out to those guys
uh there was another name that popped in
my head that i didn't write down soma
ah soma's an old hippie dude that taught
me a lot and i got to give a shout out
to subcool as well
i want to try to get back on my list so
we got uh miss jill dna genetics
soma soma taught me a lot he's kind of a
hippie sub cool taught me a lot
of what to do and what not to do as a
grower and a breeder and as a person
so subcool gets a little spot on my list
uh then we're gonna
talk about dj short uh mike you're not
even a breeder
and you know about dj sure dj shorts
blueberry the first sorry the first
three or four companies you've listed
that's the foundation of colorado's like
legal genetic pool
that's what was everywhere when that got
locked into place and
so so much of what we enjoy on the
shelves now
this is the grandparents stock that's
the truth it came from
yup from subby had a lot of the stuff
out miss jill had stuff out
dna genetics was a lot of the cushy
stuff the la kush the la
confidential what's the one that i
really liked a whole bunch the holy
grail kush that was a part of
dna genetics that might have been
reserva pravada that's a branch of dna
genetics
so yeah there's a lot of great breeders
in there soma the lavender the so mango
a lot of that stuff came from soma so
then let me get back on
track on my list here dj short that
blueberry flow
you see blueberry and flow everywhere
that old school dj short blueberry is
super sought after
uh dj short is an amazing educator
an amazing breeder a great speaker uh
he's a cool person
he's gotta you gotta open him up to get
him to talk a little bit he's not super
he's not me
for sure but once you get him talking
he's a really friendly really cool dude
um
then we gotta work our way down to jd
not just dj but jd short with second
generation genetics that dude is [ __ ]
killing it nothing but respect for that
whole family
uh they breed with purpose with
direction
uh they don't pass on [ __ ] that is not
stellar they understand the art of
breeding all the people i've mentioned
are breeding with direction and they
understand it that's what really matters
they're doing something for the
community then we're going to move into
a guy
who probably should have been mentioned
top more high on the list but i can only
do so many at a time
uh [ __ ] mr soul from brothers grimm i
really appreciate rick campanella
as a person as a breeder as a grower as
an educator rick shout out dude i
[ __ ] love you bro
uh really cool guy super stylish guy
also
um he does not fit in any box and that
is
really cool uh because everybody's
trying to be in a box right now of
course on this white guy
rasta hippie thing but mr soul has no
no box that he fits in and i [ __ ]
love that about a person difficulties
what happened mike i think you're still
here with me a little glitching
all right you keep glitching if you
glitch out too far i'll fix it
uh but i'm gonna keep rambling because i
don't think anything went wrong keep
rolling buddy
cool bro uh mr soul uh nothing but love
and respect for mr soul the [ __ ]
cindy 99
is an amazing cross anything that comes
from mr soul is quality he's a good
breeder
i see you point at the camera is
everything going cool no we're good to
go
all right buddy i'll cut out if anything
goes too crazy uh so
mr soul is on my list of breeders that i
appreciate he teaches a lot he's not
stingy with information
and he's got a very eloquent and classy
way of
speaking and teaching i know he's he's
got like nuclear physics degrees i don't
remember exactly your degree sir i
should remember that i should have
respect for that but i know he's like
an engineer he's very highly educated
from a very uh well-known school so
he's a super smart guy he could talk to
me like i'm stupid he really could
but he doesn't he talks to me like we're
equals like we're brothers he came to an
event and shook my hand and said hello
to me
that kind of stuff means a lot to me so
thank you and also i posted a podcast
about femme seeds
and it got the mr soul seal of approval
he shared the episode so that really
ah that made me giddy that day thank you
rick i appreciate that
um who else do we need to give love to
odie [ __ ] diesel from homegrown
natural wonders
that dude is a really cool guy uh i
imagine if he lived in my neighborhood
he'd have to kick me off of his couch
because he's older than me he's been to
more dead shows than a lot of people i
know
he's got a cool vibe he grows a lot he
smokes a lot he's been breeding for a
while
he'd have to make me leave i'd just be
there hanging out all the time he would
be my bro if we live closer to each
other so shout out to odie diesel
really cool guy his whole crew a bunch
of young hippie kids out there
on the coast loving it good kids mush
mouth the whole gang
uh i miss those guys i wish we could
have events to go hang out again
and then i do have one more guy at the
top of my list that i don't talk about a
lot and then i'm gonna write down
another name
because i definitely have to cover him
another guy that i don't talk about a
lot
um he's been around for a long time he's
a badass grower badass breeder he's got
clout he's got a reputation
i didn't watch enough of his videos he
wasn't
social media and quarantine really made
us come out more we're talking more
we're doing more live feeds we're
exposing our identities and ourselves
and personalities
i have grown a lot of respect for uh
jj from top dog he's a new yorker and if
he feels like he needs to tell you to go
[ __ ] yourself he'll tell you to go [ __ ]
yourself but if he feels like he needs
to tell you that he's proud of you he'll
tell you that he's proud of you
and i love a person who doesn't hold
back and sugar coat [ __ ]
just so that they can have more friends
or likes or followers if you say
something
about a certain guy and he's like nah
that guy [ __ ] me over in 82 [ __ ] that
piece of [ __ ]
he'll say it that's the new yorker in
him and i love it
he also talks like a new yorker he's got
that [ __ ] brash new york accent
and i love it like i love it just
something about when people speak
differently i'm drawn to them so
he breeds well he speaks his mind he
deserves the respect he's been around
for a long time
all these guys i'm talking about you've
seen their names and their [ __ ] on
advertising and on signs because they've
been around for a long time so those
folks all get
some huge respect uh there was one more
guy i wanted to mention his name left my
brain while i was talking
uh but i did write down kevin jodrey
dude kevin jodry uh is a breeder a
grower a cultivator
a [ __ ] a hustler a career hustler
uh a badass [ __ ] in general that
is one of the people that i really think
is moving the industry the community and
the plant forward so
uh he does so much he talks he teaches
he breeds
he is i think he is what i was aspiring
to be before i even knew he existed so
uh kevin jodrey is another person that
i've got a lot of respect for and look
up to as a grower and breeder
so i feel like there was one more name
in there that i wanted to shout out but
it left my
brain it may have been uh big mike from
exotic he's killing it
um i'm sure there are more out there
that are going to pop into my brain as
the episode goes by and i'm going to
shoot in a couple that you're going to
feel bad as soon as we hit end you'll be
like oh man
oh [ __ ] this guy and this guy and this
gal probably too [ __ ] jinx proof
yeah i could do this all night so you
guys if you're breeding out there
and i see you with the events i got
nothing but love and respect for you if
i forgot you on this list i'm [ __ ]
sorry i'm high as [ __ ]
uh and i'm just not trying to make this
a 45 minute segment so um
i appreciate the people that are
breeding with purpose the people that
are moving the plants forward the people
that are killing it you guys know who
you are
uh and if you feel like you should have
been on this list and i forgot i'm sorry
bro i love you
get nothing but love for you all the
breeders out there matt riot
let's include matt ryan and then we're
going to move forward matt riot
has a very unique personality matt riot
has no fear to tell somebody to go [ __ ]
themselves
matt wright is very opinionated but also
very educated and i like the way he does
his thing he's a good breeder uh he
breeds quality he only releases quality
he understands the plant he understands
the community and he understands the
history and importance of cannabis
so he is on my list of breeders that i
trust love and respect you're on there
matt um even though you're
[ __ ] opinionated and you got your
personality i respect that like i said
earlier people with a personality that
tell you to go [ __ ] yourself
that means a lot to me that's integrity
so even though he may have told a lot of
people to [ __ ] themselves and he ruffles
a lot of feathers
doesn't bother me one bit all right
we're gonna move on from the
breeders that i love and respect and
appreciate i want to thank our friend
senzu for the great message that got me
going on a long rant
uh thank you i appreciate that uh big
shout out to all the breeders out there
growing from their heart doing it
because they mean it all right mike
you're doing well your technical glitch
is catching up
doing good it's been smooth we uh just a
little lag issue we're good
all right all right it's probably
because it's our neighborhood where we
are about this time we start getting a
little glitchy
uh let's jump into another message that
came from our friend
c dub in michigan this is a great
message mike i thought you may have some
good
insight on this one this one says ross
to jeff
disabled veterans are close to my heart
and that of my family and i try to keep
i try to help them establish medical
grows whenever i can
for many reasons these men and women the
cost of equipment is simply too much
i would like to organize a cooperative
amongst growers that would directly
that would direct older but usable
equipment from growers who were trading
up
to this group of veterans many of whom
will suffer
uh who will suffer and continuing
medical
need how would you organize such an
effort and how would you reach out to
those
that have on behalf of those who
don't from cdub and michigan so this is
a great idea
we got a very compassionate person here
our friend cdub wants to know
how they can create a program to get
grow equipment
from growers hands who are done with
that equipment they're upgrading maybe
they've given up maybe they've got some
new [ __ ]
they want to move that old equipment
instead of throwing it away putting it
in the dumpster they want to get it to
veterans who are
then able to grow their own medicine
because a lot of these veterans are on a
fixed income
they're getting social security or
disability checks possibly
and that doesn't go very far these days
so they need a little bit of cannabis
and growing it themselves would be the
perfect way to do it we just need to get
them equipment
so what are some great ways we could
think of to kind of organize
a cooperative and get some used but
still usable equipment
into the hands of these people who
helped us out mike you have any ideas
for me because i wrote down a few things
it's
this is a tricky one because of the the
grow
community tends to be rightly so
quite paranoid um and so
getting a whole bunch of people to
gather together and say hey we all grow
cannabis
um is tricky and it kind of for any
reason
um and then to to double down on the
the difficulty you're adding and asking
for donations
donations of expensive equipment
so it's going to be all about building
personal relationships with
existing growers and
prospective growers and figuring out who
needs what and who has
what extra um and and
helping putting people either um helping
make the switch
or putting people in contact with each
other
it's you're gonna have to build your
friends list man yeah i hadn't
considered the
legality part i don't know if you're in
prohibition land or if you're in a green
state
but that's going to play a big factor
into how this program works out
yep i've tried to wrangle growers for
stuff
before and when i'm like hey i need a
whole bunch of people to come and
and stand up and say hey we grow and
immediately the room gets empty
right it's it's
my idea was maybe these people out you
could post something to craigslist where
people are buying and selling grow
equipment
and just post your idea just say hey i'm
i've got veteran
a veteran friend here who can use some
equipment if you've got any
old equipment that you're willing to
donate or if you're going to throw it
away or whatever maybe we could give it
to this
veteran so you can craigslist may be a
good spot to start
and then maybe maybe facebook maybe you
could start a facebook group for
veterans in need of grow equipment or
veterans cannabis alliance or something
that's probably already taken that came
out too naturally
but some sort of veterans and cannabis
and something to
veterans grow initiative something like
that the gi grow
there you go the gi growth something
like that to get just to help get them
some equipment so maybe post something
to craigslist maybe social
media like facebook is always a place to
start start a group on there
um then go invite all of your veteran
friends then by
invite all of your grower friends if you
know any of the two if you've got an
overlap that's a good way to get it
started
then maybe um some of the dispensaries
and grow stores
have message boards where you can
actually make a note on paper and put it
on a bulletin board with these old
things they call
push pins yeah some places still have
that i know a lot of the music stores
put that in the back so you can look for
a band
maybe some of the grocery stores yeah
yeah so maybe you can go to the
dispensary maybe you can go to the groce
store
and maybe put up a little flyer or
something like that saying hey i know
uh don't throw away that old grow gear
you buy a new gear don't throw that old
stuff away give it to a veteran in need
and help a veteran grow some weed or
something like that
then just put your number on there or
something and then you can be the middle
man you just go collect all that gear
and then you just take it to the vets as
they need it
or maybe maybe you can find some veteran
groups or maybe
the va hospital or something will help
you out maybe if it's a legal
medical cannabis market a good place
where i like to leave
podcast advertising and business cards
is the medical marijuana doctor
every time i go there i make sure to
leave a couple of business cards there
so they know you can hit me up for seeds
and i leave podcast ads there
because those are new consumers they're
getting their cards i know they're gonna
smoke possibly grow
so that's a great place to go so i don't
have
a good strategy or plan for you but i
think social media
and craigslist are a great way to start
this uh then like mike said just build
your friends list you're gonna have to
get out there and let people know what
you're doing
maybe you can do a thing with the grow
store maybe you've got a friend
at a local growth store who you can get
them
to give a discount maybe five or ten
percent or maybe you get a free piece of
merchandise a little you know just a
tiny freebie that people can get
if they contribute their old gear when
they buy new gear
like bring your old light get 10 off on
your new light or something like that
maybe you can get a store to run a
special like that and help you out
i don't know if you've got friends or
access like that but that's when friends
come into play
that's when stuff like this helps maybe
maybe you'll find that one of the grow
stores in town is ran by an old veteran
and he'll be like oh that's an amazing
idea
maybe he's got the same kind of passion
that you do mike i hear your stuff
glitching out so i'm going to slow down
and let the recording catch up
is your gear good buddy yeah i think we
sound good i just don't want to miss
anything in the recording
it's still good on my end sweet all
right so
carl i think we have answered your
question to the best of our ability
you're going to have to do some ground
work
maybe make some phone calls social media
get out there and let people know what
your mission
is and then once it starts happening it
will snowball
once people know what you're doing you
start building a following it will start
flowing that's all you got to do is get
it rolling
uh so that's my advice get it started
bro maybe go make a facebook group
create a craigslist
post and then find people on both ends
needers and givers and then make it
happen
it'll be fun it'll feel really good when
you get it going and thank you for this
bro thank you for taking initiative
uh and at least having the idea and some
passion to get this going for us i'm
sure all of those
veterans do appreciate your help all
right let's move into the next one this
one could get kind of long
but that's okay i got all night this
message
nice mike's in for the long haul this
one says
hey ross to jeff they legalized
recreational cannabis here in maine in
2016.
since then i've been very
enthusiastically trying to learn
everything i can about growing bro there
is a lot to learn keep sucking it in
it goes on to say i've enjoyed the plant
for a long time but i was afraid to try
growing when it was illegal smart move
that is
that's a risky move sometimes it says i
have a job where i can listen to
headphones at work
so when they legalized i began listening
to podcasts about growing that is the
wife when he just put in earbuds and
just go all day
yeah i think i first discovered your
podcast sometime around 2017 or 18
and began listening to blocks of early
episodes on youtube
to learn to to learn and pass the time
while at work
i went as far back as the igrow culture
episodes
nice yeah so just an update
yeah when the podcast first started i
called it i grow culture a play on the
word agriculture and i grow because
everything at the time had the i
iphone irig i everything uh so i wanted
to play with that
then i did get a message from a company
who makes
um educational programs for schools
and they were called the igrow culture
institute or something and they're like
you can't do that anymore or we will sue
you
and i was like oh cool i wanted to
change the name anyway i didn't like
that anymore
so at episode 50 we changed the name to
grow from your heart that's where the
agro culture part comes in
now that you're caught up on history it
says i heard your episode about how you
named strains today if you've been
listening to the show a recent episode
was how about about how i name strange
episode thank you bro it goes on saying
i found myself agreeing with you that
names of strains are important
i'm glad you give some thought to the
names you choose
if i had one piece of advice to give
people naming strains of cannabis it
would be
try to pick something classy and
creative
yes um something that stands out
something that doesn't scare people away
we often forget
that the main demographic of cannabis
is 18 to 40 year old bros that's mostly
who's smoking
and mostly 25 to 40 year old bros
and not that's just the demographic if
you look up cannabis study
that's who's mostly into it there's the
fringe the older demographic is getting
larger
the lady demographic is getting larger
but it's mostly bros
we forget that we need to remember that
there are ladies
there are older folks in here there are
not bros
that are consuming cannabis now this is
becoming a popular commercial commodity
we need to not scare the ladies away i
had a close friend who was a lady grower
tell me that she didn't like my stream
bounty killer because of the name bounty
killer
i named it after a reggae artist who is
called bounty killer
and also it makes big fat harvests so i
thought it was appropriate
she said i wish it had a better more
gentle name so
if we adjust we may be able to get more
ladies more older folk into our
demographic
a lot of if you're a seed breeder you're
trying to sell you got to broaden your
audience so let me get back on track
here
it says try to pick something classy and
creative it says don't pick names like
green crack or donkey dick or crystal
meth
i [ __ ] completely agree green crack
is kind of uh which makes it where if
the guy who named green crack had named
it like strawberry starburst or some
[ __ ]
we would be legal in like three more
states at least right and it may have
been on more shelves and more
dispensaries
it did get renamed the name status back
it's yeah perception's a thing and it's
it's real and it has legit effects yeah
and if uh
and now if you ever hear the word uh the
mellow that was
green crack they renamed it to the melo
after carmelo anthony because green
crack was his favorite strain is what i
think i read that's a weird nugget of
cannabis
info there don't pick names like green
crack or donkey dick or crystal meth i
agree
uh donkey dick is kind of maybe it made
big giant buds but still
and green crack was called green crack
because it made little tiny rocks that
were super hard
and everybody wanted it so it's green
crack the donkey dick makes big buds
crystal meth let's not do that but
that's another drug let's not do that
yeah you don't even have to ever type
those words together
um somebody recently asked me if i was
going to make any
kovid tribute strains and i was like nah
[ __ ] that i was like i make strains
after things i like
like ninja turtles and gi joes and great
first three rhymes after pandemics
yeah strands yeah so there will not be
any covet or any pandemic strain names
coming out of my camp
no thank you uh why honor that so it
keeps going it says why would anyone
want to compare this wonderful plant
with such a horrible drug like crack or
meth
just the name green crack actually made
me angry when i first heard of it
and it still kind of pisses me off i
don't know that it pisses me off but it
does like
rub me wrong i don't want to hear people
say that like just don't
don't say those words it goes on to say
i think names like this work against
cannabis being accepted and legalized in
more places
don't help those idiots to keep it
illegal mike you and i you and this guy
were on the exact same page
uh then it says don't give them fire
they got plenty exactly
yeah yeah i'm a white guy with
dreadlocks i have to speak clearly
because if i went up and said bro
and they already expected that from me
so it says here's the thing eventually i
started hearing
good things about green crack from some
sources so it got me thinking that maybe
there were good strains out there which
i were avoiding
simply because i thought the name was
stupid or silly thinking about it more i
know there must be yeah i'm sure that
some strain names have scared me away
um maybe there were some great seeds
that i didn't buy just because the name
was stupid or something like that
i think that that is definitely a thing
so i'm glad that you agree with me that
it's very important
not only for marketing and for as from a
marketing standpoint
point but from a cultural and an
observation standpoint the people
looking in on us like well they like to
smoke green crack
it just doesn't [ __ ] sound good
doesn't sound good
uh one of the the anti-pot groups here
in colorado
has been desperate to get all sorts all
concentrates
they want the to double crack weed
and it's it's been funny to watch them
try to get this to catch on for the last
four
years um
it's just some [ __ ] just won't catch on
and another [ __ ] catches on right away
and it's just
you can't force it kevin jodrey kevin
jojo's closest with creeps
yeah no it's not going to set us forward
at all
the the optics of dabbing are very very
tricky to explain to
to non-consumers yeah the first time you
bust out that dab torch and you start
heating up that nail people like
um so were you smoking weed today or
what are you doing over there i just
wanted to get stoned i didn't want to do
drugs yep yep i promise it's just weed
you pulled out a blowtorch yeah uh so
they wrap up this message with uh thank
you for sharing so much of your cannabis
growing knowledge with the world signed
jim owen and then jim politely reminds
me that i can say his name
because that's just a pen name and then
they sent me some pictures too and that
arise bud
looked [ __ ] amazing dude great job
great work uh jim thank you for the
great message
i hope i addressed your question and
concern i feel like i did because i
completely agree with you
you guys if you're breeding out there
you're making strains uh
pick a cooler name man it doesn't need
to be
drug related all the names in the world
out there don't go with something
that's just gonna give it a black guy
right off the start yeah but if you love
it
do it do your thing player do your thing
all right mike i feel like i've covered
all of my notes for this episode of the
show
uh i'd like to give you the opportunity
to ramble if you've got anything that
you'd like to talk about today
if not you don't have to force anything
and please uh
keep it unpolitical no not uh not doing
anything pandemic or politic related
just uh
um i feel like this has been my little
mike's moment three or four times in a
row but
i went herb shopping again at a bunch of
local shops and
man trim your [ __ ] weed oh yeah um
also if marijuana is legal where you're
at
and you're wondering about how to
attract
more consumers to your business the
trick is to put good products at
reasonable prices on the shelves
like that's i don't want to give away
the secret to business
for free but there [ __ ] is people put
good herb on the shelf at a reasonable
price
if you build it they will come that's
the truth quit focusing on random crazy
products and weird advertising tactics
and [ __ ] fancy artwork on the sides
of your building and
put some cool product on the shelf and
we will come and buy it
put good herb in the put good herb on
the shelf that's that's really all you
got to do
excellent mike i appreciate that inside
trim that [ __ ] that was much different
than what your twitter feed has been
like lately so i'm glad you went that
route um
yeah my my twitter feed's been
interesting and if you're looking for a
more militant a militant version of
white mike check out
nemopunk15 on twitter and how do we find
you on facebook
pueblo for sensible cannabis laws but uh
it's been pretty quiet lately because i
haven't felt much like
facebook written lately i've had to just
kind of stay off of facebook
lately i'm almost done with it
i'm i'm flirting with being done i i've
kind of stopped posting photos
and that's what i used it for was
keeping family updated on kid stuff
and family stuff but i stopped because i
don't want to
come across photos of my kids used in
promotional advertising for products
somewhere
else because that's how facebook works
like
if you have a facebook account you're
the [ __ ] product
that's how social media works so i've
been posting less and less especially
imagery and
yeah it's evil just go post random fish
lyrics just to let people know what i
was listening to in the car that's
usually what that nonsense that four
nonsensical words in a row usually fish
lyrics
every time i post song lyrics i get
three private messages they're like are
you okay bro
we listen to different music yeah i'm
avoiding social media because in the
in the growing groups i see the craziest
stuff and
so the growing groups are just so toxic
i don't have time to correct all of that
[ __ ] so i just
click back out and i'm done with it for
a minute come to a podcast and talk
about real stuff instead of trying to
feel all that nonsense there
that's what inspired the uh the outdoor
episode last time
yeah i liked that rant it uh
um the key to a good grow is planning
in in prep work and then just
consistency
it's if you're gonna grow a plant it's
like growing anything else that's alive
it requires daily
active work and if you forget about it
or you don't put a lot of effort in up
front so your
your gear doesn't run right or doesn't
work well together or doesn't fit in
your space or
parts of it don't work you're gonna end
up with
[ __ ] and it's gonna cost you money if
you put a little prep work into it
and do your research and then put in
your due diligence every day you're
going to grow
fire yes this is how it works
if you did the proper research and put
genetics that were worth the [ __ ]
outside or in your growth
yes yeah yeah the plan i uh
i can't believe they're still
like there's there's so much information
now when
you and me first got into cannabis there
were
one or two grow books and they were like
mythical yeah uh the the only reference
i can
think of from pop culture is in the
first american pie there's the book of
how to [ __ ] that they have to go get
from under the library shelf
it was like trying to find the anarchist
cookbook yeah
yeah um but uh
you had to take sketchy advice and then
the first
internet forums like roll it up and
whatnot you never knew
if you were talking to someone who was
trying to help you out
if you were talking to a competitor who
was trying to get you to [ __ ] up
yourself so that you wouldn't um eat up
any market share
or if you were talking to a cop who's
trying to arrest you you have no idea
yeah and so it was so much harder to
find good advice
but now it's so easy if you just do your
homework a little bit
you can get a good idea of which pieces
of equipment you need how to set them up
um what to feed your plants on what kind
of schedule
and you're going to be moderately
successful if you just put in the work
please put in the work yes so much bad
herb
just get a book read a book like it's
weird how many people like get plants
and then
like day fourth like what should i have
done on day one i'm like oh you're
already [ __ ] up dude you're already
behind everything
you gotta go to driver's ed before you
get in the car and stomp on the pedals
and then three guys in the chat give
them like you should top that you need
to top that plant right now and like
topping it's not going to do anything
for the calmag deficiency like what the
[ __ ] are you talking about
the number of people that are like add
piss yeah
it's not [ __ ] getting rid of
athlete's foot what the [ __ ] are you
doing the solution to everything in
facebook is either
more calmag or spray it with neem or now
it's doctor zion
dr zim is the new one but yeah anyway
yeah that cracks my [ __ ] up i i see post
that started off with i already had a
cow mag so [ __ ] go to step two
already
uh mike how can people find you on
patreon
uh patreon is patreon forward slash
white mike
there you go check them out patreon.com
forward slash white mic help them out
yeah hit them up uh shout out to all
those folks uh who have been helping
them out on patreon
familiar names familiar faces thank you
guys i do appreciate you helping out my
buddy
uh don't forget to check out our sponsor
seeds herenow.com use that coupon code
gfyh10 while you're checking out
uh mike thanks for hanging out dude this
was a good time i'm glad we put this
together we got to hang out for quite a
while
yeah it's uh it's been a minute but
we're getting better at this
um my little podcast
station here in the bunker is official
now all the components
are purchased working nothing's borrowed
nice next thing we're going to get you
is a stylish background
more regular shows yeah something behind
me if you guys have any [ __ ] ideas
feel free to shoot me messages
dms or post youtube we need
something light colored and that you can
put a light on
yep all right something gotta get out of
the dark
come out of the shadows now you're
supposed to say but i was born in the
shadows
all right ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls pimps and hoes friends and foes
smokers and growers clone cutters and
pollen chuckers
all you bad [ __ ] out there i
want to thank each and every one of you
for joining mike and i for episode 556
of the girl from your heart podcast
extra thanks to mike for hanging out
late night finally got the kids to bed
and got to hang out i appreciate you
being here bro
if anybody else out there has any
questions corrections or concerns you
can send me an email my email address is
grow fromyourheart
hotmail.com i'd love to hear from you um
where else was i going to go with that
my patreon that's what i need to remind
you about my patreon is patreon.com
forward slash girl from your heart
if you feel like the show is educational
informative or entertaining and you like
to throw a buck my way
please do so patreon.com forward slash
grow from your heart
um what else do we got here i feel like
there was more that needed to be said
youtube there we go check us out on the
youtube channel go to youtube
uh search for the girl from your heart
podcast click subscribe
uh click on that little bell type
looking notification there that'll let
you know every time i put out a new
episode you won't miss a show
uh you'll stay up to date with all of
mike and i's ramblings
also check out the instagram live shows
every monday i go on instagram live at 7
10 my instagram is irie underscore
genetics
it's about 7 10 mountain time every
monday i hang out for about an hour
ramble about growing cannabis you can
ask questions in the chat
i'll do my best to catch up with all
your conversation
uh ladies and gentlemen that is all i've
got for you for today i'll be back in a
couple of days with fresh new content
let's send a big giant shout out to my
buddy mr soul and until next time take a
fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
you