hey everybody this is doug benson
and you're listening to the grow from
your heart podcast
hosted by my buddy rosta jeff
[Music]
oh yeah
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rosta jeff and it is time
for episode 557 of the grow from your
heart podcast
today's episode is brought to you by our
friends at seedshearnow.com
seeds here now.com offers seats from all
of the industry's
leading breeders including miss jill
genetics duke diamond and of course irie
genetics
everything at seeds herenow.com is
backed by their award-winning
satisfaction guarantee
and for my friends on a tight budget
seedshearnow.com offers
several packs for under 30 as well as
amazing
monthly sales make sure to use coupon
code gfyh10 while checking out to save a
few bucks
again that is coupon code gfyh10 while
checking out
at seeds here now dot com
if i like to start this podcast off by
talking about what i'm smoking
today i've been taking dabs of honey
banana
full spectrum extract from green dot
labs this is a blend of
banana og and honey boo-boo on the
package the flavor is described as
frosted banana pastry i think i agree
with that
but when i first cracked the jar open
the first aroma to hit my nose
made me think of a banana liqueur i
don't know that i've ever had a banana
liqueur but that's what it smelled like
to me
almost maybe a bananas foster it smells
like it may have some ice cream or
something sweet to it
but then when i dab it that liqueur
flavor some of the sweetness goes away
and that banana pastry is dominant in
the flavor
it is also really heavy this stuff made
me sit down and chill the [ __ ] out for a
couple of minutes
on the back of the package it says it
contains 73.07
thc and non-detectable amounts of cbd
i really enjoy the honey banana full
spectrum extract
from green dot labs all right in this
episode
i'm going to focus on patreon questions
i've got a lot of wonderful questions
from patreon
before we get there let's do some shout
outs to the members of the 710 club of
course the 710 club
are the folks who support the show at
the 7 and 10 a month level or higher on
patreon
so with no further ado let's give a big
shout out to my friend brett
g let's send a big thank you shout out
to my buddy ryan p
i've always got a big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out to my
new friend helly
let's send a big thank you shout out to
my buddy easy0057
i've always got a big thank you to my
buddy nick let's send a big thank you
shout out to riley h
we've always got a big thank you for
greg s we've always got a big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to karen crawford
i've always got a big fist bump and a
high five from my buddy kurt z
let's send a big thank you shout out to
country kush i've always got a big thank
you to sean 23
and last but certainly not least let's
send a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to our friend
matt hemingway big thank you and big
shout out to
everybody who supports the show on
patreon if you're not supporting the
show already and you would like to learn
how to do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need to support
the show will be right there on the
screen
there are several tiers or levels
available to support the show
don't be shy jump in help us out at the
level that is comfortable for you
of course the show is free i want to
teach everybody to grow for free but i
know there are people out there who do
want to support the show
so patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart and of course i did include a
link
in the show notes for all of my stoner
friends all right ladies and gentlemen
boys and girls this is the part of the
show where we jump into the patreon
messages
i've got a lot of wonderful messages
from patreon the first message today
comes from our friend tonto what up
tonto good to hear from you again
we have become good friends lately this
message says hey
feel free to call me tonto what's up bro
good to see you it says i hope this
message finds you
and you're in good health i'm feeling
pretty good today
nice and stoned thank you it's too hot
if you can make it cooler somehow that
would be cool
other than that i got nothing to
complain about it says i was hoping to
get your input on how i should go about
cleaning my flower area after
pollinating i have a 4x4 organic soil
living bed
with eight plants flowering there my veg
mom cloning tent is a two by four
i know it's a lot going on but i work
with the space my wife has i know it's
not a lot going on
but i work with the space my wife has
allowed me so i don't have much room
to work with currently but i'm making it
work hey that's what growing is all
about that's also what being married is
all about
you're making it work bro you're not
frustrating the wife too much
she's not denying you complete access to
your grow you're making it work that's
what being a good grower and being a
good spouse is all about so you're doing
exactly what you need to do bro
then it goes on to say if you need a
picture uh see my instagram oh shameless
plug here follow our friend
at tonto's underscore garden on
instagram check out his grow see what
he's got going on
it goes on to say i am just about
finished going through my first round
seeds and strains
i'm interested in crossing or keeping
for the future oh
i read that as a weird rhythm but it
says i'm just about finished going
through my first round of seeds and
strains that i'm interested in crossing
or keeping for the future that's better
then it goes on to say i was thinking
about reversing them
one by one to self-pollinate and then
also pollinate the other strains
i have in with it in my flower tent
so tonto basically wants to reverse a
plant and make some seeds for
preservation
my question is how would you recommend i
clean my flowering area after to be sure
no pollen is left over from the previous
run before
starting the next cycle does pollen go
bad after a certain time
if left in an open environment this is
part of my growing journey that is brand
new
but it won't be starting until sometime
in the fall
then he signs it with thanks for all you
do you are greatly appreciated in the
cannabis community
and source of joy to many i have no
doubt hey thank you i appreciate hearing
that i'm a source of joy
a lot of people tell me that i'm
appreciated in the community but
to be a source of joy as a new thing
thank you that is cool to hear
uh let me make sure there's no more to
read and then we will take care from
tonto
all right tonto let's talk about pollen
it sounds like you are going to use
multiple males you want to
reverse a plant make some pollen put
that pollen on some females
harvest those seeds then you'll have to
do it again i wouldn't recommend having
um multiple males in one run i would do
multiple i would do different runs those
would be
male a do a crop with him finish it
clean up harvest
then do it again it sounds like that may
be your strategy you want to know how to
get rid of the pollen how to ensure that
the pollen will not
stick around for future runs and cross
pollinate cross contaminate
the other grows basically water
will destroy pollen water deactivates
pollen so
once you have harvested take down the
plants empty out the room
just spray everything down with water
you can put another another cleaning
product in there if you choose to just
clean the room anyway
some sort of uh a sanitation product a
sterilization product
maybe some uh you could put hydrogen
peroxide in there you can put there's a
product i'm really trying to think of
and it will not come to the top of my
head right now but you can put that
faizan 20 there we go that's the one i
was trying to think of
you can put some faizan 20 in there
sterilize the room clean up the room but
basically water
will deactivate the pollen so once
you've harvested the seeds you've got
the room clean there are no plants in
there
just go crazy with the water i like to
spray everything
even the equipment that probably
shouldn't get that wet i still missed it
down i unplug everything it's turned off
i put my mister as fine as it will go so
i'm putting just super mist everywhere
i'll miss it and i'll do that just every
couple of days when the plants are new
if i put new plants in there i'll just
go spray them with the foliar feed and
while i'm hitting them with the foliar
i'll also just get the rest of the room
just get the humidity real high get
water in there
again that water deactivates pollen so
if you just want to destroy the pollen
get it wet that is the main key you're
probably going to clean the room enough
between crops just in your basic
cleaning if you're getting in there and
scrubbing things down wiping everything
down you're probably going to get rid of
the pollen just in that general cleaning
some things to think about we often miss
cleaning the tops of the lights if
you've got
square shaped lights if you don't have
some lights around and they aren't
shaped the right way to gather stuff at
the top
but some lights are long like if you've
got a magnum xxl eight inch [ __ ]
reflector
you've got a big bench up there a big
seating area for pollen just to land up
there make sure you wipe all that stuff
off don't forget to look above your head
wipe all that stuff off any surface that
may get
dusty that dust is probably containing
pollen
clean that all up so water is going to
be what gets rid of the pollen
um water will help you make sure so if
you've got other plants in the area and
you're pollinating plants over here and
there are plants over here you don't
want to get pollinated
you know you're going to be jostling
pollen around spray the plants on the
other side with water
and their pistols are basically
deactivated when the water comes or when
the pollen comes the water will
the pollen will hit the water the plants
won't get pregnant on this side you can
pollinate the plants on this side don't
rely on that as your only fail safe
but that is another level uh i guess
that's a little uh
what is it birth control for your plants
there so water is the main way
to deactivate pollen water water water
spray it spray it a lot spray it
excessively
then you can just keep spraying water
when you're full you're feeding things
just spray the room also if you're
pesticide feeding or spraying
spray the room also just put more water
on the walls on the gear and wipe
everything down
get rid of it pollen usually if it's
left in that room with all the
temperature swings humidity spikes
all the activity all the light all the
darkness that pollen will probably
deactivate itself
in 60 to 90 days it could survive longer
if the conditions are right but
you're getting light and cold or light
and dark you're getting hot and cold
all the temperatures are changing the
environment is changing that pollen
that's free and loose is going to
degrade and deactivate quite quickly
so tonto i hope i answered your question
i rambled on quite a bit about that one
water is the key to deactivating paula
all right we've got another message this
one came from our friend
um they call themselves max scrim
and ruby there might be a joke in there
i don't get but what up max scrim and
ruby
welcome to the show thank you for the
patreon support the question goes hey
man
new patreon member here hey thank you
for joining never too late
says first off i love the show and i
have talked to you on instagram
this is max scrim and ruby oh anyway you
can refer to us as max
scrim and ruby what's up guys a big
shout out to my new friends it says
my question for you is the herbs now i
just purchased one and i want to know
what you think about using that
as the drying and curing part of the
grow we don't work this hard for months
to create good product and then ruin it
in the final steps
thank you for what you do for the
community brother much love from your
homie
max scrim and ruby
all right so what this listener is
asking about is a product called the
herbs
now it is a drying and curing rack that
is for sale i've seen it on social media
i've seen it advertised in a couple of
grow
magazines and grow uh geared outlets
let's talk about it for a moment i think
it is kind of modeled after
a food dehydrator this thing looks just
like a food dehydrator
it's got a setting on the front that you
set it to the setting you want it
it says that it comes pre-programmed to
dry your herb to
15 moisture within 96 hours and that is
four days if you do the math
on that 96 divided by 24 that's four
days they say that your herb will be dry
so i don't like it dry that fast
i want it to take longer they say that
it is the perfect temperature and the
perfect humidity inside
of that container to dry it perfectly i
am skeptical i would like to see some
herb that came from that
and see what it does i prefer a nice dry
a nice slow dry here in colorado if i
hang my
plants they can be dry in about five to
seven days
but i do things to make them dry more
slowly i want it to take
longer i think during the drying curing
process
a lot of chemical reactions that are
very important for quality buds
happen in that process we're not going
to get too far into that
but i think that a longer slower drying
cure
makes for a better finished product this
thing seems like a fast track to
speeding things up and that doesn't seem
like the way to go
for drying and curing although the
science behind the device
the uh just the way that they designed
it
the science the theory in theory it
looks like it would really work but i am
skeptical
and i've never seen one in person but i
feel skeptical
but i don't it could be amazing i don't
want to come on my show where a lot of
people listen and say yeah that thing
doesn't look like
it would do what you're thinking it's
going to do but it could it could not
i am scared of it because i want my buds
to dry
more slowly the one thing i did think
about
is if you're in like florida or
somewhere where it's real sticky and you
got a lot of humidity a lot of moisture
and it takes too long for your buds to
dry this may be
a good device for you but here i'm in
colorado i'm trying to slow down the
drying of my product
i want five or seven maybe 10 maybe even
12 days of drying time
this thing says 96 hours i don't know
about that herb that i've had that dried
too fast too quickly
never tasted the way that i wished it
would taste the herb that took a little
bit longer always tasted
better in my opinion so without having
touched the product without having
smoked any of the product that came out
of this device
i can't give you like a real definite
answer that would be unfair
it looks like it could go either way to
tell you the honest truth i don't think
it is the product for me
but i don't know where you are like i
said if you're in a high humidity
environment
if you really need to get that product
dried and cured out of there
that may be the way to do it if you have
been not hitting
your dry and cured goals if you're not
getting it dialed in properly this may
help
if you're completely ruining your
product at the end and you're not happy
this could be the rescuer if you're
already sucking this may improve it
but i think old-school drying and curing
is basically free you don't need to buy
too much equipment for a small grow
uh you may need a humidifier and a
dehumidifier if you're buying that much
gear that may be when it comes to
looking into one of these
but without seeing it without touching
it i can't give you a real honest
evaluation um i wish i did
have more info for you uh buy one you
said you bought one so
run it see what it does bro dry some of
your herb the way you used to and then
dry some of your herb
in this machine and compare see what you
like better and then give me some
feedback and we can talk about it
on the show all right i want to keep
moving because i do have a nice
stack of patreon messages here uh this
one says cbd trichome question
i think i took a screenshot of this one
because when i tried to print the
message it did not print so we're going
to scroll through
here we go i found the message this one
comes from our friend papa zee
and it says what up roster jeff first of
all your show has helped me and
others i'm sure beyond words that is
awesome to hear thank you
says it is an honor to have a black belt
grower such as yourself and i consider
you my mentor
and for that i am eternally grateful i
am all of your mentor and i appreciate
that you're very welcome thank you for
uh the support and the kind words
it says i get back way more than i give
through patreon
ah man you give and that is appreciated
you don't have to contribute to the show
nobody is required i put the show out
for free
so it is greatly appreciated that you
contribute to patreon thank you
then it goes on to say i'm also a fellow
drummer of 35
years what's up bro i hope your wrists
feel okay been drumming for a long time
my knees are starting to hurt my wrists
feel weird
i think it's from bashing on [ __ ] for
way too long um
keep keeping time brother then the
message goes on to say cannabis drums
and family are my
loves that's why we get along bro keeps
going it says my question is this
i am growing a critical mass one-to-one
auto
so he's got a it's got a one-to-one
ratio of cbd
to thc is what was advertised on the
package he hasn't tested the product
because it is still growing
but that is what is to be expected from
the phenotype based on advertising
it says august 5th will be eight weeks
into flower so i have just started
flushing all right so you've got a eight
or nine week plant maybe a nine or ten
week plant you've just begun the flush
it says does the 30 amber trichome
guideline apply
the same to cbd rich plants as straight
thc
plants thanks again and much love from
papa z then it says
what would i have to do to get a grow
from your heart sticker
um i would have to make them there are
no grow from your heart podcast stickers
available yet
but it is almost time for me to place an
order with my sticker maker and i may
include
the gfyh logo in that sticker print
we'll see how that one goes so when i
make stickers
uh i'll keep you posted i owe you a
sticker because you support me on
patreon so thank you
now let's talk about your trichomes uh
you're growing for
cbd you're trying to get that one-to-one
cbd to thc ratio
i am not a cbd expert that is not my
realm that is not my desire i don't grow
for cbd i want the opposite if you guys
know me
i want to get high i want to go up i
think going up makes me feel better
cbd makes me feel i lose dexterity if i
were playing i don't play video games
i don't play guitar but if i ever try to
play guitar i do kind of fiddle on a
guitar it's not my thing but i've got
one and
i dick around on it so if i smoke a cbd
product and try to dick around on the
guitar my fingers
aren't as dexterous as they would be had
i not consumed the cbd product they get
a little rubbery
a little gumby like i just don't have
the full control
like i feel like i normally would have
not consumed cbd so i'm not a cbd
expert i don't grow cbd i don't breed
cbd
but i would like to assume that you're
still going to
use that amber trichome 30 amber
trichome guideline
because we still want ripe trichomes i
think they're ripe when they are that
color i don't know
which cannabinoid they are ripe with but
it feels like that is a ripe trichome
uh we want fruits when they're ripe we
can identify when they're ripe we still
want our cannabis ripe and i think
that that trichome color is still the
way to determine that
even though we're going after the cbd
i wish i had better input for you i'm
sitting here thinking of different ways
to think of this
but i think that's the best way to do it
just go by those trichomes just like you
normally do i'm going to take a quick
drink and we're going to keep moving
all right i even thought about it while
i was drinking and i want you to
continue by following that 30
amber trichome rule and if there are any
cbd farmers out there who have better
guidance for us
let us know and then i'll feed you back
with that info as it comes into me hey
papa zee thank you for the great
question
and i do look forward to getting replies
from my audience to help you out a
little bit further
all right i do have more patreon
questions we're going to keep this show
moving
this one comes from willy's armpit i see
your name pop up a lot on patreon i give
you a shout out a lot at the start of
the show that is a really cool unique
name
i like it it stands out so i'm glad to
get your message on the show
this a message goes just a like at this
it says hello rosted jeff
hey bro good to see you i finally made
it back to patreon i'm glad you're here
brother
and you guys don't ever sweat or stress
that you can't help out on patreon that
is okay
there are plenty of people that do help
out i appreciate it
i know i pitch patreon a lot a lot of
people want to help out
don't feel like you can't listen or that
i don't like you as much because you're
not on patreon
we're all friends i treat everyone as
equals uh patreon does help get your
emails to the top of the list but i do
read
other messages that don't come from
patreon but i promise these people
to get read as soon as i can the next
recording session from the time i get
your patreon question
question i try to put you on the next
show so um
don't worry if you can't support patreon
i still want you to listen there are
people out there
that are supporting it to keep it going
even if you can't what you can do
is you can grow the best cannabis you
know how to grow when you're in your
grow do your best every day
and that pays me back do your grow the
best you can
make me proud that's what i'm here for
that means more than money to me
you grow your best herb you can make me
proud that puts a smile on my face
all right i'm gonna get back into this
message because that honey banana
got me [ __ ] rambly today this message
says
i just recently started your veg bloom
and new millennium
nutrient program if you listen back a
few episodes a lot of episodes
i do a full description of my nutrient
mix and i use new millennium bottled
nutrients
and veg bloom powder nutrients in
different facilities i use one as a base
and different facilities i use the other
in some facilities i'm mixing them and
making a turbo
nutrient mix here it's the secret sauce
ah this guy goes on to say willie's
armpit goes on to say i'm four weeks
into flour and i've never seen my plants
healthier i love hearing that
i'm sure my friends at veg bloom and my
friends at new millennium hearing love
hearing that as well
it says my garden has never looked so
happy as it does
now i've been hooked on boaty seeds for
years now bodhi makes a great product
i love bodhi but i'm definitely
switching to irie genetics
hey there's no need to switch up to irie
if bodhi's making you happy if you're
loving what's coming out of your garden
when you're growing bodhi seeds
keep growing bodhi seeds bodhi's a great
dude a great breeder
makes a great product no reason to
switch it up unless that is something
you're choosing to do
on your own just to switch it up but i
promote body body is a great
dude breeder like i said nothing wrong
with growing bodies gear
keep doing that some wonderful strains
come out of bodhi so uh where am i
i'm on this page it says anyway i can
show my love
anyway now i can show my love and
support sign me up
no one has ever done for my garden what
you have done i cannot thank you enough
i wish i could pledge more to patreon
because you are definitely
worth it hey willie's armpit just
hearing how ecstatic and delighted you
are
uh with your garden from my advice is
payment enough bro don't sweat
don't stress that you can't help me out
more on patreon you are doing what you
can you just
told me that your garden looks better
from the time i put in behind this
microphone all i had to do was come here
and talk
takes a little bit of equipment i got
some toys got some technology happening
uh some prep work but basically i sat
here and spoke into this microphone
and your garden looks better because you
took that info so
that means enough to me you don't have
to give me money thank you
keep kicking ass in your garden keep
growing the best product you can grow
and you'll pay me back every single day
big shout out to willie's armpit
ah man i'm glad your garden looks good
and if you have any questions about the
veg bloom and new millennium mix
please reach out i would love to help
you out
all right let's see let's see this one
did not come from patreon see i told you
that i read messages that don't only
come from patreon
i think by the end of this episode and
the next one i'll be caught up on
patreon messages unless we get a bunch
more
but let's keep the show moving this one
says hey ross to jeff
i wanted to run a question across you to
see if you had any ideas i feel like i
am the guy to answer
this question that says i have a 10 pack
of seeds from a breeder
back in the day i'm not going to say the
seeds or the breeder we're going to keep
that out of this
because i started three and rapid
rooters like i always do and a tray with
dome
and a tray with the dome under t5s the
temperature is 76 and the humidity is 62
percent
after a couple of days the seeds
developed fuzz on them so i cleaned them
off and put them in soil
so far after a week on sprouting
and put them in soil so far after a week
of sprouting we're going to say that was
supposed to say of sprouting
so oh they this person started off some
seeds
10 of them and they put them in rapid
rooters the way that they normally do
they put them in a tray with a dome
under t5s
uh that works for you i don't do the
dome i don't like a dome for my seeds i
don't find it necessary we use the dome
for clones to keep the humidity in there
because they don't have roots to feed
from
the seedlings they don't need as much
humidity i feel like it makes them weak
we've got to take them off the dome and
introduce them to the environment
i don't ever give them a dome they don't
start off being babied and pampered
i think it gives them a little bit of a
boost a little bit more strength the way
you're doing it if it works for you
do that but i'm just saying i don't do
the dome it says temperature 76 that
should be fine i may go a little bit
warmer but they're going to be okay
humidity is 62 that's going to work for
you after a couple of days
the seeds developed fuzz on them um
that could be a couple of things but i
want to keep reading i've never had this
problem before with this method i have
seen that some people use dr
zymes before putting seeds into the
rooter will this help or are the seeds
just bad feel free to use this question
on the show
big thanks for everything you do and
dropping free knowledge hey you are very
welcome
let's talk about this uh this could be a
couple of things
it sounds like you've done this before
and you know what you're doing but
possibly i'm not blaming you this is an
option possibly
that rapid router that moist rapid
router that seed that dome that heat
that environment
that could have caused a little bit of
that uh cobweb spiderweb look in white
mildew
that could have caused that i don't know
i'm not blaming you i'm just listing
options that could have done it it could
have been the moisture in the rapid
rooter
being stuck in the dome that could have
set up the perfect environment for that
mildew
the other option is maybe j and this is
why i didn't say the breeder of the
seeds or the name of the strain
it is possible that those seeds came
from plants that had powdery mildew in
them
and maybe they just had mildew on the
plants maybe there was some sort of a
pathogen in the plants
also maybe another option maybe when
those seeds were harvested
maybe they were not allowed to dry
properly before they were put into a
package they were still moist
they were sealed up they were put into a
package a little bit of mildew developed
that way you seal up moisture
and you give it a little bit of heat
that is the perfect environment dark
moist and warm
that's going to give you mildew so those
are three ways that that mildew could
have
happened in your seedlings you could
have gotten it in the rapid rooter
it could have happened in the plants
while they were growing or it could have
happened
in packaging when a grower brew when you
breed seeds it's a lot like having a wet
herb
and then you have a bunch of wet herbs
you get it dry enough to take the seeds
out you take the seeds out
the seeds still have moisture in them
and on them sometimes and
if you're in a big hurry you're just a
commercial producer trying to get them
out maybe just maybe
you packaged them up you didn't give
enough time still a little bit moist
that's a possibility i don't know
exactly what happened but those are the
three things that come to my mind
when i try to think about why your
little seedlings may have gotten fuzzy
now you ask people use dr zymes before
putting the seeds into the rooter
will that help uh that may have helped
depending on what that
pathogen was on there maybe possibly
probably
i've also seen people put a little bit
of hydrogen peroxide in the water to try
to take care of that
so that may have been an option for you
also i think we spoke a little bit about
this
i think you've already found a solution
for your seedlings all right i want to
thank you for the great message i hope i
solved your problem or at least gave you
a little bit of insight
i'm not sure if you want your name said
on the show you did not include it here
in the email
you know who you are big thank you i see
your name pop up
quite a bit i see you in the instagram
feed all the time thank you for hanging
out
all right i want to read another message
this one says yo rasta jeff i love the
show and the in-depth answers you give
to each question a lot of people don't
like the in-depth answers i get rambly a
little bit but i'm glad you enjoy the
in-depth answers
it says it really shows how much
preparation goes into each response
i write down a few notes on each email
and then i try to keep it spontaneous
and go from the top of my head
i did an episode a couple of shows back
where i took way too many notes and it
didn't feel natural i didn't like the
show's flow
so i try to just make a couple of bullet
points and keep it going
keep it flowing naturally keep it
conversational i'd rather talk with you
than to you or at you i think is what
i'm trying to say but
let me continue because i'm doing that
thing where i ramble again anyways i'm
watching a short video on terpenes right
now and it made me think of your comment
on a recent episode about limonene
coming out when you have your lights
closer to the plants yes
i have said before that i believe we can
bring out the limonene
if you've got a lemon flavored plant and
you want it to be even more lemony
get it a little bit too close to the
light late in flower i think
limonene is sort of a stress response
kind of a reaction
i don't know exactly what it does but
the plant goes [ __ ] it's way too hot
it's way too light i'm going to
create this thing and it makes limonine
i don't know what the plant thinks it's
gonna do
but it does that and it creates limonene
and we harvest those plants and they
taste [ __ ] lemony
i had a sour diesel plant they grew way
too close to the light
and it tastes like lemon sour diesel
that's part of what made me start
thinking about this
then i noticed those plants that got too
close to the light always have that
sour sweeter sort of thing going on all
right so let's get back into this email
it keeps going it says
this video is saying that the plant can
put out different terpenes at the top
where it is more prone to insects
including limonene
at the bottom it may put out more bitter
terpenes to keep grazing
mammals away i thought that was pretty
cool and it shows that you are on to
something with
your theory yeah i like that a lot and
that makes a lot of sense
if you think about like grazing animals
anything from like a chicken to a
[ __ ] pig
or a cow anything that would come around
and eat the bottom of a plant
it makes it taste bitter so that that
cow goes chomp chomp oh that tastes like
[ __ ] i don't want none of that and it
walks away from it
but up at the top you're going to get
completely different attackers spider
mites
they're going to be up there at the top
so it makes that limonene so when the
spider mites go up they go this is sour
bro i don't want to be up here
and they take off so i love that you
gave me some feedback and i love that
i've got some scientific support here
and then it says keep putting out that
great content from the smokin
cuskogan uh and then it says ps the
video is
terpenes and marijuana explained with dr
jake feliz so if anybody else out there
would like some supplemental terpene
education
check out terpenes in marijuana
explained
by dr jake felice it sounds like i may
be watching that video
when i'm done recording here i hate
smoking muskogen
thank you for the great feedback i love
hearing
that somebody out there supported some
of my wild
cannabis theories all right i've been
going for a minute but i've got one more
message that i want to read
let's see this one says what's happening
ross to jeff i just wanted to reach out
and give you a follow-up to a question
you read on the podcast
regarding an m-dog hermaphrodite so i
did chop her down at week six
and you were right it was loaded with
seeds
i remember saying that if you can see a
few seeds on the outside of that bud
it is probably loaded up on the inside
it sounds like i was correct it was
loaded with seeds and see uh let's see
and it also he also seeded a swamp boy's
shocky plant i had near her that was a
rough sentence but we got through it
together
i run that m-dog perpetually and the
reason i wanted to
to discuss this with you is i feel that
i have experienced genetic
drift i've done a podcast about genetic
drift
and briefly no that's not what is
happening um
we can explain genetic drift again but
that is not what genetic drift is it
says i know you've discussed this in a
couple of episodes and i feel like i've
explained this i stated the mdo i
started the m dog back in april of 2019
and i've been cloning her
before i send her into flower um not
cloning it okay so you're
uh cutting a clone letting it veg
cutting clones from that then putting
that big plant into flower that's
basically how we keep a plant around
it's similar to doing a mom plant you
just flower out that mom
it says so she's running for a little
over a year then i had that one herme
that i sent you the question on
then the following two plants also
hermed on the same spots the lower
branches
i run organics and i didn't have any
light leaks so i'm thinking this was
genetic drift
what do you think i don't have enough
data on your grow
to have a solid opinion but i think that
the plant has always been a herm and you
are just now giving it the proper
conditions to express that trait
maybe that is my assumption plants don't
tend to just
become herm that doesn't and i don't
think that's a genetic drift
thing i think you're just now giving it
the environment uh
the situation whatever there's something
that is triggering it to her that it
never had before so what is different
now
that wasn't different before is the soil
a little bit hotter
is the soil weaker is your feed more
rich is the room more humid is it too
hot
there could be any number of factors
deciding
making this plant decide that now i want
to be a her
so it says do you think cloning over and
over again for a year
caused her to just say [ __ ] this i'm
really curious to see what you think
thank you so much for your support i'm
on patreon as buzzards
bay hey buzzards bay thank you for the
question
i really don't have a definitive answer
other than
i think that you just finally gave this
plant the environment to hermaphrodite
you've been running it for a year
i don't know how many crops you've had
before that but i'm going to assume that
the first time you ran it
it's like a first date the first time
you go out first time you ran this plant
first time you took this girl out
you were real polite real gentle you
followed the book you read all the
instructions you did the cool guy kind
guy polite guy move
did all that [ __ ] right the plant was
happy with you and it put out
the second time you got cocky you're
like you put out the first time watch me
this time
you're kind of a dick i'm not saying
you're a dick i'm just saying this is
what we do
you got too comfortable with the plan
you didn't open the car door right after
dinner when you're walking that plan out
to
the car after you ate last time you
opened the car door made sure she was in
there comfortably made sure that her
dress wasn't hanging out of the car door
you tucked your dress in
closed the door nice and gently farted
while you were out of the car ran around
the car got to your door made sure the
fart smell was gone then you got in
uh the second time you went on the date
you guys after dinner you just [ __ ]
opened your own car door and jumped in
you farted in the car that's what
happens to guys
we go real careful we follow the book
the first time that second time we get
kind of cocky and we forget that there's
a lot of steps and a lot of rules
so i'm assuming that maybe the first
time you were real real careful with
this plant you're like she's new
she takes this long to flower i got a
learner i got to figure her out
second time you may have taken it for
granted said she put out real well the
first time
i'm going back for more of that the
second time but you didn't take all the
steps to get it to put out the way you
expected it to
that may be the most crass description
i've ever given on a podcast but
i think you understood exactly what the
[ __ ] i meant
all right i hope i answered your
question i really think that that plant
was probably a hermaphrodite the whole
time and you were just now
giving it the opportunity to show you
that trade
uh buzzards bay thank you for the
support on patreon and again
thank you for the great email that wraps
up all of the emails and patreon
questions for this episode of the show
to the best of my knowledge i feel like
i am caught up on patreon questions if
you've sent me a patreon question
up to what is the date today we are now
at the 1st of august
if you sent me a patreon question before
the 1st of august and i have not read it
on the show
please resend it so i can make sure to
get your question right on the show
also if you've got any new questions
send them because i will get them on the
podcast
very soon all right ladies and gentlemen
boys and girls pimps and hoes friends
and foes
smokers and growers clone cutters and
pollen chuckers all you sexy
[ __ ] out there
i want to thank each and every one of
you for listening to episode 557 of the
grow from your heart podcast
if you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
and you'd like to make a financial
contribution to the show of course you
can do so by visiting www
patreon forward slash grow from your
heart
all of the information you need to
support the show will be right there on
the screen
and again i did include that link in the
show notes and the video description
to make it easy for you to find the
patreon
also don't forget to visit our sponsors
at seeds here now.com
use coupon code gfyh10 while you're
checking out that'll save you a few
bucks
if you're only getting one pack of seeds
that will cover the cost of shipping
if you're getting multiple packs that
will save you quite a few bucks
maybe you can grab a few more packs
while you're there also check out that
under 30 section because there is a pack
from ire genetics in the under 30
section spoil yourself and upgrade your
garden all right if you've got any
questions corrections comments or
concerns i would love to hear from you
my email address of course is grow from
your heart at hotmail.com
don't be shy send me your questions i'll
get them on the show
ladies and gentlemen that is all i've
got for you for this episode i'll be
back in a couple of days with fresh new
content
i want to give a shout out to my buddy
brett g and until next time
take a fat dab and give your mom a hug
for me