[Music]
here we go welcome back podcast world
i'm your host my friends call me rosta
jeff and it is time for episode 558 of
the grow from your heart podcast
this episode of the show is brought to
you by our friends at seedshearnow.com
seeds herenow.com carry seeds from all
of the industry's
leading breeders including miss jill
genetics duke diamond and of course irie
genetics
everything at seeds herenow.com is
backed by their award-winning
satisfaction guarantee
and for my friends on a budget seeds
herenow.com offers
several packs for under 30 dollars as
well as amazing
monthly sales make sure to use coupon
code gfyh10 while checking out to save a
few bucks
again that is coupon code gfyh10 while
checking out
at seeds here now dot com
you know i like to start this podcast
off by talking about what i'm smoking
today i've been taking dabs of reba jam
live batter from green dot labs
this is a blend of jelly 13 and i-95
on the package the flavor is described
as tangerine and sour fuel
i think i completely agree with that
when i crack open the jar i am greeted
by a sweet tangerine aroma
and that is followed by a funky sour
fuel
when i take dabs of it i definitely
taste that sour fuel
if i dab it nice and cool the orange
flavor and aroma comes in a little bit
more if i go too hot
it is definitely sour and funky on the
back of the package it says the
product does contain 64.08 thc
and non-detectable amounts of cbd big
shout out to our friends
at green dot labs for the delicious riba
jam
live batter all right in this episode
i'm going to read an email about grow
room safety but before we get there
let's do some shout outs to the 710 club
let's start off with the big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to my friend eric ross
i also want to send a big thank you
shout out to grow man stan i've always
got a big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out for my
friend helly let's send a big thank you
shout out to ross decay
i also have a big thank you for easy057
let's say thanks to paparoni let's send
a big grow from your heart podcast high
five to can a reaper
i've always got a grow from your heart
podcast high five and a thank you for my
friend tommy
let's send a big thank you shout out to
adhd grower let's send a big high five
to steven smith
i've always got a big thank you shout
out for pacific northwest
dan that was hard for my brain to read
i've also got a big thank you shout out
to our buddy lemur priest
i've always got a big thank you shout
out to aaron barajas and last but
certainly not least
let's send a big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to our
friend
eric l big thank you and big shout out
to everybody who supports the show on
patreon if you're not already supporting
the show and you would like to learn how
to do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need will be
right there on the screen
and of course i did include a link in
the show notes to make it nice and easy
all right ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls pimps and hoes and friends and
foes
smokers and growers clone cutters and
paul and chuckers this is the portion of
the show where i start reading
listener emails today we're going to
focus on grow room safety
that was brought to my attention by a
listener named brandy i'm going to jump
right into their email
and it goes like this what's up rosta
jeff feel free to use my name
thank you for that info right at the
start of the message it makes it so easy
it goes on to say i've been listening to
your podcast since last fall when a dude
at my local grow shop gave me
your podcast info and the dgc info
i'm so thankful to him for that because
your podcast has helped me learn
so much yeah big thank you to that guy
at the grow store i'm glad he
introduced you to the girl from your
heart podcast and the dude grow show
if you guys aren't already watching the
dude grow show i highly encourage you to
check them out
if you're watching me on youtube if
you're listening on apple podcast or
spotify
the dude grows show is available
wherever you're watching or listening to
me just go to the service
go to the search bar type in dude grows
you'll find that podcast
i highly recommend it you will enjoy it
shout out to my friends in the dgc
i want to keep going because that riba
jam got me chattery it says
you taught me not only about cannabis
but about safety this is where the
message gets interesting it says
last night after putting our two kids to
bed my wife came downstairs and found
water running all the way down into our
living room
we just bought this house last year and
we have done a lot of work on it
including new
laminate flooring which was water
resistant thankfully
and i was completely horrified to come
downstairs and see
water everywhere that's got to be a
scary sight
says i ran to our basement to grab the
shop vac and there were waterfalls
coming from the ceiling
uh that made me feel a certain way when
you said that my stomach moved i got a
little drop in my gut my chest felt
tight
waterfalls coming from the ceiling is
never a good thing unless you paid extra
for that
it is 99 of the time a major [ __ ]
problem
um horrified isn't even a strong enough
word i agree with you
i'm feeling panic inside right now and
it's not even my house or my grow
it says sure panic took over and i ran
to the grow room to find it
completely dry and the flooding water
hadn't crept that far
i had a bit of water from another part
but it was very little
thankfully sounds like this could have
been much worse and i'm really glad it
wasn't too bad for you
it goes on to say i had just revamped
the grow last month which included
switching out lights
caulking and sealing every everything
super tight
and we repainted i was also very mindful
to place all cords and electronics up
high
that is a good step i talked about that
in a previous episode but we'll get
there in a minute
uh hanging the electronics or hanging
from hooks or sitting
on a tall shelf and i can say that the
likelihood of doing that on my own is
slim so without your knowledge without
your podcast and without
uh you're talking about how important
safety is in the grow room
i can't say i would have given the
safety much thought if
any the sound this sounds asinine and
kind of crazy we have the chords and
[ __ ] all over sometimes
which i've gone around and placed on top
of tables and desks and off the floor
we'll never have them on the floor again
thanks to you
uh you sound you seem like a [ __ ]
stand-up guy and i hope to get to meet
you
and give you a hug at some point next
year i hope when all this quarantine and
weirdness goes away that i get to meet a
lot of people and get a lot of hugs
i look forward to it it says sorry for
this long ass email but i thought you'd
enjoy this story
i mean it's crazy right yes it is crazy
so crazy that it has inspired
a redo of the grow room safety episode
it says anyway take care
stay safe as hell during this crazy
pandemic attached as a video i did watch
that video
i gave me a panic attack there was just
water falling from this person's ceiling
lots of water everywhere in places it
shouldn't be
i see exactly what you're talking about
so they wrap it up and it says from
brandy
now that has inspired a grow room safety
lesson the reason brandy was smart
enough and aware to keep their
electronics up off the floors because i
did an episode in the past but we are
now on a video format
so it's time to do a refresher of the
grow room
safety course let's talk about basic
safety
there are a lot of things we can hurt
ourselves potentially make ourselves
sick with in a grow room
always think about personal protective
equipment that is the first place to
start before you go in there
do you have the right stuff on are you
wearing the right [ __ ] you should have
gloves on
i know you're just going in there look
at the plants but if you're going to
touch a plant if you're going to touch a
bottle
put on some gloves a six millimeter or
thicker
nitrile gloves are what i recommend wear
gloves
you probably i don't know what you're
doing in your grow but possibly you have
applied a pesticide to those plants
when you sprayed that pesticide it
didn't just hit the plants it hit the
walls it hit the ceiling and hit the
doorknobs
it hit everywhere in that room so now
you're going to go in there and touch
[ __ ] in that room
you're going to pick up pesticides off
the walls you're going to get pesticides
off the doorknob
they're probably pesticides in places
you didn't think about don't get that on
your hands
then it's your face then you're gonna
get a big rash on your face you're gonna
look like a [ __ ] freak
don't do that to yourself wear
protective gloves in the grow
another thing to think about don't touch
your face if you're
if you've got the gloves on don't hit
your face with those gloves on if your
face hitches take the gloves off scratch
your face get new gloves
let's not contaminate ourselves with
pesticides also in a previous episode we
heard about a listener
who gets rashes just from coming in
contact with the plants
so wear gloves let's not give ourselves
any rashes from the plants themselves or
the pesticides
or any other foliar feeds we may have
applied to the grow
along with rubber gloves i recommend
long sleeves in a grow environment
i know it's hot in there it's not the
perfect environment for wearing long
sleeves
but you don't want to get that pesticide
on your arms like i talked about a
moment ago we had a listener
who got a rash just from touching the
plants you're wearing long sleeves
that's not an option so wear long
sleeves it can be something real
thin if you just got like a light like a
light little linen just a button-down
shirt to put on you still look nice you
look good in there and you're protecting
your arms if you're a hoodie guy wear a
hoodie
if you're a long-sleeve shirt guy wear a
long sleeve shirt if you're a guy or a
gal that doesn't want to cover up your
sleeves
you can run that risk of getting a
pesticide on your arm you can run the
risk of getting the rash
but i highly recommend gloves and long
sleeves
hopefully you're wearing pants a lot of
the times i see people wearing shorts in
the grow
i guess that's acceptable unless you're
spraying a pesticide if you are applying
something be
completely covered i know it's hot in
there we got our arms covered up
it's less likely that our legs are going
to brush up against plants but if they
do
i recommend you wear pants also always
have good
shoes i know shoes a lot of us
want to be barefoot and grow a lot of us
want to run around and feel the dirt
that's cool if that's your girl if
that's what you want to do go for that
i highly recommend shoes for several
reasons
first of all let's think about
pesticides if you are in an indoor
environment
and you have applied a pesticide where
does it all land anything that dripped
off the plants anything that wasn't
caught in the air
is on the floor if you were barefoot you
were rubbing your bare feet
on that pesticide laden floor unless you
have mops since the pesticides but if
you're in there barefoot
i'm imagining you're not a mopping kind
of person as well you're barefoot in
that dirty grow room
collecting pesticides on the bottoms of
your feet the bottoms of your feet are
one of the most absorbent parts of your
body
if you want to get a pesticide toxicity
just pour it onto the bottoms of your
feet it'll absorb really quickly it's a
good way to get yourself
sick so i recommend shoes in there to
keep yourself away from the pesticides
that could be on the floor
also anything else you may have spilled
a nutrient a nutrient bottle
a nutrient solution that's on the floor
getting into your feet
can't be good for you also not good for
your skin i get it i used to be a major
hippie too when i was younger now i wear
shoes in the grow
what if you drop something on your feet
that's gonna suck you're out of work for
a day
or two you don't want that to happen
just wear some shoes is my advice if
you're in a commercial grow
you better be wearing closed-toed shoes
if you show up to my commercial girl in
flip-flops or sandals guess what
better go to the car and find some good
shoes or go home and get some good ones
because you're not wearing that [ __ ] in
my commercial grow
protect yourselves you guys also wear
if you're around any sort of sprays if
you are mixing
pesticides if you're mixing nutrients i
recommend some sort of goggles i know
that sounds excessive
but your eyes are the most sensitive
organ
in your body that are exposed to the
outside elements i can poke you anywhere
on the chest and the arms you're going
to be cool but if i get right in your
eye one time it [ __ ] sucks dude
protect your eyes wear some goggles wear
something over your eyes when you're
mixing and spraying
anytime if you're going to reach for a
pesticide or a nutrient bottle
right before you reach for that put on
gloves and goggles it's really easy
especially in a commercial environment a
lot of times if i see you not using the
appropriate personal protective
equipment in a commercial grow
you get to take a little break you get
to come up to the office and hang out
with me while i write out a report
on how you are failing to wear the
products that i have assigned
keep yourself safe you guys this isn't
just because it looks cool
it's not just because we're nerdy we
want you to be safe
and healthy i have a friend who was
mixing nutrients by himself
and he got ph down in his eye
he wasn't wearing goggles he wasn't
wearing gloves you got ph down oh you
got phd on his hand and rubbed it into
his eye is what he did
so he got it from his skin into his eye
now he's got ph down on his hand it's
burning his hand
now he's also got it in his eye he
didn't know what to do you know what he
had to do
he pulled out his phone and used siri to
call
to his 911 room to come help him out
imagine being in that situation you
don't want the cops the paramedics
showing up at your grow
unless it's completely legal that could
be terrible so everything i'm talking
about has a purpose i'm not just coming
out here trying to be dad
i know i'm getting older but that's not
what this is about this is because i
care about you guys
and you may not have thought about this
so i'm trying to give you a reminder
and give you examples of why you might
want to use the equipment i'm talking
about
uh gloves long sleeves good shoes that
should all be self-explanatory
goggles that should be self-explanatory
like i said your eyes are sensitive i
can poke you anywhere else on your body
but the minute i touch your eyeball you
[ __ ] want to run away and take a
minute
all right another thing i want to make
sure to talk about is selecting the
appropriate
mask or respirator when applying a
pesticide
a lot of times i see guys wearing gloves
and long sleeves and they got the
goggles on when they're spraying a
pesticide but they have forgotten
to use some sort of a mask or respirator
over their face to protect themselves
when you're spraying a pesticide you're
making bubbles you're making a mist in
the room
and then you're breathing you're just
sucking up all that mist
all those bubbles you are pesticiding
yourself you're applying pesticides to
your lungs if you're not wearing the
appropriate respirator
so i highly recommend the appropriate
respirator
for pesticide applications especially if
you were using something like a paint
sprayer to make really small bubbles if
you're using a fogger
definitely definitely you need a mask or
a respirator
on the inside of your pesticides uh not
on the inside on the
outside of the pesticide bottle there is
a book if you open that book
it will tell you what personal
protective equipment you need to wear
while applying that pesticide wear all
of that stuff if it says minimum
requirement
that is the minimum requirement you can
do more but don't do less than that
also there is what is known as the
re-entry interval printed on that bottle
the rei tells you how long you need to
stay out of that grow room without
personal protective
equipment before you re-enter after
applying that pesticide
so if the rei is four hours you go in
there with your equipment you spray you
come out you set a timer for four hours
if it's a commercial grow put a sign on
the door that says hey i sprayed in here
at noon
don't go back in here until four o'clock
there are signs that are already
pre-made
from the department of agriculture they
will give them to you they will sell
them to you
put those signs on your doors to let
people know don't go in here
i sprayed this room you will get sick
then here's something to think about
if you are applying pesticides indoors
increase
the rei by a minimum of two to four
hours the rei the re-entry interval
was designed for a greenhouse or an
outdoor application they did not think
we were going to apply these pesticides
indoors indoors we don't have the sun
breaking down the pesticides we don't
have as much air movement we don't have
wind
it's not as open and free you were
trapped in that stagnant box of a grow
room
so please allow an extra two to four
hours for a re-entry interval after a
pesticide in a small
in a grow room indoors not just a small
in a big room indoors
let that pesticide break down let that
cloud of fog spray go away
don't put yourself in danger give
yourself that extra re-entry
interval also write down
every pesticide application if you're in
a commercial grow you are required
to keep a pesticide log if you were in a
personal grow i recommend
keeping a pesticide log write down every
pesticide you sprayed
the date you sprayed it the amount you
put in the mix when you mixed it up
and which plants you sprayed it on so
it'll say like
tuesday this is the date i applied these
pesticides at this much
on these plants at this time then we
have a good documentation of when you
applied things
you know when you sprayed last right now
if i say hey when did you spray for
spider mites last
do you know write that [ __ ] down then
you know
that within three to five days it is
time to treat again
so i don't get an infestation and if i
do have an infestation i need to stay on
top of a tight schedule
so pesticide logs are very important
also
in the future if you get some sort of a
rash that could be a pesticide outbreak
or a pesticide exposure
we know that you sprayed this pesticide
on these plants on this day because here
it is you wrote it down
you can help yourself out you can help
the doctor out if you do get sick
just help yourself out set yourself up
for success
so pesticide logs are very important
also i recommend having
if you're in a commercial grow this is
required but i recommend having
msds sheets for almost every product you
use
especially pesticides especially foliar
feeds then
also have them for all of your nutrients
anything that comes into that grow
just print off an msds sheet put it in a
folder next to your pesticide logs that
way any information that we need
we've got available if something does go
wrong we've got all the information we
need i hope nothing goes wrong
but if you get a rash if you get a weird
disease we can look at all of your msds
sheets and say oh he's using this
product and this product oh here's the
one right here that's giving him
seizures
maybe we can figure something out i
don't want that to happen to you but if
it does happen
all of that documentation will help us
out accountability will really help you
out in the future
and if you are keeping all of these
documents in your personal grow
when it comes time to expand into
commercial growing you're already
working with the practice it's already
something you're programmed to do
and it's not a big whole new step it's
not a whole bunch of new [ __ ] to learn
so pesticide logs and msds sheets can be
invaluable have those around in your
grow now
i just thought of if you're in an
illegal area if you're in prohibition
land
that's like evidence maybe you don't
want all that [ __ ] maybe keep that as a
google doc and maybe have a couple of
passwords so nobody can access that
but if you're in a legal area and you
were growing i would have
msds sheets and pesticide logs just as
accountability
and they work well in the future for if
you want to do some sort of applying for
jobs you could say i've already been
keeping pesticide logs and msds sheets
and also understand your local
department of agriculture rules
so i think that gets us through most of
that part
always read the labels on your
pesticides there's another note that i
wrote
that little book on the front of the
pesticide pops open and there are so
many details in there
reentry interval um what to look for for
exposure
how much to apply when to apply it uh
what personal protective equipment to
use if it is toxic if it's dangerous
uh if it's it's got all that is labeled
on there check that out
i recommend you look at that the little
booklet that pops out there's a lot of
good info in there
read it if you never have i highly
recommend that so that covers basically
like pesticide safety
and uh yeah pesticide safety application
safety
the basics of growing now let's work on
grow safety
a little bit uh when you're in the grow
there are a lot of things you can hurt
yourself with
um a lot of things i see that drive me
crazy are sticks
i do it in my grow too but those big
sticks if they're not tall enough if
they're too tall the ones that are like
four feet tall
i see a lot of people potentially poking
their eyes on those i have almost done
it myself
so you've got a plant it's starting to
droop on one side you put a couple of
sticks in there you put a zip tie around
it now your plants stand up you got a
stick on it everything is cool right
but tomorrow when you go to water that
plant or maybe you're just going to look
at the plant you lean over
you forget there's a stick in there that
stick goes right in your [ __ ] eye
those things are dangerous if you're
going to put sticks in the grow room
steaks bamboo sticks put something at
the end of that make it a flag or put a
tennis ball or a ping pong ball at the
end of it
to where it's not so pokey and it's not
such a high
danger those things will poke you right
in the eye that'll [ __ ] you up
another thing people seem to forget that
scissors are sharp when you're in the
grow room when you're in the trim room
you're hauling ass
pay attention because those fiskars are
[ __ ] sharp i've seen a lot of people
cut themselves i've seen people cut
other people pay attention you guys be
safe i shouldn't have to remind you
scissors are sharp don't leave them in
random places
don't put them in your pocket if you're
going to carry scissors around
use the little scissor holster that they
come with all the scissors come with a
little protective thing
use that [ __ ] put it on your belt if you
insist on putting the scissors in your
pocket
put them in that little sheath then put
them in your pocket be careful you guys
i don't want to have to write an
incident report on you because you were
just being dumb
scissors are sharp i know it's done that
i have to remind you but some people
need that [ __ ] reminder
also grow lights are hot as [ __ ]
those bulbs are hot don't touch those um
when it comes time to change a grow
light you can't just unscrew it and put
a new one in
it needs a little bit to cool off
depending on the size of the bulb and
how long it's been running
that thing is probably [ __ ] hot dude
don't touch it
remember grow lights are hot when
they're turned on also
blowers and extraction fans will eat
your [ __ ] fingers don't
think that you're just gonna move it or
adjust it a blower something like that
turn it off unplug it if you have to
adjust the ducting if you're gonna move
an extraction fan
i've cut my finger really badly on a
squirrel cage fan i'm showing it to the
camera i don't know if you can see that
scar on camera
i almost took the tip of that finger off
that is why it is not shaped
appropriately
i messed myself up really badly on a
blower i was
doing work on a ceiling area of a grow
and the ceiling one of the supports came
in and the blower kind of turned and my
finger went right into the opening of
the blower
and the tip of it is gone somewhere it
shred into little pieces
there were 13 stitches in my finger it
hurts right now just thinking about it
be [ __ ] careful those blowers are
dangerous uh where else are we fans
there are fans everywhere in grow rooms
in personal grows and commercial grows
those fans can be extremely dangerous
i've got dreadlocks to my knees
if you're in a grow room tie up your
dreadlocks if you've got a ponytail
stick it in your shirt those fans will
cause you problems
also in a commercial grow environment we
are required to have a
badge on us at all times that is visible
it's got to be
uh above the waist and below the neck
and it's got to be visible by the camera
so that if anybody looks at the camera
they can say that guy belongs there he's
got a badge
many of us wear the badge on a lanyard
around our necks
in colorado it is required that that
lanyard be a breakaway lanyard which
means in the middle of it it's got a
little section
that if i pull hard enough it just
breaks it doesn't have the potential or
the opportunity to wrap around my neck
and strangle me
if it becomes tied in a fan or a blower
so if you're wearing a lanyard in a grow
and you've got fans around you don't get
that lanyard caught in something and get
yourself [ __ ] hung
also if you're working with a trim
machine or a trim reaper or something
that's in front of you
don't lean over and stick your lanyard
into the trim machine
i've seen it done i've seen the lanyard
get stuck in the wood chipper the trim
machine
i've seen it put through everything pay
attention to your lanyard i recommend
the little armband they sell
armband you can put your badge in there
put it on your arm it's not dangling off
of you it's not going to end up
in the nutrients it's not going to end
up in the plants and the trimmer it's
not going to end up getting you in
trouble it's not going to get stuck in a
fan
so the fans are dangerous you guys if
you got dreadlocks long hair
ponytails keep that [ __ ] tucked away
don't get them
tied up in a fan i think my dreads would
ruin a fan honestly if it
grabbed one of these i probably just
inked the fan off the wall i'm gonna win
i don't know what kind of situation
you've got be careful i want to keep
moving
um where are we how do i fit this one in
here
people may not be prepared for this
safety uh grow room safety
it's going to stink part of being safe
is not being detected by the police
so legal safety it's going to stink be
prepared
have carbon filtration have an excuse if
somebody says it smells like skunks know
what you're gonna say have a story
also what are you gonna do if somebody
knocks on the door and wants to talk
about it
they're not allowed in your home without
a warrant lock the door
close the door behind you stand on the
front porch and talk to law enforcement
outside of your home and when they say
can we go in say
funny story i'm locked out and then you
leave and they leave too nobody goes in
your home
know what you're gonna do if you're
approached by law enforcement have a
plan
practice don't get too nervous also when
harvest time comes it is going to stink
more than it does during the grow be
prepared for that
harvest is stinky also know where you're
going to securely
store and say store and save and dry and
cure your harvest
sorry about the new tongue i'll get
caught up but it is going to stink a lot
now let's talk about uh personal safety
one of the main
ways to keep yourself safe when it comes
to growing is to shut
the [ __ ] up don't tell anybody that
doesn't need to know
i know it's a lot of fun talking about
growing i am in a completely legal
environment i grow commercially it is my
job
i pay taxes on it i get a paycheck for
it that's what i do
i can talk about it i don't know where
you are i don't know who your friends
are
i don't know who your ex-girlfriend is i
don't know who your ex-girlfriend's new
boyfriend is
so shut the [ __ ] up about your grow and
don't tell people unless it needs to be
known
that is personal safety keep your grow
and yourself safe
don't tell people if they don't need to
know they don't need to know don't bring
people into the grow nobody else needs
to be there unless they're helping you
and you're paying them nobody else needs
to be in that grow but you don't show it
off
don't flex take some pictures once the
product is harvested dried cured and
either smoked or removed from your area
post some pictures up to social media
and get some bragging rights there
but you don't need to bring people in
there and show you and that leads me
into
internet safety there are a lot of
things to talk about when it comes to
internet
safety not just uh the safety of the
internet are you revealing your identity
are you revealing your location in your
pictures are you showing that you're
allowed six plants but in your photos
you blatantly have 18
think about that type of internet safety
then think about even further
um security codes passwords is anybody
hacking you is anybody watching you
is your internet hurts let me try that
again is your internet search history
that was the word i wanted
is your internet search history going to
be a problem
if anybody wants to look at that so
think about internet
safety think about what you're posting
think about when you post it think about
what is in your photos
if i went outside to my front yard and
took a photo uh
facing a selfie facing away from my
house but you caught my neighbor's house
in the background
you could probably look at my neighbor's
address and drive around you know what
area i live in you may be able
to triangulate my location so be very
careful
with what you post on the internet also
if you've got kids
be very careful with the kids in the
house if you've got a grow room
make sure it is locked and the kids do
not have access to it
maybe you're one of those people who is
growing for a sick child maybe you're
one of the people who allows
a child to help you in the grow make
sure that that child
does not have access to the grow without
your supervision
also there are many legalities involving
children
and your growth so be careful that takes
me back to be careful what you post
if it's not legal for that child to be
in your grow do not post a picture of
that child in your grow
think about what you're posting be safe
keep the kids out of the grow
keep them safe also be honest with the
children i think that's the best way to
teach them if they say what's going on
down there
say grow in medicine otherwise they
think there's [ __ ] aliens down there
and they really want to know
but if you tell them what's happening
and you're honest they might might let
you get away with it so
let's move our way into pets i don't
like seeing
cats and dogs in the grow room i know a
lot of people like to take their animals
in there they're inclusive
but i feel that pets are vectors of
problems they carry they're probably
carrying spider mites or some sort of
bug that i don't want
or a dander or a mold or some [ __ ] that
i don't want they're out there running
around they're down there low by the
ground they play in the bushes they do
all that [ __ ]
i don't want that in my grow i keep the
pets out of the grove that is me
personally
that's my recommendation you do what
makes you happy but just know that is a
potential
carrier for problems also
keep your pets safe if they do come in
the grow
like i said earlier we're applying
pesticides we're using nutrients
dogs and cats especially dogs just like
to eat random [ __ ] and lick it anything
some of those nutrients and pesticides
could be very problematic for a little
dog even for a big dog
if a dog ate a bottle of nutrients they
would get sick if a dog
ate a bottle of pesticides it would get
sick keep that in mind
for your pets let's love our pets the
best we can and keep them safe as well
so grow room safety keep the pets and
the kids out of there and keep them safe
now another thing i want to talk about
is environmental impact
um not only do we need to think about
being safe we need to think about what
we're doing
to the earth to the world are you
causing a problem
are you going to do something that's
irreversible the earth is not yours that
little square patch that you own
that's yours but the rest of it is
everybody else's and you only own the
ground you don't own all the air
and all the bugs they tried to fly in
and out of there you don't own the life
that evolves around that earth around
that patch of land so
be mindful of your environmental impact
on
your grow if you're growing indoors or
outdoors there are things to think about
as a bottled nutrient user i get a lot
of bottles i try to find places to
recycle but they don't want to recycle
nutrient bottles in many locations
so think about that sort of stuff we
need to get away from bottles buy bigger
bottles if you can
don't buy a bunch of quartz buy the big
five gallon if you can do that
think about ways to increase uh your or
decrease
your carbon footprint something to think
about
i'm talking about trash we throw a lot
of [ __ ] away when you throw out your
trash
is it possible that anybody can discover
you're a grower through your trash
looking in the trash do they find
nutrient bottles are they finding
pesticide bottles are they finding old
scrap
leaf are they finding old stems be
careful with your trash once that goes
out onto the curb
that is public property the cops can go
through it your neighbors can go through
it the hobos are probably going to go
through it
think about what they're going to find
do you need to get rid of your trash
more carefully
i want to keep moving i've got a really
long list of stuff i want to cover and i
feel like i'm already quite a ways into
this podcast
so um always grow with the appropriate
equipment i see a lot of people building
makeshift grows i understand you don't
have a unlimited budget
and you've got to work with what you've
got but some of that [ __ ] gets
dangerous the most dangerous things i
see
is inappropriate electric run your
electricity
appropriately use the proper electric
fixtures i see people just doing random
crazy [ __ ] they have
people who are nowhere near certified
electricians going in and just running
wires and doing weird [ __ ]
that is a potential hazard that could
burn down your house if you're sharing a
building that can burn down that
building
please don't be that person who ruined
the neighborhood
because you had some one of your friends
just run some wire so we could run more
lights
don't do that if you're going to have
electrical upgrades make sure it is done
by a
what are they a certified registered
master electrician i don't know the uh
the real word a real electrician
somebody who's licensed and bonded
somebody that if they cause a problem
you can call them say it's your fault
and you [ __ ] this up you're supposed to
have a license not just one of your bros
because i think it's this wire and this
wire have it done professionally
proper electric is very important we're
running a lot of power we can cause a
lot of problems
uh to go with that i say always have a
smoke alarm a smoke detector in the grow
room
i highly recommend that also think about
what you're gonna do if that goes off
because that will bring attention
so you need to have a fire extinguisher
either the handheld type that is big
enough for your space
if you've got like five or six lights
you need a bigger fire extinguisher if
you've only got one light
you may be okay with the smaller fire
extinguisher think about the potential
problem you're going to have to deal
with and have the equipment
prepared to combat that issue they do
make a fire extinguisher that hangs
from the ceiling in a grow room and if
it reaches a certain temperature
it basically ruptures and it drops a
fire retardant dust all over the grow
it will destroy your garden but it will
put out the fire
and rescue the rest of your house so if
that is an option i highly recommend
that if you've got higher ceilings
if you've got enough space and you can
afford it i like the uh
fire extinguisher that hangs from the
ceiling it's a big red ball
and if it gets too hot it simply
explodes boom and then this
white powdery dust comes out and it
falls all over the room and it basically
extinguishes the fire that way
so a fire extinguisher is something i
highly recommend
to go with your smoke detector we want
to catch that smoke
blast out the fire and not have any
problems keep the fire extinguisher
on the outside of the grow room door if
you do hear that smoke alarm going off
you're going to touch the door see how
hot it is
if it's really hot you may just want to
[ __ ] run if it's kind of warm
push that door open back up assess the
situation have that fire extinguisher in
your hand
get going start spraying if it's too bad
get the [ __ ] out of there you guys just
run
to get the good [ __ ] that you can get
the kids get the dog get the [ __ ] out of
there
but try to extinguish it aim at the base
also
understand how to use your fire
extinguisher make sure that it's fully
charged
understand you pull the pin you do this
you point here maybe practice
maybe if you're intimidated by the fire
extinguisher if you think it's going to
be scary
just grab the fire extinguisher and take
it out to the yard and just give it a
little spray see what kind of pressure
comes out of it
see how it jerks yeah it jumps around be
prepared i know at a lot of places
if you go work at a new warehouse or a
new facility they will actually train
you and how to use the fire extinguisher
so that if you do need it you're not in
full [ __ ] panic mode it's something
you've done before
so have a smoke alarm and have a fire
extinguisher something i've already
mentioned
is a door lock lock everything lock
everything
twice maybe lock everything a third time
just for safety we don't need anybody
not invited getting into our grows
also that comes back around to shut the
[ __ ] up don't tell anybody
if they don't know it's there they don't
know it's there
now we've got everything locked we've
got everything safe
the next step i think is cameras if you
can put up cameras near your grow
without being obvious that you're
watching your grow that is a great thing
to do because
now you know when intruders are coming
and you can also
check on the plants while you're away
you can just open up your phone and go
oh
that room looks good none of the plants
look super droopy the plants look happy
the reservoirs are full
i can see most of the things i need to
see i set up my camera store i can see
what i need to see
and we've got a little bit of
reassurance and security at the same
time
another thing i really like in the grow
for safety and for many other reasons
is something like a pl grow minder unit
or something similar
this will tell me if the room gets too
hot or too cold while i'm away
if i if i reach a certain condition in
my grow room
my phone will beep and tell me hey you
need to check this out i open up the app
on my phone
i look at the peel grow minder uh
information and it'll say hey it's 90
degrees in here
i'll go i need to solve that problem
then i open up the camera look at the
camera and go
oh the plants definitely look hot and i
can see that that fan over there isn't
running or i can see that that air
conditioner you can't see the air
conditioner cut off but you get my point
i can open up the minder unit then i can
look on camera try to identify the
problem if i need to get to the grow i
can get over there and fix it
so cameras and a pl minder unit together
are invaluable you can see what's going
on and then you get a warning on your
phone if anything is out of the
parameters would you expect it to be
another thing i like is a high heat
shutdown
i've got a device on my grow lights so
all of my grow lights plug into one unit
then that unit plugs into
the 240 uh the dryer looking plug before
that dryer plug
i have got a high heat shutdown it plugs
into the dryer plug
then my light box plugs into that and
that has a wire that goes up to the very
center of the room
if that room reaches a hundred and ten
degrees uh everything turns off it just
cuts the power
to that whole box all of my lights turn
off it's not gonna heat up anymore
that will save me from roasting the
entire room and it's adjustable i can
change it from 90 to 110 as the range
i think i just left it at 110 when i
bought it so i've got a high
heat shut down to where if the room gets
too hot the lights just shut right off
i did not plug the air conditioner into
that same receptacle
so the air conditioner will continue to
run if it was running
i'm assuming that since it's 110 degrees
in there that air conditioner [ __ ] up
i need to go check it out my pl girl
minder unit sent me a message
i got to open it up and look and say
it's 100 degrees in there i need to go
figure this out
but that high heat shutdown will shut it
down while i'm in the car
running to the grow trying to get there
before the plants melt
um i mentioned this before another thing
we need is plenty of carbon filters we
need to control the aroma and odors of
our grows
if you're in a non-legal state that
aroma will be enough to get you in
trouble
have enough carbon filtration have a
carbon filter in the grow
if you're extracting air make sure that
that air is filtered something you can
do is just set up a carbon filter and a
blower and just have it blow
in the room you're just filtering the
air taking out the aroma it's also
sucking up any dust
anything that might be floating around
just keeping the air clean
while sucking out some aroma keeping you
a little bit safe also uh right by the
front door
and any entrances and exits of your
house maybe you have a little air
freshener i like to keep the cans
of uh i can't it's called it's a can of
ozone can't think of what it's called
right on a gel that is what it's called
i keep the jars of ona gel near the
doors
it's just a jar with the lid you can
unscrew the lid i don't unscrew the lid
i honestly get a drill and i drill six
or eight holes in the top of the lid it
keeps my own a gel
uh the gel has to stay moist once it
dries it stops making
air aroma so just drill holes in there
keep the owner gel jar
i just put it behind a picture right by
the door so when you come in the house
you look at the picture of my daughter
your daughter is beautiful you don't
even know there's a [ __ ] own a jar
hidden behind there
you smell it you go it smells great in
your house and i'm like i see my kid
you smell my aroma you think i'm a good
person you don't even know there's a
bunch of [ __ ] plants in the house it
works really well so
cover your aroma ona gels uh maybe some
ozium spray
don't use the thing that sprays every
[ __ ] 20 minutes that's obvious that
you're hiding something
but carbon filters owner gels those will
help you out
another thing i see people make mistakes
is timers they cannot handle
the load which we are assigning to these
timers we plug the timer into the wall
then we plug a thousand watt light into
that timer sometimes we plug 2000 watt
lights into that timer
and we expect that timer to turn off and
on every day as it's supposed to do but
what we didn't think about
is we're running 2 000 watt lights on
this one shitty timer and it's going to
melt
it may not have the capacity so make
sure that the timers you buy
are strong enough to run the amount of
electricity you are pushing through them
electricity can be very dangerous i've
talked about this recently in this
episode
let's not be the person burning down the
house by drawing too much electricity
through one receptacle
if you feel like your equipment if the
plug-in at the wall is getting hot
if your timer is getting hot if your
extension cord is getting hot
it's not thick enough strong enough you
need a bigger more powerful heavier duty
timer and extension cord i don't like
extension cords that's going to be the
next one
no shitty extension cords it's got to be
the big
thick insulated extension cord or get
the [ __ ] out if you bring in that little
the one that you're going to use to plug
in the printer or the extension cord for
your phone
don't put that in my grow no not
qualified all of the extension cords
have to be
quality extension cords the good thick
kind and always
like we talked about earlier keep your
electricity up
off the ground don't have a bunch of
cords on the ground don't have a bunch
of extension cords down on the floor
keep your electricity up high or if
there is water on the floor you don't
have any interaction between the
electric
and the water the water is going to go
straight to the floor keep that
electricity up high
three feet off the ground or higher is
ideal so no shitty extension cords and
be very
careful with your cords your cables
think about be mindful don't trip over
them don't get them wet
don't have them in places where they're
going to cause problems set yourself up
for success
another thing you really need to think
about and have prepared in a grow
is a first aid kit i don't want you to
have to use it but i hope that it is
there
i talked earlier about a friend getting
ph down on his eye
wiped around his finger wiped his eye ph
down in his eye
now he's got a call 9-1-1 that is a
terrible situation
he had to walk up the grove and scramble
up to the top of the stairs and get
outside of his house before anybody
showed up so he didn't get himself in
trouble
have a first aid kit on hand is what i'm
getting at if something does go wrong
you would much rather have a first aid
kit to take care of yourself then have
to scramble around and find all the [ __ ]
to handle yourself
if you cut yourself you're gonna need
some gauze you may need some band-aids
you may need some peroxide to clean
yourself
out maybe a couple of butterfly
band-aids think about that sort of stuff
maybe a little bit of burn cream maybe
you're just a
a clumsy person maybe you were always
hurting yourself
know what you do to yourself we know as
guys i know that i like to cut my
fingers a lot doing dumb [ __ ] trying to
pry something open
these regions of our hands they get cut
up a lot be prepared for that [ __ ]
have some band-aids have something to
clean that have some of those
butterflies around
multiple sizes of band-aids also eye
wash
many people overlook eye wash you can
buy a bottle of eye wash
from um uline is the place where we get
them
get the bottles of eye wash and if you
do get a pesticide in your eye if you
get something in your eyes
grab that bottle it's got a little spout
on it all you got to do is take off the
cap and squeeze it right into your eyes
it will rinse your eyes out help you out
quite a bit then you can get more help
but
have that eye wash around in a
commercial environment we're required to
have an eye wash
uh within i don't remember the exact
amount of feet right now i shouldn't
admit that i have to read the rules
again
but most of the time if you're applying
a pesticide you need eye wash within
reach
so we tell the guys to carry a bottle of
water or the little eye wash bottle on
their person
while applying a pesticide so that if
you [ __ ] up if the fan blows the
pesticide into your eyes you can just
reach into your pocket
rinse your eyes off right there you
don't have to go too far because you are
blinded
with [ __ ] in your eye you may not be
able to find your way out of the grow
room
so have eyewash available also
i talked about my friend who had to use
siri i'm making sure siri doesn't fire
up again
it did turn her off i have a friend who
had to use siri
to call 9-1-1 to get himself medical
help when he got ph
down in his eye here's a better option
have an emergency
contact plan who are you going to call
if something goes wrong in your grow i
know who i'm going to call
so i put that person in my phone and
i've got their name
in my phone where all i have to do is
say hey call this person
and siri will dial that person's number
i don't have to use my fingers i don't
have to use my site
i can do it just with my voice if i
unlock my phone with my thumb
so have some sort of a plan if [ __ ] does
go wrong
who you going to call the ghostbusters
aren't going to be there to help you
with your grow
have an emergency contact in mind have
their phone number planned in your phone
programmed into your phone
also what's your excuse if you got to go
to the doctor if you got to go to the
hospital because you cut yourself in the
grow room
or because you got something in your eye
what is your excuse
a lot of us can't go to the hospital and
say i was growing weed and i cut myself
they're going to go sweet we're sending
the [ __ ] cops to your house right now
and we're going to keep you here while
they're over there and then as soon as
you get done we're gonna arrest you
have a plan have an alibi have an excuse
know what you're gonna say
then here's the worst part that you can
think of but it's the last thing on my
list
how about some bail money and a lawyer
on retainer
if you're getting into the grow game and
you've got a couple of harvests under
your belt
you're starting to make a name for
yourself and this is something you're
gonna do
you need a lawyer and you need bail
money have that bail money
at your lawyer's office so where
anything goes wrong you call your lawyer
and he goes dory i got you he's already
on retainer you've paid him a little bit
of money you pay him every couple of
months just to keep him on your side
he's got that money in his safe then
when [ __ ] goes wrong he just drives
right over pays your bail money and gets
you moving it's not a long process have
that bail money and that lawyer on
retainer
then have your lawyer's phone number in
your phone
and also try to memorize it because when
you're handcuffed
and you're being booked you don't get
your phone to go through all those phone
numbers you're gonna need to know his
number
so remember your emergency contacts
phone number and remember your lawyer's
phone number
have that lawyer on retainer and have
some bail money set aside
i don't want you to have to use the
lawyer i don't want you to have to use
the fire extinguisher i don't want you
to have to use the first aid kit
but if we need them i want them to be
there it's always better to have the
[ __ ] you need on hand
and be prepared and set yourself up for
success than it is to try to figure [ __ ]
out while you're panicking and under
stress
alright ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls pimps and hoes friends and foes
smokers and growers clone cutters and
pollen chuckers i hope you found some
useful information in this episode
i really want you to grow the best
cannabis you can but i also want you to
be
as safe and healthy as possible while
doing so so please
take care of yourself pay attention and
be mindful in your grow
keep yourself and your grow partners
safe and healthy
ladies and gentlemen boys and girls if
you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
and you'd like to make a financial
contribution to the show you can do so
by visiting www.patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need will be
right there on the screen and again
i did include a link in the show notes
and the video description to make it
easy for all of my stoned
friends don't forget to visit our
sponsor at seedshearnow.com and use
coupon code gfyh10
get yourself some new seeds when you use
that coupon code you'll save 10
off that may cover the cost of shipping
if you're getting a lot of packs
that may cover even more packs don't
forget to check out the under 30 section
it seems here now because i did add
a strain to the under 30 section make
sure you check that out
if you've got any questions comments
corrections or concerns i would love to
hear from you
my email address is grow from your heart
hotmail.com
don't be shy send me your questions
ladies and gentlemen that is all i've
got for you for this episode i feel like
my throat is burning out my voice is
gone
perfectly timed thank you for hanging
out thank you for listening i'll be back
in a couple of days with fresh new
content
i want to give a giant shout out to
lovin in her eyes and until next time
take a fat dab and give your mom a hug
for me