yeah welcome back cannabis Community
it's time for episode number 56 of the
grow from your heart podcast your source
for Cannabis News education and
conversation if you're a new grower if
you're a PR grower if you're a new
smoker or a veteran Dabber if you're a
cannabis activist or if you're just
someone who's curious about the current
state of cannabis this my friends is the
podcast for you I'm your host Rost Jeff
thanks again for joining me as always
before we get started I have to send a
big huge thank you shout out to C and
Cat from the Mystic Roots band thanks a
lot for letting me use your music
joining me today again is one of our
heroes welcome back dude we got King
Cola to the left how are you bro good
man thanks for having me oh dude thanks
for coming we're excited about this uh
Sean is going to drop some knowledge on
you guys today that is going to [ __ ] up
your whole thought process on
growing yeah so uh I'm here to to give
out some information you can take it or
leave it I'm not turn just a little that
mic has uh impotency problems it likes
to droop after a while yeah so uh I'm
not my word is not law by any means but
uh this is just my how I grow this is uh
what I have discovered through my
personal uh studies but I just want to
say stop using molasses in your te's um
and yeah I mean completely and the main
reason is is a lot of people are using
molasses on a regular basis typically
when you ask somebody what they're using
in your compost tea and the same for me
um I think probably on the first episode
I probably even recommended certain
rates to use molasses at I think so and
uh you know so I mean you just this is
an evolved industry Everything Changes
we learn as we go but uh so I cut I
heard a while ago basically you need to
quit using somebody told me you need to
quit using molasses I said why they were
you know I'll get back to you and I
never heard from them again but it stuck
in my head so I quit using molasses just
cut it out and uh I didn't see a
difference you know what I mean it's not
like things quit working so it's not
acting like the bud hardener and the
sweetener like we think it is maybe yeah
you know I didn't I didn't see it so uh
I'm doing my thing and then I get back
in touch with this person and we kind of
discuss a little more
and you know a a lot of people like I
was saying for a basic compost tea what
I used to recommend and what a lot of
people are using are earthworm castings
or Alaskan humus or some sort of humic
acid they're using molasses and then
they're using like a kelp meal or
something well the reason that you use
that masses in the tea is actually not
for the reason that you had mentioned
earlier when you use Excuse me when you
use the molasses in a tea it's not for
not so much as a bud hardener for the
you know plant it's not so much a
carbohydrate for the plant as it is a
food source for the microbes in the tea
right in our te's okay and the thing
with molasses is it's a simple
carbohydrate and simple carbohydrates
feed simple organisms and that's the
simplest way to say it so molasses is an
extremely strong bacteria food uh you've
probably heard before that marijuana is
a fungal dominant plant they like fungal
dominant teas especially in flow okay uh
so by using molasses you're going to be
encouraging uh bacterial growth
well the Molasses not only feeds the
bacteria but it feeds it in an enormous
rate bacteria is naturally occurring
it's everywhere it's already in the soil
it's on our skin it's everywhere and in
between so it's already going to be
there in your tea it's going to be in
your water it's going to be in your soil
you know probably some of it's already
going to be in
molasses
so there's plenty of bacteria out there
as you add this molasses you start to
feed this bacteria and the bacteria
starts to eat the food and they start to
digest and what happens is the growth of
the bacteria happens too fast and the
organisms uh will actually use up all of
the available food and oxygen resources
so you actually drop the dissolved
oxygen levels in your tea so putting
molasses in your AAC te will take out
one of those A's it will make it go
anerobic and you will no longer be
having an air rated compost tea despite
you having bubblers running um you'll
still you're still going to take out the
oxygen you lower the dissolved oxygen
levels then you're just harvesting
anerobic bacteria basically killing off
everything we're working to create
exactly by adding the thing that we
thought was fueling our fire exactly by
adding molasses you're just taking out
everything that you just put all of your
money and time into you're just growing
the bacteria at a phenomenal rate
they're out competing everything else
and that's eventually what you put on
your plant I just Googled fungal
dominance um we can do an entire episode
on that just by what I'm reading yes you
guys are going to have to go if you want
to catch up Google fungal dominance I
can't even begin to explain it there is
so much going on in fungal dominance wow
that'll change your thinking but right
there yeah yeah definitely so uh with
the t's like I was saying it so when you
add the Molasses it can drop the
dissolved oxygen levels for anybody
who's listening who wants to know
specifically above eight parts per
million of dissolved oxygen is where you
want your teas that's when you're
Brewing aerobic organisms between
between six parts per million and E
parts per million you are facilitating
anerobic zones these organisms out
compete the aerobic organisms at a rate
of 2 to one these facilitate anerobic
zones uh this is where some really nasty
things live uh these things are in your
compost you are if like these bad
organisms are in your compost such as
you know really anerobic or eoli or
these other things just
nasties uh they're going to multiply at
an alarming rate once you start you know
creating this anerobic environment and
if you use that as a foler spray You'
just sprayed eoli under your plants
right yeah and that's the thing is they
actually like when you your tee starts
to do that the organisms that produce
acids that kill Anor robic organisms and
high enough qualities these acids can
stress and kill your
plant you know in no growing environment
anywhere is there a shortage of
bacteria so uh there's no need to just
feed more of them and stress your plants
out and uh there's other options instead
of molasses so right off the bat just
cut it out so if you want to do a te
what I would recommend would be uh
actually here one second but yeah so if
you're going to start a te uh I would
just go with worm
castings I would go with
uh Kel
meal and that's just about about it
castings and Kel meal yeah I'm sorry I'm
trying to I've got everything right now
so yeah there you go he's got a he's got
a whole computer in front of him me guys
so yeah I I tried to come prepared he
came well prepared I kind of peaked at
his notes a minute ago he's got a lot of
info yeah so we've got uh so basically
for for a really basic compost tea I'm
going to roll with Dr Elaine Ingram's
compost tea so her te's are basically
compost or you know worm castings or
whatever you can
Source uh Kel meal and then
you can add in uh instead of molasses
you can add in a humic source so you can
add in like a humic acid derived from
Pete like a dragonfly Earth medicine's
brilliant black uh there's a lot what I
would recommend actually yeah there's a
lot of different options out there but
you can add in a humic acid or or in
that place you could add in a fish Hydro
slate so for your base teas every time I
would just go with worm castings and
water outside that you can add in kelp
meal or alphalpha meal or anything like
that specific to your stage uh your
plant stage in life and then if you want
to start adding foods for the fungi
basically if you're in veg fish Hydro
slate so for vegetative growth instead
of using molasses replace it with fish
Hydro slate now fish Hydro slate it can
it can go the same way as massis it can
turn your tea anerobic really fast and I
know you're probably thinking anerobic
well you know you I personally talk
about anerobic te's and bkash and all of
these things which is you know they're
actually anob fermentations and anic
anerobic compost that's completely
different that's because we want
anerobic environments we don't want
anerobic bacteria in our aerobic teas
okay you know so they're separate but
equal you know yeah we're making a tea
and feeding that to our exactly you
don't yeah you know so when you're
fermenting don't let o get into it and
when you're ating Don't Let It Go
stagnant you know down
rubic so as far as uh food for your teas
uh like I was saying if you need to
improve your fungal count uh which
everybody wants to everybody wants
fungal dominant teas you can add uh
steel cut oat brand or steel cut oats uh
brand prowder shrimp shells I mean
there's any sort of uh really any sort
of like high protein and we can just
pick that up at the health food store
right you can pick all of that up at the
health food store actually there's a lot
of like uh I've seen a lot of stuff on
people or people are starting to consume
like fish hydr slate and stuff which I
don't know if I'm there yet but uh I
mean I wouldn't be surprised if you can
pick that up at the health food store
soon eventually
right but uh yeah so you're just
molasses I mean take it how you want it
you know take it or leave it
I recommend cutting it out I think uh
I've learned from very reable sources
and you know they're these aren't people
just you know
talking you know [ __ ] these are real
scientists these guys are sitting there
in front of their microscopes and
they're straining their minds and their
eyes so we don't have to no I don't
think you need to uh try to give
yourself any sort of credit or your
sources you've been on here enough and I
think people have realized that you are
definitely not full of [ __ ] think you've
earned your credit here I'm going to
give it to you well thank you we respect
your opinion I respect your opinion well
thank you I've been at this for years
and you teach me stuff every time you
come well I really appreciate it and uh
but yeah so I mean just cut the cut the
molasses out of your te's I used to use
it every [ __ ] day I
mean my last batch of tea and you know
what I didn't see much of a difference
uh I used I used used to use your
recommendation or the rev's
recommendation of molasses in my tea and
I made a tea just a few days ago with
some uh Bash bucket leech in there and I
actually got way more foam without the
Molasses on that bucket than I've ever
made that's the best I've ever made was
my most reent without the Molasses yeah
I mean and the plants loved it you're
going to get way better results using uh
beneficial microorganisms using things
like a cold processed fish Hydro slate
like the Browns fish Hydro slate you
grab from Rocky Mount worm company uh or
you can make your own fish Hydro slate
but uh those food sources work way
better they're way more natural natur um
it's just like us if we eat natural food
our body absorbs it much more naturally
instead of trying to go to McDonald's or
whatever exctly pull out the nutrients
and poop out the crap instead you're
able to absorb what you're eating it's
like should be it's like eating a
Pop-Tart or an apple yeah I mean it's
you know how does your body run off of
it but uh yeah the so for teas just keep
it simpler the better you know just run
your castings run you know your kelp if
you want to add a food source you can I
like I really like fish Hydra slate
during veg you see tremendous vegetative
growth and then that's how you really
step away from bottled nutrients you
know that way if you are using bottled
nutrients the only one you're using is
the fish product uh what are we using
sorry to cut you off what are we using
to feed the tea uh In Bloom you keep
saying fish hydros slate and V okay so
for if you're going to feed your tea and
Bloom uh uh soft rock phosphate there we
go yeah uh that's a lot of your ogt so
sofro phosphate but that goes right back
into you need to know what you're using
how much you're using where you're
sourcing it from if you go and you dump
astronomical amount of softrock
phosphate on your plant you're going to
you know like I said that goes right
back to you can be organic and you can
be worse than all your synthetic buddies
out there right I actually uh I think I
overused some ogt because I wasn't I was
thinking oh it's ogt let's [ __ ] it up so
I fed it instead of every two weeks I
was doing it every week because I wasn't
paying attention ention and I think the
plants sped up too much like you said
cuz they were burn they were showing
nitrogen deficiencies in like week five
and I think they're just going too fast
that's more from like the the trod Derma
like strains that they have in there but
he has soft rock phosphate also in there
which works as a food for the microbes
and it's a fungal food but you can also
get your phosphates obviously from
introducing that into the tea so it's a
great that's a great source of uh if you
need a bloom tea for SE theoretically
you should have all of that am minuted
in your soil um and it'll just kind of
take up what it wants um which kind of
rolls into what we were originally that
was our um our original idea today was
to talk about building a little bit of
soil so I believe you I like your guys
the Molasses is unnecessary those are
old school farmer tricks we were taught
that uh try it yourself make a do a test
run set one set of plants on one side of
the room one set on the other add
molasses to one set of tea or however
you're feeding add M don't add molasses
to the other see the difference for
yourself it's uh you're not going to see
enough difference to like break the bank
or anything so give it a try yeah and I
mean keep your molasses around I use it
for plenty of stuff uh
[Music]
fpjsangprobinsyano but don't use it for
the teas food source and don't use it
every time don't use it for your teas
food source guys we're over we're like
over amping the tea basically we're
making hyper little tea yeah it's all
back into little kids just like sugar
yeah they're out competing everybody
yeah all right so yeah for soil mixes uh
I really didn't even know where to start
for this one I know that everybody has
their own mix
everybody has their way of doing things
there's super soils and there's
layers and there's no till there's a
million ways to do everything so I just
I figured maybe the best way to go about
it would be to kind of just discuss uh
you know what what they are so uh okay
that sounds great perect so um a super
soil uh super soils are a term for a
nutrient charged soil uh subcool is the
father of super soils yeah subol made it
really famous and basically the idea is
you're going to create this nutrient
Rich mixture of soil and you're going to
layer the bottom of your pot with it and
then you're going to plant your plant
actually into a uh less hot medium like
so you would use a bag soil you so you
would take your five gallon container
and you'd fill the bottom so many inches
up with your super soil mix and then add
in your bag soil and then actually
transplant your plant into it
theoretically you water water your plant
The Roots grow through the bag soil
medium into the subra soil okay and then
you never have to fertilize your plant
you can just always feed up water you
know every time everything's already
mixed everything's already mixed in with
the soil um so that's one method of uh
mixing uh another method
for a lot of people is uh just like a
complete through and through mix so like
a dragon fire earth medicine just does a
really really awesome mix where they do
it's similar to the super soil but it's
actually Incorporated throughout the
entire mix so you don't like stir the
whole thing exactly so there is no like
layering and you don't pat it with you
know other soil what they'll do is they
they make their soil and then they do
what's a term called cooking which is
just composting so they let their soil
sit for a couple of weeks or a month you
know the longer the better and by doing
that you can really encourage natural
processes and if you go to dragonfly
Earth medicine feed they've got some
really cool things about how they'll you
know you know the soil that's cooking
they'll treat with bkash and lactic acid
bacteria and they pour all their excess
compost teas on it and you can do these
things too while your soil Cooks but uh
they do a like really it's more of a
Botanical mixture uh um they use like a
kelp meal Alfalfa nettle um you can go
to their websit so their Feats and kind
of find out I don't want to give away
all there yeah go check them but they've
got some check out dragonfly Earth
medicine we'll get them on the show one
day uh they're in Canada they said they
were going to come here and then they
had to go back to Canada or Washington
they're right by Canada so they had to
skip out on the show the Pacific
Northwest they're just holding it down
up there actually they're in uh Europe
right now or yeah they went to like
Prague or they went all over the IST
they're going everywhere guys when they
come back they're going to do an
interview with me and they're going to
tell me about all the things they've
seen around the world so that'll be
great yeah but they've been prot uh
perfecting the soil mix for a while and
you know I mentioned them cuz they do
like a completely Botanical base you
know everything's plant-based with their
mixes I know a lot of other people are
traditionally doing especially like with
uh the Rev and some other people
moonshine man and there's a lot of other
mixes out there which are all uh bone
meal blood meal phosphates it's real
similar to subcools mix but but it's the
same idea that you mix it throughout the
whole batch and you let it cook for a
period of time and then you grow into it
and we got to get away from the blood
meal and the bone meal feather meal yeah
there's Alternatives I mean you know
bone
meal soft rock phosphate C free nettle
Yaro fishbone meal there's other options
blood meal uh which is your nitrogen
Source uh yeah there's I don't even need
to like get into there's so many other
nitrogens alfalfa
yeah there's there's so many other
nitrogen sources I don't even need to
cover that but uh I mean you definitely
Source where your products are coming
from uh me personally uh I go with a
very simple mix uh I
use typically I like to mix my own soil
base uh the best mixture I've ever used
personally was um it's a product called
Malibu compost it's a biodynamic compost
blend uh it's [ __ ] awesome it's only
available in California it's really hard
to get here I was fortunate enough to
come across a couple of bags and uh it
was probably some of the best product
they use but it's a compost it's not a
soil mix who's in California that can
send us a couple of bags of that
somebody hook me up please yeah we need
that Malibu compost I'll give you my PO
box number just hook me up yeah but it's
a biodynamic blend so they have like
Yaro and nettle and Dand lines and all
sorts of cool stuff mixed in there but
uh so I used uh so I used a compost and
then cut it in with peite I'm I'm sorry
not pear I use a compost and then I cut
it in with worm castings uh so I make my
own like Verma compost so I'll use the
yeah the Malibu compost Rocky Mount worm
castings and then I'll add in an airator
which is typically a lot of people use
perlite I don't like perlite so much so
I use uh diatomite because I've got a
huge bag of it I've had for like years
I'm still working through it but you can
use like pumis or lava rock I like to
recommend people use things that don't
go away as fast you know uh Pearl like
floats to the top and it grinds up
really fine and it just kind of goes
away to nothing but uh I always
recommend people to do like a 50% like
lava rock or pumis or diamite something
that doesn't break down as quick and
then do another 50 like the other half
do like a rice hole or buckwheat hole
okay or some you know more of a carbon
based airator all right uh so yeah we
put in our airator and then after your
compost and your airator then you make
the decision of whether or not you're
going to want to use cocoa core or Pete
Moss I like Pete Moss but I like the
environment too and so you kind of got
to that all comes from like one swamp in
Canada or something you know so you got
it like I said Organics it seems like
it's always awesome but it's not always
the best you just kind of got to pick
what you want I've actually found best
result I like a mixture of cocoa and pea
Moss there's something about the oils
that come from the cocoa fiber that the
plant really likes yeah I I've really
like a mix of uh I've been playing
around take a dab so you better keep
talking no you're good yeah I've been
playing around with different ratios uh
5050 75 25 uh of cocoa Pete Moss but I
kind of like a half and half mixture
with it and then uh outside of that
we'll go in and then add a Kel meal
crustation NE oyer shell powder glacio
raaus
gemson uh if we really want to get into
it we'll add you know biochar and bkash
and a lot of other natural farming
inputs but that's personally for like my
hom grow I can get a into it with that
stuff but you guys can too uh listen to
this episode hit pause and Rewind all
that stuff and listen back and make a
list and if you can't afford to buy a
bunch of [ __ ] buy the first two yeah and
then next time buy the buy three of them
and then you'll make a better soil every
every time and we'll start you'll start
seeing good you should get great results
right off the B if you if you think if
you if you play it back and you think
it's too overwhelming I tell you what I
I do work with the dispensaries a lot
you know I I I run a consultation
company so if any of you guys out there
know anybody who I hate the word I hate
saying I'm going do consultations but uh
if anybody out there wants to switch you
know any facilities that want to switch
we're all licensed over here at natural
farming and you know we've got our cards
we can go in and help your favorite grow
convert to Organics but I work with a
couple of different shops and they
always seem a little overwhelmed when I
come in there and I started running my
mouth about mixing soils and you're
going to get this and this and this and
you're going to mix it together and it's
overwhelming they like the when you can
walk in there and you can be like yep
buy a pallet of this and I want a pallet
of that so uh I've actually got a
mixture for everybody out there who
wants to go and just buy a pallet of
soil or you want to go buy B of promix
or some sunshine for so just go and grab
your uh Sunshine for your
promix I recommend cutting in worm
castings 10% for your microbial
Source uh then I would just add and
depending on what you're going with so
if you go with like a sunshine for
advanced they've got like a nutrient
starter pack which is I think a there's
some like minerals in there other things
like that yeah and uh that one's a
really good one to go with and then just
add in your worm castings kelp
meal neem uh neem cake and crustation M
or oyster shell powder just kind of
dependent on how you want to grow
personally okay but that's it that's
that's a good start right there and uh
I've I've tried them out like right now
if you go to the kingor cola feed on
Instagram you can look at the uh
there's pictures of worms just all over
the containers you know top soils moving
and that's actually all done in sunshine
4 with kelp neem crustation and oyster
shell powder nice uh really simple I me
I feel like I'm getting some of the best
results that I've ever had with this
super the between this mix and then the
mix I mentioned earlier with Malibu
compost are probably the two best
results I've gotten since I've started
okay um you know it's so Hard To Source
a solid like place to get compost so if
you can't do that and you can't make
your own
compost I mean there's no shame in going
and buying a bag of soil you know what I
mean like everybody I don't know I I you
can always start a Bashi bucket that's a
great way to make some over the past
three or four weeks I don't know how
long I've been talking about the bokashi
bucket but I see it turning into Funk
inside that bucket and I will have
that's a five gallon bucket essentially
I'll have five gallons of compost to add
to a whole bunch of dirt and then in a
month or two I will have my own amazing
compost pile started from that exactly
and I mean even like even buying soil
from the store using the nicest castings
that money can buy like a rocky M worm
castings and uh it's still crazy and
then after amending the St soil it's
amazing how cheap this stuff comes out
I'm not going to say the name of this
like shop that I'm working for but I
will say that they're running 48820
gallons and we priced them out at a120
per gallon of soil wow that's amazing so
suck on that one
synthetics there you go guys and that's
for a dispensaries so they have to rely
on quality products I'm going to do a
quick commercial I hate to sneak in a
commercial but I have to do them and
this is a great time uh because a lot of
what we're talking about the organic
portion of this portions I'm going to
try this commercial again the organic
portions of this this episode we're
sponsored by my friends at the Rocky
Mountain worm company visit the Rocky
Mountain worm company in Colorado
Springs for freshw worm castings African
nightcrawlers red wigglers and all of
your soil amendments the Rocky Mountain
worm company has dragonfly Earth
medicine products in stock right now
we've been talking about that a lot uh
they have the fish hydr slates there uh
they've got brilliant black humic from
dragonfly Earth medicine uh they have a
lot of the stuff we talked about you
grab right there at the Rocky Mountain
worm company so go in there that you can
actually get their products if you're
listening far away you can get their
products shipped to your door you get
the same worm casting Sean and I use in
our Gardens many of the same amendments
check out www. rockymountainmc
company.com or if you're in Colorado
Springs Denver or Pueblo drive to 411
Tana Street in Colorado Springs Colorado
and make sure you tell them you heard
about them on the grow from your heart
podcast that'd be really cool I'm going
do another two more quick ads just
because I have to get them done these
guys pay for this and I feel bad if I
don't do them I hate cutting off Sean
he's got so much good [ __ ] to say um of
course this podcast is brought to you by
our good friends at high gr indoor
growing supplies high gr indoor growing
supplies has two locations to serve
Colorado check out the Denver store uh
618 no Denver store 6271 Beach Street
the PUO location 618 East 4th Street in
beautiful Pueblo Colorado check out Hy
grow for competitive pricing and a great
selection of indoor grow supplies all
the stuff I'm not able to get at the
Rocky Mountain worm company I pick it
all up at high gr indoor growing
supplies my lights my bulbs my neoprene
for my cloner uh nutrients for my cloner
all that stuff comes from hyro you guys
so when you're shopping there tell them
you listen to The Grow from your heart
podcast you'll get commercial pricing
you'll save a few bucks on everything
you buy it really helps out it makes it
worth going there if they don't have
what you want let them know they will
order it for you they're sweet shout out
to burn shout out to Jesse and also
shout out to Lonna we had a Growers
meeting there last night big huge shout
out to everybody that showed up dude
that place was packed it was cloudy in
there that was a good ass time last at I
promise uh this podcast is brought to
you by Nature's green remedies.com if
you need some new beans new seeds some
high-grade genetics go to Natures green
remedies.com they've got Gage green
llata lab since City R dankness mile
high can Adventure the Cali Connection I
genetics and many more leading Brands uh
right now they have a coupon code Type
in coupon code it is spring 15 for 15%
off any order and free shipping at
Natures green remedies.com all right I
didn't want to interrupt the show but
those guys paid me money for that so um
what else you got on making your own
soil or do you want to talk about
something different um no I think that
that's a this is a good point to go back
to Hy gr uh oh I do want to mention
because I feel like we've been T I don't
want to snub your other people
oh we're talking about uh no I mean
because I was telling people to go and
grab soil mix you know go yeah I want to
we'll work with Jesse a little bit and
we'll try to get uh we'll call it a
Rocky Mount natural farming mix up there
for you at the store cuz I mean they
already carry in the soil they've
already got the castings up there
they've got gashi up there yeah um yeah
you talked to Jesse we can get you fixed
with the Rocky Mount natural farming mix
which is like I said it's I mean Pro mix
Sunshine 4 kelp crustation meeme get to
rocking we'll try to get hey guys at
hyro here's my idea I want you to set up
one little section just a shelf that we
can just walk right there and get this
stuff like it'll be the grow from your
heart uh Rocky Mountain worm castings
hyro indoor growing supplies little
bonus section and just go right there
there'll be some gr Kashi there same
thing up at the shop for you too that'd
be so awesome let's do this guys that's
my proposal to you guys I'd appreciate
it so go if you can't if you can't
Source compost and all of that jazz then
go to your local Hydro Store hydro and
uh grab you a bag soil get you some
basic amendments and the the trick is is
to figure out what works for you um I
don't like this like one size fits-all
idea of growing um because it doesn't
you know me and you probably water
completely differently I bet I bet
completely differently if I used your
soil mixing methods I would probably
Slaughter those plants I guarantee I'd
kill every single one of them um and
then you do the same thing in my style
does that mean that you're a better
grower than me or vice versa no it
doesn't exactly it's just a matter of
you've got to dial it in you know I
would recommend starting out with a
promix or a sunshine 4 uh once you get a
grow or two down with that and your
really basic soil amendments then all
Sunshine 4 and promix is is Pete Moss
and an airator and you know so Source
those products what my last run was done
in with Sunshine 4 promix yeah and you
know so yeah I think people get
overwhelmed when you start talking about
the conversion to Organics but if they
only knew how close they already were
you know so many synthetic Growers are
using Sunshine for and they're using
promix it's like well next time you do
that just add in a microbial Source like
earthworm castings add in some kelp meal
you know to help prevent against you
know fungus Nats and WF flies and spider
mites add in some neem cake or
crustation meal
uh yeah I mean easy stuff like that
right you're mixing soil anyway you
should be you shouldn't I don't think
you should open the bag and just start
pulling out of the bag you should dump
it into something kind of spread it out
like I was surprised to learn that
synthe like I said I've always grown
organically so I was I see a lot of the
commercial synthetic Growers and kind of
how they're doing stuff and I was really
surprised to see even they in the [ __ ]
out of their soil I mean they're growing
you know in promix synthetically they
and they're still running
and uh yeah I mean that was something we
were trying to talk to a friend about
last night is finding that balance
between the worm castings and the
advanced nutrients he's like can I do
this and we're trying to tell him gently
that H your Advanced is just going to
kill all that stuff bro throw away those
Advanced bottles yeah you know I if you
want to make the if you want to make the
switch then you need to not get Advanced
Nutrients go get something like a
general Organics or Roots Organics or
biob Biz or and even botanic air is not
as organic as they try to advertise far
from it yeah I mean even if you were to
go age old is a really old school
product so cheap and I know so many
people who crush it with age old I've
got a friend who grows nothing but iy
genetics with nothing but age-old and
it's so cheap I mean you want to talk
about low cost of production who cares
if I mean you know you'll yield good but
even if you didn't it's so [ __ ] cheap
you're only paying for power right yeah
that's that's the truth yeah that's the
beauty of Organics Organics I'm making
the switch and I love it I've really
seen a difference in my plants uh they
perform better they don't seem and I
dude I've been growing cannabis for a
long time and the plants always seemed
like they were thriving to me and now
that I'm using the Organics I can see
that I was missing something they look
they just look they're waxier they don't
have they have more uh the cuticles on
the leaves are thicker uh the stems are
more robust and I was feeding I've fed
all the commercial brands of nutrients
before and I'm definitely noticing a
difference with just basic and just
small jumps to Organics it's not even
anything major well then you tell me you
since you come from uh the synthetic
world is it easier I hear a lot of
people tell me it's more complicated but
I am not the most I mean I do a lot of
other stuff you know what I mean I'm I'm
not in my grow like I used to be and my
my plants are fine the way I think this
seems to make more sense to me than
mixing up bottles like a scientist and
I've read all of my bottles anyway so I
know what that's coming from like I know
that that's chicken [ __ ] and seabird
guano why don't I just use chicken [ __ ]
and seabird guano yeah like and I think
I didn't trust myself to make those
mixtures I thought I'd burn something or
whatever but there are so many guides
between you the Rev and every Forum on
the internet I can find the correct
mixture for everything the podcast now
this is a good reference your plants are
going to be way more forgiving to you
putting the guano on it than to you
putting a bottled nutrient that's got
guano in it on it yeah true very true
that's more concentrated and I can
definitely add too much of that way
easily exactly I don't even like using
guano I'm going to stay away from any
kind of [ __ ] in my PLS guano is actually
extremely unsustainable to harvest um
and then it's really bad for you to
breathe in but I know a lot of people
are die hard about it and uh personally
I think it like produces some really
awesome outdoor um Jesse will swear by
it for the outdoor Growers Jesse would
come chop us down right now for saying
bad things about his Jama gu yeah the
the Guana is pretty banging for outdoor
um not you know there's other options
but hey right to each his own and if
we're dissing your growing methods I'm
sorry we're not dissing it we are just
uh trying to encourage you to do more
sustainable healthier things do what you
want do what you want you're going to
get if you if you're okay with it go for
it I don't want I don't eat meat you
know what I mean I don't I don't eat GMO
Foods I I live my I have a certain
lifestyle that I try to live by and I
incorporate that all the way into the
medicine and the plants that I grow so
you know I don't force I hang out with
people who eat meat I hang out with
people who grow synthetics like it's no
big like to eat his own you don't have
to I
Really I get attacked a lot on Instagram
and a lot of these like other places
when I feel like when I try to put
information out there I feel like I get
met with a lot of resistance um but I'm
not telling PE I'm not trying to tell
people how to do things I'm just trying
to give it put information out there um
so please don't argue with me if you
like it take it in you know if you don't
unfollow me yeah follow someone else
there's there's plenty of other
Instagram pages to troll you know you
can hit those yeah you know but uh that
being said if you if you ever have
questions and you're serious and you
want to know something just uh you know
direct message me email me email Jeff um
yeah I got your back you we'll get the
you know we'll get you the knowledge you
need yeah we know we've got resources
for all kinds of knowledge it was funny
cuz we were at a Growers meeting last
night and Sean and I were both stumped
on something and people looked at us
like well what the [ __ ] if you guys
don't know then what is the answer
they're like sorry guys there there's
some [ __ ] we're not going to know I've
never seen that so I don't know give me
three days to research it we'll find out
but right now you might have to call Jim
forer yeah but I feel like people have
this can like I don't know they've got
this idea that we can just like look at
one picture on your phone or you're
going to send me one direct message and
I'm going to know what you fed him for
the past three weeks and we'll try yeah
we'll try but sometimes yeah that one
last night was a weird challenge I don't
know what it was it was powdery
something milish looking stuff
unfortunately that was a case of uh all
too it's all too familiar like I know
him personally I was actually working
with him on that before the meeting he
was introduced to me through a friend of
mine but uh yeah I thought it was
powdering Milo originally and then we
thought it was a pH problem and we
thought it was new lock and it it all
too familiar of a problem he actually
you know wasn't too familiar with
growing uh went to the local Hydro Store
not Hydro because if he you know if
Jesse would have helped him the guy
would have been killing it but he goes
to these horrible competitors here in
town and they set him up on what he
thinks is Coco uh they give him a Coco
nutrient uh he's running it turns out
it's Pete Moss oh man and you know so it
happens and and he's embarrassed and
it's not his fault no should happen
don't be embarrassed the guy awesome and
he's learned so much and he's plants are
still alive even after all of that you
know like I mean his we saw [ __ ] up
pictures of them but hey they're still
kicking you I mean if he makes it to
harvest that's what counts you know but
uh perseverance you know you just got to
keep stay committed to it don't if you
think that I grow beautiful plants every
time you're out of your mind oh man I
just don't picture I just don't put
pictures of the ugly ones on Instagram
there's plenty of ugly [ __ ] that I've
done I'll admit it one time I had and
this was years ago the first time it was
the first time I said I was in a new
house growing in a brand new B basement
in the middle of winter and I'd never
grown in there before and you got to
dial in a room but I had a white rhino
plant in a 7even gon pot that probably
weighed between 5 and 6 o and I went to
cut it down and I noticed powdery mildew
all up the one side that was near the
exterior wall corner so that wall was
colder than the whole rest of the room
and it got powdery mildew uh it was ugly
as [ __ ] my buddy Mike was there helping
me trim and I said hey Mike watch this
and I chopped the plant and usually he's
got a hand on it when I cut it so that
it doesn't Timber you know and I just
cut that son of a [ __ ] right to the
ground just Timber
and it hit the floor and he looked at me
like what the hell man and I was like
there's powdery mildew on it we're
throwing the whole plant away yeah it
happens I mean people ask me all the
time well how do you know if it works
that's how thousands and thousands of
dollars worth of just r d try try but if
you're going to try something crazy try
it on one plant if you have the option
don't do something ridic don't defoliate
I've been trying extreme defoliation on
one plant I won't do it to more than one
I I see a difference and I like it
honestly guys I doubted it in the the
beginning but I like it and I I learned
this the hard way um in every scientific
experiment for God's sake make sure you
have a
control and maybe take some notes
exactly we're high and we forget a lot
of [ __ ] yeah cuz you don't want to run a
six-month trial to the end of [ __ ] take
pictures if you can post them on
Instagram then it'll stay there stay
there so you have notes uh we we should
go for about five more minutes guys the
last episode was short and you listen to
every minute of it I can see the stats I
can tell how long you listen holy crap
thanks for listening to the whole thing
that was cool I appreciate that I hope
you like that solo episode it's hard to
do solo shows I feel like we covered do
the Molasses thing is going to be the
groundbreaker for the episode I like
that we covered soil pretty well do you
have any wrap-up notes for soil um keep
it simple there you go keep it simple
Stoner that's what I would say that's
all I got to say all right dude huge
thanks for coming no thanks for you came
hung out for like 45 minutes before we
even recorded which is awesome it's so
awesome people are like how long does it
take and I'm like allow two or three
hours when you get here because we like
to dab and [ __ ] it's fun uh today is
a special day you guys I might get tered
for this I had to save it to the end
happy birthday Jenny Kush we love you uh
today this episode's being recorded on
the on Jenny kush's birthday she' be
36 uh can't talk too much about it
because it'll make me cry happy birthday
Jenny we love you we miss you wish we
wish you were still here with us guys
Jenny uh Google Jenny Kush if you can
check her out you must support Jenny
Kush in the movement um green and
healthy cannabis and turpex love you
guys big shout out on the next episode I
was told that Spence and the garden of
Weeden are coming so hopefully we can
get Spence over here he says he's coming
tomorrow night to I hope he brings
Maddie Big Mike's invited this will be a
good time uh also I am going to record
with the grimy Gatsby and turpex next
week so we got an episode coming up with
those guys I'm taking the recording
equipment up to Colorado Springs going
to go hang out at the turpy boy house
and hit the mother ship what up guys I
cannot wait to come um I've been talking
about Golden Goat and lemon Jeffree
seeds they are right on schedule so I'm
saying like 85 80 days from now we
should have some new seeds ready um on
the next episode I'm going to talk to
not the I think the next episode I'm
going to talk to Spence about [ __ ]
rosin dude rosin have you guys seen
rosin what the [ __ ] bro big shout out to
soil grown and the rosin thing man I've
actually uh turned some food I had a
whole bunch of food grade uh cooking
grade or whatever you want to call it
from uh my last wash my last Harvest I
mean jar is full of it sitting in the
cupboard but yeah shout out to soil gr
dabing it man if you guys are on
Instagram check out @ soil grown on
Instagram that dude is killing with some
new things called rosin Tech uh if you
guys are going to try making rosin Tech
don't burn yourselves that's all I've
got to say cuz that's going to hurt and
we're going to start seeing we've seen
rosin Tech happened and then we've seen
people follow suit and now I'm waiting
for the rosin Tech Burns that's what's
going to be next uh also if you're on
Instagram check out dragonfly Earth
medicine uh holy [ __ ] you learn a lot of
great things something I want to talk
about more in the future is the bokashi
bucket it's something I'm experimenting
with right now great results cannot
believe I didn't do this earlier thanks
a lot to Rocky Mountain worm company and
Sean for hooking me up with that that's
really cool no no problem Game Changer
dude I added the the liquid that came
out of there to my worm tea and it's the
best worm tea I've ever made and I saw
results within 24 hours on my plants
yeah and then uh everybody out there
check out uh the Bashi bucket on
Instagram um they actually have their
own page uh they're a super awesome
group of guys down in Hawaii I've had
the pleasure cat that are super cool
I've had the pleasure of meeting them I
actually I gave one of the guys uh one
of their first dabs here in it was
actually at the emerald cup but I was
dabbing them out on some full
but uh shout out to the Bashi bucket
guys they're killing it and uh I you
pick up the buckets uh if you're Hydro
shop or you're if the the Rocky Mountain
worm company does have them but if
you're not near us you can get them uh
the bokashi uh bucket guys have a
website or also Whole Food sells them so
there's a Whole Foods in your area go
check out the chicks in the yoga pants
and Ugg boots and pick yourself up a
bokashi
bucket yeah um D let's wrap up the show
I don't think there's much left to say
tonight we've done a lot of work people
have probably took four pages of notes
cuz I took a page and a half myself I
hope you guys wrote all that down shout
out to hippie nurse I know you write
down a bunch of notes I hope you went
through seven or eight pages on this
episode she really listens that's
awesome I I I just talk so I'm just glad
somebody's listen you had Notes too man
so I'm Glad You Came prepared thanks
again for coming dude you have you're
changing growing for a lot of people uh
here's a part where I wrap up the show
you guys thanks again for listening to
another episode I'll be back um in 7
days if I do another uh news episode or
something I'll post it up in the midweek
I want to start doing that I just I get
overwhelmed with time
uh don't forget to check out our
sponsors the Rocky Mountain worm company
H gr indoor growing supplies and make
sure you visit Natures green
remedies.com for your seeds and use
coupon code spring5 for 15% off if you
guys are interested in sponsoring the
podcast or if you have a product you'd
like me to review send me an email it's
grow yourheart hotmail.com and I'll get
you all the information you need uh now
the show's over please go to iTunes go
to the iTunes Store search for grow from
your heart find the review section give
me a festar rating because we're badass
right after that type in a comment let
me know what you think of the show and I
will read your comments on a future
episode Stitcher keeps messing with the
way the comments are displayed and
handled so uh leave a comment wherever
you can there I will find it and I'll
read it if you have something to say and
you're not into social media you can
email me it's gr fromhart hotmail.com
don't forget the show is available on
iTunes Stitcher and every single episode
is archived on I genetics color.com my
papers got hash all over it's all sticky
that was great uh we added a donation
added a donation button to the page on
the website if you like the show and you
think it's worth a few bucks you can go
to the website IR gentics color.com
click on the grow from heart podcast tab
at the top right is a donation button
that goes directly to my Paypal account
I'll never charge you guys anything for
the podcast every episode will always be
free all this information that Shawn
brought today was free I should pay him
for it because it was so awesome I'm
going to give him a couple dabs but I'll
never charge you anything for the show
if you feel like this show was worth
something you can make a contribution it
it'll go to my Paypal account and I will
say thank you on a show if you'd like i'
truly appreciate it uh we're on all the
social media sites just search for us
whatever you use uh make sure you follow
us on Twitter it's GF YH podcast uh big
old shout out to my ninja Spence thanks
again for listening and until next time
take a big fat dab give your mom a hug
for me