all right here we go welcome back
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rasta jeff and it is time
for episode 560 of the grow from your
heart podcast if you're watching the
video
i'm sure you can see that my buddy white
mike is joining us for another episode
welcome to the show bro
thanks man what's up everybody hey mike
we usually start the show by talking
about what we're smoking so
let's jump right into what you're
smoking today diving right into it we've
got some uh
halo live batter from our friends over
at green dot labs
uh how's it how's it smell bro
wonderful it's a really cool little
spicy
it's just fantastic i like everything
about this
i've had some of the halo we've talked
about it on the show it is one of my
favorites
yeah it uh i don't know how would you
describe the flavor
well i was trying to give you room to
talk but it's uh
lemony gas yeah ah that's totally fair
dish soap and diesel a little bit yeah
a pleasant dish though my dish soap
isn't probably a real pleasant
description but it's got that
ah there's a sweetness a cilantro almost
that comes through
yeah cool glad you agree with that it's
nice and tasty really easy to work with
eventually they're going to call me or
they'll be like hey quit saying weird
[ __ ] about our descriptions you're
really throwing people off here
shout out to our friends at green dot
labs since you were kind enough to ask
i am smoking i took a dab of a beautiful
combo i was kind of a smart ass here
i've got some
bananas foster live batter and i've also
got
honey banana full spectrum extract uh i
wanted to go full banana on this bad
[ __ ]
so i took a little scoop i took it like
a three quarters of a normal size dab of
both of them so it was still bigger than
a normal dab
i took a big chunky dab it was a nice
blend of the batter and the full
spectrum extract and bro it was [ __ ]
bananas
ah that was a really nice dab uh the one
is described as
uh the flavor is banana and sugar and
oatmeal
and the other is frosted banana pastry
it was
like a banana runs candy or sometimes
when i get those uh cheap when i used to
eat those like cheap
i like a zingers or something i got a
lot of vanilla flavor it almost had that
sort of a sweet vanilla
banana pastry the frosting that cream
cheese frosting on the top
it had that in there as well really good
flavor so that was a nice combo i'm
really glad i decided to
to do that also it punched me right
in the face that combo was beautiful
something about banana terps
a banana og banana kush uh there's
something potent about that [ __ ] i don't
ever breed the banana stuff there are
people out there that are already doing
that
i like the banana terps they really work
well for me
nice yeah they're not around enough and
they're often overlooked and forgotten
i really don't think about banana terps
until it's in front of me then i'm like
oh i do want that
like banana bread bananas foster honey
banana i always love the banana and we
forget so
shout out to the banana terps i've been
enjoying a lot of honey bananas
concentrates or just other things in
your world
okay i was wondering like more
concentrates sorry yeah they uh they
made a lot of that full spectrum extract
and i
i bought a lot of it at that dispensary
down from near where we live so
i've been enjoying the [ __ ] out of that
i had some from apothecary and some from
green dot it was it was fun to bounce it
back and forth
oh yeah yeah it's always nice having
variety variety is the spice of life and
the two companies
make their products it's the same
extraction methods basically but it's
like our
our sops are just this much different
possibly i don't know
but i mean if one of them does something
just a little bit different the product
comes out so vastly different
and i love that availability here love
it love it
awesome mike this is the point of the
show where we should uh pay some bills
and do some shout outs of course this
podcast is brought to you by our friends
at seeds herenow.com
seeds herenow.com offers seeds from all
the industry's
leading breeders including miss jill
genetics duke diamond
and of course irie genetics everything
at seeds herenow.com is backed by their
award-winning satisfaction guarantee
and for my friends on a budget seeds
herenow.com offers
several packs for under thirty dollars
as well as amazing
monthly sales make sure you check out
that under 30 dollar section
because there is a strain from ire
genetics in there the cream is available
for under 30 bucks
uh you're welcome please support that
also use coupon code gfyh10 while
checking out
how to save yourself i think you saved
10 percent gfyhd gives you 10
while checking out at seeds here now
dot com now of course is the part of the
show where we do shout outs to the
members of the 710 club 710 club are the
folks who support the show on patreon
at the 7 10 level or higher so let's
jump right into it
uh let's give a big shout out to my new
friend named
grow for me damn it when i read that
name i could just see somebody
holding one of those little watering
cans like the old school watering can
with the big thing on the end so it
spreads
and they got their overalls and they're
just [ __ ] staring at the plant going
grow for me damn it that's the name i
like elmer fudd instead of the shotgun i
see you out there with the watering can
that's completely what i see when i read
the name grow for me damn it just
just out there like staring at the plant
give it some time bro it'll grow for you
damn it
good luck out there big thanks for the
support let's move forward with the big
thank you shout out to crazy
hand grows it's always fun having a
crazy hand in the grow
mike and i have worked with a couple of
crazy hands in the grove big shout out
if you're listening
yet every girl's got a couple of crazy
hands and i love you guys you keep the
day going
big shout out yeehaw let's also give a
big shout out to our friend glenn jeroni
a long time supporter thank you for all
the support brother i do appreciate you
i want to keep moving with a big shout
out to canna reaper four
one three ah that's donut don't reaper
us too hard bro i hope you're not the
grim reaper i hope you're the good can
of reaper
uh let's move forward with the big shout
out to ned denver big respect thank you
for all the support to ned denver
uh dgc crew for life also let's send a
big thank you shout out to our friend
karen crawford
a long time grow from your heart podcast
supporter and a
badass cannabis grower thank you for all
the support i also want to send a thank
you shout out to blackbird
76. uh big thank you also let's send a
big thank you shout out to lefty
lefty's out there growing some orange
gasm and kicking ass
i always want to send a big thank you
shout out to rasta k anybody named ross
decay gets my love big fist bump thank
you for the support
let's also send a big thank you shout
out to papa zee and last
but certainly not least let's send a big
girl from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to our friend
baptista big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on
patreon if you're not already supporting
the show and you would like to do so all
you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all the information you need
will be right there on the screen
of course i will include a link in the
show notes to make it easy
for all of my friends now is the part
where i would like to
encourage you to support my friend mike
on patreon
uh mike is uh patreon.com forward slash
white mike i saw you peek in there for a
moment mike have any shoutouts you want
to throw down while we got you on the
show
yeah i pulled up so i could do just that
man thank you for asking
i was want to give a big thank you and
shout out to ez057
og purple thumb farmer z and learning
and burning thank you all
very much for supporting me on patreon
and uh
yeah let's hit it bud yeah uh i want to
take a minute and
look straight into the camera and say
ez057 thank you
uh you know why and thank you for the
support bro yeah i owe you a mike osu
thanks but i do a special thank you
fist bump i hope you see this hope you
enjoy it i do appreciate your support
means a lot to me this guy trusts me a
lot and it means a lot
so uh we've got the patreons covered we
got uh seeds here now covered
um mike you got anything you want to
ramble about or should we jump right
into these patreon questions and cover
some business
let's jump right into the first email
man all right i want to leave
you plenty of space no no no no it's not
i was
just about to pass you the [ __ ]
ramble pass you've got the hall pass if
you've got something on your white mic
mind i want to hear it bro so don't be
shy you got something you want to side
rant on [ __ ] that's what you're here
for that's what the people love
concentrate's been stellar in colorado
lately man
i uh i've had so much good product in
front of me lately it's just been fun
it's uh helping make covered a hell of a
lot easier to handle
uh yeah i don't get to go to comedy
shows
that's awesome i can i can vamp on that
all day take a dab if you'd like to but
i understand your stance on camera if
you need to turn your camera off take a
dab bro we won't laugh at you
um i'm going to totally vamp on what
you're saying because i love this topic
i don't go to comedy shows anymore there
aren't comedy shows to go to
my favorite things to do are comedy
shows and concerts and those are the
first things that we cannot do right now
like so i'm kind of going stir crazy in
my mind i love being out with the people
and [ __ ]
laughing laughter you guys if you listen
to the show from the beginning i've
talked about comedy i've tapered it off
because i feel like i'm rubbing it in a
little bit people don't care too much
about every [ __ ] comedy show i go to
but i've made friends with the people at
the comedy clubs i've made friends with
comedians i go to a lot of so my point
is i'm not doing that anymore i'm going
[ __ ] stir crazy
and i can only buy so much clothes and
shoes online
like it feels good to have a package
show up every day but now i don't get to
wear that [ __ ] anywhere
i got a new pair of shoes for every day
of the [ __ ] month i got new pants for
every day of the month i got a fresh new
shirt for every episode of the show
that's the only thing i'm wearing it on
i got new shoes on right now just
because i can't [ __ ] wear them
anywhere
like yo and the other thing i'm blowing
all my money on bro since we're not
going to shows is all these delicious
concentrates and you're right
uh whoever is stuck in the lab all day
is just cranking it out they're like oh
yeah
i'm bored i don't want to go out and get
covered let's make a bunch of fresh new
flavors
yeah you're looking like me now i'm not
going to lift up mine it's just
it's so much fun right now in colorado
like i
i feel for people in other places like i
don't know how the [ __ ] people in
arkansas are handling this [ __ ]
like the further you are from
legalization man just
moonshine buddy moonshine that's how
they're doing in arkansas
it uh just guessing sorry guys um
it's just brutal i feel for y'all i
really really do i
really do i uh i don't think i could do
this without without really good herb
no i would uh well i i'd have lost it
already
i was getting a throat tickle and i know
that the first thing i need to do when i
start getting a throw tickle is hydrate
and minimize my consumption of smoke
like just dabs and hot smoke over the
throat i did a 36 hour stretch without
taking a dab
and a couple of people that were close
to me they're like um you haven't dabbed
all day are you okay and i was like i
feel [ __ ] good but i feel weird like
i really would like to dad
and when i did finally take that dab bro
i was like it was like a good kick to
the [ __ ] dick i got so lit it was
really nice
but yeah i started getting that like i'm
bored i can't go anywhere
i'm not into se i can't if you know me
you know i can't sit there and watch tv
i can't shut the [ __ ] up long enough to
watch a commercial so not
like i'm just bouncing around nothing
now my backup plan is to get dad and
chill out and i can't do that for 36
hours i was kind of like fidgety
so yeah these dabs keep us kind of calm
down another thing though bro you know
what i've really stepped up my game on
and my garden looks even better
yeah my grow looks [ __ ] it's sexy
right now everything is right on track
where i want it to be the plants look
the way i want them to look
like everything is where i expect it to
be that you know that
corner uh you don't grow because you've
got the kids and all that but you've
worked in commercial grows and you know
there's always one corner
there's always a corner needs to be
swept and he's just cleaning that
[ __ ] corner out that corner got
cleaned
like it got it's clean took away all the
excuses yeah
i mean there's always there's always
something else you could be doing or
should be doing or
or need to do and so it's easy to put
off the
whatever can absolutely wait till
tomorrow you can't get down the road a
little bit but go if it took all those
[ __ ] excuses away
if you're not at work you're at home
yeah and that's
that's part of what sucks about covet is
enough the phone rings and you press
ignore you're basically just saying [ __ ]
you to whoever called because they know
you're home
you're not doing [ __ ] it's coveted yeah
he's like just sitting there on the
couch scrolling looking for new shoes
online or
now i've got the good excuse i was
recording i had the phone turned off and
i was recording a podcast i wasn't able
to get to you
right i've got the we built a covid
guard dub
three raised flower beds out back that
uh
all veggies i got a big bed full of corn
i got a bed full of squash and zucchini
a bed full of peas
bed full of broccoli when does the corn
come out bro because the zucchini and
squash was so
good dude the squash and zucchini are
kicking out like mad right now the peas
just started to
to really sprout um
the corn here should be in a couple of
weeks it's really it's starting to look
um
like it's getting ready to it's just
been going up so far
no uh flowers as it were the better
coming you can see it
yeah we're it's crushing it we got like
stupid lucky with the dirt or some [ __ ]
with
so many veggies but that that's helped
fill a lot of coconut hours too
yeah you delivered me a nice basket of
veggies bro and they were delicious i
couldn't eat all of that [ __ ] yet you
gave me so much that i still haven't
eaten it but i chopped some of it into
like little diced cubes and
yeah cooked it up with some vegetable
oil and put a little seasoning on it
served that next to a warm sour to it
next to a cold salad as a nice little
contrast and compliment
it was really good bro yeah some corn
next to that we'll be killing it
we've been doing fried zucchini um like
a little sauteed zucchini
getting ready to try the zucchini bread
you're gonna be zucchini
pretty soon every time we do a garden
dude we get
way too much zucchini you can't under
plant that like
even if you only put three seeds in the
ground you're gonna end up with 100
pounds of zucchini oh yeah
hell yeah and you're not even like
farmer john you're a [ __ ]
heavy white guy and you're out there
just gardening bro that's awesome
yep it uh my wife really wanted it
uh this spring she was like if we're
really gonna be trapped in the house all
summer we gotta have stuff to do
so let's let's do a garden and it was a
lot of work getting them prepped and
getting them in but
the watering system we built it's just
been kicking all kinds of ass
uh tell us about your watering system
bro that's a good thing to talk about on
a cannabis podcast
so with cannabis the drip systems that
you and i have
built usually each plant gets its own
special dripper and that leads to a lot
of [ __ ] headaches
just because you got to check each one
of them little tips every goddamn day
with the system we built for my garden
like it's just veggies
um each piece each corn stock doesn't
need to get the same amount of water
right
you just need to saturate the soil there
so uh
yeah we've just got big emitters like
you'd put for uh
a yard or a flower bed or something in
the corners of the boxes
and we didn't even do all four corners
we did on the
the two square boxes i've got diagonals
so um like one in the front right and
one in the back left
and then on the long rectangle box i've
got uh
two corners on one side and a big 180
shooting in the middle on the other side
and it seems to be covering everything a
hundred percent
the amount of veggies we're getting out
of this thing is [ __ ] ridiculous dude
they
taste good they were really sweet really
really sweet nine yellow squash in my
kitchen right now
[Music]
that we've harvested over the last
couple days that we haven't managed to
eat or give away
and we're harvesting six or seven more
tomorrow yeah
like yeah dude but i love this
conversation we got at home depot
like it's not even special stuff it's
thank god we did you're not even farmer
john out there you're just some normal
dude that doesn't really have like you
know you're not [ __ ]
licking your finger and checking the
wind and [ __ ] every day and just out
there doing what you know how to do
i fire up my morning coffee and while
i'm drinking my morning coffee i go
stare at it like i'm doing stuff
it just gets me away from the kids while
i get half a cup of coffee in me
and then i get out there with the kids
for like half an hour in the evening
and we pull weeds and pick veggies that
are ready and
it's a great little time killer oh
that's a cool experience for the kids
dude they're bringing food in from their
yard that they grew that you guys
made and then they get to have it for
dinner yup you need to see a process
they actually get to do it and they're
uh like i'm gigantic people i'm
six three 250 pounds um
if i'm being nice i'll let you have it
like i can't squeeze through some of the
corn and [ __ ] or like tiptoe through
some of the
the stuff and they can they're tiny so
that's been really helpful too like
that's cool little tiny helper bots
little box little uh useful opa loompas
yeah i think i do wants a dab buddy i'm
pretty rambly already no it's perfect
but i kind of was hoping that we could
kind of turn it into a ramble cast
because
they do and it's been pretty intensive
lately everything has just been [ __ ]
less and less and learn learn and
it's been intense shows have been really
good you talk for like seven seconds
i'll take a dab and then i'll cover you
sounds good to me i'll wait onto eating
that then so uh
i really like the last couple episodes
on safety
um a lot of the cannabis forums i've
been reading lately
you can tell that people haven't thought
all the way through
their grow setup so they've thought
about
i want to grow cannabis and they've
thought about maybe where they're going
to get the seeds
or which light they're going to use but
they haven't thought about
all of the steps all the way to the end
so they haven't thought about
planting or transplanting or cloning
harvesting which hours of the day
they're going to run their lights i mean
during the summer right now
i saw like 130 in death valley might be
a world record
vegas right now is breaking all kinds of
records
like if you're running your grow lights
during the day right now
like oh lordy you're fighting yourself
140 degrees in your grow
a lot of people don't think to wait i
can just run them
from night to morning like plant don't
give a [ __ ]
like it don't have to be to work the
next day yeah you can write it on
whatever schedule you want
and just learn taking the time to really
think through all the steps
especially drying here i know so many
people
that i mean you spend a ton of money on
good equipment and good grow lights and
good nutrients and you invest
all the time to get your plant to
harvest and then they throw it in a
cardboard box or stick it in an
oven like how many times have we seen
that bro oh
yeah we used to run a shop so we got
everybody bringing everything to us
and they would tell us what they did
they thought they were cool by doing
dumb tricks
yep everybody yeah it's
a little different this time oh why
because we set it on the door of the
oven and turn the oven on 400 for three
hours instead of letting you dry and
cure for two years i can't remember that
kid's name oh i do remember his name i
remember his dad's name now
you give me a minute that was the la
confidential let's not go let's not have
too many details but yes no but that was
the strain right
yeah we're thinking of the same kid same
family yep and that was from 10
12 years ago yeah yeah yeah and we still
remember this
pound ruined weed
yeah the safety episode like honestly
that safety episode came from
uh working in multiple commercial
facilities you know my history and
commercial grows i've been in enough
i've managed a few i've been a grunt in
a few i've consulted for
countless there was a comment on youtube
about somebody bending over with
scissors
in their pocket and i spit like i spit a
little soda out when i read that
because i've driven that kid to the
hospital twice
not the kid that made the comment but
some
younger person working for me who put
scissors in their damn pocket
forgot about it and stabbed themselves
half an hour later with him
and that's how i put that episode
together basically i've seen the [ __ ]
i've been in countless grows around
countless growers
and i've seen hungover people i've seen
stone people i've seen sober people in a
hurry
i've seen people clearing wood chippers
with broom handle
aluminum broom handles i've seen i've
seen a lot of crazy [ __ ] so that's how i
know
like you're gonna cut yourself you're
gonna stub your toe you're gonna [ __ ]
spray a chemical in your eye one day
you're gonna [ __ ]
you ever see two guys hold the two by
six and another guy walk on the two by
six to change a light bulb
because we have you ever seen a guy put
a ladder on a scissor lift and raise the
scissor lift to get
up high enough to get to that [ __ ]
light because we did
um yeah man we've seen and done a lot of
crazy [ __ ] that we probably shouldn't
even admit to having seen or done in a
commercial environment
come in in the morning and the 300 pound
carbon filter is smashed on the floor
15 feet below where it was hanging when
you left that last night like a big
ring of carbon around it and [ __ ]
like 12 plants in a tray just
smashed yeah we yeah uh
snakes and lights because we've seen
this
birds and [ __ ] exhaust fans uh
squirrels i was wondering if you were
gonna mention your finger in the fan on
that episode yeah i think i did this
episode's about safety i was like oh
he's gonna tell the finger story
uh you made me think about something i
wanted to add to the safety episode and
it just totally [ __ ] left my head
because there were so many good thoughts
happening
that it may come to me or maybe maybe
i'll just watch this episode and rethink
about it
uh something that happens in [ __ ]
random grows but yeah
we've had some crazy [ __ ] happen dude uh
the squirrel
squirrel that chewed on the [ __ ] big
cable outside and killed the power of
the whole [ __ ] building and we went
outside and found
a squirrel it was as stiff as my [ __ ]
bic pen
like from head to toe that squirrel was
barbecued and just stiff
like yeah we've seen some weird [ __ ] uh
the rattlesnakes
we had to grow uh [ __ ] 15 minutes
from here
where we found multiple [ __ ]
rattlesnakes outside i had another grow
where we found tarantulas inside
a bunch of crazy [ __ ] used to happen at
some of these commercials
lizards was common yeah lizards they
didn't even bother anybody after a while
right here's another lizard just run
them outside
what happens when the co2 tank that's
like 80 feet tall blows the seal
and dumps your whole new co2 delivery
out
in like an hour
i can walk it outside one day and i'm
i'm at the front of a long building
building's half a city block
and i'm in the front of the building and
i hear
[Music]
and i know that's a curious sound and i
start walking towards it it gets louder
and louder and louder and louder and
louder there's a certain point
i can't hear anymore because it's the
sounds so oppressive it's blocking out
other sounds
you can walk it around and there's this
nice fog emitting from the back of the
building
yeah just money flying out of that
canister
it's so hard to plan for all the [ __ ]
you're gonna run into when you grow
cannabis
yeah well then uh what happened that day
was so we have big canisters outside of
the building and a truck phil
comes up and hooks up a line and fills
those canisters with co2 so we don't
have to move canisters all the time
uh the machine is worth the co2 should
have been 10 or 14 days the guy fell
asleep in his truck bro
and he froze the line because co2 is a
cold gas it froze the lines
and it didn't stop so when he
disconnected everything was frozen
it also froze the lines inside the grow
and it was just spinning co2 in all the
grow rooms
at a ridiculous rate yeah the alarms
went off in the building we had to
evacuate
the building and [ __ ] yep yeah that was
that was pretty ridiculous
i've seen walls collapse wow because
people put up too much weight and it was
just a cheap little
cardboard or they're not cardboard
drywall
over over plywood so it's just
you never know what you're going to run
into folks safety first
then teamwork don't put [ __ ] scissors
in your pocket
yeah right scissors in your pocket yeah
i've taken plenty of people to
the emergency room for dumb dumb things
pesticide exposure was my least favorite
to go to the hospital for
because every time you walk in you're
like i've got uh
i'm a manager at a cultivation facility
and this employee
has a pesticide exposure like something
goes off and everybody that's like we
need to contaminate you
and we're always like no no no no no no
contaminate this was yesterday like we
i've always got to explain like he got
hit yesterday with the pesticides he
sees a rash today we're fine i wasn't
even in the room
he's the only sprayer we're not
contaminated i have always have to talk
fast to get us out of that one
yep like yeah yeah if one of the grow
techs went and just went by themselves
and said it i think they'd probably end
up in a decon unit
[ __ ] lockdown and [ __ ] yeah yeah but
i've seen too many of our friends get
steroid shots and [ __ ]
uh what's that pill called that they
give you claritin or the other one
uh when you're all yeah they give you a
steroid shot some claritin or whatever
and they go
good luck what the [ __ ] dude look like a
tiger on one side
right the tiger stripe rash is no joke
first time you see that you freaked the
[ __ ] out
yeah yeah second time you see that you
freak out too
but when it starts like uh the tiger
stripes get ridges that start bleeding
that's when you're like oh [ __ ]
yeah [ __ ] yeah i've never had that but
i've seen it
yeah we had a guy i don't know how much
we're allowed to talk about this because
of hipaa and all that [ __ ] but in one
case i saw a person
uh doctor yeah that's true but i saw a
person
uh get exposed to a pesticide rash and
like
he messaged me that evening he's like
hey bro i think it worked today i may
have got something he sent me
a picture a little red spot on his skin
i said bro
document that keep an eye on it we'll
check on it in the morning at work i
checked on him as soon as we got to work
let me see your little rash bro
and it was like starting to he was he's
dark skinned and it was starting to turn
even darker than him and i was like that
doesn't look good buddy we're gonna have
to check on that at the first break
at the first break it started growing
like up his rib cage and [ __ ]
and i was like yeah i think by lunch
we're taking you to the hospital
and by lunch ago come here let me see
that take a marker and draw around the
outside of it there was no
need for the marker because by lunch
[ __ ] from his
kneecap to his collarbone he looked like
somebody had clawed him or something
and the doctor said that that pesticide
that he was exposed to
was heat activated the heat in his body
was making him get a worse rash and we
were working on a grow and we were long
sleeves and [ __ ] so he was definitely
uh but yeah so he got a funky eye and it
just happened
uh within 12 24 hours it went from that
kind of looks like you may have got some
got a booboo from some pesticides to oh
[ __ ] get in the car we were taking you
to the hospital bro
yeah they gave him whatever that pill is
claritin or that doesn't sound right
but they gave him something like that
and some steroids and told him good luck
buddy
yeah the eye wash was a really good uh
really good
tip too the the really common
that i saw is you you take a dirty
trichome coated finger and stick it in
your eye
oh god you're gonna hit your eye or it's
your face and then the next thing you
know
new tremors in the side of the room
crying a little bit like what happened
oh you touched your eye another thing
i've seen people make mistakes on and
this is what i forgot a moment ago so
i'm gonna interrupt you and just [ __ ]
blast this one out
uh is and this is common in a commercial
grow and it's a bad mistake and it's
also illegal it's illegal by the health
department it's illegal by the
department of ag
keep your beverages away from your other
stuffs yeah like in the commercial
cultivation it's not uncommon to have
alcohol yeah yeah we'd have isopropyl
alcohol ph up
ph down uh dr pepper [ __ ]
like wait what and so you're stoned like
because you're working the grow and
you're [ __ ] going a million miles an
hour and i'm talking to you and i'm like
all right mike
uh i gotta get this job done i'm gonna
[ __ ] yeah bro you oh no i'll go to lunch
after i water room b
don't worry oh that's the isopropyl
alcohol [ __ ]
that was close let me grab my dr pepper
over here buddy
and you just take a drink like it was
funny and i need to drink this kombucha
because i just
pavloved my mouth but it's we were
soaking
um those spray emitters i mentioned a
while back the cog easy we were soaking
those in a costa cleaner
and someone who wasn't typically in that
part of the grow
came by and moved they were looking for
something
and they moved the container that those
were soaking in and it didn't have a lid
it just had a i think it was a piece of
tape over the top that said
you know don't touch yeah it said what
it was on it actually said what it was
because i remember this very well
and i know exactly the person she said
on their hand and ended up with a
chemical burn
um and yeah like five minutes later they
came up to us and were like why is my
hand
like red and itchy did it right now why
is it stinging it was actually
zero tall and their hand was turning
white and puffy and the skin was kind of
dying a little bit
yeah jeff was there i remember exactly
the day in that purse because they tried
to they're like what do i do and i was
like
don't don't [ __ ] around because they
were [ __ ] around that's why they got
hurt that's
yeah yeah yep
yeah see i knew what it was immediately
when i shoo when i saw
the skin reaction i knew what it was
immediately like you got zero tall on
you
and i bet it came from that like it's
just
that's where it is part of being the
boss you know what's going on in the
building but uh
yeah so keep your drinks and your
chemicals and [ __ ] separate and
have a plan don't get caustic chemicals
in your [ __ ] fingers if you've got
more than one person working there
like in your home grow it's probably
just you but in a commercial facility or
if you got a homie backing you up
label [ __ ] so that like they know that
there is
zero tall in this cup because we're
cleaning these emitters like make make
that [ __ ] known like mark stuff
i like to keep a big dry erase board and
every cultivation every room has a
dedicated dry erase board we can mark
down what's going on
when mike does something like this room
needs to be defoliated by the end of the
day michael do it mark his initials
and if i don't like the way it's
defoliated i know to go cuss mike out
for it
it's when you were talking about that on
the the episode i was thinking how nice
it is that
that we can do that in legal land now
that used to be like the
one of the top five tips for being a
grower during prohibition times was
don't keep like if you keep records make
it in code don't make it obvious because
your notes are evidence yep
and yeah now it's there's a lot less
than that we're in colorado we can just
have a big whiteboard have sops have
logs
all that [ __ ] makes life so much easier
yeah yeah the sops are one of my at
first i was uh
afraid of or intimidated or whatever
turned off by sops
and now i love a good sop like it's kind
of there's something in me
like if you want to pay me to write you
sops like oh yeah
that's like one of my favorite things to
do let me come look at your building
look at what you got we'll write
[ __ ] from walking in and washing our
hands we'll write an sop
from using the time clock all the way to
clocking out i'll get you [ __ ]
programmed with sops i love that [ __ ]
it cracks me up i've had more than one
outfit
that paid me to help tweak theirs and
then
six months later i come back to
do a follow-up and they're not following
any of it and they can't figure out why
she's not better
and it's like well have you tried
following the steps and it's all new
employees that weren't there before
and so you show that new staff the
actual sops you pull them out you pull
up the file and you go like have you
ever read
this and they go oh that's such a good
idea let me come back in like three days
and like yeah the tremors are faster
the [ __ ] weight room is faster the
quality control is faster everything
seems to be smoother here i don't know
what happened
like yeah we wrote sops like yeah yeah
we do it
now step by step sometimes it looks like
the lead grower
is just losing his mind standing there
staring at the plants and looking off
into space but
uh we've got sops and [ __ ] in our brain
we're like oh man we're gonna have to
[ __ ] do these next
seven [ __ ] steps because we already
know like we got the map in our head
sometimes we just get that weird
weird [ __ ] look right no it's i don't
envy that part of the
part of the grow i'm i'm i like my end
uh and i don't care for your end of the
grow so that's beautiful
you want to talk about metric before we
even tell them what it is
yeah tell them in three words explain to
me how you feel about metric and then
we'll tell them what it is after that
[ __ ] that spinning wheel i think that
was more than too many words but
that's going to be the general consensus
for anybody who
has to deal with metric [ __ ] that
spinning wheel metric
is the marijuana enforcement tracking
blah blah blah
system the software system and
it can be like i get why it exists but
it it is what it is
you just want them to come after me i
don't work in the med anymore ah
i don't with metric i mean i work with
med but i work with metric
i work in the back end so i don't really
have to talk to him i hand you a
clipboard and you do all that metric
[ __ ] for me thank you bro
that [ __ ] program sucks and needs
some [ __ ] updates and it's the
biggest
waste of time in people's days it's a
good program when it works the idea the
goal
this [ __ ] purpose is [ __ ] awesome
execution
thumbs down zero [ __ ] that [ __ ]
service dude
uh mike said [ __ ] that spinning wheel
when uh everybody's first question when
they get into metric is it supposed to
randomly eat a third of your day
yeah apparently that's not a bug that's
a feature yeah
um anytime we cut a clone try not
transplant but move a plant from another
room
uh anything that really happens with
plant relocation
uh recreation time you cut the clone to
the time you
you harvest it it's it's getting moved
around in metric
yeah it gets into close it's harvested
it gets weighed out and re-entered into
metric and then that's in metric too
all the waste gets put into metric all
the packages get put in the metric
so you cut a clone that goes into metric
the clone gets a number
uh the plan a comes from has a mother
plan number which is also included
in that [ __ ] clone number so you got
clone number seven five five
five five that came from plant number
seven five four four four
uh we can follow all the way down the
line where each clone of each clone of
each clone
came from which is cool because then we
can tell you uh once it's harvested they
go into batches and we can tell you what
pesticides were applied
for [ __ ] seven generations of those
plants hypothetically
uh did you see why all this is exists
during when we have a recall
yeah and it's like the 12 stores that
bought plants that were harvested
between these dates at this facility
all have to get and they can track it
down to the
the pre-rolls on the counter yep it uh
it's a nice system it's just not at all
smooth out
well half the time when you go to use it
it just the [ __ ] you get this little
wheel of death
that just spins in the middle of your
[ __ ] screen it looks like the little
thing from uh there's used to be a
trivial pursuit game and it looks like
the [ __ ] trivial pursuit thing just
spinner the
windows [ __ ] thing just spit or the
apple thing that just spins right in the
middle of the [ __ ] screen
but usually with like windows or apple
even windows i'm an apple guy [ __ ] a
windows machine in my opinion
but it works better than goddamn metric
that thing eventually does something
metric just goes [ __ ] you [ __ ] you [ __ ]
you [ __ ] you [ __ ] you and just spins in
circles in it
it's like middle fingers just coming at
you and the shittiest part is
uh this wasn't my end of the building
but i witnessed this plenty of times
because
delivery drivers would come to pick up
product from the commercial cultivation
you have to pick it up there's
dried trim cured ready to go product it
has to leave there mike just doesn't
throw on the car and take it a courier
comes and gets it
and they take that to either a
processing facility or to a dispensary
for retail sales
for that product to leave our commercial
cultivation facility
it's got to be in metric as a package
that package has to be
on a manifest for a transport or for a
transfer
if metric freezes you cannot make the
manifest
for the transfer and the package has to
sit there in our facility
even if that delivery driver drove from
boulder to pick it up to take it to a
concentrate processing facility or an
edible facility in boulder
until metric works again everybody just
hurry up and wait
so we've had delivery drivers just
kicking it in the office just
hey do you have a phone charger like
i've been here for like oh and i'm not
leaving because i mean i can't go
anywhere else because none of the other
facilities can do anything because
metrics frozen
everywhere so they just kick it yeah
there's a there's a thai food restaurant
right over there it's pretty good
there's an indian food place that way
but other than that bro just hang out
have a good time
yeah metric will ruin your whole [ __ ]
day
yeah so a lot of times i'm lucky because
when i cut the clones that i talk about
have to be put into metric
i do it on a clipboard because i got
dirty ass hands i'm dirty i'm in a hurry
and i don't want to go to the computer
and [ __ ] take off my gloves and type
in six clones of [ __ ] chem dog and go
back and put on gloves and cut more and
then wipe off again
so i keep a [ __ ] marker and a big
piece of paper and i scribble it and
mike has to [ __ ] put it in the
computer for me so
i'm pretty spoiled on that part to tell
you the goddamn truth not a lot of
growth facilities have that you're
welcome buddy yeah thank you bro i
appreciate it
so i always play any grow i work at i
get mike a spot i'm like mike's my
metric guy let's just get mike in here
we work together
my point and grunt you know what needs
to happen yup
beautiful we just got some really cool
lightning outside i hope we don't lose
internet connection but
it's really beautiful lightning bring on
the rain
yeah bring it bring it bring it um yeah
metric it can be
a [ __ ] headache shout out to anybody
out there that has to mention mess with
metric metric is in several states
metric warrior
i feel for you that's the only kind of
keyboard warrior i got love for is a
metric keyboard
it uh it can be [ __ ] brutal that's
for damn sure and
i always hated it when a delivery driver
was early
and it was like all right dude now i
gotta roll the dice like is it gonna
[ __ ] with me today
or is it gonna play nice cause it was
gonna play nice if you showed up on time
and then people are gonna say well why
don't you make the manifest at the start
of the day or the night before
there's a time limit you can only make a
manifest within a certain time frame
before the delivery leaves
also we need the delivery drivers
identification while he's on site we
need the vehicle license plate number
we need the driver's identification his
driver's license and his medical or his
colorado marijuana enforcement division
badge number
so we don't know if kyle the delivery
driver is coming in the subaru
uh we don't know if tom is coming in the
[ __ ] mitsubishi
uh we don't know if [ __ ] kyle is
driving a different car this time so
unless you can contact them and then by
lunchtime
traffic from [ __ ] boulder to pueblo
that's three hours uh kyle may bail out
[ __ ] tom maybe end up being our
[ __ ] delivery driver today so
then we gotta tear up the whole [ __ ]
manifest cancel the delivery and redo
the whole [ __ ] thing so
that's why we don't do the manifest in
the morning we've tried
you only redo three or four manifests
before you stop trying to
to prep them too early yeah and it's
brutal
you have you redo too many of them and
then all of a sudden somebody's got
questions about why you're redoing them
and
it's just the whole says i i've tried to
explain to people that are like man
legalization's gonna be awesome i'm
gonna grow weed in my basement and sell
it to stores it's like that's
that part of legalization disappears
quick yeah that's for like
six months in a new market you get that
wild wild west vibe
uh unless you're michigan it feels like
they hung out hung on to that [ __ ] for a
while but
oklahoma tightened up quite quickly
california definitely trus
tried is trying i don't know it is
trying
cali's a unique stitch they dragged
their feet for like 18 years which is
why they're having so much trouble but
the the newer emerging legalization
markets there's
they seem to to launch with much more
rules and regs in place originally than
than some of the early launches did like
when colorado and cali and
in washington first went it was just
like weeds legal now
dot dot dot like here like uh so
tell me to figure out the taxes a cut
goes to schools that's the whole rule
you can carry two ounces and you can
have 99 plants that's pretty much
the rules that we know of okay cool
let's have a good start rule wasn't even
really a rule
it was a pre-existing federal
amplifier right where the feds had a
rule in place for
it wasn't even a written down rule it
was just a rule of thumb
if they catch a guy with 99 plants the
federal government doesn't care
if the federal government finds you 100
plants they consider you al capone
so that became just the de facto
in colorado and then people for a while
were going with 499 because that was
another federal cut off
where you got one penalty for 499 and
another penalty for 500.
man so yep yeah those were the days bro
wild west days are fun people just open
a dispensary
just up here oh we've rented some space
and we put up a sign and it says weed
and he's coming to buy an eighth if he
got a card
we got four different strains and four
different jars and
we've got a juggalo with a night stick
at the door
[ __ ] we're calling it good the
owner's wife made some edibles that'll
probably [ __ ]
halfway kill you but i mean they're only
six bucks so
yeah those were the days dude shout out
to karen rest in peace love you karen
your edibles [ __ ] ruined my life in
the best of ways
i fell down the stairs at that
dispensary bro uh we ate too many of
those fudge sticks one day
and i fell down those [ __ ] stairs so
stoned and comfortable
that i just like rolled down and just
stood up and walked out of it
like it was just like how it was meant
to be like i didn't fall i just
didn't use my feet to get down because
it was
awkwardly beautiful it uh
there are so many you had to be there to
believe it
type stories at that place it's just
every day there was another one
well i was i can tell you a thousand
good ones i was the
[ __ ] the bud tender you'd step into
the bud room so you walk in and meet a
lovely lady named tree you should check
your id check your paperwork make sure
you're legit
uh my buddy would stare you down yeah
what's up tree hope you're well she'll
never hear this but i hope she's good
either way ah
and mr chandler hope you're well as well
uh so [ __ ]
uh the security guard would stare you
down and make sure you're not [ __ ]
gonna do anything crazy but he looked
more [ __ ]
threatening than anybody else so then
people would come back into the bud room
and i'd have a few jars and we'd have
some offerings and some edibles
and if you couldn't decide if you wanted
the white rhino or the northern lights
[ __ ] it i got a pipe if i could pack you
up a bowl which one you want to try
unless you're trying both you know which
one you want first
get that white rhino get a good taste
and then hit that northern lights or
whatever
the white widow whatever else i [ __ ]
said and then i really think i like that
one can i get an eighth sure man here's
an eighth and
since uh you're gonna come back i know
you come back here a lot here's a
[ __ ] gram of some other random [ __ ]
just because you buy a lot of [ __ ] here
and i want you to flavor
yeah that way you know you tried three
while you're here here's another one try
that while you're home so if you like
that and you got a lot of options and we
got a lot of people set up on medical
marijuana you'd be able to come back and
just smoke a bowl back there
uh the lady that owned the place or the
owner's wife
she loved to bake and they grew and her
favorite thing was to make edibles
her second favorite thing so it's such
good homemade
they were delicious too that was an
amazing process like
grandma made banana bread kind of
[ __ ] edibles like not like
store-bought like weird but like the
fudge dude
oh the fudge i am like 99 vegan nobody
cares i'm just
i am like mostly vegan but if some of
that fudge showed up i'd have to take a
bite
like that stuff was so freaking good and
it's like really mostly dairy
but this lady i said her favorite thing
was to make amazing edibles her second
thing
was to bring them to the dispensary and
tell mike and i
you got to try them because we can't put
them on the shelf without trying them
and this was before lab testing lab
testing used to be like this
it tastes good three people ate it an
hour later had a conversation about it
if one of us was asleep on the couch
we'd probably sell that product the
first time
i was working there and she brought in
the edibles
she's like here's your one of everything
and i was like that's amazing oh my god
thank you
and five minutes later she was like
which one have you tried i was like
it's 10 05 in the morning on
a tuesday and i'm at my new job
so none she's like well you got to try
what
an hour later it's like oh [ __ ] i have
to work now yup
yup it was like
but it seemed like fate always juggled
the [ __ ] puddle on the floor ball it
was never me
and you on the floor as one of us like
quite often one of us had to go sit in
the car and [ __ ] get an extra lunch
break
uh i'd find you out on the back patio
stairs and road joints
yeah yeah i'd find it you on that back
patio upstairs smoking a cigarette with
this look on your face
like oh he just got too high on his
break he'll be back in a few minutes
like he's got to leave mike alone but
there was always
enough of us in there we could just
juggle it like we never i managed a 40
lane bowling center it always seemed to
be the same way one of us would be like
oh you gotta you gotta hide from the
boss
and like the rest of us would just make
the [ __ ] work and his job would get done
or her job would get done
it always seemed to work that way at the
dispensary for us as well
but those edibles bro i miss that lady
and i miss her edibles
yeah the fudge was especially nice the
fudge and the banana bread i remember
specifically those were
chocolate-covered cherries like it was
just yeah cookies all any kind of
macadamia nut chocolate chip oatmeal
raisin [ __ ] sugar cookies
holiday time whatever holiday snack was
available she made that
medicated and they were this was before
all of the crazy regulations so they
were growing
uh should none of this exists anymore
she's not even here anymore so she can't
get in any trouble they were growing in
multiple multiple locations like
their house their bedrooms had plants in
every bedroom you had to move plants
over to take a piss like get them out of
the way so you use the bathroom
they had a lot of material to make
edibles they were not [ __ ]
amateur edibles she was like house how
much weed can butter
possibly hold yep
it was yeah it wasn't can of butter at
that point it was
like buttered cannabis yeah it was so
good
yeah so good yeah we would get so red
but
you're totally right dude it would be 10
in the morning it should be offering you
[ __ ]
banana bread carrot cake fudge and a
sugar cookie and you're like uh
i'm gonna get diabetes and be too high
to work by lunchtime
but you you tell her all right i had i
had a piece of the banana bread it was
wonderful i really liked it good job
thumbs up she'd be like cool which one
are you gonna eat next and five minutes
later she'll be like how did it taste
she was a happy lady bro i love that
woman she was so nice
yeah shout out to those guys i don't
want to say both of their names because
i said too much already but
without them uh we wouldn't be where we
are mike so
i always like to remember that and pay
some homage and tribute to those folks
because that was the catalyst
yeah his court trial uh introduced me
to being comfortable in a courtroom and
understanding that process
and i think he relied on you for a lot
of that sort of stuff as well
and when uh when the city ended that
like they did
that anger that and fueled me to do
years of city council [ __ ] just years
off that one injustice
so what mike is talking about is uh we
had the privilege
um i've talked about this before on the
podcast we had the privilege of being a
large part of the very first dispensary
within the city of pueblo colorado
i found some people who were trying to
open a dispensary no offense to them
they were older they're of another
generation they didn't have
the hip edge that a dispensary needed
and they didn't have any balls
they had little balls they were trying
to get it started they tried to do it on
a third floor
office space i moved the dispensary to
the [ __ ] ground floor and put a sign
out front
and [ __ ] we turned that little idea
into a [ __ ]
flourishing business it was crushing and
then one day
uh some city officials came in and
they're like nomas and they shut us down
they gave us a letter that it literally
said we're closing your business
because you're breaking the rules we're
discussing
passing into law so you have to close
and that's just how can you shut a
business down for passing rules that
don't exist yet that's
insanely [ __ ] and they did not know we
were breaking rules that did not exist
yet until we paid them
21 000 in the tax payment
that was our retail sales tax that we
paid them and then they asked how did
you make so much money in such a short
time and they came to figure out what
kind of business we had
after we'd been on the news talking
about our business after we'd made a
solid business plan with the letter of
intent
all of that was filed appropriately but
then one day they're like they made 21
in taxes let's go close that [ __ ] down
this was back when there were what
four five six dispensaries in the state
yeah
uh there may have been more than that
because uh
when i got to take weekends off
eventually i worked there for [ __ ]
six days a week for like six months dude
but when i finally
right after they opened there was a
little bit of a explosion across the
state
the broadsword they were one of the
first ten
yeah i would agree with that but then
one of my jobs
the owner would give me a budget to go
cruise to other dispensaries in colorado
springs denver boulder fort collins
wherever i could go
if i was going somewhere that weekend
he'd be like well make sure to hit
whatever here's your budget and you'd
[ __ ] throw me money dude he'd like
make sure
and we'd come back and we'd all uh there
would be back then we could smoke in the
dispensary and [ __ ] we had a little
employee area and we'd all just gather
around on monday morning and see what
jeff brought from denver
[ __ ] this is what i got a kind love
this is what i got at the ganja gourmet
this is what came from the clinic this
is what came from cam
and we'd all just set it all on the
table and just puff because the owner of
that store bought it wasn't really mine
but he gave me the money to go see
what's available at all these other
places
that was really fun and they would just
let me just [ __ ] here's 300 bucks get
us like
a few eighths of good [ __ ] like okay
that's always a good time
uh i would walk out of stores back then
um i would go into stores and i'd be
like yeah i really don't want anything
we did that a lot we did that a lot
and nah i remember when rigs first
started going down we did it again
to see how each outfit was implementing
new rules that had come down the pipe
and it was always
curious when you'd run into a shop that
was like oh we decided [ __ ] the new memo
we're not going to do any of that [ __ ]
you'd see two weeks later they're gone
and you're like wow
you don't wonder what happened to them
man there are still a couple of shops
there's one around here that you
mentioned to me that
i'm not going to say their name on the
show sorry guys i know a lot of times
you ask me to do that but i don't want
to i don't need to call businesses out
and start rivalries
we're older than that now we're past
that uh but there's one shop around here
i go there occasionally to get green dot
concentrates because when the other
spots
out or i've bought all the flavors there
or maybe i've gotten my [ __ ] limit
for the day and i gotta hit another shop
or whatever
i'll go to this place and get some green
dot it's affordable it's effective
they're
they're nice but i look around and i'm
like violation number one
a violation number two that's like at
least a ten thousand dollar [ __ ]
ticket right there
oh you just brought out instead of
bringing up the jar they bring out the
[ __ ] 10 pound
bag of flour and just weigh it with
their hand and scoop out your ounce like
this
into a baggie on the scale and i was
like that's
that i see just seven violations like
just in that transaction
and they're still there though like
they're [ __ ] they thrive there's
always a line outside that [ __ ] place
some of that [ __ ] blows my mind because
i've been in i've been involved in both
sides of the coin i've had metric
come down on us and the med come down
like this little thing that you did
and i've also called them and been like
yeah i've got a major [ __ ] problem
and they're like hey thank you for
calling we'll solve this not a big deal
so it's hard to guess what yeah i've
been on both sides of that [ __ ] coin
with
metric yeah it's such a weird
but i catch it too when i when i walk
into their obvious stuff and just like
how are you getting away with this
or uh there's one of my favorites is
there's a rule that you can't have a
window
where product is visible from the street
and there's i've been to multiple shops
where there's a giant window in the bud
room
that looks out on the street and for
some reason
it hasn't occurred to any regulator or
inspector there's one on the way
on the way to the grow that we managed
out there
there's a shop on the left side of the
road on your way out there that
uh there's always a pretty girl standing
in the [ __ ] window and it's the bud
room she's just standing by the window
to get fresh air but there's always
one of the pretty girls [ __ ] standing
there and i'm like that's the bud room
i've been in that dispensary
she's gonna weigh the weed right there
when a customer comes in and you can see
her in the window
like it's [ __ ] plain as this place
only higher it's pretty girl so like
if it was up to me that wouldn't be a
rule but
it is one and i honestly have no idea
how they haven't gotten slapped for that
yet
just especially that place because the
led doesn't like them
how many different places don't swap
their um
carbon filters though we were required
to filter
like everything that leaves the building
but there are
so many grows that haven't swapped their
carbon filters
since they built to grow originally four
or five years ago 15 minutes west of
here smells like a [ __ ] skunk
like there's a couple of spots in town
that are just like
oh man those filters are old as [ __ ] if
they're even hooked up anymore
yeah oh they're not they're blind into
the road
yeah excuse me loves it
yeah well that that that's why some of
the neighborhood complaints that's why
granny goes it smells like skunks
and we're over here going look how good
we stuck up this neighborhood bro like
we [ __ ] nailed it i've actually
gotten visits from the med before going
hey
your grow smells too bad uh you're gonna
need to add more filtration and my
answer is how do you know it's us
and the media lady goes i've been here
before you guys know what you're doing
and i was like well that's kind of
like the [ __ ] coolest compliment ever
i guess you know like [ __ ] you too but
thank you
like yeah yeah i uh
that's so funny we've run into so many
people in this industry i uh
i've had department of ag people call me
and ask me like
is this something that really has
somebody told me this and this today is
that legit
it's like oh yeah or oh definitely not
right uh my favorite is when the
department of ag would come to inspect
our grow and i would have to answer
questions for them uh the one lady was
calling her boss to ask a question and i
was like no that's this is the answer
here and she was so blown away
she was like how do you know that and
shout out to a lady named
theo walker that's how i know that thea
is a bad mama
she trains a six-hour [ __ ] class at
the colorado state university of pueblo
uh she's yeah at the colorado state
university uh the other one fort collins
it's a [ __ ] six hour class and she is
a really good teacher she's
knowledgeable she's a genius
and she [ __ ] certified me i'm train
the trainer certified for the department
of ag so
yeah i know a lot of [ __ ] so i knew more
than the department of ag rep that was
inspecting her ability not more
but i knew the regulations better than
she did which was kind of
kind of fun right we were the poster boy
bro she used to call us
and check in and see how we were doing
and [ __ ] i loved it
you guys take care of the people uh part
of being a good if you want to be a
commercial grower people are always like
what am i going to do how do i be a good
girl or you can grow we that's easier
solitary [ __ ] weirdo take care of the
plants
but contractors and [ __ ] department
of ag and department of health and the
fire department
they're all going to come knock on the
door police
be nice to them yeah oh yeah yeah those
guys immediately just kill yourself
the electrical inspector the fire
department the fire inspector yeah those
guys can shut you down
for the dumbest dumbest [ __ ] reasons
but learn how to talk to those guys too
be nice to him be punctual call them sir
like yeah step your game up yeah i'll be
punctual
yeah yeah don't make an inspector wait
no because
they'll charge you for the inspection
and [ __ ] make you reschedule
do it if you're they're sitting in the
truck and you're not there
until august yeah next august yeah
yeah inspectors don't care they just
make the [ __ ] right
or don't i won't say what department he
was
in but there was a guy
that was retiring and so
none of the businesses got inspected for
like nine months
because he was just like [ __ ] that part
of my job what are they gonna do fire me
and just didn't do inspections until he
retired and then the dude who took over
for him was like
why do i have to inspect every business
in town
none of them have been inspected in the
last year all right
we got a lot of people up we got lucky
in a facility because there was a hot
water heater installed just kind of on a
it was as close yeah you know who did it
and i mean those guys were the redo crew
instead of the build it crew they had to
come back twice for everything
but we got lucky because that inspector
that didn't give a [ __ ] about his job
the one's like you might have to go
inspect everything
he showed up and he's like where's the
hot water heater and i go it's up there
and he goes i'm not climbing the [ __ ]
ladder that looks fine
sign and i was like we signed this one
too i think we need to sign this paper
and he goes what's this for [ __ ] i
don't know they told me to have you
signed both of them and i got him to
sign off for extra [ __ ] in the
construction at the same time just
because he didn't care
i was like sign here too sir and he's
like scribble scribble and i was like
thank you
like there you go and i just got two of
our inspections passed in that building
that i'm not even involved in now but
that's pretty smooth that guy didn't
give a [ __ ] dude did not give a [ __ ]
he didn't even press hard enough to
[ __ ] sign the paper completely he was
just like
job done going home beer and truck see
you bye bye
yup and i've had the other kind of
inspection where they're like no we want
to weigh it too
yup we want to smell the water that
comes out of that pipe
yeah pull the bag out of that trash can
let's check the bottom of the can
ah how about i know this show is off the
[ __ ] rails you guys perfect what i
wanted for i triggered mike with this
[ __ ] it's my fault this is what we were
really
shopping for uh the people that come to
inspect the scales
if anybody's got ocd it's the people who
inspect
[ __ ] scales dude they come in with
uh it's like cool
but it's in a case this big yeah it's
like and they pull out these little they
put gloves on these little white gloves
and they take out these little tweezers
and they pull the weights
out of the weight case with tweezers and
they [ __ ] dust your scale off and
they blew
air into it with the air sprayer and
they calibrated it like 14 times
and certified our scale it had to have
taken up four
[ __ ] hours to certify our scales like
yeah
the more scales you have the longer that
dude's there and
i can't remember if it's once a year or
twice a year
or once every other year it was too
often though because he takes
so [ __ ] long i was like are we paying
this guy hourly
because like he's [ __ ]
the in the dispensaries they have to be
certified really frequently
and it would shut the bud room parts of
the bud room down for
all oh yeah [ __ ] day all day but he
takes the weights
scale the scale the scale out of a
little container
out of like uh it looks like when you
got a bunch of drill bits
uh but the weights are in those little
drill bit holders so you guys
could say yeah yeah socket set it's
that's similar what i'm thinking but
they're all wrapped in a little [ __ ]
fabric package too because you can't get
any moisture
on them uh moisture and [ __ ] uh
well if i sneeze at it that'll make it
way different like this is point
one and point one is so light so like in
this point two and this point three
he cleans them off as he gets them out
he's got this little rag and he [ __ ]
cleans them off and then he puts him on
the scale and he cleans it again and
puts it on the scale again
and i'm like bro that scale is accurate
like
i'd put my money on it like [ __ ] move
the [ __ ] on dude like
i don't know it was just making my blood
boil watching him take [ __ ] four
hours to calibrate six [ __ ] scales
watching them do the the hanging scale
that we weighed
um harvested plants on like
the scale unit itself looks like kind of
like a game boy
with a metal hook hanging out of one end
and then it's
zip tied to a metal bar that's on a
rolling
like a cla if you had a closet bar on a
roll rack
or a doorway um
so the rack itself is framed out maybe
five feet tall six foot long the whole
thing's
coated in trichomes and parts of plant
leaves and
a little bit of dirt the wheels on it
are all [ __ ] up
and janky and coated with [ __ ] and ache
with leaves this poor kids
trying to get it to weigh whatever on
the
oh man he was not amused i was not
amused it was taking so long
we were trying not to lose it on each
other because
and that scale sucks that's like a a
fish scale
that's kind of what that resembles like
yeah but a digital fish scale
yeah yeah so good to deal with a lot of
weird [ __ ] working on a commercial girl
mike we're way off the rails today uh
supporting
mike on yeah patreon.com forward slash
white mike
helpful cracker out also uh patreon.com
from your house
they do they like you it's like they're
hanging out with us from your heart i
took a dab a couple of minutes ago mike
pulled a dab that's not regular for this
show so we're just hanging out having a
good time thank you guys it's episode
560.
mike was like hey is it 560 i want to be
on that one i was like [ __ ] yeah bro
what do you want to talk about he's like
yeah whatever you got
i was like cool we got a list of [ __ ]
here and we have abandoned
ship it's just a good time today we've
got some more serious episodes in the
works i'm
uh had a couple people ask me if i do a
another legalization primer how to get
it going in your area so
i told jeff that one's not ready yet i
want to put a little more work into my
examples and
this is a couple more gross specific
ones lots of good email questions coming
in so
you're not going to get a whole bunch of
these ramble episodes coming up but
every now and then
we needed one of these you need one we
all the whole the collective needed this
the irie army the girl from your heart
soldiers all needed this
is a good thursday show this at nemo
punk 15 let me know
[Music]
it will bro youtube will let you know
don't worry uh they want more light i
want you to turn up your mic
don't just quit being a whiny liberal um
but
look at your back bro you keep being
able to happen some of that's not gonna
happen
i invite you onto the show for a reason
so be here be you buddy don't change
anything for anybody that's my that's
for all of you not just mike be you be
the best you you could [ __ ] be in if
someone don't like it
same for you brah uh mike what's a
really delicious food name something
really delicious that i'm not going to
want to eat
steak [ __ ] good [ __ ] bro i could
smell steak from applebee's it's right
over there
it smells good but i see people lined up
all the time not for me
the steak at applebee's is not good bro
well it does smell good
i am but there are a lot of people out
there waiting for it so
uh but it's just not for me so that's
that's what i'm talking about there's
some [ __ ] that's not for you
i if [ __ ] you're delicious bro just
the way you are i'm not saying you i'm
saying everybody out there you're
delicious you're [ __ ] beautiful you
smell good you taste just right
you're creative you're expressive you're
a good person if someone don't like you
that is not your problem
nope there's something that you can get
on this planet if somebody's got a
problem with you go play with one of the
other 6.9 billion
yeah yeah and it's not even [ __ ] that
person at this point it's just
what about that person who that's how it
should be yeah i don't even have any
negative to them i don't even have a
feeling at them
i'm too busy for like oh [ __ ] that guy
but i got a podcast to record i got some
plans to take care of i got a [ __ ] 16
year old daughter
17 year old daughter wow happy birthday
kid
right i had two kids a guard and a wife
like life is busy yeah yeah
instagram live show to try to manage and
then i gotta take some dabs somewhere in
the middle all that [ __ ] sells dressing
like nine podcasts right now bro
um yeah thank you that's a good time to
do a shameless plug i am on the grow
from your heart podcast every monday and
thursday of course
i do my monday live show on instagram if
you're not already
checking that out every monday that is a
good time it has been booming i've been
hitting record numbers for myself uh
every monday on instagram
i go on instagram live all you have to
do is follow me i'm irie underscore
genetics on instagram
uh seven times out in time you'll get a
notification on your screen it'll say
iriegenetics is live
yeah for some reason i maybe i may have
a little shadow band going i
i ruffled some feathers and somebody
probably [ __ ] ruffler
yeah well you know it's this industry so
it doesn't matter uh
they probably got me a little shadow
band going whatever it'll come out of it
but make sure you follow me just look
for it all you have to do
uh you'll see if you go to my profile if
there's a red circle around my icon that
means i'm live
or i posted something to my story but
the red circle around i think it says
live and purple over it so
if i'm live it'll let you know come
check me out on instagram live every
monday
so we got the podcast mondays and
thursdays instagram live mondays at 7
mountain time
then frequently there's not really a
rhyme or reason to my schedule on
embracing organics on youtube
every thursday night at 7 p.m on youtube
i'm on a podcast called embracing
organics not every
they're there every thursday i don't
join them every week i'm a regular
member of the panel
i jump in when i can like i said i've
got the seed company my own podcast my
daughter
plenty of dabs to strokes packaging
organics
yeah i'm they're three out of four weeks
out of the month
yeah big shout out to the whole eo crew
uh stabby dan [ __ ] tenaci
fumador zen i'm trying to look at the
screen and think of the whole brady
bunch that would be on there
i'm gonna miss somebody but i love all
you guys dave uh the whole crew my own
adopted kids love you guys
uh then on saturdays most saturdays it's
summertime
i've been taking some saturdays off but
a lot of saturdays at 2 p.m mountain
time i do
the what's it called operation grow
what we do is a whole bunch of people
got the same pack of seeds
the same nutrients the same soil they've
all got auto pots
so we're using orange gasm seeds from
ire genetics
uh in auto pots and playground soil with
new millennium nutrients
the only difference in most of the grows
yeah the only difference in most of the
girls is the lighting and the
environment the tan
oh and everybody's got a pl grow minder
unit
so we can see what everybody's doing in
their room excuse me because i'm going
to just clear my throat real hard
do it so everybody's got the same gear
basically and we all meet that's fine
they all got a minor unit going too huh
yeah yeah so i can look at the reminder
units and see what's going on and
compare that to their pictures
yeah sexy we see a lot of cool [ __ ] my
email keeps opening on my screen
repeatedly that was really weird
i fixed it but uh so uh that's every
saturday at 2 p.m
mountain time operation grow it may be
called
operation grow 2019 that's because we
started in 19 but rest assured it is
current
uh you don't have to watch any of those
shows live they're all available on
video
i leave the instagram video up also
i am going to do my best to make
more content i hinted in a previous
episode that had something to handle
um yes i think it got handled today bro
i'm confident
uh that i freed up some more time um i
think we'll be able to put out more
content
pretty soon here i don't want to make
promises i don't want this big mouth to
write
jax's little skinny ass can't cash but
uh i'm pretty good at
[ __ ] coming up with coming in on my
word so i'm trying to do more content
bro
uh on my own show um also i do things on
cannabis as well
when cannabis does breeder panels and
stuff like that i joined cannabas
and i go on their breeder panel i was on
their like uh
they did a 420 show and they did some
other stuff there's a good time but yeah
i do stuff on cannabis too so check me
out on cannabis if you're not already on
canada buzz
yeah i do a lot of [ __ ] podcasting
bro a lot
and it's there's other stuff on our
plate too and uh
like you've got a breeding project going
we've both got families we've both got
personal lives like
and there's a [ __ ] playground
it's just life is interesting right now
yo even though we're all kind of stuck
at home
yeah i have a lot of fun [ __ ] going on
digitally i've developed a new addiction
to
shoe shopping not just any shoes i got a
couple of very specific shoes that i've
fallen in love with if you follow me on
social media
you know what i'm doing you've seen it
uh but man i'm getting up early because
there are shoe drops and [ __ ] at certain
stores on
certain websites and you can only get
this one pair like today a pair of shoes
came out at like two o'clock this
afternoon and nobody [ __ ] said
anything about it
just nike sent out a message was like
there's new shoes
and i was like wait what and i went and
i was like those are fresh buy them
like but then i went to show them to
somebody else when they got off work
like an hour later i was like hey look
at these cool shoes and i was like i
can't find these on the internet
anywhere
like they came and went dude [ __ ]
that quick i got a pair of them luckily
but man that's been one of my new uh my
passions i don't play video games i
think that's my new video game is
[ __ ]
trying to chase down those shoes there's
some adrenaline that comes with it dude
i've known more than one sneaker head in
my day and yeah y'all like hunting
you know i like the very rare kid i like
a certain kind and a certain color
and when i find them i'm like i'm gonna
find this shoe and then i find them and
they're like
a couple hundred more dollars than i
want to pay for them or whatever
and i'm like that's out of my [ __ ]
price range so then that puts me on a
mission bro
that puts me on like
[Music]
maybe a month or so but i'll find him at
the price i want to pay for him i'll
find him dude
yeah yeah that's that's been my coveted
[ __ ] time pass
yeah kova does different [ __ ] to
different people man and i know
more than one person that online
shopping
is has gotten them hooked i've got a a
couple of family members that have found
some facebook group where it's a page
where
these two women are running like a
little
they find something they do a package
for like 100 bucks
and then they sell 15 10 tickets so
it's like 50 going into the bank and
then somebody for
a 15 ticket or whatever a 10 ticket
gets a hundred dollars with the stuff
and so everybody goes home
happy well everybody-ish yeah um
and they're so hooked on that um
i've got another family member that is
just like doing home repair projects
like mad
but with the time this ends their house
is gonna be worth substantially more
than it was when they the plague started
i know
you know another old guy that's done the
same thing like he's built a shed and a
fence and a [ __ ] yeah
yeah yep he just lives at lo at lowe's
now yeah
you know i almost said his name because
it's similar to lowe's i was like he
lives it
across those [ __ ] names don't do it
don't do it yeah
they don't want their name on the show
no he doesn't i'm sure he doesn't
he doesn't want the world to know he
exists um
[ __ ] yeah and i all those people at
lowe's bro i'm not even going there
never mind
this every time i have to hit a hardware
store it's the busiest place in town
yeah it is jumping still yeah i'm lucky
you know what i'm looking forward to
movie theaters opening on friday
i ain't going to see a movie i'm 100
going to get some [ __ ] popcorn
i've been missing that [ __ ] all right
movie theater popcorn man i've been
jonesing for that
that's special can you not make that is
that like a thing
i can't i don't know i'm a foodie i
think
whatever they do with the theater
whatever oil they're using whatever
machine they're using
it just it tastes different than what
you make in the microwave
not like crazy different they're both
still popcorn but
i don't know if they put a little heroin
in it or some [ __ ] but it's so much
better
sprinkle a little crack on it yep pour a
little crack on it just a little crack
uh there's a thai food restaurant in
colorado springs that
there's nothing like it so i know what
you mean like i've eaten at a million
thai food places and i'm like can we
just go there why are we wasting our
time there's the one
like i found it in college i would not
routinely because i couldn't afford it
routinely but when i wanted
chinese food i would save up so that i
could go get my 100
order from the place that was an hour
and a half away because
it was a three hour round trip you'd go
get enough to last you all goddamn week
it was just uncomparable any other place
is a cheap knockoff
i'm gonna make some people time travel
right now back in the day
uh 99 2000 2001 maybe 2002 2003
that era uh the jam band scene was
cranking it up like the string cheese
incident and all that level of bands
there's a theater in boulder called the
fox theater
my buddy robbie and i would drive to the
fox theater and park in the same little
parking area
every weekend and catch the show with
the fox it was always a hippie jam band
i've seen
a hundred shows at the fox theater but
it was a ritual
that we would go to the smelly deli
across the street
and get uh i was always into the falafel
and hummus i would get two of those bad
maybe get three of those bad
[ __ ] just because like you're
saying that chinese food restaurant it's
an hour and a half away but it is the
best thing ever
uh i had other friends that we would end
up going there and they'd get one i'd be
like bro you're gonna want to get two
because halfway home you're gonna be
dreaming about the [ __ ] thing
and now i've got other friends like if i
took gibbs with me you just i need three
of whatever he would order like i need
three of them he one now one later in
the car and one for tomorrow just
because
it's three hours away but oh my god it's
so good yep
yep shout out to the smelly deli i had
sold to somebody else and tim and baba
moved on and now it's not what it used
to be
very different now i'm still good but
not what it used to be
that's so funny when you said boulder i
was like yeah it's the fox the bird
yep yep uh baba two beef kiddos
like yep that's [ __ ] they sealed baba
at each other they both called each
other baba
baba two falafel hummus baba no hot
sauce like that's [ __ ] all you heard
in that place
you miss it dude miss it shout out to
the smelly deli
on the hill in boulder it's the place
bro
mike what else you got for us man we've
been going for a long [ __ ] time this
is a really good podcast
that's what i was just thinking when you
said we're trying to do more content i
was like [ __ ] we could split this show
i don't know what to do instead of us
there's no grown
knowledge or there's some nuggets hidden
in here but instead of giving them
[ __ ] two ramble box shows we'll just
get one really
good long ramble cast there are some
couple
really good nugget we could drop for
people who are still
listening um i know you people are still
listening
come up with something good bro cause
you're on the spot now man
i'm on patreon.com
yeah blazed and tired look at my eyes my
eyes usually aren't this red on this
podcast they're nice and toasty red
that dab of the honey banana and bananas
foster really put a [ __ ] twist on my
day that was kind of nice
if uh if if you've got ideas for what
should be behind me feel free to hit me
up on social media whichever one you
want to attack if you want my twitter
email the show or put it up on facebook
put it up on youtube what should be
behind me i just need to get you
just a plain colored background bro dark
plain black background
you uh you sent me the link for would be
work perfect i just need to get it
ordered
and uh get it attached to my ceiling
there you go guys patreon.com forward
slash
white mike he'll order that background
and if he doesn't do it soon i'll buy it
for him so it looks good on the show
add a couple of lights down here make it
a little less dingy
yeah mostly i'm just trying to blur out
my kid's got space behind me and i'm
just blurring out his stuff with
darkness
oh bro we're okay with the kids toys uh
somebody told me and i won't shout that
i'll shout them out shout out to the
person
said looks militant because i got a flag
behind me and i'm coming up all right
stuff all right it's time for the show
you're good there are plans in the
future to uh change some background
stuff but
you know time's coming time is coming
yep i got all self-conscious looking at
backgrounds i was like oh i like that
one but i don't know if i can put that
behind me or ooh there's a good 311 one
but i don't know if the band wants
my opinions on top of their logo yeah
don't do the band one dude
we'll get you a plain color one i'll
give you that thank you just a nice flat
black
flat gray one in the corner coming at
you you'll look good
make you look like humidor you'll be all
right
shout out to humidor chivador and the
portland cannabis tasting society i
think i got that right
yeah but even if that's not the right
group so that's a [ __ ] cool group
dabs are fun dabs are amazing debs have
gotten us a long way i think that's how
we started a lot of this ramble cast was
talking about
uh how this covid has uh how dabs have
gotten us through covet so
we looped it all the way back around
mike you're a good storyteller
my little project listeners that are
still with us i'm gonna
i've got to clean up and reset up my
tabletop buddha vape to go with a nice
hockey puck
some bubble hash i was gifted old school
bubble bag bubble hash
pressed into a puck like it's 94.
reminds me of a guy that used to pop up
in that old dispensary
he brought me a big old puck a bubble
hatch one time
these uh was out of nowhere i ran into
an old friend of mine and he was like
hey i ran into a guy that makes these
you want one i've got like six with me
i said sure it was like wait a second i
said sure to this now i've got this
beautiful puck of hash
what am i going to do with it i just
moved where's that vape again
so you're going to use this place and
get that wand
yeah luckily i'd spare parts get my vape
out and get it cleaned
get it set back up again hopefully it
still works so it was your intention
just to put the bubble hash
kind of break it off the chunk break it
up into kind of smaller pieces so it's
got more surface area and then just put
it directly into the wand part of the
vape
yeah the the vape loads up a lot like uh
a pipe would it's got a little screen in
it you throw some
i usually break off like two
green peas worth a hash and throw
those size chunks in there do a couple
of draws
with it hooked up to the heating element
so that the hash softens
and then get in there with a dab tool or
a paper clip
and give it a stir and really open up
that surface area
in your next three or four poles it's
like it hit the face of the shovel
perfect it's wonderful yeah we're gonna
have to get you some solvent list to try
like that as well
yeah i uh and the bubble actually is
solvent
but i mean some like some sho some
solventless honey oil
it looks like batter it's hard with
covid in the [ __ ] plague going on but
i'd like to hit
a handful of shops and really do just
kind of a tour of southern colorado and
see what people have for concentrate
that's not
bho or solvent extracts something that
would actually work in that that
tabletop vape
for a while there were a bunch of
different companies doing
bubble or key for dry sift
and they had a number of different
products on the market but for the last
couple years
i mean i haven't been looking but it
seems to me like most of the shops have
moved to
um solvent extract yeah diamonds and
sauce
there's a lot of uh solventless out
there uh solvent lists were like raws in
and
solventless honey oil pressed stuff
that's out there that's in big demand
but it's expensive right now
that's like its own special niche i talk
about uh
talk about autoflowers being like the
seed hoarders and collectors are a
special group of nerds but then
autoflowers and then like land race
those are your special niches
ah that's like there's concentrated
smokers there's [ __ ] connoisseurs
but then there's the [ __ ] heady heady
boys that are smoking the [ __ ]
solvent list and
just like 90 a gram and [ __ ] but it's
out there
i had a friend on facebook a real world
friend
post up you know hey i live in arizona
now how the [ __ ] y'all get ice cream
home here
and i just started laughing and i was
like oh girl
if you can't figure out how to get ice
cream home like we're trying to move 50
and 80 90 gram hash
home in a hundred degree heat yeah you
can't be having that ship melt in the
car
these people show up to the [ __ ]
dispensary with the cooler yeah
yeah last two times i've gone to a
dispensary man ice packs in the cooler
it's the only way to fly yep it's i'm
not gonna drop 200 on hash and get home
and have it all glued into a corner
yeah nope not again uh that's why
people sometimes when i show up people
ask me if i'm grub hub
because i carry a white cooler with me
i've got the white cooler with me
because i've got
a couple of water bottles in there that
are frozen now they're keeping
everything cool
yep i got a can of butane in there i got
a torch i got a rig
my rig is in the cooler because now when
it's hot outside like it was a hundred
and [ __ ] four degrees today bro
uh imagine if you left the rig in the
car the rig is gonna be hot as [ __ ] when
you put it to your mouth the glass is
gonna
wow 110 degree water that's done yeah
the water is going to be sizzling when
you go to
steam in your lungs and [ __ ] it's
miserable my rig was in the [ __ ]
cooler
it's like hitting chilled water it's so
nice when you hit it
my concentrates are all nice and fresh
they're in a cooler
so that's why i've got a cooler i'm not
grub hub i'm
dab hub yeah the the dispensary is only
15 minutes away from my house but it's
104 degrees the half hour i'm in the
dispensary
it doesn't matter how cool my car was on
the way over there it's [ __ ] hot and
[ __ ] when i come out
but i pop open that cooler toss my hash
inside grab a nice cold drink
roll home in comfort yep hell yeah yeah
life is good bro covet is weird man
i think the first time i left the house
in like 15 days was to go to dispensary
and there were like 10 people waiting in
line it was crowded
i had to stop going to one dispensary
for a couple days because they're like
hey
um you're back something wrong i was
like nope
[ __ ] bored you didn't interact with
other people
and why not pick up two more grams while
i'm here i wanted to see if my voice
works i haven't [ __ ] used it in a day
i want to see if anybody else could hear
me
right yeah talk to someone that wasn't
my kids right all i did was hand you my
id and say two of these please but this
is [ __ ] exciting
yeah yep
let's go [ __ ] grocery shopping for
like uh
one item i don't even know what i need
but i'll go find one
how about this bottle of kombucha that
looks good all right i've been here in
the store for 30 minutes i should
[ __ ] get out of here now
just walked around and looked at nothing
right
i uh yeah whenever i have to leave i end
up dawdling now
like if i run out for i need one thing
i'll spend 40 minutes walking around
that store being like am i sure i don't
need a second thing
yep i went to the mall for a pair of
shoes the other day and i looked at
every store in that mall there were no
people there so she was like well we've
got them all to ourselves so we just
cruised and [ __ ]
shopped it was awesome like when we
walked into the mall the people in the
stores the people like hey welcome it's
so good to see you can i help you with
anything would you like to
like can i get something off the top
shelf something off the bottom shelf
would you like that in a different color
like maybe we've got in the back for you
what were you looking for what's your
name do you know if any other people may
come here today because
because i feel like i'm a hostage right
now like they're just [ __ ]
yeah yeah the mall was fun
oh yeah i went and tried to i had to go
get a propane tank refilled
and i ended up getting propane
accessories i did not get propane
accessories but i did come home with
almost 200
in t-shirts one of them better have hank
hill on it
no no hank hill it's just the store
that's got the propane refill also has
the best shirts so
you make it sound like we live next to
like like the [ __ ] hicks gas station
in town now
we do we do get propane insurance at
walmart uh
big r that was my next guest bro that
was my next guess
carhart shirts and propane yo our lives
are different buddy
they are our lives are different it's
all right
this is an off the rails [ __ ] show
but i've been trying to keep it that way
too i've seen
opportunities 200 episodes i've seen
good opportunities to talk about
cannabis and i just flat out refused i
was like nope we're gonna go
route b for this it's just been fun
it's been a long show we've been going
for probably an hour and 25 minutes bro
so if you do get tired you need to break
probably mention that the last two times
i bought flower in town it was trimmed
so people are listening
they took that advice thank you for
trimming your [ __ ]
yeah thank you guys we do prefer trimmed
weed
yup now next step now that we're
trimming it
get rid of the goddamn boveda packs
i'm torn on the boveda packs in the
dispensary because that damn jar is open
and closed so many times
that i don't know i kind of i've got do
you want the crunch or do you want the
boveda pack that's like your options
right now and it's i know it's like
[ __ ] [ __ ] sandwich or a [ __ ] punch
to the balls
but you take your pick it
uh it is a toss-up and it is difficult
and i don't envy the people that have to
fight with the humidity levels in the
in the jars of the product but um
the system where they open the jar in
the morning and select
a display nug and that's the one they're
showing to people and there's a [ __ ]
playground so it's not like people are
smelling [ __ ] now
right um the the shops i've been going
to lately
they've just moved a glass display case
and they get the the jar close to you
yeah so that you can see it good but you
can't
smell it because now you're looking at
it through a layer of glass and it's
still in a jar
you don't know what it smells like to
you get it home and you open it up and
take a whiff but uh
um that little display jar that people
could smell and look at
before the plague hit was uh was my
favorite method and then at the end of
the day you take that one nug that has
gotten
dried out from getting sniffed by 80
people you throw that back in the
the larger jar to rehydrate and even up
and it keeps the whole jar from getting
aired out 15-20 times a day
the other solution is pre-packaged dates
and people [ __ ] hate pre-packs
they think for some reason they're going
to rip me off
like bro it's a dispensary we're not the
[ __ ]
we're not some shady dealer we're right
here we're right here on this address
every day the signs out front
like if you think it doesn't away come
back we'll check it out it'll be all
right
like the last two pre-packs i bought
weren't bad the two before that
were crap um but i knew what i was
getting
it's you can always tell
when it's half the price it's supposed
to be there's oh yeah
yep um and if it's in a store that
reason's probably not because it's
stolen it's probably because it's shitty
so if it's in an alley it could go
either way
one of my favorite shops in denver it
doesn't exist anymore but they've one of
some of the regulations they gave up but
they were one of the first that i
appreciated their pre-pack because they
were
slamming busy and i don't need i don't
need the reason we used to weigh our
weed in front of each other
is because i don't trust you you want to
see that it says 3.5 on the scale
you want to know that and i'm going to
count your money you're going to watch
the scale that's how business works
it's a dispensary i don't they do weigh
your meat if you go to the butcher but
you don't get your cereal weight in
front of you you don't get
everything weighed out in front it comes
in cans and boxes and you trust that it
says eight ounces
[ __ ] on the package i think cannabis
is we're there with the cannabis so
uh it's so much quicker there'd be a
line out the door at this place because
they were the slamminess dispensary and
it was a little tiny [ __ ] shack of a
shop
and they'd just spend all night
pre-weighing [ __ ] so that tomorrow the
shop can flow
instead of [ __ ] two blood tender
center going 3.5 again
3.5 again what do you want an 8 of this
in eighth of this okay 3.5
seal it up put a sticker on it put the
jar away get the other jar out
nah they sat there all night or there's
somebody in the back right now
just weighing out this whole pound will
be eights and if you want eights
we got them if you want a quarter you
get two eights if you want an ounce you
get eight eights
like they just bet they're busting them
out it's way better i think it's way
more efficient
and the product stays fresh vastly more
efficient
but
they didn't weigh all my concentrates in
front of me and i trust them [ __ ] out of
me
i uh it's not that it's knocking away
when it's um the last two i bought
they were in a clear packaging it looked
i mean it was a different shape but it
was essentially the packaging you get
a cheap toothbrush in like there was a
backing to it and then it had a clear
plastic bubble
that was full of herb and it was
colorado packaging compliance so it was
a [ __ ] to open in yada yada but
you could see into the pack and tell
that
it was quality looking herb that was
well trimmed and
not all stems and the the two
that i pre-packs that i bought before
that that were bad
both of them were like little pebble
nugs little gravel sized nugs
and had [ __ ] fan leaf in it
not sugar leaf not wasn't trimmed well
actual chunks of fan leaf
and in the pre-packaged tins
chunks of fan leaf and then huge sticks
for no reason
like there's a little popcorn nug on the
end and then a long stick for no reason
it's like why is this in my container
yeah a packager did this on purpose they
should be fired
yeah yeah just not accepting that
the first time you end up with that it's
so hard to buy a pre-pack
after that um my experience with
pre-rolls
three four years ago or why i haven't
had a pre-roll in three or four years
it's just i can't trust it i don't like
when people go to the dispensary and buy
the cheapest
product in the store and then leave a
bad review based on the cheapest product
they could have [ __ ] bought
that drives me crazy i bought a pre-roll
and it tastes terrible it was one of the
two dollar pre-rolls well
bro what did you expect yeah they didn't
put the gold on the [ __ ] bottom shelf
for two bucks you got to buy at least a
middle shelf product to leave a quality
review
the only time i really really supported
that complaint
was when a shop was doing if you're a
veteran you get a pre-roll for
i can't remember if it was a penny a
dime or a quarter or a dollar
i think it was a quarter um
it was stupid cheap for a pre-roll it
was seven or eight or nine dollars
cheaper than anywhere else
but you had to be a vet to go get the
deal and i had more than one
vet telling me that they heard about the
deal were excited about it
went in and tried it and ended up
getting
like trim material rolled into
a cone and were they were really pissed
that they were getting sold leaf
um and told it was a standard quality
from that place um i thought
i thought at that point they really had
a decent complaint but it's just a
regular person
like if you ask me for the cheapest [ __ ]
on the the shelf don't be surprised
it's not also the best quality cheapest
[ __ ] on the shelf
uh you just reminded me of a random oh
go ahead i'm gonna write down my topic
but you keep going and i'll take a dab
i saw a shop uh this spring
that uh they had their normal jars on
the shelf and a couple of
manager special sales or whatever but
one of the shelves it was a jar that was
mark special
with a sign that said last year's
outdoor seated
and then it was 50 an ounce instead i
think their next cheapest out the door
ounce was 89.99 or 99 bucks or whatever
um so it was substantially cheaper per
gram or whatever
per ounce but you knew what you were
getting going in it wasn't like you'd
get it home and discover
that it was that's why it's cheaper yeah
that's legit if you tell me
i saw that and i was like why is that
hard why can't other people just be up
front like that
it's so easy to just throw that up on
the side and let people know
for those of you not watching on youtube
jeff's taking a nice size dab here
really pretty butter nice big dab
nice big vapor cloud he's going to be
quiet for a minute while
that goes to his brain so i'll just keep
rambling if you need a rescue i totally
have a good ramble
do you just give me two good topics uh
we had a jar show up at a dispensary we
didn't know what it's called
random weed in a baggie somebody forgot
to label it you know stoned owners
i labeled it stinky peter
and that sounds like somebody's name
right now sounds like a guy named stinky
peter
until the first customer everyone's like
why'd you call it stinky peter the first
customer came in and
said can i smell your steam they stopped
themselves
and everybody heard it and they [ __ ]
thought it was great
can i smell your stinky peter well said
something can i check out your stinky
peter
that phrase happened so many times
throughout the day and it was well worth
putting that [ __ ] label on the jar
stinky peter uh it was a discount jar we
gave sneaky peter out for super cheap
i have a really reliable source in the
cannabis
packaging industry big shout out to one
of the
uh best cannabis packagers in the
[ __ ] weed game
she doesn't need her name said she knows
who she is i'm proud of you she's
kicking ass
uh she may have told me that there is a
national
cone shortage raw cannot provide
cones because the company the factory
that makes them is shut down
due to corona so the pre-rolls and cones
are out for them at their grow at their
facility they don't have any more that's
[ __ ] they can't order anymore and
pretty soon
that will ripple out to other states and
areas
my lighting just went weird in the
camera that was strange but
yeah pre-rolls are [ __ ] they can't
get any cones dude
the the ripples from covid
are going to keep bouncing coast to
coast for
honestly i put my money on christmas
next year
is the earliest
we're gonna really head back to normal
to what it was like in the middle of
um but every day it seems like i hear
about a new one where somebody's like
can't get watermelons it's like why not
it's like
because the trucks that ship them don't
have tires because the tire factory
yep like there's so many of those yeah i
was wondering when it was gonna really
start [ __ ] with the cannabis industry
um immediately i kind of smiled because
like i really doubt they're doing their
gorilla inspections
now where they go hit 55 shops in a day
oh yeah that's not expectations that's
not happening right now yeah
there are growth in any industry there
are shortages of
soil you can't get soil deliveries right
now uh
soil is short nutrients are short a lot
of [ __ ] is sure all the plastic stuff is
in demand the
i mean on the commercial scale how many
different trucks show up every week
it's daunting um there's a truck guy
there's a nutrients guy there's a pots
guy there's a piping guy
there's some places have a water guy
yeah
there's a co2 guy co2 guy that falls
asleep um
so many different deliveries if any part
of that chain hitches
like your co2 guy can't come for a
couple weeks that's gonna [ __ ] up your
harvest oh yeah your harvest is your
harvest is 30
smaller than it was last time that's
going to [ __ ] with your store supply you
can't get
soil delivered or cocoa delivered
[ __ ] cones
dude the cones are really gonna [ __ ]
with people there's whole dispensary
outfits
whose sole business is based on cones
existing
i know a couple of people who their jobs
are to roll cones all day
that's what they do i just read an
article
some dispensaries somewhere not in
colorado it was in another state it just
had to
um destroy thousands of free
i think that's totally fake the chick
was licking
guarantee guarantee you there's another
one where they have to toss
it was 2.6 million dollars at cartridges
and that the company's destroying it
because they won't move
and they're trash now because the the
market base has no confidence
that the state can test for
i think in that state the big fear is
lead
um but coming off all of the vaping
freer
from last year it was clearly a cutting
edge in the cartridges
so yeah what happened to that some
cartridges just
the now we got murder hornets tiger king
murder hornets
vape carts killing people i think what
happened predominantly
now the little kids are in wayfarer
cabinets that's what happened um
i think the black market
business just they got hit hard
and the anyone still surviving in that
marketplace has drastically re-uh
restructured their business model
they might have had to allegedly
i knew a guy whose twin brother's cousin
would buy a packaging that looks just
like that
you can order that packaging on a
website i won't say the name of the
website you can buy that exact packaging
and you can buy
those carts and they're empty
and allegedly i knew a guy that in
another state his hustle was to buy
carts that looked like that and fill
them up with his homemade oil
and sell them as that brand's carts for
a [ __ ] premium price in an illegal
state
and then all this scarab [ __ ] carts
came out and his business went
to zero yep there's uh
it doesn't surprise me at all um
unless you can be sure that you're
buying a regulated safe
inspected tested yep um
if it [ __ ] me up there's a a method for
me to be like
why did you do that jeff like you can
track it back to whoever
yeah we can see which plant it came from
we could see which facility it was made
i'd be shocked if that's still a thing
and that's clearly where all the nasty
carts were coming from
yeah i've got some numbers on the back
here i don't know which one is which but
i could see the
uh the growth facility the processing
facility and a couple other numbers on
here so if something went wrong with
this i would know who to contact
would be pretty easy the distributor
number
the processing lab number and the grow
number and
and batch number yep it's all right
there on the back
yeah so you'd call the dispensary or go
there and say hey this is moldy
and then [ __ ] call the producer or
just roll down the chain
they'd probably just give you a free one
but you know it feels worse than that
one for a penny because you can't do
free in colorado that's true
uh mike i'm stoned and [ __ ] running
out of energy buddy i'm getting tired
you want to start wrapping up
this [ __ ] scramble fest yeah we went
for long enough
it's been a beautiful podcast this has
been
an immense pleasure jeffrey thank you
for having me tonight oh man thanks for
this is perfect thanks for making time
to hang out
thank you still listening yo you rule
thank you
so much for listening hit us up on
social media let us know you start the
show
um thank you so much for being part of
the ire army y'all
how do they find you on social media bro
since you said hit you up on social
media
you can find me on facebook at pueblo
for sensible cannabis laws you can find
me on twitter
at nemopunk15 you can find me on patreon
at patreon.com
whitemike beautifully done or you can
email jeffrey and at the top of the
email put forward this to mike
yeah and i will do that uh my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
i look forward to your questions
comments corrections concerns or any
type of feedback thanks for listening to
this ramble fest
again mike thank you for hanging out bro
it was a pleasure to have you for we got
you for a long time tonight i hope that
people enjoyed
the killer show i loved it and if not
listen to the next episode they've
already tuned out anyway so that's just
fine
hug a hater you guys give a hater a big
old hug and whisper right in their
earbud
i love you i love you hater so weird i
love making people feel weird
um let's do this part uh if you feel
like this episode was educational
informative or entertaining i would love
your support on patreon patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
the information you need is right there
don't forget to check out the sponsor
seeds herenow.com
uh they got under seeds for under 30
bucks they've got irene genetics 30
bucks
under they got the cravings under 30.
use coupon code gfyh10 while checking
out at seeds here now that will save you
a few bucks if you're only buying one
pack that'll cover the cost of shipping
basically
uh and if you're getting multiple packs
you buy more packs
you know that's how you do it tell the
wife it's pandemic time you never know
when these sales are going to happen
like this again
got to get some seeds wife just how it
goes uh seeds here now.com coupon code
gfyh10
uh email is girlfromyourhearthotmail.com
i really think that's all we've got for
this long ass podcast episode we've paid
the bills we've covered the business we
had a good time
we came we saw let's went mike that's
the part we got to do now i feel
conquered
um i guess that means i win
um yeah mike thanks for hanging out you
guys i'll be back in a couple of days
with fresh new content let's give a big
shout out to my friend william law
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me