all right here we go welcome to the show
i'm your host my friends call me rasta
jeff and it is time for episode
562 of the grow from your heart podcast
this episode of the show is brought to
you by our friends at seedshearnow.com
seedshearnow.com offers seeds from all
of the industry's
leading breeders including miss jill
genetics duke diamond and of course
iregenetics
everything at seeds herenow.com is
backed by an award-winning satisfaction
guarantee
and for my friends on a tight budget
seeds herenow.com offers several packs
for under 30.
as well as amazing monthly sales make
sure to use coupon code gfyh10 while
checking out to save a few bucks
again that is coupon code gfyh10 while
checking out
at seeds here now.com
you know i like to start the podcast off
by talking about what i'm smoking
today was a long day i've done a lot of
podcasting and a lot of hanging out i
was on a couple of other podcasts
earlier big shout out to the dude grows
show
hung out with scottie reel and guru and
james bean earlier today
took a few dabs on that show took a few
dabs throughout the day
i've been dabbing a lot of great stuff
i've been dabbing crescendo live
batter from green dot labs i've been
dabbing some chem brulee from green dot
labs
and of course i've got a little bit of
the bananas foster
from green dot labs all of them are
tremendous all of them are delicious
that is why i seem heavily medicated
today it's been a long podcasting day
it was 95 for part of the day it was a
really hot day
ah i feel like it has cooled off quite a
bit and it is time to do a good podcast
so
let's jump right into it this is the
part of the show where we do shout outs
to the members of the 710 club of course
the 710 club
are the folks who support the podcast on
patreon at the seven dollar and ten cent
a month level or higher
so with no further ado let's give a big
girl from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to my friend aaron
let's send a big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to rasta k
let's send a big thank you shout out to
brett c i've always got a big thank you
shout out and a fist bump for my friend
ez057
i also want to send a thank you shout
out to juan rios i've always got a big
thank you shout out for flame
beard gross thank you for all the
support i also want to send a big
thank you shout out to john b let's also
send a big thank you shout out to
tonto's garden
and also i want to say to thank you to
redbeard then last but certainly not
least i want to send a special
thank you shout out to my friend eric
ross big thanks
big shout out to everybody who supports
the show on patreon
if you're not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need will be
right there on the screen once again
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who supports the show
all right let's not waste too much time
i have got a lot of great questions for
this episode
the first question on today's podcast
goes
just like this it says hey i'll be in
the live again i just thought i'd try my
luck i can't find this information
anywhere
so i think they're starting off by
saying they found me through my
instagram live feed
every monday around 7 10 p.m mountain
time
i jump on instagram live and i hang out
with my friends i take a bunch of dabs
and i ramble for about a solid
hour my instagram gives you one full
hour i'm there until they cut me off
most of the time
i try to field all of the questions that
come up in the chat i have
no way of predicting what may come up in
the chat so if you ask a question in the
chat
i'll kind of answer it if it's something
i want to ramble on and rant on i'll get
going for a few minutes
sometimes those mini rants turn into
podcast episodes
it's a great way to connect with me and
hang out mondays on instagram i'm irie
underscore genetics
check us out there on mondays i do leave
the videos up so many of the older
videos are up there
a couple of them got deleted [ __ ]
happens with instagram
but that's why we use cannabis let's
stay focused anyway this listener
was checking out the instagram live
they're going to jump in again on
another monday and try to get their
question answered but have no fear
because i'm going to read your question
here on the show it says
i'm growing in cocoa a 4x4 scrog i just
filled the net was going
to flip to flower tomorrow but i noticed
powdery mildew on the lower and some of
the other leaves
i stripped and the lower big fan leaves
at the bottom
and then it says i will use a product
they listed the product
and then it says do i wait or do i begin
flowering i'm so grateful
for any help and i fully understand that
you are busy stay
blessed um i really believe that if
you've got powdery mildew when you were
considering flipping the flower
i would wait i would wait until that
problem is under control get that
corrected
get the the issue at hand corrected get
the
reason causing the issue corrected
there's a reason why this is happening
something is incorrect in the room the
vpd is off
you're not evacuating humidity quickly
enough something's going on in there so
we need to get more airflow we need to
remove humidity from the room we need to
solve the problem
and also treat the plants at the same
time we can keep spraying the plants
with [ __ ] we can keep putting band-aids
on the plants but they will keep getting
powdery mildew if we don't correct the
room
so the overall solution is correct the
then correct the plants or tree both at
the same time solve the problem
then go into flowers so set yourself up
for success
uh if you put these plants into flower
and they've got powdery mildew
it's going to get worse the powdery
mildew will get worse and then your
options for treating that powdery mildew
will get minimized as time goes on once
you've got bud set
chunkier buds you cannot start doing
different things for those
powdery mildew problems i got way off
course there but i think you know what
i'm saying once we get buds we can't
spray with some [ __ ] so
we don't want to get buds now we want to
solve the problem
treat the plants rid of the rid the room
of the powdery mildew
then put the healthy clean plants into
flour
all right you did not include your name
so i don't know who to thank for this
great message but i hope i gave you some
good grow advice
big thanks and big shout out and i hope
you have solved your powdery
mildew problem there are a lot of things
you can do for the powdery mildew now
i think that double nickel and cease are
great products for that
there are a lot of great fungicides out
there that will solve that problem
depending on the intensity
but honestly the main thing right now is
to solve
the problem what is causing that powdery
mildew in the room we could spray the
plants all day
but if we don't take care of the issue
it will keep coming back
all right i've got another great message
here in front of me this one comes from
our friend tyler what's up tyler
been talking to you on social media hope
you're doing well this one goes man i'm
a big fan of yours i'm a big fan of
yours as well bro thank you
it says i really hope to slab dab with
you one day man i'm getting older those
slab dabs are killing me
do you go through phases this is just a
side note a good rant a rosta jeff
moment here
you go through phases where you can
smoke all of the dabs and you don't get
high
and then you go through phases where you
can just open the jar and you get
obliterated
this week has been one of the weeks
where i take a dab and every dab has
made me go
oh [ __ ] it's a it's a great thing it's
been cost effective of course today i
smoked
nearly three grams of concentrates today
but it's been a long day today is not a
normal day
ah but this has been one of the phases
where i just take a fat dab in my body's
like oh you're high bro you should sit
down for a minute
i'm not complaining it's been it's like
i'm a cheap date lately which is
always nice because on those weeks when
i smoke and smoke and smoke and nothing
happens i feel like i just burned
through the concentrates
that gets quite expensive a little bit
spendy but slab dab
uh bro i'm smoking these diamonds in
this batter uh that gets expensive
throwing down slab dabs but if you're
down i'll try it but i'm getting older
man my lungs are gonna blow out
i just know where the hospital is if we
go too hard it goes on to say i have a
question
good that's what we're here for what's
the one strain you would recommend of a
fan
of yours to buy so i can keep a mother
to remember you by
bro am i dying and nobody told me why do
you need something to remember me by
that's weird bro no i get what you're
saying ah just when you say it like that
she's like
you make me feel like i'm [ __ ] dying
and nobody told me yet what do you know
that i don't know bro
um what one strain would i recommend to
remember me by to grow a mother plant
out of and then they recommend
orangegasm
it says i'd like to do that i've got
some mothers from my dgc
free seed pack that mean more than
anything that mean
more to me than the 200 packs i have
purchased you know
ah wow that's a good sentence i do like
the big stoney indicas greasy buds that
press into terpy rosin
are more important than profile of the
high to me honestly so you prefer greasy
buds
with turpee rosin over the profile of
the high alright then it says keep on
rocking brother
you're a real cool dude thank you bro i
appreciate that you're a one bad
[ __ ] yourself
uh what am i gonna recommend here for
somebody that wants to remember me
uh you said stoney indica most of what i
breed is more of a real
head racy sativa i think the orange gasm
may be a really good thing to remember
me by somebody made me a nice plaque
uh sent me a real nice letter it had an
orange gasm package in it lately orange
gasm has been the hit
uh orange gasm has been the best seller
out of all of them the photos have been
[ __ ] amazing
so that may be a good one to remember me
by of course there is
lemon jeffrey it's got my name on the
damn package so maybe lemon jeffrey
it's tall it smells funny and it will
kick your ass so
lemon jeffrey you know but stony indicas
i would say maybe morning do since you
want that
indica that indica funk and then you
said uh stony profile
uh more important than the high terpy
rosin more important than the profile of
the high so
yeah you're gonna get that skunky
funkiness uh
but also stony indica i think morning
dew may be the one for you so
if you want the oranges go for the the
orange gasm if you want more of a skunky
stoney thing that's what i would say go
for the morning do so those are the two
of the three because i put lemon jeffrey
in there as well so man it really sounds
like i'm dying and nobody told me about
it that's what's on my mind now
so those are the three strains i would
recommend for you tyler i hope i
answered your question well
um orangegasm because it's just been a
hit lately it's been my number one
seller which means you guys love it
which means i'm obviously in love with
it which means it's a hit it's gonna
keep getting made
uh lemon jeffrey's got my name in it
because i really love that cross the
limonene is beautiful for me
but you prefer something more indica
that's why i'm gonna say morning do
for you all right tyler i hope i
answered your question well
a big thank you for the patreon support
look forward to hearing from you again
in the patreon messages that's right you
guys i answer a lot of messages
the easiest way to get in touch with me
is through patreon patreon.com forward
slash grow from your heart all of the
info you need is there
i do try to answer all of those patreon
messages on at least a
bi-weekly basis we've got another great
message here from patreon
it says hey my friend thanks for
answering about my herbs now dryer i've
heard it works great
i did mention an herbs dryer machine on
the podcast before i said that i may not
be a fan of it
when i said that i didn't think i would
like it so many people sent me messages
saying bro you should really try it out
it's a great product i use it i love it
so i may stand corrected i haven't used
it myself so i can't endorse it
but i've gotten a lot of positive
reviews and nobody has told me that they
do not like it so
that's a great thing it goes on to say
i'm listening to you and mike right now
on
8 20 2020 the freestyle shows like these
are really cool and i just want to tell
you
i appreciate you helping me get through
work ah man
thank you and i know exactly how that
feels i used to run commercial
cultivation facilities and sometimes the
days would just freaking drag on
and i would put joe rogan in my ear i
would put the dude gross crew in my ear
and those guys would make the day go by
so thank you i'm glad i'm able to do
that for you
uh thank you for noticing it thank you
for listening and obviously thank you
for the patreon
support it says you always talk about
wondering what people do
uh what people do that they can listen
to this podcast as they work yeah what
are you doing all day bro
it says i'm a professional powder coater
and wet painter
and i listen to your podcast while i
paint military
vehicle parts as well as medical
equipment
wow that is cool um i know what powder
coating is uh my uncle
uh he's gone now love you eric rest in
peace bro a lot of my family damn
grandma too i love you grandma the
recipe's grandma [ __ ] a lot of them
worked at a place in california where
they did powder coating
i was lucky enough to get some bike
parts bike parts powder coated you say
that three times fast
i had some bike parts powder coated and
my bike looked [ __ ] cool i had solar
black handlebars
solar black forks nobody in town knew
what was up with my powder coated
handlebars and forks that was cool but
so i know what powder coating is it's
got to be fun painting military vehicles
and medical equipment i bet you get
a lot of quality paint a lot of fun
experience get to see a lot of great
[ __ ]
uh you don't just paint the same random
[ __ ] every day that's probably cool
i'm gonna quit rambling and focus on the
message here it goes on to say
i love what you are doing man and i am
starting a podcast now to help spread
content and i'm interviewing master
growers who run
facilities and i'm also interviewing
breeders
it's a good idea i like that i want to
do more interviews i just don't feel
confident everybody says just do it
you're talkative you can interview
people
i feel like i cut people off and i i'm
gonna get more people on the show i
promise you it will happen
i had a couple obstacles in the way i
think we're clearing those up we're
gonna get it going
let me keep going here uh it says i
aspire to be as
big in the podcast world as you and
maybe if i get a big following
i can have you on the show um
feels weird when you say get as big in
the podcast world as me i'm just a
little show bro
uh sometimes i pop up in the top 100 on
stitcher and the education category
just a little show just a normal dude
doing my thing a one-man production here
i do appreciate uh that you think it's a
giant thing
i try to stay humble and realize it's
just a guy in a microphone doing what i
meant to do
i appreciate that as for getting me on
your podcast i've got a better idea
and this means this i'm not trying to
sound egotistical here this is really
the way that i think it would work for
both of us marketing wise instead of me
going on your show
not many people know of your show it's
new that's how it goes new shows not a
big exposure not a big audience nobody
knows about you yet
people are listening to the show you say
you want to be as big as my show uh
come on my show tell us about your show
on my show
expose yourself don't expose yourself
keep your clothes on expose your show
to my audience and that way people can
hear you on my show and my audience will
hear you if i go on your show
uh chances are this is where it sounds
egotistical chances are your
small new audience knows of my bigger
show already so you're going to get more
benefit if you come here
and will spread you to a bigger audience
just a larger catapult
will get you going and then you can post
the episode where you're on my show
i'll give you permission to post that
episode on your feed
so you can get rosta jeff on your feed
have your interview up there you get
free content you get a whole new episode
for your feed that way
uh we call it a swap cast we both get a
show out of our time
works well we'll both get exposure but i
think that's the way to do it is get you
up here on my show
i'll make a little intro for it put the
music on and stuff make it look real
killer
uh but no offense to your show or
anything i just think that marketing
wise that is probably the better
strategery is to have you come be on the
show via zoom
uh something like that uh i think i hope
that works for you
uh by the way i'm gonna mention the name
of your show it says the show is called
talking buds
i'm gonna have to check that out for you
it says first episode wasn't great
quality
but it is all on the platforms if you
ever bored and want to check it out you
guys there's a new podcast out there
called talking buds with a z budz it's
on all of the platforms he says it's
poor quality
but you know what's cool about a poor
quality first podcast this means
you got [ __ ] plenty of room for
improvement if you put out that [ __ ]
number 10 on the first episode you
wouldn't have anything else to do you'd
have to keep putting out [ __ ] tens
and it's hard i put out like solid
eights nines i try for tens but
tens are i think tens are [ __ ] that's
that's doing something i put out eights
and nines every week twice a week
if it was a seven i re-record it i don't
you won't get a seven but don't be
upset with yourself about putting out a
sub par
first episode that's totally legit you
could do that ah
you got nowhere to go but up from there
i'm gonna get back on track it says uh
but i'm trying to help get rid of the
stigma from cannabis and you and my
white mike have helped push me to do my
part have an irie day homie
much love sorry for rambling bro never
be sorry for rambling in an email to me
i am one of the kings as i think the
cool kids now say i'm the ceo
of rambling so i'll be the ceo uh don't
ever be shy to ramble to me they like it
when we ramble
podcasting is just people talking so
sometimes the side tangents are where
the [ __ ] gold comes out
so i appreciate your message uh thank
you for starting a podcast and thank you
for acknowledging that mike and i
were a big inspiration mike do you hear
that bro we helped this guy
get inspired to start a podcast i like
you we should listen
i'm going to leave this note here on the
side of the table and i'm going to check
out talking buds
maybe i'll give you an episode or two to
get going but like i said bro get a
couple episodes under your belt
uh in the feed maybe three to five
episodes have something going on i'll
listen to all of them i'll have some
content i'll know about you a little bit
we'll get you on my show
we'll just do like a 20 minute little
talk maybe 30 minutes or so
talk about you talk about your show
they'll pitch each other real quick and
then we'll send you on your merry way
and then we'll post on both of our feeds
uh but do that once you've got a couple
of episodes going up we could check them
out see what you got going on
of course you gotta you gotta have
something for me to check out before i
could really fully endorse you that may
get crazy to bring you on the show and
you're just completely crazy
that could be fun [ __ ] it let's do it
we'll see what happens anyway contact me
again bro i'll check out your show
and we will get our new friend from uh
what's it called talking buds podcast on
the show i'll let him interview me i'll
interview him at the same time
it'll be a good time we'll tag team the
whole show it'll be fun all right
thank you for the message bro did you
include a name here whose name do you
want me to say
you didn't put a name here so just once
again shout out to the talking buds
podcast they'll be on the show in the
future all right we can both practice
interviewing people on that episode and
get a little more comfortable
all right i do have another episode
another episode i wish i had a whole
nother episode
i've got another email here in front of
me this one
comes from a person who calls themselves
monkey with a u
and it goes hey ross to jeff please note
let me make sure
um well now he just said not to mention
his identity but
ah bro your name is monkey so that's
cool long time fan of who
a long time fan who finally got the
opportunity to purchase some of your
genetics
i'm in week five a flower with the
golden goat s1 and i have noticed many
many of the leaves have a bud growing
from the center
i know what you're talking about so he's
got golden goat s ones
that is a golden goat feminized seed he
said that he has got
uh is it leaves or buds let me make sure
which ones i've seen both of the leaves
have a bud growing from the center so
you've got a leaf so say your bud is
coming up here and you've got a leaf
coming out of the plant
and then there's where it spreads out it
makes the fingery leaf right about the
palm but facing up there's a little
nugget farming just one
calyx forming right there i've seen that
i think i know
a common denominator of when and why
that happens but let's keep reading
it says i was curious if this was a
mutation
that you had seen commonly i've never
seen this in the golden goat i've seen
this in jack the ripper
i've seen this in a few other strains
mostly uh sativa
tropical type varietals is where i've
seen it it says i've been growing her
organically using down to earth 444 for
veg and dr
earth 394 flower girl during flower
they're quite close to the whites
as i am very limited in a very limited
height area so i figured it could easily
be a stress
issue amazing podcast and incredible
work i can't wait to finally try
what i've heard so much about you know
i've never seen that happen
and it's weird if you've got multiple
phenotypes doing that
because that is something happening in
your room if it was just one plant
i would say that's a total anomaly in
the genetics you've got multiple plants
doing it in your room it's something
happening in there
honestly i think the reason for a plant
to spit out extra buds like that is
because it's
super happy with life it's like
bro i'm so happy those parts of the
plant that it's making are its
reproductive organs it's like
so happy i'm so horny and happy i'm
gonna make more
sex organs on different parts just so i
can get even hornier
and have more happy parts that's really
what i think is happening the plant is
so happy
it's like i've got so much light so much
nutrients everything is dialed in so
well
i'm just gonna make more buds for this
guy here you go it's trying to give you
more flowers
it's got so much energy it doesn't know
where to put those buds so it popped up
right there that's really what i think
is happening
there could be more of a scientific
answer that i'm unaware of but from when
i've seen this happen
it is always tropical sativa varietal
plants that were really
really happy so that's what i think is
happening i don't think it's a problem i
think you've got happy plants
so monkey i want to thank you for the
message i would like an update this was
sent a little bit back
i'd like to see how this crop is doing
how it went uh send me some pictures
uh send me an update on those golden
goat s ones i'd like to
likes to know how that went all right
i'm gonna get my voice together get my
thoughts together and we're gonna read
another email this one comes from i
don't know if they want their name said
it's got their full name here at the top
it says
hey my name is busy there we go they
gave us a good name feel free to use my
name and this entire email
thank you bro says i have a question
about types of pollen or
outcomes all right i love a good pollen
question breeding questions are some of
my favorites
i'll share a lot but i keep some to
myself this one is going to be good it
says
it's hard to explain but i will try my
best
i'm in it says i have a strawberry
banana female
so far i follow you i also have a
strawberry eclair female alright so you
like strawberry
flavored plants you like strawberry
banana strawberry eclair
sounds like [ __ ] i could get into it
says i plan on selfing each one to have
seeds to store for the future i follow
you so far
if i take pollen from the bubble gum cut
and add it to the a clear cut
with the phenol outcomes very much if i
would add pollen
in the opposite declared a bubble gum
seems like a silly
question but i would like to hear your
thoughts yes there will be variation
um depict and it just depends on the
dominance of the genetics that you're
using
so both of those plants have
grandparents or both those plants have
parents which are going to be
grandparents of your new offspring so
your strawberry eclair
and your strawberry banana have
different
there's a different at least one
different parent and they're possibly
two i don't know what the cross you got
the word strawberry in both of them
i'm going to assume there's one common
parent and then two different parents in
there
so different phenotypes of those plants
are going to show different expressions
then when you breed to them you may see
so
we took the grandparents the
grandparents we made the new parents we
crossed those
you may see these grandparents come up
in some phenotypes
depending on the way that you did it and
it all depends on which grandpa in which
grandma was more dominant and which
mommy and witch daddy was more dominant
so you've got the opportunity to see
this plant
this plant and these two plants on the
family tree so you can see mommy
and you can see mommy's grandparents and
you can see daddy and daddy's
grandparents
coming through some of those phenotypes
and it's all about
which plant had the genetics it's all
it's a gamble and a dice roll of which
way those genetics are going to land so
you will see
varying phenotypes depending on just how
those
genetics land it's kind of a gamble it's
like putting up a chart you get so many
attribute points on this chart and
they're going to fall
in so many ways you'll get a lot of
common things but then
you may see on one side you may see a
grandfather trait really heavily on the
other one you could see the grandmother
trait very heavily or you may not see
any of those traits there will be
variation yes
there will be variations so uh it says
seems like a silly question but i'd like
to hear your thoughts not a silly
question
at all i love it when people think about
breathing like that those are some of my
favorite questions
um you've just you've taken one
ingredient and another ingredient
and if you just if you mix things
different ways you're going to have
different outcomes yes
using the male one way you'll get
different resistance possibly a
different structure maybe different
aromas
just because that's what the male does
to the cross
or at least the pollen donor will do to
the cross and you'll unlock
recessive traits and traits from the
parents and grandparents like i keep
saying so you will see different things
uh let me get myself back on track it
says on a random note my buddy rasta
dave and his family came to colorado
what's up ross to dave i remember you
bro you got a beautiful family the
little kids are beautiful
your wife was great very nice and fun to
hang out with uh that sounds
weird but dave was there too so that's
not how that sounded said i'd like to
say thank you a lot sir and job bless we
are from missouri
and everything is new and excited
exciting here since we went medical
that was a cool little family we did get
to meet up hung out in a parking lot for
a few minutes
got to share some love a bunch of dread
heads in a parking lot little tiny kids
with dreadlocks that was adorable uh
the whole family was dreads except mama
she said she used to have dreads but
she'll get them back i'm sure one day
she'll have dreadies again so shout out
to the dreadlock family that came and
hung out
also shout out to our friend busy uh
thanks for the great question
if you've got any more breeding
questions let me know something else i
want to talk about if you're going to
preserve these i would do them
uh do one plant for a reversal at a time
don't have two males in the same room in
the same house at the same time it'll
get sloppy there will be
pollen contamination you won't have the
breeding project you think you have
so reverse either that eclair or the
strawberry other one what was it
strawberry bubble gum
isn't that what you said where am i i
can't even read any more strawberry
banana
and strawberry eclair pick one reverse
it pollinate
both uh you can pollinate both at the
same time they'll both be in the room
put the male plant in the middle
just knock it back and forth pollinate
both plants then do the opposite next
time but do them at separate times
so you've got a clear idea of which is
who the baby daddy is we always want to
know who the baby
daddy we don't want to have to take
these plants to maury and figure out
what you did
all right so that is my advice uh thank
you for the great question
and i look forward to meeting you the
next time the dead crew
comes through from missouri i hope
things go well for you out there in
missouri as well good luck on the new
medical cannabis venture all right do we
have time for one more of course we've
got time for one more
let's jump into one more you know what
i've got a screenshot on my
phone that i wanted to read this is a
great question here we go
this one says who's this come from i
don't know if they want their name said
on the show so i'm going to keep that
private you know who you are thank you
for the great question it says
great show great genetics that's a way
to start a message to me
thank you great compliment it says i
love listening to your show rasta jeff
and i've got a quick
breeding question here we go again i
love the breeding questions
says after pollinating seeds are
starting do you change the nutrients or
the lighting i hear you should start up
veg newts again
i would like to know if there's any
truth to that
so that's a really good question this
one could keep me talking for quite a
few minutes
uh so he's got a crop that is seated now
at this point in time we are not growing
for flowers we don't want
buds with big beautiful flowers and
trichomes that's not what we're growing
for at this point this grower is growing
four
seeds we have now abandoned the idea of
seedless bud we're going
seeded but it's a whole new project so
at this point
yes i do recommend changing the
nutrients we need to focus a little bit
more on growth and not buds and
trichomes we're not making big fat buds
we're making
healthy seeds so i would replace the veg
the flowering nutrients and i would put
a vegetative nutrient in there
uh keep doing the calmag don't do the
bud boosters like you would normally do
instead of doing a bud booster add
amino acids amino acids are good
building blocks for life
so that's what i would do uh you may
need some calmag you're going to want to
keep that nitrogen going to keep the
plants
with a lot of energy a lot of vigor and
a lot of momentum and then uh
they may want to go a little bit longer
than you normally flower
so pay attention to the plants don't
start flushing as early
you don't need to worry as much about
flushing because we're not going to
consume these flowers anyway they're
going to be filled with seeds
by the time you get the seeds out of
there it's mostly just dust and trash
anyway
so i do change the feeding i continue
with the vegetative newts
i don't add bloom boosters i add amino
acids
i kind of increase the calmag based on
what i see the plants do
and then i pay a lot of attention to the
plants they're kind of they're pregnant
so you got to treat them like a pregnant
lady
their needs are going to change you have
to learn how to identify those needs
by watching the plants now for lighting
um there are a few things you can do if
you're an experienced grower
and you know what to watch for um you
can
change the lights i don't talk about
this a lot but here we go come down this
path with me
uh the last two weeks of flower okay
we'll do it for the last three weeks of
a seeded crop you can turn your lights
back on
18 and 6 for the last a little bit of a
seeded crop
and it will help those seeds bulk up and
speed up i do
this earlier than i'm recommending
because i'm very experienced with my
plants i know what to look for i know
how they're going to respond i know what
they're going to do
so like i said before we're not growing
for pretty buds
if you're not growing for buds if your
goal is seeds you can turn
the time after pollination has happened
after you see seeds forming the calyxes
are swollen you know there's seeds in
there
turn the timer back to 18 6. the plants
will begin to reveg
in about 15 days 17 days you'll see
re-vegetative growth happening on the
plants don't be alarmed
we don't care about the buds we care
about the seeds tucked inside of those
buds
that extra light those extra photons
that extra ppfd
that extra energy is going to make the
seeds grow
with more vigor more quickly they'll get
harder faster
and they'll be done sooner and they'll
be more healthy seeds i know this from
experience this is how i speed up seeds
so i think you can speed them up by
putting the timer back to 18
6. that is for seeded plants you can do
it uh you can do it once you see the
seeds are building up and getting kind
of chunky
that's when it is safe to do it put them
on 18 6. let them go
and then when you start seeing the seeds
poking out of the calyxes on the tips of
the buds
pull a couple of them off and give them
a squeeze how do they feel are they
hollow do they crunch
when you squeeze them does juice come
out did that green thing come out did a
little white embryo come out
see what's inside of that seed and
you'll know when they are ripe sometimes
you need to dig deeper into the bud
sometimes the outer seeds aren't the
best seeds
sometimes those get roasted by the light
sometimes you touch them or something
you kill them
get a seed from the inside of the bud
see if it's nice and hard that is when
it is time to harvest so
you can change the light cycle back to
18 6 at the end of the flowering period
for your seeded crop to help them get
chunkier and faster
and harder at a quicker rate all right
that is my breeding advice for you
that was a golden tip i don't share that
with a lot of people so don't tell
anybody
that i told you i want to thank you for
the great message big thanks to
everybody who sent in a patreon question
or an email question
keep them coming don't be shy if you
feel like this episode was educational
informative or entertaining
and you would like to make a financial
contribution to the show all you have to
do is visit www.patreon.com forward
slash grow from your heart again
all the info is right there on the
screen and of course i did include that
link in the show notes
to make it easy for all of my friends
don't forget to visit our sponsors at
seeds herenow.com
use coupon code gfyh10 while you're
checking out
that will save you 10 if you're getting
one pack that will cover the cost of
shipping
if you're getting multiple packs that
will add up quickly then you can get
more packs what's better than more packs
of seeds
more packs of seeds and if you want even
more packs
make sure you check out that under 30
section because i did add
the cream for under 30 at seeds here
now.com
check that out get your packs now all
that stuff seeds here now.com coupon
code
gfyh10 don't forget follow me on patreon
you can also send me questions via email
my email address is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com you know that i would
love to hear from you
ladies and gentlemen boys and girls
pimps and hoes friends and foes
smokers and growers clone cutters and
paul and chuckers i'll be back in just a
couple of days with fresh new content
i want to give a big shout out to my
buddy fumidor in the flavors and until
next time
take a fat dab and give your mom a hug
for me