this is jeff tate and you're watching
the grow from your heart podcast with my
favorite weed grower rasta jeff
now take a fat dab and give your mom a
hug
for me
[Music]
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rasta jeff and it is time for
episode 563 of the grow from your heart
podcast
this episode of the show is brought to
you by our friends at seedshearnow.com
seedshearnow.com offers seeds from all
of the industry's
leading breeders including miss jill
genetics duke diamond and of course irie
genetics
everything at seeds here now.com is
backed by an award-winning satisfaction
guarantee
and for my friends on a tight budget
seeds herenow.com offers
several packs for under thirty dollars
as well as amazing
monthly sales make sure to use coupon
code gfyh10 while checking out to save a
few bucks
again that is coupon code gfyh10 while
checking out
at seeds here now dot com
you know i like to start the show off by
talking about what i'm smoking
today i've been taking dabs of bananas
foster live batter from green dot labs
this is a blend of banana og and paris
larry
on the package the flavor is described
as banana sugar and oatmeal
i think i agree with those flavor
descriptions we have talked about the
banana fosters on the show before
i really enjoy the banana terps i think
i forgot
how much i enjoy banana turps not only
do i enjoy the flavor
of a banana strain but the buzz that
comes with it is really
desirable in my opinion so i'm really
digging the
bananas foster live batter on the back
of the package it says it contains
67.57 percent thc
and non-detectable amounts of cbd big
shout out to our friends at green dot
labs for the
perfect bananas foster live batter
all right in this episode i'm going to
cover a maintenance
checklist this episode will come out on
the 31st tomorrow will be the first that
is a good time
to do a bunch of grow room maintenance
before we get to the main part of the
show let's do some shout outs to the
members of the 710 club of course the
710 club
are the folks who support the show on
patreon at the 710 level or higher
so let's start off with the big grow
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out
to giant mike and the dabbing queen
let's send a big thank you shout out to
the kinecrat
i always want to send a big thank you
shout out to totally white tops
let's send a big thank you shout out to
okiegrow720 how about a big thank you to
fat rabbit
i always want to send a big thank you
shout out to lefty's farm what's up
buddy
i've always got a big thank you for ned
denver what's up bro i always want to
send a big thank you shout out to kes
burton i always want to say thank you to
josiah w
let's send a big thank you shout out to
homie d and last but certainly not least
let's send a big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to our
friend
matt age big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who supports the show on
patreon
if you're not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do that
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need will be
right there on the screen and of course
i did include a link
in the show notes to make it nice and
easy
all right i think that covers most of
the business part of this episode
let's jump into this grow room
maintenance
checklist we spend a lot of money on
gear in the grove
we rely on all of that equipment to work
properly but it's not going to run on
its own
without a little bit of a checkup
without some maintenance without some
routine maintenance
so once in a while we need to think
about the moving parts in the grow and
maybe take care of them
update them a lot of things need
maintenance many things may need
replaced especially if you haven't been
doing maintenance
so what are some of the things in the
grow room that we really need to
maintain
i started thinking about this list uh
just by going through my day in the grow
in my head and thinking what are the
tools and equipment that i touch and
that i pay attention to
one of the first things that came to my
mind was my ph meter i use my ph meter
on a daily basis i've got multiple ph
meters
i've got a blue lab combo meter that's
stuck to the wall
the probes dangle into a reservoir i can
always see the ph the ec and the ppms
and the temperature in that reservoir at
all times i like that device
however sometimes i second guess my
equipment how do i know that that one
device is reliable
so i've got a second ph pin to double
check
my first ph pen i use the ph testing
solution i make sure that they all test
right
then i double check with two pins
occasionally i just want to double check
because ph is very important especially
to a cocoa grower somebody running a
hydro system your ph is going to be
very important so let's clean and
calibrate our ph meters on a regular
basis as a grower
your ph meter if you're a salt-based
grower if you're a coco
a hydro type grower your ph meter is
like your
hammer or your saw if you were a
carpenter that is something you bust out
every day on a daily basis
you need your hammer and your saw to
work reliably
so let's get a good quality ph pen a
good quality ec meter
all the good quality meters that you can
get we don't want trash here we don't
want junk here
like i said in a previous episode i
believe you get what you pay for when it
comes to ph meters and ec meters
and testing devices so pay for those get
quality devices
then let's maintain them let's clean
them we need to clean the probes they
come with a cleaning solution if you
don't have it order a little bit of
cleaning solution it's not expensive
clean your probes recalibrate your ph
meters if you haven't been doing it
on at least a monthly basis i recommend
weekly
every monday just start the monday off
just by calibrating your meters it
doesn't take that much time and it feels
really good to know
that your gear is in top shape so clean
and calibrate your meters your ph pin
your ec
pen your ppm pen whatever you've got
clean and calibrate those bad [ __ ]
now here is something that you may not
know i'm not sure that i knew this
when you acquire a new ph pen you are
supposed to soak
that pen in the storage solution the kci
storage solution
for 24 hours before you activate that
new ph pin
i've seen a lot of people get a new pen
pull it out of the box
dip it in calibration solution start
mixing solution and use that as their
calibration tool
uh that's not the way to do it we need
to take these pins out of the box
fill a most of them come with a little
cup fill that little cup with your kci
storage solution set the probe in there
for 24 hours
then after 24 hours use your 4 and 7 and
possibly some companies use other
calibration
standards but use your 4 and your 7 and
calibrate your device that way and then
rinse it off
then now you are ready to ph your
solution you can put it in your nutrient
solution and it will show you an
accurate reading but
those things don't come out of the box
ready to go they need some prep they
need some love we need to soak it
then we need to calibrate it so don't
forget those steps take good care of
your equipment and it will continue
to take good care of you another thing
keep that probe
on your ph pen moist if that probe dries
it dies the grower cries
keep that [ __ ] wet because once it
goes dry you've got to buy a new one and
they are not
cheap good quality ph pins are expensive
the best way to remember to always keep
your ph pen moist
is to forget to moisten one you spend
130 bucks
it dries up it dies grower cries you got
to spend another 130 bucks at the grow
store
blue lab is happy with you the guy at
the groce store is excited but you're at
130 bucks because you let that [ __ ]
dry
all right let's keep moving another
thing that i think about we need to
maintain
is cleaning all of the filters what kind
of filtration
do you have in your grow room do you
have an air conditioner
i have got a 14 000 btu rolling air
conditioner with a filter in the back of
it
that thing needs cleaned about every two
weeks it gets sticky it gets dusty in
there
it's got a filter in it pop that filter
out take it to where there's a sink and
just hose it down then let it dry
then put it back clean out that filter
that will increase airflow that will
decrease restriction air restriction on
your air conditioner which makes
the air conditioner work harder which
makes it last less time if we maintain
these devices
they will last longer for us we need
this gear to last money is expensive
we're not making a lot of money on
growing cannabis these days because
everybody's growing cannabis
every dollar and every gram counts so
maintain the gear we've got with the
time we've got
and make this gear stick around so clean
the filters and your air conditioner
clean the filters in your humidifier and
dehumidifier those should be done
probably every three to five maybe seven
days but if you haven't done it
get in there and do it and add that [ __ ]
to your task list put that on your
general maintenance list
clean the filters on the humidifier and
dehumidifier
check them they're probably gunky if you
haven't cleaned them in a while they're
probably gross
other things to check out the ro filter
if you're running reverse osmosis or if
you've got a big boy filter or a small
boy filter
are those filters in there are they any
good is your membrane any good in your
filtration
are you just running water through a
device and wasting time and not really
cleaning it and thinking you're cleaning
it
are those is it time to change those
filters is that due
also irrigation filters in a commercial
environment i run a big reservoir with a
pump
that goes up a bunch of pvc tubing in
one point of that pvc tubing
there's a straight line going up and a
filter that hangs down at a 45 degree
angle going down
the idea is that the heavy sediments
will fall into that filter and the water
will keep moving
so that by the time my water gets to the
end of the line it doesn't clog up my
emitters with chunky nutrient dust
those filters need to be cleaned often
depending on what we feed if we mix up
certain nutrients we have to clean that
[ __ ] filter while we are feeding but
most of the time it's a once every
couple of days once a week sort of thing
if you haven't cleaned that filter now
is the time get in there and clean that
[ __ ] it's the first of the month
it's monday let's get in there and clean
[ __ ] up monday is
the second but this comes out on the
31st so you've got a day to prepare and
get your [ __ ] together
so clean all of your thu your all your
stuff clean all your stuff you guys
clean all of the things that have
filters in there clean out your
reservoirs do you have a reservoir where
you've got
50 gallons of water 200 gallons of water
just 10 gallons
dump that [ __ ] out and give it a good
scrubbing let it dry
if you use any sort of a cleaner make
sure that you rinse out all of that
cleaner no matter what it is if it's
faisan if it's simple green if it's
bleach
make sure you remove all of that cleaner
from your reservoir
clean it out let it dry rinse it out
again then you can reuse it but clean
that res we don't need ship building up
on the reservoir
also another thing you need to clean is
the pump
many of us are using many different
styles of pumps we've got hydro pumps
we've got mix pumps
lots of pumps going on many of those
pumps have little filters in them
many of those pumps have little moving
parts take it apart
get a toothbrush clean that [ __ ] out i
know it sounds tedious but
do you want your grow room to be a
ferrari or do you want it to be a 92
prelude
you've got the opportunity to make the
grow room the ferrari if you take care
of it it will never run like a ferrari
if you put [ __ ] prelude care and love
into it if you got one of them preludes
it's just balling out there
no disrespect but you know what i'm
talking about that dude with the primer
gray prelude that's [ __ ] falling
apart
you didn't take care of it it's falling
apart now if you got that ferrari
every day you're tinkering on that
ferrari making sure that every corner is
polished and buffed the rims look shiny
the undercarriage is clean
you're making sure that ferrari is well
maintained there's oil level is perfect
brake fluid is perfect
muffler fluid is perfect you got it all
going just the way you need it let's
make our grow rooms [ __ ] ferraris
uh then we can win the race another
thing i see people forgetting to clean
especially in a commercial environment
is the measuring
cups which we measure our nutrients i
don't know what size of a grill you're
working with you may have a shot glass
you measure 20 milliliters
you may have a like a small pitcher you
measure 100 milliliters
whatever device you are pouring your
nutrient solution from the bottle into
this measuring cup
let's clean the measuring cup why not
it's probably got some nutrient stains
on it it's got different colors on it
are those salts mixing into the other
nutrients you're pouring in there
did bottle a just mix in with bottle b
and then bottle c mixed with a
and b what are you doing to your
nutrient solution let's clean
those mixing cups it's really not that
hard while we're cleaning those mixing
cups let's also
calibrate the scale which we may use to
measure dry
powdered nutrients if you're using veg
bloom you weigh those nutrients out by
the gram they're powdered you don't need
to you don't do milliliters or whatever
you put it on a scale and you do two
five grams if it's the base you're doing
five grams per gallon if it's
shine you're probably doing two it's
plus life you're probably doing one gram
per gallon
we've got a scale let's clean the scale
off i see those scales covered in
nutrients and it's gross
let's just clean that [ __ ] up get a
paper towel get some cleaner and just
clean that bad [ __ ] up get a rag if
you're not a paper towel kind of guy
i get it someone's going to give me
feedback i mean i noticed as soon as i
said that
but let's clean up that scale let's also
calibrate the scale
we've calibrated our ph pens we've
calibrated everything else let's
calibrate the scale it's real easy
most of the scales come with the
calibration weight keep that handy have
that
next to your msds sheet or something to
where you could just grab it measure
make sure it weighs right make sure it's
accurate go back to work measure your
nutrients
we're measuring 5 grams per gallon if
you've got 20 gallons that's 100 grams
if you're just a little bit off you can
end up with 110 grams and that could
actually have seriously adverse effects
on the plants or
you could give them 90 grams and the
plants are going to be starving
so make sure that you calibrate and
clean up the scale
if you are using a scale for dry
nutrients
we're going to move on a little bit to
things that i see in the grow actual
grow space
a lot of growers have lights these are
old school but a lot of people are still
doing them some of the breeders still
use these
you've got a light with a vented hood
with glass between the bulb
and the canopy of your plant so you got
basically a big metal shoe box with
glass on the bottom so that the bulb is
inside there
and it shines down through the glass and
then you put ducting on both ends and
you can run air over it
that way the heat from your bulb doesn't
go down to your plants it just gets
blown right away by the ducting
it stays inside there because of the
glass that glass gets
really dirty let's clean that glass you
guys there are
pesticide sprays stuck to it there are
dead bugs stuck to it
there's hair stuck to it let's clean
those turn them off let them cool
because they're hot those lights have
been running don't forget the lights are
hot
unplug them let them cool for a little
while get a little bit of a wind some
windex or some kind of a cleaner
on a rag or a paper towel or a newspaper
however you do it just clean those
those pieces of glass in there that is
reducing your light
by so much percent i'm gonna say that
glass probably cuts down your light by
five to fifteen percent that's a guess
i'm really not a scientist when it comes
to light but then for every little
speckle of
pesticide spray or foliar spray or every
bug on there you're losing
two three five more percent and you're
paying for it you're still plugging that
light in
it's still cranking out electricity it's
still pumping out light
maybe you're not getting as much light
over the canopy as you thought
let's keep moving i've got a lot to try
to cover that's why i'm talking kind of
fast here
um check all of the moving parts i don't
know what else you've got in your grow
anything that makes noise that words
that moves around the fans are the fans
clicking is one of them wobbling do they
oscillate properly
check all of that stuff do a safety
check is there something for your dreads
to get caught up on is there some corner
for you to get snagged on is there a
sharp spot on a table
is there a stick for you to poke your
eye on do that kind of maintenance
and just set yourself up for success so
you don't have to slow down in the
future
when you got your hands full and you're
in a rush take the time now to put some
duct tape on that sharp corner
maybe clean up that stuff you're gonna
trip on that's more of a cleanliness
episode but check out all the moving
parts we've got air conditioners
humidifiers dehumidifiers
we've got a ton of stuff to check on
anything that's moving that's got parts
check on it listen to it sometimes i can
hear the dehumidifier making the wrong
noise it's way up there and i can hear
it the rhythm should be
but sometimes
that means something went wrong we need
to check on it pay attention to that
kind of [ __ ]
um check outside for light leaks
if you're growing at home just walk
around walk around the house
walk around the building look for light
leaks do you see any signs that there is
a grow
inside the building is there light
reflecting through your ducting is there
light reflecting through some weird spot
you didn't think of
can you see the light at all can you
hear any of your equipment outside that
would tell
thieves snitches or cops that you've got
something going on
that's part of the maintenance routine
walk around the building walk outside
and check for light leaks
um is your carbon filter working
that's another important thing to think
about is your odor control
actually controlling odor sometimes i
can walk into a commercial cultivation
facility and i don't even smell herb i'm
around cannabis so much
my nose is blank to it that's just like
smelling normal air to me
so i don't smell ganja i've driven away
from my house before and i've come home
and went
oh [ __ ] i need a new carbon filter so
make sure your carbon filter is working
you may need to leave for a full day
go away for the entire day because your
nose is [ __ ] up you smell your skunk
weed
you don't even notice it go away for the
day come back when you walk in the house
really pay attention do i smell my own
ganja
if you smell it other people can smell
it because you're accustomed to
it and if you can smell it it's out of
control you need a new carbon filter i
think
many companies say they last two years
depending on how moist the room is
how much air you've been blowing through
it how well you took care of it
how i don't know did you jostle it
around when you moved it there are so
many contributing factors
a good one should last about 18 months a
crappy one will last you maybe a year
if they're really good maybe two years i
only trust mine for about 18 months
because i don't need that stink going
out of the house
so check on your carbon filter excuse me
for clearing the throat here
check on all of the moving parts check
on all your gear then let's move into
uh part of a maintenance routine is also
ordering
supplies what else are we going to need
this month it's so much easier to order
everything
in one shot and get one delivery or if
you're going to the store it's so much
easier to go there
i order for a commercial warehouse i
can't go pick it up in the car we get
trucks delivered so
my mindset's a little bit different but
do one order every month if you can that
way you don't have to go to the grow
store
too many times and be seen there too
much every time you're there you're
going to make an impulse buy and buy
some dumb [ __ ] you didn't need
also every time you're there you're
exposing yourself to other people who
grow who probably have spider mites or
pollen or powdery mildew or something on
them
also you're exposing yourself to a sales
guy who's going to sell you some [ __ ]
you don't need and change your whole
strategy
and also you're going to find other
growers that are going to give you ideas
and
sway you from doing what you're doing
and you're doing your thing it's cool to
get more input but
don't let that grow store going seeing
all that fantastical [ __ ]
don't let it blow your mind and sway you
from your original goal you're doing
fine
so minimal trips to the growth store and
we can do that by making a nice list
what do we need to get we need nutrients
we know we're always going to need
nutrients
every week every month we need to feed
the plants
a good responsible grower plans their
feed for almost the entire grow before
the growth starts
i know what the plants are going to get
through veg weeks one through three
weeks three through five and six through
nine i know what i'm feeding
every day to those plants so i can go to
the store and buy
all of those bottles in one shot i don't
have to go back makes it
very easy for me and the grocer loves it
because i don't have to go bother them
again
so think about all the nutrients you're
going to need have a strategy
go to the grow store get all those
nutrients in one shot also
get all of your pesticides and
fungicides in one shot think about what
you're going to get
you should already have a strategy
before you're even far enough into the
grow to need
pesticides and fungicides have a
strategy purchase the products
have them ready go shake the bottles are
your bottles low if they get this low i
need to order more
order more of that [ __ ] so make a list
order your pesticides i always recommend
having three
different pesticides on hand i know that
sounds weird
but the bugs don't like a rotation if
i've got three different pesticides they
don't know if i'm gonna throw an
uppercut
a left hook or a right cross they have
no idea what the [ __ ] to look for
i can eradicate bugs quite quickly also
i keep one
fungicide on deck at all times as well
if i see a powdery mildew situation or
something
i've already got the products here to
get rid of it so be prepared
also gloves and personal protective
equipment buying gloves here and there
gets expensive if you can buy enough
gloves to last you the month that is
much
more cost effective and again if you're
getting it online
less amazon shipments if you're going to
the store less visits to the store
get your gloves your personal protective
equipment if you're spraying you need a
tyvek suit
if you need respirator cartridges those
are hard to get right now
honestly uh the respirator cartridges
are on back order
everywhere uh so respirator cartridges
hopefully you got a couple of those
stocked up for your grow but
get all the personal protective
equipment another thing we should think
about is
how long have those bulbs been in that
grow room if you're running conventional
bulbs like hbs or metal halide bulbs
they don't last forever it is time to
change them i always
write down when i put new bulbs in a
room i've got a spot where i keep
documentation for the grow
so i'll put in a commercial grow here's
how i do it i will write on a piece of
duct tape new bulbs on january 1st and i
put that piece of duct tape on the door
to the grow room
it's very obvious these bulbs january
1st
so in the determined amount of time my
determined amount of time
and the owner and investors determined
amount of time for changing bulbs are
always different
uh they don't want to buy bulbs until
it's [ __ ] dark in the grow they don't
realize that those bulbs are
still sucking up 100 of the electricity
but not putting out 100 of the light
because the bulbs are dying so they
don't [ __ ] want to buy new bulbs
until the harvest comes
and they realize why didn't we pull as
much as we did last time and you say
the bulbs are shot we're not getting as
much light as we did and they go oh
really it would have made that much
difference we'll buy bulbs now
and you had to show them the hard way so
how long have your bulbs been in your
grow is it time to swap those out
did you use a par meter did you do
anything to document how much light
you're getting and how much light you're
getting now did you write down the day
that those bulbs were put in there
maybe it's time to get new bulbs mark
down the day and start fresh with a good
idea
because like i said when you plug in
that ballast that electricity happens it
gets generated it gets moved down the
cable it gets put into your [ __ ]
socket
it tries to come out of the light it's
still giving it a thousand watts if your
bulb's only going
i'm burned out i'm gonna put out like
700 watts you're ripping yourself off
for 30
you're still paying for it the electric
company doesn't go oh your harvest was
light
we'll give you a break they don't give
half of a [ __ ]
so make sure your light bulbs are in
good condition if you're using leds
those should last for quite a while but
they will degrade over time
you have a much longer life span on your
leds
what else are we gonna talk about mop
heads and stuff like that order cleaning
supplies
many of you overlook how important
cleanliness is in your grow room and you
just kind of half-ass
that let's stop that [ __ ] it's the first
of the month let's get in there and
clean all that [ __ ] up and start off
with a fresh
clean month you may need new mop heads i
am certain that you need trash bags
maybe you need another dedicated trash
can for the grow area
that you can just set right there and
not have to go chasing down a trash bag
all the time have a trash can
prepared to go also do you need to order
more rags or paper towels or whatever
you use to clean stuff
also do you have a bunch of newspapers
on hand so when you spill something
you can just go grab a stack of old
newspaper and stack those newspapers on
the wetness and it'll suck it all up for
you
that is a grow trick from way back in
the day keep all the old newspapers in a
pile
if you spill some liquids drop the
newspaper on there newspaper will clean
it right up
it was free throw it away not a big deal
another thing you may need to stock up
on
if you can find it i highly recommend
that you get some isopropyl alcohol
i like to clean my [ __ ] with 91 iso
it's hard as [ __ ] to find right now
during these weird pandemic times
uh isopropyl alcohol will hit the shelf
and it is frenzied over
and it is a melee people put in the
carts and it's gone i usually grab about
six bottles
try to keep them stacked up on top of
the fridge if you can get some isopropyl
alcohol for cleaning your equipment
that is gold that's going to be useful
for many
many cleaning applications of the grill
you can clean your scissors with it when
you're cutting clones
you're trimming i like to have some iso
around i also like to clean the rigs
with it
so when you're ordering supplies and
[ __ ] try to get yourself some iso
uh you may need to go hit the smaller
stores if walmart doesn't have it i hate
walmart i don't go to walmart i would
much
prefer walgreens but sometimes you got
to go all over the place looking for
iso right now so order all of your stuff
that's part of the maintenance on the on
the first you got to
check all of the equipment any moving
parts anything that squeaks rattles runs
anything that takes water anything that
takes a filter maintenance all of that
gear like i said before all of the
equipment
is expensive and it will last much
longer if we just give it some love
every occasionally once a week once
every two weeks once a month
as often as it needs make sure you check
on your equipment once you've checked on
all the equipment
how are your nutrients and supplies
doing you don't want to run out of [ __ ]
you don't want to be cutting clones and
realize oh i don't have any clone gel
you've got all these clones cut you got
your dome set up and no [ __ ] clone
gel
make sure you've got all of the stuff
you're going to need set yourself up for
success then once you've got all your
nutrients and things
that's when you're going to need
pesticides and things like that
then we will move into cleaning supplies
make sure you've got all the shelves
stocked
make sure you're well ready to go and
prepared also part of the
monthly maintenance checklist i almost
forgot does the fire extinguisher have a
charge
your fire extinguisher's got a little
gauge the fire extinguisher may be a
rasta because it's got a red a yellow
and a green chart on it
and you want to be obviously in that
green that's when the fire extinguisher
is the best when it gets to the yellow
it is time to get that fire extinguisher
either replaced or recharged
uh depending on the size quality and
brand of your fire extinguisher
many of them once they get to that point
uh they're done they've got to be
disposed of properly
some of them if they're the correct kind
you can take it to the fire department
and they will actually recharge that for
you
and make sure that you've got a safe
fire extinguisher also while we're on
this subject
check all the batteries and your smoke
detectors and your carbon monoxide
detectors if you're
running co2 in your grow space that
carbon monoxide detector be
a totally different story but if you are
if you've got smoke detectors
go test them out make sure that they
work we don't want to just have them as
props we want those
to work all right i think that wraps up
my grow room
maintenance episode i think the other
thing i could say is just stand by the
door occasionally and just look
i notice a lot of details that i didn't
think about but i'm just looking i've
just got this look into the grill
just looking just glassing just staring
at the plants
i don't know what i'm looking for but
i'll find something i always find one
thing
that the grower the grow tech would be
like what are you staring at boss i
don't know yet but it'll tell me
and then a couple couple minutes into my
weird stare i go that
that's the problem we gotta fix you guys
i need a guy to come help me solve this
problem and then we get a grow tech on
it and i go help them figure it out
we solve the issue i notice a lot of
problems just doing the growers
gays notice a lot of issues that way
able to solve them that's a lot of
passion and a lot of dedication to the
plants
all right you guys i need to wrap up
this episode i want to thank you guys
for hanging out with me for another
episode of the grow from your heart
podcast
if you feel like this show is
educational informative or entertaining
and you'd like to make a financial
contribution to the show
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need will be
right there on the screen of course
don't forget to visit our sponsors at
seedshearnow.com
seedshearnow.com has seeds from all of
the industries
leading breeders and don't forget about
that under 30 section where you can
score a pack of the cream
for 30. at seedshearnow.com use coupon
code gfyh10 to save yourself a few bucks
if you're buying one pack that'll cover
the cost of shipping if you were getting
several packs
that just may buy you another pack of
seeds seeds herenow.com
coupon code gfyh10 if you've got any
corrections questions comments or
concerns i would love to hear from you
my email address is grow from your heart
hotmail.com
don't be shy reach out send me some
messages uh that is all i've got for you
for this episode ladies and gentlemen i
want to thank you guys for hanging out
i want to give a giant shout out to miss
mel and until next time take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me