[Music]
welcome back podcast world i'm your host
my friends call me rosta jeff and it's
time for episode 568 of the grow from
your heart podcast
this episode of the show is brought to
you by my friends at seedshearnow.com
seeds herenow.com carry seeds from all
of the industries
leading breeders including miss jill
genetics duke diamond and of course irie
genetics
everything at seeds herenow.com is
backed by their award-winning
satisfaction guarantee
from my friends on a tight budget seeds
herenow.com offers several packs for
under 30 dollars as well as
amazing monthly sales make sure to use
coupon code gfyh10 while checking out to
save a few bucks
again that is coupon code gfyh10 while
checking out
at seeds here now.com
you know i like to start this podcast
off by talking about what i'm smoking
today i've been taking dabs the
fortissimo
full spectrum extract from green dot
labs this is a blend of crescendo and
hsb the hsb is han solo burger
on the package the flavor is described
as 98 octane
dumpster and funk that is completely
accurate
when i crack this open it smells like a
hot bar
trash can that doesn't sound like a
pleasant description but i
love it there is some hot bar trash can
what is the other one in here 98 octane
i'm not sure the specific octane but i
definitely get a funky
gassy feely aroma so the description of
98 octane dumpster and funk
is completely accurate it smells like a
garlicky
dumpster fire and i [ __ ] love it on
the back of the package it says it
contains
64.93 thc and non-detectable amounts of
cbd
i'll show it to the camera there nice
beautiful color nice chunky diamonds
just enough terp sauce big shout out to
our friends at green dot labs for the
tremendous fortissimo full spectrum
extract all right ladies and gentlemen
boys and girls pimps and hoes friends
and foes smokers and growers clone
cutters and paul and chuckers in this
episode
i'm going to read a couple of messages
from patreon before we get to the
message portion of the show
let's do some shout outs to a few of the
folks who support the show on patreon
let's start off with the big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to our friend eric ross
let's send a big thank you shout out to
dr phil good what's up brother let's
send a big thank you shout out to wyatt
herb
let's send a big thank you shout out to
tyler filth what up filthy filth good to
see you bro
let's send a big thank you shout out to
dr dendro let's follow that up with a
big thank you shout out to nick
i've always got a thank you shout out
for juan rios i'd like to send a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to our friend tony like
baloney
i want to send a big thank you fist bump
to our buddy big huff i want to send a
giant grow from your heart podcast thank
you shout out to dave's not here
and last but certainly not least let's
send a big thank you shout out to my
friend advanced pools
big thanks a big shout out to everybody
who continues to support the show on
patreon
if you are not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need is right
there on the screen of course i did
include
a link in the show notes and in the
video description to make it easy
for my friends and again really thank
you
for all of the continued support i will
be updating those patreon tiers
very soon make a few more options make
it a little bit easier for you guys to
understand there's a lot going on on
that page i understand that i will make
some adjustments but anyway
thank you and shout out to the
fortissimo for getting me rambly at the
start
of the show all right i don't wanna
waste too much time i'm obviously nice
and chattery let's jump right into the
patreon messages uh actually before we
get there i've got an update i almost
skipped a part it says update right here
on my page
in a previous episode i spoke about
grafting and i said that i believe
that when we do grafting and i said i
have no science behind this i said i've
got no uh
no actual experience in this i said this
was my belief and my assumption i
believe that if we graft
two plants together eventually over time
those genetics will
intermingle or meld or shift somehow to
where
that is one plant and i think the
genetics will change the outcome the
flowers the fruits of that plant will be
different over time many people
disagreed with me
many people said that that was not a
thing that the genetics will stay true
to each branch of the plant if you
carefully label it you'll know what it
is forever
well i had another listener actually tag
me in an article
and send me a link to an article where
it showed evidence of
a plant changing its genetics the plant
used was a tobacco plant
but it did show that some genes did move
around so big shout out to my buddy big
huff
for tagging me in an article and
pointing out the fact that i may have
been correct the first time in my
assumption and believing
that if you graft a plant over time
eventually those genetics could
and possibly will mingle or meld or
whatever the scientific word is for that
i am being honest and open that i do not
have the scientific education or
terminology for this scenario
but in my grower knowledge mind i feel
like
those genetics would definitely move
around if you cut off if i cut off your
arm if we traded arms
cut off we're gonna go with uh we're
gonna do left leg i don't if i had to
lose a limb i would choose my left leg
that's a drummer thing uh cut off our
left legs you get my left leg i get your
left leg we're gonna walk funny because
i'm six
five i got long ass legs you probably
don't have legs as long as mine i'm
gonna walk funny you're gonna walk funny
over time your leg and my leg which is
we've traded i don't know what to call
these anymore but our new legs
are going to adapt and adjust to our
body it's not going to be your leg
anymore it's not going to be my leg
anymore it may still have
your jeans in it and my jeans in it but
it's going to become mine it's going to
be part of my body
i think 20 years from now if we're still
alive we won't even we'll still know
that we've got a leg transplant because
it's [ __ ] one's way longer
but our bodies will go that's my leg now
and it will be completely adjusted to it
our genetics will have melded in and
meshed in
we'll forget that that's somebody else's
leg our body will go that's my leg now
and you'll function just like your leg
this is all hypothetical don't take me
too seriously i think the plant will do
the same thing
oh you gave me a new arm let's move
around and those genetics that make it
cherry kush and those genetics that make
it purple
haze they will you'll somehow you're not
breeding but you're going to make a
cherry haze
sort of a thing out of that on accident
in my opinion and somebody has posted an
article that says that did happen
with different varietals of tobacco
plants so
my first assumption and belief has been
shown to have been accurate
i hope that stirred up more controversy
because i look forward to hearing
your feedback and your input on that
update
so when i said that i feel like grafting
will cause genetics to move i may have
been right in my original assumption
that was the short version of that long
ramble
now is the part when we're going to jump
into the patreon messages
on this episode and i mean it this time
this is not another false start
we're actually going to get into the
patreon messages the first one comes
from our friend tree
star meadow who may have for may have
thought i forgot who he was bro i did
not forget who you are thank you i
i got nothing but love and support and
respect for you and appreciation
this message goes like this it says hey
ross to jeff tree star meadow here i'm
the guy who framed the orange gasm for
you thank you that is an amazing gift i
spoke briefly about it here on the show
our friend treestar sent me a beautiful
frame it's thick it's beautiful it's got
a lot of artwork going
on to it and inside of that frame is a
framed package of
orange gasm seeds and he said that that
orange gasm made his life easier and he
thanked me for making my life easier
he has no idea that the orange gasm has
made my life easier it's made my life
better that's been my number one seller
lately it's been paying the bills so to
speak it has been my hit
song it's been the one making my company
soar so uh big thanks and big respect
and big appreciation for the gift of the
orange gasm
framed package that was beautiful it
goes on to say i was listening to your
podcast today and i felt it was high
time
get it high time i got on patreon and
became a supporter of you and also the
dgc
big thank you i appreciate that our
friend treestar signed up to support
myself
and the dgc on patreon today i do
appreciate that and
coming from the dgc thank you they
appreciate it as well
uh it goes on to say it goes without
saying you've been a tremendous help in
making me a better grower
it's only right that i support you
financially after all you've done for me
i spend my weekdays alone
building and shipping squares and
rectangles from a small industrial
warehouse
it's the voices of rasta jeff scotty
guru and the dude that keep me company
uh man i love knowing that i'm keeping
you company and i think i have a good
hint at what you do all day because you
sent me a box
um man i'm glad that we were able to
keep you sane because that type of a job
would drive me crazy
i need some sort of variation some sort
of chaos in my life
so i'm glad that we're able to keep you
sane and thank you for noticing that
you've gotten a vast education from me
and made you a better grower that's my
goal knowing that i made you a better
grower
that is my goal i love the patreon
contributions don't get me wrong i love
financial support that makes life better
it makes things fun
but just knowing that somebody out there
is enjoying their garden more
having a more successful outcome that's
what the show was about in the first
place so that means a lot to me
i should keep moving because i am
[ __ ] rambly it says even though we've
never met i feel like i hang out with
you guys
all the time i get to learn and laugh
concurrently and to me it is worth my 10
dollars a month i know exactly what you
feel
i listen to a lot of podcasts as well
one of my favorite podcasts
maybe possibly one of my heads one of my
top five favorite podcast a couple of my
favorite podcasts actually have been
disrupted lately
uh the church of what's happening now
with joey diaz is done joey diaz has
moved back to
new jersey because uh there's no point
in being in la he doesn't have his
producer anymore
that was one of my favorite podcasts it
is gone i would listen to uncle joey on
a daily basis a lot like you guys listen
to me
and i felt like i'm friends with joey
i've met joey i've smoked some
concentrates with joey before i've been
around joey hung out with joey but it
was like keeping up with my friend
every day via that podcast when that
podcast ended
i miss uncle joey i am not getting part
of my entertainment part of my life is
missing
kovit didn't really hit me too hard
until all of my entertainment started
going away that's what i'm noticing so
i feel like i know uncle joey and i feel
like i miss him so i understand exactly
where you're coming from the other
podcast that disappeared on me is the
fighter and the kid
if you're a t fat k fan you understand
what happened there i miss
seeing that old gay owl on the other
couch i really do and if you're a t
fat k fan you understand exactly what
i'm talking about i miss calan on
that red couch seeing the other guys on
the red couches just doesn't do it for
me
i miss my bro callan so i understand
exactly what you mean about hanging out
with me
um i consume a lot of podcasts so i feel
the exact thing
and i actually since i hit a certain
tier on my patreon i have gone and
started contributing to other podcasts
that i enjoy
because i felt that it was time to give
back the karma so thank you for throwing
me 10 bucks and throwing the dude gross
crew 10 bucks
i actually contributed to mike's patreon
because mike comes on my show and helps
me out
i figured it was my responsibility to
contribute to white mike's patreon and
say thanks to mike
also i contributed to joey diaz of
course and
uh the fighter and the kid or not the
fighter and the kid i rejected my
fighter i re
revoked it because i didn't like what
they gave me uh but the
the king and the sting they get a couple
bucks from me but i did go do some
contributions because you guys are
hooking me up so fat
let's get back on track here at least a
little tiny bit it says i'm glad you
loved your frame
i wanted to make sure you received the
note was included with it
that was the most important part um the
note meant a lot to me the whole package
was beautiful and meant a lot to me
i knew that my mom was going to be
showing up in my house later that day
so i left the framed package and the
note laying
on the table where i knew she would walk
by and just curiously pick it up and
read it
and it was left out there invitingly she
wasn't invading space or anything by
reading that i left it there to be read
and she read it
and she told me later she's like whoever
wrote that is really nice that's a
really sweet thing for someone to say
and she even felt like the look on her
face i could see the sincerity that she
felt your note so
yeah that was really cool thank you i
did appreciate it i felt every word of
that
that stuff means a lot to me i do a lot
of work sometimes i don't realize
exactly how many lives i've touched so
your thank you note did go a long way
i'm building a new office space
i've been saying that for a couple of
weeks i needed some plants to harvest i
had my office was a grow room for a
minute you know things that breeders do
i'm going to rebuild the office space
and that will definitely go in a spot
where i look frequently
because i want to see that and be
reminded of that quite often it's going
to get its own dedicated little spot
so thank you there's more it says uh
thank you for doing what you do i'm off
to take a fat dab
and as soon as we're able to travel i'll
give my mom a hug
for you much love they signed it with
their real name
and then tree star meadow bro i'll never
forget who you are i'll never forget
that package
that you sent me that will always mean a
lot to me while you're off
traveling uh and giving your mom a hug
why don't you come take a dab with me if
we could travel we could do some [ __ ]
i owe you a dab i owe you a high five
come take a dab with me
you're always invited i look forward to
meeting you tristar thank you for the
great message
uh let's keep moving you guys because i
am rambling i can get way off track in
this podcast so let's stay focused
let's keep this choo choo train on the
rails just a little bit
i've got another great patreon question
this one is a
series of questions that comes from our
friend wyatt herb
and it goes a lot like this it says yo
rasta jeff i took your patreon advice on
your podcast today and i'm sending you a
message i wanted to check that my 7.10
level is okay and if i would be included
in the shout outs i love your show
brother
best podcast by far that was the first
message from wyatt herb
uh yes brother i did receive your
contribution and the 7.10
level is exactly what you need to get a
shout out on the show
uh so shout out to wyatt herb i think
you did get a shout out at the start of
this show if you didn't it's coming up
i write them down at the start of the
show and i try to do about ten you did
get a shot at the start of this one
try to give about nine to twelve shout
outs depending on how long your names
are
so that's where the shout outs fall into
place you gotta throw down ten seven
dollars and ten cents on the patreon
and then i write down ten or twelve of
them at the start of each episode to
throw out
uh your patreon did make it uh this
one's showing too many people's names
reading through the paper up here
but your patreon message did make it and
you do get a shout out so once again
shout out to wyatt herb
thank you for the contribution i want to
keep going it there is more
it goes also a request and a question if
you don't mind good sir
have you watched that danny carey drum
video numa
i asked you on your instagram live i
know you weren't a big tool fan
but every time you talk about drums i
think about how you must watch the solo
at 6 minutes and 30 seconds in is crazy
the time signature is nuts four counts
ain't happening
uh watch it for the craft that is a
great comment there is cannabis related
content in this question
um i am a huge musician a huge music fan
i've been playing the drums since i was
14 or 15 years old that's quite a bit of
time if you know how old i am by now
i've been playing for a while i can
count odd times i could get a good feel
for [ __ ]
um a lot of people sent me
that exact video i don't know what
happened that video must have gotten
popular must have been trending or
something on the same day that i said
something about the drums because
three or four people sent me that video
within a three or four day time period
also somebody that means a lot to me is
a huge tool fan i thought it would be
time to give that song a listen
and learn it a little bit i've got the
idea of this song but i don't have all
of the parts
memorized and comfortably figured out
but i know
i can count it i know the time
signatures i know the pieces i know the
changes
it's just comfortably flowing with that
is going to take me a minute but i can
do it
so i'm not there yet i can get to it
i'll be able to play the whole thing all
the way through that won't be a
too big of a deal in a year i'll be
knocking that out it may take a year
but it's only because i just get to play
a little bit practice on that just a
little bit but
uh yeah it's a fun song i'll get there i
know you guys this is not cannabis
related but it was a great question
uh so many people sent me that that
video all like within a week and i was
like this is a sign
and then you asked me hey have you tried
that and i was like i want to go [ __ ]
try this so i listened to it i wrote
down the exact date of the first time i
attempted to play it so i've got that
written down i think it was the fourth
of september
uh so that means by i don't know six
months from now i should have some solid
progress on it i know that sounds like a
long time but it is a
monster of a song it's gonna be a lot of
fun it'll be a lot of exercise
as well uh four counts ain't happening
that drum solo in the middle is all four
bro it's just a camouflaged
four it's a different feel the rest of
it is five
and six it's one two three four five six
one two three four five with a couple of
one
twos right in the middle there to [ __ ]
up the pattern let's get back on talking
about cannabis it says
i do have questions for you uh what are
the options for us
deep in prohibition land to buy legit
clones i've always wanted to grow
a real deal cut but i have no idea who
to trust or
if the stuff online is credible i'm in
i'm not even going to say your state
because i don't want to give any hints
of where you are
since you're talking about being in
prohibition land i'm in prohibition land
so the local scene is basically
non-existent i know i can try the trade
game but i'm not extremely handy in
forms etc
and i don't hear much about the online
clone sales at all
any help uh the clone game can be a
risky game
the only if you don't know other growers
if there's not a growing community in
your neighborhood
if you don't know anybody with clones
you're going to have to rely on the
internet
you're going to have to rely on forums
or social media or something that can be
risky
you don't know what you're going to get
i can almost guarantee you you're going
to get
spider mites powdery mildew thrips some
sort of fungus gnats or some sort of
problems
those always come free with clones
expect that that's just part of doing
business when it comes to getting clones
i don't recommend if you don't have a
trusted reliable
source i just don't recommend doing it
unless you're really desperate
and hard up for a new variety that you
really really need something new in the
garden
maybe go on a forum find somebody doing
it but you've got to trust the seller
and the sender that thing is going to
end up coming to you in the mail
did they label it so where it doesn't
look like it's a [ __ ] clone do they
package it safely to where it doesn't
look like it's a clone you don't want to
set yourself up
to get in trouble from somebody you
don't even know who's careless i like to
kind of vet people
learn how they do business see how they
do things how they do one thing is how
they do all things if they're sloppy in
one aspect they're going to be sloppy
when they send you [ __ ] don't deal
business
don't deal with them don't do business
with them they can put you in trouble
um i don't know what else to say for
damn i stuttered hard they're not even
going gonna edit i don't know what else
to tell you or to say
when it comes to uh getting clones like
be very careful like you said the
the forums and [ __ ] are gonna be your
best bet but who knows if those people
are even going to send you what you ask
for there's no reason
for somebody to fake you and say they've
got something but it's a good way to
make money if i know you're looking for
granddaddy purple clones i've got
granddaddy purple clones suddenly
if you're looking for lemon haze clones
i know i've got lemon haze clones
suddenly it's just how some people are
it's how that's gonna work so be very
careful when it comes to clone shopping
online
i don't have much advice for that i
would say find some grower friends
and trade cuts directly with them when
you get those cuts put them into
quarantine
treat them like they've got bugs treat
them for about two weeks in another room
if you can
treat them every third day with
different pesticides maybe combinations
of pesticides pay attention to them
treat them with the fungicide get rid of
all the problems they could come with
like i said clones come with free
problems so treat them for that
i'm trying to think of better advice
while i'm rambling um if you want real
deal cuts
i think the best way to do it is to shop
for s1
seeds of the cuts that you're hot for
this is basically
why i made golden goat feminized seeds
golden goat was a really popular cut
when i started
kind of coming up in the breeding game
and making seeds to give out in bulk
quantities to people golden goat was the
big
hot [ __ ] in my scene so i reversed the
golden goat my intention was
i can't send clones out to everybody but
i can get seeds to
everybody so if you get s-1 seeds
that is as close as you're going to get
to getting a clone of a certain cultivar
without
running the risk of having a clone
mailed to you without that clone not
being what you're told it is without
getting the bugs and problems that come
with the clone so i think
seeds are going to be the closest option
and again
s1 seeds are self seeds that's when you
take a cultivar
you treat it with a solution take the
pollen from that plant and put it on
another clone of the same plant
you've used two girl plants you treated
wanted with some magic
now those are going to make feminized
seeds you've got s1
feminized seeds no adulteration of the
genetics
it's going to be as close as you can
find to that strain without getting a
dirty clone
without outcrossing it or something like
that so i don't have good advice on
getting legit clones buying legit clones
if you're going to buy stuff like that
online be very careful you have to trust
the seller you have to trust the shipper
you put yourself in a lot of positions
that way
once you get the clone is it
contaminated infected infested and is it
even indeed what you are told it's
labeled as
that's a big gamble i would recommend
you get some feminized s1 seeds
from a reliable breeder from a reliable
seed
seller of course i do recommend seeds
herenow.com and use coupon code gfyh10
while you do that
if you want some blueberry cookies s
ones i've made those available that is
the leonardo
if you want golden goat feminized seeds
the s1s are available
those are both available at
seedsharenow.com
let me know what you're looking for
maybe i can help you find some s-ones
maybe uh let's keep moving there is more
to this i keep sitting on this big
dreadlock if you see me keeping keep
reaching behind me trying to get this
dread out from under me it's driving me
crazy
none of your worry let's keep moving it
goes uh where are we
i'm moving i'm loving my irie genetics i
have four of your strains in my room now
and i couldn't be happier
thank you brother lots of love that is a
great compliment i want to know which
four you're growing and i would love
to see photos of those four you're
running four strains i want to know
which four you've got together
and i'm glad that you couldn't be
happier that means a lot to me i love
that my product is making you happy
then it says here's a great question do
you think i could get a blue raspberry
truffle fino
from a bebop seed since they have the
two strained combos and he means the two
same parents
or will the sex of the parents limit
what traits they can
express um so
the story here is blue raspberry truffle
is an arise
to blueberry cookies it's in a ryze male
pollinated a blueberry cookies
the bebop is the opposite i reversed
blueberry cookies to make pollen
and pollinated my female arise so you're
going to find
vast differences because the male was
completely different
the female arise and the male arise are
different plants if i was using
if they were both reversed and done that
way you'd find more common phenotypes
and you'd be more likely to find the
blue raspberry truffle in there
but since i used the female arise
that kind of takes away from the
opportunity to get the blue rat
you'll still find it but it's not the
same male that's too different it's a
different plant in the mix it's not the
male it's the female
which will carry different traits but it
is an opportunity it is a possibility
because you've still got those two
flavors in the mix
also you're going to see more of the
male most of the time you're going to
find more of the male
kind of carries the structure and the
shape a little bit so that's what you're
going to see different you're going to
see more of the blueberry cookies shape
and less of the arise shape in that
plant is what i think you're going to
find
so it is possible but since i used the
arise number four female and not the
king solomon male
you're going to see differences because
those are two different plants they're
from the same line the same progeny
but they're they're different they're
they were selected for different traits
so it is possible uh with the two strain
combos yes
but uh you'd be if you want the blue
raspberry truffle you'd be better off
getting
the blue raspberry truffle that's what i
think all right wyatt herb i think that
is the end of your message yes i've got
one more message to go
i want to thank you for the great
message again if anybody else out there
would like to join the patreon and get
your question moved up to the top it is
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart
also i will answer your questions via
email the email address is grow from
your heart at hotmail.com
of course patreon is the way to move
your message right up
to the top i do have another message
that comes from a
long time patreon supporter this one
comes from mr glenn geroni
uh it says jeff you can obviously use my
name if this makes it to the podcast
that's good because when i hold up the
message
your name shows up real big through the
paper so
uh big shout out to glen geroni this
message goes like this
as i approach the first two rooms of my
commercial grow coming to the final date
i'm wondering whether or not to flush
with ph
ro water or just regular ro water
normally i add my newts and my ph is
right on the money
however i would prefer not to add ph
down to water if it is not necessary
ro is what we have to use due to small
amounts of aluminum
of aluminum in the well water
all right so our friend glenn jeroni is
coming up on their
uh what is it the uh the first
two rooms of their commercial grow
congratulations on the first harvest in
your commercial grow that's exciting
and he's wondering if he should flush
with ph
or not ph ro water he's using reverse
osmosis water
uh he says without adjusting the ph it
comes out at 6.9 to 7.2
that's just about neutral uh let's see
he's wondering if he should adjust the
ph to 5.9 to 6.1
normally he adds newts and the ph is
right on the money at 6.0
right now he doesn't want to add ph down
to the water if it's not
necessary i want to know if it will be
okay
to flush with the current ro water
when we're flushing we're basically
trying to rinse out
the medium that is holding the plants we
just want to get the soil the cocoa we
want to rinse that out so there's
nothing left for the plant to eat
so if you're using ro water
ro water will stop the plant from up
taking more nutrients
when the water is ph it is able to
uptake nutrients
if it is at the wrong ph it can't uptake
nutrients so it's not going to eat
anymore so
i don't find a reason to ph the flushing
water you're trying to make that plant
cannibalize itself and stop eating you
basically just want to get water through
there
so water on your normal this is
something i want to clear up as well i
say when we're flushing
feed clean water for two weeks until
it's harvest time
i don't mean water every day for two
weeks
and i'm sure glenn jeroni is smart
enough here for this this is for some
people that were confused when they were
listening what i mean is
water on your normal schedule if you're
going to harvest in 14 days
today water till you get about 20 runoff
wait for that plant to dry until it's
thirsty again then water until you get
runoff with just clean plain water that
will flush out the plants
i do not mean [ __ ] drown the plant
every day until it's running off 20
percent
that will kill your plant your plant
will be dead you won't get time to flush
it
four days into the flush phase it's
[ __ ] over you're gonna blame it on me
don't do that water it heavily until you
get 20
runoff let it dry up maybe even a little
extra dry
do it all over again you should get
three five times of that depending on
how often you water your plants you
should get three to five good [ __ ]
flushes out of that
and that will make your plants burn well
there's a lot of stuff that can go into
a flushing conversation
what are you trying to flush out a lot
of the stuff you're trying to flush out
has actually been turned into buds what
are you actually flushing you can't
remove the stuff from the buds
i don't think i'm not sure i'm still
learning still reading still digging
into that controversy
but we just want to clean the soil so
the plants will quit eating
um i think that not adjusting the ph
the plants aren't going to eat they're
going to drink still they're going to
get water but they're not going to
uptake any nutrients and that is our
goal so
i don't find it necessary to adjust the
ph of the water
at the end of the flowering phase that's
going to make it a lot easier in your
commercial grow that's going to save you
a step it's going to save you money on a
product
you don't have to put the pen in there
and stir it around and try to get it at
the right ph
i say go for it just water the [ __ ] out
of them all right the next question says
what feminized genetics does irie
genetics offer that you would recommend
for a commercial grow
i can create whatever environment each
particular cultivar needs with no
problems
i'm wanting quality first and quantity
second
uh you'll get both with the strain i'm
going to recommend so what do you
suggest i run of yours in
my commercial grow and he said feminize
seeds so right now i'm going to strongly
recommend orange gasm orange gasm is
the [ __ ] winner in a commercial grow
for feminized seeds
it puts out good fat harvest it doesn't
take super long to finish
it's got mad bag of peel it smells like
delicious oranges
if you want to make concentrates out of
it the concentrates just smell like
[ __ ] orange candy
it's easy to grow it it'll suck up a lot
of nutrients though you got to feed the
[ __ ] out of it but
it can take abuse it can take all kinds
of rooms
if your room is too hot too cold too
humid too dry it's going to be okay
i heavily strongly highly recommend
orange gasm from my feminine feminize
lineup for your commercial grow
um so then it also says there are pics
attached i saw the pictures
it said not to brag but i am [ __ ]
killing it you were killing it bro i saw
your photos i will testify
you are [ __ ] killing it it says it
feels good i've come
so far in four years and a large amount
of my personal development
has been inspired by your episodes i am
seeing a trend here a lot of people are
telling me lately
that they are becoming better growers
because of my episodes i've been doing
the show for about six years now
that means people have been listening
for four to six years this guy's been
listening for four years
or at least growing for four years and
is noticing personal
development inspired by the episodes
that means a lot to me
you guys inspire me to get better i have
to be a better grower a better speaker a
better podcaster
because i'm getting a bigger audience a
better show i got to stay on top of my
[ __ ]
i always got to be the sensei but i'm
still learning all the time so you guys
inspire me
to have personal development as well so
thank you for that perfect dynamic
it says i prefer to learn more from
someone else's mistakes and that is what
you're providing
to growers everywhere thanks for
everything homie
from glen gironi uh yes
i am not a ninja i'm not a uh a wizard i
have made a lot of mistakes
don't ever get me wrong i am not perfect
when i talk about all the success i've
had there are a lot of failures that
came with that success but it's how you
deal with those failures
that make you successful if you fall off
that horse
nine times you get on that horse nine
[ __ ] times the tenth time you won't
fall off you're probably gonna win
i've probably fallen down 15 times and
gotten up
[ __ ] 15 times you guys so that is how
it goes glenn jeroni thank you for the
great patreon message i want to thank
everybody for the
podcast contributions today
if you feel like this episode was
educational informative and or
entertaining and you'd like to make a
financial contribution to the show
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need will be
right there on the screen once again
big thanks to everybody for all of the
continued patreon support it does mean a
lot to me i know i come on here i talk
real fast
i blow right by the ads right through
the patreon sincerely
that shit's awesome thank you i
appreciate it i never
ever expected this little podcast to do
what it is doing now
uh today my instagram live got over a
hundred
viewers that's the first time it's ever
done that if you're not checking out the
instagram it's irie underscore genetics
on instagram live
check out the instagram live shows if
you like my podcast you'll love the
instagram live
it's freestyle it's free flow and i take
dabs my point is
thank you you guys are blowing up the
podcast you're blowing up my patreon
my instagram is going crazy my youtube
is going crazy i
appreciate it without you guys i've said
this before i am some
psychopath with too many electronics and
too many toys this would be weird
without your guys's exchange on the
other end
so thank you i do appreciate it where
else are we
i also like it when you follow me on
cannabis cannabis is a cannabis friendly
social media application
you cannot buy trade or sell cannabis on
cannabiz
but you can post your cannabis related
content you could post your weed
pictures you could post your dab videos
you could post your concentrates
if you've got a problem in your grow you
can post a picture and say what the [ __ ]
is wrong with my plants
a bunch of people will chime in and help
you out you won't be hated on
you won't be deleted or blocked because
you grow cannabis we will support and
celebrate your cannabis content so i
invite you
to find me on cannabaz go to your uh
your app store whatever you got if you
got an apple phone if you got an android
phone go to your app store
find cannabis c-a-n-n-a-b-u-z-z
canna buzz it's real easy to find it's
free download the app create yourself a
name
a screen name a [ __ ] username all
that good stuff
sign in find me i'm irie underscore
genetics give me a follow
check out what i've got going on
cannabis i think you will enjoy the
application
also don't forget to check out our
sponsors seeds here now if you need some
regular feminized or autoflower seeds
seeds here now is the place make sure to
use coupon code gfyh10 while checking
out that will save you
10 off of your order ladies and
gentlemen my throat is done for the day
i want to thank you guys for hanging out
for episode 568 of the grow from your
heart podcast
i'll be back in just a few days i want
to give a giant shout out to my friend
dave's not here
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you