yeah welcome back podcast world it's
time for episode number 57 of the grow
from your heart podcast your source for
Cannabis News education and conversation
if you're a new grower a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
veteran Dabber if you're a cannabis
activist or someone who's just curious
about the current state of cannabis this
my friends is the podcast for you I'm
your host rosta Jeff thanks again for
joining me as always I want to send a
big huge thank you shout out to the
Mystic Roots band for letting me use
their music on the show big huge thanks
to cat and coot and the whole Mystic
Roots crew how are you guys doing today
man I'm hanging out by myself just me
getting down to some ray music taking
some dabs dabbing on some Kim dog nectar
that I picked up at nugs uh with green
and healthy cannabis in Colorado Springs
this is some delicious shatter I really
like this had me a little uh little
Twitter ped all day from this shatter
digging it it's just me hanging out so
we're going to turn down the music and
we're going to read some news I've got
an iTunes comment to read but before we
get that far the organic portions of
this episode were sponsored by my good
friends at the Rocky Mountain worm
company visit the Rocky Mountain worm
company in Colorado Springs for fresh
worm castings African nightcrawlers red
wigglers and all of your organic soil
amendments the Rocky Mountain worm
company has dragonfly Earth medicine
products in stock right now Rocky
Mountain worm company will ship to your
door that's right they'll ship Rocky
Mountain worm castings the same worm
castings that I use and many of the same
amendments that I use will get shipped
straight to your door just check out
www. rockymountain worm company.com uh
if you're in the Colorado Springs
Colorado area the store is located at
411 Tiana Street in Colorado Springs
Colorado and make sure you tell them
that you heard about them through the
grow from your heart podcast
also portions of this show are brought
to you by my good friends at H gr indoor
growing supplies H gr indoor growing
supplies has two locations to serve
Colorado visit the Denver store at 6271
Beach Street or check out the Pueblo
location on 618 East 4th Street in
beautiful Pueblo Colorado check out hyro
for competitive pricing and a great
selection of indoor growing supplies
hyro a grow store ran by folks who
actually grow hyro is running a special
for the podcast listeners when you check
out at hyro tell them you listen to The
Grow from your heart podcast and they
will give you commercial pricing on your
entire purchase that's right also the
show is brought to you by my good
friends at Natures green remedies.com
what's up Yankee I hope you're doing
well my friend visit Natures green
remedies.com for gag green genetics
llata Labs Sin City rare dankness mile
high can Adventure the Cali Connection
MTG IE genetics and many more trusted
Brands Nature's green remedies is
running a special for the podcast
listeners type in coupon code uh what's
what's the coupon code it's spring 15
and you'll get 15% off any order and you
always get free priority shipping at
Nature's green remedies.com and guys
that coupon code is good through the
month of March so make sure you shop now
big thanks and much respect to Nature's
green remedies for the promotion and the
continued support they've been with us
since the very beginning guys I only use
sponsors that I completely trust so you
can trust anybody that I talk about on
this show and if they mess with you if
they screw you over if one of our
sponsors [ __ ] you over in any way let
me know and I will help solve the
problem and I may even drop them as a
sponsor because I don't need to
advertise somebody that doesn't support
the community that's how strongly I feel
about it so support all of our sponsors
uh if you're interested in sponsoring
the show send me an email it's grow from
yourheart hotmail.com and I'll get you
all of the information that you need all
right I'm going to turn down the music
here it's a little loud in my ear going
turn that down and let's go to iTunes
and let's read an iTunes comment here it
is this comment is from White trike the
comment is this show is great keep it up
well thanks a lot for the comment white
trike I appreciate that I like hearing
that the show is great and I like the
encouragement so I definitely definitely
will keep it up thanks for that comment
thanks to everybody that's left a
comment in the past let's go to Twitter
I've actually got a couple of Twitter
comments I want to read I feel like I'm
doing a Doug Benson ComEd uh standup
comedy show because Doug Benson just
stands there and reads tweets the whole
time and that's kind of what I'm doing
to you guys but I like supporting the
listeners there wouldn't be a podcast if
there weren't listeners they just be me
talking into a mic for no reason so I
appreciate you guys a lot scrolling
through looking for this notification
here where is it Mr omnio he says
sitting in the garden in the sun while
listening to Rost to Jeff on the girl
from your heart podcast explain worm
casting benefits and Seed genetics ASG
GoodLife Mr omnio dude thanks for
listening to me while you're gardening
that's what I'm hoping for I hope you
guys are in the garden uh learning stuff
while you're playing with the plants
maybe you're on the drive to or from
work maybe you're at work hopefully I'm
in your entertaining you and teaching
you something about
cannabis um Also let's see uh Adrien
ghee the amazing Adrian he said at grow
for uh could be a he or a she let me
check on your stuff here I don't want to
call you he if you're a female I'm sorry
Adrian is kind of a unisex name no that
is a dude in that picture it's
definitely a dude so he Adrien says now
I got to go back to your comment here we
go uh at grow fromy heart podcast just
uh started listening to your podcast
it's great lots of good info and of
course I replied I said thanks for
listening on Twitter uh dude thanks for
listening to the show that's what I'm
here for I'm trying to teach you guys
trying to educate a little bit trying to
move cannabis forward I think if we uh
talk more positively about this plant
people will be less afraid it's all we
got to do is open the door to talk about
it so again big thanks and big shout out
to White trike for the iTunes comment
there uh if you leave a comment on
iTunes or Stitcher I will read it on the
show you guys and if you don't want to
leave a comment on iTunes or Stitcher
send me a tweet it's gfyh podcast or
find me on Facebook and I'll respond to
you there if you want to say something
anonymously you can send me a personal
or private message and I will keep your
name private you can also email me it's
grow fromy yourheart
hotmail.com I know that's a lot of
contact information but if you want to
be in touch I'd love to hear from you so
I said at the beginning of the show that
I had a bunch of news and stuff to talk
about so let's uh click on some stuff
here we go clicking away click click
click and I'm finding the first news
article the first news article is um a
kind of hits home here because I
actually am a medical marijuana
caregiver the way you become a caregiver
um all you really have to do is have um
so I'm a there's a patient there's
that's what we call the person that
smokes a medical marijuana there's a
patient that person goes to the doctor
they get their medical marijuana
recommendation and then when you send
that into the state of Colorado you can
assign a caregiver and that's where uh
my name goes onto that paper my name and
my address and a copy of my ID gets sent
to the state and I become a caregiver
which means I am now responsible for
growing medical cannabis for my friend
who signed me up and um there is a limit
of five people that you're allowed to be
a caregiver for so you can be you can
have yourself plus five other people and
you can grow cannabis for them um that's
kind of how it was and before you were
allowed to have six plants per person
but then there are doctors that are
willing to write you an extended plant
count so if you say uh my back hurts a
lot or I've got fibromyalgia and I don't
smoke cannabis I actually make oils out
of all of this and I need a lot more
plants the doctors will be a little
compassionate and they will write you
what's called an extended plant count
and sometimes that costs you more money
but in the long run that's worth it
because you need your medicine and that
just allows you to grow more plants and
possess more cannabis so the state has
kind of caught on that some of some
people are going to the doctor and there
are some doctors in Colorado that it
just costs money if you want the
original six plants it's cheap you go in
there and pay a cheap like $45 $50 visit
if you want uh 12 plants they double it
if you want 25 plants they pretty much
quadruple your price if you're wanting
50 plants you're paying five times what
you did before there are some doctors
that will write a 99 plant
recommendation for $500 flat uh so you
can grow 99 plants in your house for
$500 for one year um that's how it was
but now they're making all kinds of
rules because they have seen that what
happens is a lot of people sign up for
99 plants and if you grow 99 sgon pots
hopefully you're pulling a whole bunch
of weight and then that's hitting the
black market and they're kind of aware
of that and they don't want that
happening in the state of Colorado
anymore they're really trying to crack
down and tax every gram of pot that's
produced I'm going to take a sip here
and then I'll read you this news article
I've
got I've got some yba mate here it's
nice and hot got to be careful with that
woo all right so the uh this news
article comes from a website called the
Cannabis shout out to the Cannabis I uh
I pull a lot of news articles from this
site this was actually published
February 26th so I'm a little bit behind
but this is still relevant the article
was by Joey bunch of the Denver Post the
headline is Colorado MMJ caregiver Bill
clears senate
committee the article says a state
senate committee on Thursday unanimously
approved a bill that would require
medical marijuana caregivers to register
and allow state agencies to share enough
information to to ensure pot grown for
medicine isn't sold
illegally while pot sold for
recreational use has been subject to a
battery of tests and regulations since
it became legal last year medical
marijuana has gone relatively
unregulated requiring only that
caregivers be at least 18 years old and
have sub significant responsibility for
the care of a licensed medical marijuana
user uh there's actually a spot on the
application that asks what services you
provide for your patient um I write
spiritual counseling I write that I
drive them to from their doctor's
appointments uh because a lot of that is
true uh I prepare meals for some of my
patients um yeah they ask for what you
do and so you got to fill that in and
actually they have they denied one of my
caregiver requests I had to refill out
the paper and put better reasoning
because they did not like my reasons why
I was part of their significant
responsibility so they are paying a
little bit of attention I'll get back to
the article it says the regulatory bill
was characterized by the state agency
and law enforcement officials as a
benefit to caregivers because those
registered would not have to face arrest
or cost or costly legal proceedings if
they're registered with the state the
bill is supported by the Colorado
Cannabis Chamber of Commerce the medical
marijuana supporters testified they were
concerned about cost from regulations
patient privacy and the risk risks of
untested medical marijuana this bill is
re really about assessing law
enforcement but it's doing so at the
expense of the rights of patients and
caregivers said Colorado marijuana
activist Robert Chase who opposed the
legislation leg ation I'm sorry uh in
2009 when the US Attorney General's
office advised federal agents not to
intervene in cases that are compliant
with state laws medical marijuana licens
have exploded in Colorado in 2008 there
were 4,819 licensed medical marijuana
patients in Colorado said Senator Irene
agular as of last December there were 11
15,46 s license loser users said agular
the bill Senate sponsor but to keep
federal Regulators out of ad's pot
business the state must regulate it
adequately she said the federal
expectation is that states that have
allowed marijuana to be legal and local
governments will be implementing strong
and effective Regulatory and enforcement
systems that will protect Public Safety
public health and law enforcement
interest she said while the average age
of Colorado medical marijuana user is 42
years old the number of children has
increased in the past 2 years on
indications pot helps children with
seizures and other illnesses in March
Colorado had 35 patients younger than 18
by last December the number of miners
had grown to 462 agular said Sierra
riddle of Colorado Springs said she
moved from Utah in 2013 because her son
has cancer and needs medical marijuana
um big shout out to team Landon what's
up I didn't even know Sierra was going
to be mentioned in this article those
are uh people that we support in
Colorado Springs so support team Landon
and Sierra riddle if you can big shout
out uh the amount of children that are
increasing on the medical marijuana
registry needs to be considered because
it's only going to increase more she
said these rules and laws need to be put
in place to protect our children to
protect their plant count and to protect
our rights to grow their plants now this
article kind of hits home because I'm a
caregiver myself and the local rules are
changing here to where uh we are we are
being reduced on the number of patients
we are allowed to have which will also
reduce the number of plants we are
allowed to have and they have also
reduced the amount of space we are
allowed to use so that means the five
people that I'm responsible for
providing medical marijuana to somebody
is going to have to find somebody else
to grow their medicine for them and the
state doesn't give a [ __ ] that I've have
been responsible for them for the past
seven or eight years it has been my
responsibility and my duty to take care
of these people I have established a
relationship with them and I have a
significant role in caring for these
people but the state does not care they
need to end that and find a new
caregiver to grow their medical cannabis
for them uh I think that's [ __ ]
because I know these people I know what
strains they like I have bred strains
for my patients yes that's what I do I
have people that smoke medical cannabis
and I will breed strains for them the
night nurse was inspired by my friend
Doug um he's an older cat and his body
hurts and he has a hard time sleeping
when he smoked the torab Bora he said
holy [ __ ] and when he smoked the
Grateful Dog he said holy [ __ ] those
were two of his favorite strains ever so
I felt like it was my job to make a
hybrid of the two and then find the
right phenotype that worked for Doug and
when I grew those he loved it and now
guess what sorry Doug I don't get to be
your caregiver anymore because the state
doesn't give a [ __ ] about our Bonafide
relationship that we've developed over
years not really Doug I'm keeping you
but that's my example and team Landon
there are little kids out there with
brain tumors cancers seizures lymphoma
kids have all kinds of bad things that
adults have and now we need to let these
kids have their caregivers have plant
counts this is messed up this is why I'm
fired up because this is what medical
this is what started the Cannabis
movement in Colorado was medical
cannabis and caregivers caregivers are
what started it the patients and the
caregivers are ground zero and now guess
who's being screwed right out of this
steel the patients and the caregivers
because they want us to be forced to
shop at Recreational dispensaries where
taxes are [ __ ] ridiculous and we
cannot afford it how are we going to
medicate ourselves that way the reason
we are medicating ourselves with
cannabis is so that we don't have to
jump through somebody else's Hoops so
that we don't have to go stand in line
to pay ridiculous prices for medicine
you're [ __ ] us over guys sorry end of
rant I'm passionate about this it pisses
me off because the patients that started
medical cannabis are now the people that
nobody I can't say nobody the people
that most of this industry is looking
over right now we've forgotten them it's
all about the patient Patients First
without the patients there would have
been no medical marijuana movement there
would not have been caregivers there
would have not been hom grows and we
would not have gotten as far as we've
gotten today we be years behind if we
did not start this with medical
marijuana all right so think about the
patience you guys I'm going to do the
best I can I'm going to have to register
my grows with my city and with my state
they're going to come to my private grow
and they're going to look through my
grows and make sure that I'm following
all of the laws and that everything is
done up to code I'm going to sign up to
do that because I'm well known around
here and if I don't do it I know they
will come here and they will try to
press some kind of legal charges on me
um there are paper papers that I can
fill out to have an excuse or an
exception to have more uh patients but I
don't see I'm going to really have to
pull a lot of reasons out of the air
because their their paperwork they don't
have any compassion they have check
marks you know what I mean does this
this and this happen then no and it's
just like talking to a computer instead
of a person with compassion it sucks all
right that's enough on that article give
me a second all right guys I'm back I
took a couple dabs I calmed down I'm not
so pissed off about that last article
anymore but we have a whole new article
coming up and this could uh this could
do a lot of things to to us uh the sub
headline is another lawsuit has been
filed in federal court over Colorado's
marijuana legalization Amendment uh the
headline is new lawsuit sheriffs from
Colorado and elsewhere challenge
amendment 64 what makes the new suit
unique is that it is also asking for a
federal judge to overturn Amendment 64's
protections for marijuana use and pro uh
possession uh this article is written by
Kirk Mitchell and John inold of the
Denver Post let's get right into into it
six Colorado sheriffs sued their own
governor in federal court on Thursday
arguing that state laws legalizing
marijuana require them to violate
federal law joining the sheriffs in the
lawsuit the fourth to be filed against
Colorado over marijuana legalization are
the sheriffs and prosecutors from
Nebraska and Kansas the suit argues that
federal law Supremacy means Colorado
cannot allow people to possess or use
marijuana for recreational purposes and
it cannot license stores to sell it the
law does not challenge Colorado's
medical marijuana laws or stores the
suit is about one thing the rule of the
law larer County Sheriff Justin Smith
said in a news release release I said
released geez uh the Colorado
Constitution mandates that all elected
officials including sheriffs swear an
oath of office to uphold both the United
States as well as the Colorado
constitutions the suit names Governor
John Hickenlooper as the lone defendant
Colorado's attorney general Cynthia
Kaufman will defend the State against
the lawsuit of spokesman for her
said the lawsuit excuse me the lawsuit
has the backing of national
anti-legalization groups and its
Nationwide Ambitions were apparent in
the choice of where to announce the suit
in a news conference Thursday morning at
the national Press Club in Washington DC
Smith told reporters that Colorado's
passage of amendment 64 created a
constitutional shutdown in the state the
amendment which voters approved in 2012
made it legal for people over 21 in
Colorado to possess limited amounts of
marijuana and for licens stores to sell
marijuana cannabis we think that col we
think that what Colorado has done is
illegal we think it's unconstitutional
Scots Bluff County Nebraska Sheriff Mark
Overman who is also a plaintiff in the
suit said at the news conference I
believe my fellow plaintiffs believe
that this case is going to have National
ramifications and if we win then we can
reverse what looks like a surrender to a
pro marijuana crowd the lawsuit follows
another legal challenge filed in
December by Nebraska and Oklahoma which
asked the US Supreme Court to strike
down the history-making law two lawsuits
filed earlier this year by the
anti-legalization group Safe Streets
Alliance on behalf of several Colorado
residents are also pending against the
state over amendment 64 similar to the
previous lawsuits the new suit seeks to
close all of Colorado's recreational
marijuana stores but it also asks
Federal a federal judge to overturn
Amendment 64's protections for marijuana
use and possession the law enforcement
officials suit claim that local officers
are breaking federal law and
international treaties when they find
marijuana but they do not seize it at
Thursday's news conference Yuma County
Sheriff Chad day said Colorado's
marijuana laws now prohibit officers
from seizing marijuana in C certain
circumstances putting officers he said
in an inevitable uh position that's kind
of funny uh by supporting and upholding
one we violating the other he said I'm
excited to very least get an answer from
the courts D these cops are not robots
they are people and they know they're
they know what they're supposed to do
these guys are acting like we've got
droids out there acting as police
officers and we're going to flip their
switch and make their computers crash
this is ridiculous dude uh Sam Cayman
I'm probably saying that wrong Sam k a
law professor at the University of
Denver was skeptical of the sheriff's
argument he said no law requires local
officers to act as deao federal drug
agents of the four lawsuits this is the
one with the least Merit cman said they
have targeted not just the marijuana
store regulation piece but they're also
essentially saying Colorado can't
legalized marijuana no one has ever gone
that far Colorado plan ifs in the latest
lawsuit include Smith day Elbert County
Sheriff Shane Heap Hinsdale County
Sheriff Ronald Bruce kyowa County
Sheriff Casey Sheridan and Delta County
Sheriff Frederick mcke of the six
Colorado sheriffs involved in the
lawsuit only Smith is from a county that
approved amendment 64 with 50 55% of
8,000 or
86410 voters approving the measure the
measure was approved in 33 of 64
Colorado counties by a 55%
margin also known named as Plains are
three Nebraska sheriffs Adam Hayward of
duel County Mark Overman of Scott Bluff
County and John Jensen of Cheyenne
County Cheyenne County attorney Paul Sha
of Nebraska and Sheriff Charles moer of
Sherman Wallace and gy counties in
Kansas also signed the document sorry I
kind of s in that last part there but
that was a lot of names is really all uh
as in the excuse me as in the lawsuit
filed in Nebraska and Oklahoma the law
enforcement officials from Nebraska and
Kansas are are arguing in the new
lawsuit that marijuana flowing out of
Colorado Post legalization has led to
more arrests and strain their budgets um
I'm going to jump in here and say so
legalize pot and your States just
legalize weed in Nebraska and Oklahoma
and Kansas and uh you won't have to
worry about arresting more people and
straining your budget you'll be able to
sell a cannabis like we do here in
Colorado and you'll be able to fill up
your cash registers at the stores and
you'll be able to fix your stupid ass
roads that you guys have du think about
it come on let's use our [ __ ] brains
people all right it's actually taking
money out of Sherman County taxpayers
Pockets uh Burton pianalto uh the
sheriff in Sherman County Kansas said at
Thursday's news conference in January
nine out of the 46 people booked into
Sherman County Jail were susp ected of
possessing or Distributing hallucina
hallucinogenic drugs the category under
which marijuana is classified in Kansas
criminal law according to an online
booking log two out of the 15 inmates
listed on Thursday as being currently
housed in the county jail face charges
related to hallucinogenic drugs so more
[ __ ] they call cannabis a
hallucinogenic drug which is right in
the same category as probably LSD
mushrooms
ecstasy um this is some cannabis you
guys this is Medical SCH marijuana it's
funny to think that over an invisible
line that this is now a hallucinogenic
drug and you cross this invisible line
and now it's recreational cannabis and
then you can cross another line and it's
medical marijuana this is so good I love
the uh time and place that we live in
this is so amazing to me all right uh
where was I Colorado officials have not
yet responded to any of the pinning
lawsuits previously State Attorneys have
argued that Colorado's more permissive
marijuana laws both for medical and
recreational use and sales do not out to
legalization of marijuana instead they
contend that marijuana remains illegal
in Colorado aside from the specific
exemptions allowed under the medical and
recreational marijuana laws when
Nebraska and Oklahoma filed their
lawsuit against Colorado last year then
Colorado Attorney General John John
suthers said in a statement that it
appears the plaintiff's primary
grievance stems from a non-enforcement
of federal laws regarding marijuana as
opposed to choices made by the voters of
Colorado Mason tvert one of the lead
proponent on of amendment 64 said if the
lawsuits are successful in Striking down
the measure it would lead to a system of
marijuana chaos which I would love to
see what happened I don't want it to
happen but it'd be really neat to see
how it's dealt with because there are
dispensaries on every other Corner in
Denver every other Corner in Colorado
Springs bublo West has 12 or 15
dispensaries now in that small community
they are everywhere they'd be hard to
come and they'd have to go to California
they'd have to go to every state that's
got medical cannabis they couldn't just
come here cuz then that would be uh
they'd be singling us out says this is
just another case of the arrest and
prosecution industry teaming up with
marijuana prohibition groups to roll
back the progress that has been made in
Colorado he said in a statement Thursday
uh us rep Jared pus said in a statement
that the US Department of Justice and
President Obama have made clear that
they will not interfere with the states
whose citizens voted for recreational
marijuana use this lawsuit is a silly
attempt to circumvent the will of
Colorado voters and is a waste of time
po statement said says unfortunately
these frivolous lawsuits will likely
continue until we pass my bipartisan
regulate marijuana like alcohol act and
finally end the outdated Federal
prohibition of
marijuana so these states have filed a
suit and they're trying to sue us to
shut down our recreational marijuana
program because they can't get cannabis
to stop coming into their states I think
I said it the first time stop [ __ ]
with us and do what you can to make
respectable responsible cannabis laws in
Nebraska and Kansas and Oklahoma and
then the states bordering those will
have to follow suit and then eventually
it'll just be a whole green map instead
of having a red and blue map we'll start
having all green States this will be
great all right so here's another
article that I keep seeing pop up on
social media I'm finding this article on
the Cannabis I get a lot of my articles
from there this was written by
Christopher Ingraham from The Washington
Post there's a cute little headline
article here or headline picture of a
little bunny rabbit sitting on a digital
scale and the bunny weighs 93.2 grams
that's kind of cute um the headline says
Utah DEA warns of stoned rabbits if
State passes medical marijuana bill I'll
say it again DEA warns of stoned rabbits
if State passes medical marijuana bill
now let you take that in now I'll read
the
article Utah is considering a bill that
would allow patients with certain
debilitating conditions to be treated
with edible forms of marijuana
if the bill passes the state's Wildlife
May cultivate a taste for the plant lose
their fear of humans and basically be
high all the time that's according to
testimony presented to a Utah State
panel last week by an agent of The Drug
Enforcement Administration IDE deal in
facts IDE deal in science said special
agent Matt Fairbanks who's been working
in the state for a decade he is a member
of the marijuana eradication team in
Utah some of his colleagues in Georgia
recently achieved notoriety by re raing
a retirees Garden and seizing a number
of okra plants Fairbanks spoke of his
time eliminating Backcountry marijuana
grows in the Utah mountains specifically
the environmental costs associated with
large-scale weed cultivation on public
land personally I've seen entire
mountainsides subjected to pesticides
harmful chemicals deforestation and
erosion he said the ramifications to the
Flora the animal life the contaminated
water are still unknown Fairbanks said
that at some illegal marijuana grow
sites he saw rabbits that had C ated a
taste for the marijuana he continued one
of them refused to leave us as we took
all the marijuana around him but his
Natural Instincts to run Were Somehow
gone it's true that illegal pot farming
can have harmful environmental
consequences of course nothing about
these consequences is unique to
marijuana If corn were outlawed the
cartels would start growing it on
national forests the per plant
environmental toll would be about the
same which is kind of a neat fact uh but
Bounty marijuana grows are a direct
result of marijuana's illegal status if
you're concerned about the environmental
impact of the grows an alternative is to
legalize and regulate the plant so that
people can grow it on farms and in their
Gardens rather than on remote Mountain
sides now regarding Stone rabbits some
wild animals apparently do develop a
taste for
bud but I don't know that the occasional
High rabbit constitutes for grounds for
keeping marijuana Prohibition in place
any more than drunk squirrels are an
argument for outlawing alcohol and let's
not even get started on the Nationwide
epidemic of catnip
abuse there was a time not too long ago
when drug Warriors terrified a nation
with images of the devil's weed and reer
Madness now it seems that enforcers of
marijuana law Conjuring up a stoned
Bunny not scary enough for the Utah
State it seems the panel approved the
bill and sent it to the full Senate
where it will be debated this week well
good luck to you Utah I hope that this
bill passes I hope that you're allowed
to consume an edible form of marijuana
um outlawing cannabis in your state
because the rabbits are going to get
stoned would be a lot like outlawing
roads because dogs and squirrels are
going to get ran over it's kind of a
stupid ass argument come up with
something better uh we aren't buying
that [ __ ] anymore because I've got
one more news article that I want to
read and then we are going to wrap up
the
show uh this one is from the to of the
Town actually and this will be the final
news article that I am ever going to
read from the to of the town and I will
tell you why
this article comes from the to of the
town and it says after 5 years to of the
Town says goodbye since 2009 to of the
town has brought you the biggest
marijuana news and the loudest pop views
from across the country and around the
world along the way we've covered the
huge progress many states have made
toward legalization and wondered why
others are so far behind this country
still has a long way to go but things
are looking up and we have our fingers
crossed that 2015 will be another big
year for legalization but the to won't
be around to see it at least not in its
present form this is the toes uh to of
the town's final day of publication and
this was actually written at the end of
the year uh don't worry we're not
quitting the movement we're just
returning the focus of our marijuana
coverage to our local voice Media Group
papers you can still read William
breed's weekly pot reviews and ask a
stoner column at westward.com where they
started and you can continue to follow
him on Twitter and on Facebook and you
can keep following to on Facebook and
Twitter too for the latest marijuana
news from all of our papers many thanks
for reading and supporting us for the
past 5 years we couldn't have covered
the marijuana Community without such a
strong one reading us oh the community
itself is a strong one I was thrown off
by the way they worded that uh and all
of our archives will remain online
because we wouldn't want you to lose
access to our serious reporting on
issues of medicine and our light-hearted
coverage of stoner movies light one up
for us won't you so this is a little
outdated because this was put out at the
end of the year the start of this year
at the end of last year the to of the
town is not posting any more news I used
to pull a lot of news articles from
there but I will not have them as a
resource anymore so we will miss you to
of the town you were a great resource
for my little podcast here you provided
a lot of news articles I'll do a dab for
you later I'll miss the to of the town
all right guys that's enough news for
one episode I'm going to wrap up the
show here it's been about 30 minutes
let's see how far we've been going look
at that I'm getting good at this I did
31 minutes I didn't even know what how
much time we've done I'm getting good
all right let's see let's tease some
next things I think the garden of Weeden
will be here on the next episode I have
a phone interview planned with a cat
known as soil grown on Instagram uh soil
grown is doing something he calls rosent
Tech if you haven't seen that we'll talk
about that a little bit on the next
episode uh Garden of we will be here
we're going to talk about canopy
management big shout out to our friends
Greenworks who got us started on this
canopy management product project uh in
an upcoming episode we will have turpex
and uh hunt from the Grammy Gatsby to
come talk about some things I'm actually
going to Colorado Springs to interview
those guys also big shout out to
fastberry what's up fastberry on
Instagram dude you asked me a couple of
questions today on Instagram and then
you asked me if you were bothering me no
dude you're not bothering me at all I
love the questions I love that you
listen to the podcast I love that you
support all of the iry genetics stuff on
Instagram I love that you listen to The
Grow from your heart podcast you're
never bothering me dude ask me more
questions uh I will use your questions
as material for the show you'll hear
your stuff broadcasted to the whole
world so dude you're never bothering me
and that goes for everybody if you send
me an email if you send me a tweet if
you send me a Facebook message whatever
however you hit me up you're not
bothering me I will answer you sometimes
it'll take a minute because you wouldn't
believe how many emails and messages I
get but I will respond to you uh the
best way to contact me uh would be to
join my Forum on IR genetics.com go to
The Forum create an account and go
somewhere and ask me a question there
there's an ask the breeder part ask a
question there and I will answer you
because that's my Forum uh I'm fully
respons responsible for that and I check
that I try to get on there every Monday
uh I can't do it every Monday because
life goes certain ways but ask a
question I'll answer it on the Forum and
then uh if I ever need new uh testers
for new seeds that's the first place I
go to look for testers I look for your
grow photos I check out your profile on
my Forum because that shows me that
you're interested in my brand and you're
kind of loyal so join the Forum I would
appreciate that uh big shout out to my
friend Judy also big shout out to hippie
nurse and a big shout out to Dreadful
Jay look forward to seeing everybody at
the Cannabis Cup all right let's wrap up
this show let's get to that last paper
where I read all that stuff uh don't
forget to check out our sponsors the
Rocky Mountain worm company and hyro
indoor growing supplies make sure you
visit Nature's green remedies.com make
sure you use that coupon code spring15
for 15% off your entire order uh if
you're interested in sponsoring the
podcast or if you have a product you'd
like me to review send me an email grow
from yourart at hotmail.com and I'll get
you all the information that you need
guys now that the show is over please go
to the iTunes Store uh search for grow
from your heart find the review section
give me a five star rating after that
type in a comment and let me know what
you think of the show and I will read
your comment on a future episode uh
Stitcher keeps changing the way the
comments are handled so leave a comment
wherever you can on there and I will
find it and I will read that if you have
something to say in your want into the
social media thing you can email me it's
grow yourheart hotmail.com don't forget
every show is available on iTunes
Stitcher and also iy gentics
color.com don't forget we added that
donation button to the podcast page if
you feel like the show is worth a couple
bucks you can go to the website IR
gentics color.com click on the grow
fromy heart podcast tab at the top of
the right uh the top right there's a
donation button that goes directly to my
Paypal account you guys will never
charge you anything for the podcast I
keep saying that because I mean it this
is going to be a free podcast but if you
feel like making a donation or a
contribution for the amount of time that
I spent on this show for the amount of
time that I spent putting the show
together I buy water bottles for
everybody that comes on the show I smoke
everybody out it takes a couple of my
day uh I got to do web service and stuff
like that so I'm not begging you I'm
just letting you know this if you want
to throw down something I would
appreciate it I'll give you a shout out
on the show uh we are on all the social
media sites search for us grow from your
heart on Twitter it's gfyh podcast
there's a Facebook um if you're going to
look for us on Instagram it's I gentics
I just combined everything it's one
Instagram page I think that's the end of
the show guys I covered everything I
wanted to say thanks a lot for listening
uh big huge shout out to my ninja Spence
until next time take a big fat dab and
give your mom a hug for
me we've got to narrow it down got to
cut out this
striate between the work and the fun
then you will find your work is easily
done enough opportun staring you down
you know feel like I feel take a good
look around you can live without every
struggle cut the rest don't
just keep your