good morning noon or evening or wherever
you are this is um
hey hi everybody and you're listening to
the girl from your heart podcast
with rasta jeff grow from your heart
flow from your heart listen with your
heart or something like that
[Music]
all right here we go welcome back
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rasta jeff and it is time for
episode 570 of the grow from your heart
podcast
this episode of the show is brought to
you by my friends at seedshearnow.com
seedshearnow.com carry seeds from all
the industries
leading breeders including miss jill
genetics duke diamond and of course irie
genetics
everything at seeds herenow.com is
backed by an award-winning satisfaction
guarantee
and for my friends on a tight budget
seeds herenow.com offers several packs
for under thirty dollars as well as
amazing
monthly sales make sure to use coupon
code gfyh10 while checking out to save a
few bucks
again that is coupon code gfyh10 while
checking out
at seeds here now.com
you know i like to start this podcast
off by talking about what i'm smoking
today i've been taking dabs of angel's
breath live batter from green dot labs
this is a blend of halo and purple
starburst on the package the flavor is
described as
gas floral and apple i think i
completely agree with that
when i crack open the jar i'm greeted
with that gassy aroma
when i take a dab that is when the
sweetness of the floral kicks in
then after i exhale that is when a sour
apple flavor
just lingers on my tongue and i
completely enjoy it
one thing i should mention is that this
concentrate kicked
my ass i took a couple of fat dabs and
now i'm sitting here
in mellow mode i'm super chilled out
this has got me nice and relaxed
on the back of the package it says it
contains 67.11
thc big shout out to our friends at
green dot labs for the
tremendously potent angels breath live
batter all right in this episode i'm
going to read a few emails and patreon
messages
before we get there let's do some shout
outs to a few of the folks in the 710
club of course the 710 club
are the folks who support us on patreon
at the 7 and 10 cent a month level or
higher
so let's start off with the big grow
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out to my buddy lemur priest
let's follow that up with the grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to nick
i also want to say thank you to mike
molds let's send a big thank you shout
out to
tad masterson i want to send a big thank
you shout out to jesse
i've always got a big thank you shout
out for brian c let's send a special
thank you shout out to brad
i'll let send a big thank you shout out
to our new member d tom420
and last but certainly not least i want
to send a giant thank you shout out to
my friend
tree star meadows big thanks and big
shout out to everybody who supports the
show on patreon
if you are not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need to support
the show
will be right there on the screen and of
course i did include a link in the show
notes
to make that nice and easy for my
friends
all right let's not waste too much time
let's not let me get too rambling and
too off track
let's jump right into the first email
for today's episode
this one comes from our friend they
signed it one love from zombie
this one comes from our friend zombie
this is a great question it goes
like this hey bro i had a quick question
about splitting a grow space
i have a room that is approximately
seven feet wide by seven feet deep and
10-ish
feet tall all right i've got a good
visual of that in my head
i currently have a 5x5 grow tent in the
room
and the wasted space is driving me nuts
uh yeah you've got a big room there
you're wasting uh at least two feet by
two feet each direction
there's a lot of wasted space you could
be doing a lot more productivity
a lot more production in there a lot
more plants is what i'm trying to say
that would drive me nuts as well let's
keep going the message says after much
brainstorming i think the best solution
is going to be building
a wall between the flower space at three
and a half by seven feet
and a veg mother space at three by seven
feet
um okay i think there's an extra foot
somewhere there but that mats out i
think
feel free to add your thoughts and input
on that
um my thoughts so far is that that
doesn't matter
there's a half a foot somewhere missing
but uh you're close enough then it's
gonna go on to say
my question however is about accessing
the flowering space
there's only one door to the room and
i'm thinking it should open into the veg
space
since so there is no risk of a light
leak
from my main area causing trouble i get
what you're asking and yes that does
make great sense i will elaborate
our friend has a big room he wants to
divide the room into two spaces
he's thinking about building a wall
almost right down the center maybe leave
one side maybe leave that flower space a
little bit bigger the veg and mom's side
a little smaller
but build a wall right down the middle
now we've got two rooms he's wondering
if he should access the room through
that veg space yes absolutely
the veg space we can interrupt that
light cycle the veg will be on more
often than the flowering cycle
we're gonna run an 18-6 cycle perhaps a
24-hour on cycle in there
let's walk into the grow through the veg
space i'm gonna keep going because there
is more to this it says
so my issue is that i have a standard
door in the room
i have to keep so much space clear to
physically open the door
i'm wondering if you've seen anything in
your experience consulting low-key grows
that would be a good substitute for a
standard door that i could maintain
usable space in the veg and mother
area so i had a couple of great
suggestions and ideas for my friend
zombie here
i said that my first recommendation
would be to build
a just frame out a door a wall in the
room make it just a crappy frame it
won't take a lot of work just
some two by fours build a frame frame
out a wall staple some poly to that wall
now you've got a brand new wall if you
don't have a lot of tools if you can't
build a frame
you can staple it to the ceiling you can
staple it to the walls and let it hang
put a 2x4 down on the floor and wrap it
around the 2x4 that'll give it some
structure at the bottom give it some
support some stability you've got it
stapled to the walls to the ceiling
you've got it held to the floor that
should keep it in place depending on how
big
this piece of panda film is or poly or
whatever you're going to use i'd
recommend
i think paulie and panda film are just
the same thing just different words for
the same [ __ ]
i get some thick panda film staple it up
to the ceiling staple it to the walls
before you staple it fold it to make a
little fold-over you're doubling up the
thickness of material
then put a piece of duct tape over it
then put the staples through the duct
tape
now you've got three pieces of material
you are duct taping through the ceiling
or to the ceiling
so when that weight of that poly starts
pulling down it doesn't tear
the poly right away it'll give you duct
tape and two pieces of poly worth of
stretching
before it starts to tear so make a
division
make a wall make a poly wall then at
most grow stores you will find
one of my favorite inventions it is a
zipper it comes rolled up it's a long
rolled up zipper
you take that zipper and you think about
where you want your door to be
you unroll the zipper and it's got a
sticker on the back of it you take it
off just like you're putting on a big
bumper sticker
and you start from the floor and you go
up or you can start at the top and go
down but it's easier to start at the
floor and go up in my opinion
put that zipper right at the floor and
unroll it and work your way up
now you unzip the zipper and take a
blade and cut
right between those two pieces and now
when you're ready to close it your
zipper slides up and down and you've got
a zippered
door so we've made a poly wall we built
a just a minimal frame
you don't need a lot of framing just
enough to keep the panda film supported
build the wall then buy the zipper
hydrafarm or other companies make this
zipper it just sticks right on
i can't explain it any better than that
it's a zipper they come zipped up
it's got sticky on it you stick it on
just like a sticker you
unzip it and then you cut right up the
middle where you zip and now you've made
a separation and you can zip that closed
i hope that makes sense i'm explaining
it the best i can
it looks good in my mind can't you see
in my mind to see what i'm trying to
show you
all right jump in there for a minute get
a free visual then jump out because
there's [ __ ] you do not want to see
let's keep moving uh we've built a poly
wall we put a little bit of a zipper on
there
now you can enter that flowering room
through the veg space of course you want
to go into the flowering room make that
the back part
don't go in there when the veg is on and
the flowering room is off make sure the
flowering room is on
time that right but you should never
have to enter the veg through the flower
that's one
thing you should always follow now let's
address this door
question you did ask how can i make some
space for the door
that is a very good question here's a
very good suggestion
i learned this from a uh i don't
remember where i learned this
here's a really good suggestion i may
edit that i may not here's a suggestion
for your door space
one thing i have seen is most of the
time doors swing open
one thing i've seen people do is make a
sliding door if the door just slides
over
if it just moves to the side and doesn't
swing you don't get that whole swinging
space wasted
however much square footage that is of
the door the door is probably two three
feet long
you gotta have that big swinging space
that's a lot of space wasted you could
probably put
two three maybe four seven gallon pots
in the space that it takes to swing a
door
so i understand that that is valuable
real estate make a sliding door
the door doesn't have to swing if you
can put a sliding door there
if you could take the door off and just
pop it off and on in and out every day
that would be cool i understand this
could be your home i don't know where
you're doing this
but a sliding door would save you a lot
of space i'm sure the house doesn't have
a sliding door that room probably
doesn't have a sliding door now
but in a lot of places where the homes
are smaller they don't have a lot of
space
you will see that a sliding door is more
effective more efficient more economical
might be the word i'm looking for but
anyway sliding door
would help you out so um i would say
instead of dividing it by 50 50
i would say probably do 60 40 maybe
uh 35 7 what is the math there 65
35 something like that uh yeah i know
i'm doing math on the fly we'll call it
engineer math
uh divide a little bit differently then
build that poly wall stick the zipper on
there and then build yourself a sliding
door
let me make sure i answered all of the
questions in here it looks like i
covered you uh yep
and then it says one love from zombie a
zombie big love big respect thank you
for the great message
i want to hear how this worked out for
you i want to know if you were able to
build that wall because i did reply to
zombie with the detailed email gave him
some great info
i wanna know how that went for you
please let me know alright i'm gonna
keep moving so i don't get too rambly
and get too off topic here
our next message comes from um
oh it says my name is jeff this message
comes from another listener named jeff
what's up jeff
good to meet you and it says hey ross to
jeff
i apologize and the delay for thanking
you for the pack of sun
kiss uh never a delay and a thanks i get
it the world is busy
you said thank you you are very welcome
i'm glad i was able to help you out with
a pack of sun-kissed seeds
it says they are perfect for me so thank
you i and i remember getting this person
a pack of sun kiss i understand the
situation
uh that's in the past we won't talk too
much about that but you're very welcome
for the pack of seeds i hope they will
work well for you i know it says i've
got a question for the show
first i see no difference in seed banks
that they sell cbd genetics and the
flowers are loaded with trichomes
what exactly is that made out of if it's
almost
no thc um okay so i think the question
you're saying is that you see
seeds advertised on seed banks that are
supposed to be high in
cbd but they are covered in trichomes
those trichomes just don't contain thc
that plant is not
known to produce thc that's not one of
the traits of that plant
so that is cbd within that plant that's
what they're advertising i haven't grown
that seed
i can't testify what it's going to do
but uh
you're saying what is exactly is that
made out of if it's almost no thc
inside of those trichomes it is cbd
that's all it is in there
no thc they're lab testing it is not
showing the presence of thc
so it goes on to say and they are
different density
or shape or anything really i think
you're asking if
cbd buds are any different than thc buds
it is basically the same plant hemp and
cannabis
are basically the same plant in colorado
the main distinction between hemp and
cannabis
is a lab test that tells you if that
plant has point
three percent thc or higher if it's got
more than that
it is now a cannabis plant it is not a
hemp plant that may be 0.3 or 0.03
somebody will correct me i didn't look
before i started the show i have a bad
habit of forgetting
that number uh it's not something i need
to pay attention to a lot
but that is basically the distinction
between hemp
and cannabis is thc or cbd and a lab
test it is the same plant
it's the same thing it's just different
traits does one put
does one express thc or does one express
cbd sometimes you get both
and there are also other cannabinoids
that we're learning about and
discovering they're just not as uh
prevalent and popular
at this time you're going to hear about
uh cbv
if you haven't already that'll be the
next one that i predict will be really
popular and cbg as well
so it goes on it says i see a lot of
websites taking use
the same pictures for multiple strains
and breeders
i'm not sure what you mean by that the
same website website
uses the same strain multiple pictures
strains and breeders
if the one breeder is on multiple
websites you should use the same pick
but i think you might be saying that you
see the same picture pop up on multiple
websites that's kind of [ __ ]
that shouldn't be happening i'm not sure
exactly what you mean there
i can't speak too much on that without a
clear idea of what you mean
it says um i see a lot of websites
taking these the same pictures
and it says i was the man at playing
memory as a kid i've even seen it in a
few grow books
so yeah i think there weren't as many
photographers and as many people
taking cannabis photography and doing it
and so people were able to be kind of
sneaky for a little while now the
industry has
gotten more transparent a while back
everybody was just working in the
shadows nobody knew who the breeders
were nobody knew what the growers looked
like nobody knew who the photographers
were
so it was easier to kind of do people
and not be completely honest and
completely transparent
so hopefully those times are passed
hopefully you're going to start seeing
actual real legit photos of the plants
i know some breeders will put pictures
of the mom plants they can get photos
out early and start selling the seeds
i don't like to do that kind of stuff i
don't think that's right i can't speak
for what you saw
but hopefully it doesn't happen anymore
hopefully the industry has changed
with all the transparency with
legalization hopefully that [ __ ] goes
away
that says you've also seen it in grow
books i'm sure i'm sure you've seen that
sort of stuff it's gonna happen
but uh hopefully it doesn't happen
anymore we are getting more integrity in
the industry is the word i've been
fishing for
uh then there's more to this it says
second question is what you
what brought you to be a rastafarian i
know very little about it
i was raised baptist and i hit a certain
age and i couldn't pretend
anymore to believe it so now i have no
faith
ah that's okay it says i was curious if
you were brought up with your beliefs or
found them later in life all right let
me jump in here before i go too far
what brought me to rastafari um
just like most people i was at a point
in life where i was looking for
something i didn't know i was looking
for something but there was a gap in my
life i didn't know what it was
i met a couple of people who were rasta
and they taught me a lot of great things
i was really drawn to one guy shout out
ross chris
you always mean a lot to me bro also big
shout out to ross bradley
those two guys taught me a lot they
influenced and inspired me quite a bit
they kind of looked after me they
wouldn't let me get too out of line if
my
line of thinking was too outlandish
they'd say bro that's not right and
they'd kind of
reel me in uh ross chris was seriously
still is a heavy practicing rastafarian
rasta brad is he's got rasta in his
heart he doesn't follow rasta so much
now
i had to kind of adjust to a different
lifestyle but those guys taught me a lot
i think being around them being exposed
to rasta
all the right things just the stars
lined up there's another rasta saying it
says
he who feels it knows it and i know it
so
ah and no i wasn't raised around
rastafari
our family celebrated christmas and
easter but i don't think we
went to church more than five times when
i was a kid so
uh they believed in christianity but
they weren't christians if that's
like they acted they were walmart
christians they were american christians
they were holiday christians that might
be the way to put it uh
they tried to be celebratory and whatnot
but ah no our family wasn't
really faith or religious based that was
all on my own
i kind of discovered that uh as an as a
young adult
and kind of just on my own because of
some friends and just being around my
friends and having a gap and when i
started
i knew that my life was going well and i
knew that when i acknowledged the good
things in my life i got more good things
and when i started thinking jaw for
those things and listening to the
guidance of rastafari those good things
started coming in abundance and i still
still follow that every day give thanks
for what i'm given every day
and the good gifts keep coming so i must
be doing something right
uh people don't want to hear too much
about religious talk on a podcast they
don't come here for that they come here
for grow knowledge
so thank you for the quick opportunity
to talk about rastafari for a moment
a lot of people have asked me i've kind
of avoided the question on the podcast
that's for me that's not for you and a
lot of people don't care so
uh i became rastafari because ross chris
and ross brad were really inspirational
uh because i knew there were a lot of
good things going on in my life and a
lot of it was pointing to rastafari
and uh i don't know it's been there ever
since and it's never going away
so that's where rasta came from i want
to keep going it says i believe your
fans are not a bunch of judgmental
pricks and would love to get a little
deeper
into what made rosted jeff i hope that
was uh
enough and not too much i'm sure some
people got bored but rastafari thank you
for hanging out
says i sure would too you can use my
name it is
jeff hey jeff thank you for the great
message thank you for the
cannabis culture and cultivation
question i wish i had more answers for
you about your cbd
question i don't know why you're seeing
the same photo for different strains
uh that is just bad ethics and no
integrity
hopefully that [ __ ] stops and rastafari
i think i explained how rasta landed on
me where are we in this show we're about
19 minutes in
let's knock out one more message uh this
one comes from
justice groves make sure you follow
justice underscore grows on instagram
justice's question actually casey's
question goes
just like this it says hey jeff i
learned about your podcast
via the grow cast and i've really been
enjoying your grow advice
and other content big shout out to our
buddy jordan river for having me on the
grow cast
thank you for the opportunity i need to
return the favor and get you on the show
here really soon
let's talk about it it said uh you said
uh feel free to email me with questions
so here it goes that's right i told you
email with questions
if anybody else out there has a cannabis
culture or cultivation question
i would love to hear from you my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
this question goes a lot like this
i purchased regular seeds for the first
time and i'm trying to figure out
how and when to cull the males i'm
growing in a single 4x4 tent which i use
for both
veg and flower i prefer the scrog method
for plant training i see where we're
going to run into problems here
however i typically begin scrogging
during the mid
veg stage and i'm assuming i won't be
able to identify the sex
until very late in veg or early flower i
obviously don't want to
scrog all of my plants and then try to
untangle and remove a bunch of males
after they've grown into the netting any
advice you can provide on how to best
resolve this issue would be greatly
appreciated
thanks for the great work you do from
casey also known as
justice groves on instagram this is a
great question this will get me talking
for quite a few minutes
we need to realize that the first run
with the batch of seeds is not the
production
run you were thinking about growing big
ass plants
scrogging them out training them
spending a bunch of time on them
and you don't even know what you've got
you don't know if you've got males you
don't know if you've got hermaphrodites
you don't know if you've got [ __ ]
phenotypes
you don't know what's in there so we
need to readjust our approach we need to
do
a phenol hunt and a finder run before we
do a big production run
you do have a couple of options if you
don't want to waste a lot of time
if you just want to find the males and
cull the males and get them out of there
a real easy way to do it is to put the
plants
under 1212 lighting reduce the lights to
12 give them 12 hours of darkness 12
hours of daytime
in about 10 to 15 days you will see sex
those plants will show you if they're
boys or girls
as soon as you have verified the sex of
the plants put the timer back on 18
6. if these plants only get about 14
days into flower
it will not take much to revert them
back to veg
then you can put them under your scrog
screen spread them out the way you need
to
you're not going to waste a lot of space
that is a very quick and easy way
to determine sex you can just throw the
plants right under 12 12
and they will show you if they're boys
or girls then put them right back into
veg take those boys out of there
spread those girls out get them in the
scrog net just the way you need to
another option is to cut a clone i know
you've only got the one room
if you had two rooms this is what i
would do i would cut a clone
from each of those plants i would label
the plants first plant one plant two
plant three
if you want to name them [ __ ] carol
karen and eileen you can do that
but label them then take a clone make
sure that the clone is labeled
appropriately karen carol and eileen one
two and three however you want to do it
then put those clones under 1212
lighting
the clones will root and they will show
you sex within like i said earlier 10 to
15 days
those clones will start to grow balls or
they'll grow pistols and you can tell if
you've got males or
females then you can throw the clones
away go throw the big plants away
spread out those females but since you
have only got the one space
i think your best bet is to put the
plants under 12
12 lighting let them show you if they're
male or female
then return them back to 18 and 6 or 24
hours of lighting whichever you prefer
whichever you're doing
the 24 hours of lighting will re-veg
them more quickly but i think the plants
will grow more happily
with the 18 6. everybody likes a nap i'd
probably kick ass with 24-hour days
i've got a lot of energy i last a long
time but i will need a nap eventually so
i think 18 6 may be the way to go
so let me read back over the question
make sure i didn't skip anything
yes we are all at the same point here i
would say put your plants in 12 12 for
just a few days
as soon as you see sex put that timer
back on 18-6
put that scrog net up everything will go
just as planned but you've got to keep
in mind
that sometimes that first run isn't
meant to be a production run i would
rather you
grow them small don't even scrog them
out just put them in there
turn them and burn them and see what
you've got now i understand that you
don't have clones
so even if you do have amazing keepers
you can't run it again
but in most ideal situations we would
have a clone that we could run
over and over again what are you going
to do bro are you going to run these
seeds one time and let them go
what if you get the most amazing [ __ ]
keeper plant out of this and you don't
have a clone
we are both going to be heartbroken
that's when you're going to have to
learn how to reveg
oh man all right you're going to want it
more tense that's what i'm thinking
you're gonna want more tents really
really soon so uh justice grows my
advice for you is to put those plants
under 1212 lighting until they begin to
show you sex
as soon as you see sex pull the boys out
put the girls all back in that
uh 18 6 lighting throw up the scrog net
grow them into the scrog net as soon as
the net is filled
flip them into flower put up another net
i'm sure you know what to do from there
all right i want to thank you for the
great message i feel like we have
covered enough ground on this episode i
want to thank you guys again for
listening to episode 570 of the grow
from your heart podcast
thank you for the great emails and
questions again if you've got questions
my email address is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com i would love to hear from
you
the quickest way to get your emails to
the top of the list is to join the
patreon campaign
that's right at the 10 level that will
move your question right up to the top
of the list i'll read your question
on the next episode i record keep in
mind that i am recorded ahead
i'm probably two or three episodes ahead
right now so if he sent me an episode
today it wouldn't come out for probably
four
uh three or four episodes we can do math
right i can
can you i know what i'm saying are you
listening either way
i'll get your messages on the show
through the patreon and once again
thanks for all the patreon support
if you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
and you would like to make a financial
contribution to the show
all you have to do is join me on patreon
it's www.patreon.com forward slash grow
from your heart
all of the information you need is on
the screen of course i did include a
link
in the show notes and the video
description to make it nice and easy for
you
just click on there it'll take you right
where you need to be also don't forget
to visit our sponsors at
seedshearnow.com
use coupon code gfyh10 while you're
checking out that'll save you
10 off your order like i keep saying if
you're getting one pack
that will cover the cost of shipping if
you're getting multiple packages
that will give you the opportunity for
more seeds what's better than seeds
more seeds all right get you some seeds
upgrade your garden also don't forget
about that under 30 tab
click on the under 30 section you can
find yourself a pack of the cream
for 30 and maybe 25 right now at
seedshearnow.com
i said it before if you've got any
questions comments corrections or
concerns
i would love to hear from you the email
address is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com that is all i've got for
you ladies and gentlemen boys and girls
i'll be back in just a couple of days
with fresh new content
i want to give a giant shout out to tom
hill and until next time
take a fat dab and give your mom a hug
for me