[Music]
welcome back podcast world i'm your host
my friends call me rasta jeff and it is
time for episode 571 of the grow from
your heart podcast this episode of the
show is brought to you by our friends at
seedshearnow.com seedshearnow.com offers
seeds from all of the industry's leading
breeders
including miss jill genetics duke
diamond and of course irie genetics
everything at seeds herenow.com is
backed by their award-winning
satisfaction guarantee
and for my friends on a tight budget
seeds herenow.com offers several packs
for under 30
as well as amazing monthly sales
make sure to use coupon code gfyh10
while checking
out to save a few bucks again that is
coupon code gfyh10
while checking out at seeds here now.com
if you're watching on the youtube
channel i'm sure you can see by now that
i'm joined by white mike
welcome to the show mike thanks man
what's up everybody
hope everybody's doing well i hope
you're doing well mike uh we brought
mike on to do what i'm going to call the
legalization presentation but this is
the part of the show where we usually
talk about what we're smoking
so i'm going to be polite and i'm going
to ask you mike what are you smoking on
today bro
i've been enjoying some flour from one
of our local dispensaries
excellent flour from a local dispensary
i love your perfectly vague
descriptions that's that's what i'm
going for
and it's it's solid herb solid herb
there we go there's some details
i heard uh one of the the newer outfits
in town had some good flowers so
i went and checked it out rumors seemed
to be true and
i've been enjoying it will you go back
yeah definitely excellent the gummies i
like they have a for a few bucks cheaper
a bottle than everybody else and their
flower is good so
they'll get some of my money for a while
[ __ ] having flour on the shelf right now
is a selling point a lot of the
dispensaries are picked pretty clean
yeah yeah a lot of shelves are pretty
empty lately and
what's there's been kind of
disappointing so
um having somebody that had several nice
looking selections was
a pleasure to find excellent i never
thought i would see empty shelves at
this time of year and i haven't seen
something like that
in a long time it's scary going into the
dispensary right now with minimal
selections
what are you enjoying right now buddy
good question bro i am dabbing on garlic
banger number nine live batter from
green dot labs i'm sure you guys know
green dot is one of my favorites for
concentrate companies
and of course anything with the word
garlic in it is one of my favorites
uh the garlic banger is a blend of head
banger and hsb
of hsb is han solo burger the package
describes the flavor as garlic
sour and gas on the back of the package
it says 69.12
thc and non-detectable cbd i love the
garlic banger dude this is one of my
uh probably top five concentrates and
since i've been dabbing it
i can't think of anything else so i
don't know what the other top four
are uh so yeah that's perfect
concentrate big shout out to our friends
at green dot labs
for the mind erasing and delicious
tasting that's a beautiful [ __ ]
description right there
uh the garlic banger number nine there
are two different numbers there's number
six and number nine
i can't decide which one i like better
but that's what i'm smoking on
all right mike let me get myself back on
track i'm going to give you a bunch of
time and a bunch of space to do your
legalization presentation but
i do owe some friends some shout outs
from patreon so let's do some shout outs
to the members of the 710 club of course
the 710 club
are the folks who support the show on
patreon at the ten 7.10 a month level or
higher
so with no further ado let's start off
with the big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to my friend
brazilian vibrations
i want to send a big thank you shout out
to wyatt criplin i want to say thank you
to grant m
i want to send a big thank you shout out
to davey jones i want to send a thank
you shout out to smokey j
let's send a big fist bumping a thank
you shout out to big huff i've always
got a big thank you shout out for joey
mead
i want to send a special thank you shout
out to yi [ __ ] ha
and last but certainly not least let's
send a big girl from your heart podcast
thank you shout out to my friend
lemur priest big thanks and big shout
out to everybody who supports the show
if you're not already supporting the
show on patreon and you would like to
learn how to do so
all you have to do is visit
dot www.patreon.com forward slash grow
from your heart all of the information
you need is right there on the screen
and i did include a link in the show
notes and the video description
to make it easy for all of my stoned or
working friends i'm not sure what you're
doing right now but there's a link
also let me encourage you to support
white mike on patreon
why mike is here to contribute to the
show white mike is a major contributor
to the community
so i encourage you to join white mike on
patreon it's patreon.com
forward slash white mike super easy to
find support my buddy
i'm supporting white mike on patreon you
should too all the cool kids are doing
it
thanks bro oh man thank you for the
support uh you contribute to the show
heavily you have contributed behind the
scenes heavily to
my cannabis career without white mike's
involvement without
some of the foundation and bricks that
you laid my towers wouldn't be standing
so i do appreciate it bro
uh that is definitely i notice it and it
doesn't go unnoticed when i start
thinking about
the past and the future you're always
involved so thank you bro
it's been like a decade now we've been
building it we have been playing
together for quite a while and it has
been a good time
it has been a good time been some scary
moments some rocky roads but we always
seem to do pretty well together
moving into the old place i found some
relics from way
back in the origin days and they all
make me smile
did you see the smile which is when you
said relics i got excited
finding finding spots for them in the
new house is a lot of fun
cool old business cards and old pictures
and things exactly that it was one of
your ivory cards from the metamark days
oh man it was it was a caregiver card
with your number across the back and i
smiled i was like i wonder if this is
the first one
that that might have been dude awesome
yep
wow metamar days if you know you know
all right ladies and gentlemen i have
been teasing that we're going to let
mike have a bunch of space in this
episode i know i bring mike on
uh and i talk over him a lot i'm trying
to steer the show today i'm going to
steer the show very minimally
if i catch mike out in left field i will
bring him back onto the train tracks
if i catch him too far off the
microphone i will glue his face back to
the microphone for you
i'm trying to stay up on people we hear
you yes we really are i'm trying not to
sneeze into my microphone right now so
excuse me if it does happen
a lot of listeners have been asking for
guidance
on how to get into legalization how to
start joining city council meetings
basically where do i start to get to
where you guys are now
mike and i understand and appreciate and
are grateful for the fact that we're in
a location
where we can drive to a store that's
four minutes away and pay cash money
for the top quality concentrates and not
have to worry about police taking it
from us getting arrested
anything it's we've got a lot of freedom
here we enjoy it so
mike has been given the opportunity to
put together what i'm calling the
legalization presentation just because i
like silly [ __ ] like that
but i gave him some time to put
something together and i'm giving him
the format
i'm gonna try to stay out of the way and
not over talk you but i'm just gonna
shut up now and say
mike uh the mic is yours brother good
luck and have fun man it's time for the
white mike's legalization presentation
have at it brother
thanks bro um listeners before we dive
into this
it's kind of hard to know how far
to go into some of these topics
um i've been studying legalization or
the idea of it
in one way or another for like 20 years
so there's
a lot of different talking points and
arguments just sort of rattling around
in my head
i've tried to hone it down to
sort of the key starter package for
what is anybody who's interested need to
know
to be effective arguing for legalization
in their area
i hope i've done a good job in narrowing
it down
if you want more information or would
have appreciated less information you
can hit me up on social media
um it's at nemopunk15 on twitter or you
can find me on facebook at pueblo for
sensible cannabis laws
or you can get a hold of me by emailing
the show
links provided in the show notes perfect
thank you mike so
legalization um
if you're getting into this argument
right now you're lucky
uh you've got a lot of good data to pull
from
you've got a lot of other people's work
to build on
and study and sort of repurpose for your
own arguments
despite like 80 years of propaganda in
[ __ ] and drug war nonsense that's
been built on top of cannabis
um we've got a lot of positives working
in our favor
and our favor during for this argument
um
prohibition as a concept is just crap
um going back the first prohibition this
is one of my favorite arguments i steal
it from a guy named neil frank
franklin who's the founder of a group
called law enforcement
against prohibition so a group of
ex-cops and judges that
just saw prohibition in action and can't
tolerate it anymore so they formed a
group to fight it
um and his uh his little comment was the
very first prohibition is
um god telling adam and eve don't eat
that apple
and god was the cop he only had to watch
two people
and that apple got eight quick
that's just how it goes um there's a
little human nature in that story too
not only does prohibition not a very
good policy and it's hard to enforce
but it's sort of human nature to go oh
don't touch that
you know it's just you tell us not to
and the first thing our brain does is
i wonder why oh i'm gonna try it and
find out why
um and so when little old me when they
instituted dare when i was in fifth or
sixth grade or whenever they gave it to
us
the first thing everyone in my class
thought was
well they're probably telling us about
this because it's fun we should go find
it and try
yeah that's exactly what i thought and
i thought it was weird then and when i
was in college in
saw some studies where they looked at if
dare worked
and they found that the dare that we
went through was zero to negative two
percent effective
so for every hundred kids that went
through the dare i went through
two of them that wouldn't have gone out
to look for drugs were like
we should probably go try some drugs so
um if you're looking to get in
and start arguing against cannabis
prohibition in your area
know that you're not alone and that
it's not a craziest argument as it might
originally seem
especially if you come from a lot of the
the propaganda
that we grew up in and then i know
for a fact is still pretty prevalent
around the country even in the us right
now where it seems like legalization is
right around the corner
but it seemed like that since 1970
and we're still not there
so first prohibition is a terrible
policy on its own right
second cops were never meant to protect
you from you they were protect to
protect you from me
like if i go beat up jeff the cops can
arrest me for beating up jeff
but if i beat up me and i tell the cops
i kick my own ass they're just going to
look at me and go
what do you want us to do about it and
it's the same thing with
drug laws the trying to
catch somebody who doesn't want to be
caught and doesn't want to report
the other people involved it's just a
really hard crime to solve
because nobody leaves a typical pot deal
upset somebody wanted to buy some
marijuana somebody wanted to sell some
marijuana
those two connected and both left happy
or at least not disgruntled
unfortunately it doesn't always work
that way because prohibition isn't
doesn't create a awesomely safe
marketplace
but in theory both parties are there for
their own ends and
those ends get met quickly and everybody
goes home happy
um it's not like an assault where
there's somebody that got their ass
kicked that's salty about it right
no victim no crime is what you're saying
very much so
and immoralists or prohibitionists
love to paint you know it's a moral
failing or some sort other nonsense on
the why
smoking a joint in the privacy of your
own home should be really really
terrible and
a crime that needs to be prevented
punished
and when you start breaking down
especially now where
i mean colorado's been legal for
eight years now the law passed in 2012.
um all of 2013 was a planning year
stores have been open since 2014 that's
six years we've had dispensary
retail dispensaries we've had medical
dispensaries since 08
cali's had medical dispensaries since
that's 20 years now and society hasn't
tipped over it
it hasn't gone insane
try as they might you can't pin
a lot of mayhem on legal cannabis that's
why
canada followed colorado and in
washington state in legalization
so is uruguay so is mexico now i believe
we're clearly headed towards a world
where
cannabis is legal and
at this point there's a lot of good data
that you can draw on to make your
arguments
much more impactful than mine were when
i started
because when i started a lot of this was
theoretical
and so when you were trying to explain
to people that if there's a legal market
the black market kind of goes away
they look at you funny and now you can
show them that that's where seven
billion dollars worth of cannabis sales
comes from and
the legal market around the us right now
those aren't new customers
their existing customers spending
dollars they would have spent anyway
they're just choosing to shop in a
regulated market now seven
billion it's that's an old number even
it's probably nine or 11
now and that's just the legal market wow
um good estimates on the
like it's it's easier to know like the
size of the cosmetics market or the
dental market in the us
because the sales figures are easier to
track
than it is with the illegal business is
but yeah
um the dea has been putting out
estimates every year
for i mean since the 70s estimating the
size of
of different drug markets in the u.s and
they
put the u.s cannabis market somewhere
north of 35 billion
um and that's a really old number my
guess is it's closer to
50 to 60. wow and those are those are
prohibition dollars and so there's a
huge
markup because it's an illegal product
but if you figured about a third of that
so 25 30 billion dollars
is what the the u.s market is
potentially for legal cannabis
and right now the legal market's about
11 billion strong i think
10 or 11. it's a lot of money so there's
a lot of black market money still on the
table for the legal market to scoop up
but when i was first making this
argument
it was hard to get all that information
in front of people the internet didn't
exist like it does today even
um you didn't have people like me
coaching you on podcasts
the data wasn't there yet even in
libraries you had trouble finding books
about it so
um i mean the landscape is vastly
different now
and that all plays to our benefit um
even if you're you're arguing to someone
who is staunchly
anti-legalization they've been exposed
to a lot of these arguments and talking
points
and know that you're not just a crazy
hippie shouting nonsense
um because that's kind of what it felt
like when when i
started um there was a real sense that
you had to overcome the chi chin chong
kind of veil that automatically got
thrown over you as soon as you said
i'm here to talk about cannabis they'd
go hippie
yeah you just immediately uh you had to
overcome
tons of [ __ ] um because you were the
cannabis guy
and it that's not so true anymore it's
still true it's just not
nearly as true as it used to be and
you've got a lot more firepower and it's
way easier to back it up now
for example
um one of the things you're going to
want to do if you're
you're going to start arguing for
legalization in your area
my biggest tip for you is to just learn
and read and watch as much as you can on
cannabis
cannabis prohibition if you just type in
cannabis documentaries into youtube
you're going to find dozens of good ones
same thing with netflix
grab a pen hit pause real quick go grab
a pen
some examples that you're definitely
going to want to familiarize
yourself with if you haven't already
the union uh subtitled the business
behind getting high
you can find that on youtube for sure
same thing with a documentary called the
culture high
um i'm pretty sure waiting to inhale is
still available on youtube if it's not i
know you can find it
searching on the internet for a minute
um
if you're more of a reader check out a
book called my medicine by a guy named
urban rosenfeld
fantastic book gives you an insider's
view
of the very earliest days of medical
marijuana in the u.s
and it's a story almost nobody knows
about
and when you tell people they think
you're [ __ ] with them like the
federal government's run a medical
marijuana program since 1982
where they mail people um tins
with i think it's 11 ounces per 10
in pre-rolled joints like even saying it
right now it sounds like i'm making [ __ ]
up
but it's real you can go on youtube you
can see the tin you can see the joints
you can hear the testimonials from these
people
um there's a lot a lot of history to
draw from now that just wasn't
accessible when i started
um so absorb read and learn
everything you can and get used to
thinking
the arguments that you're hearing people
make in terms of
where you would like to see the law
change so if you're watching a
documentary say the union
a lot of it's said in british columbia
uh i think that one's from 2004
2007 and so at the time
one of the the hot spots for cannabis
production was british columbia
and one of the desirable selling points
for flour in the country was this is
from british columbia
and so the whole documentary sort of
details what the black market's like
in that point in time and
as they're talking take the numbers
they're saying and apply them to your
town or your city or your state
and when you start conveying this
information to other people in your area
and pointing to different data sets that
are publicly available
those arguments are extremely impactful
when you can say
you know our town has 160 000 people in
it
if we were to legalize marijuana
the numbers say that we would be making
around you know a million a year
between sales tax and licensing fees
and if we allowed production as well
we'd be looking at another million or so
in excise tax and all of a sudden your
city councilman
who didn't really want to listen to the
stoner guy again today
is thinking well that's two and a half
million dollars that i could put towards
this pet project or that pet project
um and all of a sudden
you've got them hooked into your
argument a little bit better
while you're reading and learning and
watching everything you can on cannabis
and prohibition also check out
local meetings in your area i always
recommend
start local if you've never argued in
front of a governing body before don't
start at a state legislature
it's very intimidating start at a town
meeting or a city council
these meetings are open to the public
and because there's a playground
in the whole world's upside down because
of covid
all of these are open on the web now and
they're very easily accessible
two minutes on google and you're able to
find
when your city council or town committee
or whatever they're called meet
what time of day the meetings are how to
view them remotely
and watch a lot of that like as much as
you can stomach
and i it's most boring [ __ ] you'll ever
see
um it's sort of my super power is being
able to sit through these meetings and
not die
um that's a great skill set that i bring
to the cannabis community
but uh if you want to go down to city
council
and say city council we should break
with a hundred years now of tradition
and legalize cannabis
here's why and you want that that
message to be well received
and appreciated your best bet
is to watch a lot of city council
meetings or if you want to do a state
assembly a state assembly meeting
and get used to how those are meetings
are run
what the flow is what all the procedures
are
who all the players are who does what
who says what
what order things happen in um
i've seen a lot of people go and
look very foolish because they go with
zero
preparation and a hundred percent
passion
and it's the taking the time and sitting
through
meaning after meaning about zoning code
and fire code and watching the little
old lady speak about people speeding on
our street
or the loud music at night or
watching the the big city presentation
where a whole block of people have come
down to
to rally because too many garbage trucks
go down their alley every week
you really get a feel for how your city
runs
who the important players are who the
decision makers are
and the more you watch the more you
learn what those people care about
so you can really tailor your arguments
and make them effective
um say somebody's really passionate
about the police
and they want the police to reinvest
more time into
more important type crimes you can point
out that in colorado a state with 5.7
something million people we have 6 000
fewer marijuana arrests per year now
and that's those six thousand hey i
caught mike and jeff smoking a joint
behind the arby's
and i had to you know handcuff him pat
him down put him in the back of the
squad car
take them to the jail process them it's
just a minor offense we do some
paperwork we take some pictures
there they go home seven hours later
takes about three hours of the officer's
time
we don't do that six thousand times a
year now
and that those man hours add up
like if you do the math the normal 40
hour work week is 2080 hours a year
and that's if you work five days a week
40 hours a week
or not five days a week but 40 hours a
week and 52 weeks a year it's 2080.
six thousand arrests at two or three
hours per arrest
it's 12 to 18 000 man hours we just
freed up
and how many rapes can you solve in that
time how many murders can you solve in
that time
um if you're
you somebody is on the other side of
that particular coin and is fired up
about
police abuse of power 90
of the videos where the cop pulls
somebody over and decides to [ __ ] with
that somebody
it starts with jeff i smell marijuana in
your car would you please step out
it's it's always i smell weed they never
smell meth
they never smell heroin they they rarely
smell alcohol
it's always i smell weed and if
i smell weed is no longer a reason to
[ __ ] with people
it just takes that off the menu
if somebody's got a passion project
where they want to fund something
the data is there now where you can look
up and say
there's this many people in our city if
we use the numbers
in colorado and there's no reason to say
they don't
shouldn't apply to say new york or
wyoming or
or australia that our
area could likely see this much money
coming in every year
and we can put that towards whatever we
want and all of a sudden you've got a
bunch of people who started off
not wanting to even listen to you now
they're thinking about
you know we're already buying and
selling the pod like everybody who wants
it gets it here
prohibition is such a terrible policy
that it's
literally created a marketplace where
every high school has a distribution
center
yeah like you couldn't dream up a worse
distribution system than the one
prohibition created
if you were trying to keep drugs out of
the hands of people who shouldn't be on
drugs
i agree it's just prohibition's bad on
in
every way and
the more you learn about the history of
cannabis prohibition
the medical effects of cannabis the
health effects of cannabis
um what's happened in states since
they've legalized or since they've
allowed medical
and how much it costs to try to enforce
all this and prohibit it
it gets really easy to to start
okay i listened to this meeting for 10
hours i figured out what this guy and
this guy really care about
i know how to sway their votes my way
now i just have to tailor the argument
like so
and so it's just it's really just about
doing your prep work and
and knowing who your target audience is
and then getting comfortable
and if you watch the proceedings enough
you'll get comfortable enough to know
when
and how to do your five-minute spiel on
why
your area should legalize pot
it's really just about the prep work and
you're lucky the documentaries now are
good
they didn't even exist when me and jeff
were starting yeah you guys are spoiled
now
and you're welcome we have some fun
notes we got here
just to give you all some fun numbers to
think about
um in 2019 the state of colorado like i
said
5.7 million people we collected
302 million 458
426 cannabis taxes
in 2019 and every report i've read this
year says
our sales numbers are way higher during
covid
so we're gonna crush that number next
year this year
302 million dollars yep
um new york for example has got 8.3
million people
almost 8.4 they're looking at
a projected revenue of 436 million a
year
if they get on the legalization train
they
haven't yet they're they continually
fumble the ball trying to craft the
perfect legalization model
rather than letting uh what's the phrase
they're letting the
perfect get in the way of the good so
rather than making any progress they
keep talking about how next year they're
going to make the perfect leap forward
um we did the cop hours that we could
save
different ways you can argue for
legalization in your area
if you don't want to go sacrifice
yourself on the alternate city council
like i did
writing op-eds to your local paper or a
larger paper
is super super easy to do
some things you should know that will
make you more confident
every newspaper has an op-ed section
and they're desperate for free content
so the odds your letter gets published
are pretty good if you follow a few
really simple rules
if you click on their submission
criteria which will be easy to find on
their papers website
you can go to the denver post click the
opinion section
and if you scroll to the bottom there
will be a tab that says
submit an op-ed and it'll tell you
here's your word limit
don't cuss don't make it personal
and if you do that there's like an 85
percent chance they'll publish your
letter doesn't matter what it's
about you could be bitching about the
ducks at the city park
or the people driving fast down your
street
or different marijuana laws in your area
and another important piece of
information
most newspapers have no way to double
check
who your name is on the bottom of the
letter and so i can write a letter and
say my name's jeff
and they'll publish it saying jeff wrote
it and then jeff will call me and be
like what the [ __ ] dude
if you're gonna submit a letter under my
name tell me yeah
but you don't have to use your name
there's famous examples of people in our
history who wrote
wonderful impactful op-eds to the paper
under pseudonyms like benjamin franklin
famously did it
um but op-eds are really
kind of oddly powerful um it's 2020 and
we're we all decided to be dumb
and so most people can't tell the
difference between
a fact investigated report and an
opinion letter
and so your opinion letter to the editor
is already going to have more
impact than it probably should because
it's an opinion
but nobody can tell that anymore
um and the other thing with the writing
op-eds is they get picked up they get
they get if uh they get a lot of clicks
on the local paper they'll get picked up
by the national outlet
and other people will discuss it and all
of a sudden
elected officials are being asked did
you see the op-ed in sunday's paper that
you know from
from ross to jeff that said we should
legalize weed
what do you think about that mayor and
all of a sudden
it's a major news story that's that's
generating more than just
people saw it and got to read your
arguments
my other big tip is stay informed as
much as possible
on what's going on in your local area
in your state and nationally
especially if you're regularly arguing
for legalization
and that's really what it takes
the places that haven't moved in the us
anyway
on legalization are almost exclusively
places now
where someone in elected office
has to submit a bill to change the law
the general public can't put a petition
together and get it on the ballot
themselves
so you've got to convince somebody that
holds elective office
to submit the change for you and you do
that by pestering the [ __ ] out of them
and every day every week every month
however often you can send that person
an email
call their office hey it's me again
just wanted to remind you if marijuana
were legal we'd have an extra this much
in the state budget this month
have a nice wednesday um
hey i saw you wanted you know more money
for snow removal in
in district one next year but you can't
find in the budget
i know how you could just contact me
next month
just keep sending emails keep calling
keep pestering those people
and if you make your arguments short
concise
and tuned to their cares and their wants
and needs
you're going to have an impact and it's
not going to take as long as you think
you will
we're so lucky now we've overcome so
much of the [ __ ] that we
and baggage that we've been carrying in
this movement for so long
the internet finally freed up enough
information i think
i agree the show's like this dude shows
like this
um i think that's about what i've got
straightened
or lined out so far what uh any
questions for me jeff
you know the only note i wrote down and
this is kind of it's related
do you have any favorite activists that
we should follow or listen to or people
that can give us some guidance
um definitely follow marijuana moment
you can subscribe to a newsletter you
can check in with the website you can
follow the
those guys on twitter
fantastic cannabis reporting um
russ belleville if you're really into
data russ is one of the best
data miners i've ever seen um
it's like a dog with a bone radical rust
will
dig into some talking point like a
[ __ ] honey badger
and then post all the data for free to
his website awesome
um and so if if there's a marijuana
talking point that
you really want to deep dive data on but
don't really
feel like doing all that legwork
yourself you can check in with radical
russ and see if he's already done it for
you and wants to point you in the right
direction
um definitely check those documentaries
that i listed before
i'm checking with your local normal
office
check out law enforcement against
prohibition or leap
they do some interesting stuff around
the country every year
lots of good advocacy work about uh
all sorts of stuff not just prohibition
being horrible policy but
lots of law enforcement reform stuff
type too
if you follow me on twitter you'll see
me retweeting a lot of their stuff or a
lot of their members stuff
mike tweets a lot of great cannabis
content so just follow mike on twitter
for sure
that will give you a good heads up on
things to follow
yeah my twitter is pretty good for state
and foreign cannabis stuff i stay up on
that
yes uh at nemo punk 15 on the twitter
give the give the guy a follow
uh mike i see you scrolling through your
notes there have we covered everything
is it time to start wrapping up the
uh this is going to be all the talking
parts i want this can definitely be part
one
um i've got some little notes down like
let's say mere jeff me and jeff are in a
city called pueblo colorado
our population is about 160 000.
um our little city that has
eight dispensaries and this wasn't this
number is from when we only had seven up
and running in 2018.
we see better than a million in taxes
and fees
and that's not production or excise tax
yet
that's just seven stores
doing their daily business paying sales
tax on it
and and paying their licensing fees to
operate it's an insane number
it's a million bucks that goes into the
economy
yeah that's a new fire station right
that's close to you could at least build
this structure you build a damn fire
station
you're welcome it's uh
i don't know i don't know what to find
it's one of those things when you get
into when you get into city and state
budgets
the numbers get really big quick and and
like colorado's pulling in
300 300 million plus in marijuana taxes
every year and it's
one percent of our state budget um
and those two numbers in your head are
kind of hard to hold at the same time at
least if you're me
um because 300 million dollars like if i
had that personally like
my life would be kush for forever even
if i did dumb [ __ ] ex
expensive dumb [ __ ] every day 300
million is enough to get me through all
the days i'd be competitively
trying to spend through that money but
it uh
at the state level it doesn't go that
far when you figure out how much a
highway costs to build or a school
system costs to maintain
um it's the law large numbers when
there's this many of us
um [ __ ] just costs a lot
and so when you're making especially the
economic argument
keep in mind that it's not going to be a
golden parachute
kind of magic bullet but that money can
do so much good like here locally
a huge chunk of the money we collect
goes towards scholarships
where any kid can get um
it's a couple of thousand i think it's
four thousand now any kid
local kid that graduates high school in
pueblo can apply for a scholarship and
get like four grand
as long as they go to one of the local
colleges and we're opening it up so that
it can be any college in the u.s
i wish they would have done that
originally more kids wouldn't have been
able to benefit
but uh it took a minute for the program
to really get up and running and really
get funded
but now they're giving away almost i
think 700
000 a year in scholarships and that's
for a community like pueblo that's
huge yeah um we had a couple of middle
schools down here
where they didn't have sidewalks and so
it was just
like a road where the cars drive and
then
field and there's houses and it's kind
of in the middle of a
semi-suburban area but they hadn't
gotten around to having the money to
pave the sidewalks yet and so
in a very real way kids were walking in
the street with bus and car traffic to
get to school every day
the kids that walked and rode their bike
had to do so on the same road as the
buses and [ __ ]
super unsafe but it was all we could
afford
until we legalized pot and we had some
extra revenue laying around that wasn't
already
earmarked for some desperate need and
now those schools have nice safe
sidewalks that's awesome
a couple of parks got refurbished and it
doesn't it's like ooh
a park but like for the people who use
that that's huge
yeah like i've got a two and a
five-year-old the little park up the
street that i drove by and never
considered for 35 years
that [ __ ] is vital now
vital like sunshine and water vital yeah
oh yeah
and marijuana taxes can pay to keep that
up and keep the equipment decent
it's uh the way that you can use that
money is really big because it's
it's brand new money it's not money
that's already allocated you don't have
to take it from jeff to give it to mike
it's brand new money coming into the
flow that you can allocate anywhere you
want
and then there's a bunch of ancillary
money like not only is there sales tax
but
you and i have a job like how many
people work in the cannabis industry in
our town
all of those people are now employed
they now buy dinner they now buy
groceries they now
buy from the dispensary they're able to
do [ __ ] 1300 1400 people in pueblo like
it's a
shitload of jobs yeah um
it's a massive amount of investment
uh when uh when an area goes legal
um in pueblo here i think it was 50 some
million in investment that first year
than 2013.
52 million i think was the number in
just one year
in economic investment down here so what
that meant for
the electricians and the hvac techs and
the
the drywall crews and the roof and crews
all those guys um i mean
2012 wasn't exactly an economic boom
time either was 2013.
and so this money flowing into colorado
honestly saved a lot of small
contracting businesses it turned our
town around it made trinidad colorado a
different town
that place used to be dusty and barely
existing and no disrespect
it was falling apart it was old and
dying there's a ton of replication
exactly that um you can just
google what mary legalpot did to
trinidad colorado
yeah there's uh at least one
really good interview with their sheriff
where he states i didn't like the idea
i was kind of against it but my hand was
forced
and it's revitalized the town
um places that went from like an annual
budget of a couple of thousand
have a budget of a couple of million now
what's before a little pocket above
colorado springs the one with only two
shops
uh two stores in it manitou springs yeah
um is this little gem in colorado where
it was like locals it was the the cool
spot to take your date when you were 25
in colorado
a little hippy spot a little mountain
hippie town
wonderful food great scene great place
to hang out in the spring and fall
but super duper poor falling apart
crumbling
hadn't seen reinvestment or or a tax win
fall in 30 years 50 years some [ __ ]
there's there are two marijuana stores
that they allow
and the taxes they bring in have paved
like most of the streets
it's it's really really cool to see and
the crazy thing is is this is all
business that's already happening
it's it's not business that we have to
invent it's it's just removing it from a
black
untaxed and unregulated market into a
legal one
and man you can do so much good with
that money
this town is better this town wasn't a
super shitty town it was kind of on the
verge of like is it going to make it or
is it going to fall apart
and when cannabis came people like i
said all those 13 1400 people they got
jobs but not only did they get jobs but
there are owners and investors that show
up in their bmws and porsches
they come here and they want to eat here
and they don't want to eat at all the
old and no offense the old restaurants
they were here i'm not going to list
them i was going to bash some of them
but they don't want to eat at those
places
they want the fancy [ __ ] so now the
riverwalk area's got all kinds of new
fancy restaurants
now the north end of town where we go
shopping has all kinds of new cool
places because the owners
and their wives and their kids all want
to go shopping and do fancy [ __ ]
some of the owners are ladies too i just
made it that all the owners are men i
apologize for that a lot of them are
ladies
but they want to go shopping they want
to get their food so we're getting more
stuff here because of cannabis
things used to close at like eight
o'clock now you get till 10 here i know
that's not extravagant but you get until
10 to get food now
this is one of the things that [ __ ]
with me so much when i moved here
everything closed at 7 30.
yeah but uh little by little and ice
legal cannabis has so much to do with
this and it's
it's not like it was a magic bullet his
pueblo was on a slow decline and had
been for 30 or 40 years
since the steel mill went from employing
50 000 to 1.5 000
um since then the town's been on a slow
decline
and legal cannabis we're on a slow
incline now
we're slowly working back up every
couple of months
[ __ ] gets a tiny bit better um
look every six months you'll notice oh
there's a new restaurant oh there's a
new
you know florist oh there's a new
dentist office yeah
just little by little by little the
whole city's coming back and it's
legal cannabis is the lifeblood doing it
man this is local
local talk here so uh the locals will
love this i live in pueblo mike and i
are in pueblo colorado springs is the
town
uh well it was an hour north of us now
since
cannabis is happening it's creeping
south 45 minutes north of us yeah pueblo
is moving north and colorado springs is
moving south we're going to devour the
town in the middle called fountain we're
just going to eat it up and spit it out
pretty soon
fountain yeah i'll be like uh where are
you i'm at the north end of puebla we'll
cross
drive 20 feet and be in colorado springs
because cannabis is bringing
it's got the economy going yeah there's
a whole new music scene here well in a
refurbished
music scene here we got a really cool
club that wouldn't be here without the
cannabis scene so yeah
i think it's brought us a lot of great
[ __ ] economic incline
uh jobs the people that have jobs in the
cannabis industry would be doing
that a lot of us would just be doing
crime
it's that it's huge demographic yeah
yeah we went from the black market to
doing it on a
on a time clock paying taxes doing it
under cameras
it's it's there's no good count on how
many people
the the black market for cannabis
employs
but if you take the numbers i was given
earlier the 35 to 50 billion dollar
range that's
the the same size as the cosmetics
market in the u.s
so if you think about all the lipstick
and the eyeliner
and the the rouge and the lip gloss and
the [ __ ]
shampoo and lotion and all that and you
take all the people it takes to make
all those products and to market those
products and distribute them
and put them on store shelves and to
check you out at the register and
there's
all that same amount of people but
they're illegal pot growers and dealers
and traffickers and
movers and smoke-outs and yep
if you uh want a more entertainment
version of um like why prohibition is a
bad idea i just thought it's the 10th
anniversary of boardwalk empire
um [ __ ] fantastic hbo
show on uh alcohol prohibition we can
always count on mike to wrap it back
around to an hbo movie
or a series um there's also uh an oldie
but a goodie check out weeds
um it's just show away before it's time
from showtime
weeds gave me a panic attack dude uh i
know i said i was gonna let you have a
lot of
yeah i said i was gonna give you a lot
of space in this show but i'm gonna butt
in with this weed stock
i grew up in my adolescent time my
teenage years i was doing her job
i was doing her hustle i was buying
cheap and selling high buying in bulk
and selling and smalling making money
i watched uh nancy botwin make
so many [ __ ] day one stupid mistakes
that i would
i would be yelling at my [ __ ] tv
you're [ __ ] and i dude i would be
panicking like the cops are coming nancy
like dude that show that lady made me so
[ __ ] nervous dude
it just it's my favorite example when
people
try to attack legalization in colorado
because one of the
the negative numbers that's gone up a
little is the grow busts
um over the last couple of years since
the legalization the cops are busting
a larger number it grows but uh
possession and consumption arrests are
down by six thousand
and so it's it went up by like 150 but
it went down by 6 000.
um but uh they talk about
growing pot in the house in a trap house
like it's a new concept
it was so common it was a [ __ ] hit tv
show back in 2006. we got a clip
from the busts that i have seen uh
what is it televised or talked about on
the news broadcasted shared whatever
there's a word for it that i'm missing
it'll come to me uh from what i've seen
most of those are from people who came
from other places
because they thought let's go to
colorado weeds illegal they didn't even
bother to
they didn't read the rule book they
showed up and they hung up lights and
[ __ ] planted a bunch of seeds or
bought a bunch of clones and got
going didn't realize legal doesn't
the black market operates the that's how
they produce their product is they
they try to grow it somewhere where they
don't think anyone will know or care
and i guess in florida because a lot of
growers when they first started busting
illegal house girls were from florida i
wasn't going to say but i let you do it
they published down in the papers in the
news
published colorado legalized uh cannabis
but they didn't smart
in my word had six months of meetings
where everybody in town learned what the
rules were gonna be first
so they thought they could get away with
just renting the place and filling it
with plants
everybody that saw it was like wait a
second i don't remember no
city meeting or no notice saying they
were going to put a marijuana business
there i that that that's shady
just stand out like a sore thumb they
did not blend in at all
just an update a fire department cost
400 per square foot
[Laughter]
i'm glad you checked i had to check i
was curious um
i thought the mill was pretty low for
fire department i think those fire
trucks cost like half a mile piece yeah
houses are
houses are a mill so like yeah yeah like
not not this one but i mean like you
know
there are a million dollar houses a few
blocks from here so right that's way
more
fire departments got technology in there
we're way off track mike i said i was
going to keep us out of the [ __ ]
woods today out of the corn maze
uh dude i'm proud of you did a good job
on your legalization presentation i'm
sure people are going to have a lot of
questions
uh for those people fire off all the
questions you want folks yes
grow from your heart at hotmail.com is
the best way to send me an email
contact mike through the twitter leave
comments on youtube michael go check the
youtube comments he's got access to that
so
uh yeah leave us some feedback we would
love it i kind of just interrupted you
and cut you off while pulling us out of
the weeds
do you have any more uh some of those
mike's final moments or any [ __ ] you
want to add to this before i start
wrapping up the show
no just be kind to each other folks um
study study study if you want to be a
cannabis advocate it's
uh it's nice now that we've gotten rid
of
a lot of the baggage that came with it
um
if you take your time and do your
homework you you won't have
too much of a an uphill battle becoming
a candidate
cannabis advocate um know that once you
do it that's sort of your cross for life
though
yeah you can't be a preschool teacher it
will always be googleable
um you can google my full name and the
city that i'm in
and it will come up with reports of me
and city council you'll be able to see
my picture on the front of the newspaper
um one of the very first times i went
and spoke at a public meeting
they had me on the very front page of
the chieftain the next [ __ ] morning
oh man how nerve-wracking
yeah it was just a reminder that the the
squeaky wheel gets greased
so i love waking up to text messages and
calls like hey bro you're in the paper
today like
what the [ __ ] did i do and it's just a
picture of me looking blazed as [ __ ] at
city council
hey i'm here bro yeah they took a
picture of me
a lady resigned at city council she's
like i'd like to announce today that
this is my last meeting i am resigning
i'm stepping down from my position
and a lot of people uh i didn't i wasn't
too involved in city council but i knew
at the time that people
hated her i was like i've seen posters
about basically [ __ ] this lady
and she just quit and so i made this
face of like oh [ __ ] she just quit
and they took a picture of me right as i
was like oh damn that [ __ ] just quit in
front of everybody
and they just posted that picture on the
[ __ ] newspaper and i was like oh
that's a dumbass picture of me
it's that whole incident
taught me a lot about local politics
one of our local trash companies and
it's not like they're a special business
so they had magic resources or a lot of
people or employees
to pull up on it was just two or three
people that got really pissed about
something
and spent enough time on facebook and
talking to people in their life
to to get 25 or 30 people to show up on
on monday night
like every other monday night for like
seven or eight times and so it took a
couple of months
it took a lot of people showing up over
and over and over again
but after two or three months of this
group showing up every week
or every other week when they met um
their message got hurt and i think three
people resigned
like it was a major overhaul of city
government at that point
um in retrospect i really should have
gone for one of the open seats
but uh i told you
it really taught me that politics is all
perception
and if you can get it doesn't take that
many if you can get
15 or 20 or 30 people to show up
and if you can all do something the same
you'll really scare the [ __ ] out of
people
so if we can all wear neon green
t-shirts or
royal blue t-shirts they don't even have
to say
something you don't even have to take
the time to throw a stencil across
it and print like we don't like how you
haul trash or
legalize pot or whatever on them they
can just all be neon green
and hi you know me and all the people in
matching shirts behind me are here to
say
we should legalize pot and we're going
to come back every week and say that
until you do
and the first week everybody's like sure
you are
in the next meeting everybody's like oh
they came back he
and by the fifth meeting they're like
[ __ ] like what happens
if more people start showing up is
because the news was talking to that guy
before the meeting
and you know i i saw him last
after the last meeting on the news too
all of a sudden
your little group and whatever your
issue is is getting
major major time during the conversation
and that's when [ __ ] really changes um
colorado tried to legalize before we got
it done and we failed hard
and but we moved the conversation and
now that we are where we are as a
country
like you're there it's if if places like
new york and new jersey can convince
their legislators that
getting legalization done in one form or
another
is important even if we don't get it
perfect we can always go back and adjust
if we can get movement in one or two
more states we
we're it's over we're there
nice that's a good spot to start
wrapping it up mike let's leave an
opportunity for a part two this is going
to be
just about an hour long which is a
perfect podcast for the two of us they
like it when we ramble
uh thank you bro and good job you did a
wonderful job there will be plenty of
questions
uh we'll get plenty of feedback we'll
have to do a revision or a part two
uh boys and girls ladies and gentlemen
pimps and hoes friends and foes smokers
growers clone cutters pollen chuckers
all you bad [ __ ] out there in
podcast land
i want to thank you for listening if you
feel like this episode was educational
informative or entertaining
and you would like to support white mike
on patreon i encourage you to do so
check him out at patreon.com forward
slash white mike
of course you can support the show uh
this one is all about white mike the
show's patreon is patreon.com forward
slash grow from your heart
you hear that one every time give mike
some love also support seeds herenow.com
get yourself some seeds regular
feminized autoflowers from the leading
breeders on the planet they are
available at seeds here now use coupon
code gfyh10
save 10 i keep saying this if you get
multiple packs
that'll maybe save you enough money to
get more packs of seeds
save 10 on a big order that'll buy
another pack if you're just buying one
pack
the 10 off will cover the cost of
shipping that'll help you out
also i mentioned that under 30 tab check
out the cream on the under 30 tab get
the cream for 30 bucks
trying to show you something to do yeah
it's a five pack of seeds for 30 bucks
uh really great strain fix up your
garden elevate your game
uh what else do we got make sure you
follow mike on social media he is
nemopunk15
on the twitter and make sure you check
out pueblo for sensible cannabis laws on
facebook
uh we may encourage him to start going
on there again he's kind of taking a
break but we'll get him moving
uh dude thank you for hanging out this
was a good show i keep saying it but
questions comments corrections or
concerns my email address is grow from
your heart at hotmail.com i would love
to hear from you
that's all i've got for you that's all
mike's got for you we'll be back with
part two eventually i'll be back in a
couple of days with fresh new content
i want to give a giant shout out to my
friend tanto's garden and until next
time
take a fat dab and give your mom a hug
for me