[Music]
welcome to the show podcast world i'm
your host my friends call me rasta jeff
and it is time for episode 572 of the
grow from your heart podcast
this episode of the show is brought to
you by our friends at seedshearnow.com
seeds herenow.com offers seeds from all
of the industries
leading breeders including miss jill
genetics duke diamond and of course irie
genetics
everything at seedshearnow.com is backed
by their award-winning satisfaction
guarantee
and for my friends on a tight budget
seedshearnow.com offers several packs
for under 30
as well as amazing monthly sales
make sure to use coupon code gfyh10
while checking out to save a few bucks
again that is coupon code gfyh10
while checking out at seeds here now
dot com you know i like to start the
podcast off by talking about what i'm
smoking
today i've been taking dabs of fatso
number one
full spectrum extract from green dot
labs this is a blend of
gmo and legend og on the package the
flavor is described as dark roast
garlic and fuel i think there is also a
hint of bar
trash can in here which may sound
disgusting but i honestly
love this gross funky aroma that comes
from the fat zone
there is definitely a dark roast aroma
there's a garlic there's a fuel
but then there is also i keep saying it
a hint of funky
bar trash can and i really can't get
enough of it i'm showing the diamonds to
the camera there
on the back of the package it says it
contains 82.68
thc and non-detectable amounts of cbd
i'm sure you can tell by the intro in
this podcast that the dab i just took
[ __ ] me up my chest is caving in my
lungs feel a little bit heavy
i'm over here trying to catch my breath
i'm sure you can hear it into the
microphone
big shout out to our friends at green
dot labs for the
delicious fatso number one full spectrum
extract i am
heavily medicated my eyes are nice and
low i'm chilling out in the new chair if
you're watching on the video i'm sure
you've noticed by now
i am recording from a brand new
recording area that's right
i've set up a new little office space
slash recording area
i will be getting the equipment dialed
in i'll be getting the office recording
space dialed in
something i could use is a studio name
every recording studio's got a cool
studio name i need a studio name so you
guys send me your submissions i'd love
to hear from you
you can send me a tweet on twitter it's
at gfyh podcast
you can send me a message on facebook
find the girl from your heart podcast
you can find me on instagram it's uh the
grow from your heart podcast on
instagram or of course send me an email
grow from your heart at hotmail
hotmail.com
i would love to hear from you help me
name my brand new studio
also i've got a very important thing i
want to talk about
i want to say happy birthday to
[ __ ] sub cool i'm recording on
sub cool's birthday
happy birthday you bad [ __ ] rest
in peace suck cool
if you've been following me for a while
you know that i learned a lot from sub
cool
i know sub cool is a very controversial
figure in the cannabis industry
you either love them or hate them i've
got nothing but love and respect for the
dude
he taught me a lot he taught me what to
do and i keep saying it he also taught
me what not to do
in the cannabis industry subcool was a
pioneer
he was way ahead of me in the game
without his template his guideline his
guidance his input his friendship and
advice
i would not be the grower the breeder
the podcaster that i am today so
happy birthday [ __ ] sub cool
miss you bro wish you were still here
wish i could send you a message and you
reply with some [ __ ] off-the-wall
crazy [ __ ] that i did not expect
but you're gone still love you i'm gonna
keep growing in your honor
i did cross your jack the ripper to a
bunch of my stuff so
we collabed subcool and i talked about
collabing quite often
but he always had so much going on and
we were so far away
and i always had a lot going on so we
never did it and i
took the liberty of crossing his jack
the ripper i found a jack the ripper
male
i pollinated a bunch of my elite females
and some of my favorite female cuts with
that jack the ripper
there are a bunch of seeds people are
going to start asking for them again
they are not ready yet
they're getting sorted they're getting
counted they'll be sent out to testers
very soon i'll grow a bunch out myself
anyway i wanted to send love to sub cool
that's my whole point of that big rant
big shout out happy [ __ ]
birthday to sub cool rest in peace big
man wish you were here
i [ __ ] miss you uh we celebrated sub
cool today on instagram a little bit
queen v and will went on and did a one
hour live session where they smoked a
joint that was
about the size of a small baseball bat
they were normal people at the start by
the end
they were talking funny they were pale
and red-faced at the same time
they were drooling and dizzy it was fun
to watch great times big shout out to
those folks
for keeping sub cool spirit alive today
all right you guys i'm super rambly
this is the part of the show where we
need to give some love to the folks who
support the show on patreon
let's start off with the big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to
jucifer from grocl grokla homa let me
say that again you deserve a good
solid shout out with that cool [ __ ]
name shout out to
jucifer from groklahoma thank you for
all of the patreon support
let's follow that up with the big grow
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out to david h
let's say a big thank you to learning
and burning i want to send a big thank
you shout out to fractured teeth
let's send a big thank you to glenn
geroni i want to say thank you to canna
organic illinois
let's send a big thank you shout out to
brett g i want to send a special thank
you to colby i want to send a big fist
bump to dr
ew let's send a big thank you shout out
to freak fish and last but certainly not
least
let's send a big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out
to tad [ __ ] masterson big
thanks and big shout out to everybody
who continues to support the podcast
if you're not already supporting the
show on patreon and you would like to
learn how to do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need will be
right there on the screen
and of course i did include a link in
the show notes and the video description
to make it nice and easy for all of my
stoner friends all right i'm looking at
my notes to see where we are
next i feel like i've caught up on all
the business that was the business
that part's been handled let's talk
about the main
topic of today's podcast
i keep saying a bunch of [ __ ] on the
internet you guys
people think that they can identify the
sex of a seed by looking at the seed
people think that they've got gorilla
glue four seeds let's talk about some
[ __ ] that i keep
reading on the internet one of my
favorite things that i've been seeing
and this is a long old school myth and
i'm here to dispel today
if you plant your cannabis plants near
blueberries
or near strawberries i don't think
that's going to make your plants taste
like [ __ ] blueberries or strawberries
that is not the trick to get blueberry
or strawberry flavored or scented
cannabis
that is genetics that is bread
selectively bred into the cannabis we
find a strain that tastes like
strawberries a little bit
we breed that to something else we find
a phenotype that tastes a little bit
more strawberry than last time
then we use that plant and possibly the
old strawberry phenotype and breed that
and we get rid of all of the phenotypes
that aren't even more strawberry so we
breed
that flavor in or maybe we're breeding
it out we're bringing it out
and breeding that for you to have your
strawberry or blueblair blueberry
flavored cannabis you say that 10 times
fast you'll [ __ ] it up too it's okay
so the rumor that you can make your herb
taste
like strawberries or blueberries or
apples by growing it
near strawberries blueberries or apples
is very unlikely
it may get a hint of it maybe possibly
but i don't think it's going to make it
have that
bold blueberry strawberry aroma flavor
that people want it to have
also i don't think feeding your plants
like juices and [ __ ] are going to have
the same effect you're not going to get
if you feed your plants blueberry juice
you're not going to get blueberry
flavored buds that's not a real thing
and here is some evidence to support
that
a lot of us feed our plants a lot of
really funky flavored and smelling
things
people that are running uh the k f the
korean natural farming doing the
fermented fruit juices that stuff
doesn't smell like berries and bubble
gum
but when they grow their herb it smells
like berries and bubble gum
a lot of people put bat [ __ ] cow [ __ ]
horse [ __ ] chicken [ __ ]
into their herb it doesn't smell and
taste like bat [ __ ] cow [ __ ]
goat [ __ ] or chicken [ __ ] so the rumor
the idea
the myth that cannabis will taste like
berries should you plant it near berries
has just been debunked quit saying that
[ __ ]
all right the next one i want to debunk
today is that you can
judge the ripeness of your cannabis
plants by the pistols
i hear people i see people on social
media say you can tell if your plant is
done by the hairs
first of all if you're saying hairs
you're already off on the wrong foot
those are pistols also those pistols do
not indicate ripeness of your cannabis
plants in
any way those are the sex glands of
your female plant those are there to
pick up pollen
they're flapping in the wind the pollen
lands on that slides down that
ends up in the ovule then a seed forms
inside of there
that has nothing to do we're not smoking
pistols are we you don't look at the
pistols and go those are great for
smoking
we are smoking trichomes why not measure
the
ripeness of our plant by the thing we
are going to consume the part that
contains the active ingredient
that we want to consume we want thc
why not judge the trichomes by the
amount of thc the ripeness of the thc
in my opinion judging your plant's
ripeness
by the pistols or the hairs is like
judging the ripeness of an apple
by looking at the dirt underneath the
tree it does not do you
a bit of [ __ ] good so you cannot
determine the ripeness of your cannabis
plants by looking at the pistols
the pistols will change colors if they
get sprayed with something the pistols
will change colors if they get too dry
the pistols can change brown and wither
up if they get pollinated the pistols
will wither up and dry if you touch them
too much
maybe an insect damaged them maybe they
got too much sun exposure
maybe maybe that plant has passed its
pollination point
and it is no longer able to receive
pollen those plants only want pollen up
till about day 40
but we flower them until about day 65 or
70.
so judging by those pistols is a failure
to begin with stop doing that
you're [ __ ] up all right i'm going
really fast but
i'm kind of just trying out this new
gear i want to keep moving because what
if this doesn't sound really good and i
record a really long podcast
so i'm going to move on to the next
mother [ __ ] rumor i would like to
dispel today on this episode i'm moving
to another page i've got a couple that
i'm trying to save here because i'm
doing them in a certain order uh you
cannot
can not not cannot impossible
to visually identify the sex
of a cannabis seed by looking at
that seed if that were possible
i would pay you to come sort out all of
the male and female seeds from my seed
batches
i would keep the males so i could grow
nothing but elite males for myself and
have killer breeding projects
then we would sell all of the female
seeds i can guarantee you they were
females
female seeds cost twice as much as
non-female seeds
non-feminized seeds so if you could do
that magic trick for me
i would hire you unfortunately that
little chart that you see on social
media that says if it's got this shape
to it
or this pointy tip here this volcano
shape here or an acorn shaped here
that is complete and total mother
[ __ ] [ __ ] debunked roster jeff
calls [ __ ]
if you can do it if you can prove it
come to my spot
i will give you a hundred seeds i will
let you number them we will label them
we will plant them
one through one hundred we will veg them
until they're
two inches tall is that two inches i
don't know we'll veg them until they're
three and a half inches tall that's how
tall gi joe is three and three quarters
that's this tall
judge them tillers tall veg them tillers
tall as gi joe
then we'll be we're we're going to
flower them we're going to remember
everyone you marked male and female
we're going to write it down on the
container in which that seed is in we're
going to know i'm going to have
documentation
if you're ninety percent right i'll be
[ __ ] amazed if you're seventy percent
right i might still be impressed
fifty percent is just [ __ ] lucky
guesses you gotta be more than sixty or
seventy percent
i doubt you're gonna get it right i have
never seen anybody accurately do that
i don't [ __ ] believe it one bit if
you can do it come on over i'll [ __ ]
pay you there's a prize involved
so you cannot visually identify the sex
of seeds by looking at them people are
gonna say what about feminized seeds
that's [ __ ] cheating i know they're
female seeds because i made them they're
feminized i did that
so what if i [ __ ] with you what if i
give you a bunch of seeds and tell you
to sex them for me and i put some female
seeds in there that i know are femmes
the minute i see you say this one's a
boy you're already wrong so we already
know that your whole [ __ ] theory
is all [ __ ] up so you cannot identify
seeds by looking at them where are we
what do we want to go with next i've got
two more big ones that i know are going
to let me rant for a couple of seconds
not too far into this podcast let's talk
about this one
uh this one just drives me nuts
professionally as an industry as a
community as a movement we need to
work toward more professionalism and a
way we can do that is by using proper
terminology like i said before
those hairs are called pistols you
already sound more credible more
educated more advanced if you say
pistols and quit saying hairs
so let's work on another word that
drives me [ __ ] crazy and if you don't
care
that's cool i just want to give you a
heads up if you want to sound a little
bit more
educated and be taken a little more
seriously in the group
let's talk about the word herme herme
drives me nuts
hermes not a [ __ ] word hermaphrodite
is the word
if you're gonna say hermie just say herm
don't put the me on
there on there for some reason it sounds
very juvenile very elementary school
very playground-ish
herme i don't know it bothers the [ __ ]
out of me also the word isn't
hermaphrodite
the word is intersex if a plant shows
male
and female sex parts that plant carries
intersex traits
let's wipe the word herme out of our
vocabulary
no more herme maybe hermaphrodite maybe
herm if you're typing fast
let's work on intersex this plant shows
intersex traits
it didn't go herm on you it showed
now another thing i want to address that
falls right into this category
maybe a sub-note of this category i see
people saying
that they put there was a male plant
near their plants
and it made their females turn
hermaphroditic
and seed up you guys that is not what's
happening let's think about basic
biology
you've got a male plant he's got male
pollen sacs
you've got a female plant she's got what
do we talk about earlier
pistols and ovules now how does nature
work what do boys and girls do
they [ __ ] how does that happen the
pollen which is basically the sperm
hits the pistol which takes that pistol
to the ovule
which is where babies are made just like
in nature bro it's sperming up the egg
so those plants that you were saying
that some people on social media keep
saying
my plants were near a male plant and
they hermed nah bro
they [ __ ] and your plants are pregnant
it's seeded up no herming happened you
let a male go
and that male pollinated that female
plant it wasn't a herm that's nature
that's biology 101.
they [ __ ] all right i'm going to move
on from talking about plants [ __ ] i'm
going to quit saying like that
i'm sure a couple of people threw up in
their mouths every time i said that
let's talk about another thing um
the phrase clone only now
a lot of people don't even understand
what i'm talking about when i say clone
only let's pick the strain
gorilla glue number four gorilla glue
number four is a plant that is a clone
only gorilla glue 4 was bred by josie
wales rest in peace brother josie wells
he's no longer with us but his work
lives on forever
gorilla glue 4 is known as number 4
because there was a batch of seeds
number 4 was the prize
seedling out of that batch so he
probably had
i'm going to assume since i've seen
gorilla glue 7 i'm going to assume there
were 10 plants
just guessing hypothetically follow me
here we've got 10 plants
our friend has named them gorilla glue
he probably didn't name them until after
he smoked them and smelled
it either way let's focus on the story
ten seedlings
grew them out he realized number four
and number seven are the [ __ ] keepers
he smokes them i'm assuming and making
this up this is my assumption here
don't don't [ __ ] criticize me too
much but this is how this works
he smokes them he realizes this smells
or tastes like gorilla glue
names it gorilla glue but there are 10
seedlings so they all got numbered
gorilla glue 1 through ten the boys
probably got removed i don't know they
got put in another room the females got
to flower
there's probably five girls five boys
just hypothetically that's how breeding
and selecting works
of those five there was number four and
number seven
amongst that five hypothetically so
they got their numbers their number
indications because of the specific
phenotype that those plants were from
that cross
so number four gorilla glue number four
is a selected cut which was selected
by josie wales it was named gorilla glue
and the cut was number four because it
was probably the fourth plant in the
tray
hence gorilla glue number four
now why is it a clone only because
josie never put out a male plant of the
gorilla glue number four he never
released a male
so it is clone only there are no
unadulterated seeds of gorilla glue
number four
available on the market unless josie put
them out and he did
not and let's talk about that if he did
breed to it
they wouldn't be gorilla glue number
four seeds they would be
gorilla glue number four crossed to
something
which would lose the name gorilla glue
number four
so let's talk about this in a couple of
other terms
if he took a gorilla if anybody took a
gorilla glue number four plant and bred
to it you can make seeds but they are
not gorilla glue four they are now
adulterated
gorilla glue four seeds bred to
something it's gorilla glue for ex
other plant cross to another plant the
only
way it is possible to have pure gorilla
glue number four seeds
is to have s1 feminized gorilla glue
number four seeds what that means
is we took a gorilla glue number four
plant the official
clone only plant the selection that
josie whales selected himself
and labeled number four you have to take
that plant
take two clones of that same plant treat
one with the solution there are multiple
ways to reverse a plant of course i
recommend silver thiosulfate
apply silver thiosulfate to the one
plant it will create pollen sacs
apply that pollen to the female plant at
the right time
now you have produced gorilla glue
number four
seeds you have self the gorilla glue it
is not adulterated there are no
other genetics within that cross so the
only
way that you can have gorilla glue
number four
seeds is if they are feminized as ones
otherwise those seeds people are selling
you giving you trading to you
offering you are [ __ ] that is not
gorilla glue number four
unless they reversed it and made
feminized
seeds let's talk about this in other
terms that may
make it more clear for other people
let's talk about an animal that is
nearly extinct i'm going to create an
animal
uh we're going to call it the uh the
purple wombat there's only
one female purple wombat left on the
planet just one
how are we gonna make more we're not
because there's only one [ __ ] female
there's no sperm
one purple wombat on the planet it's a
girl where are we gonna get some sperm
from there are no dudes around
we're not we're not going to make more
purple wombats
that is how biology and breeding work
there is only
one female of gorilla glue number four
there was never a male released
josie didn't put out the mail you can't
make more unadulterated crosses without
the mail
so that is my rant on clone only clone
only means
that there was never seeds or a male
release to make seeds with
of course breeders like myself have kind
of [ __ ] this all up and started making
feminized seeds let's talk about golden
goat
i did not make golden goat i need to
give a shout out to dr
dank who made the golden goat mr dank dr
dank
i apologize for getting it wrong on a
podcast big respect either way
i'm live on the spot trying to keep up
with my own brain mr dank made golden
goat
i acquired the golden goat clone it was
a clone
only there is no male of golden goat
available
this guy put out the clone of golden
goat clone only no seeds no male plant
until i got a hold of it and made that
s1 my purpose for making the s1 is
because people in other places were
seeing my pictures of golden go
and saying that's [ __ ] amazing can i
have some of that i can't really easily
ship clones all over the place but
allegedly we can get you seeds all over
the world
so i made golden goat seeds from a
golden goat plant i took a golden goat
took two clones of it treated one with
silver thiosulfate
it made pollen i applied that pollen
onto a female golden goat the same plant
just two clones so it's clone only i'm
using the clone
then i made seeds from that those seeds
are golden goat
s1 feminized seeds that is the only way
you can get pure unadulterated golden
goat
also i've made a golden goat back cross
which means
i took a plant that was very similar to
golden goat and crossed it to the golden
goat and the offspring looks very much
like golden goat i've talked about my
process in that
in depth in a couple of episodes but
that is a back cross
since there is not a male of golden goat
available i had to use a different male
to put pollen on that plant to make
seeds that is not
pure golden goat that is a bat cross
it's been adulterated
it is my responsibility as a responsible
breeder
to label that as the back cross which
it is so that is my rant on clone only
that is my rant and my reasoning on why
there is no
gorilla glue [ __ ] seeds that are not
s-ones
that's my rant on why there's no golden
goat that's my rant on why there are no
girl scout cookies
many of these plants were clone only and
there were no
options for other seeds the only person
that had the seeds were the guys that
made it
so let's say i make a cross let's talk
about something i'm not going to release
um i don't even want to tell you some
[ __ ] that i've got going on that i'm not
going to release
let's just say that i took a rise and i
crossed it to this new blue kombucha
bottle that's
there's a blue kombucha bottle in front
of me that's a new [ __ ] strain name
a rise to blue kombucha bottle i'm gonna
grow out 25 seeds of it i'm gonna find
the [ __ ] champion female out of there
i've got this amazing
arise to blue kombucha female we're
gonna call it kombucha rise that's how
my brain works kombucha rise
but i'm never gonna give anybody a seed
i'm gonna hoard these seeds
these are mine blue kombucha rye seeds
all go in my safe
they're locked away i'm going to forget
about them maybe i'll lose them
i don't know they won't germinate that's
it there's this one plant that i grew
this blue kombucha rise that i selected
i got rid of all the others they weren't
[ __ ] elites i've got one blue
kombucha rise
make more of that you can't do it
because there's no mail i didn't give
anybody any seeds
maybe i gave you the clone but i will
never give you the seeds
you've got that clone you can't make
more of that unless
you adulterate it with other pollen or
you self it so that's my rant on
clone only uh gorilla glue 4 girl scout
cookies
uh there are a lot of other things out
there that are clone only blue dream is
clone only
a lot of that popular [ __ ] that you guys
are really seeking is clone only so
part of why i'm doing this rant is to
let you know to be careful i need to
educate you i want to educate you be
careful in your quest for seeds
don't get duped don't get ripped off
don't fall for false labeling
uh look for a seed brand a seed vendor
that's been around for a while
i'm not saying only shop with me there
are a lot of people that have been
around a lot longer than me
that have a lot of other things to offer
that i don't offer but be
very careful when you're shopping if
they've got blue dream
if they've got gorilla glue if they've
got girl scout cookies
and it just says regular seeds and
doesn't tell you what it's crossed with
be very leery of those seeds
all right ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls pimps and hoes friends and foes
smokers growers clone cutters pollen
chuckers skateboarders seed hoarders
all you bad [ __ ] out there in
the cannabis community a special shout
out to all the weed nerds
i want to thank you guys for listening
to episode 572 of the grow from your
heart podcast
the first episode from the new office
slash
studio once again i would love your
input your feedback let me know how the
show
sounded let me know how it looks on the
camera the shirt is blue so i realize we
need some new lighting in here that may
be the next investment
what else was i gonna say i don't even
remember where i was headed with that
let me know what you think
uh if you feel like the episode was
educational informative oh i need a name
for the studio
name the studio where else was i i don't
[ __ ] know i need lighting
blah blah ramble ramble ramble back on
track here we go if you feel like the
episode was educational informative and
or entertaining
and you would like to support the show
on patreon all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need will be
right there on the screen
of course don't forget to visit our
sponsors at seedshearnow.com
use coupon code gfyh10 to save yourself
10 percent
um also cannabis join us on cannabis
cannabis is a free social media
application download it on your
apple or android device create a
username login
it works just like most of the other
social media applications except
we encourage you to post your cannabis
related
content join us i've been doing
giveaways and auctions on cannabis
i think you will enjoy it find me over
there i'm irie underscore
genetics if you've got any questions
corrections comments or concerns i would
love to hear from you
my email address is grow from your heart
hotmail.com
send me a message let me know what you
think of the show once again i'm looking
for feedback and studio name suggestions
let me know what you think of the sound
let me know what you think of the video
uh
let me know what you think of the
lighting just give me some feedback i'm
needy help me out all right ladies and
gentlemen boys and girls that's all i've
got for this episode i want to give a
giant shout out to my friend ez057
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
hey