[Music]
welcome back podcast world i'm your host
my friends call me rosta jeff and it is
time for episode 573 of the grow from
your heart podcast
this episode of the show is brought to
you by our friends at seedshearnow.com
seedshearnow.com offers seats from all
of the industry's
leading breeders including miss jill
genetics duke diamond and of course irie
genetics
everything at seedshearnow.com is backed
by their award-winning satisfaction
guarantee
and for my friends on a tight budget
seeds herenow.com offers several packs
for under 30.
as well as amazing monthly sales
make sure to use coupon code gfyh10
while checking out to save a few bucks
again that is coupon code gfyh10 while
checking out
at seeds here dot com
you know i like to start the podcast off
by talking about what i'm smoking
today i've been taking dabs of melon
smash live batter
this is a blend of tangelo and day
wrecker bx
on the package the flavor is described
as melons and fuel
i think i completely agree with that
when i crack open the jar
it is watermelony there's a hint of
strawberries coming out of there
then when i take a dab i am greeted with
that fuel flavor on my tongue
i really do enjoy it it's got a very
pleasant buzz on the back of the package
it says it contains
67.15 total thc
so big shout out to the melon smash live
batter for keeping me happily medicated
through this podcast
all right this is the part of the show
where i do shout outs to the members of
the 710 club of course the 710 club
are the folks who support the show on
patreon at the 7
and 10 a month level or higher so with
no further ado let's do some shout outs
too let's start off with the big grow
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out to xavier c
let's send a big thank you in a rasta
fist bump to ross decay
let's send a big special thank you shout
out to the kanekrat let's send them some
love to grant m
i want to send a big thank you shout out
to grandpa mark i've got a special thank
you shout out for eric
ross let's send a big high five and a
thank you shout out to brandon
i want to send a special thank you to
kes burton thank you for all the work
you're doing with the veterans and all
the teaching you're doing
uh let's send a big thank you shout out
to josiah and last but certainly
not least let's send a big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to dominic
c big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon
if you're not already supporting the
show on patreon and you would like to
learn how to do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need will be
right there on the screen and of course
i did include a link
in the show notes to make it nice and
easy for all of my friends all you have
to do is go to the show
if you're listening on apple podcast or
spotify click on the notes click on the
details there will be a link right there
of course you're watching on youtube
there is a link in the video description
of course i do recommend youtube because
you can see my
lovely new video set up you can see the
new brightness i got going on in the
camera
and of course i do appreciate and
encourage feedback i got a lot of
feedback on the last episode
people said put some light in that damn
room i've adjusted some light i've
adjusted some settings
do you approve i'm seeking approval i
want your feedback let me know what you
think
grow from your heart hotmail.com or
leave a comment on the youtube channel
or hit me up on twitter at gfyh podcast
that feels like a lot of rambling to
start the show where else can we go from
there
thanks to all my friends who support us
on patreon um
what else what else where do we go from
here there are new shirts available if
you're watching on youtube you can see
i'm rocking this fresh new
irie genetics lemon jeffree shirt says
irie genetics on there
it's got the lemon jeffrey logo on it it
does say irie genetics but it is not a
blatantly cannabis themed t-shirt
if you're looking for some fresh new
gear you can get them i do have an
etsy store my website is being rebuilt
shout out to the people who are
rebuilding my website that is under
construction now
the new site iriegenetics.com should be
available in about four weeks from today
i will let you know when that's ready
but until then we are selling the shirts
on my etsy store
it is irie gifts llc
on etsy you should be able to find it
search ire gifts llc on etsy
you will find ire genetics lemon jeffree
shirts also let me do a quick reach over
here
you will find these beautiful orange
gasm t-shirts i'm holding one up for the
camera now
it says irie genetics it's got the
orange gasm logo on it again not
blatantly cannabis but it does say irie
genetics if you're one of those people
who wants to support but can't wear a
weed themed shirt
this may be something for you holding
that up for the camera so you can get a
nice clear view
nice bright vivid colors nice artwork i
really enjoy it shout out to my friend
kevin hartman for the great art
and shout out to the people who made the
shirts they know who they are
anyway grab yourself some shirts on the
etsy store
irie gifts llc on etsy get yourself a
lemon jeffree and an orange gas i'm
sure by the time this episode comes out
there may
be golden goat shirts available if not
check back very soon they are due the
same day that this podcast is due
i will inspect them make sure they
printed them well make sure they're
quality shirts as soon as they pass my
inspection
kapow they go up there onto the etsy
store they will be available so check
for those
uh probably by the time this episode
airs if not 24 hours from the time this
episode comes out we will have golden
goat
t-shirts available all right i feel like
i've covered a lot of business and a lot
of ground here at the start of the show
uh we did the patreon part we did the
shirts i feel like it is time to jump
into the message
portion of this podcast i do have a
great question this one comes from a
long-time listener someone who interacts
with me quite a bit it's funny he said
he didn't want to send a message because
he's been bugging me a lot
bro you're never bugging me i love the
interaction i love the messages i love
the support
uh keep sending the questions and
responses
i love it you guys are never bugging me
i love the cannabis questions i love the
community interaction
i do get a lot of messages so if it
takes me a minute to reply i'm not
ignoring you i didn't forget
uh there are a hundred new messages in
my inbox and i gotta find you but i will
get there
the email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com keep the messages
coming
i'm [ __ ] rambly let's get to the
point
this message goes just like this it says
hey ross to jeff please don't use my
real name i like that a lot when people
tell me not to use their real name makes
it easy
i know who gets a shout out from this
one i know not to use your name
let's keep going it says i've been
meaning to write to you since episode
560 to tell you how much i enjoyed
hearing you and mike drop
stories and knowledge you two just
bullshitting provided so much
information that people like me would
never hear and that made 560 a great
episode
it thanks a lot that was a fun episode
to record we really went off the rails
uh we really had a good time it was just
two dudes hanging out i'm glad you guys
appreciate it it also says my incentive
to write was increased because i have a
question about something that just
happened to me so we've got some
first-hand experience inspiring
questions
let's not waste too much time it goes
like this i don't want to mention the
breeder or the seed bank involved very
classy thank you i would have edited
that out anyway but i like your approach
it says
i ordered a particular strain from a
seed bank which i am sure you are
familiar with
but does not carry iri genetics uh
it says my habit is to grow one seed out
to learn the plant before i grow
more i'd put this and an orange gasm in
a flower tent at the same time
they were two of the they were the two
prettiest girls in the tent
these plants were two and one half weeks
into flower
so i pulled them out of the tent to give
them a close visual inspection
you know just in case all right so where
we are is
uh this listener bought some seeds uh
they bought a pack of seeds from a
vendor that does not carry ivory
genetics which is just fine i encourage
you to grow more stuff
of course i want you to buy my seeds and
grow them but there are so many things
out there
don't stick with just me try more [ __ ]
and then also you'll see
where things stand uh so our friend
bought some seeds they also bought some
orange seeds
they grow one seed from a pack at a time
so now they've got an orgasm seed
growing and they've got this other seed
growing which we're not going to
name so they are how are we one two and
one half weeks and a flower
he's taken his plants out of the tent to
take a look just like we're supposed to
do and i already know how this is gonna
go
uh it says you've probably guessed by
now that i found male pollen sacks
growing alongside
female flowers on the plant in question
so the plant that is not the orange gasm
is showing female flowers on one plant
on one bud
and male flowers on another we've got an
intersex
plant here it is showing us two
different traits let's keep talking
about this it says the orange gasm
was fine so the orange gasm hasn't shown
you any
intersex or hermaphroditic traits it is
still flowering as a female
it says thankfully no pollen has been
released
um no problem that you know of don't get
too excited yeah those [ __ ] go
more quickly than we think sometimes i
don't want to
[ __ ] burst your bubble but hopefully
i'm really hoping you got in there early
enough that they go sooner than we
expect sometimes
uh it says it's tough to commit can
aside but that guy gal had to go yes get
those the [ __ ] out of there don't feel
bad at all
about committing plant caniside uh we
are
looking for uh professional athletes
we're looking for high level
uh [ __ ] olympic athletes and that one
was not performing it couldn't even run
around the track so it had to go
uh this is an elite club and we are very
selective i'm not afraid to admit that i
[ __ ] choose favorites in my garden
that's how it goes
uh it's okay to do that with plants we
can't do it with people all right let's
keep moving forward i'm [ __ ] rambly
today
uh where are we so that had to go the
breeder in question had online reviews
indicating problems with hermaphrodites
so i contacted the seed bank and after
much wrangling i got some relief
you're very lucky there because a lot of
the seed banks if you say you germinated
the seeds they're going to tell you that
those were meant as souvenirs and you
can't germinate them anyway so you
[ __ ] up by germinating them
and now you're [ __ ] out of luck so
you're lucky you got anywhere with that
seed bank honestly
uh it says however the seed bank blamed
me of course they did
of course they did i'll wait to see
exactly what the seller does before i
decide if i'm satisfied with its
response
needless to say i won't grow any more
seeds from that pack
most likely that company is going to
blow you off you did send me details
about where this came from that i left
out of the show
they are not going to reply to you
they're not going to do [ __ ] for you and
my assumption in my experience they're
going to tell you that it was all your
fault to have a good day
they may give you a coupon or something
for more seeds but i don't think you're
going to be satisfied with the fix here
that's why i recommend seeds herenow.com
100 satisfaction guarantee
if seeds go wrong that you buy at seeds
here now you send them a message you say
hey these seeds didn't work
they will replace them then they will
let me know that they had to replace
them and then i replaced them so
the only person i i cover my mistakes if
your seeds don't work i cover them to
the seed bank the seed bank covers you
we want to make sure everybody's happy
that's how customer service should work
so
let me know if you ever got a problem
with ire genetics seeds send me an email
iregenetics hotmail.com i'll do my best
to help you out
don't troll me don't be a dick be polite
about it we'll take care of you
um so i really think your [ __ ] out of
luck with those seeds that you got but
luckily
you were a guy that once runs one seed
at a time a lot of people run the whole
pack
that could have been a 10 pack or a 12
pack of seeds imagine if you run 12 of
them and found 12 herms
you would have had 12 times the soil
water nutrient space
it would have been compounded by 12 so
i'm kind of glad you're a guy that runs
one at a time
and if you got one intersex plant out of
that batch
so far they are a hundred percent
problematic seeds i can only imagine
what's going to come from the other 10
or 12 or maybe six
uh if there were femmes that company
sells packs of six femmes i think so
uh you would have had five more
problematic plants on your hands i need
to get myself back on track or this
podcast is going to end up being like 44
days long
let's get focused here it says so here
is my question these pollen sacks
uh were what i would call genetic herms
as opposed to stress
herms so uh he's calling them genetic
hermaphrodites and not
stress hermaphrodites in my mind those
labels indicate that uh
this is kind of a weird boundary to
cross here kind of a fine line to dance
on
but he's saying that he assumes some
plants
are more genetically prone and poorly
selected to be herms and some are just
triggered
that trait was lying in that plant and
it would have been brought out
but i'm going to get to that part let me
just keep talking it says am i correct
that if pollen sacs develop on a plant
side by side with female flowers that
the trait is within the genetics of the
strain and not a result of stress
while i did have less than a week of
slightly higher temp temperatures during
a short heat wave
conditions in the tent were pretty
normal can you explain the process
of hermaphroditism and cannabis
including the difference
between what causes male female parts on
the same node
and what causes another to or anthers to
sprout from
flowers thanks for the benefit of your
expertise
i don't know that i am an expert in the
category of
hermaphroditism or intersex plants um
kinda if i see that i get rid of the
plants but i do
understand what you are asking sometimes
you will see a plant
later in flower start throwing uh we
call them nanners they're just
single male flowers that pop up in the
middle of a bud
i think those are more from stressing a
plant those are more from problems i
think
when your plant produced these male
flowers early into flower like that
that that is a hermaphroditic plant
those are probably problematic seeds
that were poorly selected
i did reply to our friend here he signed
it with uh
uh this is from used to be cool there we
go he did sign it from used to be cool
he signed it with us to be cool if i
just showed your name on the screen i
will block that out because i held up
your email
but um so i did reply to used to be cool
and i said
hey i think both of those examples are
predetermined traits in the plant a lot
like color and structure
so that hermaphroditism is a trait
within that plant it is a trait
just like the smell of the plant just
like the growth uh maybe it's really
good with pm maybe it's not also
maybe it's got intersex that's just an
alien which this plant carries
so i said we provide the environmental
situation
to trigger that expression so that plant
held that intersex trait we had to give
it the environment to bring that
intersex trait out
just like a lot of times you can make
some plants turn cold or turn purple if
you get them cold that's a trait we can
bring out through environmental factors
density is a lot determined by
environmental factors we can get airy
buds or we can get dense buds from the
same plant
based on the environment so we are
giving it the situation to express
different things if i put you i'm trying
to think of different situations i can
put you in if i put you
uh near a bunch of junk food all the
time and make you watch crap tv
you're gonna turn into a junk food
eating crap-minded person if i give you
health food and healthy things to do all
day
you'll become a healthy person who's
physically fit with a strong healthy
mind
that is a product of your environment
that is how you express your environment
plants do the same thing i'm trying to
stay on track and also give good
examples uh so these plants
were given the environment to show
hermaphroditism
um and i'm getting off track of what i
wrote here let me keep going with what i
wrote i said a breeder should be testing
his seeds before releasing them
i think what you got was poor breeding
and
untested seeds that were prone to
intersex traits
poorly selected parent stock for femmes
will make hermaphroditic offspring
that's not the word i wrote here but
it says plants that flip from major
stress are more common
because cannabis wants to survive and
will reproduce
so if you leave most cannabis plants
growing for too long they will find a
way to produ reproduce
they will start throwing off very few
hermaphroditic male flowers or male
flowers not even hermaphroditic flowers
they will be male flowers they'll start
throwing those off
the idea of this plant is nobody's gonna
pick me no one's gonna pollinate me i'll
[ __ ] self-pollinate myself so i can
survive that's cannabis whole goal it
wants to make seeds
so it can grow again next year so it can
make seeds and grow again
next year so i'm going to try to get
myself back where i was here
uh the plants want to survive so that
hint of
hermaphroditism is in a lot of plants
breeders should be selecting plants more
carefully to where we don't have
such likelihood for hermaphroditism in
the offspring
i think what this guy got what used to
be cool got was just
poorly bred untested uh untried and true
genetics these genetics should have been
test grown
if they showed hermaphroditism if they
showed intersex traits two and a half
weeks into flower like that
the breeder should have seen that one of
yours did it a hundred percent of yours
did it
that means a few of his had to have done
it and he should have seen that and he
should have said
these are [ __ ] i should not sell these
to anybody i need to grow these myself
and find some gems or give them to my
friends and warn them that these are
[ __ ]
but they should not have gone to market
no vendor no retailer should have ever
gotten their hands on these that was
poor practices bad customer service bad
selection
bad ethics bad breeding uh that's [ __ ]
up is what that is
um so that should have been removed from
the gene pool
now this guy's passing on hermaphroditic
seeds a bunch of people are going to buy
these seeds they're going to spend money
they're going to be pissed off i'm
getting way off track it says um
balls and pistols on the same branch
show obvious intersex traits a few
nanners
and a mostly looking female is more
likely a grower issue
so if you're causing the plants or
hermaphrodite and it's just spitting out
a couple of male flowers
that is probably a light leak some sort
of stress but if it's showing
straight up balls and female flowers on
the same plant
that was a poorly selected breeding
project it should have been eliminated
it should have been scrapped
uh then i wrapped my message up with i'm
high as [ __ ] so i hope this
makes sense yeah sometimes you guys i'm
answering messages at three in the
morning
and i'm high as [ __ ] um so mainly that
should have been found in test batches
and you should not have been sold those
seeds
i don't think any of that
hermaphroditism was your fault
uh since you've got another plant in
there the orange gasm didn't show you
any problems
that's an indicator that that was a
problem with the genetics
and not your fault all right i hope i
rambled right through your question i
hope i gave you some useful advice
i do appreciate all of the interaction
with you brother and i look forward to
hearing
your reply to my reply all right i want
to keep moving i do have a screenshot in
my phone from another message
somebody sent me a message on i don't
remember if this came from youtube or
cano buzz but my phone will tell me
if i quit stumbling and get right to it
all right this one is from cana buzz
and it says hey ross to jeff i just
discovered your show via the dgc
shout out to my friends at the dude grow
show our new friend found us through the
dude grow show so thank you for finding
me from the dgc
it says you mentioned you are limited to
a low plant count at home yes i'm in
colorado
our plant count here uh it is a six
plant per person cap for recreational
cannabis
however i do have a medical cannabis
card which allows me six more plants so
i'm now allowed 12
plants in my personal grow that's what
i'm allowed to have because of the state
of colorado
so that does limit me very low to
breeding i've got 12 plants i'm allowed
to work with
this goes on and says could you talk
about the logistics of breeding at home
with a low
plant count yes that is something i
could definitely elaborate on
um the difference between breeding in a
bigger facility and breeding in a
smaller facility
is definitely smaller batches smaller
scales which means more focus
um i'm only allowed 12 plants so if you
really want to think about it
how many mom plants do i keep and then
how many plants do i put in the veg room
and then i need a male plant also or how
many plants do i put into the flower
room
so i've got mother plants veg plants
flower plants
and a male plant and hopefully backups
or clones of whatever i'm working with
so i've got to be really really
selective of what i'm using
and what i'm going to breed with and
what makes and doesn't make the cut to
stay in my stable
so if you want to breed on a very small
scale because of plant counts you need
to focus on your goals you can't have
any plants that aren't
winners aren't champions aren't
potential breeders you've got to have
nothing but winners in there all right
so let's use my
12 plant state legal count to do a
little breeding project
we've got a couple of options when it
comes to breeding do you want to breed
one plant to one plant do you want to
breed one male plant to a bunch of
female plants
do you want to breed a reversed female
to other females
what is your ultimate goal that's going
to be a lot of the decision making
when it comes to logistics of breeding
at home
since i run a commercial seed breeding
company
i like to make multiple strains at one
time so i usually put
king solomon my popular male in the room
with several females so that he can hit
the strawberry fields the platinum tangy
the blueberry cookies
and then we can make uh what do we make
there we make sun kiss we make
strawberry fields and we make blue
raspberry truffle out of those
i'll put the morning dew or the grateful
dog in there so we can make morning dew
i'll put an arise female in there so we
can make a rise f2 seeds
then maybe when you're not looking i'll
sneak something brand new in there so i
can make a brand new cross
so i've got a bunch of the old trusty
reliable stuff to restock the stores
then also i've got a brand new thing to
send out to my testers i can build more
hype keep stuff going
while i'm doing productivity so since i
make commercial production
i'm putting a male in there with five or
six tried and trued females
that boy hits those girls then i make a
batch of five or six
different crosses then i harvest those
they're ready to go
the thing i have to think about is i've
got a certain amount of mother plants
i know which genetics i want to keep so
i select a few of those
those plants are now eating up part of
my plant count so king solomon is always
around he's always eating a part of my
plant count
strawberry fields uh what is the other
one platinum tangy blueberry cookies
those are eating up part of my plant
count so those are there
those are going to get cloned off of or
they're going to get dragged into the
flower room
with the male plant now my issue is i
need to keep those plants around because
i want to breed with them again in the
future
so now i've got to take a clone of them
those clones are starting to eat up my
plant count
so what i've got to do is carefully
think about how many mother plants i'm
going to keep
how many plants i'm going to throw into
the breeding room then how i'm going to
keep clones of those to keep them for
preservation
it is a really nice balance and a really
nice juggle
luckily i do have other places where i
can store mother plants i've got friends
that i can rely on
they will keep genetics for me they've
just got a mother plant of certain
things where if i want to breed with
that
i just call them up and i say hey i'm
going to need six clones of this plant
in this many days can you get them going
for me
and they take 12 clones and i go pick my
favorite six and they get to run the
other six and that's how we
make sure that genetics stay alive i've
got some
really trustworthy friends who have got
some really good genetics
[ __ ] stashed away for me or i
wouldn't be able to do a lot of the
projects that i do
so you've got to be able to keep your
mother plants you've got to have veg
plants that will eventually become
flower plants and you need clones
to keep preservation of your stuff
another thing you can do
is you can re-veg if you don't have the
numbers
you can re-veg this is going to sound
crazy to a new breeder but this is
something that is completely possible
i've done it i can show you the seeds i
can show you the mother plant
i've got proof so here's what i've done
i took a plant
i put it into flour for 18 days and i
pollinated it
i let that [ __ ] sit for about five
days with pollen in it
then i put it back into the veg room
under 18
6. what i know right my plant is
pregnant
and now i'm putting it back in veg
slowly over time
that plant went back into a vegetative
stage also
the seeds inside of that plant kept
maturing because
that plant didn't care if it was in
flour or if it was in veg it was already
pregnant and it was going to make seeds
so my plant is in the veg room making
seeds
about six or seven weeks into that
process i harvested all of the seeds
from that plant
as i did so i left a bunch of those new
shoots that grew out because the plant
was fully re-veging
so i just left those shoots that were
growing out and that plant is now
completely in reveg and has given me
fresh clones so i put a plant into flour
i pollinated it i moved that plant back
into a veg room
i harvested that plant for all of its
seeds that plant is now a mother plant
that has been giving me clones
which are now back into the flower room
being pollinated
all over again i was able to pollinate
my plant
harvest seeds from it preserve the
genetics and create more clones from the
same
plant and once this plant grows out big
enough i will put it back
in the flower room and pollinate it one
more time because i've got a clone from
it and i've got a keeper and i just want
to say that i've seeded that plant
multiple times and pulled harvest from
it because it's fun
so that is a way to preserve your
genetics the main
struggle i have is preserving my
genetics i want to keep all of my plants
here they're like my babies they're my
kids they're honestly my business and my
livelihood
i want to keep my eyes on them but i
can't do it because i have to let my
other
trustworthy friends keep my veg plants
around for me my mother plants around
because i don't have the legal space
they don't want to grow they don't have
a use for it so i
help them out in certain ways and they
help me out by keeping my plants around
so
um that is one way for preservation
that's another way to do it let me get
myself on track here
one thing that low numbers really helps
is with focus
without low if i were unlimited my
breeding would be crazy i wouldn't be
focused i like the tight focus that it
gives me
i'm only allowed so many plants i can't
go too far so it keeps me really focused
on having
nothing but elite winners in my lineup
the problem is i have a hard time
testing because now i'm limited to so
many plants so if i keep six moms i can
run six seeds
so i've got to find the boys and the
girls out of those and call those
oh that's a struggle now let's talk a
little bit about
pheno hunting because if you're breeding
you're going to be pheno hunting to find
the keepers from your crosses
a lot of people like to do large
phenohunts but when you're minimized by
legal plant counts you can only run 12
at a time
what's to stop you from running 10 right
now picking the best
and then running 9 right next to it next
time and pick the best out of that batch
if it's
the one from before or a new one just
keep picking the best one every time
run 10 seeds find the alpha [ __ ]
female
run 10 more run nine more seeds and that
one next to it
and compare that one to all of them find
the best one out of it do it until you
are satisfied
and you know that you have got the gem
the female plant that you want
do that for your male plant also you
don't have to run large batches
i said batches i don't know why i said
it that way but you don't have to run
large batches in populations
to final hunt if you're limited by
numbers you can do
if you do 10 10 seed phenohunts you've
ran 100 seeds
it's going to take you a little bit more
time it's going to take but in that more
time
you're only paying attention to 10
plants at a time you can really focus
and pay attention to each one like i
said a moment ago
unlimited numbers makes it hard to pay
attention to everything
like if you've got a hundred kids
running around how do you remember all
hundred of their names if you got ten
kids you can remember all ten of their
names hopefully because i feel like i
need a [ __ ] dab mid show but i'm not
gonna press pause and take a dab we're
just gonna keep going
um so you have got to manage how you
keep your genetics you've got to focus
in something that will be really nice if
you're trapped in a small grow is you
won't get super huge with all of your
ideas and creations
you may be able to focus in and make
further filial generations instead of
just making new crosses
make a batch of seeds keep the male and
female around use the rest of your count
to plant however many seeds you've got
left if you take a male plant and a
female plant cross those make
seeds whatever your plant count is
you've got two off your count now
fill the rest of that count up with
seeds that you just made grow those
seeds out
if you want to breed again find the best
male and the best female and keep those
now maybe a time to decide if you want
the original male and female around or
if it's time to get rid of them
keep that new male and that new female
breed those together
now you've got the f2s now you've got
f2s to play with you can [ __ ] find
the male and female out of there
and keep going and keep getting rid of
the old parents as you go
or you can add new [ __ ] to the mix as
long as you keep
preservation of your old genetics in a
clone form or give them to your buddy or
learn how to reveg
you can continue your breeding projects
all right so i did say that i was going
to talk about my 12
plant breeding program and i keep
getting sidetracked let's focus in a
little bit on my 12
plant breeding project i'm allowed to
have six plants in flower and six plants
in veg
so i try to get six plants that i know
i'm going to breed with from my friends
that house my genetics
i put those into the flower room and i
get them going i put the mail in there
about 10 to 14 days before the girls i
get him started i move him way over to
the corner
then i put the five females in there and
i get them going
and then when it's pollen time i shake
that dude and i cut him down so now i've
got five in one room
that leaves me seven other plants to
play with i've got six
in the veg room already vegging so
they're about 30 days behind
my flower room so that every [ __ ] 60
days
i get to clean up the flower room spray
it down rebuild a little bit of stuff
put in new filters put in new [ __ ] and
drag new plants in there
i never miss a day if i'm on track if
i'm on cycle
if things win according to plan
sometimes plants take a little bit
longer for the plants to harden up so if
i've got a new cross that i've been
playing with i may have to wait a couple
of weeks for that one plant to finish up
before i could put new plants back into
the flower room but generally
i've got half of the room filled with
plants that are pollinated and getting
finished
and then i've got a veg room that is
filled with the other half of my plant
count that are vegging out getting
popped and twisted and
cleaned up so that when it is flower
time they are nice and ready as soon as
i harvest i clean up make sure all the
pollen is out of the room
put more plants in there and then we get
more veg plants and we start growing
them up about
14 30 days into that depending on what
i'm gonna grow
uh the main thing is just always have a
plan always know where the next plants
are coming from
always have some clones prepared if i
wasn't blessed enough to have some
friends helping me out i would probably
have to reduce
my plants to four plants in the bedroom
four
in the mother room and four in flower
which would be my 12
plant count so i would have dedicated
mother plants i'd have three females and
a male
and i would take a clone off of those
those would go into the veg room
then they would go into the flower room
and i would always have four moms
four veggies and four flowers and how i
would work that
so i'd have to be really strategic with
that that means that i would have one
boy plant
and three female plants to work with or
four females and i could just
take turns just reversing them and
pollinating them however many
combinations that would give me is that
16 or is that 32 or is it 64
i don't know dude but there's some math
to be involved in there it's 4 times 4
times four it's four times the amount of
opportunities you've got so that's a lot
of four times fours
we are way off track today all right so
since i am a commercial breeder and i'm
breeding for multiple strains that is
how i would do it
if you were a personal breeder and
you're just trying to breed for one
project
i would recommend having a male and
maybe one or two females to work with
instead of making a bunch of new crosses
work on furthering that line make that
filial generation all the way to like f5
or f6 where you can dial in the exact
traits that you want another fun thing
to do is work two lines work one line
for
smell work one line for potency work
them both to about four or five and then
breed those together and then you get
the potency and flavor you were looking
for
that's a really fun way to do it take
the a line and the b line of two of the
same crosses
work them for different traits and then
breed those together in the end
that's something a lot of people are
overlooking and forgetting about that's
when breeding gets really fun
so i've been rambling for a long time i
hope i answered your question about
small-scale breeding at home mainly
focus on
keeping the genetics you you want to
breed that [ __ ] again so have the
genetics then leave yourself some room
for veg plants and flowering plants
and then also you may need to eliminate
plants in the future so that you can
sprout some of the seeds
that you have produced it's always a
challenge testing your new stuff because
we just want to
sprout a hundred of them and that's when
we start getting in trouble so
i hope i answered your question if
you've got any more questions i do look
forward to hearing from you
you can hit me back again on cano buzz
or the preferred method is to send me an
email my email address is grow from your
heart
at hotmail.com all right ladies and
gentlemen boys and girls pimps and hoes
friends and foes smokers and growers
clone cutters and paul and chuckers i
want to thank you again for listening to
another episode of the grow from your
heart podcast
if you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
and you'd like to make a financial
contribution to the show
all you have to do is visit www.patreon
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you will need will be
right there on the screen and of course
i did include that link
in the show notes to make it easy for my
stoner
friends don't forget to visit our
sponsors at seedshearnow.com and use
coupon code gfyh10 while checking out to
save a few bucks also don't forget to
check out that under 30 tab
there are some irie genetic strains in
the under 30 section
get yourself some cream for 30 bucks
upgrade your garden
improve your performance i don't know
what that even means if you've got any
questions corrections or concerns i
would love to hear from you my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
don't be shy send me some messages also
don't forget about the t-shirts on the
etsy store we've got the lemon jeffrey
shirts we've got the orange gasm shirts
and coming soon that golden goat shirt
will be available
check that out go to etsy and search for
irie gifts
llc i'll pop right up you'll see the
shirts get some
look good all right podcast roll that's
all i've got for you for today i'll be
back in just a couple of days with fresh
new content
i want to give a giant shout out to my
friend mason hines and until next time
take a fat dab and give your mom a hug
for me
you