[Music]
welcome back podcast world i'm your host
my friends call me rosta jeff and it is
time for episode 574 of the grow from
your heart podcast
this episode of the show is brought to
you by our friends at seedshearnow.com
seedshearnow.com offers seats from all
of the industries
leading breeders including miss jill
genetics duke diamond and of course irie
genetics
everything at seeds herenow.com is
backed by their award-winning
satisfaction guarantee
and for my friends on a tight budget
seeds herenow.com offers several packs
for under 30 dollars
as well as amazing monthly sales
make sure to use coupon code gfyh10
while checking out to save a few bucks
again that is coupon code gfyh10 while
checking out
at seeds here now dot
com you know i like to start this
podcast off by talking about what i'm
smoking
today i've been taking dabs of fatso og
number one full spectrum extract this is
a blend of gmo and legend og
on the package the flavor is described
as dark roast garlic
and fuel i completely agree with that i
completely love that flavor description
i love that type of flavor and aroma on
my tongue makes my taste buds happy
and i really love the nice buzz it's
kind of a heavy buzz it's got my eyes
nice and heavy it's got me chilled out
in my chair
really digging the buzz from the fatso
og on the back of the package it says it
contains 82.68
thc and non-detectable amounts of cbd
big shout out to fatso for making
perfect podcast
concentrate all right in this episode
i'm going to read a few messages from
patreon
before we get there let's do some shout
outs to a few of the folks who support
the show on patreon
let's start off with the big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to papa z
i want to send a big thank you shout out
to kurt z i've always got a big thank
you shout out for aaron
let's send a big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to the
captain and commander of the 710 club
let's send a big thank you shout out to
lemur priest
i want to send a big thank you shout out
to ez057
let's send a big special thank you shout
out to girls grow 2.
i want to send a special thank you and a
fist bump to blackbird 76.
i've always got a thank you shout out
for tonto's garden let's send a big
thank you shout out to canadareaper413
and last but certainly not least i want
to send a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to smoke what
thank you guys for all of the support
big thanks big shout out to everybody
who continues to support the show on
patreon
if you're not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need is right
there on the screen of course i did
include a link in the show notes to make
it nice and easy for everybody
who's busy got your hands full maybe
you're driving
don't wreck the car to sign up for
patreon but don't forget
patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all right where are we going
next we are going to talk about these
fancy shirts the last time we spoke i
had a couple of shirts available
there are now at the time of this
episode is being recorded there are
three shirts available on my etsy store
if you go to i've actually if you visit
iriegenetics.com and click on the store
tab
that will take you directly to my etsy
store that website is under construction
but the store
tab is functioning it is
iriegenetics.com
click on the store tab or simply go to
etsy search for irie gifts llc that will
get you there
i'm about to show you the fancy shirts
last time i think i showed you let's
recap what we showed last time and build
suspense that's always fun
if you're watching on the video show on
youtube like i encourage you get to see
the
lemon jeffree t-shirts what i'm holding
up now is a small
that is a small shirt just so you know
what size i'm playing with that is the
lemon jeffree shirt
the next one i'm going to show the
camera will be the orange gasm shirt
again i'm showing the camera a small
just in case you're judging what size
maybe you should buy
that is a small orange gasm shirt it's
got the orange gasm logo says irie
genetics on it
all of these shirts are they do have the
words irie genetics on them so it's got
my brand listed on there but they are
not blatantly cannabis they don't have
weed leaves or anything like that
they do have the orange for orange gasm
and the lemon for lemon jeffrey on there
one of my buttons on my shirt popped
open as i was showing you that we're
getting a little a little risque here
uh but anyway uh it's got the logo on
there this one may be my favorite i
thought the lemon jeffrey would be my
favorite i thought the orange gasm would
be my favorite they all battled for
favorites
but the look on this little goat's face
this golden goat shirt
i'm loving the look on the goat's face
he just looks nice and stone his little
stoned goat
that is the golden goat shirt
once again the shirt that i showed the
camera was a small so if you guys are
looking for the shirts once again
they are on iregenetics.com click on the
store tab i do apologize the website is
under construction
give me three or four weeks and that
website will impress you
big shout out to my friend who was
working on it we've had a couple of
meetings
uh both of us are doing late night
meetings trying to get this website
going we're both uh
stone and half asleep trying to
communicate on a website we're getting
it going
be patient with us anyhow
iriegenetics.com click on the store tab
that will get you to the store
or simply visit etsy.com search for irie
gifts llc you'll see the shirts grab one
get styled out then send me a picture of
yourself in the shirt when i send it to
you i want to see what you look like and
give me permission to share it or tell
me do or do not share this
i'll post it up to social media you'll
get some followers and i'll get to share
what the shirts look like on people all
right
let's move forward ladies and gentlemen
where are we gonna go from here like
axel rose said
where do we go now i think this is the
part of the show where we jump into
reading patreon messages
i've got a great big stack of emails and
messages here in front of me
let's not waste too much more time with
my stone rambles and let's get right
into it the first couple are going to be
from patreon
they're going to be mainly compliments
and praise then we're going to move into
some grow
questions uh this one comes from smoke
j smokey j and it goes just like this i
just got my mail from seeds herenow.com
that was the eg easiest purchase i have
ever made
i just got some shredder raphael and sun
kiss from you
uh that is a nice lineup dude you got
the shredder for that like lemony and
funky terps raphael for that strawberry
stuff and sun kiss for the orange terps
you were gonna be a happy camper in a
few weeks here it goes on to say
i'm very excited to get them started
also the five pack of sun kiss
actually had seven seeds in there you
guys i didn't make this message up this
came from an actual patreon subscriber
who bought seeds and was
extremely happy with their experience
they found seven seeds in their five
pack
i'm not going to say you're going to
find five in yours but sometimes that
happens if i'm in a good mood and we're
packing up seeds
and i know that i'm going to have enough
seeds to fill the amount of packages i
made
i may just go put extra seeds in there
just to make sure you're happy
i know you guys work really hard for
your money money's expensive time is
expensive
the whole time you're at work you're
away from whatever it is that makes you
happy
most of us aren't as blessed as myself i
love my job i've built a career for
myself i love this most of us aren't
that blessed you got to go somewhere and
listen to some [ __ ] tell you what to
do all day you don't want to do that all
day
you got to be away from your xbox you
got to be away from your loved ones you
got to be away from your puppy you got
to be away from pornhub whatever it is
that's got your attention
you can't [ __ ] do that because you're
working for some [ __ ] all day just
for enough money to barely get by
and then you got to work a few weeks and
save up a few weeks so you could buy
some seeds i understand i get it
i want you to be happy i want you to set
yourselves up for success when you get
the seeds
i do what i can to make sure you were
successful if you get
seven in a pack that's almost like 30
it's almost 50
extra for free right i'm not good at
math that quickly but i know that money
is expensive i know that being away from
home to make money sucks you want to be
with your family your puppy your plants
your [ __ ] xbox whatever else you got
at home going on you want to be there
or maybe you just want to be on the road
doing something else i want to be at a
fish show having a good time maybe you
want to be
seeing whatever band you want to see
either way money is expensive and i
appreciate that you trust me and spend
your money
on my brand with me that means a lot to
me so i make sure to make sure that you
are happy it's a
it's a good symbiosis you guys are going
to stay happy you keep me happy
thank you so you found seven seeds in
there you're very welcome
make me proud when you grow those i want
to see pictures if you've got a friend
who is in need that wants to grow that
has never grown before that's got some
space
maybe you could be a nice guy and pass
on those extra two beans
get your friend growing see if they find
a winner also we're gonna keep going it
says
you're an inspiration to me to better my
grow and better myself
thanks again so much from smokey j
smokey j thank you this is a two-way
relationship uh if i just did podcasts
and made seeds that weren't quality and
nobody enjoyed it nobody appreciated it
i would probably be i think it'd be a
mental hospital if i set this gear up
twice a week and just did this and
nobody cared
that would be a sign of psycho or
psychotic or some weirdness and i would
need
medication and a padded room so it's a
two-way street thank you man and also
the seed business is the same if i was
just making seeds and selling them and
nobody
purchased them nobody cared about them
i'd be hungry so thank you i do
appreciate your trust
and uh your your faith in me and my
brand so thank you dude i appreciate
that
i'm [ __ ] rambling i love it when i
get talkative like this because it makes
good podcasts
but i've got to keep moving uh big shout
out to smoke
uh smokey j and thank you for the
patreon support
this one comes from do they want their
name said
yes it says right in the beginning it
says hey rosta jeff
somebody needs to write that song hey
arrested jeff it'll get going
uh my name is brad good to meet you brad
i'm rosta jeff it says i've been
listening every week for about two years
now
and i'm almost mostly caught up with
your back catalog too
man that's 573 episodes you've listened
to
i would be sick of my own voice by now
thank you i hope you've learned a lot
and i'm sure you've got some questions
by now and i hope you've heard the
progression of the show
uh this show has changed evolved morphed
rotated a lot i used to do segments and
[ __ ] at the beginning
i used to type out almost everything i
was going to say throughout the entire
show would be written
and i would sit here and read a script
this is how i recommend you transplant
plants first you want to place your hand
on top of the soil and gently grip the
stem
then turn the pot upside down and shake
it gently until the pot comes out
like i was [ __ ] i was robotic it
wasn't as much fun
i took a while to get comfortable doing
this look at me now i got like four
notes and i just ramble this is a lot of
fun now
so thank you for uh watching my journey
all of you thank you for watching the
evolution the journey the progression of
the podcast
and if you listened through the episodes
when i had my head injury
uh i apologize and thank you there were
some episodes you guys in about
uh 2015 around april i think it was
i hit my head and some of the episodes
are [ __ ] goofy i tried to keep going
uh i wasn't all there and people were
emailing me saying hey what the [ __ ] are
you saying on this episode bro and i was
like i don't even know
i really couldn't tell you either so uh
thank you guys for being patient with me
and dealing with me through that
let's get me back on track this guy's
been listening for two years caught up
on the back catalog keep up the good
work the shows keep getting better so
you were paying attention thank you
i'm getting better at speaking getting
better at podcasting more comfortable
with this microphone
and also i'm becoming a better grower
i'm experienced and exposed to more [ __ ]
every time i go to a grow to a facility
i still troll the internet like i used
to to read what's going on and grows
i'm still watching all the hot breeders
trying to better myself every day if i
stop then you guys will beat me and
you'll be way ahead of me and there'll
be no reason for me to have a show so
i gotta stay training too or the sensei
sensei will get passed up by the student
uh it says i've been a patreon
contributor for a year now but i want to
step it up to the 710 club
ah thank you i appreciate that don't
anybody out there don't feel like you
have to contribute or you have to step
up your contributions that is a
voluntary thing that i love and
appreciate
if you can't do it somebody out there
will cover it for you our friend brad
here just covered a couple of people for
the month you guys get to listen and
enjoy it
if you can't afford or support the
patreon uh just tell a friend to listen
to the show
anyway brad thank you for catching up on
all the episodes that is a lot of clicks
wherever you're listening
uh you've increased my listens by 500 if
you're listening on stitcher or apple
podcast or youtube
i got 500 clicks out of you and that
really moves the show along
makes it more available on algorithms so
that's awesome thank you
and thank you for the support and thank
you for mentioning that the show
keeps getting better brad did write a
quite lengthy email we're not going to
read it all here on the episode but it
says
the last two guys coughing was a great
show i always enjoy when white mike
comes on
and you guys talk about the industry and
history you hear that mike
they enjoy our rambles so we need you to
come back soon
uh you don't have to come back just to
do the legalization part two come hang
out again mike you're always invited
uh this guy loves your company then it
says your recent episode on making fem
seeds was also very interesting
i like it when you get into some more of
the more unique topics
i'm glad you're paying attention thank
you i don't know if some of those
in-depth lessons lose people or if you
guys care or not so i love feedback
thank you
also goes on to say i also enjoy the
shows when jesse
is on i'm sure he's getting into crunch
time with his grows this time of year
uh there's a lot more of this message
but i wanted to cover the first uh
crucial and important topics a couple of
compliments and
invitations for my friends to come back
yes jesse is a busy man
i'm not even sure where jesse is right
now jesse could be in mexico jesse could
be in oklahoma
he could be in colorado he could be down
the street from me i'm not sure where
the dude is
he moves around a lot shout out to jesse
um
i like what i've got but sometimes jesse
i'm [ __ ] jealous of your lifestyle
bro
you're like i'm like what are you doing
tomorrow like i'm flying to tulsa and
i'm like oh we'll come over the next day
you're like
oh i'm going to mexico for three days
after that and then i'll be back and i'm
like what are you even doing bro but i
love it i love it
that carefree floaty lifestyle is
[ __ ] awesome but mike and jesse this
isn't
an official formal invitation this
listener wants you guys back on the show
so
come on the show gentlemen whether it's
here in person whether it's zoom
you guys are invited i want you on the
show all right
brad i want to thank you for the long
message it wraps up with
uh anyway thanks for reading anyway
thanks for reading my long message i
don't know what my mouth said but my
brain didn't make it right there
anyway thanks for reading my long
message not really any questions here
but if you choose to read this on one of
your feedback shows
there you go buddy you got in the
feedback portion of this show you can
use brad
that is also fine for the 710 shout out
big shout out to our new
friend brad for supporting the show with
the 710 level or higher
then it says i hope i can meet you at an
event someday when this is all over
have a great podcast from brad hey brad
thank you
i hope that when this is over we do get
to meet at the dude grows cup
or maybe at a uh uh one of the events
i'm not even gonna start listing them
cause i'm just gonna get heartbroken
that none of them are happening
oh brad thank you for the great message
bro we're gonna keep moving forward
i've got another message this one is all
thanks and praise for the podcast this
comes from jay
tapa and it says your grow lessons
deserve my patronage i get more
impressed with you every day roster jeff
thank you wow that means a lot to me i
don't know that i'm aiming to impress
i like that i do impress that feels
[ __ ] good it wasn't my goal i'm
coming out here to give you a quality
podcast and improve your grow
so i'm glad that you're impressed and
thank you for the patronage
my grow lessons earned that patronage
thank you very much if you ever have any
questions or anything like that please
feel free to reach out and ask your
questions
uh big shout out to our friend jay toppa
all right we've got one more excuse me i
hope you didn't hear that come through
the microphone we're gonna take a drink
and make sure that doesn't happen again
thanks for hanging out you guys this is
a fun episode it's going really well for
me
i feel like i was going way too fast in
the last podcast episode i don't know
what
whatever i smoked before the show just
made my brain spin i couldn't keep up
with my own brain so
thank you for all the compliments on the
last episode i feel like this one's
going much more smoothly from
for me
get a little hydration going on and we
will continue with the show
i'm not even going to edit this part out
it's like you're hanging out with me
thank you for being here
uh also thank you for all the
compliments on the new studio space
slash office space i took your advice i
put a light in front of me
i can already tell the difference on the
camera there are
new toys coming in the works i need some
time to go shopping i want to look at
some new gear i'm going to buy some new
[ __ ] and do some cool stuff for you guys
i appreciate
you watching i appreciate how many
people have been joining on and
following the videos following the audio
show
i owe it to you to kind of upgrade the
show a little bit all the patreon
contributions will make that easy there
will be a new camera coming there will
be some lighting coming
i may get a new microphone this one
sounds good right i've been looking at
the sm7b i'd love to have it it looks
nice and professional but
this thing does it bro i sound pretty
good i think
anyway i should quit rambling and focus
on this or again we're going to have a
real long episode and that thing i just
said about doing a great show is not
going to count anymore
let's keep moving you guys this one
comes from our good friend tanto's
garden what up tonto always good to hear
from you big brother
uh this message goes like this hey let
me move it this way so i can look toward
the camera a little bit
i'm currently taking in as much
information as my brain will handle on
breeding right now
i just finished episode 331 and had
someone email
on how you and cannabis has impacted
them yes in some episodes people
message me and let me know how cannabis
has impacted their lives
and it said uh i hadn't done so in a
while so i thought i
would i love this type of feedback from
my listeners it goes on to say
i'm a proud veteran of princess
patricia's canadian light
infantry or ppcli for short
who sustained both physical and mental
injuries during
my service my condition affected me
in my everyday life in one way or
another which cannabis
has helped with immensely i will start
by thanking you for putting all that
information effort and your own time
plus guests
on the internet for free of charge there
is so much to unpack here first of all
thank you for your service i'm not in
canada but still
you're a soldier you put yourself out
there and you've been injured
mentally and physically uh maybe not
fighting for my country but for your
country and that is commendable and
respectable
i you can tell by looking at me i'm not
soldier material
i would probably [ __ ] out and cry to be
quite honest with you they start
shooting at me
i'm gonna [ __ ] duck and cry and hope
you've got my back so thank you
for having people's backs that is not
meant for me i'm not
i'm not for war i'm not for battle i'm
not for there
doesn't need to be any bloodshed and
killing and [ __ ] we should all [ __ ]
smoke some dabs and have a good time
i understand the world doesn't [ __ ]
work like that so there needs to be
unfortunately there needs to be somebody
protecting my high ass
and i appreciate that you're out there
doing it because uh back in the day they
just find [ __ ] to do it and i'm
tall and slender and healthy and smart
and [ __ ]
fast and agile guess what i'd be at war
and just you and go shoot people i'd be
like ah
no i'd be nope not for me so thank you i
do appreciate it and i do respect it um
i'll never disrespect a soldier or
anything like that so thank you
let me find my place in this message i
wanted to make sure to catch up on that
um and thank you for putting your life
on the line and getting injured man
i'm sorry for that anyway and you're
welcome for all of the free information
i feel like
i owe this i don't know what that even
means but it comes out of me naturally i
was
compelled to do a podcast it felt like i
owed the world to do it i try not to
bring
my religious or my faithful talk into
this too much but
when josh says some stuff i've got to
listen and josh said
rosta jeff do a podcast and teach all
the people how to grow weed because they
love the way you grow weed and they love
your photography
why would you keep that to yourself send
them home so they grow wheat just as
good as yours
and i went okay and i bought gear and i
have a podcast it just it came out of me
playing the drums happens the same way
jaw says
what if you put the beats here instead
of doing it this way and i go yeah i'm
going to do that and [ __ ] works for me
when i listen to jaw follow jaws
guidance and give thanks for it and
don't
stray too far things go really well so
uh this podcast comes
it has to happen i do it i think i'd
like spontaneously combust or melt down
or something
if i didn't do this podcast so it just
it's got to be free
it's for the people uh it's karmic i
don't know i've got to be doing it so
thank you for noticing that i'm doing it
and i'm putting my
heart and soul into it my time and
energy and it's free
i do ask for patreon contributions but i
don't put the show behind a paywall even
if you can't help me on patreon you
still get it the people on patreon
are they're in a position where they
can't help and they do that i understand
how that goes
i want it free i'm [ __ ] rambling
today let's keep going it says
um free of charge without this podcast i
don't know if i would have taken the
plunge
into growing also you've given me
passion and some purpose through growing
this hobby of growing and cannabis has
had such a profound
positive impact on getting my health and
my life back together
that makes all of the money i spent on
all this equipment right here all the
time i spent today setting up the time i
spent trying to balance this [ __ ]
light on the edge of my desk right here
those couple of sentences make all of
this effort worth it
there's somebody out there who soldiers
i hate to even
go down this thought but soldiers take
their own lives people who are in this
type of position if they don't have
something to live for
if they don't have a positive they cling
to the negative and they take their own
lives we may
i don't want to judge my friend here but
we're giving this person
positive light at the end of a dark dark
[ __ ] tunnel and that feels really
good
it says we've given him passion and
purpose uh that's what people need
without passion and purpose we get
lonely and dark and depressed
passion and purpose are what we live for
that's what keeps you inspired and
without passion and purpose your [ __ ]
couch potato right
uh so we've given our friend passion and
purpose through growing cannabis
the hobby of growing cannabis has had a
profound impact
on health and life mental physical
spiritual uh you feel better because
you're spending time with your plants
you're in there
when you're spending time with the
plants you got to think about them you
have to pay attention to them so you
can't
think about the post-traumatic stress
that's in the mind you've got to focus
on the plants
so you're thinking about the plants
you're getting away from the ptsd
then you've got an outcome that you can
be proud of you're proud of that
then you get to smoke that outcome now
you're stoned
and now the ptsd the problems that's all
gone and guess what we get to wake up
tomorrow
and go back in the garden and do it all
over again now since we're feeling
better
spending time away from our own thoughts
spending time in the garden we start
feeling better
consuming a product that makes us feel
better getting a better attitude
now maybe we can have better
relationships with people simple things
like that will compound
maybe maybe after a few months you'll
develop a really
maybe that guy at the store that you
just keep your hat down because you
don't want to deal with the [ __ ]
cashier at the store
maybe you'll say hey thank you have a
good day and they'll go damn that guy
just told me to have a good day
nobody's told me to have a good day all
day and instead of yelling at their wife
when they get home they'll go
hey honey i brought you a snickers bar
ripples you guys
ripples i know i got rambly there but
that's how small ripples [ __ ] happen
let's get [ __ ] focused here uh
profound impact
on getting your life and health back
together thank you i love hearing stuff
like that
it says the next thing to tell you is
that i have provided that you have
provided a positive impact both on my
mental health and
my garden there are days where a hole of
depression
has sucked me so far down that i don't
even have the willpower
to go water my plants but this is where
your little voice little voice bro i
gotta turn up my microphone i'm just
picking on you brother
uh this is where my little voice pops
into your head it says
roster jeff says be the best grower i
can be and i do my best
and that will be all the thanks he needs
i love that dude i love that i always
say if you can't help me out on patreon
just take care of your plants the best
you can make your plants happy
love them for me that is free this guy's
doing it sometimes that ptsd and
depression can be a [ __ ] trust me
i come on here and i smile when i had
that head injury there were terrible
thoughts in my head i couldn't deal with
what my brain was doing to me there were
dark dark alleys that i didn't want to
go down
without good friends i may have
journeyed down some of those alleys
without my mama having my back without
mike checking on me without all the
other people that were around loving me
things may have not have been as pretty
as they came out so
depression ptsd can be a hell of a [ __ ]
i get it
when you hear my little voice in there
and you go bro let's go water those
plants
these plants are going to make you so
happy just go water the plants
i love that that gets you up and gets
you moving thank you i love that
good work soldier where are we now uh
ross jeff says water the plants
ah let's see that is all the motivation
i need
that i sometimes begin to the long crawl
out of that hole i hope on those days
you feel that extra positivity vibe
coming through the universe
so thank you for being such a positive
support to the community and to those
like me bro this is
probably my favorite email i've gotten
in a long time and i've gotten some
pretty cool messages
it's gonna go on there is more it says
there are people who go through life not
knowing
that they have truly impacted someone's
life and also potentially push them onto
a different
path cannabis and you have potentially
given me
that push and have helped me during my
long road of rehab over the last couple
of years
so what path you have possibly sent me
down i'm currently upgrading my high
school courses
to possibly go into a program for
microbiology at a
at a local college bro our friend here
was having a hard time
struggling and is now going uh
upgrading high school courses and
possibly going to a program for
microbiology
we're sparking brains and changing
futures here at the show you guys this
is amazing
i didn't realize that my push was going
this far i'm not going to let it go to
my head i'm going to let it go to my
heart
thank you taunto this is [ __ ] awesome
i wish you all the best
if i can do anything else if you have
any specific help that i can offer you
send me a message let me know i'd be
honored to help you out stay in school
uh don't be a fool uh do good man go to
micro micro by
microbiology college i can't even say
the word you're going to school for it
uh he wraps it up with i will end this
with i want you to know that you have
made a difference in someone's life
thank you for being an educator
podcaster grower friend
breeder and a good human being
from tonto tonto thank you
thank you so much brother these messages
mean a lot to me uh
i jokingly wrote that this message is
like recharge
for my soul it's like you just gave me
my weekly dose of recharge
and i want to grow vigorously um man
this is awesome
i am uh one click of emotions away from
a small tear in my eye to tell you the
honest truth this is a [ __ ] amazing
message
i feel it in my heart it's recharging me
thank you this is inspiring and keeps me
going you guys this is what makes me do
a free podcast
feedback like this tonto thank you fist
bump
handshake uh salute however you want to
do it bro thank you
i respect you and appreciate your
support all right i want to keep moving
because i've got a lot of messages i
don't even know how long i've been going
doesn't really matter we're just going
to keep going i'm the boss i didn't say
we had to quit yet
it's a good show we're having fun look
good feel good let's keep moving
this is more of a grow question i feel
like i've moved into the grow
question part of the stack i want to
move that message out of there so you
guys can't read my scribbles on there
yeah i'm insecure about my handwriting
on that paper that's my business
thank you for hanging out guys we've
gotten so comfortable together i hope
you're as comfortable with me as i am
with you by now
574 episodes what a [ __ ] party this
message comes from our friend riley in
illinois and it says what up rosta jeff
this is riley from illinois back with
yet
another question don't be shy bro i love
answering your questions
it says thanks again for all of your
help with my previous question
i had a hermaphrodite and it was likely
caused by an extension cord
that has an orange light up tip
ah that's possible that's possible if
that much
light caused that plant to hurt i would
just get rid of those genetics
that's too uh that's too finicky anyway
and i know what you mean sometimes those
extension cords have the orange light up
tips you can find it in the dark and you
know where to plug in
i know what you mean but i would i'd
still reconsider
anyway it says i sprayed the room down
and my next crop is looking beautiful
with no
intersex plants yet yeah keep an eye on
them bro
keep an eye on them um hopefully you
don't have that problem again
hopefully you've gotten rid of that
extension cord hopefully you checked
that there were no light leaks
let's stay focused there is a brand new
question it says i do have another
question for you
i accidentally left my uv supplement
light on
overnight how long does it typically
take for plants to show hermaphroditic
traits
uh will one day of uv being on for 16
hours while all
of the other lights off caused this
plant to herm
i'm sure you can't say 100 as there are
many other factors that can be at play
but
any of your advice is greatly
appreciated let me write down a note
that i forgot to write
oh okay there we go notes on the fly um
so
our friend riley here has left his uv
light on for 16 hours that means it was
on
your plants if you're in flower let's
see if you're if you're in veg this is
not a problem if you're in flower
um i'm not sure why it was on for 16
extra hours you got a 12 12 cycle it
should have gone off
anyway the light stayed on that's the
bottom line here we had a uv light stay
on
honestly i am not educated
in uv lighting when it comes to cannabis
growing cultivation
cannabis production commercial growing
feeding plants loving plants knowing
plants
i will say that lighting is my weakest
part of that whole subject
i know the plants very well i can look
at plants and tell you what's wrong with
them
i can breed plants i can fix grow rooms
i am
a little bit uneducated as not as
educated as i should be
when it comes to grow lights and grow
light technology all those graphs and
things my brain
honestly my brain just isn't interested
i want to learn about it my brain goes
nah let's go look at microbes or
something so i go read about microbes
that's i could do that i probably
shouldn't but
that's what my brain chooses to do and
then we let guys like keith from
blacksail big shout out to keith from
blacksail let's get you on the show bro
come talk on my show about the mccree
curve
and teach me about lighting and help me
understand lighting a little bit better
that's my official invite to you keith
i'll reach out via text here this week
and try to get you on the show
but honestly i'm not educated in
lighting so i don't know enough about
specifically uvs to talk
i'm going to talk about plants in
general
uh this is going to be very very plant
specific very cultivar specific i don't
know
what plant you're working with you may
have multiple plants in the room
some will react differently than others
to this
light era this is basically the same as
a light leak you had light interruptions
during your dark period
this could cause problems so it's going
to be very plant specific
i would watch four problems uh watch and
see if you see male flowers popping up
on
any branches of your plants look on the
top branches look on the lower
branches don't just look at the tops and
think you're okay look down in the lower
part of the plant where you don't get a
lot of light
look and see if you've got male flowers
popping up out of those buds anywhere on
that plant look very carefully on all
the plants that are in there
watch for intersex traits watch for male
flowers
um check now and then also keep checking
throughout the entire grow cycle they
may take a little bit to pop up that is
one of your major parts of this question
how long until they pop up you may never
see male flowers you may never see
pollen sacks you may never see anthers
but you may get seeds at the end so
it is hard to guess you may not know
exactly what happened until you harvest
and cut them down and see what you've
got
you're gonna have to chop it down and
when you're trimming it you'll know if
there are seeds in there
you'll start seeing buds with the
calyxes are just extra swollen there's a
seed inside of there drop those seeds
out
see what you've got um then
uh watch for seeds if you've got seeds
in there i would say grow some of the
seeds that's gonna be fun you may
have just accidentally made a bunch of
seeds for yourself to play with
um don't sell the seeds if you did make
seeds
don't be that guy that decides to sell
them do not sell these seeds these are
accidental seeds they're not made for
the market they're made for you
possibly some of your grow friends if
you've got some friends that need some
seeds
you can donate these seeds to them if
they come with a solid
disclaimer hey these were accidental
light leak seeds i don't know if these
are going to be
hermaphrodites if they're going to be
feminized seeds or if they're going to
be
wild mutants they could be anything
they've got a lot of potential
to be problematic they've also got a lot
of potential to be real [ __ ] hitters
um i wrote down gorilla glue number four
was an
accidental pollination that made a
champion of course that was a male
female cross to the best of my knowledge
but it was an
accident golden goat was an accident
of course that was a male female
pollination again an accident
girl scout cookies there's a lot of
controversy around the girl scout
cookies line i think girl scout cookies
was bag seed i don't think anybody
really knows what happened
but if it was bag seed that's the same
as what you've got see they came from
buds and we don't know where it came
from and it grew out to be
the biggest [ __ ] trend in cannabis
for several years
a lot of the controversy in cannabis is
around that strain still is i don't even
know what the real cross of it is
so there you go cookies got real popular
and it was bag seed
now let's talk about the entire chem dog
family was bag seed so that was some of
the most amazing herb ever found
chem 91 kim four kim d kim's sister
excuse me all the subsequent chem
crosses that came from there
all of those chem crosses came from one
bag of weed
if you don't know what the story of chem
dog and the legend of the 13 beans that
is something that you should research
if you consider yourself a cannabis
historian or someone that's really
interested in cannabis if you're a weed
nerd
chem dog and the legend of the 13 beans
kem bought some weed there were 13 seeds
in there
he grew a few of them that's where the
chem dog lineage came from that was bag
seed
if there are seeds in your bud they are
bag seed
like i said a moment ago they've got the
potential to be the next chem 91 the
next gorilla glue number four
or they can also be the next thing that
[ __ ] up your garden and wreak havoc
in your grow room so if you did make
those seeds grow them yourself and see
what you've got
maybe you've got some fun in there maybe
you've got some problems it's always fun
to grow seeds that you made
even if it was an accident so i know you
want to know
how long until you're gonna see herm uh
seven to ten days probably maybe 14 days
maybe a little bit later it all depends
on how those plants react i'm not sure
what cuts you've got in there i'm not
sure how sensitive they are to light i'm
not sure what their critical periods are
i'm not sure excuse me i'm not sure who
bred them i don't know what's up with
those plants so i don't want to give you
any false hope but look out for seeds
look out for problems and just pay close
attention
i'm going to take a drink and then i've
got one more thing to ramble about
on this message
if they are seated they are not a total
loss first you've got a bunch of seeds
to play with as a breeder that's fun
even if they're not
available for a market or something you
want to sell grow them see what you've
got run ten of them
run them in beer cups put them in a beer
cup veg them out until they're
three and three quarters inches tall the
size of a gi joe and then put them into
flour and see what you get
they could be [ __ ] awesome they could
be total [ __ ] but if they're in a beer
cup they're only 10 of them you're only
wasting so much space
find out what you've got they could be
really [ __ ] cool now if they are
seated you can still uh i wouldn't want
to really smoke the flour if it's seeded
you can but you got to clean the [ __ ]
seeds out of the flour before you smoke
it that's a pain in the ass that's like
old school back in the day we don't need
to do that
but you can process and use seeded herbs
you can extract it you can make edibles
out of it
uh you can make bubble hash out of it if
you find out there's seeds in there
running through the bubble bags
you're just gonna separate the seeds and
everything just like you normally would
the seeds are gonna be right there in
the mix you can still make bubble out of
it
you can also still make bho if you're
one of those guys that is still running
bho you can absolutely make
bho out of seeded products so you can
make bho
uh grind it up pull the seeds out or
just pack the [ __ ] seeded buds into
the tube and extract it just like that
or if you're making diamonds and sauce
do your method with the seeded product
just get the seeds out or don't that is
up to you
one thing i'd recommend though do not
press it if there's seeds in there
that's probably obvious to most people
but to some people i am not certain that
that's obvious
let's not go pressing uh the seated butt
it'll blow up like popcorn
it'll be like when you used to smoke a
seed in the joint you don't want to do
that
so it is not a total loss even if it is
seeded sorry i'm making myself a edit
note uh it is not a total loss even if
it is
seeded uh you can still make bubble hash
you can make bho you can make butters
you could probably make salves and
topicals and whatever else you want to
do with it
but don't press it because you don't
want blowing up seeds like a
popcorn bowl so i wish i could give you
better advice i wish i could tell you
exactly when they're going to herm if
they are going to her but i don't know
that that's going to happen
my best advice is keep an eye on each
and every single plant
look at every plant every day pay
attention look at the top look in the
middle
absolutely look at the bottom when
you're doing work in there
just look around at the plants do what i
call the growers gaze just stare at them
just slowly look across the room and
you'll go oh [ __ ] there it is and you'll
see that intersex
trait popping up on one of your plants
that's how you're going to find it
if you do find it i'm hoping you don't
to tell you the truth all right riley
i've been rambling for quite a few
minutes on your message i'm going to
move forward i want to thank you again
for the great message
and i look forward to hearing from you
again in the future
all right ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls pimps and hoes friends and foes
smokers and growers clone cutters and
pollen chuckers all you beautiful
[ __ ] out there
i've been going for close to 40 minutes
so it is time to wrap up this podcast i
want to thank you again for hanging out
if you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
and you'd like to make a financial
contribution to the show
of course you can do so by visiting
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information
you need is right there on the screen
also don't forget to grab yourself an
irie genetics t-shirt
i will put a link to the store and the
show notes and the video description
uh make sure you check out our sponsor
at seedshearnow.com use coupon code
gfyh10 while checking out to save a few
bucks
also don't forget to check out that
under 30 section you can get yourself a
pack of irie genetics
the cream is available for 30
uh what else do we got make sure to
check out cannabis cannabis is a free
social media application for your
android or apple device
it works a lot like the other social
media applications except
we encourage and promote you to post
your cannabis related content
you cannot buy sell or trade cannabis on
cannabis but you can post your photos
you can post your dab videos you can
post your bong rip videos
you can do your silly duck face dab
videos out there if that's what you're
into
and we will not make fun of you we will
not delete your account we will do
not delete your posts we will not
persecute or prosecute you for being a
cannabis enthusiast on cannabis
we want you to come hang out join
cannabis it's a free application give it
a download create yourself an account
find me i'm irie underscore genetics on
cannabis come join
the cannabis community big shout out to
j.r token and q for keeping that app
running
nothing but love and respect for both of
those fellas everybody over there thank
you guys
what else do we got for you an email if
you have got corrections questions
comments or concerns i'd love to hear
from you the email address is grow from
your heart
at hotmail.com i think that's all i've
got for you for this episode
i want to thank you once again for
hanging out i'll be back in just a
couple of days with fresh new content
i'm going to give a giant shout out to
my friend greg walker and until next
time take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me