hey everyone it's three tokes and you're
tuned in to the grow from your heart
podcast
[Music]
welcome to the show podcast world i'm
your host my friends call me rasta jeff
and it is time for episode 575 of the
grow from your heart podcast
this episode of the show is brought to
you by our friends at seedshearnow.com
seedshearnow.com carries seats from all
the industries
leading breeders including miss jill
genetics duke diamond and of course irie
genetics
everything at seedshearnow.com is backed
by their award-winning satisfaction
guarantee
and for my friends on a tight budget
seedshearnow.com offers several packs
for under thirty dollars
as well as amazing monthly sales make
sure to use coupon code gfyh10 while
checking out to save a few bucks
again that is coupon code gfyh10
while checking out at seeds here now
dot com you know i like to start this
podcast off by talking about what i'm
smoking
today i've been taking dabs of bananas
foster live
batter this is a blend of banana og and
paris larry
on the package the flavor is described
as banana sugar
and oatmeal i think i agree with that
that's a really unique combination of
flavors
sort of like a banana sugar cookie or
something like that it's got that
candied banana flavor and there's
definitely a sweetness maybe an oatmeal
cookie aftertaste
i really love the banana terps and the
buzz i get from banana
flavored dabs on the back of the package
it says it contains
67.49 thc and non-detectable amounts of
cbd big shout out to the bananas
foster live batter all right in this
episode i'm going to cover
a few patreon questions before we get
there let's do some shout outs to a few
members of the 710 club
of course the 710 club are the folks who
support us on patreon
at the seven dollar and ten cent a month
level or higher
so let's start off with the big grow
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out to matt h
i want to send a big thank you shout out
to keith k i want to send a special
thank you shout out to redbeard
i always want to send a big thank you
shout out to john k i've got a big grow
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out for totally white tops
let's send a big thank you shout out to
kianacrat i've always got a big thank
you shout out for glenn geroni
let's send a special thank you shout out
to dominic c and last but certainly not
least
let's send a big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to oaky grow
7 20. big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon
if you're not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
the information you need to support the
show
will be right there on the screen and of
course i did include
a link in the show notes and the video
description
all right you guys this is the portion
of the show where we jump into the
patreon messages
let's not waste too much time the first
message comes from austin ron
and it goes just like this
uh peace grover love and gracias from
the heart of prohibition land the lone
star state
so we've got listeners down in texas
thank you for the message big shout out
to my friends in texas
it goes like this i am an avid listener
of your channels
i'm a new home grower and i love your
succinct and detailed as necessary
knowledge
thanks for letting us into your growers
headspace thank you i appreciate that
you are very welcome
and thanks for listening to all of my
channels i think you include
the podcast the instagram live feeds the
ins uh the embracing organics
appearances
and all of the other random places where
i pop up thank you for checking me out
the message goes on to say i thought i
would share this on grafting
a rather obscure topic in the command
cannabis community
but after listening to your assertions
correction
and recorrection i found this and while
not conclusive the following offers
indication if
not evidence that offspring from grafted
plants
contain dna from both plants
who would have thunk it thanks for
fighting the good fight rock on bro
from our friend austin ron so
a few episodes back i did talk about
grafting somebody asked me if i was
interested in grafting if i could give
advice about grafting
i said that in my opinion that if we
graft one plant to another plant
that over time those genetics will
mingle and we will not have true
genetics on both branches
i've been receiving controversial
messages no hate mail or anything like
that but some people are saying
that is possible some people say it is
impossible some people told me i was
reaching no longer reaching here is
volunteered
scientific evidence i think all of the
evidence points to the fact that the
genes
will move uh i tried to explain it
succinctly in my last episode but
if i cut off your arm and i cut off my
arm and we swap arms
sure that's your arm that's my arm
mine's gonna be the real pale long
gangly arm you'll be the darker arm and
thicker arm on my body
we'll know where they came from but the
blood will move
eventually the dna will move all of
what's me will be in that arm all of
what's you will be in your arm will be
your arm
i think it'll mix i think the trees the
plants the branches will do the same
thing
now we've got some scientific evidence
from our friend austin ron so big shout
out thank you to austin ron
i will skim this article just to appease
my mind i want to know that there is
some proof out there
if you guys are interested i will
include this link in the show notes and
you can read the article about grafting
i'm going to set it right here on my
computer so don't
forget to do that and also write the
word link here on the notes
and hopefully i remember all right let's
move forward big shout out to austin ron
thank you for the patreon support and
for the great
update on my lesson all right i want to
keep moving because i do have quite a
few great messages
from patreon this one comes from
c-dub and norcal it says rasta jeff
vibration
it's a good way to start a message then
it goes like this thank you for all of
the good vibes and helpful information
that you keep radiating
that's [ __ ] a great way to start a
message good vibes and information that
i'm radiating thank you for noticing
goes on to say i'd like to send some of
that love back your way
blessings of peace and health thank you
uh
big respect it says and may your
genetics be strong and your flowers
beautiful you have seen evidence of such
so your blessings are working
it goes on it says i was hoping to ask a
few questions and i do not object of you
using any of this
in any formal uh format oh any formal
format except sharing my email of course
i'll keep you safe and private bro
it goes on to say i was hoping i know
you're into concentrates
but uh which feminized seeds from irie
would you recommend
for a flower smoker i primarily smoke
with bongs and sometimes
joints growing is limited to a couple 10
to 15 gallon containers outdoor
and stealth is appreciated shorter and
not quite so fragrant
um so you want a recommendation on an
irie genetics
strain you're not a concentrate smoker
you're going to be smoking the flowers
probably through the bong or sometimes a
joint i like your style
uh you want to grow in 10 to 15 gallon
containers outdoors stealth would be
ideal so you don't want something that
smells like skunks and feet and [ __ ]
so far i think that we need to recommend
orange gasm to you
orange gasm is really easy to grow it's
a beautiful plant it's easy to handle
outdoors
it's not going to smell like skunk ass
and dirty feet and cannabis it's going
to smell like oranges
and orange creamsicles so you're going
to get a different aroma that's a little
bit less suspicious
it's also easier to grow outdoors it
doesn't take super long to finish
and i think it'll make you really happy
in the joint and in the bong it's gonna
taste like
[ __ ] sweet delicious oranges and if
you're into that orange flavor
that'll be beautiful for you if not i
may recommend
we're gonna want something outdoors a
little bit shorter ah
man it's hard to get away from the
skunky stuff maybe some strawberry
starburst but it may take too long to
finish wherever you are
the prana may get you away with it but
that prana's got that herb smell to it
although it's a wonderful plant outdoors
there is a lot more to this message let
me keep moving
excuse me for the cough there i did take
dabs before the show and it's a cannabis
podcast
i make off again it goes on to say i was
also wondering about
autoflowers outdoors is that worth
starting for the fall
or the winter i'm pretty sure i could
keep them out of any rain
but is there enough light and warmth to
produce any quality
flower uh i am not an
autoflower expert i don't really i don't
grow any autoflowers i don't know much
about autoflowers
but if you can get them to finish before
any adverse conditions
yeah they'll flower out there put them
out there they'll grow they'll flower
you'll get usable product
uh depending on who you buy your seeds
from and how you take care of them
your results may vary but uh yeah
autoflowers will work as long as they
don't get snowed on and get destroyed by
the winter environment
um outdoor autoflowers are a great idea
it goes on to say i'm pretty sure i
could keep them oh we read that part
uh if so any recommendations for
breeders on
feminized autoflower seeds um i am
friends with
mephisto genetics daz from mephisto is a
great dude has helped me out has done me
a huge favor
so i'm going to return the favor and say
i would recommend
mephisto m-e-p-h-i-s-t-o
mephisto for feminized seeds ah that is
who i've seen the best results from uh
that's who i've heard the best from
again disclaimer huge disclaimer i do
not grow femme or
autoflowers so i can't testify firsthand
this is all from what i've seen
read and heard also the dude's a friend
of mine so i want to give him a shout
out and rep him
uh but mephisto otter autoflowers would
be the way to go
it says i'm in norcal and i've had some
uh falling ash
and it keeps swirling around the breeze
and getting on the plant
i don't know what to believe about bud
washing all right so we're working into
a brand new question here
i don't know what to believe about bud
washing i was hoping you could shed some
light
on that subject should i even be
considering it it's only a little bit of
ash
there's a lot of differing opinions and
i really don't know who is reputable
but the bud washing recipe i've been
considering
are and then he shares his recipe with
me and i'm going to [ __ ] all over that
recipe don't do that i've got a better
idea for you
not even going to read that plan here on
the air so our listener friend is in
california and unfortunately they're
being
ravaged and devastated by wildfires
right now big love and big shout out to
everybody who's having to deal with that
fire
my heart goes out to you fire is [ __ ]
terrible i've seen several people
displaced due to fire
uh thank your uh thank you or whatever
you believe in thank you that your
shit's not burned down because a lot of
stuff burned down this summer and is
continuing to burn
the point is there is ash falling from
the sky
in california there was ash falling from
the sky in colorado
a lot of people were getting ashes in
their plants we could see the ash
building up in the buds we could see ash
laying on the leaves
a lot of people were scrambling and
turning i said scrambling a lot of
people were scrambling and trying to
figure out what to do
some people were out there with shop
vacs trying to suck off the ash
some people are out there with leaf
blowers trying to blow the ash off some
people just said [ __ ] it and let the ash
develop because there's nothing they can
do about such a large crop
with ash falling from the sky some
people are going to result
to or resort to what is known as bud
washing and it is exactly what it sounds
like it is a post
harvest bud wash just like giving your
car a wash giving anything else a wash
it is the same idea this is most
commonly done
for crops that have been infested with
powdery mildew this will wash the
powdery mildew off of there
you can do this to a commercial crop you
can run this commercial crop that has
been treated the way i'm going to tell
you
through microbial testing after it's had
powdery mildew on it
if it's done properly this method will
remove the powdery mildew and he will
pass
colorado regulated microbe testing so
if you've got powdery mildew on your
buds if you've got ashes on your buds
that is the only reason i would
recommend bud washing
in most cases i don't find it necessary
i find it to be more
you're going to cause more problems than
you are good unless
you've already got powdery mildew or
ashes
i honestly don't want to recommend that
you wash powdery mildew off
however i understand that people are
going to do what they've got to do
people grew a big ass crop if it's a
private grow if it's an indoor grow an
outdoor grow a commercial grow
people grew a product and they see it
and they do not want to throw it away
if it were up to me that would get
tossed that is a non-viable product
that's a failure
we've got to chalk that one up to me
[ __ ] up and having to correct an
issue
not everybody thinks the way that i do
not everybody operates the way i do so
there are going to be
different solutions when it comes to ash
and powdery mildew
sometimes you gotta scramble the ash i
that's not your fault i understand you
gotta make a product so you gotta wash
it off
that's more acceptable than powdery
mildew to me but if you're going to do
a flower wash or a post harvest bud
wash if you insist on doing so this is
how i recommend you do it i'm going to
take a quick drink and then we'll jump
into it all right
so you had a three bucket method in mind
i don't recommend the three buckets at
all
i use one five gallon bucket and i dump
my five gallon bucket
uh frequently you can see the powdery
mildew layer you can probably see the
ash layer develop on the top of the
water
so as soon as you see that nice little
funky layer dump it and start over that
way you know you're getting a good
cleaning out of this
so the basic way to do bud washing i get
a five gallon bucket
and i fill it most of the way with water
you've got to leave some room because
you're going to put buds in your hands
in there you need
room to work in there fill it most of
the way with water
you got 5 gallons of water in a 5 gallon
bucket there's an inch to work with
maybe 2 inches
then i use 30 hydrogen peroxide the
expensive [ __ ] the good
[ __ ] that is what i buy that is what i
use depending on
the amount of powdery mildew i'm trying
to rinse off of my plants
or perhaps the amount of ash i'm trying
to wash off of my plants
that will help me determine how much
peroxide i want to add to this water
i may start with approximately 25
milliliters per 5 gallon bucket
if my [ __ ] is real intense and real bad
i may consider
50 mils i would never go above 70
milliliters
of hydrogen peroxide per 5 gallon bucket
of water
if it's if you need more than that it's
a lost cause you done [ __ ] up don't
even bother washing it
so we've got our five gallon bucket and
we have put
30 to 50 maybe a little bit more
milliliters
of 30 hydrogen peroxide in this bucket
disclaimer time sidebar personal
protective
equipment must be used
before you even pick up the bottle of
hydrogen peroxide
before you think about it put on rubber
gloves
before you pick up the bottle put on
some sort of goggles
the hydrogen peroxide will [ __ ] your
skin and your eyes up
very bad if it comes in contact with
your skin and or
eyes it will burn your eyes to [ __ ]
it will burn your skin and make your
skin turn white and bubbly depending on
how sensitive your skin is
you will have different reactions i've
seen hydrogen peroxide and zero tall
reactions on skin before
you don't want it it's really easy to
prevent
put on gloves put on a long sleeve shirt
put on you're wearing a mask already
because it's coveted time put on a mask
over your face
put on some rubber or some goggles not
rubber gloves put don't put rubber
gloves on your face
if i catch you with rubber gloves on
your face you're going to get a drug
test and get rid no
put some goggles on your face so you
don't get that [ __ ] in your eyes
protect yourself this stuff will
dissolve the powdery mildew that means
it will also dissolve
other organic components which could be
your eyeball let's not do that
now you're going to get paranoid that
it's going to dissolve your trichomes
we're just going to rinse it and pull it
out we're not going to be in there long
enough to do anything
to get rid of the trichomes it's not
intense enough to do that
it's just going to wash that powdery
mildew right off of there so you've got
your personal protective
equipment you've got gloves you've got
goggles and i say before you even get
the [ __ ] peroxide out because
i've seen people reach for a product on
a shelf and they pull it off the shelf
and the lid wasn't on it all the way and
they poured it on themselves
i've seen people shake a bottle just you
go to grab whatever and you shake your
drink like this and the lid's not on it
and it [ __ ] splashes into your face
wear some protective equipment that [ __ ]
won't happen so you've got your
proper personal protective equipment you
got your gloves you got your goggles
uh maybe a mask hopefully long sleeves
always
guys wear shoes i know it's fun if
you're outdoors you're being a [ __ ]
hippie
wear some shoes you don't want
pesticides and products on your feet the
soles of your feet are one of the number
one most absorbent parts of your body
for absorbing pesticides and toxic
chemicals
uh probably also absorbing positive [ __ ]
but we don't think about that we don't
stress on it
i know that you shouldn't be running
around barefoot in a grow because if
i've applied a pesticide in the grow
it landed on the floor and now it's
going up through the bottoms of your
feet
into your body protect yourself stay
safe i know you want to have fun and be
a hippie it feels real good
but this is growing we need to be safe
we're smoking medical cannabis so we
don't get cancer
let's not go [ __ ] play with
pesticides and absorb them in our feet
to give us cancer we need to balance
this [ __ ] out so personal protective
equipment you've got your hydrogen
peroxide
30 to 50 maybe a little bit more
milliliters mixed into your five gallon
bucket of water i just use plain water
right from the tap
just room temperature or whatever
temperature you can [ __ ] with hose
temperature i guess you probably have
uh then i've got gloves on i've got my
plants i've harvested my plants
i cut it into manageable sections that's
just chunks probably branches
somewhere between 6 8 10 12 maybe 14
inches long
however deep that five gallon bucket is
i want to grab my buds
my branches just one branch at a time
you can do a handful if you want to i
prefer one at a time it's more effective
dunk that [ __ ] right into the hydrogen
peroxide solution
and give it a good swirl just shake it
around you're trying to just
jostle that powdery mildew right off of
that bud and then pull it out of there
and give it a look
do you still see more powdery mildew on
there does it need another rinse
put it in there give it a jostle shake
it around once you are confident
that you have knocked off all the
powdery mildew and don't go [ __ ]
crazy with this jostling motion
we're just trying to knock it off gently
knock off the powdery mildew we're not
trying to
smack the trichomes off of the branches
not trying to smack the trichomes off
the buds knock the buds off the branches
not trying to destroy everything we're
trying to fix our problem we [ __ ] up
so just gently
jostle it in that water knock those
tricoms off give it a good rinse
pull it out then hang it up and let it
drip dry
and put a fan near it for a little while
while it's drying don't put the fan
right directly on it but have air moving
have a dehumidifier near it so you can
get rid of all that excess moisture
do not trap these plants that you just
dunked into a
humid area you do not want to cause
mildew problems in these plants give
them
plenty of airflow and a wide open space
or somewhere you can evacuate all of
that stale air you need
if you're indoors you need a blower
extracting air you need a dehumidifier
if you're outdoors
just let that water evaporate as it
needs to the buds will take a few hours
to dry
but they were already wet inside they
were moist
there's natural water in there they get
rained on the environment does that to
them
they will dry again don't trap them
in a stagnant humid environment
so basically what we're going to do
we're going to mix up our we're going to
put on our personal protective equipment
we're going to mix up our hydrogen
peroxide solution
we're going to dunk each and every
branch into there then we're going to
hang it up in a well
ventilated area that it will not get
moldy that is our basic
method for bud washing i don't like the
method that you chose because
mixing a couple of those ingredients
together is going to make foam like a
volcano like we used to do in school
and that doesn't seem necessary to do to
my plants it's also going to add
different flavors a couple of the things
you added in your recipe we'll add
flavors we don't need those flavors
the hydrogen peroxide will evaporate or
dissipate
very rapidly very very rapidly it will
be gone before the water
so there will be no remaining aroma no
remaining flavor
no residuals at all if you do it
correctly if you've got big giant buds
that are
[ __ ] footballs or donkey dicks or
whatever you want to call them
you may need to cut those big chunky
buds down to smaller more manageable
pieces
because inside there you're going to get
moisture trapped in there and you may
cause potential problems
so if you've got big chunky football
donkey dick whatever you want to call
them buds big spears
maybe break them down into smaller more
manageable pieces
pieces that aren't going to have a bunch
of moisture trapped inside of there so
that you create your own problem after
doing your dunk
be very mindful that you just added a
bunch of unnecessary water
to your hanging drying and curing
environment you need to remove that
water you need to keep airflow happening
the shit's going to drip all over the
floor you may have to come mop that [ __ ]
up off the floor just to get the water
out of the room
now is the time to really think you're
trying to save the crop not make it
worse
all right c-dub in norcal i hope i
helped you out that was a great question
i do see a lot of people out there
talking about it and performing bud
washes right now it's not something i
would do unless it's highly
highly necessary but i understand that
ash is undesirable
we don't want ashes on the buds until
right before we hit it
or right before it gets to our lungs so
that's the way to rinse them off
uh 30 hydrogen peroxide you can also use
zero tall
maybe use less zero tall than hydrogen
peroxide if you choose to do so
but the 30 hydrogen peroxide at 30 to 50
mils per gallon
drop it in there give it a shake knock
that pm off knock those ashes off
then hang it up to dry let me know how
this works for you if you've got any
follow-up questions
i would be more than happy to help you
out send me an email i read genetics
hotmail.com or hit me on patreon
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart
i'm gonna take a quick look here to see
how long we've been recording i've got
my time going on my phone
we've got plenty of time for at least
one more message this one comes from our
friend north north terps
what up north good to hear from you bro
i hope you're doing well i talked to
north quite a bit
this message goes what up rosta jeff
it's always a pleasure to communicate
with you it's always great to hear from
you too brother says shout out to white
mike on his recent episode on
operation legalize the world i love that
bro mike
uh your next operation is legalize the
world we're not doing just states
anymore we're not doing our nation
it is a global mission legalized
worldwide mike you are heading that
that is yours uh you are in charge you
direct the army
let us know what you need we're going to
legalize worldwide let's get serious it
says anyways
with that being said i have a question
if maybe you could clarify on using
microbes
okay i have a question maybe you could
clarify on using microbes there should
be a period there
it says i've been experimenting with it
using hydro
and i'm just curious if there is a
preferred method of microbes and feeding
and process for the best way to balance
your ph
as quickly as possible so that i don't
run into deficiencies
or if i'm asking the right question i
think you might know what i'm trying to
get at
and i'm hoping you can help thank you my
guru
peace love and respect i do know exactly
what you're talking about
when we add our microbes to our ph
solution
it can drastically change the ph of our
feeding solution
it can drastically change the ph i don't
know if it's going to go up or down it
depends on where your solution is and
what microbes you're using i think it
goes way up i think when we
add the when i had recharge i think my
ph goes up
so this listener so north is concerned
that
we are disrupting the ph to a manner
which it will
disrupt the uptake of the elements and
nutrients that are available to the
plant
in that nutrient solution which is a
valid concern we just put a bunch of
expensive nutrients into a reservoir
into a tank into a feeding system
and then we're going to feed it to our
plants and hope the plants get the best
out of that but now i'm going to add
another product that's going to [ __ ]
that all up
and mess up the ph and make some of the
veil the nutrients unavailable to my
plant
i think i understand what you're asking
um
so we mix up our stuff we add a liquid
or a powder uh some are gonna some
people are gonna say to adjust your ph
before you add your microbes and some
people will say to adjust the ph
after you add your microbes i think if
you
get your solution mixed up adjust your
ph and then add your microbes you'll be
fine
i also think it will work perfectly the
other way i bet you
scotty and guru have some information
maybe an update on this
i want to see what happens if you ask
them the exact same question because
they make a microbial product
and i'm using a lot of my experience and
knowledge uh to talk from
using that microbial product shout out
to recharge real grover's recharge
this is not a recharge ad but that's one
of the main products i use so
i know where you're coming from with
this question when we mix in that
recharge
it makes the ph go crazy then we add
that to our plant
you are concerned that since we have
usually we are stubborn about the ph we
want to adjust the ph we're in the right
a
range to make elements bioavailable to
our plants
when those microbes come in contact with
the water
and the rhizosphere there is a
carbonic reaction that happens uh to the
best of my knowledge
almost instantly it doesn't take a lot
of time for
the other elements the water the
rhizosphere the other nutrients to
neutralize
that effect within the microbe so that
ph swing will be
minimized within seconds if not minutes
depending on the size of your
rhizosphere
and the amount of water but you're not
using [ __ ] hundreds of gallons so i
think it's gonna happen
almost instantaneously when that water
hits the rhizosphere
i think it's all just gonna go oh wait i
was way out of whack because i was in
water i was in suspension but now
i have hit something that i know what to
do with and it all
i think it balances itself out almost
instantly
um again i would like to hear guru and
scotty's feedback and input on this if
you guys are listening dude chime in
either send me a message or just do a
podcast about it the question is
uh are my microbes is the ph of my
microbes gonna mess up my uptake of my
plants and how do i prevent that from
happening that's the gist of the
question so
if you guys have feedback i invite you
uh to send me a message
or uh do your own show about it scotty
and guru check out the dude grow show
of course uh scotty real is the
proprietor of
recharge so he's gonna have answers to
this um i hate to just pass the buck on
a question but when i know that there's
an expert
right down the street that we can
contact i think that's what we'll do i'm
going to write down a note
to ask guru i'm writing that
i'm going to write it on this page also
so i can find this one
and then we'll ask guru and scotty real
but i think i gave you the appropriate
answer i think that that
i think the carbonic reaction happens
almost instantaneously
to where you don't have to worry about
that ph fluctuation
uh for just a very short amount of time
i don't think it's of any concern
i am going to talk to people who are
absolutely more qualified to answer that
question i'm not shy to admit that
i am not a microbe expert and since guru
and scotty are just a text message away
i will ask them however it is
not an appropriate time to message them
i'm recording kind of late at night i
get some self
time to myself late at night here they'd
probably be mad at me if i text them
right now so i'm not going to do that
but i will get in touch with my friends
we'll get you
some more useful information all right
north north terps uh i hope i helped you
out a little bit and hopefully scotty
and guru heard this and they will chime
in and give you a little bit more info
if not i'll get it going for you alright
i've got one more
great message that i want to answer on
this episode thank you guys for hanging
out it's two long episodes in a row
feeling good on this episode again thank
you i got my groove back i got my rhythm
back
this message comes from girls grow 2 and
it goes
just like this it says hey ross to jeff
i love the legalization presentation
with white mike
and just became a patreon of his that is
awesome
our friend girls grow too saw the
legalization presentation that featured
white mike and they went and signed up
for white mike's patreon thank you
i appreciate that i'm sure mike
appreciates it as well
and absolutely i'm sure that mike's wife
and little kids appreciate that because
he spoils them he doesn't spend money on
himself he's going to spend
that contribution on his family so shout
out to mike and his family he
appreciates your help
let me keep moving because i'm [ __ ]
rambly it says mike is great and i love
the chemistry you two have he did well
staying on the mic that is a huge
compliment because sometimes mike does
have problems staying on the microphone
uh thank you i kept him on the mic he
kept himself on the mic that is a huge
notice
good job mike people are liking your
show now there is a question here it
says
uh my family my wife finally said yes to
me getting a real grow light for
christmas this year
ah that's pretty awesome i love it that
the wife has given you some permission
uh it says i'm looking for a light that
would work in a four by five room
my budget is a hard 250. so he's got 250
bucks
to light up a 4x5 room uh probably
looking for an led it doesn't say does
it say oh it says i would love a cannon
i don't think it's in the budget i don't
think a canon led is in the budget even
if you go to
blacksailmarket.com and use coupon code
rosta jeff
and get yourself a nice deal but i don't
think that 250 is gonna get you there
it says i don't think it's in the budget
as a disabled combat veteran with
epilepsy
my grow is my life and gives me purpose
this is the second episode where i've
read
about somebody being a combat veteran
with a grow
giving them a new purpose i love this i
love that we're helping you out that you
have found some purpose
uh it says uh where are we you're
secretly my mentor that means a lot to
me thank you it's not a secret anymore
uh thank you if you ever need help in
the grow
just reach out directly i'll be more
than happy to help you out
it goes on with thank you for all you do
for the industry and the community
much love your way brother much love and
much respect your way as well i said in
the last episode
i appreciate veterans and especially
combat veterans and people who've been
blown up in war and [ __ ]
uh i guess i'm a giant [ __ ] because
i don't see myself armed and equipped
and shooting at people and
i said in the last episode if you shoot
at me or throw a grenade at me i'm
[ __ ] running i quit
[ __ ] that game over so i appreciate you
and respect you for what you do
uh that does mean a lot to me i said it
in the last episode
without people protecting my freedom i
don't know how much freedom i would have
so without getting all patriotic and
weird on the episode and political
thank you i appreciate your service um
man i don't know what to recommend for a
250 dollar
light to fill a four by five sealed room
i wish we could get you a couple of
canon leds i think one canon led would
fill a three by three space
and get your plants happy in that three
by three and then slowly we could
upgrade maybe next christmas maybe next
birthday or something
we could talk the wife into a new light
but 250 is not going to cover
a canon led it's going to get you close
also here is where i'm torn i kind of
work with black sail they're friends of
mine we've got agreements
i shouldn't be advertising other lights
in here i really don't know what other
light company to recommend
but i do have a large audience with a
lot of reach
and a lot of compassion so here's what
i'm going to do for you for my friend
girls grow 2.
i need some advice will you guys that
are listening and are watching please
comment on the youtube channel
and recommend a good solid grow light
for around
250 bucks for a disabled veteran
who needs some help they're a combat
veteran with epilepsy we need to grow
them some quality medicine
we need to improve their garden so i
need some advice
on a 250 dollar light it doesn't have to
be an led it doesn't say led in here
led would probably be best it's going to
save on electricity it's going to be
easier to cool
so if we can get a 250 watt led light
that will work in a 4x5 room that would
be awesome
please leave comments details and
information in the video description
here
so that our friend knows where to go
look all you've got to do is go to
youtube
pull up episode 475 and there will be
advice left in the comments and thank
you to my audience members
that are going to help us out i do
appreciate that now here's another thing
that i'm going to do
and i'm going to do it completely
shamelessly this is not for me
this is for a disabled combat veteran
this young man
has served our country and helped us out
and he's [ __ ] up because of it so
it's our turn to serve him back uh he's
got 250 and he needs some grow lights
is there a grow light company out there
that can fill in his gap
if 250 is a good start and your light
costs three or four hundred bucks
is there somebody out there that wants
to help out a disabled veteran
i'll give you a shout out on the podcast
let me know what you can do
send me an email let's grow from your
heart at hotmail.com let's help out
our disabled veteran friends we owe it
to them all right
so i think that's what i can do for you
i don't have a recommendation but
all the [ __ ] that i just said is going
to be better than a recommendation for a
light
thank you for the uh dude thank you for
the [ __ ] the protection
uh for the service and thank you for all
the patreon support i see your name on
patreon a lot
we communicate quite a bit uh thank you
thanks again thank you for the great
message
and i hope this works out well for you
all right ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls pimps and hoes friends and foes
smokers and growers
combat veterans and uh everybody else
out there i don't know who else to put
in that group
you you and all your friends and family
i want to thank you guys for listening
i want to thank you for hanging out this
was another fun episode i found my
groove again
i can't wait to record more episodes if
it wasn't so late i'd probably just go
again
i want to thank you guys for listening
if you feel like the episode was
educational informative or entertaining
and you'd like to make a financial
contribution to the show all you have to
do is visit www.patreon.com forward
slash grow from your heart of course all
the information you need
will be right there and i did include a
link in the show notes and the video
description
to make it super easy don't forget to
check out our sponsors at
seedshearnow.com
use coupon code gfyh10 to save yourself
a couple of bucks
don't forget you can get a pack of the
cream for under 30 and that under
30 section if you've got any corrections
questions comments or concerns
i would love to hear from you my email
address again is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
don't be shy send me some messages
questions concerns corrections comments
feedback
criticism i'm all ears let's see what
you got
that is all i've got for you for this
episode my throat is done my voice is
burnt out perfectly timed
i want to thank you guys again for
hanging out i should be back in just a
couple of days with fresh new content
i want to give a giant shout out to
smoke what and until next time take a
fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me