welcome back podcast world i'm your host
my friends call me rosta jeff and it is
time for episode 579 of the grow from
your heart podcast
this episode of the show is brought to
you by our friends at seeds herenow.com
seeds herenow.com offers seeds from all
of the industry's leading breeders
including miss jill genetics duke
diamond and of course irie genetics
everything at seeds here now.com is
backed by an award-winning satisfaction
guarantee
and for my friends on a tight budget
seeds herenow.com offers several packs
for under 30
as well as amazing monthly sales make
sure to use coupon code gfyh10 while
checking out to save a few bucks
again that is coupon code gfyh10 while
checking out at seeds
here now dot com if you guys are joining
me on the youtube video i'm sure you can
see that white mike is here
welcome to the show bro thanks man
what's up everybody
dude you sound great on the microphone
today compliments we've been hanging out
before the show and you've sounded
wonderful
so far stay right where you are don't
change it trying to stay on the mic
everybody
yeah you're doing a really good job on
it bro um mike what are you smoking on
today bro
all kinds of deliciousness that's a good
answer
one of our local dispensaries had some
fire
golden goat flower i've been enjoying a
lot of that
yep we uh we were shopping together that
day had him open the jar
um thanks to kovid you can't get your
face in the jar anymore which is always
a little
yeah iffy to me but uh it was nice to
get a good
whiff of what you were buying get a good
look at what you were buying
but uh now they like stick it in the
butcher case in front of you and open it
so you can see it
and as soon as they crack the jar we can
smell the goat and yeah it's pretty
tasty
it threw my mask i was wearing a mask
and i could smell i said oh that's good
golden goat as soon as it opened up yeah
i've been enjoying it's got me in a
nice podcasting mood what uh what have
you been smoking on lately buddy
i'm glad you asked oh let me fix my mic
i just turned myself down too much
uh thank you for asking mike i'm smoking
halo live batter
uh this is a blend of headbanger and
infinity og i do the thing where i talk
about what it says on the package it
says it tastes like deconstructed sour
diesel i don't know
what the [ __ ] deconstructed sour diesel
tastes like
but it is kind of coffee and gassy at
the same time it's got some earthy tones
to it
i really do enjoy it on the back of the
package it says 66.74
thc non-detectable amounts of cbd
uh halo live batter i dig it dude uh
really nice buzz
uh perfect chilled out mode yeah that
taste is great it's got a funky gassy
disgustingly delicious aroma and those
are my favorites those
gross and delicious that i'm if you see
me
hitting a cart this episode that's
what's in the cart is some halo oil
i may need to grab myself a couple of
pens or a couple of fat joints for these
episodes when we hang out because i need
something to do with my hands i don't
know what to do with my hands
like i noticed that if i keep this on me
i don't move around
at the desk as much yeah i may need out
of my sound management plan
it's working bro i may need a pop up
prop and or pacifier for myself
but it's working dude keep doing what
you're doing you sound great and you
look great and you're [ __ ] stoned so
everything is perfect uh speaking of
people who look great see anything but
people can see me now yeah oh yeah we
put some lights in mike's face you guys
people have been saying that he looks
like a talking head
uh we put a light in front of him that
is what mike looks like that's his
smiling face there so
thanks for joining me today bro uh and
thanks for checking out my new lighting
situation in the room here
i'm doing my best this looks dope thank
you bro thank you
uh doing what i can with uh with what
i've got trying to move away from that
old crowded dusty space
there are more improvements coming i
keep teasing that you guys are going to
be as excited as i improvements coming
mike knows what's coming mike if you
tell anyone you know how it goes i got
to kill you
it's more improvements y'all yes it's
coming
uh i tried to segue into it smoothly a
moment ago but we didn't make it there
so this is the part of the show where we
are going to do
shout outs to the members of the 710
club of course the 710 club are the
folks who support
uh the grow from your heart podcast on
patreon at the seven dollar and
ten cent a month level or higher so i'm
going to do some shout outs let's start
off with the big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out
to our good friend godfather kush let's
send a thank you shout out to matt h
i want to send a thank you shout out to
just a smokin i want to send a shout out
to one of my favorite names i see on
patreon which is willie's armpit that's
[ __ ] cool shout out willie and your
armpit
let's send a shout out to keith k i want
to send a special thank you shout out to
one of our longest
standing patreon contributors big
special shout out to john bendet
a special shout out to brett g uh
special super thank you shout out to the
captain and commander of
the ire army let's send a special thank
you shout out to the two lemur priest
and last but certainly not least uh
let's send a big
thank you shout out to our friend
thecanocrat who is actually on
eagle gardens podcast as we speak had to
check out to come do the podcast but
shout out to the candycrat
uh big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who supports the grow from
your heart podcast
on patreon if you'd like to support the
podcast on patreon it's really easy
go to patreon.com forward slash grow
from your heart i will include a link in
the show notes
to make it easy the reason i'm rushing
through that part is because i need to
give mike an opportunity
to do some shout outs to a few of his
patrons and give some love so mike
michael turn it over to you
these are mike's patreon shout outs
um i want to give a shout out to papa
zee um
giant mike uh the grow from your heart
podcast is a new sponsor
appreciate that buddy uh richard thank
you very much
ez05 appreciate it farmer z
and learning and vernon um all my
patreon supporters i appreciate you very
very much
um if you'd like to support me on
patreon it's patreon.com forward slash
white mike very well done buddy very
well done
uh doesn't it feel nice getting some
support from the community we put in a
few hours dude they turn around and give
us hours back
it uh it makes me feel um awesome
it's so much love thank you so much all
of our supporters
i agree yeah getting choked up a little
bit part of that's the dab i took right
promised
myself most of that's the dab i just
took
um part of that's the the support it's
uh it's growing every week and uh
yeah guys thank you so much yeah thank
you everybody
i truly appreciate it mike appreciates
it uh we were joking before the show i
made a joke on another episode that mike
spends the patreon funding on his kids
and he goes buddy
you couldn't be more right so true super
funny yeah the kids are getting spoiled
because of you guys so
uh the kids i'm not gonna say their
names we'll keep their names private on
the show but those two little guys
are sending you guys uh sticky fist
bumps
right if you're wondering where i am
it's it's uh small children
are exhausting yeah yeah that's why he's
not on the show that's also why he's
hidden when it's that's why we've got
him hidden away in a small dark space
right now
he's just sequestered from the family
for a moment so he can get some time
and if you're not on video this is sort
of a weird
moment of the show but the background
behind me is flat black so i really just
do look like a floating head right now
on this completely do
you've been called the floating head in
the videos uh i am learning more about
video production probably worse
we'll get mike up to speed i have been
using uh some of my patreon
contributions for things to improve the
show and once i get my show where i want
it we're gonna get
some of my patreon contributions over
toward mike's area to get his
recording space looking as good as mine
uh we owe it to the
to mike and to the audience here so yeah
we're gonna do that mike this is a good
flow this may turn into a long episode
we did not intend for this long of a
show but
i think we took the appropriate dabs
today we're dabbed
i was involved they like it when we
ramble
oh they most certainly do that's going
to be a good one uh mike is this the
time of the show where we segue into the
email portion of the podcast you want to
jump right into that part
i think we should we checked off all the
the essentials right we did
any ads we did the shout outs we did the
intro song
yeah it's time to talk about the topic
of the show yeah we covered all the
important stuff we said thank you to the
people that help us make the show happen
and that is really the important part
we reminded that advertiser and you say
appetizers
appetizers are complete onto the meal
all right oh i thought you said
advertisers and i was jokingly saying
appetizers but you did say appetizers
i said appetizers come on bro i'm stoned
you're gonna make me hungry
um let's focus in here just a little bit
because it's
early to jump off the jumping board uh
the diving board this early into the
show
i've got a great email in front of me do
they want their name
said it's just letters and numbers
anyway so i'm not gonna say their name
uh it says ross to jeff i listened to
your podcast today and there was a short
portion on grow safety if you followed
the show a little while back i've done a
done a couple of episodes now on keeping
yourself and your grow safe
i don't want you poking your eye i don't
want you going to jail i don't want you
burning down the house
so i've done what i can to update you on
ideas of how to keep your grow and your
family and yourself safe
while you were growing in the house we
don't need problems in the house so
uh this goes on it says you said
something that i have often thought
about if someone shows up
and there is some dank in the air how
would i explain that
[ __ ] away so this person lives
apparently in prohibition land
and they want they've got a good excuse
so if somebody knocks on the door and
they say hey bro
we smell cannabis in your house there is
a problem this person has a wonderful in
my opinion what could be a wonderful
excuse and i want some feedback from
mike to see if he thinks this would fly
he said my answer is to have
a quarter or two of hemp buds in the
house
if anyone comes over knocking on the
door about the odor and so
inside or out i hand over the hemp buds
and say sorry sir
i ordered this on the internet here's
the packaging and everything
i was under the impression that cbd hemp
was now
okay i might cost me 50 bucks but i know
someone is paying attention
and it will keep my ass out of jail that
is like a good warning that somebody
knows you're smoking in there and you
need to adjust and adapt and maybe get
rid of some things and maybe stop doing
some [ __ ]
uh it says no one knocking on your door
would have any further reason to believe
it was anything else unless you look
like a stoner high guilty
uh which would be the thing not to do in
prohibition land yeah
i am very blessed and lucky uh to live
here in colorado where i can have these
dreadlocks you guys
these dreads are tied up in a nice big
old bundle right now because they do get
ridiculous these things go to
uh my calf region and i am six and a
half feet tall
so these things are a little bit
ridiculous i can't look like this
bro that's absolutely what it is in
georgia florida
alabama texas it's all and hey
i said uh i've made some jokes about
texas on a previous show that i was on
i'm sorry texas i still love you guys
there are great people down there in
texas
those were jokes i'm funny laugh with me
um but so yeah we can't look like this
in [ __ ] a lot of places mike we're
very blessed that we have
legal cannabis here and i think the
police know that guys that look like you
and i we're not the ones with the other
drugs on us we're the ones with the
cannabis because
you can tell the crowds apart i think
and cinnamon now there's no need to [ __ ]
with us like that guy's a wheathead
wheat is legal we're gonna go mess with
the other heads because they're the
problems
they'll get the ones going through your
trash and [ __ ] trying to break into
your house
um so yeah don't look like a stoner is
rule number one
mike how do you feel about this approach
if we were in let's just pick a state
you i'll let you pick a state so nobody
bashes me for bashing a state
well no that's my my thought on it is
that it really really really really
really depends on where you live um
a lot of places have already
preemptively stepped on this excuse for
why it smells like herb at your place
and said that smokable hemp isn't
allowed even though cbd
or legal hemp sort of is allowed
okay there's uh at least one state
that's
still saying it doesn't matter what the
feds say about
industrial hemp we say no still um
there are a lot of states who haven't
invested in the technology to
definitively prove
high thc cbd no thc
so i'm going to cut you off because you
just said something that uh i forgot
what i was going to cut you off for oh
some states
we said colorado said hey fed [ __ ] you
we're going legal other states have said
hey [ __ ] you with your cbd we still
don't want it i didn't realize that that
was a thing
there's opposition just they can oppose
just like we approved the fed that's
pretty cool
i didn't even realize that that was a
thing sometimes i'm ignorant ignorance
is bliss
um but uh
if this ploy has any effect or a
positive effect
really depends on where you're standing
okay um
a lot of places it smells like herb here
is still probable cause for a search on
its own
um so even if you say
it smells lit or it smells like this
because of this legal reason at the door
they're going to say it doesn't matter
we still get to search
and work right still smells like
cannabis and we need to make sure it's
not cannabis
in places like colorado smell alone is
no longer probable cause
and so um like unless you're driving and
it smells like burnt joint
but um it's your home it's a grow
situation
at home i had a it's been an interesting
for you i'm going to totally interrupt
you and i apologize but that's
that's this is a good thing it's worth
it it's worth it um i have a friend
who was pulled over in the great state
here of colorado
and he was not even allegedly he was
straight up smoking a blunt enjoying his
ass
smoking a blunt and he got pulled over
and he said i'm smoking a [ __ ] blonde
i'm not even gonna try like and he took
a couple of fat rips off of it and put
it in the ashtray and rolled down the
window and said what's up officer
and the cop said whoa it smells like
wheat in there what's your hurry and my
buddy goes i'm trying to go to a thing
he's actually going to
he was meeting me somewhere it's like
i'm going to a thing and uh
trying to get there and the cop goes
yeah we're driving a little bit too fast
to be smoking a [ __ ] blunt you might
want to slow yourself down and gave him
a speeding ticket
and my buddy was like kind of freaking
out and he was all like paranoid and the
cops like you can relax or we know
you're smoking in there but you don't
seem intoxicated
he told him that consumption did not
constitute
impairment and he's like you seem fine
you're driving too fast you weren't
swerving you weren't doing anything
wrong
slow it down if you're gonna smoke a
blunt while you're driving and sent him
on his way dude
it's up to the cop how much they want to
[ __ ] with you yeah
um and unfortunately right now
um there's a lot of stories where they
choose to [ __ ] with you extra
right there's also plenty of stories
where they choose to [ __ ] with you less
um and unfortunately wildly
we're going the same place [ __ ] very
we're headed the same place it depends
on what you look like and where you're
located yep
yep um i've been fortunate
i get away with stuff um there's a
reason why we nicknamed you
why i i'm gonna take the honor why i
nicknamed you white mike because you
look like a white guy just a basic
general white guy not gonna cause any
problems
also you guys just for an update i call
him white mike because if i'm ever
breaking two rules at a time he will
remind me only break one law at a time
they'd be like hey you're smoking that
blunt and going [ __ ] 90 pick one
either flick the blunt out the window or
go 70
like he'll remind me he's always like
one he's my free
legal guidance he's one of my [ __ ]
best friends on the planet and he's good
at [ __ ] psychology and law
that's my white friend over there that's
why mike and i just get to say you can't
give yourself a nickname like you don't
right if it's a real nickname you didn't
have a hand and craft in it
um but yeah this uh i
i i just talked to somebody who
was busted growing they had a uh
an odor control failure um
a passerby alerted the authorities
by the time person got home from work
they had a why the [ __ ] you growing all
this weed problem on their doorstep and
they tried to say it was all legal hemp
um luckily
cops don't go to school for lots of
stuff and they
the school they go to isn't real long or
detailed
and so a lot of officers have no [ __ ]
idea what they're looking at or what
they're talking about which has led to
a lot of amusement on my part and
probably in the community's part when we
see a bust
and they're taking the news crew through
the grow house and they point at a
carbon filter and go
this is a co2 generator and then it's
like man the only thing that got right
was the lights
right i've seen that video by the way
that's funny but uh
in practical terms um one of the things
i told that person is if
they took all the plant matter which
they tend to do
they uh they do exactly what you see
them do they stuff all the plants in a
bunch of trash bags
and then haul that to an evidence locker
anyone who's grown
anything knows that when you do that to
a living plant
what you've done is you've killed a
marijuana farm and you've started a mold
farm
so by the time that product gets to a
lab can they tell if it's thc or cbd
product who the [ __ ] knows
i think varies wildly from state to
state based on
technology i can smell that moldy
[ __ ] dead plant in that bag it's like
lawn clippings plus puke
uh-huh and it doesn't take long to mold
out either you take a bunch of plants
stick them in a plastic bag you stick
that in the dark you come back a couple
of days later you've got a
big [ __ ] bag of mold um
and it's the same thing with the the
hemp flour if you say no it smells like
that because it's hemp flower
if you're lucky they take the hemp
flower
or take your word for it if you're not
lucky
they send it off to get tested they come
back an hour later with a warrant
i mean we actually got to be careful
does not seem like a good ploy
we have to be careful with the claim
that it's hemp flour because now with
the farm bill and a bunch of hemp acts
you were required to have licensing and
permits to grow to commercially
cultivate hemp
it is almost safer to grow cannabis than
it is to grow hemp so if they come
and you're growing cannabis and they say
is this weed or hemp and you say it's
hemp
they're going to go get the department
of agriculture and you're supposed to
have a [ __ ] license for that and you
can still
get as hefty of a fine you're not going
to face the jail time but you'll get
fined
well i mean this takes me back to one of
the things i always recommend is really
know the law in your area
because depending on where you're
standing in the u.s you can have
all the cannabis plants you want just at
your house other places you can only
have a few
other places the plants have to test a
certain way
and who's to say who gets to test what
there's at least one business a fit
going through all kinds of legal
headaches right now because
they bought a shitload of legal hemp
seed on the open market
and it wasn't the whole batch that they
got but a
chunk of their seed ended up being high
thc
rather than cbd dominant and so they had
this big field of
hemp and then one corner of it was a
high thc cannabis
so they're dealing with major headaches
right now
other places are dealing with the exact
same headaches because their [ __ ] tested
at one percent thc
those seed sellers should potentially be
held responsible they knew if they
offered something that wasn't as
advertised there should be some recourse
to the seed sellers
i'm a seed maker i i hold myself
responsible for that kind of a claim
if this was a federally legal business
operating with normal business practices
all that [ __ ] would just be in place um
but it's
not because well that's the second half
of the show right
yep well do you want to work our way
into that mike um
segway yes segway i'm not going to drop
that clip in i haven't used it
if we need it for somewhere here's time
to make a segue uh this is the part
where we're going to let
uh mike work his way into a little bit
of politics because it is voting time
there's a lot of critical stuff
happening
i've got a platform with an audience and
i feel it is almost my responsibility to
educate and inform on other things than
just cannabis this is cannabis related
it's cannabis involved it's important
uh i think i can quit rambling and i can
let
mike start rambling a little bit the
first thing i wrote down though bro was
uh political signs
so if you want to tell us your story
about your political science and then
we'll work it into the rest of your your
stuff
um with covid and everybody just being
home most of the time
um like our worlds have kind of
collapsed in on each other
and uh i don't know about y'all but one
of the things i do to keep myself sane
and keep the kids sane is
we take little walks around the
neighborhood and not long walks just
around the block and
you know one week one one day we do the
the right side of the block next week we
do the left side of the block
kind of loop around and we've watched
the evolution of the political signs
going up and down our street and around
our neighborhood
in this part of town it's really chill
there's not a lot of signage
in about maybe two months ago
six weeks ago one house on our street
puts out there was no trump sign at
first it started out with two local
conservatives
um so like uh
what is it a senator level and then a
state rep level
sign in the front yard and like two days
later there was a trump sign to go with
it it seemed like he just didn't have
the trump sign yet
and that was the only signs on our
street for a minute and then
i live right across the street from a
military vet
and
one day i come home and he's definitely
got where his american flag normally is
there's a trump flag but it's a trump
flag i haven't seen before because it
seems like it's trump on one side
american flag on the other and i'm not
great with flag etiquette but
immediately my brain was like
wait alarm bells that looks really weird
you should look at that more and figure
out what the hell you're looking at
so over the next two days
it goes from trump flag on one side
american flag on the other
to double-side an american flag to
double-sided trump flag
and me and the wife are talking about
this just laughing going
is it a husband and wife fighting like
is it going up and coming down does
the guy not sure about his support what
the hell is going on
and what it turns out is it's just badly
hung up
and it's a one-sided trump flag and
again just terrible flag etiquette it's
hung up
um overlaid on his american flag he's
got the american flag set up on
the front of his house and he's just
clipped the trump flag right next to it
in the same
guide rings and so depending on which
way the wind's flapping
or if it's hanging still it looks all it
looks like six different flags at once
so at this point in the story there's
the one house down the street with three
little yard signs in the flag
then i go down the street and all of the
houses around the first house
have blind signs out they've surrounded
the dude
then two other people on the street put
out biden flags
or not buying flags buying signs then
next morning all of the biden signs are
gone
they just disappeared somebody came
through and stole them all
two days later they're all back and
everybody's doubled up now
nice so i'm waiting to see that happened
yesterday everybody doubled up
so i'm waiting to see where this goes
between now and the election
like it's just a sad little thing that's
my weird little world right now people
welcome to it
uh i don't remember if it was you or
another friend that told me that they
watched a neighbor
put some trump signs in the trash can
um i've seen that story on a couple of
different uh
platforms in a couple of different
versions it could have been fake though
and i may have fallen honestly big crap
this election's so bad [ __ ] that like
there's all of it
um i saw one dude and when i saw this
picture i was like
homie's kind of begging for trouble and
when i saw the footage of the trouble
that inevitably happened i was like
and they had a camera set up to catch it
homie was probably kind of begging for
trouble
but it was a huge like semi trailer
like the big full-size semi-trailer
worth a hay bale
stacked up and then a shitload of biden
flags all over it and i don't remember
what
stated it was in but i remember thinking
that's a pretty conservative area for
such a giant biden display
made out of obviously flammable material
seems like a bad idea
and sure [ __ ] a few days later it was on
fire
um so who knows but just in our little
area
it's it's fun just watching the
neighborhood go
my wife ordered a couple of biden flags
and we haven't put them up yet because
we don't want to be
the like we don't want to one-up anybody
and start a thing
oh do it it's like christmas we're
sticking to yours we're sticking to the
yard sign until the yard sign disappears
if somebody jacks the yard sign all five
flags are going up [ __ ] it
you guys could be like uh like the
[ __ ] uh
[ __ ] i lost it in my national lampoon's
christmas vacation you could be like the
guy hanging up super lights bro
yeah it's uh it's tough it's such a
weird election because i'm not
like i'm not a super fan of of biden i
definitely
didn't pick biden in the primaries he
was i don't even remember saying my dad
clearly had a phone call it was back
when
all of the candidates were still in um
right after bloomberg got in the race
i was like i don't know who it's gonna
be right now but i know it's not gonna
be biden or bloomberg
and we had like an hour-long
conversation about how we were sure it
wasn't gonna be either those candidates
oops but uh along this track while we're
talking politics on a weed show
is the last episode i was on was my
legalization primer
and man i don't know if i got too high
or if my script
lost a page but i don't think i told you
all the vote
[ __ ] dude of all the things not to
mention
vote vote vote vote
most of the states that have legal
cannabis
recreational legal cannabis we got there
because we have a system in place that
allows
citizens to put questions directly on
the ballot
citizens overcame whatever hurdles are
in place to do that
we got the word out we convinced our
parents to vote with us
and we legalized it a lot of places
where
cannabis isn't recreationally legal
you've got to elect people to office
who will do all those first steps for
you
and right now that's a pain in the ass
to get done
um presidential candidate wise right now
um another reason we're doing a
political show on a cannabis podcast
both presidential campaigns trump and
biden are now
clear on their marijuana positions
um the biden campaign their policy goal
is decrim
decriminalization no legalization
no federal legalization they just want
to get the feds out of it
in my mind it's a half step a lot of
states have had decrim for a lot of
years
and we arrested a [ __ ] load of people
from marijuana crimes during that time
because decram doesn't mean [ __ ] for
production
um and if you've got a whole ounce on
you they call that
attempted deal anyway so right
distribution i mean [ __ ]
yeah if you get caught with 29 grams of
hot sandwich baggies
you're a major drug trafficker under a
decrim model usually so
it's i mean it's a step forward you
can't say it's not
but it's not legalization it's not
um like if i was running for president
it wouldn't be
my marijuana policy that's for damn sure
but
it's just going to interrupt you and ask
you what your marijuana policy would be
mike
legalization just falls without
legalization just like cigarettes like
other industries
probably not just like cigarettes but
similar um
i finally quit smoking in january after
like 20 something years
congrats bro so um i've been anti
or i'm his anti-tobacco now as i've ever
been in my life
not like violently anti-tobacco or
anything but
i see them at least favorably and
i've never liked that particular
regulation model
it's not bad but it's not good either
we can do better i think we've already
done better with colorado's marijuana
model
okay um i wouldn't just
blanket take colorado's model and push
it over all the states
either um we've definitely made mistakes
oh for sure um some were working to
correct now
some people are gleefully making worse
but uh i think we're better than most
places
um and i think if if there was a
presidential candidate right now
that said we're gonna push colorado's
model on all 50 states like i'd be
looking to get a tattoo with that
person's name
i'd be so [ __ ] excited where are you
gonna put it
i don't know my throat
biden 420 try to crash your neck bro
no it's uh i mean honestly for a long
time
uh drug legalization policy
wonk like me voting for biden [ __ ]
hurts i'm not gonna say it doesn't
but uh um we've covered their proposal
now let's talk about the opposition yes
um
which is weird calling the the party in
the
the white house the opposition at all
but uh
um trump has said positive things
towards legalization in the past
um he's said lots of positive things
about medical marijuana in the past
and he's currently sending threatening
cease and desist letters to a medical
marijuana
campaign and a legalization campaign
because they're accurately quoting him
threatening them to stop using things he
said
that support the cause they're
supporting
pretty clear he's anti-cannabis he sided
with
the rest of the right politically here
in his
anti-cannabis just like we've had
all through american history since the
late 1800s so
such a weird thing if you're voting
based on just cannabis
there's your sign i like the way you
wrapped that up and made that a peaceful
division if you're voting for cannabis
mike knows who you should vote for i
think you do by now
uh that's really a weird approach to it
to send a cease and desist to say
you can't even use my quotes that i said
in your campaign even though what i said
is
real like how can you [ __ ] block
somebody's story broke to death
check out marijuana moment for in-depth
reporting on this story but uh
i saw the headline and i went that's
[ __ ] stupid
yeah like that's that is almost
advertising
cannabis is insanely popular it's more
advertising for the campaign that was
that he's against now that campaign
would have gotten
a little bit advertising legs you know
what i mean however much they paid for
now it's got trump money behind it it's
looking it only would have gotten so far
and fizzled out now it's gotten a whole
another
got picked up and re-thrown down the
field they got a whole other throw
[ __ ] one reason people like me are
reading about it
is because it's so weird medical
marijuana is
supported by like 60 80 of the people
depending on which people you're talking
about it's
wildly popular i mean it's popular like
ice cream
yeah it's it's insanely popular
it's disturbing that it's still illegal
federally and there's still so many
restrictions on it despite its
popularity
with the voters but it's i mean it's a
contentious election we're
two weeks out now and to just slap
that many people for no reason none like
it wasn't like anybody was pointing to
these quotes and
it wasn't causing a problem for their
campaign or anything it wasn't even
contentious it wasn't news at all
until they sent a cease and desist
letter that was angry and threatening
and now it's just national news that's
so funny
yeah that that ad campaign just expanded
tenfold
good job shitload of conservative
cannabis fanatics
um they love cannabis and they love vote
republican
and that's gotta suck
i'm sorry i'm not not even trying to be
a dick i know a lot of republicans my
i've got republicans in my family
um i'm liberal about a lot of stuff but
i'm conservative about a lot of stuff
too
just not any social issues um like i'm a
gun nut too
so dude i wasn't going to bring that up
i'm all about cannabis and i'm i'm all
about a lot of things i'm not even going
to mention but i think if you want to
have a gun
have a [ __ ] gun like you should have
all about freedoms
yeah do the things that you want to do
that's the thing i like is freedom don't
[ __ ] with me don't [ __ ] with other
people
as long as my freedom isn't [ __ ] with
your freedom and we aren't stepping on
each other in any other way that's
[ __ ]
freedom bro let's have a good ass time
hugs and dabs and guns and
[ __ ] yeah love who you want [ __ ]
love what you want
[ __ ] yeah dude yeah yeah your [ __ ]
ain't my
business my [ __ ] and your business like
let's have a good time and be ourselves
what uh i definitely wanted to get on
the show and do
a little here's where the candidates are
at peace for
uh for the girl for the heart community
and the ire army
i know you all look to me for some of
that stuff and i appreciate it
and if you're on the fence and looking
for a cannabis reason to vote a or b
um there you go i think most of the
audience watching the dreadlocked white
guy with the cannabis show were already
uh most of them have probably already
made their decisions but
hopefully maybe we encouraged a small
portion of people
maybe we just divided ourselves from
some of our friends but either way
we are who we are hope you enjoyed the
show uh mike thank you dude thank you
for your contribution to the show the
community
for what you do you look like you got
something to say go for it well just
the group in our community that i
really reaching out to or the group that
don't vote
or the group that hate left and right so
they vote third party or don't vote
at all um or the people that think
everything sucks so why bother like
it's literally just made up of people
it's just
us like it's weird to think that if me
and jeff were a little older and a lot
less stony
like we could be senators or
presidents or yeah i compared the
justices or the people that say that
voting doesn't matter
those are the people that if i took you
to a restaurant and i gave you the menu
and you're like i don't care just bring
me something
if i bring you [ __ ] mashed potatoes
and chicken wings that's what you
[ __ ] get
that's what you're stuck with if you
would have voted you could have looked
at the menu and maybe
you could have said i want soup in a
salad and i could have considered that
instead you didn't even bother to show
up and [ __ ] voice your opinion so you
got [ __ ]
cold mashed potatoes and [ __ ] chicken
wings dude i hope you're happy being a
four-year-old at the table
well it's i mean it's brutal for people
like like i'm
crazy liberal about a lot of stuff um
like biden and obama before him are very
center politically like there's a left
and a right when you talk about politics
and they're smack in the [ __ ] middle
center um between right and left we
don't really have a left
as far as parties are concerned in the
us we have a center and we have a
far to the right um and over our
my lifetime our lifetimes we've watched
it go from a little left to center and
right of center
to way way right of center and smack
dead middle
and a lot of that has to do with
young people tend to be more liberal on
stuff and more left leaning
and just don't vote in primaries and
small races and small elections
um turnout's getting much better for the
presidential elections but
in the primaries it's minimal
and that's like everybody's like man i
wish i was voting for bernie
it's like well dude's been in congress
as long as biden
you just never built that coalition of
people that are going to go nuts in the
primary
it's that younger voter base we've got
to get out to the other elections
and it's just not happening right now
and for the cannabis community
we're so [ __ ] big if we could unify
even for a minute it would change [ __ ]
globally
but it's so hard to get us on the same
page about anything man
yeah the simpsons nailed it uh south
park nailed it
uh family guy nailed it i'm gonna vote
to legalize cannabis
that was yesterday bro unfortunately
that's how a lot of us play the game
um you guys pick up a pick up our friend
yep do it mike get out and vote get your
friends out to vote make sure they're
registered
make sure they go down election day get
in line together sit there and [ __ ]
together if you have to
um social media will help you register
to vote instagram and facebook are
making it simple
just click if you open up one of those
apps or everybody's on either instagram
or
facebook or something on your phone
every app you open right now on the top
it's like are you registered to vote
because they want you to participate
do it it's easy if you're still not
registered to vote it's because you're
actively ducking it
like it's they're making it as easy as
it's ever been in our lifetimes
um i feel for places where i'm watching
people
wait five six eight eleven hours to vote
even this early and people are showing
up and wrecking numbers
all over the country um they're waiting
in huge lines
and in colorado i think the longest i've
waited in the last
10 years to vote is like 15 minutes
and part of that was because the
elevator is slow in the building
this year it took me about five minutes
uh open up the ballot
scribble in some bubbles because i know
who i'm looking for go in and scribble
all my marks fold it back
up sign it put it in an envelope and
then a few blocks from my house there's
a little uh
unfortunately bro they took a big trash
can and [ __ ] put a lid on it poked a
hole in it
and that is the official ballot box uh
before you put your ballots
but you drop them all in there uh yeah
so
it took me just a couple minutes and
drove up jumped out of the car and i
threw it in the collection box man yep
took a couple more it's more secure than
it looks
yeah yeah it's much more secure than it
looks took two with me so that some
other people didn't have to go out and
face covered conditions so they could
just stay on the couch and watch the
game
so i got three ballots delivered all in
one move yeah
i was gonna say if you guys are out
there and you need to vote uh go or if
you got a stone or a friend that won't
vote go pick them up take them to vote
help them to do it
a lot of us got ballots in the mail just
go over to their house and help them
fill that [ __ ] out make it fun
uh teach them and if you don't vote you
don't get to [ __ ] and complain about
how things are that's just how it is
yeah it's like literally if you if you
say that it sucks so you don't
participate like you're the reason it
sucks
it's it's your choices it's people not
voting
are why shitty people stay in elected
office forever
um it's because familiarity is
comforting
and people just don't vote in nor
in the numbers they need to it's bananas
like
our country seeks out other countries
when they vote
and we put it on the news and we clap
and applaud when they vote
but we don't go turn out to vote it's so
[ __ ] weird
um please go vote yes please please
please go vote
um i don't even care who you vote for
just get out and vote make your
answer just go participate and it's not
that hard to do it's not
once you're there it's real easy i said
earlier a lot of people can vote uh on
oh you can't do it online you can do it
through the mail right now your ballot
comes in the mail you just gotta
scroll in bubble auto system so easy
yeah if you don't know
anything other than that you're
registered
when the ballot shows up at your house
if that's all you know is that you want
to vote
when the ballot shows up at your house
you've got all the time in the world
to sit there and what's joe biden think
about this spend a couple hours on his
page
spent a couple hours watching videos of
him talk
what's trump think a couple hours
watching him talk
if you all have seen a ballot so far in
this election you know that those two
aren't the only two
listed under who do you want to vote for
for president maybe you all want to vote
for kanye check out his platform
please don't vote for that [ __ ]
but uh um it's so nice i was
thinking looking at the ballot this year
with all the different questions on it
what a pain in the ass it would be if
you had to go stand in a voting booth
and no one oh yeah yeah i definitely
want a crib sheet before i went into the
voting booth
which is perfectly legal i made one
before i even started
voting like i had a paper like a
guideline to help me
while i was doing my own ballot so i
didn't make any mistakes
um what was i gonna say helpful you
don't have to fill in all the bubbles if
you don't know one
you don't have to fill in everything if
there's some local [ __ ] that you're like
i don't even know what the
[ __ ] that means you don't just skip it
it's not a test in school
just you can vote for the president and
whoever else you want that you're
comfortable with and
there's like 170 [ __ ] bubbles on
there fill out five of them you'll be
okay
there were two people locally this round
that i do not like as people and i do
not like these candidates who were
running unopposed
and so they didn't get a vote for me
exactly um
they're running on a post it doesn't
matter there's nobody to vote against
but uh they don't get my vote and on
election night they're going to see it
because they're good they report it if
you watch the news it's called an
undervote
and uh they they list it for like
um say for example biden voters
in in our area the people down the
ticket democrat
if they get less votes than biden did
they listed as an undervote
and so it can be like jeff got a
thousand votes mike only got 740
and it'll say it underneath that i'm
pointed out is an undervote
so yeah [ __ ] them that's my little dig
to them nice
you could have just wrote my name in the
in the opposition spot and voted for me
bro
uh missed opportunity yes people please
vote
you all like it when we ramble right now
we're rambling about voting
just get out and vote yes and i promise
you the next podcast will be
heavily cannabis oriented if you've made
it this far you probably
aren't too concerned about that uh and i
try not to let mike know that cannabis
people checked out now they're already
gone if they no offense to you mike if
they're interested in cannabis only
they've already checked out they won't
even know
i see numbers on youtube it's cool yeah
uh no i have you here because
uh you may not get all of the viewers
but the few that do stick around for you
not the few the the
kind folks that do they [ __ ] love you
you've got a cult so we're always gonna
have you on
the white mic division of the irie army
that sounds weird so let's not put it
that way again
but yeah your your little sect is uh you
definitely have your own little
your club in the back of the club so i
love it i appreciate it folks thank you
very much
and uh i absolutely love all the shout
outs and the the support i get through
emails and patreon and
um feel free to reach out to me y'all i
i like chatting
and i'm stuck at home with the kids all
the time so i'll probably reply if
you're going to tell them how to
to reach out you got to tell them how to
do it uh you can find me on
patreon it's patreon forward slash white
mic you can find me at twitter at
nemopunk15 you can find me on facebook
at pueblo for sensible cannabis laws
there you go great ways to find my
support is patreon if you've got a long
question
feel free to send it to the show's email
address yes the show's email address is
grow from your heart at hotmail.com
thanks mike good toss there
um what i was going to say was oh
support mike on patreon
i do all the cool kids are doing it you
should do it for some reason mike typed
in 720 so i'm giving him 720 and not 710
a month i don't know if he did that on
purpose
uh but uh just slapping it together
there since you're a 311 fan i'm
surprised you don't have a 311 tier
that was just the thing i thought you
should that's one of the new tiers
that's going in i was i have a little
list planned out of different stuff i
want to do with the patreon but
if y'all have any ideas feel free to
shoot it to me because i'm
kind of reaching i've got new stuff
coming up and there will be more patreon
things involved with what's coming up i
just i
i smile so much when i think about it
i've done so many cool things they're
coming up i can't reveal it yet
i'm the kind of guy that like if i built
a new car from the ground up you
wouldn't see that car until it had
nitrous in it and i was [ __ ] flying
down the track would be the debut
unless it doesn't have nitrous and
wheels yet so uh once we put some wheels
on this [ __ ] we will put it on the
track and we'll [ __ ]
flex don't worry i'm ready uh but
support mike
that's where i think i was going with
that uh patreon there will be more stuff
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart if you want to support the show
also support seeds herenow.com and use
coupon code gfyh10 when you check out
that will save you 10 off of your order
that applies to everything throughout
the store not just
irie genetics products that was a
question from somebody
if you're watching us on listening to us
on apple podcast stitcher radio spotify
anything like that
i highly recommend that was rude i'm
sorry i did that in your earbuds i
highly recommend
that you check out the show on the
youtube channel go to youtube search for
the grow from your heart podcast
click on the subscribe button also click
on that little bell that will give you a
notification every time i put out a new
episode
you will get notified you will never
miss any of the grow from your heart
content
i'll be putting out a lot of great stuff
lately i think you will enjoy it
uh like mike said earlier if you've got
comments corrections questions or
concerns the email
is grow from your heart at hotmail.com i
would love to hear from you
don't be freaking shy i want to thank
mike for hanging out dude mike that was
a great presentation good conversation
uh just the right amount of rambles uh
thank you bro it was a good time
appreciate it man thanks for having me
um
i need to get over and dab get back into
the old studio
or the all new and improved studio
do a live episode that would be awesome
yes it would mike don't feel like you
have to wait for me
thank you so much sorry bro i just
talked right over you don't feel like
you ever have to wait for an invite to
come on the show if you've got something
to say
something to talk about if you just want
to hang out bro send me a message we'll
zoom it up i'll make a podcast out of
it uh the people love having you on here
so look forward to the next time we got
you on the show bro
love being here man thanks for having me
thank you listeners thanks for sticking
with us this long
that is it thank you guys vote there we
go stay
there you go mike said it all i think
that is time to wrap up the show
um i'll be back in a couple of days with
the solo show that will be heavily
cannabis focused i'll leave the politics
and the nonsense out of the next one
this one was very important in my
opinion thank you mike
thank you guys for listening i want to
give a big shout out to a listener who
goes by jg
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me