[Music]
man we got to turn on the mics huh that
might help jeez what's up everybody it's
time for another episode of The Grow
from your heart podcast time for episode
number
58 man I hope you guys are as dabbed out
as we are I'm not even going to do the
big old long intro thanks for joining me
everybody I do have to give a big shout
out to cat and CP from the Mystic Roots
band we are high as [ __ ] speaking of we
what's up Spence what up what up joining
me across the table is my buddy Garden
of Weeden he showed up with a Mothership
rig and a Pelican case I knew we were
going to get wrecked as soon as he
walked in let's do one quick ad and then
we're going to get to this show uh this
organic portions of this podcast were
brought to you by my good friends at the
Rocky Mountain worm company visit the
Rocky Mountain worm company in Colorado
Springs for fresh worm castings African
nightcrawlers red wigglers and all of
your organic soil amendments the Rocky
Mountain worm company has dragonfly
Earth medicine products in stock now uh
you can get the same worm castings that
I use the same casting that Spence uses
the same casting that Sean and Jesse use
you can get them all through www. Rocky
Mountain worm company.com or if you're
in Colorado visit them at 411 Tiana
Street and Colorado Springs Tiana hey
it's the [ __ ] literally that is the [ __ ]
turn down the music here it's loud in my
head uh always this podcast is brought
to you by high gr indoor growing suppli
wise shout out to Jesse shout out to
burn also big shout out to Spence dude
thanks for coming to the grover meeting
the other night sure uh that kind of got
chaotic it wasn't much of a grow lesson
we just smoke too much weed we all
smoke sometimes we should get a like a a
board well I'm going to prepare
something next time so that it's not
just a bunch of smoking let's do a
question box so at the end there you go
everybody has to do a question to have
idea and you just pick it out and we'll
answer we'll try to answer whatever
questions people have uh guys if you
listen to the show and you come to the
Growers meetings all you got to do is
email me or tweet me and I will uh base
my next lesson for The Growers meeting
around some of your questions also we'll
do that so shout out to I gr and or
growing supplies uh they have a Denver
location 6271 Beach Street also 618 East
4th Street in beautiful peblo Colorado
the next time you shop at high gr indoor
growing supplies tell them you listen to
The Grow from your heart podcast and you
will get commercial pricing on your
entire order that's [ __ ] super sweet
super fat deal everybody wants to save
some money Spence you had something to
say go for it bro so I just try to take
a a selfie that said episode 58 and
there's a dab like right over my camera
to where you it's like gold it's all
cloudy that is good dab life for sure
yeah you know you you know you're a dab
if your phone is sticky and has dabs on
it if you go to pick up your car keys
and there's half a dab stuck to it I had
a dab in my beard the other morning when
I woke up and I don't know what the hell
happened there but dab life you got to
give a shout out to the dabs and what's
up with you taking selfies on the show
that's OG right there OG triple triple
big shout out to the sponsors did quick
ads cuz Spence is here and we're high
and I just want to get to the
conversation I don't want to ramble
about commercials you guys don't want to
hear a lot of commercials but if you
guys are interested in sponsoring the
show send me an email it's grow yourart
hotmail.com I'll get you all of that
info so uh smints texted me the other
day he's like let's do a podcast dog and
so I said what do you uh want to talk
about and he said canopy management so
we're going to jump right into it that
was a good three minute intro I like it
I like it no Rambles no [ __ ] so
canopy management I've been watching
Spence follow uh a guy named Greenworks
on Instagram so a lot of this will be
inspired by our buddy Greenworks big
shout out shout out to the homie shout
out to the homie I choked when I said
that I guess I'm not allowed to say that
that was odd man so uh yeah shout out to
Greenworks he kind of inspired Spence to
set up some really killer uh cage like
uh not really cages the cages Holding On
Top do you want to explain how you did
it or do you want me to keep rambling
for you all right so it's essentially a
single plant scog to where you have
uh we use bigger pods Greenworks uses
27s I'm pretty sure something like that
I use right around 20s um so it's a 20
gallon pot I've seen them and they look
pretty big they're about 22 in around
about 18 in tall they're they're huge
maybe even more than 18 maybe about 24
in tall the plants the oh yeah the pots
are 2ot tall probably easy um but it's
just it's it works for what it is it's
all about you know working the surface
area you're giving especially like in
areas where they limit plant counts you
know what I'm saying that that that
could do a lot of things for
people I'm writing down the word surface
area CU that's a good thing to think
about we're going to go back to that so
yeah this for people with limited plant
counts in Colorado well in our location
they're definitely messing with plant
counts and uh we're not going to be able
to grow as many plants as we used to so
what Spence has done he's taken these
giant pots and he takes a plant and he
build a uh PVC sort of a frame around it
so it's he's got a square frame now
above the plant how big is that square
um anywhere from 4X it's a 4x4 Square
cage basically you build a a cage out of
your PVC and you do layers of Trail list
for support um you know some people do
I'm not the only one that does it by the
way there's a lot of people now that are
that are trying it because it works I
mean it's it's more bang for your book
if you have you know especially it's in
my opinion it's strain dependent um you
can still get good yields but you'll get
better yields out of you know strains
that are built for that system Gorilla
Glue loves it loves it Bounty Killer
loves it you know what I'm saying so
like those moonshine Haze that Haze
plant loves to just grow all inside that
net so you know there's things like that
that works and cookies they'll do decent
but not like you know a gorilla glue
would do so essentially it's a you know
4x4 cage with you know multiple um
trellises and then you you know will
lollipop from the soil to the first
trellis you know so everything from that
first trellis up
will be just nugs naked okay yeah wow
all right so you got you got your frame
you got a square then you put a net over
and then you just got excuse me guys I'm
choked up from the dabs but then you
just got a bud going through each part
of the screen and you put another screen
on to support it and then if it gets out
of control because it's Gorilla Glue you
got to put another third screen up there
if you need to and and then but then
again it's more about you know canopy
management like making sure while it's
you know especially through the stretch
phase from day one of flower till day 21
22 when it's growing like crazy you'll
want to get in there and really like tie
them down make sure they're not growing
out of what they need to so it's you
know with those trellis Nets I think
they're like 3x3 squares or 4x4 squares
you know you want to try to essentially
get a nug or a cola to hit every single
one of those squares I mean there's I
don't know if there's 60 of them on a
plant so just you know the surface area
works okay wow okay so how uh early in
veg do you start manipulating the screen
so um typically what I do is I'll go
from um a one gon pot or a clone to a
one gallon and one gallon to a three and
I'll let that three kind of get bulky in
that three gallon and then straight into
the final pots and then give them you
know five six weeks Veg it's really not
as long as people think it is it's
especially when it's strain dependent
and strains grow you know faster than
other strains yeah and it's going to be
worth it in the end you're going to get
the weight in the end so once you you
know find your strain um that you want
to use you know you basically are
training it through the Nets you know
what I'm saying so if it's getting too
tall throw another trellis on it make it
go back under the trellis you know what
I'm saying keep bending it yeah you can
keep bending it what I like to do is I
like to just kind of on your first
screen you kind of spread it open and
then you let all the insides grow up and
everything on the outside's going to
grow okay around in the cage so all
those little shoots that would just be
cut off if you're lollipopping normally
you're going to grow into actual bra
yeah they're going to go straight up
into branches so with the Gorilla Glue
you're going to get long extended
branches out of those like I have
branches from like the bottom of the
stock that shoot clear up to the top
damn canopy management okay I I read an
article a long time ago that kind of
introduced me to this idea the article
was actually called growing on the grid
is what I think it was called and the uh
author was Eric bixa I'm going to Google
that just to make sure but uh he was
used to be a writer for high times and
he wrote an article about this I'm
searching his name while I talk
but I'm pretty sure that's it I want to
make sure because I want to give you
guys a reference yeah it's called
growing on the grid with Eric bixa it'll
kind of uh if you guys want to read more
about it this is kind of we're going to
give you the uh the in action in
practice sort of talk Eric bixa is he
writes a lot so he's going to give you a
really technical explanation on it
however I'm not sure how many times he's
done it Spence here has done it are you
messaging
Greenworks no we're going to try to get
Greenworks to call in one day and we'll
talk to him we've got I just actually
learned how to uh record quality phone
interviews using FaceTime uh I probably
can do it with Skype also I just haven't
experimented with that yet the other
night I opened up FaceTime and played
around and I'll be able to record so if
you guys want to be on the show and
you're far away FaceTime is now the way
to do it it'll be great Greenworks I'm
inviting you call us um speaking of
FaceTime I'm going to get uh I want to
talk about this guy in a couple of
minutes but I'll want talk more about
can canopy management but I have a phone
interview planned with a guy named soil
grown from Instagram we'll talk about
his Tech here pretty soon nice yeah so
you've got this uh 20 gallon pot full of
soil um you've got you said you go from
a clone cup into the 1gallon pot into
the three and then the three goes into
the 20 um do you top before you
transplant into the 20 at all
[Music]
um I I'm not really a big topper
depending on strain so like for the
system Gorilla Glue I don't it's a plant
to me some people do top it um but I'm
more of just a kind of you know working
it through the net so I'll take one
branch and take it all the way to the
left side and take this branch and take
it to the right side and eventually in
that system it's going to fill itself
back up W I didn't realize it would work
that extremely so if I've got like if I
took my whole arm and just bent it over
it's going to just make little shoots
and this is just going to be horizontal
for 4 feet across the room pretty or 2
feet from each room yeah so essentially
what you want to do is you you know as
your you know your colas grow your nod
stack uh vertically they grow together
up so if you were to bend that Branch
all the way down you're taking each one
of those Bud sights turning them up
which creates more Bud sights on that
plant than you would get stacking it
together okay so you're not going to you
may not get as many longas you won't get
like giant colas but you'll get a bunch
and it's all about the space because
we're not trying to grow concrete
underneath the plant we're trying to
grow all of the space for the plant all
right that makes pretty good sense uh so
you don't top it all that's see I would
have topped them that's why I would have
[ __ ] from the very beginning some
strains I do um Gorilla Glue is one of
the ones I it kind of grows that's wild
it grows by itself it'll grow with his
eyes closed yeah we're probably taunting
a lot of people because a lot of the
world can't get their hands on a gorilla
glue cut but there's there's you know
there's some things I would do um early
in veg you know cuz you give them a nice
you know five six week veg so a couple
two weeks worth of you know fimming and
you know training and stuff like that
and then you know kind of once say 3
weeks before flower you got to got to
let them heal up a little bit yeah yeah
at least two weeks 3 weeks quit messing
with them so that they know what to do
cuz they are apical dominant they want
to know which way is up still they got
to build up some
hormones all right um man I have like
seven questions in my head and I can't I
was like which ask a
question if it's not Gorilla Glue uh
what other strain do you like to
scrog let's see cuz I know you've got to
killer Arsenal have you done the White
Widow this way no no this this is my
first go at it so like and it looks
impressive for his first go I'm blown
I'm blown away and it's I'm still
learning like the curve I'm still
picking up the curve which is you know
going from you know seven and 10 up to
20s and two plants that are two to three
times the size you know maintenance on
those plants like you always have to be
like cleaning up the bottoms and stuff
cuz imagine you know a 6ot plant that's
4 and 1/2 ft wide you know there's no
light underneath there so the things
like the leaves and stuff die off just
because they don't get light to survive
so you have to constantly be in there
picking them off um and things like that
it's a good thing to think about now I
like that you said that would have been
a six foot tall plant and that you've
gotten it down to four feet tall that
kind of puts it into a lot of
perspective for me yeah like my I'm
running gavitas in
a 9 foot ceiling room but it's all about
can you keep them down the light the
gavitas will work for you it's just all
about like in my opinion when you when
plants get tall and get close up to the
gavitas then they kind of feel how
powerful they are but when you get that
canopy yeah when you got that canopy
management all the way down you know
it's all about surface
area how do you have a prediction on how
much weight you're going to pull per
thousand watt light with this new system
well right now per th000 watt I'll
probably pull on my first
go probably 6 700 gram per Gorilla Glue
that's not bad at all that's over a
pound that's a pound and a quarter yeah
pound and a half if you're and if it
comes back right okay and that'll be
pound and a half with and it's only in a
4K I'm running a 4K gavitas and for a
six we veg that's not bad at all not at
all the plants really grow like when you
put them from a three gallon pot into a
plant a pot that's oh I've seen the
stocks of your plants and they're bigger
around than these microphones stand
they're almost as big as my arms and I'm
I'm not that big of a dude so like their
wrist sides for sure wow yeah it's
impressive your rooms look great I've
been in there well I've been in there in
a few days or so but I've been there
recently and they look pretty darn good
shout out to Big Mike Maddie uh Michael
oh everybody that keeps the Gardens on
track who else helps over there um the
crew t comes over T what's up cousin
Phil oh we can't forget Phil I I need to
get Phil on a on a podcast Phil is
really the the he raps Phil raps oh we
can let him come rap he can do all that
throw up a beat and let Phil rap He raps
better than I do I'll tell you that
bring Phil and slop can do some raps
together you guys were invited on the
show boys if you listen to this Michael
uh Big Mike slop Phil Maddie you guys
are always welcome whenever you want to
do a podcast just text me say can it's
podcast time can we do a live podcast at
the
[Music]
cup uh we couldn't do it like live
broadcasting but we from there yeah what
if I have a house and all that see I
talked about taking my recording
equipment to the cup and just taking it
to my hotel bring it to my house yeah
bring it to your house and we could do
it up there and record people call cool
people that's what I was thinking hey
hey guy you're cool come come podcast
with us you cool guys want to come be my
show
yeah if you guys are going to be this is
not set in stone but if you guys are
going to be in the Denver area during
the Cannabis Cup and you're down with
Spence and you want to take a dab with
roster Jeff in the garden of Weeden crew
um there's a good chance I will bring
some maybe not this big old setup but I
might bring some small recording gear I
just have a lot going on I don't want
this to disappear while I'm at the cup
or something like from the car or some
[ __ ] I get this is my livelihood so I'd
be crushed without it but uh this gear
some kind of recording gear may end up
at the can I've got my phone if nothing
else that works well but yeah let's do a
podcast or let's at least hang out at
the Cannabis Cup you guys and take some
dabs this show won't come out for uh
probably a week from it's tomorrow yeah
a week from tomorrow so yeah but they'll
have plenty of time it's just the middle
of March when this comes out let's meet
up to Canabis cup you guys let's take
some dabs I should have some uh Jeff OG
dabs if Spence is down to blast it for
me I'll let him do that no digity no
diggity let's do this all right where
were we we're talking about canopy
management I feel like we got a lot of
that covered um if you're not going to
do the scrags you can lollipop really
heavily that's another good way to make
space for what you've got uh kind of pay
attention get down on your knees and see
how far the light is getting into your
plants and when you don't see any light
hitting those leaves just clean that
[ __ ] off from the bottom there because
there's no light getting there it's
going to be a waste of space my op
there's also other ways of canopy
management like there's you can do
staking um I do lots of staking me too I
I honestly do both I I like the scrog
system but I still like the old school
you know State like look going in a room
and being 100 steaks deep in there and
it's like oh Lord that's how uh dread
over at River Rock does it if you walk
through there it's Stak Central those
guys got all the wood steak City yeah
yeah they got wood for days uh I like
some steaks I grow some i t I tend to
grow tall plants I use a seven gallon
pot and I veg them till they're about
three and a half ft tall so they end up
six feet tall by the end and that
requires either a T tomato cage or some
staking yeah I like the staking because
I can pull it apart and I can BR I can
support each Nug in a different area so
I can kind of do what you do you're just
surface area basically train it to like
this this cola's got this section this
cola's got this section you want to kind
of fill as many sections as you can yeah
yeah and if you think about what kind of
genetics you're using like we were
saying the Golden Goat or the Gorilla
Glue makes a whole bunch of heads M the
Golden Goat will make a whole bunch of
heads cookies doesn't really like to do
it so maybe grow a whole bunch of small
cookies plants like just if you can do a
bunch of twoot tall 3ft tall cookies
plants flower it yeah that's the way to
go with a plant like that just a sea of
green again G Kush just do a bunch of
small ones instead of one giant plant
it's all about the genetics and canopy
management I guess mhm yeah uh use a fan
you still need fans when you're doing
all this people forget about air flow we
can't stress enough about air flow
somebody was telling me they had powdery
Milo they couldn't figure out how to
beat it and they're asking what to spray
and I said Don't Spray something get a
dehumidifier and clean out the air in
your room so they're simple stuff cut
all that [ __ ] off if you can yeah cut
all that [ __ ] down if I see any bad [ __ ]
is going bye-bye bye-bye all right what
else you got about canopy management you
want to talk about something
different it's good 15
minutes uh canopy management um let's
see um what do you think about the
levels of your lights during flower to
help you know like in earlier do or the
first couple weeks of flower do you keep
them lower do you keep them further away
you know I kind of my lights don't move
uh I start sometimes I'll put my plants
on a 5 gallon bucket to get them higher
but for the duration of the grow my PL
my lights don't move I'm tall and I hate
moving the lights down where I hit my
head on them I keep them as high as
they'll go in the rooms um one thing I
do is I don't change out from the
halides to the sodiums for the first two
weeks of flower you stay blue stay blue
yeah and they keeps them I feel like
they don't stretch as far and uh when I
do the switch I see them start to bulk
up right away at the two weeks instead
of doing that extra week yeah and I
really think that that helps and I have
stopped doing the V with blue lights
yeah okay so they're just used that
probably that change from Blue to HPS
kind of gives them
a time span they got to get used to that
[ __ ] real quick I do dark periods you
know before flower and I was about to
say I've stopped doing that I don't uh I
just don't find it useful really it
doesn't do anything I used to veg under
24 hours and then I would veg for 24 and
then go dark for 24 and then start my
flower and I noticed it would trigger a
little more quickly but yeah uh it's not
enough time to do anything I kind of
like let my plants do their thing for
some reason I just feel like when I go
cuz you know when so I go 18 18 to six
yeah that's what I'm doing into flow so
usually like when they sleep they're
ugly you know they're just sleeping you
know what I'm saying I'm not the
prettiest person when I'm asleep um and
then when they you know eventually when
the lights come back on they get into
the swing of things and then you know
before the lights cut cut off they'll
start going back down and then when I
usually hit that um I 48 Hours dark
they're as soon as I go in the rooms
even when it's dark they're already
praying and ready I feel like they're
just preparing themselves for the time
change yeah they excited for it yeah
it's crazy how like you the plants will
be veg looking and then that dark period
you go in there and it's like oh [ __ ]
they're
ready plants are these plants tell us
what they want that's for sure I like
that guys don't be afraid to try a
different light cycle my mother plants
run on a 195 cycle recommended by D or
is it 195 yeah 195 recommended by DJ
Short and that's the best performance
I've ever had from a mother plant so
don't be afraid to experiment with some
stuff uh now I do the uh I do 186 in my
veg areas and then my flower I just go
straight 1212 because I don't really uh
I don't do the all the dark period I
don't do I do 122 the dark period is the
only thing I do just start flower some
of the best her I've ever grown was
actually grown under a uh under a single
Hood in a 5x5 Hydro Hut with a 600 watt
uh high pressure sodium and a 400 wat
metal hly in the same bulb and that
Grilla bulb that hydrarm makes the
double bulb yeah yeah and I used one of
those I liked it that was great great
butd it had great flavor it looked great
some of my best pictures came from that
run of flow it was definitely quality
buds my best grow of that headband cut
ever yeah what are you uh what are you
dabbing over there bro uh some Bounty
Killer say what nice shout out to the
dude that uh grew the Bounty Killer
what's up bro I see you over there I
know what you're
doing appreciate you every
day so uh you want to talk about
Greenworks for a minute or not greenw
works uh what's his name uh sh I wrote
it down cuz I keep for soil grown
there's so many of these new Instagram
names that I can't keep up honestly I
try to be on top of all the social media
but there's so many things going
on uh if you guys have something that
you want to hear about canopy management
that we missed remind me cuz we went
quickly uh there's still more to talk
about but we're uh we've done enough on
it that's like 15 minutes we're going to
talk about some new
[ __ ] oh you hear that you guys that's a
Mothership rig right over there it's a
little Mothership mini with the wing arm
mother [ __ ] carb cap on it it's a bounty
killer live resin life doesn't get much
better than that
y'all the look on Spence's face proves
it I'm not sure that he knows where he
is right
now your eyes your hoodie and the
microphone cover are all the same shade
of red don't worry I ain't worried I'm
just letting you know don't try to drive
home like that uh so there's this new
[ __ ] it's called rosin Rosen Rosen Rosen
I've been calling it Rosen I've been
calling it Rosen I've been calling it
Rosen Rosen Rosen Rosen whichever way
you want to do do it uh it's spelled r o
i n so we can't argue that uh I saw it
first on Instagram from a dude named
soil called soil grown this dude uh what
do you think bro how do you feel about
it I don't want to give away too much of
his Tech because we're going to have him
here on the show pretty soon
um I will gladly support somebody trying
something new for sure like no doubts um
I was listening to Hash church today um
shout out to Hash Church check that out
don't like don't freak out on me cuz I
say this cuz people argue about it all
the time but it's the first
nonsolvent actual not there's not like
water as much as you don't you don't
believe it it's a solvent um and the
butane and propane those are all
solvents but he's just using pure heat
to extract oils there's no you can't use
heat as a solvent heat and pressure
that's pressure it's pretty impressive
did you see the picture of the SL like
the whole slab he posted oh no I the I
saw one it's like rolled up in a worm
around a car had a giant one it was big
as his face so like he's been going in
lately yeah I've got a scheduled phone
interview with him uh he said Tuesday or
Wednesday he hasn't confirmed a specific
time but we're going to talk to him I'll
probably just piece that right into this
episode you guys if I can get him to
call me on time that's all I need and
I'll throw that into this show probably
right here so here's an interview maybe
hopefully with soil grown how you doing
today bro great man I'm doing good cool
man thanks for pulling some time away
from your work to join
us yeah not a problem
uh dude I'm just gonna I know you're a
busy man I'm just going to get right to
it and start asking a couple of quick
questions first of all can you explain
to me a little bit about what rosent is
and how you got the
idea um well okay rmch I think that
comes from uh from somebody named
compassion that I guess was uh on IC
mag um he does a he does a robing tech
with like a no
melt uh hash you know so you take your
hash your no melt and you can turn it
into
M by pulling all the uh the resin out of
the no you know with a double boiler a
bowl and your no melt so uh so I did
this uh different
method um I rosin I guess what rosin is
is technically it's just a form of resin
obtained from like plants you know okay
that's where like I don't I don't know
why it's called rosin I mean it's
similar like rosin what I know rosin has
was like you know for boat strings for
friction
but uh I don't know where the term
actually stuck in cannabis but that's
where I know it from and it's really
kind of related to resin you know in a
way okay all right but um the way I got
my my idea I mean it came from basically
I'm I'm a hash be you know so yeah I'm
GNA have my melt so I decide uh I need
to figure something out I have all this
snow melt and I remember back when uh
collected Nick put something on on uh
the IG about uh taking like a a flat
iron just for pressing you know just
press out your hash much simpler than
heating up a wand or you know doing
something like that you can get the
right temp just to press it out and have
a proper press
G well I used to take my uh wife's hair
crawler and I would uh sometimes I'd get
it too hot you know by accident I would
notice that it would separate you see
the oil and then the hash I wouldn't
think any this was like you know this
was a this was a while back so I didn't
think anything of it I would just pull
the parchment back up and now I have a
pressed Patty that was over pressed I
with too much sheat but uh otherwise it
was some press hash you know okay made
it smokeable made it better yeah you
know I made a little better how years
ago do you think that
was that was not too long ago maybe
about two years ago okay probably about
two years ago when I did that and then
uh yeah just doing like the FY teex
anything that didn't know I would triple
press it you know try to try to increase
the mou quality on it some stuff didn't
some stuff
did so what gave you the idea to just
start pressing straight buds without try
and hash in
there all right so uh so once I ran out
of my no melt all my no melt and turning
it into rosin and
smoking we just took I don't know we're
just sitting here smoking you know I'm
not I smoke flour but my thing is
dabbing I'm I'm oh yeah more the
extracts you know me too definitely
yeah so so we're just I'm sitting here
uh bullshitting with my uh
father-in-law and I'm like hey let's try
this I grabbed the nug he's like what
are you doing I put it in between the
parchment just like I would a h you know
a a rolled up ball a hash and uh my
surprise resin squeezed out of the bud
we were both in shock like no way so I
scooped up the oil did it again scooped
it up there was a little there was
enough on the end looked like dab so we
tried it
out and
uh and uh to my surprise you know melt
it to nothing nothing like no
residue and sometimes you get from even
good BHO will leave a residue sometimes
so that's impressive yeah yeah exactly
very sweet very [ __ ] cool man you got
lucky figuring that one out yeah I would
I would you know luck luck the way to
say it but uh I mean I just I'd say I'm
I mean if I didn't do it I did like if I
didn't sit here and smoke like I do
every day and I wasn't so much into the
to the concentrate aspect of cannabis
you I wouldn't be the one to respect the
Lu you know yeah man much respect for
putting in the work for putting in the
time to get to there and for loving that
the extracts as much as you do to find
that for us because it seems to be the
thing now bro you're blowing up on
Instagram yeah uh you know I didn't and
when I posted I really didn't expect it
I thought it'd be like you know
something some of these uh um hash
makers were like could could utilize for
all their the no notes and then once I
started posting up the flower I was just
thinking you know some people would be
like you know in awe about it but I
didn't expect that no way yeah bro can
you tell me just kind of a brief I know
it's just a pretty simple process can
you tell me kind of briefly how you do
it yeah I mean I would say it it's
probably the most simplest process of
extraction I would say uh I mean if you
want to do it the most basic way to do
it for anybody at home is just grab your
uh grab your lady's flat eye on your
hair straightener get the widest one you
can digital settings would be Optimum if
not I mean when I first did it I had it
up to
420° you roast buds yeah I mean the
Turin were I I I wasn't worried about uh
I was I wanted tur but I wanted that
melt you know so to my surprise I was
pulling melt out and now that I've
fine-tuned it a little bit and there's
going to be a lot more evolving to it
it's just in the beginning stage for
sure but uh you know it's fine tuning
and stuff you get those those turps out
of it but so you just get the uh the
straightening comb or the flat iron and
then just basically put some parchment
in there yeah so you put it between the
parchment and then uh put it between the
flat iron you want to do it in a quick
as fastest possible put it between the
flat iron and then press it as hard as
you can you know press it as hard as you
can for about I'd say one to two two to
three seconds depending like how hot you
got your your iron but you really you
hear it come out mostly it comes down to
trial and error and hearing that that
sound of knowing when to pull up and you
know knowing when you have it too hot
it's it's a lot of ear it really
is all right so I just got to practice
and waste a couple of buds but it
doesn't look like you're doing a lot of
buds at one time so that's not too big
of a deal to waste a couple
nuggets yeah yeah I don't do the the
hair straighten anymore I mean I do the
Press now yeah I see you doing big
things now yeah it's a little bigger you
know I'm still I have a lot of other
plans for for something uh make it more
efficient process but right now this
this seems to work it's if I can sign P
this to make it workable then whatever
goes on after it's just going to be
better there you go keep improving every
day that's the way this industry is
working so how are you doing are you
doing anything special to prepare the
buds do you like them a little moist you
like them dry do you like them crispy do
you like them
cured uh I'd say a properly grown well
cured but uh you mean that's how I would
look at it but that is too dry Works um
something that might have a little too
much moisture it probably will work I
haven't uh had too much like uh trial
with that I've had like fresh nugs and I
haven't had too many results with it uh
nothing nothing to to be ecstatic about
okay so it's better to let the moisture
come out a little bit let it dry
up and I don't know what how the
moisture is gonna affect the extract
whether we see it or not I I can't see
how it wouldn't you know moisture heat
and resin it's just somehow trapping in
there just like when you're pring some
not properly dried iwe you know you're
trapping moisture so I don't I can see
that being the same to this process all
right do uh do certain strains work
better do like indicas or sativas work
better or do you have a favorite strain
that works the best for make and rosin
uh right now I'm finding that indas are
are producing they have the most resin I
mean I've even had some real Frosty
sativas you only putting out like eight
9% but I've had some indicas P around I
mean anywhere from like 9 to 22% you
know wow that's impressive that's
getting up there with the the BHO
pools yeah I mean it really depends on
how much time and effort you want to put
into if you want to sit there and do it
as Point ons I mean you want to break
the the bud down if you're doing it in a
whole gram you're probably not going to
get the percentage you're looking
for on big scale it might suffice
because uh you're going to be how
efficient the process
but all right so break it up a little
bit or the more the more broken up the
better actually all right that's good to
know um does how does the flavor of a
Rosen dab compared to like a BHO dab or
a solventless dab are you still getting
good
flavors yeah H man it's it's
unbelievable I can't wait to send in
some of these samples for testing that
was be one of my next questions I was
gonna ask if you've had anything tested
or if anybody that you know has had it
tested yet yeah actually a foundation
extracts I think some somebody else had
some actually hash tested seemed like it
was pretty high in CBD okay I posted up
the results on my Ig page with the uh
the results from Foundation extract I
think it was like 83% THC and 8% turine
wow that's pretty man and I don't know
who I'm just guessing that it was made
off of a a hair straightener you know
okay so a little bit less uh control on
it have you seen any hatred from all the
BHO people the guys that spent thousands
of dollars on equipment and now you're
just doing it with a shirt
press uh yeah you know I've seen a
little bit of hate you know uh it's not
it's not bad some of it's more of like
on the down low some people are kind of
burnt and then most of the time D A lot
of people are just like just not giving
it a chance but then you know like I'll
see them I'll see some of these people
like changing their minds about it
they're trying it out once they try it
like can't knock it till you try it
right well that's how this industry is
though you know this industry is Cy they
make decisions right away yeah it is
you're right you're right it's just how
the way the world it's the way the world
works but you know when you do that
you're gonna be the one to miss out on
something like this that's truth guys if
you ever get a chance anybody that's
listening if you get a chance take a dab
of some rosin before you diss it try the
rosin Tech yourself don't don't be a
hater so bro are you be surprised there
you go how's the high is it similar to a
normal dab
yeah I'd say it's uh it's strong I would
compare it more to like uh iwe or like a
a hash daab rather than a b dab to me do
you get that heavy chested feeling like
you do sometimes from a water dab when
uh or an iwe dab do you get a that heavy
chested like thick feeling sometimes in
my opinion it's the smoothest dab nice
are you gonna be in Denver for the
Cannabis
Cup I'm still not 100% sure about the
the Denver cup but uh we're going to
most likely be in chalice this year all
right well if you were at the Denver cup
you better find me I'm a tall white guy
with dreadlocks I would love to Tech for
sure we'll definitely link we'll make
that worth our time do you think uh
you're GNA enter any uh contest or any
cups or anything like that anytime soon
bro
um I think the the next Cup going on is
that we that we're going to enter is
chalice we're setting up for we're
starting to prepare for it nice you're
going to put rosin Tech in there yeah
definitely going to see some uh
solventless he extracted oil
um and then I'm hoping to have some ice
wax in as well very cool I can't wait to
see what the rosin Tech does up next to
ice wax and also up next to BHO they'll
probably make a category for it by the
time that that the event happens but I'm
still excited to see it competitions as
far as I see I mean it's nonf I mean
don't they throw the clear in that
category yeah all right so you're in
that category you're going to you're
going to be competing bro you'll be
right up there with those guys I have
faith in it from what I've seen people
are loving it and the fact is you know
there's it's there natural Tes whether
it went through heat the process that I
went just can't forget that it's
solventless you know I'm not I'm not big
on smoking solvent solvent extracts
that's that's something that's in my
mind I have for years not I'm not
against it you know there's there's some
very
enjoyable extracts made from solvent but
I just my bird smoke
and and a lot of people seem turnning
that way lately too yeah and I you know
I see the clean meds movement going you
know it's definitely picking up well
thanks for uh supporting the clean meds
movement bro we need more people like
yourself that are aware of what we're
doing for the community and to our
bodies and with our medicine that's cool
I appreciate it and respect it a lot bro
yeah all for man for sure man I'm G to
wrap up this phone interview I told you
i' only take about 15 minutes of your
time we're getting pretty close to that
uh how can people find you on Instagram
uh on soil grown so uh sooil grown on
Instagram yeah or hashtag uh soil gr
Tech or I mean I don't really do too
much of the hashtags for the soil gr
Tech but uh you you'll find you'll see
the soil gr just type in rosch and
you'll definitely findr somewhere in
there there you go search for rosch on
Instagram you'll definitely find this
guy but do you have any shout outs or
anything you want to give or anything
you want us to look at since you've got
a lot of people listening to you
something you want to say to the world
uh I just I would just say don't knock
it not don't knock it till you try it
give it to try it just remember that
it's clean meds and uh you know although
it's a simple extraction process it does
take a lot of work and you know it's a I
would say I would call it a
connoisseur's extract connoisseurs
concentrate nice I like that all right
bro well I truly appreciate you calling
in for the show man if you ever have
anything else you want to say on the
show you've got my phone number uh stay
in touch with me if you're in Denver I
look forward to meeting you at the cup
man hey thanks thanks for uh a shot je
oh thanks thanks for being on the show
man go take a dab of some rosin for me
and I'll take a dab with some turpex BHO
for you definitely right on brother stay
up take care of yourself you too take
care peace Brother later all right that
was fun maybe that happened maybe it
didn't maybe it did maybe it did I don't
know hopefully it did but uh this dude
uh yeah you just heard what he said
hopefully right maybe yeah that's a fun
way to do a
podcast so uh Spence is heating me up
one of these Bounty Killer live res dabs
off the Mother Ship uh I might not be
able to talk for a couple seconds cuz
Spence likes to wreck
me get ready I'm ready bro I'm taking a
drink I'm grabbing the dab Spence holds
on to the rig for a little bit of time
because he knows I like to take dabs
that are too hot which we call glowes in
This Crew they're not even like super
glow but it's just hot it's a little too
hot I'll agree but I like the way uh I
like the way I get the dab when it's
that
way clunk he's just smacking this
Mothership rig on the table like it's
nothing
sounds so
cool oh that's me getting super high
right now is what that sound is the
sound of my brain is better it's like uh
bubble rapid
fireworks Pop Rocks pop rocks yeah my
brain feels like pop rocks that's what
I'm going to say next
time what do you uh what do you think of
the the RA in
um I'm Blown Away by it um he's using
equipment that everybody has I've seen
people use uh flat iron or I think black
people call that a pressing comb don't
they is that the same thing H comb yeah
yeah yeah they're not the same they're
not the same all right there's a girl
that see on One show that you were on on
One show that you were on I said you're
the only black person that's been in my
house I me in Colorado I grew up in
Southern California bro I had like all
kinds of Black Folk on my block but this
one girl Laticia she had she called it a
flat iron or a straightening comb I
thought it was the same [ __ ] but never
mind a flat IR maybe not I don't know
but these guys are using [ __ ] that's
around the house and handmade uh Adam
Han from handmade app Peril he showed me
his what he posted uh his slab because
of course he had a t-shirt press already
and he's like I got this game figured
out and he's winning but I'm amazed that
they're using [ __ ] that is just kind of
around the house and making Earl you
know solventless hash that is dab yeah
yeah I haven't tried it yet um I
actually I I lied I
tried um but I think it has more
something to do with the moistured
content of how your weed is dried like
weed down here is really dry so it's
just maybe I needed to do more pressure
or something like that it's just we'll
we'll talk to him here in a couple of
days and we'll SP that in so hopefully
by the hopefully by the time this airs
we've got his part to piece in and you
actually know cuz dude that rosin Tech
is great and if just just I'm going to
talk about it because I wanted to save
it and let him talk about it but maybe
we won't get his interview this dude's
taking a t-shirt press and he's modified
it and he puts a layer of parchment
paper a little layer of buds and another
parchment paper and squishes it for
about 4 seconds and lifts it up pulls
the parchment out and he's got pretty
much Earl it looks like yeah slides the
weed off into the floor and stops on it
all
day I've seen some dude who has a tea
jar and just once he's done with it he
makes tea in the morning with it cuz
it's still still got stuff in there he
didn't get it all out yeah yeah so big
shout out to at soil grown if he uh if
he called in and did that interview
extra super huge shout out if you didn't
still check him out on Instagram it's @
soil grown uh check out the Rosen Tech
it's really really really cool [ __ ] uh
since I'm going through my notes Here I
have to give a big shout out to Judy
what's up Judy hope you're listening to
the show I appreciate
it sorry I'm coughing from that dab I've
have one more thing to talk about that I
have to remind you guys um the prizes
have been shipped remember we did prizes
from episode 50 those have been shipped
uh two people never gave me their
addresses both of those Prize winners
were from Facebook you guys go on
Facebook uh and give me your address if
you want your prize you have until the
next episode airs to claim your prize
and if those prizes are not claimed they
will be uh sacrificed to the Cannabis
gods and recycled for future episode
prizes all right um I said that I said
that cool cool uh what else you got on
your brain bro how things been man you
been growing your ass off oh man just
getting ready for uh we're going to go
on a cup
tour so Denver's our first one then
we're going to
do
Oregon possibly Michigan wow Michigan
that's stretching out far it's it's one
of the smaller ones and they accept out
of state cards so oh sweet that's cool
you know and then
Seattle Seattle's fun bro I love the
weather and Seattle's off the chain yeah
and you got family there don't you yeah
so shout out to the family food the
weather all right see I got to start
traveling to more of these cups I'm just
a solo grower so I don't have anybody
backing up my grow when I go so it's
hard to uh hard to get away for three or
four days after that third day you start
like I don't I mean I when I had to go
to Vegas for the secret CR and I was
like oh my God I need to go home
somebody take me home yep let's just go
first flight I need to get there there
check on the plants and then I'll fly
back yeah yeah it's all it's about just
got to walk in the room make sure that
everything's alive one
time uh tweet me guys what do you do
when you go out of town and you grow a
pot how do you keep your plants alive
when you go out of town I'm just curious
I know what to do I just want to know
how you do it tweet me it's gfyh podcast
I'm curious I want to know tell me what
you do what um how's that uh your strain
you're working on going so uh right
before you came over tonight I was at
the GR space taken pictures of like 20
different phenotypes of black cherry Kim
and I've narrowed it down there's one
that is definitely a breeder uh it's
purple it's got the great bud structure
it smells like uh purple Laffy Taffy
it's got a weird and you can smell it
from far away it's got a weird
overpowering Aroma Laffy Taffy are SLA
right I don't like great Laffy Taffy
coincident I'm black and I don't like
grapes sorry I wasn't going there um but
I do like Laffy Taffy they sliming so
that flavor yeah yeah and the smell too
you can open a pack of Laffy Taffy and
smell it before you even eat it and
that's kind of how it is when I walked
in the room and I I could smell that one
plant all the time so I had to single it
out I was like this little [ __ ] right
here is going to be a winner and she
happened to be one of the best purple
phenotypes uh she grows a nice top Cola
nice structure so I'm going to use that
one and then there's one uh that's a
little lighter purple but has more of a
cam dog sort of a smell so that one's
going to be an option and there's one
with no purple also or no purple at all
but tons of tricomes tons of Trikes and
a great chemi kind of funky uh Cherry
resiny kind of smell so those three or
four females are going to get put in the
room with the black cherry male along
with I got a couple other girls that are
going to go in there I don't know if I
even want to say what girls are going in
there on the show cuz I got some great
strain ideas I want to see what they do
uh there will be some new black cherry
crosses coming up uh that won't have
that breeding project won't happen until
probably Midsummer maybe after the
summer summer heat kind of kills some
ideas around here yeah you got to shut
down some things uh right now I've got
Golden Goat a a reversed Golden Goat
male it's a female that's now a male in
a room with some lemon skunks so there's
more lemon Jeffrey being made there's
more Golden Goat seeds being made and
I'm creating sunshine girl and I've also
put gorilla glue in there so we'll have
yeah Gorilla Glue Golden Goat we're
going to need a name for that that be
kind of tight I don't even like Golden
Goat Weed but that might be tough uh
golden when I cross anything to Golden
Goat it makes it more resiny and Gorilla
Glue is already resining already so it's
going to be neat but uh there's also a
plant in there a headband plant and I
think I've told this story before the
last time I pollinated a headband plant
it died it died yeah so I put that [ __ ]
in there again we're going to see yeah
we're going to see if it up now just had
a bad day or was [ __ ] yeah if there's
something to that cuz I don't know what
I did last time yeah every other plant
was happy she wasn't [ __ ] with that
last time she didn't take that bukaki
very well she said or no just shriveled
up shriveled up uh you got any shout
outs you want to give to
anybody oh man oh I put you on the spot
you're about to take a dab and I hit you
up no I wasn't going to take a dab let's
see shout out to Maddie um Big
Mike Michael
sloppy Fong Phil Taylor
Stephanie sarak Nani Seda King Earl
Earl these guys have my mom and my daddy
oh nice that's the sweetest
uh what What's Her remind me what kind
of I can't think of what he is he's a
beardy I wanted to call him horny to but
he's a bearded uh bearded dragon dude he
looks like a he looks like a dinosaur
when you guys got him he was like micro
machine th yeah like the size the whole
thing is from head to tail was the size
of my thumb and now he's like the length
of my arm and that dude looks crazy now
he a [ __ ] he sits in his cage like
what's up I'll get you he's one of the
only like reptiles that when you say his
name he'll turn and like look at you so
it's like you can hear his name like my
SN I have a snake she she kicks it um
but Earl is on point he's got a picture
of a booty in there he'd be up there
like scratching the
booty funny you guys have uh the garden
of Weeden house is definitely one of the
funnest places to hang out you never
know what's going to go on it's chaotic
but they got the hookups there it's all
comfy and chill let's see uh smokers
club uh we'll be doing a booth at the
cup uh garden weed and smokers club
Booth look for me there I'll be hanging
out a little bit yeah it'll be it's
going to be a good time so enjoy 420 and
come hang out with us everyone's going
to be mad at me cuz I'm going to be out
of seeds by the end of the first day of
the C cup so this just how it works by
the time I get to Denver uh I'll be
there Friday and by the end of Friday
night I could be out of seat I'm trying
bu
before the C even starts yeah yeah well
you're here now let's uh let's talk in a
minute got a box over here with some iy
stickers all over it guess what's in
there I do owe a big huge shout out to
green and healthy cannabis in Colorado
Springs Colorado if you're looking for
the turpex on the Lolo cheap man they
got the Duran poison wax that is fire I
shouldn't even hype you up on that
because by the time you get there that
deran will be gone they'll have some
brand new [ __ ] that'll be even better
did he just tag Us in some he tags us in
a lot of [ __ ] yeah cuz they love us when
the drop oh yeah there was uh it was
probably Friday cuz uh know what day is
it it's it was Saturday there's a new
drop Saturday of new good stuff so every
few days they get new drops of great
great medicine over it green and healthy
cannabis it's uh 212 21st Street I think
it's South 21st I'm going to pull up the
correct address it was yesterday what do
you want the address yeah 212 South 21st
Street yeah there we go that's what I
think color Springs Colorado Springs
guys if you're in Denver if you're in
poblo if you are what's uh what's west
of Colorado Springs mountains right if
you're in those mountains if you're in
manitu Springs man if you're in what's
to the east that's uh that's just the
planes you're out there on the planes if
you're in Payton you're up in Diamond
Dave's neighborhood shout out no shout
out NE get a shout out
uh no shout out at all for that uh I
take no um yeah if you're in that area
go to green healthy cannabis and get
yourself some TPX medicine on the cheap
it's uh I don't rep other dispensaries
very often uh green and healthy cannabis
that's where Hunt is where the turpy
boys are that's the homies they're going
to be on I think they'll be on the next
episode I'm going up there Thursday to
record with them uh I'm ahead of myself
because an episode came out today and
then I've got one pre-recorded and then
I've got this one and then I'll have
hunt uh it's going to get [ __ ]
awesome here I'll have shows coming out
maybe uh I think the show I did last
week I'll put out on a Wednesday going
to have a Wednesday show this week or
last week it'll already special edition
boom yeah I watched this uh
have you seen the like the co bear
report on T so there's one I think it's
Kean Peele maybe but he was doing like a
black C report and they were talking
about Ferguson and it was [ __ ]
hilarious dog it was probably one some
funniest [ __ ] ion we we ain't going to
talk about it but it was hilarious but
you guys got to watch it also uh what's
the guy's name bungla uh just Google
buckl bunglow buckl I want to say
bunglow because uh there Joe Joe Koy has
a character called bunglow I think I got
him confused but uh
on YouTube Type in Russell phone pranks
um I can't think of the [ __ ] name of
the show right now oh [ __ ] we're GNA
Google it because it's worth it this guy
deserves a huge shout out he entertained
me the other day dude he is Hil shout
out to Fong too cuz Fong gives Fong is
where I originate on my Asian voices
from uh all right so what's going there
no come on dude what it
called onage pranks that's what it's
called Ownage Pranks yeah uh this guy
kills it I can't call to BU thear
TSX it's pretty good dude that's pretty
good so if you're bored you got some
time to kill check out YouTube check out
onage pranks uh any of the ones with
Tyrone in them are [ __ ] hilarious
it's all one guy doing all those voices
he calls people and harasses them but he
does call and apologize so he's not a
total dick but that's my recommendation
for the week I've never done a
recommendation for the week I guess now
that I've said that I'm goingon to have
to recommend something every [ __ ]
week huh God damn it oops I recommend a
mother K next week
then the week after that uh Vector
torches and then the week after that uh
root beer root beer [ __ ] yeah and then
the week after that we're going to go
with the gnail from
emotech that's plenty of recommendations
that should get you shout out to emotech
that should be long enough for you to
forget yeah shout out what's up giddy
thanks for the enail I need one for my
car bro do you have one with like a
power converter that plugs into the mini
that can PL Dash yeah with a suction cup
on it or something some Velcro so we can
velcro that [ __ ] to the dash you got a
radio attachment yeah cigarette lighter
hookup I'm about to do a dab you guys
then we're going to wrap up the show I'm
G to try to do the closing part of the
show right after this oh God this a big
chunky dab here we go say something
interesting
Spence
um I'm not really an interesting
person but I'm nice with a carb cap
though sometimes it's what I need from
you this likes to give me big fat nasty
dabs he knows how I like it I don't even
like big dabs either I think that's why
I do
it cuz I don't like them so I make other
people do it oh yeah pop rocks in the
brain there we go see I remembered oh my
brain is sticky now all right guys we're
going to wrap it up because I'm super
duper high like level 11 don't worry I'm
going to be all right I ain't going to
fall over nothing I'm already in a chair
nothing can go wrong game oh what do you
recommend if you play have you played
Destiny it seems to be what everybody's
hooked up it's not my team all right
then you like those sports games don't
you I like basketball and football but
recently I've been playing Grand Theft
Auto [ __ ] [ __ ] up five stars cruising
hey Tony if you have my grand theft auto
five let let me get that back cuz I just
got inspired yep you know we can play on
what what do you have I got an Xbox uh
then we can't be Bros online CU you're
the PlayStation
Clan Spence kills it on the basketball
game though nobody at the house can beat
him they're all pissed off at him every
time I go go over there no no that's a
lie that is a lie and then the football
I win football uh the UFC one is fun to
watch you guys play too cuz I think
someone's going to break a controller
one day over there dude I've almost
that's why mine's broke right now cuz I
like slammed It On The Ground man I
can't tell you smoke more weed don't get
so stressed out over the video games bro
just all right yeah end of the show
right onto the garden of Weeden crew for
going to the gym every uh yeah shout out
shout out to the gym um the fitness
these guys have been killing it with
their Fitness we'll talk about that on
another episode let's talk about um next
episode let's talk about some healthy
[ __ ] yeah yeah we don't always have to
talk about just weed because this is
part of our uh part of what we're doing
too be I think taking care good care of
my plants has taught me to take better
care of me and I've said that
before all right guys thanks again for
listening to another episode we've gone
on and on we keep saying we're going to
wrap it up but we dab the [ __ ] out and I
can go as long as I want uh I'll be back
in a few more days uh the next episode
should be hunting the freaking turpex
boys that should be awesome
don't forget to check out the sponsors
the Rocky Mountain worm company High gr
indor growing supplies uh if you're
interested in sponsoring the podcast or
if you have a product you like us review
send me an email it's grow from yourart
hotmail.com guys I say this every time
now that the show is over please go to
the iTunes Store search for grow from
your heart find the review section give
me a festar rating after that type in a
comment let me know what you think of
the show and I will read your comment on
a future episode Stitcher keeps [ __ ]
with the way comments are posted so post
it wherever you can and I'll find it on
Stitcher if you have something to say
and you're not into the social media
thing you can find me at grow fromy
heart
hotmail.com uh don't forget the show is
available on iTunes Stitcher and every
single episode will always be archived
on iry gentics
color.com don't forget about the
donation button on the website it's iry
genetics.com click on the grow from your
heart podcast tab at the top right
there's that donation button not begging
but if you want to throw something in
there I would definitely appreciate it
I'll give you a shout out on the show we
are on all the social media sites just
search for us grow from your heart uh
Twitter it's gfyh podcast um dude thanks
for coming
Spence for sure for sure uh we'll have
Spence back on in a few episodes we'll
talk about healthy stuff we'll talk
about uh man can I tell them that you
were about to embark on a breeding
project I just did so I hope I could say
that on the show yeah we'll talk about
it yeah we'll talk about that in the
future so until uh next time you guys
take a fat dab give your mom a hug for
me bir
[Music]
we