[Music]
in the house
greetings from podcastville this episode
of the show is brought to you by our
friends at seedshearnow.com
seedshearnow.com offers seeds from all
of the industry's
leading breeders including miss jill
genetics duke diamond and of course irie
genetics
everything at seeds herenow.com is
backed by their award-winning
satisfaction guarantee
and for my friends on a tight budget
seeds herenow.com offers several packs
for under 30 dollars as well as amazing
monthly sales make sure to use coupon
code gfyh10 while checking out to save a
few bucks
again that is coupon code gfyh10 while
checking out
at seeds here now dot com
welcome to the show podcast world it is
time for episode 580 of the grow from
your heart podcast
you know i like to start the podcast off
by talking about what i'm smoking
today i've been taking dabs of tkd
number 10 live batter
this is a blend of chem d and triangle
kush
i've been trying to take a dab and
experience the flavor before i read the
label and let the label influence my
mouth
i took a dab and i said wow that tastes
like o.g kush and sour mothballs
then i read the label and it says the
flavor should taste
like sour petrol and lemon so
there's kind of a cushy description in
there and the sour part fell in but i
got a sour
cushy mothball which may not sound like
the most pleasant description unless
you're a cush connoisseur
and that is [ __ ] delicious i loved it
it was tremendous i expected it to be
more of a uh
kind of a punch to the face kind of lay
me down a little bit honestly it made me
kind of
kind of go it got me moving it got me
chatty i was organizing my recording
space here real nice you ever smoked
those kind of concentrates you're like
i'm gonna record a podcast
next thing you know uh you're not
recording anything you're [ __ ]
organizing your space and checking your
facebook and
looking at instagram is that kind of
concentrate so
big shout out to the tkd number 10
live batter for making a great podcast
happen
uh ladies and gentlemen in this episode
i'm going to read a couple of
patreon messages and emails before we
get there let's do a few shout outs to a
few members of the
710 club of course the 710 club
excuse me i'm all choked up about the
710 club thank you guys i love your
support
anyway the 710 club are the folks who
support us on patreon at the 7.10 a
month level or higher
so with no further ado let's give a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to humble green thumb
stay humble brother big shout out uh
let's send a girl from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to the flava
maker keep making those flavors bro
let's send a big thank you shout out to
nova scotia grower big shout out to our
canadian friends thank you for listening
up there
let's follow that one up with the big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to ill
tempered sea bass i get a lot of cool
names in here and that one will never
leave my brain an ill-tempered sea bass
i just see a giant pissed off sea bass
maybe not pissed off but ill-tempered is
the right word ah
you can't smoke weed if you're a sea
bass because you're goddamn under water
maybe you can i don't know maybe you got
some tech i don't know about shout me
out if you do if you got that underwater
smoke tech
for our sea bass friend we could show
them the [ __ ] out let me know let's
follow this one up with a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to black hawks fan
i don't know enough about hockey to have
any jokes but go avalanche because i'm
in colorado that's what i'm supposed to
say
uh let's follow that up with a big shout
out to omar t
let's follow that one up in the big grow
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out to gangster
and last but certainly not least let's
send a big thank you shout out
and a fist bump to our friend j g
big thank you and big shout out to
everybody who supports the podcast on
patreon
if you're not already supporting the
show and you'd like to learn how to do
so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need will be
right there on the screen and of course
i did include a link in the show notes
and in the video description
to make it easy for all of my friends if
you see me playing with the camera it's
because when i did that fist bump toward
the camera it really messed up the
lighting here
trying to undo that redo that there we
go i think i may have fixed it
that was funny to me you got to watch
the video to see what happened i
fist bumped at the camera and the
lighting went to [ __ ] hopefully it'll
re-auto focus for me
using the macbook i do promise you there
are improvements coming
um where else are we going to go from
here those are the shout outs follow us
on patreon
thank you let's not waste too much time
let's get to the email
portion of this podcast i can get quite
chatty and quite rambly sometimes
let's not let too much of that happen
the first message
in today's episode comes from our friend
papa wheely what up papa wheelie good to
see you
haven't heard from me in a minute this
one goes like this hey ross to jeff
it's papa wheely again hey funny story
revel into your outdoor rant episode
maybe two weeks ago i went on facebook
well that's where you screwed up so i
went on facebook in a group called
cannabis growing and
tips or i think that's the name anyway i
don't remember when i joined but
sometimes
something in a post catches my eye when
i'm on there there are a lot of facebook
groups that talk about growing cannabis
and consuming cannabis i try to be
helpful and encouraging in those groups
but sometimes i have to leave because
there are people
uh you can get really really bad advice
in there and that is a lot of what
inspired this podcast i would see
a horrible advice and i said horrible
you're gonna get that h across the
screen again horrible
i would see horrible terrible advice on
social media
on forums mainly i started in the forums
reading
roll it up and other forms from back in
the day and i would just see people say
like well spray that plant with gasoline
and i'd be like wait what the [ __ ]
and they would mean it they'd think that
it's a really good thing and they're
giving advice
and i think a lot of the advice i saw
was going to compound problems yeah it
may look like you
solved the problem today but tomorrow
you're gonna have gasoline-flavored buds
like
so it just drove me crazy that's a lot
of what started this podcast seeing that
[ __ ] on facebook
and i agree with you uh it can be tricky
to navigate i want to catch up and fall
back into this one
there is more to this it says so as soon
as someone posts a question and needs
uh so as soon as someone posts a
question and needs help there are like
20 plus comments almost
instantly some are the wrong answer some
are right or
ask the right follow-up questions but
the thing i hate is that 25
of the people talk [ __ ] and make fun of
the guy or his plants on his first grow
or they are just
rude yeah it's ridiculous i try to help
people
people get mad at me because i ask
questions i say well what was your goal
when you fed the plants
[ __ ] humans i don't know whatever you
feed the plants what was your goal when
you fed the plants i just picked humans
from bob's burgers that's where that
came from if you wondered why i pulled a
strange reference because there were
humans in the burgers
but why did you feed your plants [ __ ]
mushrooms why'd you pour kombucha
in there what was your goal when i asked
them that they're like well who do you
think you are i'm like
you're on social media asking for grow
advice and i have a lot of it and i just
want to know why you're what your goal
is and maybe i can steer you in the
right direction but yes people are
confrontational
uh and really ridiculous and boastful
and territorial on social media
so it goes on it says so a guy posted
last week asking what was going on with
his plants and a pick
i was thinking heat stress but couldn't
tell for sure but me and most of the
growers
are having the same issue right now yeah
because it's hot outside uh
these people ripped them apart because
he's about posting such a shitty plant
and
all sorts of [ __ ] isn't it sad but then
you go look at those people talking [ __ ]
you look at their plants
they're even worse they're even sadder
they don't realize they've got [ __ ]
spider mites everywhere
like my plants look amazing and you're
looking like you've got spider mites you
got more [ __ ] spider mites than weed
in there
those are the people that are talking
[ __ ] usually it says but me and most of
the growers oh where am i now i lost my
spot so i responded
to the guy i said what you need to do is
join cannabis or listen and join
the grow from your heart podcast or the
dgc that is awesome and thank you for
reaching out to somebody on social media
and letting them know about the podcast
and about resources that are available
to them a lot of people don't even know
that we exist
i don't do a lot of podcast advertising
you guys are my advertisers the word of
mouth that you provide
uh the algorithms on itunes or apple
podcast and stitcher and spotify and
of course youtube uh those are where i'm
advertised and big shout out to the dude
grows crew those guys
uh give me a lot of advertising so thank
you scotty real the dude guru
everybody behind the scenes they give me
a lot of support uh that's where i get a
lot of advertising a lot of follows come
from the dude grow
show so i'm gonna reciprocate now if
you're following my show and you have
not listened to the dude grows show the
dude grows podcast
wherever you were listening to me that
show is available i encourage you to go
listen to the dude grow show
uh very uh friendly show same spirit
same idea same goal we want you to grow
better cannabis and have a good time
doing it
and i don't feel any rivalry any uh
competition there's nothing like that
those are my bros we hang out we smoke
together
we do a different show it's a different
style it's a different format there's
multiple dudes there there's just
usually the one of me we've had mike on
the show a couple of times which we may
want to address here while we're talking
but
um yeah mainly it's just me here so it's
a totally different vibe i've got a
different approach to growing sometimes
they've got a different approach to
growing sometimes
but all that information will add up and
then you can use what works best for you
i'm gonna get back on track like i said
[ __ ] rambly from the dabs anyway
uh make sure you follow the dude grows
crew the dude grows show great people
uh the dgc when i say dgc that means
dude grows crew that is the group of
people that follows
the dude grows show i call the irie
genetics followers the irie army
i don't know if the podcast folks are
the irie army as well you can be irie
army if you want we've never given them
an official name but
let's keep on moving because dabs and
rambles anyway
because this community and facebook
blows yes the community on facebook
can blow i try not to let it get to me
but sometimes
uh you do the thing it looks like you
just got in a fight with your girlfriend
or you just got a shitty text from work
or something where you just close the
app and throw your phone down you're
like ah
like facebook makes me do that that's
the only app that i get that feeling
from when i just go uh
i seriously face palm like [ __ ] and
everyone's like what's wrong like that's
just facebook
so i stay off of there a little bit
because i don't need to poison myself
with that
i try to put up a big filter when i'm
doing it let's keep going it says
um i'm not perfect but [ __ ] people like
that
i kind of agree with you i try to say
[ __ ] certain people but yeah [ __ ] people
that are like that on social media
actually no hug a hater give people like
that a big hug just send them smiley
emojis and be cool with them
they're not going to change no matter
what we do so we can hate them we can
love them
uh every village has its idiot every
village has its [ __ ]
somebody's got to be that guy so as long
as it's not you that's cool
um it says i could never even i could
never even break someone's balls without
at least
knowing them right people are so
comfortable breaking your balls on the
internet
um after that episode that mike and i
put out we got our balls broken over the
internet luckily
um having 500 episodes under my belt a
nice following on
instagram i do instagram lives i've been
at this for a minute i was on periscope
before periscope was popular
i've been doing this for a while i can
handle some trolling i'm not asking for
it i'm not saying troll me but
uh the messages and the uh the
non-encouraging words that's what i'm
gonna say that we got on
youtube and emails from the last uh show
uh yeah people
they're they're keyboard warriors when
there's no uh face to face contact
they'll say whatever the [ __ ] they think
they can say
uh but they don't say that [ __ ] when
you're in the same room with them it's
way different
it says there's a lot of that out there
now and no one wants to be the one who
doesn't know and if there's 50 replies
chances are it got covered yes that is
the truth most of the time the useful
information gets buried by all of the
[ __ ]
i will post a link to the podcast in
three or four sentences about what we
can do for your grow
and it'll just get you got to filter
through to even find it it's
feed it vinegar spray it with fire dip
it in bleach and then there's my useful
answer
and it just gets overlooked and then
people laugh at me for giving useful
advice
like your hippie magic won't work and
i'm like what the [ __ ] a commercial
[ __ ] grower probably do commercial
consultations and you should pay me for
the [ __ ] sentence i just posted but
they don't even enjoy it
um we're gonna keep going it says but
you would be surprised so people just
argue with whatever the other
guy said then someone says then it's
time to battle and the guy posting is
stuck there
uh with no answer and confused and he is
racist yeah that's
that's [ __ ] funny yeah it turns into
uh the f trump and i shouldn't even have
said that since i may
bleep that out actually it turns into
the anti-trump and then it also turns
into that guy being racist and then it
just continues
uh yeah that is social media bro um
usually i make a bunch of notes on my
paper when i print out your email
i write a couple of notes so i don't i
don't just blindly go into it i've got
something to say after it
all i wrote on your message was yep i
agree
that's that's what i got for you dude
that is social media that is facebook
that is a large part i've said this why
i started this podcast because
it's hard to filter through the [ __ ]
on the internet you don't have to have
any uh
qualifications any documentation no
licensing no regulations you could post
whatever you want on the internet and
some people will believe it
so that's where we are with society
today that's not just cannabis that is
the whole damn world all right my buddy
papa wheelie i want to thank you for the
great message i'm sorry you're having a
tough time on social media don't let it
get to you
uh remember that that is the place where
i don't know it's just where all the
nonsense happens the real stuff is
happening here the real people that care
we're not doing that to each other when
we're talking hang out with some real
folks
you sound like a great person a great
guy you get a good head on your
shoulders
don't let social media get to you i know
you're trying to referee in there
but it's like trying to herd kittens
refereeing on facebook you just got to
let it happen just do your thing
enjoy your grow if people want to listen
to you maybe start your own group that
may be the way to do it but people
you'll get a following of people that
realize you know what you're talking
about and they'll listen to you they'll
ask you questions
and that little bit will make the
[ __ ] face punch feeling that you get
from facebook
it'll make all of that go away it'll
balance it out and make it feel good
you'll get a little bit of reward
to go with the face punch is what i
think i'm trying to say all right papa
willy thank you for the great message
i'm gonna keep going
because this is going to be a long show
if i don't focus uh this one comes from
used to be cool what's up brother
i got a bunch of great messages from a
bunch of familiar friends in this one i
like this
this one goes hey rosted jeff um let's
see
there's some parts we can skip here
don't use my name uh we just call you
used to be cool we got a cool alias for
you
it says i'm sorry we weren't able to
meet during your recent trip to colorado
however what a breath of fresh air
uh fresh breath of fresh air to be in
the mountains where everyone wore masks
in public
uh yeah you were up there getting fresh
air no mask no uh social distancing
because there were no other people up
there
i hope you had a good time i'm sorry i
missed you uh you understand what was
going on you actually uh
commented on it we don't need to bring
people into that it actually says here
scotty reel said on the show that i had
a tooth pulled yes i had a
little bit of dental work done and i was
unable to hang out that tooth came out
the same day you were in town
i was in no mood for company i apologize
that dentist kicked my ass but here we
are now
hanging out on the show uh dennis didn't
kick my ass that it was he did a good
job but god damn that sucked
um go to the dentist don't be afraid it
goes on it says i have three questions
for you and i'll try to be brief three
questions bro three
all right i'll do them all just to spoil
you and thank you for the great message
it said
i had a plant herm in my flower tent
with other plants
i was during week six that is the worst
[ __ ] time for herms
uh it says it was not one of yours
that's a good thing it says of which i
have two ggs and one l-o-g
a funny thing when i read that the first
time i had to rack my brain i was like
what the [ __ ] is log and i just gave up
and moved on i just hit me it's
liberation og
had to stop thinking about it and the
information just fell right out of the
sky to me
uh gg of course is probably the golden
goat it goes on it says i've inspected
my other plants and i don't think it was
seeded
and it's almost harvest time so maybe i
skated by this time however
i wondered how long does pollen stay
viable when it has been released with my
other plants that is a really good
question
that is going to be environmentally
dependent it'll probably sit around in
the open for like a month maybe longer
maybe six maybe eight weeks depending on
the environment keep that in mind
the heat will destroy and break down
your pollen cold will preserve your
pollen humidity and moisture
destroy pollen so if you've had it 50 60
humidity in that room that pollen is
getting deactivated a little bit more
every day
if you've got it up to 70 or 80 in there
the pollen is starting to cake together
it's turning weird colors it's not going
to be any good anymore after that
um but if you don't touch it i'm going
to say it's probably good if you just
if you just dumped pollen right here on
the desk and left it there and left it
this room stays pretty cool it's not too
hot because i got
sneakers and seeds in here as i try to
keep it cool they both like the cool
i kind of like it cool i guess i think
that pollen would stay on the desk for
quite a while and i could tell when it
starts changing colors and getting bad
on me and that will take a little bit
i can keep pollen in the fridge for a
long long time
uh put it in the crisper drawer in the
fridge i've seen it put in the freezer
when stored properly pollen will stay
for a long long time out in the open
i'm gonna say depending on your
environment two to six maybe eight weeks
max
and i'm not saying like completely
active lots of bunches of pollen but
you could have it's like you could have
just a little [ __ ] pollen is tiny
dude you know how
tiny pollen is you'd have this one
little grain of pollen somewhere that
could still be active after a few weeks
uh that is my opinion i have no science
to back that up that is debatable it is
debated
but i think it sticks around for quite a
while if we don't [ __ ] it up if you have
humidity if you've got wind and moisture
and
uh a lot of varying temperatures extreme
heat
that could destroy it more quickly the
extreme cold will preserve it like i
said cold keeps stuff around
heat cooks things and deteriorates it
breaks it down so
a couple of weeks to a lot of weeks is
my uh unofficial official answer
it goes on it says my second question
i'm gonna bill you for the second one
the first one was free the second one
i'm gonna bill you for
says i have never used humidity packs
but recently it seems as though they are
stealing flavor from
buds and long-term storage what is your
opinion on using them
you know for a long time i thought that
the humidipacks were messing up the
flavor when i worked at a commercial
grow
where we were sealing stuff up it was
how they did it when i came in and i
thought sure
it seems to be working but i noticed
everything had like a uh
like a watery flavor like just straight
when you're smoking it it tasted like
there was water in the buds it had
i've got a very sensitive palette i
could taste a lot of things i'm sure you
could tell by my flavor descriptions
uh when i smoke concentrates when i
smoke flowers i can tell you if you use
too much worm castings and [ __ ] like
that
but i could taste i could taste like a
wet watery
sort of a flavor in the buds and when i
wasn't smoking stuff that came out of
the humidity pack jars i didn't taste
that
also that stuff tasted stale it tasted
bland it all tasted the same like that
watery flavor
so in my opinion long-term extreme
long-term storage yes it did start
stealing the terps and the flavors
once mike and i took over that facility
and the harvesting and drying and curing
was done in a much more controlled
manner by mike and i
we eliminated the humidipacks eventually
we did our serve we did our method with
the humidipacks and it tasted
better then we got rid of them and it
tasted even better so
what i concluded in my mind in my theory
in my study
my unofficial study was that the
humidipacks work well
for like a shorter term storage if the
product is dried and cured properly
you've got to dry it and cure it
properly to give it that effect
then that works for like a medium
storage not a super long storage and
our versions of long lasting wheat are
probably vastly different but you can't
keep it around for super long in there
that's when i start thinking it steals
the terps
when it's not like uh beyond that like
we should have smoked that like a week
ago and you know when it gets to that
point
uh that's when i feel like they start
ripping off the terps if it's
dried and cured properly and it's just
being moved from the facility
to the store and then it goes on the
shelf and sells in a few days
i don't feel like we lose any terps it's
when it sits around in that container
for a long time that's when i feel like
your terps get stolen
so i do agree um i've actually seen
friends do experiments and comparisons
when they put a fresh bud in a jar
without a humidipack and a fresh blood
in a jar with a humidipack
the one with the humidipack i'm not
going to say the brand name it did burn
smoke
and grind better um but that was like a
week or two weeks that they put it in
there i think once you get to that four
and six
six week time period that's when your
terps start kind of getting ripped off
i'm gonna take a quick drink and then we
will answer question number three
all right we've come to your last
question and the last question goes
i've got a concern with red and purple
stems all three of my og plants have
developed red stems
despite having ample magnesium in my
super soil recipe
how do i know when red stems and pedials
are genetic and when they are
from a deficiency um knowing og kush
plants quite often your og kush
crosses and og kush things will have
purple leaves and purple pedials so that
could very well be
just a genetic thing don't panic too
much but i do have some good advice for
you
there are a few things that cause red
and purple pedials and you've got to
make sure you've got red or
purple it sounds like you've got red and
purple you could have a combo it could
be right in the middle
but hopefully my advice leads you to one
direction it could be nutrients
um if you have got red and purple stems
and crunchy leaves uh that is probably
uh let's see where were we now that's
probably a phosphorus problem you've
probably got a phosphorus deficiency
uh red and purple stems and crunchy
leaves is a phosphorus deficiency if
it's just
purple and the leaves aren't super
crunchy that is probably your magnesium
deficiency
um also your ph could be too low
that could be causing a nutrient
deficiency a nutrient lockout too low of
a ph
could make the nutrients not absorb the
cold
could be causing your pedials to turn
pinkish purple
red if the tops of the pitial is
changing colors but the underside isn't
that is probably from cold if the whole
thing all the way through is changing
colors
that's going to be from nutrients are
the leaves changing colors as well
if the leaves are changing colors as
well that is probably from low ph
uh and also from the cold if they're
crunchy again that's going to be from
phosphorus
genetics do that i mentioned a minute
ago that the og kush varietals will do
that
uh stuff from the afghanistan region
we'll get the purple petioles
uh you see a lot of the um what did i
used to grow a long time the torabora
used to get just straight up purple
petioles a lot of the grateful dog
crosses will give you purple pee deals
too and i said
said it multiple ways because i've heard
it multiple ways and now you're still
listening
um also something that may
not have come to your mind while you
were working in the garden if you have
done any bending popping and twisting or
manipulation of that plant
some of the new areas that are being
exposed to light may turn purple that
may be a reaction to being exposed to
light
parts that were going straight up maybe
you snapped it and twisted it and bent
it down a little bit that new part
that's getting light
that may turn purple on you as a
reaction a response
to new light and also a little bit of
stress the combo
will add some purple onto there so
you've got a couple of options
red and purple stems with crunchy leaves
again is probably a phosphorus
deficiency
uh just purple pedials is probably a
magnesium problem
the ph could be too low now here's
something to think about
uh too much potassium will block out
your magnesium if you've got too much
potassium in your feed mix
your plants will not absorb the
magnesium
also the opposite is true if you have
got too much calmag
you can give yourself a potassium
deficiency
so make sure that your nutrient mix is
where you need it to be
uh see if your if you've got crunchy
leaves that's going to tell you it's
phosphorous if it's just straight up
purple
that is a magnesium problem it could be
the ph check the ph of your solution
i've done a couple of episodes now on ph
meters and checking ph and dialing in
your gear
maybe check make sure the ph is accurate
that you're getting the ph of the
solution you think
um maybe the temperature could be a
little bit warmer in that room
i can only tell you what i suspect and
what could be options now you've got to
go in there
and do a little investigating and see
one of my options work best for you and
see what you need to correct if it is a
phosphorus or a magnesium issue that is
going to be very easy to correct
hopefully oh you said you were in super
soil uh you probably make a top dress
make a tea you might be able to pull
that out
i'm not a super soil or an organics
expert so i'm going to keep my mouth
shut and not
say anything wrong in that path all
right used to be cool i want to thank
you for the great message he wraps it up
with thanks for any help you can give me
and give your mom a hug for me i promise
i'll take a fat dab and i'll give my mom
a hug for you
it goes on to say ps i recently turned
man how quickly it goes by happy [ __ ]
birthday bro i hope you had a marvelous
birthday
i cannot wait to wish you a happy 67th
68th and bros 69th birthday as well
and on and on and on can't wait to wish
you many more happy years happy birthday
brother i hope to hear from you again
soon i hope we can figure out
the issues with your plans big shout out
to used to
be cool all right i've got another
message here in front of me let's move
right into this one
this one says good evening rosted jeff
do you want your name said i don't know
if you want your name said but good
evening my friend thank you for reaching
out
it goes on and it says i hope this email
is finding you happy
healthy and feeling good i am all of the
above so thank you it says i'm reaching
out today from newly decriminalized
virginia to some
to ask some questions as well as thank
you for the wealth of information you
provide and for all of the work you have
put into our industry that is a
wonderful
wonderful sentence i've got answers for
your questions uh thank you
for thanking me and thanks for noticing
that i put a lot of work into the
community and
the industry it goes on to say your
genetics your community outreach and
uh your willingness to share information
are all very inspirational and they've
directly
been directly benefited me greatly so
much respect brother that is awesome
thank you for
uh once again thank you for noticing and
you're welcome you are very welcome keep
doing what you're doing
keep watching the show uh that's all i
ask tell more people about the show too
you can do that
it goes on to say my questions mainly
surround the usage of co2 and commercial
cannabis grows i work for a chemical
detection company
and i'm looking into opportunities for
synergy in your industry that i have a
personal
interest in um yeah that's a really
viable
ancillary product that we need in the
grows it's not directly cannabis
you don't have to have all of the
cannabis licensing it's going to be much
easier for you
it's a great opportunity let's talk
about it it says
how widespread is co2 supplementation in
commercial grows
very it is very very viable and very
widespread it is in almost every
commercial grow if it's not in the
commercial grow when i get there
i request it that's one of the things we
install almost immediately
then it says what ppm range is generally
targeted for optimal
growth um the problem with that is that
co2 can become a little bit expensive i
would prefer
a little bit higher than what we
normally run most of the time we go
between 900 and 1100 ppms of co2 in the
rooms
um i would like to go closer to 12 maybe
uh that may sound a little bit
ridiculous but you'll see explosive
[ __ ] growth at that rate but getting
a big
uh 100 foot by 100 foot by 12 or 18 foot
tall grow facility
to maximize that with 1400 ppms of co2
for 12 hours a day
is a struggle and it's very expensive so
we aim for the 900 to 1100
uh ppms of co2 uh consistently from
the time the lights come on till the
lights come off we want that amount of
co2 in there
so there are things creating co2 all day
we'll talk about that in a minute
then it says are co2 levels monitored at
various
sites throughout a commercial grow
facility yes they
are um osha requires that we monitor
monitor
the co2 very carefully it's got to be
installed professionally
it's got to be monitored we've got to
have uh there are bright yellow flashing
lights that go off and say
dangerous hazardous co2 levels and the
alarm goes off and it will scare
the [ __ ] out of you it is completely
loud so we've got a lot of meters a lot
of monitors and
alarms to go with it then it says is
exposure
to high levels of co2 a concern for
workers no
because of all the monitors and meters
and osha regulations that i talked about
before
if it does get too high too dangerously
high that alarm will go off and
everybody in the building will hear it
it is as loud as the fire alarm and it's
[ __ ]
it's kind of scary it's a got a really
obnoxious sound to it so it says
i'd appreciate your input and i look
forward to the changing
legislation in my state and hopefully
seeing illegal ivory genetics growing in
virginia
soil very soon me too i'd love to see
some photos of some stuff growing down
there
it goes on to say uh for the first time
let's see
oh yeah it says could you redact my name
and my company absolutely your name and
company will not be said
i'll keep the email paper down here so
that nobody sees any of that
great question about co2 i did say we
would talk a little bit about how co2 is
used in a facility
in the state of colorado uh to the best
of my knowledge at the last time i
checked
co2 burners are illegal in a colorado
commercial
cultivation facility so you cannot hang
up the
co2 burner hook it up to the natural gas
and run that that is not allowed
i think they deem that a fire hazard
kind of makes sense um so what we do
we've got a service from a company i
can't remember the name i think it is
called green
co2 i can see the logo in my head i'm
pretty sure it's green co2 shout out to
you guys if that's who you are
sorry if that's not who you are we
actually get uh big tanks installed
outside they pour a concrete slab
outside
the appropriate size depending on how
many tanks we're gonna get they gotta
pour a pad outside then they put
six foot tall co2 canisters depending on
the size of your rooms and how much co2
you're going to need they come and do
calculations they've got the equipment
the math to do that
they've already done that they know how
to do it they come and do a calculation
they say you're going to need
this much co2 per room per delivery time
so they put tanks outside
that they can drive a big truck up that
is loaded with co2 in the truck
they attach a hose to our main tanks and
it fills up all of our tanks at one time
they just park for a minute
i watch the guy play on his phone
[ __ ] i don't know what he's doing
scrolling whatever
the little dingy thing goes off and he
goes oh the [ __ ] is full
and he gets out and he unplugs the cord
and he puts a little thing back in
closes up a gate puts a lock on it
because people steal [ __ ] everything
that's outside
he waves and he drives off and my co2 is
refilled for the next duration of time
until he comes back usually about a week
i think he came about every tuesday so
then
he fills up those big tanks those big
tanks run to a main line
inside of the facility and then each
room has a
controller and a monitor and on that
controller monitor you type in
how much co2 you want in the room and
then it will
release co2 we run lines around the
perimeter of the ceiling of the room
so you see where my tapestry is here in
the back of the room there'd just be a
line of
like a plastic line a perforated plastic
line that would go all the way around
the room about the door
the door jam height right around the
door frame there it just goes all the
way around the room and we run that
perforated line all the way around the
rooms
and then when you turn on the co2 it
just pumps through the room and that
monitor reads it and it says oh you're
it
the set the number you set and it turns
it off and then sometimes the machines
will freeze sometimes [ __ ] will go wrong
sometimes co2 will keep coming out and
it'll tell you you're at 2 000 ppm's of
co2
when it hits uh 2500 i think the alarm
goes off and you got to go outside
uh it's a really high number it could be
like 25 it's 250 000
it only went off a couple of times but
when it went off we [ __ ] heard it
so they deliver the big tanks the tanks
are set up the tanks run to
a controller and a monitor you tell it
how much you want
it's got a light sensor on it so it
knows when the lights are on and when
the lights are off because we don't want
to run co2 during the lights off that is
a waste of money it's also not good for
the plants
so it's got the light sensor we tell it
how much to pump out it comes on
it's shooting they told me that the
technology shoots a beam out
approximately three feet
every 30 seconds and measures the amount
of co2 present at that area
three feet from the monitor every 30
seconds and adjusted there
we also hang a few other monitors
throughout the facility at strategic
places
and it monitors there and the fans are
supposed to activate and move it around
if we have everything dialed in it's
always hard to get all of the parts
moving all together at the same time you
guys honestly there's always one or two
things that need to be dialed in and a
giant commercial grow
we'll get them dialed in but then uh
once you get that dialed in something
else is gonna break too and you get to
work on that
it's a lot of fun but we use a lot of
co2 and that is the short version
i don't know all the technical part we
run the lines we run the controller
and then sometimes the lines freeze but
as long as you've got good customer
service
the co2 works wonderfully it only breaks
down a couple of times
most of the time it's right after a
refill the [ __ ] lines will freeze and
then they don't stop and then all your
co2 is just pumping through the building
but it is a great advantage to
commercial growing you'll see
uh tremendous robust growth uh you can
run a little bit higher of a temperature
in the grow room so in the summer
if you're struggling for a couple of
extra degrees pump up that co2
that'll cover you uh yeah i really think
it's helpful
so uh you don't want your name said but
you know who you are uh big thank you
for the great message you are welcome
for the great advice i hope you have a
successful adventure in the cannabis
industry if you do choose to provide us
with co2
it's a very necessary uh supplement so
uh
if you're going to get into it please
get into it and be reliable that's what
we need in this industry is reliable
businesses
alright ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls pimps and hoes friends and foes
smokers and growers clone cutters and
pollen chuckers
chads and brads britney's and courtney's
all you fine cannabis growers out there
i want to thank you again for listening
to another episode of the grow from your
heart podcast
if you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
and you'd like to make a financial
contribution to the show all you have to
do is visit www.patreon.com forward
slash grow from your heart
all of the information you need will be
right there on the screen don't forget
that there is a link in the show notes
and the video description
to make it nice and easy for all of my
friends don't forget to visit our
sponsor at seedshearnow.com and use
coupon code gfyh10 while checking out
that will save you 10 off your full
order if you're just getting one pack of
seeds that'll cover the cost of shipping
if you're getting multiple packs
that will buy you more seeds what's
better than seeds
more seeds just tell the wife i needed
more seeds they were on sale
just tell them they were on sale babe
you'll be okay also don't forget about
that under 30 section
if you go to seeds herenow.com click on
the under 30 section tab there's a pack
of the cream
for under 30 you can get some irie
genetics in your garden
for less than 30 bucks increase your
performance elevate your game
i don't even know what that means what
else do we got for you if you've got any
questions corrections comments or
concerns i would love to hear from you
my email address is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com do not be shy i look
forward to hearing from you also while
we're talking
i want to invite you to check out my new
updated website that's right
iriegenetics.com is the new home
for all things ire genetics if you're
looking for seed vendors information
about strains i've bred if you're
looking for the podcast if you're
looking for sweet new irie genetics
t-shirts
if you're looking for the podcast if
you're looking for patreon it is all
right there in one spot
contact information social media links
it will all be
updated uh iriegenetics.com
give it a look i think you'll be proud
of what we're doing big shout out to my
buddy buzzbro
for all of the website help i think
that's all we've got for you for this
episode ladies and gentlemen
i'll be back in just a couple of days
with fresh new content i want to give a
giant shout out to my friends giant mike
and the dab and queen
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me