[Music]
welcome back podcast world i'm your host
my friends call me ross to jeff and it
is time for episode 581 of the grow from
your heart podcast
this episode of the show is brought to
you by our friends at seedshearnow.com
seedshearnow.com offers seeds from all
of the industry's leading breeders
including miss jill
genetics duke diamond and of course
irene genetics
everything at seeds herenow.com is
backed by an award-winning satisfaction
guarantee
and for my friends on a tight budget
seedsharenow.com offers several packs
for under 30
as well as amazing monthly sales make
sure to use coupon code gfyh10 while
checking out to save a few bucks
again that is coupon code gfyh10 while
checking out
at seeds here now.com
ladies and gentlemen i'm sure you heard
him coughing into the mic just a moment
ago and if you're watching on youtube
you see that smiling face
i'd like to welcome mike back to the
show welcome to the show bro
thanks man what's up everybody we are
hanging out bro are you as freezing as i
am it is a cold
[ __ ] colorado it's so cold out right
now oh man i hate to break it to you i
looked over at the camera
digit and madness yeah it was seven
degrees last time i looked i just
the cameras before we pressed record and
you're gonna love this update
it's [ __ ] snowing again we've got at
least seven inches out there in the yard
it's going to be 10 or 12 inches by the
time we wake up this time
i was not prepared we got like 10 in my
yard at least
it's it's over a foot in a couple of
spots i had to shovel it today i'm
intimately familiar with that snow
our friend tony posted a picture of a 16
ounce mountain dew bottle
and he posted a timeline over the day of
that bottle getting filled up and by the
end of the day
it wasn't filled up it was just stacked
up along the side
it was about 12 ounces deep by the time
the end of the day
we got pummeled we haven't seen this
much snow in puebla since i moved here
like a decade ago
came out of nowhere it came out of
nowhere it was like hey we might get
some snow tomorrow and then
it was like hey guess what here's all
the [ __ ] snow so yeah we
expected on halloween usually we say
halloween we're gonna get snow here
where we live
uh we are uh just about a week early so
shout out to mother nature for kicking
our ass i hope you guys got your outdoor
plants down on time that was my first
thought is uh
i know two people that did an outdoor
this year and i know they both got out
of the ground
this week so they're all they're all in
dry and cure already but i'm
there a lot of outdoor grows down this
part of the state man i hope they got
out of the ground
so many people growing from here to new
mexico i know a lot of people growing
i have a friend who had to cancel his
weekend plans to just harvest it
so we got pummeled we were not expecting
it this is not the grow from your
weather podcast this is a cannabis
podcast i just wanted to talk about how
freaking cold it is it is a cold
colorado evening kind of set the tone
for the night
another great way to set the tone is to
talk about what we are smoking mike what
are you smoking on this evening brother
um i've been enjoying some local flower
there's a shop in town that had some
i mentioned it the last time i was on
the show some really good golden goat
that i'm enjoying some scentsy star from
that same shop there
they've been impressive lately you said
so much on the last show that i don't
know if anybody remembers or
cares about my herb recommendation yeah
if you can find some good golden goat
grab you some real quick it's delicious
i think we're going to move right on a
forward about the last episode you were
on um we appreciate the feedback
what are you smoking on these days buddy
uh good toss buddy i am smoking some
sour best lemons live batter it's a
blend of sour best
[ __ ] ever at northern lemon tree
northern lights on the package they
describe the flavor as lemons
lemons and even more lemons i've talked
about this on the podcast
[ __ ] agree dude it's lemontastic
those lemon perps are my friend my
favorite they work with my uh
i've got a brain injury it still exists
it's still i've got weird lingering
[ __ ] fuzzies from it it was years ago
years ago if you know the years ago joke
shout out in a fist bump but years ago
i had a brain injury some lingering
effects occasionally
i've noticed the lemony limonene type
terps kind of correct some of the
in my opinion i don't know you may see
differently on that from another
perspective but i feel like it kind of
fixes
my glitches my skips like uh if your
brain is a [ __ ] record i've got a
little
little skip somewhere and occasionally
some songs it'll just it'll just it'll
just and you got to nudge the record
player to get it going that's my brain
i feel like the limit
it wipes off the scratch on my cd or it
fills in the scratch on my record or
whatever and it makes my
uh my brain flow a little more smoothly
my beats don't have that weird skip
remember when you would download music
from uh limewire and occasionally
you [ __ ] boom and chat camp boom chat
and then occasionally you're
in the middle of the song and you're
like oh [ __ ] you have a little seizure
from it
that's what my brain does occasionally
you'll hear the beat will be smooth and
then the middle the b you get
just this weird [ __ ] up note that
doesn't belong there this makes those
notes go away this the lemony terps
makes that not happen so that's where
i'm headed with all that [ __ ]
rambles
this is your regular advisement to avoid
head injuries
yeah that's uh that's the first piece of
advice is don't bang your name when
at all possible you should duck um or
don't be six foot five that's what it's
some of us are just born to smash our
faces into things i was the moving
object in that situation i am to blame
it wasn't like something else nowhere
and hit me
the street light didn't dive in front of
your car it was yeah
it was a [ __ ] i was in a town an
older part of town
where um there's a word that they use to
describe the people the descendants from
this part of the world i don't know if
it's a derogatory term but they call
themselves that here but those people
are very short
they're smaller people and the houses
here were built for those shorter people
they were five nine i'm six five i think
their doorways are six feet tall
i went through that doorway and cracked
the top of my head oh my god
knocked myself out and fell down the
stairs slid down the stairs while i was
unconscious
i woke up to my friends carrying me up
the stairs wondering what the [ __ ]
just happened to me
um so don't be sick
six five worth of human tumbling down
some stairs makes a racket
let's go [ __ ] out anybody in the house
my computer just told me that my
internet connection is unstable mike so
if things go weird i'm going to keep
recording as business as usual and we'll
catch up we'll make a good podcast
that sounds good in my headphones so
we'll keep rolling folks if we lose you
we'll sorry got a lot of unstable [ __ ]
in my life this internet connection
welcome to the play internet i wondered
with all the uh the snow if we were
gonna have any issues this has been a
fun show already mike we're not even to
the patreon shout outs let's jump into
the part where we give shout outs to the
members of the 710 club of course the
710 club
who support the podcast at the 7.10
a month level or higher on patreon so
let's just jump right into it i want to
give a giant shout out and a fist bump
to my friend mobius groves
listen to thank you shout out to adam h
let's follow that up with a thank you
shout out to justin t
let's say thank you to ty g i've got a
thank you shout out to sticky sack
i'm not sure if that's a good job or if
you need a bath you either got some
chronic in your pocket or do you need a
shower buddy let's give a big shout out
to crawley cuts
let's give a thank you shout out to 716
vibes i want to send a big thank you
shout out to rumble buns i get a lot of
names in my
inboxes on patreon uh rumble buns is one
i will never forget let's send a big
thank you shout out to
uh kojaks let's follow that up with a
thank you shout out to lisa
s and last but certainly not least i
want to send a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to mike
v hill big thank you and big shout out
to everybody who supports the show on
patreon
if you that's the big finger like uncle
sam if you are not already supporting
the show on patreon
and you would like to learn how to do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need to
support the podcast will be right there
on the show of course there is a link
in the show notes and the video
description wherever you're watching or
listening there's a link there
to make it super easy for all of my
friends now to be polite
this is the portion of the show where i
toss it over to our buddy white mike to
do some shout outs from patreon it's all
yours bro
thanks man um i've also got a patreon
going folks it's
patreon.com forward slash white mike um
shout outs i got this uh this time
around i got uh farmer z
thank you very much ez057 i appreciate
the support
giant mike and the dab and queen um
thank you so much for signing up
learning and burning always appreciated
man papa z
richard and the grow from your heart
podcast i appreciate it so much folks
thank you very much um if you'd like to
support either of us on patreon i
encourage you to do so
that's right all the cool kids are
supporting mike i encourage you to do it
uh also help me out too if you're so
inclined right now if you can only help
one of us i encourage you to help out
white mike i'm doing quite well on
patreon thank you guys
i do appreciate it you will see the
fruits of your
contributions very soon i keep teasing
you um your stuff is coming up the
patreon contributions the patreon
so much construction to jeff's you guys
will get uh
you guys will get some uh heads up first
on patreon you'll get some teases but
thank you guys
um yeah but help out mike because i've
done quite well help out mike on patreon
if you're thinking about
throwing some bucks our way maybe uh if
you're gonna do five my way do a buck to
mike and 420 to me
just do 420 to mike however you want to
do it but help mike out i'm doing
[ __ ] fine this month thank you guys
i appreciate it send a buck mike's way
thanks man
yeah dude [ __ ] spoil them little kids
there's only one of me and there's like
[ __ ] how many of you over there dude
so many so many enough
the answer is enough yes um yeah
uh yeah there's one of me here i got
another one but she's not here it's
easier
uh she's 17 easier to deal with than the
tiny ones
dude i can't wait until like long
paragraph form explanations will fly
with my kids like they're fun
they're five and two right now like
because i said so is as elaborate as i
can get without causing confusion
and i just said that there was a 17 year
old female in my life i'd like to
clarify that that is my daughter i just
wanted
his daughter that sounded kind of creepy
for a moment there i'm just gonna
step in 17 year old daughters are
expensive but there's just one or her at
me it's not like [ __ ]
the tribe that you've got [ __ ] there
so right
yeah um and i can explain
no expensive like you were just saying i
could say no that's 900
you can't have that your kids are like
but daddy why so
yeah yep
um snowden is their first real snow so
we've been having fun oh that is cool
bro that is cool
yeah it's a good time for first time for
everything with that little one and
that's awesome
yeah uh dude the littlest one the
two-year-old uh
first real time in snow he didn't have
gloves on for like five minutes and then
came in
and we knew it was gonna happen but he
lost his mind when those poor little
fingers started warming up
that was what my afternoon was right
there like anybody that's got a kid
knows
how my day went yep they were
fun and then they were wet and then they
were exhausted yep so a couple of dabs
in a podcast seemed like the perfect way
to wrap up the day
perfect bro that picture of broccoli
that you posted was awesome
i'm impressed for the people following
along with my kovid garden
the last thing we harvested was a stem
of broccoli the size of my
five-year-old's head
literally massive basically it was so
good if he carries it he's like hidden
behind i'm like where's your boy that's
just walking broccoli
it's like an umbrella that's yup he
could have [ __ ] lived underneath it
if you
were a little smaller all right we've
covered the basics of the
uh we talked about it being cold we
covered patreon we did the commercial we
talked about what we're smoking
mike is here i'm here you guys are here
we're all here jeff's here y'all don't
sweat it
i'm more here than usual this is pretty
great um
i want to give a shout out to the new
office space it's going to be feeling
good
focused it was too cold to do anything
today so i got all this energy
um i want to give a shout out to black
sail market
uh shout out to keith keith personally i
know it's a company but keith is the
person that did this the one that
stepped up
a few episodes ago i read an email from
a
combat veteran who had some money for a
grow light and they were a little bit
short of a quality light they probably
could have gotten a decent light for
their money
but it's the girl from your heart
podcast we don't [ __ ] with decent we
[ __ ] with high quality we want
you want to get the right stuff yeah so
um i was talking with my friend keith on
the embracing organic show we had a
little hangout
after the show shout out to embracing
organics and the whole crew there but
keith was on there we were bullshitting
a little bit and he's like hey did that
veteran ever get a light
and i was like we got a couple of
opportunities and a few options but i'd
love to hear your
what you've got to say because i work
with black sail i run black sail lights
in my i've got a flower space with black
sails i got a veg stace
a veg space with black sail cannon
lights and i love them they work very
well
and he looks at me and he goes bro i
want to give that lady he said that
person he didn't realize
by the way that combat veteran is a lady
so all you people that were like shout
out bro
uh shout out ma'am sorry we gotta
correct that that is a lady
a very nice lady too i've spoken with
them several times but
uh keith was like i want to give that
veteran a light and i was like well
here's the info be in touch and then i
put them in touch
and today keith sent that person a grow
light they've got a candidate yeah
on their way i not to toot my own horn
but they're also going to be growing
some irie genetics underneath that canon
led we got to get them set up oh i love
it
yeah so shout out to keith he stepped up
uh sent them a cannon
we let them keep the money that they had
in the episode they said that they had a
little bit of money for a grow light
we didn't even ask for that funding we
let them keep that maybe they can get
some nice
or some soil or some newts or some power
bill or
i hope always more to be covered when it
comes to building a growth so shout out
to keith
uh keith is also a veteran uh he is
uh i [ __ ] i should remember the
branch of military he's from i feel
disrespectful now
uh but that doesn't stick in my brain
i've got this weird brain injury some
things go some things don't that was the
one that didn't i'm sorry
but i'd at least respect him and
remember that he's a soldier so uh when
he realized it was a soldier he
definitely felt uh some compassion and
wanted to help out some camaraderie
i love it yeah so a soldier helping a
soldier a disabled person he's been
helped by a well
a younger [ __ ] person keith is a
young healthy dude so it's really good
to see something like that we got people
helping people the podcast brought
people together
that doesn't mean we have to stop uh
there are other veterans out there that
need lights
it is terrible that we have to do this
if you are a veteran in desperate need
of a light i know another person who has
offered there are several other people
who have offered lights they've got
leftover lights laying around that are
still usable there's a guy that you and
i know very well
who offered brand new grow lights and i
want to get those to veterans that need
them
i hate that i have to do it this way i'd
like you to kind of verify that you're a
veteran i don't know how to do that
keith knew how to do it because
he said as soon as he spoke to another
veteran they would know
yeah it's it's like if you don't know
calculus like you can't it's something
you can fake for more than a minute yeah
like i know bros and i when bros and i
talk
you're a bro bro and we bro out bro but
veterans i don't know veteran lingo and
i couldn't catch it but
we need to vet these vets a little bit
make sure they're actually because i
hate to say it
nowadays people are not completely
[ __ ] on the whole world's belka titan
yeah everybody's up in their scam game
yep it could be
it could be someone in a totally
different country telling me that
there's somebody that they're totally
not trying to get free [ __ ] out of me
it's terrible that the world is that way
that i even have to question somebody's
claim that they're a veteran but we need
to vet a couple of people
i would like to find a couple of people
who are deserving and in need of some
grow lights and the people that have
offered to give out these lights and i
told you we got the one taken care of
this is where you guys are going to come
into play thank you i appreciate you
it's really cool that um i love that i
can
have this pool i all i did was talk into
the mic a bunch of people sent messages
saying i have got equipment for these
veterans i love that we can create that
sort of a community thank you guys
thank you so much guys everybody gals
literally everybody that's reached out
thank you very much
the veterans that are going to get these
lights and free seeds definitely thank
you very much and i
have another good friend with the
nutrient company we're going to see if
maybe we can get some boxes of nutrients
out to these people at the same time
if they're running the nutrients i
recommend and the lights that i
recommend they're
set up for success and we'll get them
taken care of these people are blowed up
and
have ptsd we've got to take care of the
people that uh
i don't even i'm not a person i'm not
four wall but people had to do it and
it's not
his his or her fault so we gotta help
them
like they're all family to us we gotta
pick them up they're now they're [ __ ]
irie army they're not only us army or
u.s marines are irie army now
it's our turn to take care of them so uh
no soldier left behind here in the irie
army
diary army we do more dabs before 9 00
a.m than you do all day bro
all right but shout out to keith i
wonder i'm so so pumped with how the
community came together for this one
this is
huge y'all thank you so much it feels
good that
i i don't like to think that i did that
bro but i mean it feels good that
we did that bro like and then people
stepped up all i did was say stuff i
talked into this mic that goes into a
box that goes to the internet
and then people were like people in need
we're people that help so
that's [ __ ] cool that's growing from
your heart you guys thank you
yeah i talk a lot of [ __ ] i giggle a lot
i tell a lot of jokes but
thank you this one's serious um
where else we gonna go we briefly
glossed over this one a moment ago but i
want to go back to it
i want to send a big thank you shout out
to everybody who
sent a comment or a message or an email
or any sort of feedback or reply
to episode 579 i feel like mike did a
very good job he was very well spoken
very well put together
the past two shows you've been on thanks
bro [ __ ] awesome bro
um i appreciate you i appreciate what
you're saying people don't have to agree
with us a hundred percent
there are adult ways and non-adult ways
to go about agreeing and not agreeing
shout out to everybody uh who replied in
an adult manner if you agreed or not and
that's as far as i'm gonna go with that
we don't need to address anything else i
think we gave everybody a shout out that
deserves it
thank you mike you did a wonderful job
always welcome back
no matter what the youtube comments say
oh i do appreciate it yeah these
people suck on the internet sometimes
that's all that's cool don't read be
good
don't read the comments i i read the my
skit is thick i ain't worried
i check them on youtube because i'm the
host and producer of the show i want
some feedback but
uh i don't i try to avoid the comments
it's not healthy
like oh bro we're so blessed like it's
one of the reasons why i'm so pumped
that the community was able to help out
um the vet that that's been uh doing
emails with the show and get some lights
out um
to a handful of people now it's it's so
cool that we can give back like we're so
blessed like
we live in the us we're white males like
no one's hunting us for sport like life
is good man fighting
redlocks i'd be yeah the cops wouldn't
even [ __ ]
herbs legal here like life is good
and we're we're fortunate and and to be
able to give back is great like
people being rude on the internet like
oh please
i avoid most of these somebody said you
better shade from my toddler
right somebody asked if i had noticed
the negative comment on itunes and i was
like the what
because it doesn't i know uh
i know what content i'm putting out i'm
not going to be a different person it's
not going to be a different show because
somebody says here's shelley sucks go
listen to the other free cannabis
podcasts out there if you don't like
mine
anyway we've given them an attention
thank you mike i thought you did a
wonderful job
i also want to send a shout out to
everybody who hangs out in the premieres
uh i do the premieres of the show at
midnight uh if it's the show comes out
on monday morning and thursday morning
so it's 12 o'clock monday
12 o'clock thursday thank you those
premieres are fun we're getting more and
more people in there every time
it's a fun chat nice little love chat
sesh
i may not comment excuse me for the
throat clearing i may not comment a
whole lot
we both got dab throat sorry y'all
picked it right at the same time for
both of us too i'm lurking though if i'm
not commenting i'm lurking watching the
comments watching you guys chat and it's
a good time thank you i enjoy it
the funnest part is uh we do our chat
there on the premiere you and i hung out
last night and left some comments and
chatted with the people
as soon as it ended i was like well now
what am i going to do i clicked over to
watch eagle because eagle gardens was
live
everybody from the chat just migrated
right over to eagle and we all
together so shout out to that's [ __ ]
cool shout out to
everybody that's been on eagle lately
you guys are killing it uh if you're not
watching eagle gardens
the name of the show is [ __ ] talking
[ __ ] with eagle uh it's on
right now i don't know what time you're
listening to this where you're watching
the dude [ __ ] doesn't log out of
youtube i love him and respect him
uh one day he's gonna need a [ __ ]
break and like i'm proud of him
he's gone the entire time of kovid uh
the entire time that the quarantine and
covid situation has been happening he
has not missed a single night of
podcasting
they do at least an hour or three wow
he'll have a guest on like you and i do
and he'll interview the guest and then
he'll wrap it up and it'll be like i'll
be back in two minutes guys and i'm
pretty sure he goes and takes a piss and
gets a drink and comes back
and he does the rabbit hole and that's
just whatever we're just gonna talk
about whatever go down the rabbit hole
and that goes until i fall asleep dude i
never am able to end that show because
they go forever
they go forever so shout out to eagle
for keeping us entertained about to
everybody putting out
all of this amazing content when
quarantine happened people got stressed
out we didn't know what we were going to
do
uh content providers have stepped the
[ __ ] up i'm a content
consumer being self-employed and i
basically live alone i'm here by myself
90 of the time i'm hanging out i've got
joey diaz
or rogan in my ear but a lot of the time
i got eagle gardens i got fumador
i got all those guys that are our local
friends i've got them on the youtube i'm
watching them it's really cool
i've made a lot of cool friends through
it too so i'm not just on both sides of
the screen people that are on the shows
i'm friends new friends with them
um family tree seeds cascadian grown
made friends with those guys through uh
these kind of shows also the audience i
become really close with them over
the cove times so i've gotten to chat
and interact with a lot more viewers and
listeners lately
yeah that stepped way up the last couple
months we've got time
thanks for reaching out to everybody
yeah not only do we provide you guys
content but you guys recharge us i say
that you guys are like nutrients and
recharge for us we put these shows
together
it doesn't seem like a lot of work i had
to learn equipment i had a little tech
issue
[ __ ] before we recorded here had me
scratching my head i got it figured out
and we're going
but and it took us a few minutes to
write a podcast together it's not all
just [ __ ] press record and go you
gotta have a plan you gotta have a plot
you gotta know what you're doing
it's gotta go to the internet usually
sometimes
it depends on what show i'm on uh some
shows we just [ __ ] press go and hope
for the best
but uh i don't even remember where the
[ __ ] i was but yeah we've had a lot more
interaction time because of this coved
time so thank you guys it's
recharging us all the feedback uh
everybody that's been putting out great
content you keep me going
uh the people that join us in the
premieres it has been really fun i was
worried about
uh the possible depression with covid
times especially
uh and we didn't get a summer to play
that's like what recharge
and then it got dark and gloomy and some
people myself included i can get bummed
out in these cold
[ __ ] depressed times i'm from
california bro i'm from sunshine and
beaches and [ __ ] and you brought me to
this cold snowy [ __ ]
it's hard for my brain to go but i want
to go outside and play i need vitamin d
and it's like no it's cold and shitty
you've got to hibernate
it makes me i don't know if it's
depressed or what but it's a feeling
dude people are basically complex house
plants with emotions like you need water
and you need
sunlight yes if you take one of those
away
the human ain't gonna do so hot my
opportunity for sunlight was about four
hours today and it was seven degrees
during that window so it wasn't
enjoyable
i was outside working a snow shovel
during that period but in my shoulders
yeah it was not awesome i would have
tipped you fat to shovel my [ __ ]
but all of the people making the content
interacting listening participating
patreon uh they are keeping myself sane
uh my instagram live audience helps keep
me sane
i hung up an hour and several like an
hour and a half today on instagram live
and that was a good time
that's like social interaction and then
the best part is you don't have to kick
them out when you're done you don't have
to be like all right guys i
need to poop and get some food you need
to leave now you're like all right i'm
done click
they're [ __ ] they're out it's over
they couldn't [ __ ] linger if they
wanted to you don't have to kick any
stone people [ __ ] couch
it's too [ __ ] high to drive home it's
[ __ ] awesome
so cozy but thank you guys i know i'm
off on a ramble today that lemon dab got
me going it's kind of a fun podcast
episode
uh but really all of the interaction all
that support i've had a lot of fun
i know it's been a podcast filled with
shout outs we've been going for almost
25 minutes here
i haven't really done a lot of cannabis
related content but we need to catch up
after the last show that we did people
are there's a couple people out there
with their cheeks clenched wondering
which direction the shell is gonna turn
yeah i think it's gonna be rambles are
they gonna do cannabis stuff is mike
gonna do another politics rant
i think it's just gonna be gonna happen
yourself and uh
us getting your audience back i feel
like i may have lost a couple of people
because that last episode honestly
we lost to the right people it's fine
yeah it's that's the thing about people
who jump off the boat like they
clearly didn't want to be here if y'all
made it to 570 sub episodes and hadn't
realized that i was a liberals liberal
liberal
y'all ain't been listening all right
let's pull this one back we're getting
into that water again
no no yeah no the show has a point we're
not doing politics tonight y'all it's
just
it's been a fun what 72 hours
yeah we're just enjoying the ride and
posted and then got back together
oh the show's only been out for 12 hours
at this point yeah
24 hours now while we're recording the
show has been out for 24 hours
yep and i thought you technically owned
[ __ ]
there were seven comments before we
recorded
oh so good i had 200 and something
emails when i woke up today most of them
were
comments and emails about the show so
that was interesting all right so i know
that we're doing a bunch of shout outs
it hasn't we haven't done any cannabis
content probably not going to do any
cannabis content on this episode we're
going to hang out and have a good time
because
mike and i wanted to catch up and hang
out we missed you guys mike missed you
guys mike had some free time honestly
um but i do for free giant shout out to
my friend
buzz bros uh make sure you follow buzz
bros on instagram it's just like it
sounds b-u-z-b-r-o-s give them a follow
give them a shout out
that nice guy has rebuilt my website
that's right i've complained about my
website for quite a while
uh the new website is iregenetics.com it
used to have
colorado at the end of it we're going to
convert everything to the new website
iriegenetics.com
i'm excited about the build it looks
really good now we're putting
we're sprucing it up it's got the
outline the framework is in place
i'm gonna do a lot of work on that over
the next week he gave me a
three week deadline about two weeks ago
and he's already way ahead of schedule
i'm excited i'm impressed i'm pleased
with what he looks really good so far
thank you bro we scrolled through it for
a couple of moments here before the show
i go looking for errors and things that
we need to correct and update when i get
a moment and i'm really excited with the
way that the website has evolved so
you guys if you were looking for
anything i read genetics related
sometimes i talk about my genetics where
to buy the genetics where to buy
t-shirts how to join us on patreon
how to listen to the podcast how to
contact me
one location there's no more of the
scrambling around [ __ ]
my email is this my website's here
patreon's here
uh it is all in one location it is all
iriegenetics.com
i like our connections wavering buddy
your your voice just went on
iwaki all right as long as it is
recording properly in one of our devices
i've got two recording devices here
uh we'll make that work but thank you
but when i saw your face i definitely
knew that a
spot for an idiot we'll just have to
double listen sorry folks yeah we may
not even take that out they may get to
see that little behind the scenes part
it's snowing like a son of a [ __ ] it's
a six degrees outside
we're liable to get some tanks i think
the first time we tried one of these
zoom podcasts i called it a bunker
session and
it feels more and more like that every
every time we do one but
i think we got the technology figured
out mostly hopefully
i sound really good in everybody's ears
this week um there's a new piece of tech
that should be bringing my volume up
yeah it's snowing like a beast outside
and we can't do anything about the
internet connection so
we're trying folks we really are we're
having fun though we are having fun
i think everybody that's that that
listens to the show really likes
the the content we've been putting out
your show has been crushing it
the grow episode's been so good lately
thank you bro and it's only going to get
better i keep teasing stuff that's
coming along i've made a couple of hints
of things that may happen
uh thank you for the compliments but i
know we can do better and it is time
in place um i don't want to talk too
much about it here because i just want
to say that things are in place
and patreon will see it first i can't i
can't wait for us to be podcasting from
the same space again
like there is something lost when it's
i'm staring at a
screen with lights in my face there's
just that millisecond of social like is
he done talking do i talk now do i talk
over him like there's that one
millisecond that we both hesitate
so yeah i mean it's a lot harder to
deduce over
over zoom than it is in in person and uh
just hanging out with you for a brief
moment the other day as you were headed
uh from the dispensary just seeing you
for that moment
uh just human interaction was [ __ ]
golden that was cool
yeah like you forget what human
interaction is like during covet [ __ ]
it's and it's just the store clerk and
the people in your house
i thought i was confused like someone's
at the doorbell and i didn't order
grubhub what the [ __ ] is going on
i did not bring you a sandwich no it's
better it was better there was a human
with concentrates right i bought
conversation and hash
way better down to hang out with white
mike i haven't seen you in a minute bro
i felt like a dog is like how you been
bro what's going on
how's everything going how's the wife is
that new house coming along well you
want a podcast what do you want to talk
about
this is [ __ ] excited dude yeah it uh
i i'm happy to skip the odd social
engagement because i i'd rather stay
home and avoid people but
man it's we've had enough of that just
invite me to a [ __ ] mixer and we'll
chitchat
for hours yeah i'm torn people want me
to go to events and people are throwing
events and i'm like give me just a
little bit more time see how all this
stuff plays out and then
in a little bit we'll go to events like
i'm fighting the urge to just try to
chit chat with
people texting me random political stuff
like vote no on this it's like okay but
like how was your day
oh i told those people send me a message
like hey have you voted on this
i tell them my views and then i ask them
where
i'm sending them um quotes from some of
my favorite comedians and other podcasts
but i decided that maybe some of the
things that we're saying might be lewd
and could get me in trouble and i might
not want to do that anymore
uh sent a a quote from one of my
favorite podcasts
to one of the political uh whatever
they're called and they replied with
another quote from the same podcast
nice i told me to count on me i'm gonna
vote for you just because you knew what
that was
nice the one the one i had fun trolling
was the
the uh we want to warranty your car
i had fun with those people i was like
you really don't want to warranty my car
watch i'll tell you about it and watch
you hang up on me
that got me off their list quick i
worked at a telemarketing firm
for a summer and they gave me
jedi training like that's
behind a microphone that's part of it
also a stage presence and just so much
time doing i was a musician for a long
time
uh not the front man but i was on the
stage singing or playing the drums i was
never singing explain the drums
i was just on stage people were looking
at you and that [ __ ] and then i
worked i've worked retail
uh but uh yeah i've totally lost my
train of thought so jump in with
something
yeah you get uh you get comfortable in
front of a camera from the talk and
doing retail jesus
yeah yeah they just want to come in and
buy some [ __ ] and you got to deal with
them what the [ __ ] was i saying mike put
me back on track
i don't even remember this is a high ass
ramble cast man though the last two rips
on my pen got me space coasting
social places yep
places dabs hoodies yeah we lost it
[ __ ] chitchat covered jove and i
sound like mark norman can you uh
are you having trouble telling the
length of time that has passed
like can you think back of stuff that
happened can you tell if it was in march
or if it was in august um
i checked in with you i was like bro am
i going crazy because
this sweater thing that i bought this
[ __ ] it's all wool
it's [ __ ] for a complete warm season
i'm nice and warm
i don't have the heater on uh i'm warm
because of this [ __ ] i bought this in
like march because i couldn't tell
uh what season or month it was anymore
we got ripped off for a summer
i was like well we don't get to go out
it's not summer i feel like in the
summer i go to a concert and a comedy
show every [ __ ] weekend that's how i
roll comedy show concert comedy
concert didn't do that thought it was
fall because of that found myself buying
pants and sweaters and things online
when i was doing online shopping so now
that the winter is here i've got a whole
new [ __ ]
fall winter out new wardrobe yeah
because i was just
like you're saying i didn't know what
the [ __ ] season or time of year it was
and now that it's uh dark so early i
really have no concept of [ __ ] time
like i woke up 6 30 in the morning and
looked at my phone i looked at the clock
and it said 6 30 and i looked at the sky
and i was like am or pm dude
like i'm not even [ __ ] here like yeah
yeah it's i had somebody asking me um
this is basic stuff about like how long
my kids been back in school
and i was completely unable to give them
an accurate
like it's been six weeks it's been two
months it's been nine months
like there's just no concept of time
anymore
i would base my time off of events that
happened like well it had to be
in march because we saw bobby lee it had
to be in
on the way home from the brennan shop
comedy show or it was between these two
like but yep yeah there's been none of
that man
none of that and uh we're gearing up for
the holidays
and talking about like well we only want
to have one or two people at a time so
we're going to do this and that person
gets to come for this one but not that
one man
it's going to be an interesting window
that's for damn sure yeah
lots of podcasting stay tuned be
prepared personally
yeah more content coming at you the one
i'll be ramblecast we did have a couple
of good emails selected for this show
we'll do those next show
those are definitely going to come up in
another episode they may have already
happened in the episode before this just
because of the magic of the way that
podcasting and editing will be
different good emails for the next one
yeah if that's how she go
yeah we picked a couple but i think we
had so much fun just hanging out that we
uh
may have forgotten that there was a job
to do mike we had too much fun in the
break that's all right
we did the job we we we chatted
we came they saw we went yeah it's uh
it's a covered cast yo we're uh we're
here
we're baked ah ask us questions
speaking of baked bro let's wrap up this
podcast and take some freaking dabs how
does that sound
i like that idea all right podcast i
like that idea
um yeah reach out to us ask us questions
how can they get a hold of you jeff if i
wanted to send you an email how would i
go it's about it
uh the best way to do it would be to
send me an email at
growfromyourheart hotmail.com that'll
get to me mike do you have a preferred
method so that uh if this message
garnishes garners garnishes
renders any [ __ ] emails um you can
hit me up at uh
nemopunk15 on twitter or pueblo for
sensible cannabis allows on facebook
um you could also just send an email to
the grow from your heart podcast email
and
put forward the white mic at the top
make jeff do some
clerical work i was going to say don't
give them just the twitter because they
may want to cuss you out in more than
140 characters
that's what the dms are for so you can
send your hey mail to my dms and i won't
look at it there either
on our patreons patreon.com forward
slash grow from your heart patreon.com
forward slash white mike
help us both again if you can only do
one this month do white mike
uh when the fresh year starts come back
hang out with roster jeff
uh don't forget to check us out on
youtube go to the youtube channel
search for the grow from your heart
podcast click subscribe click on that
little bell what that little bell does
every time i put out a new episode
you will get a notification in the
future uh there may be some bonus
surprise episodes that don't come out on
the regular schedule
don't miss them hit that notification
button you will get the notification
don't forget to check out my new website
i'm proud of it i'm excited i want you
to join it
uh go check out there's nothing to join
i just want you to go look at it
dot com there's a link to buy seeds a
lot of people say how do we get your
seeds
links are on there all the vendors are
there there's a link to the patreon i'll
link to the podcast a link to all of the
shirts there are more shirts coming i
got three designs up now
more shirts in the works does that rhyme
it's happening
i'm wrapping the merch is amazing y'all
you need to check it out if you haven't
already
thank you bro uh you got to come by and
pick up your shirts because
yep i placed an order you should too
yeah all the cool kids are doing it man
they are i think that's all we've got
mike let's wrap this up before we get
too rambly again because we can dig
ourselves into a bigger hole and never
showed up we are good at that
thank you for hanging out bro if you're
a listener that's like
no dig i want to hear from you reach out
yeah we'll just do more episodes they're
going to get more content maybe not
today but in the very near future
very near future folks we're not going
anywhere um
yeah it's too cold to go anywhere bro
it's too [ __ ] cold
and it's covety all right i gotta watch
this
yeah song ends so uh dude thank you for
hanging out let's hang out take some
dabs after this
everybody else i'll see you in just a
couple of days with fresh new content
let's give a giant shout out to my
friend thecanacrat and until next time
take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me