[Music]
ocean
roster jeff in the house
greetings from podcast ville this
episode of the show is brought to you by
our friends at seedshearnow.com
seeds herenow.com offers seeds from all
of the industry's
leading breeders including miss jill
genetics exotic genetics and of course
irie genetics everything at seeds
herenow.com is backed by an
award-winning satisfaction guarantee
and for my friends on a tight budget
seedshearnow.com offers several packs
for under 30
as well as amazing monthly sales
make sure to use coupon code gfyh10
while checking out to save a few bucks
again that is coupon code gfyh10 while
checking out
at seeds here now dot com
you know i like to start this podcast
off by talking about what i'm smoking
today i've been taking dabs of doses and
mimosas
live batter this is a blend of bottle
wash and tahitian punch
on the package the flavor is described
as citrus lavender and champagne
you know i really got the citrus flavor
the champagne is definitely abundant
when you hit it and taste it
i never got the lavender flavor or aroma
but that is a good thing because i am
not a big fan of lavender
or lilac flavors or aromas so it worked
out perfectly for me
i'm sure if i went a little bit hotter
or a little bit cooler maybe i'd pull
out that lavender but i'm not gonna try
because i feel lucky that i didn't get
that flavor in my mouth
on the back of the package it says the
product does contain 68.21
thc and non-detectable amounts of cbd
i feel like i've got a nice head buzz
i'm nice and rambly i feel like i'm
going a little bit fast but that may be
good
for a podcast so shout out to the doses
and mimosas
live batter all right in this episode
i'm going to read a few patreon messages
before we get there let's do a few shout
outs to a few members of the 710 club
of course the 710 club are the folks who
support us on patreon
at the seven dollar and ten cent a month
level or higher
so let's start off with the big grow
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out to karen crawford
let's follow that one up with a big
shout out to lefty hope you're doing
well brother
let's follow that one up with the big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to my buddy
kes burton hey kes i see what you're
doing with the veterans thank you for
all of your work i see it i notice it
and i appreciate it
big fist bump lots of respect let's
follow that one up with a special grow
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out to our buddy mike
m i want to send a big thank you shout
out and a high five to our buddy kent
let's follow that up with the grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to dankster
i want to send a big special thank you
to kojaks i've always got a grow from
your heart podcast thank you
high five and a shout out and a fist
bump uh to my friend ned denver
let's send a big thank you shout out to
a long time listener and long time
supporter named tommy big shout out
tommy thank you for all the support bro
and last but certainly not least i want
to send a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to my good friend
tree star meadow big thanks and big
shout out to everybody who continues to
support the show on patreon
if you are not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need will be
right there on patreon they will teach
you how to join they will show you
what's available
and i do thank you for the support of
course i did include a link
in the show notes and the video
description to make it nice and easy for
you
i will also pop up a smooth little
graphic on the screen so you can read it
while you're watching the video
alright so shout out to everybody on
patreon i do appreciate
all of that support support the show
like i said before in a previous episode
and on a patreon video
all of those patreon contributions made
this new
studio setup happen i'm sure you could
tell i've got this bright ass light in
my face i got this brand new camera
slick new table we've been over this
patreon did that
thank you i appreciate it also let me
know what you feel
what you think of this new setup do i
sound good do i look good do i feel good
you tell me i appreciate your feedback
my email address is grow fromyourheart
at hotmail.com all right where are we
going to go from here
uh i wanted to make some suggestions to
you guys i don't usually come on here
and make
movie or video or tv show suggestions
for you but i feel like i would do you a
disservice
if i did not mention how much i laughed
at a new show
called the cabin that's right my friend
bert kreischer has a new show on netflix
it is called the cabin
the first 30 seconds had me sold i knew
that i was not going to leave the couch
the tv the netflix for the duration of
however many shows
were on that [ __ ] series i sat there
and watched them
smoked dabs until i was unconscious and
watched every episode of the cabin
i promise you within the first 30
seconds you know exactly what you're
getting into
you will not stop laughing that first 30
seconds tells you
exactly what to expect it sets the tone
sets the pace so
without gushing too much about my friend
bert kreischer i highly recommend his
show
called the cabin so i'm gonna follow
that up with another recommendation and
then we will move into cannabis content
i promise you i highly recommend the
comedy store
uh documentary on showtime i am a huge
comedy fan a comedy nerd
i love stand-up comedy i love comedy
specials i love comedians
i think laughter feels good what's
better after you smoke a fat dab what's
better
than laughing your ass off i can think
of a couple things we're not going to
talk about those here on the show but
laughter is one of the best [ __ ]
things on the planet you could be in a
terrible mood
you could be sick as [ __ ] and the
stupidest [ __ ] can make you laugh your
ass off and for however long you're
laughing
you're not thinking about the dumb [ __ ]
that's happening in your mind in your
body
in the world or intense times here in
the world we've got a lot of stuff going
on i'm not even gonna mention it i've
done enough mentioning crazy [ __ ] on
this show right
we're gonna we need laughter we need
other things i think laughter is [ __ ]
beautiful it's good for your soul it's
good for your spirit it's good for your
heart it's good for your body
it's recharging so here's something you
can laugh at you guys i think the comedy
store documentary on showtime
will make you laugh if you're a comedy
nerd if you know
who a lot of those people are and who
they're talking about it just may make
you cry
it's a very touching documentary it
shows a lot about
the comedy scene the coming up of comedy
and it shows you kind of a behind the
scenes look of
something i'm really passionate about so
if you're into comedy if you want
a dramatic comedy thing that you could
watch you're going to laugh at it your
significant other will laugh at
it you both may shed a tear i highly
recommend the comedy store documentary
enough of jeff's recommendations let's
talk about growing cannabis right
i said i was going to read some patreon
messages i've got a couple of great
messages here from friends who support
the show on patreon
this one comes from a fine young man who
calls himself yee mo
[ __ ] ha and that's he spelled it
perfect yee ma [ __ ] has exactly what
it says
it goes on it says i do have a question
to the best of your knowledge has the
strain name standing ovation been taken
or even ovation
bro that's a great [ __ ] name let me
explain to you how he came across this
name it says
i was just glassing in the grow room
this morning and looking at all the
praying leaves
seeing healthy happy plants thinking
about the incredible results i have had
lately
and just thought the name would be so
appropriate for so many
reasons yeah i get it when you're in
there looking at the plants in the
morning they've got their leaves up in
the in the air they're [ __ ] praying
they're giving you that standing ovation
i get it dude i see when you said the
name i knew where the inspiration came
from
i think i may have written that down
before i don't want to take credit for a
name that i don't promise you is written
on the list but
i think it was standing o and we'll talk
about that in a moment but
it says i feel like you yourself should
take a bow as we all applaud your work
that's pretty good bro thank you
then it says and you know how it feels
when friends try your herb and they're
like god damn and sometimes you deserve
a standing ovation
plus there's a linguistic connection
between a rise innovation that i thought
was interesting
but i was high yes you're high but this
is still great bro some of the best
ideas come out of us when we are baked
it says if it resonates at all with you
and hasn't been taken
i hope you consider the suggestion much
respect
my dude um so instead of using it for a
rise
how about also good idea bro bravo great
idea i'm gonna give you [ __ ] some
cheers for that one uh you get a
standing ovation
i'm gonna [ __ ] stand up and [ __ ]
there you go you officially literally
got a standing o out of me for that one
so what we're gonna do instead of using
it for a rise
i think it would work better with orange
gasm because
i've always tried to make hashtag oh
face a thing when i'm advertising orange
guys i'm
never caught on but now maybe that i've
said it out loud it was mine that was my
intention
hashtag oh face for orange asm i thought
it would be funny marketing i thought it
was funny i tried that when i posted it
up to instagram nobody even noticed that
i was posting
oh face it got overlooked but um the
standing ovation the o face uh that
those could be different phenotypes we
could name a phenotype
of the orange gasm the standing ovation
or that oh face that's just something
that could go along with the marketing
for the orange gasm i don't think i'm
going to use it as a strained name
if there's another breeder out there
that wants to use that as a strain name
i don't
it doesn't fit my stuff uh it kind of
does but i'm not going to go for it i
think it would be more of a phenotype
name like we labeled that phenotype the
roster jeff cut the mean girl cut
the pungent cut and now you got the
standing o cut and the o
face cut that's where i find it would be
more appropriate
i do appreciate the feedback i hate to
reject your name here on a show but i do
love that name suggestion it is just not
for me right now
however it may come up in the future if
somebody else beats me to it that's a
great name
somebody should market that [ __ ] all
right we're going to keep moving because
i've got a couple of great messages here
this one comes from our friend hg
and it says hey ross to jeff i'm a big
fan of the show and i've recently
become able to supply my own medicine
due to
largely your tips ah man thank you
that's [ __ ] that's a hard sense for
my brain to figure out what to say it's
hard to read but
once i figured it out i'm glad you were
growing great medicine
and supply your own medicine largely due
to my tips it makes more sense when i
said it out loud again
you saved my summer 2019 from death so
thank you
bro i'm glad i could rescue your summer
2019 crop
it says on a recent episode you and
white mike and i actually corrected you
on that one it was jesse that said this
on the episode i think it could have
been mike
90 sure jesse is the one that said what
you're going to talk about here
it says uh you and jesse talked about
how you guys used to cut around
caterpillar damage but now that you've
learned more uh
you've learned more so now you just cut
that [ __ ] away can you please elaborate
as to what you have learned and some
detail as to how your practices are
different
now um so yes in the outdoor episode
we did talk about how back in the day if
we found a bud with caterpillar damage
in it we try to cut that part away
and now we do things differently now we
would simply
throw the damaged contaminated buds away
there are several reasons for that
um now we're not greedy uh back in the
day we were
and i hate to say we were black market
growers where we had to do things
sneakily and we didn't have big
facilities and every [ __ ] gram
counted to pay the rent and
all the other things now it's not such a
cutthroat it is cutthroat but there's
also quality assurance i've got
uh less ego less uh less struggle
less strife what is the uh the mentality
when there's not enough to go around i
used to have that mentality
now there's enough to go around so i
don't have to try to market that
terrible product that's not safe and
dangerous i'm not as greedy
i've got better morals i've got better
ethics and everybody deserves
better better quality that stuff with
the caterpillar damage the bug [ __ ] in
it
that's not rasta jeff quality that's not
up to my ethics
my responsibility is to provide a better
product my responsibility is to find
that problem
and make sure that doesn't get to people
we're making
a medical marijuana product it says
medical marijuana on it so people that
are consuming this
have a medical condition i don't know if
it's a broken knee or a lung disorder
but i don't want to give somebody with
the lung disorder
buds with [ __ ] caterpillar damage in
it i don't want to give them buds with
powdery mildew in it i don't want to
give them buds with spider mite eggs in
it
so it's my responsibility to have better
standards than that than to
just cut around it and give them the
part that looks good you just throw the
part that isn't good
away and you save your reputation you
save your business
and you save the patients their patients
the people we're growing for medical
marijuana this is their medicine
i don't want to make them sicker when
people consume the product that i grow
and create
they feel better and i get to watch them
i go to their house and we roll up right
and they're like bro i don't feel good
my muscles hurt i don't mean
i was that was almost disrespectful the
way i did that but that's what i see it
they're like [ __ ] tensed up
bro my body sucks it hurts i'm [ __ ]
in pain and i'm like well here bro take
a [ __ ] dab and let's smoke this joint
and by the time i leave they're like bro
so have a good day i'll see you next
time thanks for coming by and their arms
are waving around and their neck is
flopping because they're loosened up and
they're smiling and they're having a
good time
i got to do that to somebody me myself
and my crew
i bred it my crew and i grew it we
harvested trimmed it took care of it got
it to a patient
that didn't feel well they consumed it
they feel better that fills me with
pride and all kinds of other [ __ ]
amazing words a lot of great things i
get filled up
jubilation may be the appropriate word
i've never used jubilation before
there we go but it fills me up with all
kinds of good feelings
i want to feel good about what i'm
giving my patients my friends the people
that consume the products i grow
if i knew that there was caterpillar
eggs caterpillar [ __ ] caterpillar damage
mold bud rot fungus in there i wouldn't
feel good about it
i would say and i'm gonna use my buddy
old doug as an example
old doug's not the healthiest [ __ ]
old guy on the planet old doug could
probably smoke some healthy cannabis and
be just fine if we gave him some
contaminated [ __ ]
in probably three five seven to ten days
doug's gonna start coughing up weird
[ __ ] doug's gonna tell me bro i just
haven't felt good for the past couple
days and i'm gonna go
oh man i wonder if it was because of
that caterpillar weed that i sold him or
that [ __ ] powdery mildew weed that i
sold him
and i'm gonna feel like [ __ ] that's not
what i'm here for
i don't want to feel like [ __ ] about
anything that i do to people i i did
enough of that [ __ ] [ __ ] when i was
younger
20s early 30s those are [ __ ] days
i'm i'm a [ __ ]
grown ass man now it's time to do
grown-ass man things and step up so
that is the long way of saying i've just
learned a lot about
myself about my goals about my ethics
about quality
about maintaining a business it's not
about making that extra eighth out of
the bag today
it's about making a long-term customer
and patient
that wants to buy 365 eighths every day
through the next year because they
didn't get one moldy one from me today
they'll buy 364 days in a row with
intentions to buy
the next 365 but if you sell them one
eighth
that they find some [ __ ] in it you
just lost 365 eighths worth of sales
from that person
because there are plenty of dispensaries
growers and other people distributing
the same product as us you've got to
have
high standards good quality and you
gotta have good ethics and good morals
so i think i went on
long enough about that part i'm gonna
keep going um
the trimmers so usually we said we used
to cut that part out
this is where the trimmers come in as
the quality assurance
part of the cultivation facility a lot
of people downplay the importance of the
tremors
they think the lead growers the [ __ ]
king the cultivation team
are like the the knights and [ __ ] and
then the trim crew or the peons
the villagers that is in no way the
truth
the [ __ ] trim crew is just as
important as the lead grower and the
growtex
just as important as the security guard
the manager the owner and the
consultants those trimmers
are quality assurance they touch every
single bud that goes through the
cultivation facility
we chop it down we hang it up while
they're cutting it they see it while
they're cutting it down
while they're leafing the hanging plants
they see it they're looking at it
they're touching it hands on face to
face
they have a closer relationship with
some of those plants than i do sometimes
because they've cut it up into little
pieces and got to hold on to it like
this
when i saw it it was in a pot it was
[ __ ] huge they get to get up close
and very personal so they're trimming it
they've got a big magnifying glass it's
probably the size of an ipad and it just
sits right over the buds and they put
their hands on their scissors under that
they can see powdery mildew caterpillar
damage spider mite damage
seeds anything that may be in there
they're going to spot it they
are my quality control their quality
assurance they touch every bud
every flower that goes into your jar
past the tremors hands
they inspected it while they were
trimming it they saw that caterpillar
damage so
the trimmers are the ones that find that
that is where the quality control
happens
so you guys if you're thinking that the
trimmers aren't [ __ ] super important
without them your ship will
crash and they are quality control so
don't buy machines and take good care of
your trimmers that's where i'm headed
with that there is more to this
it says i am in spring outdoor flower
with a lot of caterpillar damage
i've caught so many and cut away so much
already i may
have to do everclear extract for the
first time just for sanitary reasons
because i see caterpillar dung
everywhere by the time i'm reading this
message you've probably harvested that
outdoor this was sitting in the pile
just cooking i apologize for taking a
long time to get to that message
however i hope i did answer your
question about cutting parts out and why
we changed our methods
because we simply grew up we've learned
how to manage ourselves our businesses
and our crops
a little bit more professionally and we
know that the people relying on us
deserve better than that from us and we
should teach people better as well
uh lead by example that's a thing that
i've been taught so i want to keep going
because i can get quite rambly
i've got one more uh question for this
episode and it goes like this
it says hey rosted jeff hey bro thanks
for reaching out says i want to start by
saying thank you for the wealth of
knowledge you are consistently sharing
and thanks for taking care of the audio
as well as you do thank you for noticing
i've got all new equipment here so i
hope the audio sounds as good as you are
expecting i hope i'm up to par
i've still got to learn where to keep
this microphone i feel like right here
is best but now it's in my view for
reading so there's some negotiating to
be done
but i do appreciate the compliments let
me know what you think about the new
video i keep mentioning video and i
haven't said the most important part if
you are not watching on youtube at this
point
i highly recommend you check us out on
youtube i've done some major upgrades
the video is now in 4k it looks [ __ ]
super crispy in my opinion
i'm still learning how to work the
lighting i'm learning some camera
settings
really like the way it looks on my
screens today hopefully it comes up just
like that on the video but
i think you will appreciate the 4k video
and i will get some sun on this shiny
forehead i'm used to wearing a hat
trying to adult a little bit harder
without the hat so thank you for all the
comments
trust me i know let's stay focused uh
you like the audio
uh tell me what you think about the
video not just you everybody out there
hit me on twitter at
podcast or send me an email
growfromyourheart hotmail.com
let's keep me focused because i'm high
as [ __ ] today it says another big shout
out
to your flavor and high profiles from
what you're dabbing on
as well i love hearing what you guys are
able to get out there in colorado
i'm glad you appreciate it bro because
some people have sent me messages saying
quit talking about what you're dabbing
we don't [ __ ] care
you're just showing off you're rubbing
it in i live in a place where i can't
get that and all you do is piss me off
so i'm glad that you appreciate it and
that you can live vicariously through me
that's what i'm trying to do
i'm trying to let you know what i smoked
what i got to experience
what the flavor was like what the terps
were like and then i tried to tell you
uh how it made me feel also that will
give you an indication of why i'm
[ __ ] talking so goddamn fast which is
from this doses in mimosas it's got me
firing on all cylinders that is for damn
sure i like it it's a good thing
but sometimes when i smoke the tkd
number 10 that one puts me like kind of
chilled out and i get a little bit
slower
so that's why i share because i like you
guys to know kind of bring you in with
me
and also some of my friends live near me
or in the same state and all over
colorado you can get the doses and
mimosas
so maybe they're dabbing the same thing
and they'll grab a jar of it and go hey
me too
they're hitting the doses and mimosas
with me and then we're both talking too
fast
unity that's all i'm trying to do is
bring you in bro share my life i'm glad
you enjoy it
let's keep going it says i'm about to
harvest some of my plants and i've
always heard
mild bro science regarding hours of
darkness prior to harvest
i've heard you talk about your last few
days being 18
6 but i'm not sure i remember if you
talked about darkness
i have seen some test results that seem
to show some different cannabinoid
levels when harvested
different uh during different intervals
of light deprivation
i'm sure that is accurate so what we're
talking about is at the end of harvest
those last couple of days so your plants
say they go 65 days
we're going to put them for 65 days in
flower than 67 68 69
total [ __ ] darkness that's what this
guy is talking about
that is not uncommon i hear about that a
lot it's usually 24 or 48 hours of total
darkness this guy is going to go three
full days
um i guess that can't be a huge problem
it's not they're already in the dark
they're not gonna herm out or
anything like that they don't have time
um so
he says he has seen different
cannabinoid levels
uh from different uh levels of light
deprivation i completely agree with that
and believe that
they're going to change and kind of
freak out toward the end there so you're
going to see different things by doing
different things to them that completely
makes sense
um i actually do 18 6 for the last 10
days
and i don't do a dark cycle a long dark
cycle right now
honestly most of what i'm growing is
either a phenohunt run
so i don't want to do something super
crazy to that so i do just 12
12 or 11 13 on my phenohunt test runs
my seated crops they all finish at 18 6.
my smokable flower runs
uh sometimes i do them 18 six for the
last two weeks or 10 days
but a lot of times i don't have room and
manipulation space because i have other
things in the rooms
but most of the time it's 18 six for the
last 10 days if i can
but i don't do that longer uh dark
period
if they're seeded i do them 18 6 for
like [ __ ] 30 full days
maybe even longer but those are seeded
plants my
my my world is crazy when it comes to
growing let me keep focused so i don't
give any weird advice here
it says i just toss my uh three plants
into a dark room for
what will amount to 36 hours of total
darkness prior to chop tomorrow night
after work so we got 36 hours not three
days i misread that
uh can you speak to the efficacy or lack
thereof of darkness
prior to harvest thanks again for
everything you can use my name if needed
uh shout out to my friend evan thank you
for the great message uh evan you said
in the beginning of the message that you
have
heard a bunch of bro science i'm going
to back your bro science up with a whole
bunch
of bro science i don't have a lab i
don't have testing equipment
but i've got experience in my opinion my
experience is
as valid as a book as a lab because i
can see what's happening i'm pretty
observational i'm pretty smart
but again this is bro science from
things i've read and things i've seen in
my own grow so
what i understand is light degrades
terpenes as the
powerful grow light is shining down onto
your plants and hitting your trichomes
the terpenes are being uh disrupted
volatized
destroyed uh there are other words that
we can use vaporized
in the process so darkness would
probably in theory
increase terps you ever go in the room
during the day
and it smells like moist grow room you
go in the grow room during the dark
cycle
it smells like [ __ ] dank weed that
kind of gives me the belief that
something's happening in the dark cycle
it's not just a transpiration or a
respiration thing i think there are more
terps present in that dark cycle because
the heat and the light are not breaking
them down
so dark for tert preservation is a good
start
also heat breaks down your terps so the
cold in there
when it's not as bright it's not as hot
so that cool dark
you may be building up more terpenes
that may be a real thing
also i have experienced that some
cultivars do
gain in density they get tighter in
structure the buds tighten up they get a
little chunkier
i have noticed that in like more indica
dominant
wider leafed purple kind of plants they
will do that a little bit more
the thinner leafed longer skinnier
sativa
kind of plants they don't do it as much
so
ah that's something that i've noticed
also i don't think your plants are going
to make
more trichomes while they are in the
dark we've only got 72
hours or 36 hours that's a day and a
half
if you do produce more trichomes those
plants have been in flower for days
we've been waiting for those trichomes
to get ripe any new trichomes that pop
up aren't going to have time to ripen
so that's why we're going to see varying
test results in my theory in my opinion
also i think lab testing is the only way
you're going to get
totally completely accurate information
on what we're doing keep in mind i did
say bro
science this is totally bro science i
gave a lot of disclaimers on that
but what i think happens when you put
your plant in the darkness like that it
kind of goes in panic mode
and it knows that it's over it's like
hey the plant relies on the sun the sun
tells it
hey it's springtime it's supposed to veg
then it goes hey it's fall time i'm
supposed to flower
and then it starts going hey the days
have been getting short i better hurry
up and finish
my whole goal in life is to get
pollinated so i can reproduce and make
seeds and if you're not going to
pollinate me
and let me produce seeds i'm just going
to get bigger and bigger and make bigger
fatter buds
so when you turn off the sun it goes
dude it's the [ __ ]
end so those buds just beef up and swell
the best they can at the end
then you've got that darkness that
darkness provides
more terpenes i think and then you've
got that cool which provides more
terpenes i think so
you're going to get swelling you're
going to get ripening of the trichomes
because they don't have
the daytime cycle the plant's just going
to freak out some of the
processes aren't going to happen so it
may help you ripen up it may help you
get a little more density
and it may add to flavor this is going
to be strain specific this could be
cultivar specific this could just be
very specific to the plant you were like
one out of seven plants in your grow may
love this how many plants you see you've
got you've got three
one of them may hate this two of them
may hate this they all three may love it
it's going to be based on the plant that
you were doing this with but
in most results it doesn't cause in most
experience it doesn't cause problems
it causes more uh increase in density
and flavors and aromas
all right my buddy evan i do appreciate
the great message and the great question
if anybody out there has any comments
corrections questions or concerns
involving any of the
emails i read on today's episode i would
love to hear from you again my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
don't be shy send me some feedback i
love corrections
and questions if you feel like this
episode was educational informative or
entertaining
and you'd like to make a financial
contribution to the show all you have to
do is visit www.patreon.com forward
slash grow from your heart
all of the information you need to
support the show will be right there on
the screen
again thank you to everybody who
supports the show
where are we from there oh cano buzz
please follow me on cannabaz
cannabuzz is a cannabis friendly social
media application that does not mean you
can buy sell or trade cannabis on
cannabiz
but you can post your cannabis related
content you can post your grow photos
you could post your dab videos
you could post your pictures of your dog
in the grow room you could post a
picture of your plant that's got a
problem and you can say what's wrong
with my plant
and myself and a bunch of other
experienced growers will chime in and
will say
looks like a calmag deficiency we'll let
you know what's going on with your plant
give you some advice on how to fix it
there's a great community on cannabis
they do
live panels they do live chats there are
a lot of videos on there
you would enjoy you would appreciate so
check us out on cannabis
simply go to your application store in
your mobile device download canon buzz
install it it is free create yourself a
username
then log in then give me a follow i am
irie underscore genetics on cannabis
i look forward to seeing you there if
you've got questions
send them to me you can send them to me
on cannabuzz or grow from your heart
at hotmail.com don't forget to check us
out on youtube
simply go to youtube search for the grow
from your heart podcast click subscribe
also click on that little bell what that
little bell does is every time i put out
a new episode it will give you a notice
a notification
so you never miss any of my content all
right that is all i've got for you for
this episode i want to thank you again
for hanging out
i'll be back in a couple of days with
fresh new content i want to give a giant
shout out to my buddy dave's not here
and until next time take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me