welcome back podcast world i'm your host
my friends call me rasta jeff and it is
time for episode 585
of the grow from your heart podcast you
know i like to start the show off by
talking about what i'm smoking
today i've been taking dads of og lime
killer live batter
i think it smells like limes and
gatorade powder it's got a really nice
head buzz to it
it's got me talking kind of fast and
it's got my brain moving quite quickly
so this should make perfect podcast
concentrates
so big shout out to the og lime killer
live
batter in this episode i'm going to read
a couple of patreon messages
before we get there let's do a few shout
outs to a few members of the 710 club of
course the 710 club
are the folks who support us on patreon
at the 7.10 a month level or
higher so with no further ado let's
start off with the big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out to our
friend mister
let's follow that one up with a shout
out to our buddy jeffrey i want to send
a special thank you shout out to i want
to talk to samson
let's follow that up with the grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to ocannabis613
let's send a big thank you shout out to
yannick bucci if i said that incorrectly
send me an email and i will say it
correctly the next time i give you a
shout out
let's follow that up with the big grow
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out to frugalrock
i want to send a thank you shout out to
learning and vernon i've always got a
special thank you shout out to justice
smokin
let's send a thank you shout out to
xavier c and last but certainly not
least
let's send a big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out
to our friend a d h d
grower big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who supports the show
if you are not supporting the show on
patreon and you would like to learn how
to do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
the information you need on will be
right there on the screen and of course
i did include a link in the show notes
and in the video description to make it
nice and easy for all of my
friends also ladies and gentlemen i do
invite you and encourage you to check
out the new updated website i knew i do
keep saying that the website is updated
and approved on every episode
i think we are almost complete with the
upgrades the updates
uh iriegenetics.com and
iriegeneticscolorado.com are all updated
the only thing we need to do is add a
few more strain descriptions
add a few more strain photos update a
few of those things
everything will be up to speed i will
add more strains over time
but i am proud of what we've got up
there big shout out to my friend who
helped me with the new web design i do
appreciate the help
uh big shout out to everybody who has
sent me feedback and encouragement
on the new website i do appreciate it uh
there's more stuff coming soon
so by the time you hear this we should
be upgraded but if there's a strain
you're curious about on there
please take a look so if you're
interested in anything i read genetics
if it's
iriegenetic seeds the grow from your
heart podcast if you're looking for my
social media
if you need to contact me everything is
right there at iregenetics.com please do
take a look
also there are more shirts and hoodies
on the website that's right i have added
pink and gray arise t-shirts and hoodies
you get a pink t-shirt
or a pink hoodie or a gray t-shirt or a
gray hoodie
grab them quickly because some of the
sizes already sold out i had to
replenish them
some of those already sold out again so
go quickly grab your t-shirts and
hoodies
before they sell out all right that is
enough chatter here at the start of the
show let's jump into a few
patreon messages i've got a great
message here right in front of me this
one comes from our friend chris what's
up kris good to hear from you bro
i love picking on you making fun of your
name that's all in love and respect
this message goes just like this it's a
full moon so i just flipped to flower
i like that a lot of people follow the
full moon for their flowering cycles
i can respect that it goes on to say i
probably effed that up by taking
pictures just now
ah that's funny you turned it to 12 12
the lights went off and you realized i
should
take some pictures in the dark if it was
the first day that's not a big deal and
it says it was day one so no worries
there
it goes on to say the big one is a rise
the shorter one is morning dew
i probably need to make the canopy more
even for flower
flower picks in 63 to 70 days so he's
sent me some vegetative pictures i did
not uh save them to show them to you
guys
but we've got the important part of the
email and i look forward to seeing
uh flower picks in 63 to 70 days don't
wait 63
catch me around week six that's when the
photos start getting really good so
snap some photos then anyway there is a
lot to this it says thank you for the
reply i was just about to send you an
email with some questions here's the
great part of the message
it says with your new leds do you notice
it takes less
time to finish so i'm sure if you've
been paying attention to the show you
know that i've started growing
in some spaces with black sail canon
leds from black sail market
and i really do enjoy and appreciate the
results i am seeing
with my led lights the plants are
growing uh quite quickly
the stalks are a little bit thicker the
inner node spacing is a little bit
tighter
the plants seem overall just a little
bit healthier so
do i notice it takes less time to finish
yes i do notice that it could probably
uh come down
about three to five days sooner than
what i'm used to with the hps lights
they're
finishing up a little bit more quickly
just three to five days maybe a week at
the most i don't have enough
experience yet i don't have enough
completed crops to have a good
solid reliable report but yes it did
seem like they finished a little bit
earlier this time
then it goes on to say how far above the
canopy do you hang
your led lights um
unfortunately i ran out of space so i
started off at the recommended
uh black sail sends a recommendation
sheet in
the with the lights there's like a
little instruction sheet i think they
say to start off about
36 inches above the canopy to the best
of my memory
i started off as recommended i saw that
the plants were happy but i thought
maybe they could take a little bit more
light
so i lowered them then the plants were
growing like crazy
i put them into flour and that thing
that happens the plants got taller than
anticipated i didn't flower early enough
and they got real tall
i was worried that those plants were
going to get burned by that bright light
but they did not
they got about 10 to 14 inches somewhere
in that range depending on which plant
it was which phenotype it was
they got about 10 to 14 inches from
those leds and they did not cause
any problems there was no crinkling no
burning no leaf issues everything looked
okay so
uh 10 to 14 inches didn't seem to cause
a problem they were
they needed a lot of water at that rate
they were definitely drinking and eating
a lot
so 10 to 14 inches is as close as i
would go and the only reason i did that
is because i ran out of space i was
growing that
strawberry starburst in there the
strawberry fields in there and it got up
near the lights because it was just
growing too long got tall on me
i would prefer to stay probably about 18
inches away from that light
but i didn't see any problems when i got
10 to 14 other than
i needed more water so it says dimmed or
no i don't dim
i don't dim the lights i feel like i
paid for that light i want all the
wattage from it
maybe i could have dimmed it when they
were getting close but that's just not
my style
i paid for all that so um yes they did
finish faster
uh they did start to grow into the light
and no i did not dim it those are the
notes that i wrote down for you
so there is more it says should i feed
to week six and flush on the plants in
these pictures here's
where we get into another question these
plants were supposed to be in cocoa but
i used a hot organic mix and then
transplanted into cocoa
that's kind of where your plants are
getting a little bit confused they got
one rhizosphere right in the middle
that's
cocoa that's how that's soil and it's
holding a bunch of nutrients
and it's a hot mix and then on the
outside you've got cocoa so they're not
sure
what to do they're kind of confused it
said i feed them have strength nutrients
they tend to burn if i go heavier than
that at the moment
because you got two different root zones
and they're kind of confused it said
most likely the vpd
is too high if you think the vpd is too
high you're probably correct a lot of
people say it could be this
it's probably exactly what it is
currently it's open vented with 86
degrees and 63
humidity that's a little bit warm and
that's a lot of humidity in there so
yeah it says but i plan to close things
up and use
the ac and add co2 a couple of weeks
into flower that will definitely help
you out
but yes your vpd is off and i don't have
a picture of those plants to help you
out to tell you
uh what to do with them but it does
sound like yes your vpd is off you're
asking if you should
uh feed to week six and then flush the
plants
i don't have a picture to tell you but
if you think the vpd is off
give them a flush then get them on a
solid regular feeding just wash out that
cocoa soil mix it's only going to take
one rinse to get anything out of there
then mix up a solid feeding you need a
good a good npk a good calmac put some
enzymes in there put some microbes in
there
maybe a kelp product in there get a good
solid diet for those plants give them a
good solid meal
like they just got out of jail or the
hospital and you want to feed them up
real nice and get them healthy again
give them a rinse get all the crap out
of them mix up a solid feed
and then feed them and then let's pay
attention to what happens to them from
there
and also let's correct the vpd that vpd
is probably
uh making it not able to make the plants
not able to eat properly
so they can't get the proper nutrition
if you're even giving it to them
and they're confused by that double root
zone stuff they don't know what to do
with the soilless mix the hot soilless
mix in the middle and the cocoa on the
outside
they're confused bro so that's going to
be a struggle
for the next couple of weeks if you're
in week 6 i would say flush them
water them with a good feed see how they
react and then consider your moves from
there if they respond well to that
flushing and new feeding
uh proceed with caution until about week
eight then flush and then finish them
if they keep acting weird you're gonna
have to adjust your feedings
uh you said that they go they burn if
you go any more than half strength so
feed them half strength man keep going
half strength all the way up to the end
don't burn them
don't [ __ ] them up give them what they
need try to nurse them all the way to
the end and learn from it
baby them learn as much as you can take
a lot of notes observe a lot see what
they do for you
then it says last question at harvest do
the pistols
shrivel when the butt is ripe or should
i just watch the trichomes
i'm gonna look right into the camera
here always
judge ripeness by your trichomes always
that's what tells you when the plants
are ripe those pistils the stigmas
those are the breeding parts of the
plant those are there to catch pollen
and slide that pollen down into the
calyx into the ovule
start making a seed those pistols those
stigmas aren't for ripeness
we're gonna smoke them because they're
there but they don't have anything to do
with the buzz
with the ripeness we don't need those
you could wipe all of those off and the
cannabis will still be the same it will
still be high quality
if all the the hairs from your buds end
up in the bottom of the bag before you
smoke it
and all you smoke are trichomes you'll
still get high if all the trichomes come
off your buds and all you smoke are
hairs
you're not going to get high so let's
not judge ripeness
ever by the pistols or the stigmas of
our plants the only way to determine
ripeness of a cannabis plant
is through the trichomes you want amber
trichomes a lot of people say 20 to 30
percent amber i can agree with that
cut them down dry them and cure them
they'll be perfect at that point
judge your ripeness always looking into
the camera right here again we're going
to zoom in on my face for this one
always determine the ripeness of your
cannabis plant by the color of the
trichomes
nothing else matters all right you're
not going to smoke the leaves you are
that's not what we're aiming for if
you're going to make a concentrate all
you're going to consume
is the trichomes we're not going to
smoke the leaves we're not trying to
smoke the hairs or the stigmas our goal
is to smoke
ripe trichomes so judge all of your
ripeness
by your trichomes that is when you cut
down is when the trichomes are ripe
all right i think i covered all of the
questions in this it says thanks for the
advice
and reply in advance from your friend
chris hey chris thanks for all of the uh
continued patreon support
and thank you for the great message and
i do apologize that this one took me a
minute to get to
i just saw the date on there and i'm
late bro a big shout out and thank you
for the support
all right let's keep moving this message
comes from a good friend
known as yee mo [ __ ] ha he spells it
y-e-e-m-u-f-u-k-k-i-n-h-a-w just in case
you wondered that looks like ye mo
[ __ ] hot of me
it starts off with irie army for life
ah that's right dude i re army for life
it goes on to say how's it going rasta
jeff it's your friend yee mo
[ __ ] ha i hope you and your loved
ones are well
i myself am great i'm pretty sure that
my loved ones are doing well also
it says i would love to hear your
thoughts on how you would strategize if
you were in a scenario
similar to the situation i am in
if you are growing nothing more than
your own small personal garden i've got
a 3x5
or a 3.5 by 3.5 veg space and a 5x5
flower space and a separate spot for
seedlings and clones
what would you be looking for in regards
to narrowing out
about three keepers if your goal is to
have a rotation
of flavors as well as trying to avoid
tolerance build up
to a particular cultivar that's a very
great question
said my first set of irie beans arrived
in april and after running the females
through flour a couple of times and
separating the good weed from the
incredible weed
i have a firefly and a lemon jeffrey
that are both far superior
to any herb you can find for miles
around here
i really loved it i really love hearing
that my genetics are making people happy
and that they've got superior
product compared to everybody around
them it does go on to say what does it
say
um scarlet begonias is also incredibly
bonkers
but she grows so fast i have a hard time
staying on top of her
isn't that a bummer that that plant
grows so fast it messes up your schedule
that's how the redheaded stranger that i
bred it from was in my commercial grows
i had to cut clones of that two weeks
later i'd cut clones of everybody else
today
and then in two weeks we'll cut that one
because she's gonna go
so quickly that i just don't need her
for that two weeks she'll get way too
big she'll outgrow everybody else and
[ __ ] up the rhythm so i know what you're
saying
uh the mommy plant that made that one
had hyper hyper vigor i'm trying to get
my mic right in my face here
all right let's keep moving it says i
know lemon skunk is the mother of both
firefly and lemon jeffrey
even though these two are not that
similar to each other and i'm thinking
long term
if i can part with one of them i'll have
to make a tough decision either way
one will stay so where would you go from
there if you were trying to establish a
small
variety of killers that would be a good
rotation this is a very good question
if you are a medical grower and you're
growing for yourself you need to keep
your medicine supplied but
if you continue to smoke the same thing
over and over again you will get what i
call strain lock or strain burnout
if i smoked lemon jeffrey is one of my
top five
favorite strains ever of all time if i
smoked lemon jeffrey all day every day
by day seven or eight it's not gonna do
much i'm gonna smoke it i'm a heavy
smoker you guys so it may take most
people like a month it's gonna take me a
week
ten days i'm gonna be smoking it and
smoking it on days one through three i'm
gonna be like this good weed i'm nice
and high by day four i'm gonna be like
that ain't working so much day five i'm
gonna be like yeah i need to switch it
up by day seven i'm gonna be like
nothing's even happening when i smoke
all this
so i do believe you get sort of a strain
lock you get too used to smoking the
same thing
also if you're growing to uh for a
profit you need to switch it up to
switch it up for your clientele
people are going to get bored buying the
same [ __ ] all the same time so
here is a very good question how do we
keep a good rotation of just
three different strains and you did say
that you've got the lemon jeffrey in
there
uh you said you've got the firefly in
there and you mentioned
scarlet begonias and you want three
keepers
the main thing is what works for you it
sounds like you're in love
with the uh the firefly and the lemon
jeffrey which are similar but different
which will be
that's a great thing if those work for
you medicinally
they are very similar but also very
different so they're going to have
similar medicinal properties but they'll
be different enough to where i think you
could probably switch them out
and not get a strain lock from switching
those two different types
now you said you've got the scarlet
begonias but it goes too fast for you
and it's incredibly bonkers yes some of
the head buzzes
the sativa dominant varieties that come
from that scarlet begonias cross will
give you a panic attack that make you
feel all warm when you smoke it
uh make you feel like your blood's on
fire and you got a sweater on you just
get so hot and panicky
it is bonkers is a great word for it uh
but it says
where would you go if you had to pick
three four
killers for a good rotation uh man what
works the best for you it sounds like
those two lemon strains are working
great for you it doesn't sound like the
scarlet begonias was your favorite
what i would do is i would pick one for
the day and one for the night
and then possibly either one to pay the
bills if you know what i mean
and then maybe one for rotation so
you've got your
lemon sunrise you got your lemon jeffrey
and then we need something else in there
just to rotate out of those two are kind
of the lemon sunrise and lemon jeffrey
are more i would consider daytime smoke
they're gonna keep you up keep your head
going keep your brain spinning keep you
active
so i would recommend maybe something a
little bit more mellow
ah maybe something like the double dose
or the dark hollow or something
kind of chill you out a little bit also
those are so far
they don't have as many of the same
cannabinoids and terps
as the uh the lemon strains they're more
earthy uh more cushy
different variety different flavor
different aroma different buzz they do
have that arise parent in there
but the mommy plants are so vastly
different that the buzz
and the medicinal effect are going to be
way different so i would say
um stick with those two lemons if
they're working for you you don't want
to get rid of those
if they're working for you but the
funnest part about growing
is you have more seeds and you get to
hunt that next phenotype every time you
get rid of one as long as you've got one
or two that work you've got room to get
that rotation you've got one to play
with but i would work with the two
lemons
and then maybe dark hollow and maybe uh
double dose
because those are vastly different from
the two you're working with
you can work with the two have them in
rotation have the other one
as that third like nighttime medicine or
switch it up but what works the best
for you what's best for you medicinally
that's what we need i don't know what
strains work the best for you
i don't know what your your brain and
your body and all of that stuff require
i don't know if you're trying to stay
energized all day i don't know if you're
trying to take a nap
i don't know exactly what you need but
uh i would stick with the two you've got
and then just do auditions since you've
got two that are reliable
let's just pop some seeds man and see if
you can run some uh
some dark hollow run a couple of dark
hollow seeds see if one of those does
the magic trick for you if not
you don't have to keep it abandon it
you've still got those two champions
right there for you
so maybe that's my advice as a breeder
as a grower as somebody who's always
looking for the next one
i would say keep those two reliable
there and then just have that third spot
as an audition spot and if something
better beats those two
keep the two new best and that third
spot is your new audition spot maybe
you're going to end up with lemon
jeffrey
and dark hollow and something that isn't
even released yet
you just haven't found it yet so just
have two reliables
and one that's being an audition or
always have one that's like that backup
rotation that's always different from
the other two
so i would stick with the lemon jeffree
the lemon sunrise
and then i keep saying it but i feel
like dark hollow or double dose
would fill in that gap very well it's a
different flavor it's a different aroma
and it's a different buzz
and also that double dose puts out big
harvests
uh the dark hollow puts out a big
harvest so you're not gonna lose any
weight
i know the lemon jeffrey and the lemon
sunrise really put out fat harvest so
if you're expecting a big fat yield like
that you'll still keep all of that
all right i hope i answered your
question there i'm going to go back over
this real quick and make sure i got you
um yeah i think we're good the struggle
is real
it's trying to decide what to grow not
just for you but for me
i have limited plant counts and as a
breeder who wants to do new projects and
new things
i completely understand your struggle uh
and then i'm gonna make new stuff as
soon as you decide what you like
i'm gonna make new stuff to keep you on
your toes and make the decisions hard
for you
all right you [ __ ] hi i want to
thank you for the great message uh thank
you for all the continued patreon
support
i do appreciate it i've got one more
email here in front of me
this one comes from our friend tucker
and it goes
like this it says hey ross to jeff how
are you brother i am
marvelous i'm doing wonderfully tonight
thank you for asking
it goes on to say i hope all is irie
everything i read
it says i am hoping you can answer a few
questions on ipm and i was wondering if
you had a recommendation for where to
get some predator
bugs for my garden that is a great
question
predator bugs are a great way for uh to
manage an integrated pest management
system
it says i mostly deal with the pressure
from spider mites and fungus gnats
but the spider mites are what i am
mostly concerned with i would love to
treat my veg
and have an idea of what would be best
to release for flower
i know you said recently on a podcast
you're moving away from sprays
and i would like to follow suit as you
have shown me a great deal
on things concerning ipm thanks and
praises
to jah big respect thank you for the
great message yes ja rastafari big
thanks and praises to ja
let's talk about adding some beneficial
uh
beneficial bugs sorry that was harder to
say than it looked let's add some
beneficial bugs to your integrated pest
management system those are a lot of
words there
um they asked for a reputable place to
get them i am not paid by anybody i'm
not sponsored by anybody
in my opinion the most reliable spot for
a home grower to acquire
uh living bugs is from arbico dash
organics.com i've had great experience
with them
a lot of my friends have had great
experience with them i like them a lot
but also you have to be responsible and
shop locally first if possible if you
can find
a local insectiary that has the bugs you
need i would recommend getting them from
them
the less time your bugs are in the mail
or on the road or in a shipping
container
the more likely you are to get living
bugs
they are a living product we're buying
bugs that we want to come out aggressive
and hungry
we need them to come out of the box
ready to go we don't need them lethargic
and dead from a trip they don't
they don't need jetlag when they get
here so try to get them from as local of
a source as you can
maybe google put in your city and state
and then insectiary
and see if you can find an insect area
that will sell small batches to you
if not contact your local nurseries and
see if they are offering predator bugs
or maybe if they're using predator bugs
maybe they will
add some for you to their next order
that's often a way that it happens in
smaller communities
again i do recommend shopping locally
try to find somewhere that is close to
you
you don't want them to have to be
shipped for too far the most important
thing you do
is get the correct insect for the job if
you've got fungus gnats you want one bug
if you've got thrips you may want
another
if you've got spider mites you're going
to want to get a couple of bugs but
another thing to keep in mind is your
environment
how dry how humid how hot and how cold
is it in your area those things are
going to affect
how long your pests stick around yes you
may buy thousands of predator bugs
you may release a whole bunch of
swarovskis a whole bunch of californias
a whole bunch of california kiss a whole
bunch of green lace wings
and they may be hanging out for a couple
of days and they'll realize it's way too
[ __ ] cold here
and they'll find ways just to get out if
you can document your temperature and
humidity
and know kind of where you stay you
should know your regular temperature and
humidity in your grow environment
document that contact your local
insectiary
let them know the pest you are facing
and let them know your environmental
conditions
and they will make a recommendation on
the appropriate pest
and if you tell them how much space you
are working with square footage and
amount of plants and amount of lamps
uh they'll do a quick equation most of
them will know off the top of their head
say i'm facing this much pest pressure
it's either moderate or heavy pest
pressure
i've got these bugs maybe don't mention
cannabis
maybe don't mention cannabis i don't
know who you're talking to i don't know
what state you're in
maybe don't tell them you're growing
cannabis plants they probably won't ask
what kind of plants you're growing if
they do
you can say you're growing hops or you
can say you're growing tomatoes
those are very similar but let them know
what pests you're facing
let them know your environment are you
in indoors are you in a greenhouse are
you outdoors do you have high humidity
what are your temperatures what are your
bugs let them make recommendations for
you
i said before i recommend the
californicus the swarovskis
hypoaspis miles persimilis greenlay
swings
there are quite a few that i could go on
with i don't have any notes about bugs
i'm recommending those are all off the
top of my head
so i hope you got some good advice there
again the insectiaries are going to have
the best advice for your region they're
going to know
what pests to expect and they're going
to know what bugs best eradicate those
pests
in your area and what bugs survive in
your environment the best
all right uh tucker i hope i answered
your question thoroughly
if you've got any follow-up questions i
would love to hear from you you know my
email address is
grow from your heart at hotmail.com
all right ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls pimps and hoes friends and foes
chicks and bros smokers growers clone
cutters pollen chuckers
all you rad ass growers out there
everybody out there in the cannabis
community
i want to thank you again for listening
to episode 385 of the grow from your
heart podcast
if you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
and you'd like to make a financial
contribution to the show all you have to
do is visit www www.patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need to support
the show
will be right there on the screen also
don't forget to check us out on youtube
go to youtube
search for the grow from your heart
podcast click on that subscribe button
click on the little notification bell
every time i put out a new episode
you will get a notification you will
never miss any content
and i would appreciate it if you leave
some comments or at least click like on
the videos
what that will do is help us move up in
the algorithm the more likes i get the
more comments i get
the more likely we are to see be seen by
more growers
the more growers that see us the more
the show grows the more the show grows
more growers see us the more growers
that see us
the more people are growing better
cannabis out there
the more high quality cannabis out there
the easy it is for us to
overgrow the government make it legal
everywhere we want everybody growing
good herbs so that everywhere you go
there's good herb available so click on
youtube click subscribe
leave me some comments let me know what
you think about the show let me know
what you think of the new setup
if you've got any advice comments tips
uh questions corrections or concerns
you can leave those on youtube or you
can email me at grow from your heart
at hotmail.com don't forget to check out
the website at iregeneticscolorado.com
i think that is all i've got for you for
this episode i'll be back in a couple of
days with fresh new content
i want to give a giant shout out to my
friend kurt zee and until next time take
a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me