welcome back podcast world i'm your host
my friends call me rosta jeff and it is
time for episode 586
of the grow from your heart podcast this
evening i'm recording on veterans day
so i'd like to start the show off with a
big thank you shout out to all of the
veterans out there
in this episode i'm going to read a few
patreon messages
one of those messages comes from a
veteran another one comes from a
listener with questions about selecting
male plants
for breeding before we get to those
patreon messages
you know i like to start the show off by
talking about what i'm smoking
today i've been taking dabs of coin
style live batter
this is a blend of sugar town express
and lemon g13
on the package the flavor is described
as a coin style
margarita on the rocks it has been a
really long time since i've had a coin
style margarita on the rocks
so i'm just going to agree with that on
the back of the package it says it
contains
65.85 thc and non-detectable amounts of
cbd so big shout out to the coin
style live batter all right let's do
some shout outs to a few members of the
710 club
of course the 710 club are the folks who
support us on patreon
at the 7.10 a month level or higher so
with no further ado let's start it off
with the big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to our
friend rumble buns
let's follow that up with a big thank
you shout out to our friend jacob w
let's send a big thank you shout out and
a fist bump to matt h
i want to send a thank you shout out to
a long time supporter let's say thank
you to godfather cush
i want to send a big thank you shout out
to redbeard what up redbeard i think i
might be part of your gang
let's follow that up with the big grow
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out to our friend kanna organic illinois
big shout out to our friends out there
in illinois i want to follow that one up
with a special thank you shout out to
our friend glenn geroni thank you for
the long time support
i've also got a big thank you shout out
for another longtime supporter let's
send a special thank you
to the kanekrat and another long time
follower and supporter let's say a
special thank you to blackbird76
i want to send a big high five and a
fist bump to my friend craig compton
let's follow that one up with a special
thank you shout out to michael harper
and last but certainly not least let's
send a big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out to the captain and
commander of the 710 club
let's send a big thank you shout out to
lemur priest
big thank you and big shout out to
everybody who supports the show on
patreon
if you are not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need to
support the show will be right there on
the screen
once again thank you for all of the
support and i did include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it nice and easy for everybody
who's got their hands full during the
show
all right i think that is enough
rambling and chatter at the start of the
show
let's jump right into some of these
patreon
messages i did say that the first
message comes from a veteran so with no
further
ado this one goes just like this it says
greetings and salutations
i hope this message finds you and all
that hear it safe and enjoying life
i am safe i'm nice and warm i'm enjoying
life so thank you i hope you're doing
the same my friend
it goes on to say in episode 576
you assisted a fellow veteran and that's
when i learned of your show
uh then they said apologies for taking
so long hey uh no
reason to apologize for just discovering
the show i'm glad you are here
i'm glad you're able to listen and i'm
glad you're able to learn uh and i do
plan on helping more veterans you said
that uh
you heard when i assisted a veteran i
did get a light into the hands of a
grower there is a
brand new grow light thanks to keith at
black sail there is a package of seeds
thanks to irie genetics
in a veterans hands they are growing uh
because we help them out so
thanks to the ire army for all the
support we will be helping more veterans
a lot of people have reached out
needing lights a few people have reached
out trying to give out lights there's
just one of me so connecting all of
these people is taking me a little bit
i will get it organized it will happen i
have a lot going on
not making excuses just letting you know
it is in progress
uh there will be more lights given out
let's keep going it says i myself am a
disabled veteran
i suffered a botched whipple surgery
while in the navy in 2003
and willingly would provide proof uh the
statement about providing proof is
because i have mentioned on the show
that
there are too many people out there
trying to take advantage of kind people
too many people trying to take
advantage of the covid situation and
they are taking donations and receiving
gifts
uh on un uh deservingly i guess it is uh
stolen valor is what they're doing
and this veteran is just saying before
you even ask i can prove that i'm a
veteran
uh i trust you if you're gonna write in
and tell me you're a veteran and not ask
for anything like that i believe you
this message all tells me that you were
a veteran i have no doubt in there but
thank you for backing that up
it goes on it does say i have never
grown but i've been a cannabis
connoisseur
for half of my lifetime i'm finally
getting the courage
to cut a cold turkey cut off va
doctor recommended prescription opioids
after 10 years
so the veteran doctor was recommending a
prescribing opioids
for the past 10 years he's finally cut
it off and found it difficult so we
turned to the beautiful form of
gardening
and found that not only do i have a
great set of green lungs but i also have
a green
thumb to match uh yes being a military
person you have got
uh what's the word dedication uh
discipline
all of that stuff is driven into you and
now you've got passion
so with that dedication passion
discipline you will be an amazing
grower i often find that people with uh
kitchen background they've got
discipline
and motivation people with martial arts
background wrestling backgrounds people
that wrestled in school
worked in kitchens they're always good
growers good in the gardens because
they've got that determination that
discipline
and then you put passion behind that
that turns those people into savages
in the grow room it does go on to say i
definitely
don't have much in the way of friends or
family well you do now now you were a
part of the irie army so welcome to the
crew
uh welcome to the gang it says so i
enjoy your podcast and the people i get
to interact with in chat during the show
uh that means you're hanging out in the
premieres on youtube so thank you for
being there on youtube at midnight
the shows do come out monday night at
midnight monday morning at midnight and
thursday morning at midnight
we do a premiere on youtube i hang out i
chat with the gang that's there
join us hang out you can meet our new
veteran friend named mister be in the
live chat with us
it's a good time it's a it's always a
ramble fest some kind of a giggle fest
shout out to dave's not here uh og
purple thumb a lot of great people in
there
i can't list all of you a lot of you are
on my mind i can't say all your names
right now it'll get to be a long show
but come hang out with us on mondays i
encourage you that's where our friend is
talking about that they hang out
there is more to go on with uh this and
the podcast and the people again are
interact oh this is
this is the assist oh let's see this and
the there we go
this and the assist shown to the i'm not
gonna edit that out for you guys you can
see that i'm a real person
this and the assist shown to the lady
veteran is the reason for me deciding to
become a 10
a month financial contributor thank you
i'm sure that being a disabled veteran
that
you don't have a lot of spare money so
that 10 bucks means a lot to me that
you're on a very limited income you
don't have a way that i know of that you
can just go make extra money a lot of us
can just go get a second job we could do
a side job make some extra money
you may not have that option and if you
do you may lose some of your benefits so
thank you for contributing some of that
allotted money to me i appreciate that i
respect that a lot thank you um it goes
on to say
um oh i wanted to put in there uh you're
in the irie army now that's a lot less
push-ups and a lot more bong rips that's
actually a note that i wrote on my paper
had to say that so it goes on to say not
being able to afford the high quality
gear i decided that high quality
information is even better
especially when applied properly sounds
like we've got a
macgyver on our hands here and i like
this kind of person someone that learns
they've got the motivation the
determination the discipline and now
when there's a will there is a way
and our macgyver veteran friend here is
going to whip up some [ __ ] and make it
happen i love the way he does it we'll
keep going
it says so ever since i listened to
episode
576 i've been slowing i've been slowly
listening to all of your previous
episodes while taking copious amounts of
notes
ah man i'm glad you're catching up and
learning a lot it says i am growing in a
closet
with a complete home depot grow kit
and he said that's been acquired by
wandering around home depot looking for
comparable items
to the vast array i see and i
implemented while learning about
my wonderful new craft and trade
there are a lot of great things at home
depot that could definitely build you a
nice grow
i'm sure you've got a good start i was
at home depot looking for lighting for
this new area there's a new ceiling
light up here you probably can't tell
because these lights are overpowering
i got a new led ceiling like that [ __ ]
is bright
when i was there i saw this big square
led light panel and i thought
that would be an amazing grow light for
somebody who had to be stealth like
so there are things at home depot at
lowe's at your local hardware shop that
will definitely
get you through a growth build yourself
a nice little macgyver grow space just
like our veteran friend here is doing
it says i do have a grow question that
has eluded me all right i look forward
to this one
it says knowing that our beautiful divas
can tolerate higher temperatures when
implementing co2
my question is why push these higher
temps when i've also come across the
information
that higher temperatures also destroy
the terps
so yes that is accurate when we are
running
high amounts of co2 in a grow room we
can also run higher temperatures
it's not necessary but you can do it uh
generally i'll keep the grow in the low
80s high 70s low 80s and flowering
usually 79
84 that's kind of where i want to be
don't go any higher than 84.
like i try to say about 77 82 but i mean
84 because it's summertime in colorado
it gets hot sometimes
so i try not to go any hotter than that
if you're running a lot of co2
you can go 87 88 degrees maybe a little
higher i don't like to go too much
higher than
that when you're running co2 the plants
won't react
too poorly to that but you do have that
risk
of burning off the terps now the reason
most people are running
the heat a little bit higher with the
co2 is because they can't
cool the room efficiently and instead of
investing in more cooling equipment
they got co2 that is quite often the
case not always
but that is a way if you've got a little
bit too much heat you can't get it down
that couple of degrees
you can't plug in another air
conditioner you can't get more
ventilation you're struggling with
two three maybe four more degrees spend
the money on co2 you get bigger better
faster growth and you don't have to
battle the heat
so it's not always the perfect solution
to have the high temp in the co2
sometimes it's just circumstance and it
is what was done sometimes it was the
easiest solution sometimes it was the
cheapest solution
sometimes it was the only solution so
you were correct in all of the above
things that we can go higher temps
with higher co2 and you were also
correct in thinking
that higher temperatures do volatize our
terpenes
um i think i don't think that the
temperatures we are getting
the differential between no co2 and co2
temperature grow rooms are enough to
destroy
too many terps it's just a few degrees
you're getting up to like
i don't even want to say 90 degrees that
that's gonna start [ __ ] with terps
but a lot of what we're talking about i
think comes from the old school grow
world like i said this came from when we
couldn't add another air conditioner or
maybe the black market grow world or the
underground grow world or the free
market grow world whatever you want to
call it
the non-regulated grow world where
people had to be a little bit more
secretive a little bit more quiet about
it
so it wasn't always ideal to
run the co2 without the air conditioner
but it wasn't there wasn't another
option
also the reason i brought up old school
and back in the day
because we probably didn't know as much
about terps then we didn't know
we were cooking the terps off so we just
thought it's
[ __ ] cool enough to let the plants
grow they're happening so let's just let
it grow
so they were probably just using the co2
because they couldn't cool the room and
it was the option
uh i don't know that that heat is going
to be enough to disrupt and destroy the
terps
and also we didn't know about terps at
that time so
that's why we weren't too worried about
the terpenes serpents are kind of
for a little while there uh terpenes
were just the word of the day
phenotype was the word of the day for a
little while uh terps will go away and
it's gonna be something new it was cbd
for a minute
so now that terps have been the hot
thing we've all learned about terps and
that's why
we're more concerned more educated and
more worried about terps now we try not
to get the room so hot hopefully
but i think part of it was because we
couldn't add more air conditioning
because we were in a black market grow
and i think another part of it is
because we simply were not educated
on terpenes and the volatility of
terpenes so i want to continue there's
more it says lastly
in episode 581 you broached the issue of
somehow being able to verify
if somebody is truly a veteran i'm not
sure if you're able to incorporate the
services
but omaha stakes had a surface a service
called
id me where veterans are able to contr
confirm
their veteran status also most veterans
could share a redacted copy of their
dd213 form
i would gladly share my unredacted dd213
for some growers love hey i trust you
and respect you and believe you my
friend
uh you're not trying to get one over on
me you're not trying to get anything
from me you actually give to me on
patreon
so i believe you fully trust in you i
believe that you are a veteran
that is great advice great information
we may use that in the future
i think when my veteran friend keith
talks to vets he can tell
it's just like when a surfer talks to a
surfer a grower talks to a grower a
drummer talks to a drummer
some stuff you just can't fake so i
think uh we will catch on eventually
and if not if somebody needs to lie to
us that [ __ ] bad to get a light and
they're gonna say they're a veteran and
be that shitty of a person we'll give
them a light maybe they'll still grow
and they still get to be a shitty person
inside and know it
maybe they can grow and grow out of
being a shitty person but i do trust you
i believe you and this is a good way
to vet people and we can we can throw
this out there if we need to
it goes on to say uh please give up a
personal shout out dab and a fist bump
and especially
an especially resinous hand salute to
all of the military
veterans and their family members
yes this is veterans day as i record now
so let's send up a big
high five a fist bump a resinous
sticky handshake and a big fat bong rip
a fat
joint and a big old dab of freedom for
all of our veteran friends thank you
guys
i do appreciate you i've said it before
i'm not cut out for war
i don't agree with war i wish that [ __ ]
wouldn't happen it's gonna happen that i
it's just the world that we live in and
i'm glad that you're out there doing it
because
i am not fit for that [ __ ] so thank you
i do appreciate it
all right thank you uh to our friend mr
i think i should call you sir
right that's our last veteran was a man
so i better be careful
uh thank you for the message and thank
you for your service and thank you
for the continued support if you've got
any grow questions out there i'd love to
hear back from you don't be shy
you're a patreon member reach out to me
on patreon
all right let's keep moving or this
episode will get extremely long
this one comes from a familiar friend
this one comes from north north terps
what up north good to hear from you
again brother
uh this one says good morning good
evening anywho rasta jeff my man how is
it going it's going well bro
i'm hanging out here got these bright
lights in front of me i'm hanging out
with all my friends
i think things are great it says i wish
you well
before i get to my question i just
wanted to mention that maybe you should
brighten up your background with your
new studio a little bit um
i'm still learning the lighting i'm
learning a couple of things we'll get it
dialed in
i may put some plants right here and
here or something i may leave it
spacious
i don't know if you've noticed i got
little mini roster jeff on the desk
today hanging out with us
trying to decorate without clutter but
thank you for the feedback
let's keep going because i am getting
rambly from that dab it feels like it's
still kicking in
it says my question is i have a couple
of male
arise plants leaving their vegetative
stage that
just passed some rigorous testing and i
know i need to wait for this stem
rub smells so where is your number one
favorite spot on the plant
to get a good stem rub smell
and then he follows it up with this big
old question and what are your top
five traits you use to select males
both for flavor and for structure peace
love and
respect that's a great question let's
start with the very first one
so when we're trying to predict what a
plant is going to smell like in
the vegetative stage it is very common
just to give that
stem a rub now keep in mind that stem
rub is not going to tell you what the
plants are going to smell like
in flower in the finished stage it's
going to give you a good hint of some of
the aromas available
i know what i'm looking for in veg i
know what those veg
flavors translate to and convert to
later down the line in flour
i like a male plant that kind of smells
like puke
i know that sounds disgusting but the
male plants
that have a mothball and vomit sort of
aroma
always put out amazing terpenes once
they pollinate something
and that stuff flowers that's like a
very good
starting ingredient balls and puke it
may sound disgusting to you now
but when you get some cannabis that
smells and or tastes like mothballs and
puke
you're going to be ecstatic you're going
to love the flavor the aromas are going
to be
tremendous and thick and heavy and the
buzz will be delightful so
that is something i really enjoy is the
vomit mothball
sort of a bar trash can fermented funk
sort of an aroma
i like that in a male stem rub when and
where do i rub
rub everywhere and rub often i get in
there and violate
that bitch's space that's my plant i can
touch wherever i want
i start down low give it a little rub
smell the fingers
use another hand give it another rub in
another spot smell your fingers
rub your hands on your pants and act
like you're getting that all that smell
away
smell them again see if they smell like
pants then [ __ ] rub that stem
somewhere else and give it a smell
i get all over that [ __ ] plant she's
mine i grew it i bred it i can violate
the [ __ ] out of it
i get in there and touch it all over the
place to see what it smells like
sometimes i'll pull off a big leaf and
just squish that leaf around in my
fingers
see what kind of smells i get there i
like to get in there and smell the [ __ ]
out of them so
ah all over the place for stem rubs dude
start low
go up higher smell the leaves smell that
[ __ ] smell the essence of that plant
that's your baby girl get in there
and enjoy it the best you can now let's
talk about
five traits that i may look for when
selecting a male plant that's a very
good question to ask a breeder
with a very prolific male plant who's
been uh becoming very popular lately in
the breeding scene
things that i look for when it comes to
breeding from a male
vigor i don't want some slow shitty
wispy growing plant when i plant those
plants i want to watch that seedling go
i do not want the most vigorous fastest
growing plant that is usually
that one is too much male it's going to
have too much male dominance in the
cross it's like
if you just took this one male and
crossed it to anything
everything else you cross it to is going
to come out like that male you're going
to make a bunch of outcrosses that are
that male
the idea is to find a male that
complements all of the females you cross
it to so i don't want that first
tall male but i want one that's got a
lot of vigor to it
nice good growth not just not the run
not the slow wispy shitty one
not the one we're all waiting on we
don't want that one i want a good
vigorous plant so that's number one
vigor then i look for
shape and structure what is the shape of
the plant what is the structure of the
plant
can the branches hold themselves up does
it make a big thick stock and nice
robust branches or does it make a wispy
shitty middle stock and then try to
branch out real crazy
does it branch evenly does it honestly
you've got to have your goal in mind
that's something i've got written down
here toward the end but
the shape and structure are all about
your goal if you want a plant
that you're going to be able to scrog
out real well you might want one that
you could top and makes a lot of nice
branching that are all the same length
if you're the kind of guy that doesn't
do scrogging and you do the trees with
the pole in the middle
with a mono cropping with a monopole
maybe you want those sativa style plants
to grow long and skinny
and just long skinny branches up the top
maybe
maybe you want a short squatty indica
plant that's all about your goal
that's like if you want to make
chocolate you got to put some chocolate
in there if you want to make some
something else i'm not a cook so i don't
even know where to go with this but if
you want chocolate in it you got to have
chocolate in the mix if you want vanilla
in it you got to have vanilla in the mix
that's just how the male plant works so
you need vigor you need a good structure
and a good shape
the structure and the shape are going to
be a lot of what goes into your
your offspring so get a good structure
and a good shape look at leaf size
that's going to tell you a lot also i
also look for aroma
i mentioned that i like that bar trash
can mothballs dirty feet
all kinds of funky disgustingness i like
those aromas
that always translates into a good
stinky offspring the progeny will smell
gross and good you'll get that funky
mothball
puke aroma with whatever you're crossing
it with so
my arisemail has like a funky cushy
sweetness
when you rub the stem it's like sweet
vomit it's like somebody had too much
cheesecake and beer and threw up that's
really what it smells like to me
it's [ __ ] delicious strawberry
cheesecake and vomit give it
maybe bubble gum in there give it a
little smell you're like that's [ __ ]
disgusting
then you cross it with a plant like
platinum tangy which smells like just
straight oranges
and it comes off like gassy oranges and
it's so beautiful so
i like that flavor and aroma another
thing i really look for when i'm picking
male plants is flowering time
a lot of people don't grow a male plant
out past two or three weeks because they
go into panic mode and got to get rid of
it
even some breeders never get to see
their male plants past week four
i've posted pictures i've got pictures
of several male plants in rooms
that are past weeks nine and ten maybe
into week 11.
i really like to see what these plants
do i need to know
how long it takes them to get into full
flower how long are they going to
continue to flower
what do they look like if you flower
them for a really long time
if i let them go for a long time do i
see any problems
i want them to flower out i want them to
produce pollen i want to keep the leaves
nice and healthy
all the way through their life do those
male plants here's another thing
are they uh susceptible or resistant to
bugs and mildew
if i've got powdery mildew or spider
mites in one area i'll take that male
plant over there
and see how that male plant reacts to
those things i've got to abuse my male
plants so
uh vigor structure aroma flower time
i don't want the first males to flower
and show me that they're males
that one that's super hyper vigorous
hyper dominant hyper ready to just be
like i'm a boy let's pollinate [ __ ]
he's a little bit too dominant i don't
want that much testosterone in my mix
he's just gonna make everybody else just
a bunch of meatheads he's gonna dominate
the mix
not what i need so i want the one if i
add if i have 10 seeds i talk about this
a lot if i have 10 seeds
hypothetically 10 regular seeds
hypothetically five will be males five
will be girls let's get rid of those
five girls
they can go to your garden you get the
girls i'll grow the boys this time
that first plant that shows me it's a
male will probably get cold because he's
got too much male
energy to the grow i don't want him in
there spreading all that male gene back
in there
i want to make a new hybrid not just
reproductions of this male
so we get rid of that first guy second
guy might get a chance
that third and fourth guy is usually
where i go the fifth one is slow
he's lagging he gets cold two three and
four are the candidates usually number
three and four
are the ones i choose i've got a good
track record for choosing males so i
think i've got a good
criteria and scenario for picking my
boys so
i don't want the one that is too too
vigorous right out of the gate but i
want one that
goes into flour and starts producing
pollen at a reasonable time
around day 21 25 i want to get a lot of
pollen coming out around day 32 i really
want him going
then i want to see how he goes how long
until he reaches that full
flower then how long until he stops
producing pollen as a breeder making a
lot of seeds that's very important to me
now another thing i really like to find
in a male plant
is trichomes if i see trichome and resin
development on a male plant early in
flower
that is a breeding candidate that means
it is going to pass
trichomes onto the females the females
naturally make trichomes if your males
are making trichomes too
you got two ingredients with trichomes
lots of trichome production is what that
means to me
more trichomes more cannabinoids more
cannabinoids a better buzz more
desirable product
that's what you're going for so if it's
got trichomes on it you want to breed
with it i know i've gone past
five by now but let's keep talking
something else i really like
is a good color everybody's growing
they're posting pictures
if a good color comes out of my male
plants that is a bonus if i can get some
nice fall
wintery colors in there that is a great
thing some oranges some purple some dark
colored hues
that's something that is always a bonus
i've seen purple trichomes come out of
male plants i've seen male plants
produce purple male flowers
i've seen a lot of great [ __ ] so get in
there and breed use a bunch of male
plants
grow them see what you like then the
best way
the only real way to test those males is
to germinate
and grow the seeds you have made there
are a few things to test when you get to
that point
how well do those seeds germinate put
however many if you made 100 seeds maybe
germinate 10 of them and just see how
with intentions not even to grow them
this is just a germ test
throw 10 of them however you normally
germinate i do the paper towel method
throw ten in the paper towel germinate
them count them if you got seven of them
seventy percent germination rate that's
not super good 80 is good 90 is the best
100 you're [ __ ] killing it
but i guess 100 is the best 90 is
[ __ ] way acceptable
see how many germinate see how many duds
you have then grow them out
i just said you don't have intentions to
grow this let's [ __ ] grow it maybe we
change our mind let's grow these out
then let's see if there are any
hermaphrodites let's see if there are
any mutants let's see if there are any
[ __ ] weirdos
let's see if they even make it to the
veg stage maybe they just die out and
turn into duds before they get that far
then let's see if they're hermaphrodites
let's see if they show intersex traits
maybe you've got the next [ __ ] chem
dog in there maybe you've got the new
golden goat
maybe you just bred the new [ __ ]
skittles in there we don't know what
you've got until you grow it
now grow it in perfect conditions and
see what you come up with
if it does well in perfect conditions
our next step is to take it to a [ __ ]
up grow room and grow it in there
everybody has a friend who always gets a
certain problem
we all know that that one guy always has
powdery mildew i know that one grow over
there always has spider mites this one
dude
always gets thrips let's take these
plants to a couple of those places and
find out
what happens when we put them in a room
with thrips what happens when we put
them near powdery mildew
what happens when we treat them too hot
and too cold how do they reply to that
how do they react
if your plants freak out right away that
is not something for a market but it may
be something you want to grow yourself
so those are the ways that i check and
audition
and select male plants for breeding i
base it off of vigor
i base it off of the shape and the
structure of the plant i check out the
aromas
they come from that plant i give it stem
rubs i smell the flowers i let it flower
out
then i pay attention to how long it
takes to flower how much pollen it
produces for me
then i look for trichomes and colors and
just anything else that may stand out
being a breeder and a grower that has
had access to a lot of rooms
a lot of plants like when i work in
commercial facilities my numbers
to grow are much expanded compared to a
lot of other people's numbers
so i've gotten to see a lot of male
plants and that makes it much easier for
me to select
if you've only got 10 one may not stand
out
if you've got a hundred one of them is
gonna say i am the bad [ __ ] in
this group
i don't know what you've got to work
with but you really start seeing more
uh more opportunities more standouts
when you work with larger populations
those outliers are more obvious they
become more present more available when
you work with a lot
so i've got a lot of experience picking
boys and like i said before i feel like
i've got a pretty good track record
at picking male plants for breeding so
again it is all about your goal
what do you want to do do you want
plants that are short and squat and
smell like oranges
you may want to find a short squatty
male and a female that smells like
oranges
do you want plants that are tall and
lanky and smell like strawberries maybe
find a tall lanky meal plant and a girl
that smells like strawberries
it's all about your overall goal most of
all
have fun uh grow from your heart breed
with love
and make sure uh that you test
everything before you give it to anybody
but if you're just growing it for
yourself have fun man make a bunch of
seeds
grow the [ __ ] out of them take a lot of
notes and enjoy it
and then what are you going to do next
are you going to back cross and try to
lock in a trait are you going to f2 and
try to
stabilize some things figure out what
you want to do from there it's always
more fun to breed
as soon as you start breeding you want
to breed more then you want to breed
more
and then you want to breed more and then
you want to grow those and it just turns
it then you turn into me that you then
you end up here
uh so i want to thank you for the great
message north i think i got really
rambling on that one i feel like i
really gave you a good answer
i think that is all we've got for this
episode i want to thank you guys again
for hanging out if you feel like this
episode was educational informative or
entertaining
and you would like to support the show
on patreon all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need of
course is right there on the screen
and i did include a link in the show
notes and the video description
to make it nice and easy for all of my
friends also don't forget to check out
the youtube channel if you are listening
on the audio formats
i highly recommend you check us out on
youtube go to youtube search for the
grow from your heart
podcast click subscribe click on that
little bell that little bell is the
notification button
every time i put out more content you
will get a notification you will never
miss a podcast episode
also leave a comment on the videos let
us know what you think of the show
also it's real easy to click that like
button give us a thumbs up that will
make the show
climb in the algorithm climb in the
rankings more people will see the show
more people will be able to grow better
cannabis we can overgrow the government
legalize the world one click at a time i
might need to copyright that
anyway let's keep moving if you've got
any questions comments corrections or
concerns my email address is grow from
your heart at hotmail.com i would love
to hear from you
do not be shy i look forward to your
incoming messages
that is all i've got for you today i
want to give a giant shout out to our
friend brian c
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me