[Music]
welcome back podcast world i'm your host
my friends call me rosta jeff and it is
time for episode 587
of the grow from your heart podcast if
you're watching on youtube i'm sure you
could tell by now that white mike is
joining me
welcome to the show bro what's up man
thanks for having me
dude thanks for joining me you sound
great on the microphone today sorry for
interrupting you there right at the
start of the show
you sound amazing you look good keep it
up bro thank you for joining me
try to stay on the microphone yeah man
you're getting better at it the audience
has noticed they made a lot of
compliments and i found some gear that
makes you sound better so
this is going to be a great challenge
changes some setup changes
i think we got it figured out folks
we're going to mike some lighting pretty
soon and make him look as sharp as i do
also
he doesn't record as much as i do but
we're going to get him up to speed
anyway in this episode we're going to
talk about edibles a quite often
overlooked subject in the
cannabis podcasting realm we're going to
focus on edibles in this episode
before we get there let's do some shout
outs to a few of the folks who support
us in the 710 club
of course the 710 club are the folks who
support us on patreon
at the 7 and 10 cent a month level or
higher so i'm gonna kick it off with the
big grow from your heart podcast thank
you shout out to my buddy papa z
let's follow that up with a thank you
shout out to glenn geroni i want to send
a big girl from your heart podcast thank
you shout out to my buddy kenna organic
let's send a special thank you shout out
to my good friend tree star meadow thank
you bro
let's send a thank you shout out to tart
and mike i wanna send a big grow from
your
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to our buddy jake
let's send a special thank you shout out
to gangster i've got a thank you shout
out for tyler filth what up you filthy
[ __ ] thank you for hanging out
listen to thank you shout out to matt h
let's send a big special girl from your
heart podcast thank you shout out to
stoned
trout bum and last but certainly not
least i want to send a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out a high five and a fist bump
to our friend grant m big thanks and big
shout out to everybody who supports the
show on patreon
if you're not already supporting the
show i highly recommend you to do so and
you can do that by visiting www dot
patreon forward slash grow from your
heart all of the information you need is
right there on the screen
now is the time when i want to give mike
the opportunity to thank his patreon so
here's your chance bro go for it mike
um thank you everybody that supports me
on patreon i really really appreciate it
um i want to give a shout out to a
handful of people
uh papa zee giant mike and the dab and
queen
grow from your heart podcast thanks for
the support bro thank you bro
richard thank you very much ez057 always
appreciated
og purple thumb farmer z learning and
burning
couldn't do this without y'all thank you
very much that is the truth thank you
guys
we do appreciate it i did mention at the
start of the show that we're going to
talk about edibles
i'm not sure if you noticed during the
shout outs uh the [ __ ] edibles are
working dude
we usually start the show by talking
about what we're smoking let's talk
about what we have eaten and what we've
consumed mike what are you going in on
yeah what did you eat this evening this
afternoon before the show
the edible i've been obsessed with
lately are these gummy candies
made right here in pueblo uh taste buds
those of you on youtube i just held it
up for the camera these ones are some
blue raspberry sativa
um just 10 milligram gummies uh
if you're a big guy like me you care
about quality
and forever in colorado that quality of
the candy you get here was shitty
for a minute yeah this was the first
company that was like we're really going
to put together
a good piece of candy and i was like
that's what i've been waiting for summer
what you got
and i've been a fan since nice and you
said those are made here in pueblo huh
yep that's awesome i did not know that
so i'm glad you told me about that that
feels good that you're supporting a
local product
i don't know where this product was
grown or made i know where i bought it
and it was delicious i am i ate a uh
maybe possibly a little bit too much
of a caramel and corn cotta bar this is
cannabis cannabis infused chocolate bar
100 milligrams of thc and zero
milligrams of cbd
uh i ate i think i've had about 20 or 40
i 20 milligrams of it earlier
as we started the show and i'm going to
eat more of it as well so i've had 20
i'm going to eat a little bit more it's
starting to work i think i'm going to
eat up to 40 because i've noticed
that lately 50 uh is right about where i
start getting a little bit
silly where you want to be if i don't
dab
50 is cool but if i eat 50 milligrams
and take a dab dude then i'm like oh
should i need a minute
like and that's fun sometimes but i got
[ __ ] to do man we got to record i got to
edit i got to do stuff so i can't i
think i'm going to go 40 and a couple of
dabs and we'll see what that does
that's why i only ate 20 for tonight's
show because i knew i was going to be
hitting my pen
and taking a couple dabs and i didn't
want to get over medicated
which i'll do that with edibles too yeah
it's not hard
not hard like yeah i'm going to crack
this open and make sure that i'm not
lying to make sure yeah
so i ate 20 and i'm going to eat 20 more
as the show goes on that's that's my
goal
yeah when back in the day when it was a
a cookie your friend made that tasted
like feet and
something from under the lawnmower it uh
it was harder to over
consume now everything's delicious yeah
these
chocolate candies are really really good
it can be dangerous
yeah i've uh i've gotten myself into a
little trouble just enjoying what i
purchased and then
you know five or six deep you're like
oops
all right man you call and scans some
[ __ ] you said edibles from back in the
day that tasted like poop remember when
they just tasted just like
green green plants you're like why does
it taste like i'm eating green plants
like people were just putting weed in
the edibles you guys don't put just weed
in your brownie mix put make some butter
and put the butter or some just drop
some shatter in the brownie mix stir
that in real good put some put a bunch
of distillate in there
oh yeah but don't just go to the cooking
mode
whatever the recipe calls for yeah add
that
not a bunch we're not we're not horses
we're not cows we don't need to graze on
a bunch of greens like that i get enough
greens in my diet let's not eat a bunch
of wheat i mean you can if you want
to but that's that's not the way i
recommend it
um so we're going to talk about edibles
i've eaten some edibles i'm going to eat
more
i think a good spot to start with
talking about edibles mike
might be the basic number one thing
dosage
no learn your dosage and maybe people
are jumping into edibles for the first
time i'm saying know your dosage like i
don't [ __ ] know my dosage
we can't even get edibles where i am so
learn your dosage you got to learn your
dosage
i used to say start off with like 10
milligrams i'm gonna say maybe start off
with five milligrams
it uh it all depends on your tolerance
level
and uh when i was working a retail
counter as a bud tender
edibles a lot of people would
um like that i hadn't smoked in 30 years
crowd and i just retired and i want to
get back into cannabis
uh edible seemed like a softer i don't
have to smoke anything i protected my
lungs
[Music]
type option to get back into cannabis or
to to
dip your toe into the water and uh
no
it's so so easy to overdo it when you're
when you're eating it and it's delicious
yeah um yeah and if you're a
non-consumer
consuming for the first time at all um
it's so so easy to consume more than
we'll be
enjoyable yes absolutely
so i think uh the the joke that mike and
i both made is you can't un-eat
that second dose when you eat eat five
or ten milligrams
and give it a solid hour before you see
what happens
i've eaten the edibles i probably 40
minutes ago and i'm just now
barely starting to feel it kick in and
i'm sure in like the next 20 minutes
it's going to get me
it's going to start moving in i'm
starting to feel warm my eyes are
getting a little heavy
my attention is moving around it's not
right here like it should be
it's an edible show we're gonna be just
fine i'm good with that i'm a [ __ ]
professional
well i'm the worst thing that's gonna
happen is i'm gonna get too high we're
gonna make a shitty podcast like i'm not
gonna have to call my mom again
you know yeah yeah but some people if
this is their first experience and they
get that oh god i'm too high it could
ruin the whole idea of using it for
medicine and we may make them gun shy
like if the first experience with
something sucks we could totally ruin it
for him forever
so yeah eat that first dose and give it
a solid hour
and then if you don't feel it wait a
little bit longer and eat another small
dose because you don't want to realize
about an hour and 20 in that
both of those doses are kicking in like
that's that's when it gets shitty
if you live in a legalization area
you should be able to buy store-bought
edibles that are
um lab tested for consistency
potency and it's easy to identify how
much
of your candy bar cookie or brownie or
candy is five milligrams 10 milligrams
20 milligrams
so i'm going to show this this candy bar
this was 100 it's divided into
obvious small pieces each of those
triangles is a little five
milligram piece and so i know just by
breaking off one of those five milligram
pieces i know exactly what i'm eating i
just popped a five milligram piece into
my mouth a moment ago
i know exactly how much medicine i'm
getting i'm not going to overdo it i'm
not going to under do it
one beautiful gummy it's got the stamp
on it to show you how much it is
yep you can't see it in my poorly lit
studio but uh
says right on the front 10 milligrams
thc
or i should say it says thc exclamation
point
like you see on the bottle here that is
printed on these i was going to pick it
up and show it to you again but it
melted on my face
every edible in colorado yeah these have
that stamped on there as well it says
thc with an exclamation point it says
coda on there so i know that every bite
of this is a thc
laden chocolate bar there's no hiding it
maybe if it melted but that's that's a
totally different story the packaging
this was a [ __ ] for me to open i'm an
adult and this was still hard for me to
open so kids getting into this would be
a challenge
i love the little disadvantage and it
makes it really easy we did was making
it hard to get into
yeah and covered in labels one of my
only
one of my only complaints about the
colorado edible industry is
i have dietary restrictions and i am
breaking
by my diet they're reflect they're my
own restrictions i place them on myself
i have to flex those i have to be
flexible with them to consume this this
doesn't fit into my
general guidelines of my dietary
restrictions i wish there were more
things available for my
uh what i'm looking for but if i want to
get good and medicated i got to eat some
chocolate or some gummies or something
and i opted for chocolate to be my
the thing dude honestly since i've been
eating in the diet that i'm on this
chocolate is [ __ ] delicious
this is special um
we used to have anything could be
infused in colorado and then
that scared the [ __ ] out of some people
so
they put some brackets around what we
can infuse and what we can't
shout out to the ganja gourmet back in
the day there's quite a few
exactly there's quite a few options
though so
if you're looking for something special
or you want to try something unique you
can take some time on on something like
weed maps and find something that you
want to try
and everything recreational in colorado
will be 100 milligrams of package 10
milligrams a piece
so if you've never consumed before it's
super easy to say oh i'm gonna take half
a piece and start with five
or if you're a regular consumer it's
easy to start with
20 30 40 milligrams yeah i'm 25 in now
start slow and build slow yeah
it's it's a lot of fun to get stoned
it's a lot of fun to eat a couple
edibles and go for a nice ride
um it's not fun to get way too high
it's uh like jeff mentioned before the
the saying is you can't
uneat drugs like once it's in the tummy
you're on the roller coaster there's no
putting your hand up there's no getting
off the roller coaster early
you're on that [ __ ] until she comes to
a stop on its own volition
yep and that might be an hour that might
be seven hours yeah that might be sweet
some tears and some diapers involved in
that ride there's some famous instances
of people coming to colorado and over
consuming and then writing about
it for major publications
and you should take the time to read
those accounts
or to go on youtube and type in
um cop calls 9-1-1 after eating pot
brownie
yeah that's a good one too um don't be
that guy
don't be that guy so i highly recommend
if you can get some store-bought edibles
i love if your friend makes edibles
that's awesome but if you're new at it
let's get something from the store
because i don't know mike may have put a
gram of some concentrate and some
edibles and stirred it up and he's like
those are there was 85 grams of
milligrams of thc in that
concentrate so then that means there's
85 in here there are six pieces do the
math
that's what you're getting i don't know
who knows if that was really what was in
that concentrate who knows if mike
stirred it all the way
who knows if i got the piece on the
corner with all of the concentrate who
knows if mike got the piece with all the
concentrate
i prefer a lab and i know not everybody
some people are in places where that's
not an option they're giving me the
finger saying i'm going to take what i
can get do that enjoy that but
if you've got the opportunity to the
world's not spoiled like us but if
you've got the option
a lot of the states have become spoiled
like us so it is kind of an option get
those
and also i don't even i just this is a
side branch it's not even on my paper
maybe you're getting if you're in
another state and you're buying edibles
that look like they're from colorado be
careful maybe that's just a hershey bar
or something that your homie made that
they got some bait all the good edibles
from the colorado packaging and
repackaged that [ __ ] and just sent it
along so be careful if your edibles come
in suspiciously familiar packaging like
if it says reefers instead of snickers
on it or
instead of reese's that's probably not a
legit store-bought edible because all
those have been stopped because of the
copyright laws
so that's a good way to tell that hey
i'm buying a weird edible right here
but i prefer a lab tested edible
something made in a colorado regulated
kitchen i'm kind of picky about not only
what i'll eat but who i will eat from
do i mean not to be
weird with it but like we're [ __ ] old
now like i
i can't accidentally get too glazed and
miss
36 hours of my life you got two kids
dude
yeah if i go awol for 36 hours i wake up
with like cops looking
for me and [ __ ] like it's no bueno for
everybody involved
and so i i used to work with the dude
who made
fire edibles and uh
i was always happy to gobble one down
but like now
i i'd make sure it was a really safe
moment to eat one of those where i could
miss 10 hours
in nba yeah um
it's and with the store-bought you can
avoid that like i know exactly what my
experience is going to be
regardless if i got the coffee and
donuts or if i got gummies or
breath strips i know that i'm 30
milligrams in now
and i know that i can handle that and i
didn't accidentally consume the bottom
brownie or the [ __ ] bottom scoop of
something with all the potency in it
yeah i know that we're good
so mine are getting me right behind the
eyes right now i'm enjoying the [ __ ] out
of it
yeah my um these bright lights dude geez
the bright lights and edibles are a fun
combination
and also if anybody's saying why aren't
you recording with a fancy camera it's
easier to zoom
i'm i'm waiting for a piece of equipment
so i can link up the sony camera so we
can zoom with that sorry i'm not in 4k
today you guys probably a relief on your
eyes do not
see me in 4k for once but on purple so
it makes up for it
um i highly prefer these store-bought
edibles that was my last note that we
went over
if you can get them if not eat what you
can dude good luck um
if you're making them make sure you stir
that [ __ ] up we don't want one brownie
that's all of the potency one brownie
that yeah get online and take some time
and try to get your dosing
where uh where you've got a concept of
what it might be
um i've hurt myself with homemade
edibles before
we all have we all have i think do you
know any of those people that say
edibles simply don't work on them
like edibles just don't work what do you
recommend for them come to colorado and
get one of those
thousand milligram bars at a retro shop
and eat that whole thing and hang out
with me and see what happens
no um well if they say it doesn't work
slow build up
um one of the things i like to do with
the new product
is uh you know i'd eat 10 and then two
hours
later i'd eat 20 and then two hours
later i need 30 2 hours later i need 40
and just let that roller coaster ride
begin
and usually 10 don't do [ __ ] but by the
time i'm eating 40 at a chunk like
game on yeah yeah and uh for the people
that say edibles don't work for me it's
usually
they bought an undetermined quality of
of pot at some point and somehow tried
to make food with it
and oh yeah okay it wasn't successful
and it and that's what their edibles
don't work on me story
and that's where it comes from and it's
like well did did you put in the oven at
375 for 40 minutes and just burn out all
the thc
or did you get a shitty eight the mids
right and then put it into a two bigger
tray and so there was only seven
milligrams per brownie
like i see that here and then i see
people that also buy
an edible and they say well i ate part
of it before i went into work and then
part of it at lunch and i gave part of
it to my friend
i'm like so nobody got high like you
just spread [ __ ] a bunch of
milligrams around so far that nothing
you ate like three before lunch and
three at work and
everybody micro dosed yeah everybody and
nobody felt a goddamn thing from it yeah
i see that as sort of a thing as well um
we get uh you can get
pills here in colorado that are just 10
milligram pills
and i used to love those throughout the
day
and more than once like did i take some
at the beginning of my lunch break or
the after my lunch at the end of my
lunch break i don't remember i'll take
two more on my way
back in and then right before third
break you're sitting there holding onto
the counter like trying to maintain eye
contact
so i did take those i did take those
other edibles oops took someone at the
start of my break in the middle of the
break and at the end of the break and
now i'm [ __ ] glazed like a ham
perfect so you were talking you said a
minute ago about putting the
uh con or the herb in the oven or
putting the brownie mix in the oven
let's talk about
um de-carbing and decarboxylation
um i'm gonna sound like joe rogan for a
minute here and you guys have
heard this rant from joe rogan something
different happens when you eat medical
cannabis or cannabis it does not become
when normal cannabis when you consume it
when you smoke it you consume delta 9
thc that gives you the buzz that you're
used to delta 9 thc
there's probably cbd and other
cannabinoids in there but then one we're
[ __ ] familiar with is the thc that's
what i'm after give me
delta 9 thc when you eat that your body
converts it into
11 hydroxy thc or hydroxy thc
which makes it more psychoactive more
bioavailable to your body
it makes it longer lasting it makes it
deeper penetrating is something that i
wrote down and we'll talk about why i
said that in a minute
but that is the scientific thing of
what's happening that's why you get a
different buzz from it
it becomes something different in your
liver your liver heats it up processes
it
it becomes this hydroxy thc which is
different than delta nine different
different compound different buzz treats
you differently that's the main thing
that's happening so now that leads me
into talking about decarbing
when you take cannabis flowers if you're
going to make edibles it needs to be
decarb to make it more bioavailable
for your body if you just took a bunch
of weed and ate it you may get a little
bit of buzz
if you took that weed and heated it to
the appropriate temperature to activate
those cannabinoids you would get a much
better buzz
sometimes that happens in the cooking or
baking process but a lot of times it
will be done
sometimes it happens in the extraction
process if you're making a concentrate
it'll kind of decarb there as well
sometimes you may need to de-carb your
product on its own if you're making a
butter or something
now you may need to de-carb that butter
so that is something you need to
research
that makes the i don't make edibles i'm
not an edible uh professional but if
you're making edibles de-carbing
decarboxylation is something i highly
recommend you do some research on
that is what makes that delta 11
available in your body even more
bioavailable
there's another thing called nano
infusion i don't understand nano
infusion completely
part of what i read some people say it's
not good to consume nano infused
products so
read about nano infusion i tried a
product it was a liquid
syrupy type product it was i don't even
like talking about it was like sauce or
syrup is what it's trying to act like
but you can just pour a little bit of
this stuff in a cup and drink it and
don't even drink it like sauce just
drink it like itself and know that
you're gonna get lit from it
it was a thousand milligrams of nano
infused drink and i drink just a little
sip of it and i could feel it hit my
body
too quickly it was like whoa that was
fast
so i don't that's scary high scary
quickly to me i could really mess myself
up with that so
if you want to get medicated super
quickly check out the nano infused
drink products they're available in
california not in colorado
that i know of uh because they're so
potent but so you got to decarb things
and then check out nano infusion that
was my quick
uh the part that i did write a couple of
detailed notes about so
mike it looks like you got something to
say bail me out well the edibles
one the the sum up version of what jeff
just said is
they edibles hit harder and last longer
than
smoking it the the other thing when
you're smoking it
you can it's called titrate you can
titrate your dose a lot
smoother and a lot more precise um
i'm trying to think of a good analogy
right here and i think it's the edibles
that are [ __ ] me up here
um but uh i just threw a piece of candy
in my mouth
for smoking's like paying for stuff with
loose change like you can be super
precise
but edibles is like paying for stuff
with gold bars
like there's going to be a lot of like
waiting around for your
your change to come back to you it's not
precise at all you got to go with a big
old chunk
like but once you dial it in i've seen
so many people
gross themselves with edibles like
um we used to get
vegetable oil that was infused by
someone else in college
and the brownies we would make just had
a reputation for like sometimes it was a
nice
mild pleasant and other times it was
like a sledgehammer of the forehead for
12 hours
and good lord like
i've seen people do it the same with the
the store-bought edibles
oh yeah yeah thinking about it you
intend to eat 30 milligrams
the next thing you know like something
funny happened in front of you on the
television or on your phone
and now you're 60 milligrams deep before
you realize what you're doing
yep especially with good candy like what
i'm munching on
the downside is that they come on super
strong and they can take you into a
different
realm i like joey diaz says you can
[ __ ] see the devil or you can see god
depends on what the [ __ ] which edibles
you ate but
that's why they're so useful that's why
they're so helpful for the medical
community or for i'm trying to get high
off if i like to get real high
i don't have to take four dabs like if i
were gonna go somewhere and didn't want
to go dab i could just take one of these
with me and just sneak it into my mouth
and we'd be cool
but it's very uh it's longer lasting and
i think it's really once you dial in
your dosage i think it's cost effective
the edibles aren't too expensive uh
compared to how much i smoke and what my
smoke products cost
compared to what the edibles cost it's
still cost effective it matters out
and i feel like it goes this may be a
weird way to put i feel like it goes
deeper
like if i've got some pain i can smoke
and if i've got like
level six back pain it'll take it to
like a three but if you got level seven
back pain and you eat edibles it'll
knock you down to a two
like the edibles are just oh yeah know
where to go they're like they're
swimming around in your body going oh it
hurts over here watch
oh it hurts over here my knees are my
knees or my back are really hurting
um i go with edibles to to attack the
pain not
smoking it's i'll sit here and dab for
all afternoon trying to get rid of knee
pain
but if i you know chew down a cbd gummy
and four or five
thc 10 milligrammers so i'm at like 50
and 50.
um within an hour and a half my knee
pain will be dialed back to a two or
three
do you feel like the cbd uh inhibits
the giggly fun time buzz from the thc
but makes it more focused on the pain
relief
all right and that's why i don't mess
with you they work really really well
together
um it does tend to dial back the stony
um one of the other phenomena i wanted
to bring up
on this episode ask you if you've
experienced it
um i've experienced it repeatedly lately
i'm pretty good at knowing where my
tolerance is
if i'm smoking flour dabs edibles
and i'll be riding like a nice pleasant
like three or four level high like out
of ten
i'm just rocking out at a three or four
maintaining
and then something environmental wise
happens
and it takes me to a [ __ ] nine just
out of nowhere and i end up
just laughing hysterically oh yeah or
i mean it's usually laughing
hysterically but or destroying a bunch
of food out of nowhere
i love when you eat edibles and then go
somewhere and you're at like the mall or
at the sneaker shop or somewhere and
you're like oh wait
oh [ __ ] there's those edibles they just
got me just now like oh we
this is gonna be i gotta get out of the
mall i gotta leave target
like i gotta where's my car and you just
ditch your just your shopping cart and
you just [ __ ]
bail i'm i'm done bye
yeah when i first got into the
this gummy brand um i met the owner
doing a political campaign thing and
then like two months later the holidays
came around
and i needed something that was going to
be even more discreet than a vapor pen
and was like there's nothing more
discreet than gummies
yeah um
and just fantastic but i found myself
slightly over medicated it like now go
get seconds at thanksgiving
so it was kind of a perfect fortuitous
little moment for it
did you still go get seconds bro oh for
sure of course you did for sure
that's the best thing when you're over
medicated is food
the last time i had a black market
edible
i thought i was fine and i was scrolling
through one of those
like here's 12 funny memes about
whatever the [ __ ]
it wasn't even anything particular and
it wouldn't have hit me like this at any
other moment but with my medicated level
and the the situation i was in
i about died in a parking lot behind a
place
like everybody else was in the next room
eating chicken
i'm in the back just curled up on the
floor
tik tok isn't that funny until you meet
up it wasn't even tick tock it was just
uh it was just a regular ass
picture and word meme list and it was
hitting me like
tyson that's great that is great
edibles are wonderful for that man if
you want to make an a
take an afternoon from ordinary to
extraordinary i recommend some [ __ ]
edibles
yeah i had to take a break because i
worked with a group of savages and we
were all just eating way too many
edibles
people that listened to the podcast back
in the day thousands of milligrams do
not belong on a single piece of bacon
that's all i'm gonna say
yeah we were i'm not a bacon consumer
but there were there were a thousand
milligram edibles eaten during work
shifts and work did get done not not all
of it
but the work was happening one of your
favorite stories
involves somebody getting too glazed to
sing
oh yeah i haven't seen i haven't seen a
performer do it
but i've seen a lot of other people who
had [ __ ] to do that was like
nope they had one too many brownies and
they're just gonna stay on the couch
till wednesday
uh we actually were at a dab event and
there was a rapper who raps about dabs
and he took a dab on stage and had to
have the crowd come up and karaoke his
songs for him because
he was dabbed the [ __ ] out and couldn't
sing anymore it was pretty funny
shout out to hash it'll [ __ ] up your day
yes
or fix it both i'm not sure both
all right mike i feel like i've covered
all of my bullet points
uh do you have any notes written down
that you'd like to cover or is it time
to turn it into a ramble fest here
we talked about going easy yes i brought
up that it seems like a kinder gentler
reintroduction or introduction to
cannabis
but because of your inability to slowly
dose yourself it tends not to be that
gentle
um
yeah those are the main points [ __ ] all
right all right i think we got all the
business part covered up
on the show that was a fun show my good
edible lesson
i hope people learned something uh i got
edibled out so i'm not sure how much we
taught
i i honestly i was just sitting here
thinking how long have we been going and
that's when i realized how hard the
edibles have hit me and i
honestly can't tell you how long we've
been talking i know that it's perfect
i know what time it is i can still read
the clock
but i don't remember what time we go i
do so it's perfect i'm not going to tell
you because i like y'all learn some [ __ ]
i like the level of confusion in your
eye you should definitely
reach out and interact with us on social
media if you've got edible questions
there you go that's a great thing for a
great segue for us
if you'd like to reach out to us if
you've got corrections questions
comments updates or concerns
uh my email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com you can reach mike
at nemo punk 15 on twitter is probably
the best way
yeah i just drank a bunch of water and
it's trying to make me burp while i'm
speaking excuse me for that um
yeah also if you feel like the episode
was educational informative or
entertaining we would appreciate it if
you support us on patreon you can find
me at patreon.com forward slash grow
from your heart
mike's patreon is very similar it's
patreon.com forward slash
white mike how could you forget that
support white mike i'm not done with the
show but i thought it'd be a good time
to
shout out all that good good time to
drop the contact info case y'all want to
reach out and laugh at us for being too
glazed to remember what our last couple
bullet points on the edible show
that's why i did the patreon and the
email addresses now just in case
i've got notes but they've gone to [ __ ]
they're all half crossed out
half out of order now so i haven't been
doing paper notes
i've gone uh i've gone mostly digital on
the new podcast format yeah it's
uh but i've got since i'm doing the zoom
i've got you are on my note screen right
now
so i'm trying to go paperless yeah i'd
be a little bit more that's one or two
sheets of paper every episode that i'm
not wasting
it's gonna be more cost effective more
environmentally friendly and
why am i doing it on paper like a
caveman anyway i got digital stuff
2020 baby yeah dude we upgraded all the
toys let's go digital
the new studio sounds really good like
that microphone sounds crispy with my
headphones today thank you
uh you got you sound pretty great too
you did a [ __ ] good job staying on
the mic get you turned up pretty hot
over here so
hopefully the listeners can hear me too
oh yeah
i sounded great to us the shows where
they said they couldn't hear me
uh this new device shout out to the pod
track
p4 makes us both sound pretty good shout
out to the new piece of tech making me
sound
crispy all right 40 milligrams of
edibles i think i feel about 20 or 30 of
them right now moving through my body my
palms are getting a little bit sweaty my
eyes are a little bit heavy i like it
i'm going to try to hang on and just
keep podcasting for a few so that we can
see what happens to us over the
course of this podcast here over the
next few minutes you want to grab an
email you want to do some rambles
uh i didn't recipe anything like that i
did not prepare
anything let's talk about here's some
fun [ __ ] we could talk about nothing
that we can't [ __ ] this up we can't miss
any notes we can't do anything wrong
uh we can give a huge shout out to our
friend karen rest in peace karen i love
you i miss you hope you're well
shout out to tom also let's talk about
when
we used to manage a dispensary in pueblo
colorado mike and i had
some other friends it wasn't just there
was a group of us that
uh managed and ran i was the [ __ ]
general manager i guess would have been
if there was a real title in that place
i was the [ __ ] the guy that did jose
tom
yeah yeah tom was the the owner guy i
was the guy right under tom i
then mike was right next to me and then
there was a couple other people working
with us
chrysanne was like everybody's [ __ ]
like second right-hand man
she was amazing tree was amazing uh but
uh tom was the owner and karen was tom's
wife she unfortunately passed away we
miss you karen i always got a [ __ ]
spot in my heart for karen nothing but
love for that lady she was one of the
sweetest people i've ever
ever interacted with like genuinely
sweet um
carrying sweet she also made a wicked
edible
she made she made baked goods she made
fudge candies anything
not just medicated but she could make
anything she cooked and she was
she's just a sweetly that loved to
nourish people she made amazing
medicated edibles ah fudge i've said
that fudge two or three times now
that the fudge was so good the banana
bread the banana bread the
the christmas cookies with the sprinkles
on them the uh
not the banana bread the walnut bread
was it there's another kind of nut bread
that she made that was delicious
they would serve us full meals and
everything in the meal was medicated
she would make so we had a dispensary
and back in the day you could first time
i ever saw medicated barbecue sauce
yeah yeah back then you could make
edibles in your private kitchen at home
and take them and sell them in your
dispensary that's how long ago this was
this was the wild wild west
absolutely no rule days yeah yeah this
was just
however we were inventing the rules as
we went they were making the rules
around us is what they were doing
so karen would make trays of fudge and
banana bread and cookies and medicated
cupcakes with medicated frosting with
medicated sprinkles and medicated syrup
and she would bring all these edibles to
the office where we work
and she would have a pile of here's a
cupcake for mike and a cupcake for jeff
and medicated fudge for mike and fudge
for jeff and
one of everything for everybody that
works there for everybody
and she would encourage you to try all
of them while you're at work today
so i would start off my work shift with
a medicated cupcake
like i mentioned before the cupcake is
medicated the frosting is medicated
she put medication in the [ __ ]
sprinkles then put medicated syrup over
it
and then served me a drink with [ __ ]
ganja in that as well so i'm washing
down my medicated
[ __ ] cupcake with a medicated
chocolate soy milk or some [ __ ] back in
the day
we would get lit by lunch so roasted
and she would come check on us and be
like so what did you what did you eat
i'm like i ate the cupcake and i'm lit
and she's like cool now go eat the fudge
and the two cookies
and the glazed ham and the [ __ ] other
nine items i gave you
and let us know what you think about
that and i'd be like i can't handle it
dude
and they would encourage it and not even
mind that sometimes i'd
be working in the middle of a shift and
just put my hands on my face and be like
i need a minute i'm too high to even i
shouldn't even be [ __ ] standing in
public right now and you've got me
serving customers like give me just a
minute to get my life together
they were cool with it like ha ha he ate
too many of the cookies
like it was those were good old times
shout out to karen and tom i missed that
place
that's where mike and i met each other i
distinctly remember standing behind that
counter
holding on to the underside of the
counter putting positive pressure
with my arms pushing my feet down on the
ground a little bit harder than gravity
was pushing me normally
just to make sure i was all good for a
minute
it just there were definitely some fun
times in that i fell down the stairs at
that dispensary
uh that had lots
it had a couple of nights it had uh 180
degree turn so you go down one and then
you turn 180 and go down another turn
180 and go down another instead of just
one long [ __ ] death fall you got a
few death falls
i fell down one and made the turn and
fell down another flight too
like i actually made the [ __ ] turn
while i was falling but i was so high on
edibles
that i was like that drunk driver that
gets in a car wreck and all the sober
people die but the drunk driver is so
gumbied that he just [ __ ] rubbers
around in the car and nothing happens
that was me as i fell down the stairs i
just gumby legs
jello rolled down that [ __ ] thing
yeah i had a little job blessing and a
little rubber roll going on
no pain it was [ __ ] hilarious
everybody laughed at me i laughed at me
uh that was a good time fell down the
stairs high as [ __ ]
shout out to metamar ministries in
pueblo colorado no longer exists there's
many
so many firsts in that place but the
edibles
oh good lord yeah i bet ah so good
that's the
that was the first time i learned the
edibles could really be like amazingly
delicious
um the ones i was making in college
every time the
especially when we're using the real
potent oil it's just that heavy green
chlorophyll flavor he can't escape
and uh the stuff karen was making was
legitimately delicious
like it it would have sold as a regular
food item anywhere comfortably
oh yeah but it would lay you the [ __ ]
out
and then people knew that if they
watched those cookies on the shelf if
those cookies didn't sell by friday that
when you come in
on friday that old lady comes in
saturday so jeff will give you cookies
friday evening if you buy a lot of stuff
every friday like that after work rush
if there were 10 or 12 cookies left if
you bought an ounce here's a cookie bro
or if you were cool like if you're just
there's some people that came in were
just [ __ ] cool some people were dicks
uh working at that dispensary randomly
stacks of pizzas would show up
just pizza hut would be like hey this
guy named jake sent you
12 pizzas like [ __ ] yeah jake's awesome
dude i know jake and his girlfriend they
come in here all the time
i remember them the next time you see
jake guess what he gets two [ __ ]
medicated cookies because he just sent
me pizzas last time
we used to get all kinds of that was
there were maybe
30 dispensaries in the country then
yeah there were only four or
six in the state of colorado at the time
um then the bronze before
anything existed yeah the broadstar damn
explosion happened on broadway
in denver they called it little
broadster dam because suddenly there
were dispensaries on every other block
and that's when we hired you to come
work with our dispensaries so that i
could get some time off we hired a
couple other people i was working
seven days a week from open to close as
the only bud tender and the only guy
there basically
uh so we had a couple other people hired
on and then the owner
was giving me funding on the weekends to
go
scout out other dispensaries like go to
every shop that you can within this many
miles we'd drive up to denver and
[ __ ]
go hit 10 or 12 dispatch there weren't
even 10 or 12. [ __ ] up in denver yep
yep yep we'd go hit four or five because
that's all there were at the time go hit
four or five dispensaries buy a couple
of products from
each one and then bring it down and show
it to the owner of the dispensary and
talk about how we can get better
products and how we can set up like
those dispensaries
so i've been doing recon work on that
[ __ ] since 2008-2007
uh yeah we had a good time doing all
that going and checking out other
dispensaries
buying crazy good product and some
terrible product back in the day
going to buy edibles and rewatable
distance from my house so like
literally it was get up tie your shoes
scroll up the block
open the world's first weed store like
yeah [ __ ] fantasyland it seems like a
dream at this point
but before there were rules there's a
lot of [ __ ] funny
a lot of funny that staircase i don't
know how none of us died
eating three or four pieces of banana
bread in the shift and then having to
run up to the fourth floor or grab more
or something for
yeah no it should have killed one of us
yes
or the heat up on that fourth floor
yeah did you ever go in the basement of
that building
nope yeah there's no stairs so you've
got you've got one two four i never went
to
never never went to b yeah it's
interesting down there
um so that was a random side rant there
nobody's ever been in that build a lot
of maybe some people have been in that
building that are listening not too many
though
uh the first dispensary in pueblo
colorado there was one in the county
uh outside of our city limits that was
open at the same time but
i think we were getting the majority of
the business and then a couple others
opened
um i'm not going to say their names with
uh i think i only got the pleasure
working there for like
six weeks or so and
literally when i started there was one
and it was metamar and there was another
one
talking about opening their doors in the
county and it's the one you're thinking
of
yeah and it's five or six weeks later
when the city shut us down
there were like eight yeah our one
friend opened two shops up pretty
quickly
yeah and within the year there were
20 yeah and then we were driving that's
one
of the first i want to say the first
regulation bill happened in 2010
and that's when we went from a thousand
shops to 500
essentially overnight the rules took a
little while to kick in i
think it was a six-month period where
like they rolled out
the first five big rules yeah and those
rules
so many people three months later but
yeah it was
one after the next doctor reefer
disappeared
the spinning sign people's all those
[ __ ] stores disappeared
um let's elaborate on that a little bit
everyone's going what happened
uh so back in the day we called it the
wild wild west
you could grow you could get herb from
basically anywhere it was medical
cannabis so everybody was growing at
home
and if you got a medical marijuana card
you could increase your plant count
dramatically back then
so you could grow pretty decent
quantities of product
and i could backpack up four a quarter
pounds of herb
and stop at four different dispensaries
and sell four quarter pounds
for cash they would hand me just cash
somewhere between seven hundred and a
thousand dollars cash for a quarter
pound of good weed and i would leave
get in the car drive to the next spot
and do it until i was out of herb
every harvest just go dump them off at
the dispensaries then there's
a million jeff's running around the
state to the
the handful of dispensaries that we had
and eventually it was like a thousand
um every shop had different herb
nothing was regulated there were no
rules yet
the state was pretending like
the industry didn't exist and so
the industry kept creating their own
rules
in hopes that when the state finally did
look upon us they weren't as
horrified as they otherwise might be
yeah yeah
that's a good way to put it led to a lot
of silliness
at the time but um
i mean i it was just
the perfect storm of like
balls or hutzpah and
i'm sick of this i'm not i'm just gonna
turn a blind eye from the cops
because if you talk to law enforcement
which i ended up doing a lot when i was
doing city council stuff
by the time we had a medical marijuana
registry
in cards they were like [ __ ] it i'ma
look for cocaine
like i'm just done it's i'm tired of
them saying they've got a card and then
i've gotta [ __ ] look at the card and
then they've
got a plant count and then they can have
so many [ __ ] it
like i just you say weed i say
i'm here for the guns or the heroine and
you know what i mean
it just exploded overnight we went from
first there was one store south of
colorado springs that was
the dispensary and they were on the news
every [ __ ] night for like four months
and every night it was the same report
where the guy was like yeah medical
marijuana is a thing
you should be able to get it without
being a good gardener
that's what i'm here for here's the
weird [ __ ] thing we've come up with
to pretend this is legal
and it sort of falls under the framework
of colorado's medical marijuana law
which was purposefully written to be a
little bit confusing
yep and the news people were just aghast
you should go up and pull the footage if
you're interested you'll laugh your ass
off if you're not familiar with
um it you remember the name of that i
know it's michael lee was the owner of
the place but do you remember the name
of that dispensary
uh i can see the b-roll footage a car's
getting off the highway and pulling up
in front of the building but i've
shopped there
um for a while they were tracking plants
they were to sign like if you signed up
there with their
uh with them for them to grow your
medical plans
they would have six plants with your
name tag on them
and they would try to keep track that
bud all the way to a storage bin
with your name on the front and only you
could come in and buy from that bin
it was so complicated um but it was
one of those you know if the state ever
is like no you're really
a just a big drug dealer you could say
like no
patients and medical programs the
caregiver program that's what we operate
intentions at metamar we tried to call
it a caregiver program because like you
said
uh we had i was a grower i was a
caregiver there i had like was a
patient's assigned to me
yeah yeah and that's that means so i
could do store runs
i'm a caregiver mike's a patient he
comes in he's like i can't grow weed but
you can so i will assign you my plant
count now i get mike's
medical marijuana card he assigns me as
the caregiver on the card i get to grow
his six plants
now every time he comes to my dispensary
since i'm growing his six plants
he gets medicine every time he comes
because back in the day it was hard to
keep up with medicine
also if you sign us up as your caregiver
we'll give you bonuses and extras and
gifts which now is kind of frowned upon
in the industry but
uh they've regulated that quite a bit
but yeah so that's how that used to work
back in the day and then we just grow a
[ __ ] ton of weed and
it wouldn't be a lot then they came up
with vertical integration was one of the
things that crushed a lot of the
businesses
you had to back in the day you could
just buy it and get it from wherever
now it had to come 70 of your product
had to be produced by you
in a cultivation facility that you were
involved with so you could only buy 30
outside product that messed up a lot of
things
people that were basement buccaneers
like me had to quit doing our thing
the state took a spent a lot of years
pretending like
the medical marijuana industry didn't
exist
and waiting for the feds to stay step in
and say it couldn't exist
and when that didn't happen
they sort of went around the state and
created a list of the things that most
offended them and got together and sort
of compared lists
and the stuff that went to the top of
that list they just obliterated
um signs spinning yes this
is specifically explicitly
prohibited um by anyone
in the the dispensary or cannabis
industry if
you put a sign spinner in front of your
place like little caesars does that
[ __ ] i think they should allow those
because those are the best signs of like
low quality weed if you're spinning a
[ __ ] sign for a five dollar gram that
tells me don't [ __ ] shop there
that's straight up what that means to me
um
no advertising no windows to the sales
floor
for a while they wanted to pass a rule
that the dispensary had to be
negatively air pressured so that when
the doors
opened uh no stinky pot air would escape
on towards the sidewalk it would be
sucked into the building
through some sort of high-end filtration
system
and it's funny because they didn't
understand that carbon filters are a
thing and so they didn't just say carbon
filters um
they were talking about it like it's a
[ __ ] bio weapons
yeah oh because they think carbon
filters make co2 when they look at them
it uh but that first
that first i really think it was 2010.
um colorado legitimately went from a
thousand retail locations to 500
um within a couple of months well then
after the vertical integration i would
only interrupt you i apologize keep
going well though vertical integration
was a big piece of that the
uh the 70 30 rule is only now finally
fully being dissolved
and on the one hand
it's an incredibly profitable business
model if you can get it right
but on the other hand it's a [ __ ]
nightmare from
start to finish yeah that's like saying
that 7-eleven can only sell 7-eleven
products but now they don't have
doritos and [ __ ] coke in there and
that's the you need doritos and coke in
your 7-eleven
jacket store has to be good at raising
cows like it just gets too [ __ ]
complicated yeah
yep exactly but then i think
the next thing that really [ __ ]
everything up and made a lot of the
mom and pop the the bros style shops and
i loved them those shops it was like you
and me working there like walking like
what's up
bro i got this [ __ ] kush you're gonna
love it bro you got dreads and [ __ ] i'll
give it to you for cheaper because
you're cool bro here you go
like i missed those shops those were so
fun now it's like welcome to the
dispensary it's all plasticky i went to
one place and they made me take the
[ __ ] tour
i was like no i want i want the the
concentrates i could see them on that
shelf like well over here we do this
follow me for the rest of the tour i was
like you're wasting my [ __ ] time i
don't care about your tour
but the next thing that i think ruined
us was the uh
the cameras and everything it's a good
idea but
nobody could afford it like you have to
upgrade your security system in six
months to have
a camera on every square foot of your
cultivation retail yeah so if i go here
you have to be able to see me at two
angles if i go here two angles i know
everywhere i dispensary owner that at
that point they shut their
their marijuana store down and opened up
a security business
probably the smartest they literally
shift gear shifted gears to
well this is dumb and way too expensive
i can't afford it but
like i can be the sales manager who
sells the other 12 business owners i
know the cameras they need
yeah that's probably the smartest move
he could have made shout out to that guy
um down here
they immediately added the first one of
the first things they did they
added regulations saying you had to
improve the property
above and beyond building code and you
had to beautify the parking lot yeah
out of the sidewalk all the way to the
street and it's all of a sudden
instead of just being able to find a a
retail location
make a deal with the landlord and say
okay now i've got a 3 000
a month rent you know put together
storefront
buy a big gun safe you know bolt at the
floor in the back
and you know buy a couple pounds of weed
from a friend of yours who grows
and open a business all of a sudden you
can't do that anymore now you need four
hundred thousand dollars to improve the
the parking lot you need another two
hundred thousand dollars to put in the
security system
and the new wall they want between the
safe and the what the [ __ ]
and then licensing the licensing became
super ridiculously expensive for a
little while so all those costs pushed
out
the way i put it is all the people that
had seoul got pushed out by all the
people with money
and you could watch there were
dispensaries in denver i would go to we
would stand in [ __ ]
line to get product we knew that every
the second friday of every month this
one strain came out you could buy seven
grams
i would take the vortex yeah yeah then
there was another spot yeah
yeah we would line up for that and then
when all these new rules happened all
those places fell off and we watched the
quality
decline the availability is through the
roof there was never more herb
but i didn't [ __ ] want any of it it
was it just turned all the [ __ ] really
quickly with all those rules
so a couple of places they i mean they
specifically
pushed pushed out anybody without large
capital behind them they had
requirements like you had to have 400
thousand dollars in an escrow account
yeah
um pueblo our city of pueblo was going
to pass that rule and so i pointed out
that we weren't allowed access to banks
and so that's you were just insisting we
all had a duffel bag with 400
they wanted to do 200 000 down here um a
duffel bag with 200 000 in it that we
just like i guess showed the inspector
when they came by to check and what's
the purpose of that money
like what's what is that sitting there
for their original intent
was if we got sued for being a weed
weed business yeah a drug
what's the [ __ ] phrase if somebody
got sick from something they got from
you you'd have to have some sort of oh
no there's an official legal term for
running
a property where people consume drugs
and i'm spacing the name
drug den um essentially yeah it's a drug
den law
um but it was essentially insurance an
insurance
fund in case you got sued because i
don't know somebody bought
something from your store and then
plowed into somebody on the way home
it was just nonsense
and one of my favorite people down here
in city government
fought really hard every time somebody
brought up an insane rule like that she
would
like do we have this rule for florists
or or the oil change place or the
shooting range then why do we want to do
it for pot
and if the only answer she was given was
because it's pot
she would say well then [ __ ] off yeah
that's right that's the way to do it
i don't think it should be treated like
if you don't treat it like a
ridiculous drug that's super [ __ ]
druggy then it's not a drug that's super
druggy if we treat it like
like alcohol and cigarettes are widely
accepted if nowadays i kind of think
it's cool that if you see somebody
walking around with a cigarette people
look at them like they're a [ __ ]
because they're slowly killing
themselves and i love it that we look at
them condescendingly
but if they want to enjoy a cigarette or
a beer do your thing
have a good time we don't treat it like
it's the devil and it's some [ __ ]
crazy drug
i think if cannabis was treated like
that on all levels like politically
uh physically uh what's what i'm looking
for financially there's another
economically that's the word
economically yeah all of those things if
we just treated it just like
just like this bottle of water dude i
want one i could buy one
since we don't treat it if i made water
illegal
now this that people might shoot me for
it people might steal it from me but
since there's so many of them
here not at everywhere so if i went
somewhere where there aren't a lot of
these
drop me off in the desert in the middle
of some [ __ ] third world country
where they don't have this
it's a totally different story they're
gonna shoot me for they're gonna kill me
they're gonna dismember me and take it
from me
because there isn't any there because
yeah so you get the point dude when that
shit's legal
if it's just like bananas nobody gives a
[ __ ] about bananas
because they can get them they're there
we don't treat them like they're weird
it's there's a million million reasons
why cannabis should be legal
it's it's insane the more you look at it
the more insane it seems that it's
illegal
in uh we're getting there though bro
we're getting there so many states are
on board
so many countries are on board i have
more i feel bad because i didn't prep
and check
like five more with the most recent way
off on a side tangent here this has
nothing to do with edibles anymore other
than the fact that i'm high as [ __ ] off
some edibles so
um that's what the people want uh
they like it when we ramble
2024 they like it when we ramble
well like we're getting there i think
there's only six or eight states left
that don't have some sort of
quality cannabis access law that's
awesome they're a medical program that
basically anyone can join if they want
or
something i can't wait till i can just
drive from
colorado out to california pick up a
couple friends and then drive out to new
york and we all have a fat bag of herb
or our dabs
all of it with us and nobody worries
about anything i can travel some again
man for a while it was like all right so
weeds legal in colorado and washington
state
and i don't want to go to seattle so i
can't travel
but now there's plenty of places with
legal herb
our uh medical marijuana cards are good
in new mexico now so
new mexico is a reciprocal state if you
want to go down and check out the other
whatever
ends we could travel and enjoy i was
gonna say places i might just be happy
enough just to be able to go places i
don't even care if we can smoke weed
places now
my introverted ass is gonna be excited
to have plans when this [ __ ] is over
yeah dude all of the events that we
should normally be attending
these would be the time this would be
the couple of months where i would be
preparing for the next two or three
large events that come
and they're not coming and i feel really
weird for that i'd be getting
we should be worn out from whatever dumb
halloween event we just did
right yep yep i didn't get to wear my
chewbacca costume this year
yeah it's uh we're polishing up on
thanksgiving we just cancel all that
so i uh it's one of the reasons i was so
excited i was like oh you're doing an
edible show [ __ ] i want in
i won't make time for this [ __ ] yeah um
it's just let's get some more content
out there because i know a lot of people
are in the same boat i am where it was
i just had to [ __ ] cancel
thanksgiving i don't want to think about
that [ __ ]
let's see our family haven't done us did
jeff get [ __ ] let's get those two
glazed [ __ ] into a telling
cast our family had to cancel
thanksgiving talk we just had that a
couple of days ago we all called and
like hey uh
i don't think we're going and like no we
expected that and i was like oh really
and they're like yeah we bought
containers and i was like oh [ __ ]
so everybody gets to go meals i'm gonna
send
uh one person's gonna go around and pick
them up and take them to everybody
so it works out pretty well for our
family
my wife likes to host um she loves to
have people over she loves to put plates
of food in front of people she loves
it's like one of her core personality
traits
in the last house we lived in before
this was a great home
but it was not a home where you could
host people it was just not
designed there wasn't a dining room
space we didn't have a table space
and especially when we had uh
a four-year-old and a one-year-old
there's just no [ __ ] room
like unless we want to sit on the floor
all crisscross
style with our plates in our laps we
can't have more than four people over at
once
and so when we found this place that was
like her main criteria for house
shopping was nice
what's thanksgiving gonna be like and
for this year to be like no we're gonna
cancel [ __ ] all summer
she's been staring it down just like
nope it'll be over by thanksgiving
i'm having thanksgiving i don't care
what happens we're doing thanksgiving
and when she came to me on her own and
was like we should cancel
i was super proud of her yeah but also
like super heartbroken for it too
just get a bunch of cardboard cutouts
bro like all the sports are doing and
also i think she's got a local family
scheduled to come by and get a plate
cool she's just gonna have go plates
ready at the end of the driveway
that's cool that's people that still
feels good
serving people i get turkey sandwiches
so i'm happy as [ __ ]
yeah happy holidays should not be
ripping this
pen but it's delicious
these these are dangerous people i
really want to eat
more of that edibles it was delicious
but you can see how heavy my eyes have
gotten through this episode
yep this has been fun i got the bright
lights but i didn't have to talk into
the camera i like talking to you i love
the new camera but talking to it feels
i'm just talking to the camera so it
feels really weird it was fun to have
somebody
uh to ramble back at me in this episode
yeah i uh i i figured out how i like to
have the camera sick
so i can pay attention to you and follow
the show rather than
way over analyzing whatever i'm
broadcasting to the world
yeah i try not to even look at myself
that i i'm distracting and trying to
check on my eyes occasionally because i
feel they're heavy uh but yeah i mainly
try to just look at you over here
i can only imagine what my [ __ ] eyes
look like this episode i am glazed as
[ __ ] from those gummies
you got the glasses stuff behind i don't
even have a hat on today i got the
dreads out of the way
todd's eyes just doing it all right bro
i feel like we're getting off course
here in super rambly so
um unless you've got any more super wise
words of wisdom let's wrap it up and let
these fine people get back to their days
get back to their lives get back to
whatever else they were doing we'll get
out of their ears for a moment
uh you got anything left to say for
these kind folks that are listening
and watching thank you so much for
watching and listening hit us up on
social media ask us questions
and one more time how do they do that
mike how do they find you on the social
media
you can find me at twitter at
nemopunk15 you can find me on facebook
at pueblo for
sensible cannabis laws i'm shadow bands
so you got to search that one a little
bit harder than you might otherwise have
to
because facebook sensors cannabis
related content
everyone from the podcast i never give
out my
instagram but they always find me there
it's at nemopunk15 on instagram too
i've tagged you in a couple things
they're finding you now and you can hit
me up on uh
patreon it's patreon slash white mike
i was gonna prompt that one for you good
job i think that's all of them
i think you got them all you can find uh
the grow from your heart podcast on
instagram i'm trying to post more there
i don't post enough
uh check out irie underscore genetics on
instagram actually check out my website
iriegenetics.com
everything you need is there the youtube
channels there all of the social media
stuff is there
the web store to buy shirts and gear is
there all of the vendors for irie
genetics are there
mention the store the store is dope yes
by the time this episode comes out there
will be
more of the original irie genetics og
logo shirts up there
so grab those they're like six designs
of t-shirts up there by the time you
look this would be awesome
um where else was i headed oh the
edibles are working if you wondered
um i think i may go for 10 more
milligrams but i'm going to need a snack
and then we'll take some dabs and see
how the night wraps up
um social media the website that's what
i was going to say find us on the
website iregenetics.com
also uh let me know what you think of
the website it's still evolving make
sure to check back
often on patreon.com forward slash grow
from your heart if you've got questions
corrections comments or concerns
uh the email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com i think i said
everything correctly
i think i got it all covered mike thank
you again for hanging out bro
oh yeah man thanks for having me yeah
dude we'll get you back on more episodes
um oh it's it's all me my schedule is
insane right now
um covered with two kids in the house
we're going back into
restrictions so yes we are
my day starts at seven a.m it ends at 10
p.m
and if there's energy left for anything
it's
pretty mind-numbing way past 10 now so
thank you brother
all right guys we're going to wrap up
this [ __ ] crash bro that's that's
that's when i'm at work
i don't have the energy of those boys i
wish i had the energy of one of those
two boys
i don't that's why i'm not on the
podcast as much as i want to be that's
what i'm saying
all right we'll get you back mike let me
know whenever you're free send a text
say hey 30 minutes i'm on the show and
i'll make sure to get cleaned up and get
on here for you
all right ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls pimps and hoes friends and foes
smokers grovers clone cutters paul and
chuckers
uh karen's and becky's uh chads and
brads
who else do i got for you i don't know
who else to mention everybody out there
listening in podcast world i want to
thank you again for listening to another
episode of the grow from your heart
podcast we look forward to your feedback
let us know
what you thought of this edible episode
the high rambles we gave you
we do appreciate the feedback um i think
that's all we've got for you i covered
all of my notes thanks again to mike
thanks to you for listening
check us out on the youtube channel and
let's give a giant shout out to our
friend kurt zee
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
you