[Music]
welcome back podcast world
i'm your host my friends call me rasta
jeff and it is time for episode 589
of the grow from your heart podcast you
know i like to start the show off by
talking about what i'm smoking
today i've been taking dabs of cake face
batter from binsk
in my opinion this tastes like diesel
fuel and cake batter
maybe if you went and got some diesel
fuel in the truck drove home whipped up
a little cake batter
and then smelled your fingers it would
taste like a sweet diesel-fuelly cake
batter and i find it
delightful on the back of the package it
says it contains
71.82 percent thc and non-detectable
amounts of cbd
just the way i like to concentrate so
big shout out to our friends
at binsk for the delicious cake face
live batter all right in this episode
i'm going to talk about a power outage i
experienced
we're going to talk a little bit about
curing our medicine before we get there
let's do a few shout outs to a few folks
on patreon
let's start off with the big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to my friend north north terps
let's follow that up with a big thank
you shout out to our buddy keith k
i want to send a big girl from your
heart podcast thank you shout out to my
buddy gramps memo
i've always got a big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out for
paparoni
i want to send a special thank you shout
out to our friend groman stan
i've always got a big high five and a
fist bumps for our buddy ez057
let's follow that up with the big grow
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out to our buddy blackhawks fan
i want to send a big thank you shout out
to kojaks i want to send a special thank
you to 716 vibes
and last but certainly not least let's
send a big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out
to my friend kenna reaper413
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who supports the show on
patreon
if you're not already supporting the
show and you'd like to learn how to do
so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need will be
right there on the screen and of course
i did include a link
in the show notes and the video
description to make it nice and easy
for all of my friends all right thank
you guys for all the patreon support
it does mean a lot to me also thank you
for all of the feedback i got on the
last podcast episode
i did an episode thanking you guys for
all the love and support just like a
good audience just like a bunch of good
friends
you guys came back and sent me a bunch
of love a bunch of thanks a bunch of
words of encouragement
so thank you that stuff meant a lot to
me thank you for all the feedback
from the last episode also um thank you
for all of the
uh feedback on the errors and mistakes i
have made in the past couple of episodes
i'm gonna man up to it right here uh i
have made so many
typos and small errors in the podcast in
the past few episodes uh not a lot of
big mistakes but a couple of
just numbers uh one time it was 87 and i
said 83 or something like that
um i've done a few typos if you're
watching the videos
i spell patreon wrong all the [ __ ]
time just small details like that
i guess i need to stop taking so many
dabs after i finish the show and then go
to edit
uh maybe one last dab between finishing
and editing the show so i can get my
[ __ ] together
i do apologize for all of the typos the
miss speaking
but i didn't [ __ ] up the audio in the
video the video looks good and it sounds
real good and that's what i've been
focused on
so i will get my [ __ ] together i will
get my brains back in my head and we
will say the correct numbers
uh i'll say the correct things i know
that you guys are relying on me
to guide you in a certain way and i
don't want to say the wrong thing and
mess up your garden
so if i [ __ ] you up in any sort of way
i apologize i'm going to man up to it
right here
i'm human um i woke up this morning and
i had to pee
sometimes i sneeze sometimes i stutter i
say a lot of silly embarrassing [ __ ] i'm
a human
i'm going to make mistakes i apologize
for the mistakes i have made and please
forgive me for the mistakes that i will
make in the future
cause i promise you i'm gonna [ __ ] up
again i'm not done [ __ ] up
um i'm not gonna try but i promise you
i'm gonna keep [ __ ] up that's how i
get better so you get better
with support from our friends friendly
encouragement friendly pointing out that
we [ __ ] up we will get better through
it together
so don't be shy if you see me make any
mistakes if i say some weird [ __ ] if
there are typos
typos in the podcast episodes that's
pretty much too late but if you want to
let me know that i've made a typo some
sort of error
i encourage it the email address is grow
from your heart at hotmail.com
if that's too much for you to remember i
invite you to go check out my website on
the website iriegenetics.com
there is a contact me button all you
have to do is contact that click on that
part
you could type in your questions your
concerns your comments you can contact
me right there through the website
also sign up for the mailing list uh
that's a whole other subject let me keep
myself
on track here again i apologize for the
typos
and thank you for the friendly feedback
i'm gonna get my [ __ ] together and not
do that again
uh where are we headed with this i was
talking about the website i have added
new
t-shirts to the website that's right by
the time you hear this episode
there will be brand new irie genetics
logo t-shirts replenished on the website
i don't know why i said brand new it's
the old logo that is replenished the
shirts are brand new the logo itself is
not brand new
that original colorado flag logo it is
back go to iriegenetics.com
click on the store i will take you right
there you can check out the irie
genetics logo t-shirts
i've got orange gasm shirts there are
lemon jeffree t-shirts up there they're
golden goat shirts
and now there are arise t-shirts and
hoodies in two different colors
there's an irie genetics logo t-shirt
and last but certainly not least i have
just added by the time this show ends
there will be
grow from your heart podcast t-shirts on
the website that's right
iriegenetics.com is your place for all
things rasta jeff
grow from your heart podcast all things
ire genetics related
check out the website there's a
newsletter on there a newsletter spot on
there
if you go in and subscribe to the
newsletter every time i do a new strain
drop every time i put out a deal on etsy
or on the web store or at one of the
vendors or if i add a new vendor
you will be notified through the
mailchimp web notification
i'll send you an email you'll stay
updated with all things iregenetics that
way
i encourage you join the mailing list
where are we going from there
oh for the shirts i want to send a big
shout out to my buddy handmade
big shout out to my buddy adam at
handmade apparel uh they're the ones
that printed the ivory logo shirts and
the gfyhd shirts
and they look [ __ ] stellar the shirts
are so bright the colors are so bold
the logos are super vivid i am proud i
am impressed
so shout out to adam and handmade
apparel uh quick turnaround time
great quality and very affordable shirts
thank you they're gonna look good on
people
i should have been wearing one today but
i think i am
trying not to wear graphic tees as much
not my own brand
i don't want to wear my brand i may wear
your brand but it's almost i've grown
out of wearing my brand it feels a
little bit silly sometimes
when they go rasta jeff of irie genetics
and i'm more in a [ __ ] irie genetics
t-shirt i'm not a cartoon character i'm
not a comic book hero
i don't need to have my own logo on my
chest all the time but sometimes it's
acceptable i guess anyway i'm rambling
and chattery today
shout out to our friends at binsk for
the [ __ ] concentrates that got me
high as [ __ ] and made me rambly
i enjoy it let's try to get me back on
track where are we headed with this
podcast it is my job to keep this thing
on the rails
here we go this is what we're going to
talk about now recently the power went
out where i grow
i wasn't here or i wasn't there and i
showed up at the grow
the whole neighborhood was dark i was
like something's going on pulled up
it was dark none of the normal sounds
you hear in the grow were happening
i went to where the grow is the clone
machine was not bubbling that was my
number one concern
i've got an easy cloner going usually i
hear that constant
it just never stops there's always the
sound of that just a whirring watering
thing happening it's always going
i did not hear that so i went into a
light panic mode i wouldn't say a major
panic mode i did go into a light panic
and i said [ __ ] the cloner's not working
i wonder how long that's been going um i
noticed all the lights were out the air
conditioner was out
the fans were not blowing everything was
shut down the cloner was my major
concern like i've said but
this made me think maybe i should tell
our friends what we could do
in the situation of a power outage the
number one thing i thought of
is to remind you to buy digital timers
when you're buying timers for your grow
you've got the opportunity to buy
digital timers with the battery backup
or you can buy those
shitty timers with the little pegs that
you push down and then they turn you
plug them in and they turn and
as time goes by those pegs are either up
or down and those pegs tell it to be off
or on
those are fine but when the power goes
out
those timers stop spinning so those
little pegs
nothing happens while the time time is
out while the power is out nothing
happens
that timer quits turning so when the
power comes back on it resumes where it
is
so if you're in the middle of your
flowering cycle the timer goes off
you're six hours into flower
and your flowering day power goes off
power comes on
anytime later we're going to say three
hours later now your timer is going to
kick back on and it's going to continue
the six hour day cycle that you've got
programmed
because time stood still on your timer
while time kept moving in the real world
on the babylon clock
time kept moving on the sun clock time
kept moving on your little broken timer
with the power outage
time stayed still so when the time comes
back on all of your cycles all of your
routines all of your rhythms are now
[ __ ] nothing is the way you expected
it to be
you've got to go back and manually
readjust the time on that timer
or it's going to be off until you fix it
and sometimes
the power goes off and you're not at the
place where the power goes off maybe i
didn't show up at that grow
in time and the power came back on and
it had been off for four hours i never
would have known that timer would have
adjusted
itself four hours so my grow would have
been off everything would have been
mistimed by four hours
and that could that could destroy
everything so buy
the digital timer with a battery backup
that way when the power goes out
if the power were to go out here and i
had that timer plugged in behind me
it would keep ticking it would follow
the normal babylon clock it would follow
the rest it would follow my cell phone
because my phone doesn't die when the
power goes out
that clock keeps going so would my
battery back up clock
that way when the power does come back
on it can it'll stay on the same
schedule
when the power goes off it does not
continue to run my light with the backup
battery don't think that's what the
backup battery is for
that backup battery is to keep the time
at the same time
then when the power comes back on it is
still whatever time it is on your phone
on the babylon clock it's that time
still
on your timer all of your cycles are set
where they should be
you shouldn't miss a beat other than
that time that it was off so i hope i
made that point clearly because that was
a lot of [ __ ] rambling uh once again
shout out to the dabs
buy digital timers if you have got the
opportunity
digital timers are much better than the
analog timers that stick
and don't keep flowing when the time
cuts out when the power cuts out
time stops on those so get yourself a
digital timer and stay
correct on your time now where do we go
from there i keep mentioning that easy
cloner that was the thing that made me
panic the most
i ran and i checked the ez cloner i
lifted it up and i touched the roots of
the plants they were barely starting to
root
they were wet they were moist they were
not dripping with water like i would
like them to be but they had moisture to
them which means they were going to
survive
so that power couldn't have been out for
very long so
what i do with my power cleaner with my
ez cloner turbo cloner power cloner all
of those electric cloners that spray
water from the bottom
if your power does go out my advice to
you is about every 30 minutes to an hour
lift that lid up and just use a spray
bottle and spray those roots spray those
where they would normally get misted
spray them just manually go in there
with a spray bottle and spray the [ __ ]
out of them
if you need to scoop up some of the
water that is in the cloner and use that
water as your spray just go ahead and
spray them
that way the roots stay nice and wet or
the root zone where the roots are going
to happen stay nice and wet and you
don't kill off your clones
spray them every 30 45 minutes just keep
them wet maybe once every hour and they
will survive so that is a way to keep
the easy cloner
the turbo cloners alive now if you are
missing light hours
that's okay the power went off while i
was gone that is okay
you cannot have power the lights come on
during the dark cycle that is a problem
having the lights go off during the
darks during the day cycle
if the lights go off during the day
cycle all you're really losing
is that photosynthetic energy you're not
getting the photons the energy
the light energy from the from the light
that day so your plants are going to
lack that little bit
but it's not as detrimental as if you
were getting interruptions
in the dark period so you can miss a few
hours um
one thing i did notice quickly very
quickly the temperature and humidity of
my grow spaces
went out of control it was really humid
in there it was really stagnant it was
quite funky
the temperature was moving around i
could feel the humidity in there
however i couldn't tell you what the
temperature or humidity are because the
devices i use
are attached to a plug-in device and
when the power went out
they were no longer powered i didn't
know what was happening in that room for
that period of time when the power came
back on
all my monitors came back on but my
monitoring devices are powered by
electricity
and when the power went out so did my
device so i don't know what happened in
that room
during that power outage it could have
been a hundred and whatever degrees it
could have been four degrees i don't
know
it could have been fifty percent
humidity it could have been ninety
percent
i don't know i could only tell you that
i could feel it it was damp in there and
it was funky so
everything went out of control the
humidity the temperature it was all
wacky for quite
a while um all you can do is [ __ ]
hope for the best in that situation i
don't know what happened
because i didn't have a monitor uh what
i can say is
hope for it to get back on schedule as
soon as possible when that power comes
on
go and check all of your timers go check
all of your settings and make sure
everything is set exactly how you
thought it was check your light timer
check all of your pumps if you're
running hydro check all of those pumps
check all of your fans check your air
conditioner anything that plugs in that
can [ __ ] up
check it when the power goes out because
it probably did
[ __ ] up uh where are we gonna go from
here i've got a lot of notes i feel like
i skipped something oh
if the power keeps going off and on uh
it was happening here
i think they were working on it down the
street so if the power goes off and on
if it's like on for a few minutes and
then it shuts off and then it comes on
it shuts off and you know it's going to
keep doing that
just unplug everything if you can flip
the breaker flip the [ __ ] breaker to
stop the power to that room because
it is very stressful on your grow lights
uh maybe some of the modern leds will
handle it but your hps
and your uh halide and your sodium
lights they're not going to handle off
and on
cycles that rapidly very well
excuse me got to clear my throat here
they're not going to handle the off and
on very well
it would be better for your equipment
just to unplug it let it be off for a
couple of hours once you're sure they've
got their [ __ ] fixed then plug it back
in
and get it running that'll be better for
your equipment and probably better for
the plants
you don't want jumping humidity spikes
you don't want humidity dips you don't
want hot and cold all day
the plants are not going to know what to
do with that that's going to cause you
powdery mildew issues that's going to
cause problems
uh slower growth it's going to [ __ ]
things up in the grow also
that's going to mess up your bulbs those
bulbs only get so many strike times for
them to come on
if you have to strike it six times today
plus hot starts are not good
that'll slow down your ballast
performance and your bulb so it may be
best just to unplug it
and make sure it doesn't keep going off
and on i'm making sure i've got all my
notes covered here
um so make sure you reset everything
when it comes back on like i said before
everything
that can [ __ ] up when the power goes off
will [ __ ] up when the power goes off
you've got to get everything back in
sync
don't just assume that that fan is going
to come back on when you think it should
that air conditioner will come on that
those bubblers will cycle as you think
so
go ahead and check them part of being a
good grower and being an okay grower
is that eye for detail did you bother to
go check on all the settings did you
bother
to go make sure that things were correct
or did you just assume
hope and pray because assuming hoping
and praying might not get you there if
you physically got your stoned ass up
off the couch and went and looked you
know it's good
you've only got yourself to blame put
some pride into your work set yourself
up for success
go check on that [ __ ] dude it's that
easy i'm in love with my plants i'm in
love with my garden so
uh if i hear something make the wrong
noise i'm in there looking like what
made that noise what happened
i can hear from the garage from the
driveway
i can hear the cycles of the house and i
know what should be happening and if i
hear the wrong noise
before i'm even to the door i know
there's a problem that's how much i know
might grow
the other thing i wanted to mention on
this part is um
daylight savings time we just adjusted a
couple of weeks ago to daylight savings
time
my question for you is did you adjust
your grow room or did you adjust your
life to it because those plants didn't
care
that it was daylight savings time
they've been on 12 12 for so long did
you [ __ ] change that or did you just
let it ride send me an email grow from
your heart at hotmail.com let me know
what you did
for daylight savings time and what can
you what are you going to do when it
comes back
because a lot of us have our lights
scheduled right before you leave for
work you got an hour when the lights
come on so you can water them
or maybe they come on right when you get
home from work how are you adjusting to
daylight savings time did you adjust
your life
or did you just go in there and straight
up change the [ __ ] timer in the
middle of a flowering cycle
let me know what you did grow from your
heart at hotmail.com
all right podcast world this is the part
of the show where i read a message from
patreon
once again i do encourage you to support
the show on patreon at patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart
today's patreon message goes
a lot like this it says what's up rosta
jeff and what's up mike you hear it mike
you're getting a shout out i invite you
to be back on the show
it goes like this it says i just did a
fat dab and i gave my mom a hug and now
i've got a quick
question that is perfect the question
goes like this
have you ever heard of the paper bag
method we have recently started using
the paper bag method
and it seems to be working out pretty
well the only thing i'm running into is
that i'm still
having a little bit of a green taste to
it seven days after being in the bag
so i need to let it cure for another
seven to fourteen days or let it dry in
the bag for another three to seven days
i hope to hear from you soon this may be
only the only month i can give 10 bucks
because i need to save up for some of
your genetics
from your friend jake hey jake don't
stress bro if you can't support the show
on patreon
i do understand it is voluntary it is
not mandatory i do appreciate the
support you're giving us now
and it's time to get you some seeds bro
i'd rather see you growing seeds in your
garden
than supporting me on patreon because
the seeds will give back
i'm going to give to you for free grow
some seeds and then when you can
come find me on patreon again no hard
feelings thank you for the great message
thank you for the patreon support now
let's talk about this paper bag
method i've heard of the paper bag
method what is the paper bag method that
is drying
and curing basically curing our cannabis
in a brown paper bag a lot of people
will
cut the plants down they'll let them
hang until they're dry until the stems
snap a little bit
they do it perfectly right up until then
then when it comes to the curing process
they put them in a brown paper bag that
brown paper bag is then
rolled up and sealed up at the end some
people put it in the refrigerator
some people leave it in a cool dry dark
area some people
do it different ways however i don't
approve or like the brown paper bag
method
because it leaves a brown paper bag
flavor to your buds that is why i highly
always recommend drying and curing in
either glass
if you can or in plastic in a large
commercial environment i will cure
in a plastic container a very big
plastic container we'll talk about that
in a moment
but i think that your product tastes
like
green and brown paper bag because you
are drying and curing
in a brown paper bag the idea is to get
the
chlorophyll to release from those buds
so the moisture and the air create a gas
inside that environment when you seal
that bag up there's a
an anaerobic gas is created in there
that gas will eat the chlorophyll
that chlorophyll then becomes a vapor
and needs to escape from the environment
it's not escaping it is getting stuck in
your brown paper bag
it is staying right there and that
flavor is just sticking
to your buds if you wrap those buds in
uh something that
a sushi roll those buds are gonna taste
like a sushi roll if you wrap them in a
wet towel they'll taste like a wet towel
if you wrap your dried buds in a blunt
wrap they taste like [ __ ] sorry that's
my opinion i just wanted to throw that
out there
if you wrap your wet buds in a brown
paper bag they're going to taste like a
brown paper bag and chlorophyll so
that's why i believe you are getting
this non-desirable flavor and aroma i
never
ever recommend drying in cardboard or
paper bags or
anything like that that paper material
will hold the moisture
that moisture will hold the chlorophyll
that chlorophyll will put that flavor
right back into your buds so i prefer i
recommend drying in glass or large
plastic containers
the way you want to do it and this is
just a quick method of how i would
recommend doing it
cut the plants down get the big leaves
off of them let them hang until the stem
snap you want those stems popping not
exploding but cracking
at that point trim them you want i
prefer a dry trim i think it's much
easier it's much quicker
it's not as messy i just think it's much
more efficient so
hang them uh take off the big leaves let
them dry
cut it into smaller pieces and trim it
up at that point put it into
a glass jar fill the glass jar about 90
of the way full you want some room for
air in there put those buds in the jar
i am very ocd also i'm very committed to
my grow
i'm able to do these things i set a
timer for 30 minutes when i first put
them in the jar
seal up that jar 30 minutes 30 minutes
later i come back i dump them out of the
jar let those buds sit for a minute make
sure they're not too sticky too tacky
too wet
if i agree if i believe that they are
the appropriate moisture level to put
back in the jar
they go back in the jar i seal it up now
i set my alarm for about an hour
i come back i check in an hour pour the
buds out of the jar
feel them are they ready to go back in
the jar maybe i jarred too early this is
my opportunity
to say i'm gonna [ __ ] this up i'm not
going to put them back in the jar yet
so i'll let them sit out until i feel
like they're right this is kind of an
art form you have to learn this
they don't want to be so wet that the
buds if you squeeze them you don't want
it to stay
flattened you want it spongy to where it
pops back up but you also don't want it
so dry that when you squeeze it it turns
to dust
you want to put it in there to where
there's enough moisture in the jar to
trigger
the reaction to make the anaerobes eat
the chlorophyll
but you don't want it so moist in there
that you're going to create a moldy
environment
so now is your opportunity to check it
out check it the first hour
if it's appropriate put it back in the
jar if not let it sit
if it sits out for a while catch up with
us to this step put it back in the jar
we've all got our buds dried
appropriately put them back in the jar
set a timer i'm gonna set a timer for
another hour depending on how
sticky those buds were one to two hours
i'm gonna come back and check on them
at this point we are starting the curing
process they're not too moist i'm sure
they're not too moist they can go in the
jar for an extended time
i'm gonna check on them every four hours
for the next two days
pop open that jar let it sit for 10
maybe 20 minutes depending on the level
of moisture
and the aromas that come out of that jar
if it still
feels sticky and moist when you touch
the buds
give it a little more time if they're
starting to dry out don't give it so
much time
then slowly increase your time that it's
left in that jar
you can go from four hours to six hours
to eight
to twelve eventually 24 36 48 hours
before you burp that jar
don't leave it closed too long too early
is the major thing to look at
if you can do multiple jars if you can
set up like four or five jars from your
harvest and only open this one every
so often and this one longer and this
one longer maybe
maybe see what happens if you do longer
and shorter periods you've got to
experiment a little bit with curing
i wish i could give you perfect
parameters but your environment is what
is going to play the most into your
drying and curing
uh differences it's i'm in colorado it's
cold and dry here
i can dry and cure herb super quickly if
you're in florida
it's going to be super moist it's going
to take a lot longer for your herb to
dry so
your environment and how wet the buds
were when they went into the curing
container are going to determine
how often and how soon you need to open
those jars so don't let
my advice [ __ ] you up if you're in a if
you got wetter buds
do it sooner and more often if they're
drier do it less
and longer intervals that's my advice so
i said i would do it in large
plastic containers if i had a lot of
product
i am known for running commercial
cultivation facilities i'm a commercial
cultivation consultant you can hire me
i will go to your commercial cultivation
facility i'll spend a day there
looking at your grow seeing what kind of
strategy you have seeing what kind of
standard operating procedures you are
using i'll learn the staff a little bit
i'll see who is on top of their game and
the staff i'll see where your weakest
link is
and i can make recommendations on how to
improve the overall performance of your
facility in a short amount of time that
is my job
part of my job is improving people's
drying and curing method
i see a lot of wacky [ __ ] so let's talk
about the way i do it in a commercial
environment we do it the same way
we start the same way as the glass jar
method and a small cultivation
cut the plant take off the big leaves
cut the plants down hang them upside
down until the stems pop
when those stems start to pop i will cut
the bigger
buds and branches off of the plants and
leave that main stock so you got the big
stock with the main
christmas tree coming out the menorah
cut all the buds off of that now you
just got the menorah
that part goes in another area that's
got to get weighed and accounted for
before we can throw it away that's
another story
i will take those big buds they're
probably the length of my arm
somewhere between 16 and 30 inches long
yes we do grow buds that big in a
commercial cultivation facility
we fill the room with those buds we chop
them until they will fit into
a large sterlite or rubbermaid
container it's about uh 30 inches long
maybe 36 32 inches long
it's about a foot and a half tall and
it's got a lid that goes on top of it
you all know about the storage
containers i'm talking about
if you've moved they're used used for
moving if you ship groceries i see a lot
of groceries shipped in these things
it's a sterlite storage container you
can get them at target you can get them
just about anywhere you buy plastic
stuff those are great for drying and
curing your product
if you have a large amount of product i
know they are not airtight we're going
to get to that in a moment
but i take my plants and i will put the
plants inside of those containers
i'll mark the date that they went into
that container and then i will put them
in a dry and cure room now let's talk
about my dry and cure room this is why
the containers don't need to be airtight
i have got a humidifier on a controller
that every time it gets below or above
humidity that dehumidifier comes on i
don't know if i said humidifier or
dehumidifier in the first round but
my point is i've got both devices i have
a humidifier and a dehumidifier in the
room
both set to 50 percent now they are
fighting all day long
it's going to stay 50 percent stays
about somewhere between
45 and 55 maybe 60 to 50 percent uh
relative humidity in that room
constantly with those two devices going
it's colorado it gets hot it gets cold
it gets dry it gets wet
so the devices do have to adjust to the
normal they have to fight the normal
atmosphere
but for the most part it is 50 relative
humidity in my drying and curing room
so i've got those sterlite bins filled
with buds they're mostly airtight they
seal up pretty well
but then to compensate for the lack of
seal in there i make the entire room
ideal for those plants to be dried and
cured in i also dried those plants in
that room with the 50
relative humidity and the perfect
temperature in there usually about 75
degrees depends on
like i said outside factors uh other
environmental factors make a huge
difference but
that's the way we do it in a commercial
environment then uh
i've got a person that used to be mike
he used to be ernie uh there are a
couple other guys that i've taught very
well how to dry and cure buds in a
commercial environment
you got to take all those big bins line
them up on the floor
pop the lids off of every single one of
them go and put your hand in there and
see the moisture level of those buds
i like to turn them over i don't let
them sit with the bottom buds on the
bottom the entire time
flip them those bottom buds need some
fresh air too so they can dry properly
flip them over so i will open them all
up we will leave them open for a
determined amount of time
like i said before if they're brand new
they'll stay open for maybe an hour on a
commercial grow in that 50
room then we'll seal them back up maybe
it'll just be 15 minutes maybe we pop
them open and go oh these are ready
when we go oh these are ready that's
when they get trimmed they don't even
get trimmed all the way
until they're done being dried and cured
we can keep them in stasis in that room
and they get perfect for the trim crew
and when we need them we just go get
them we can catch up
that way it's not a struggle to be
trimming everything all at once we take
down uh
50 to 100 lights worth of plants all at
once you don't want to have to scramble
to trim that all today
you can get it bucked down you can get
it in those containers get it in the dry
and cure bins
get it in a stasis situation and then
when you need it go ahead and trim it
get it bagged up send it out to the
stores that's the way we do it in a big
grill i use the big
plastic bins in a room that is dialed in
all right so um i hope i did not ruin
your hopes and dreams by saying that
your cure method does need improvement
i think as long as you're drying and
curing in paper bags you're going to
have
a chlorophyll and brown paper bag taste
glass jars are not expensive
ironically there are not any glass jars
available
anywhere right now we are in a pandemic
situation and i think everybody decided
to can their product or they all harvest
it early because glass jars are hard to
find right now
good luck with that but that's what i
recommend glass jars if you cannot find
glass i
recommend plastic as my second
recommendation go for the medical grade
plastic if you can the quality food
grade plastics
if not do what you've got to do but get
away from that brown paper bag
i don't think you're ever going to be
satisfied you're like crippling yourself
you're running you're running you're
about to
win the race and then right at the end
of the race you're like [ __ ] i'm
gonna sit down and just
eat a sandwich you could have won but
instead you put your [ __ ] in a brown
paper bag
don't do that anymore let's upgrade your
garden let's upgrade your game let's
start drying and curing and
glass if you can plastic is your next
bet
i've also seen people do it in stainless
steel containers that would work for me
sounds expensive to buy a bunch of
stainless steel containers however
if that works you do that all right jake
i want to thank you for the great
message i also want to thank you for the
continued patreon support
i think that is all i've got for this
episode if you feel like this episode
was educational informative or
entertaining
and you would like to make a financial
contribution to the show again all you
have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need is right there
on the screen if you've got any
corrections questions comments or
concerns
i would love to hear from you the email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
or visit the website at iregenetics.com
and there is a little contact us tab on
there there's also a grow
help tab on the website that's right a
grow help tab if you've got grow
questions i invite you
to go to the grow help tab fill out the
little grow help form
that'll help me answer you there are a
few questions in there
that when people send me an email
they're like my plants have problems
what's wrong
i've always got seven follow-up
questions i just answer those i ask
those questions on
that web forum you fill that out that
gives me some information
then i can help you out more efficiently
and also i may use your question
on the podcast so we're helping each
other out there thank you
um what else where was i going from
there the corrections the website i
think that is all i've got for you
uh don't forget to subscribe to the
youtube channel go to youtube search for
the grow from your heart podcast
click on subscribe click on that little
bell that way you don't miss any
episodes
any content uh that's all i've got my
voice is burning out i think it is time
for me to get some food and take a few
more dabs
i want to thank you again for listening
to this episode of the grow from your
heart podcast i'll be back in just a
couple of days with fresh new content
i want to give a giant shout out to my
buddy grim bull the druid and until next
time take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me