okay I'm ready Nebraska yeah you know we
smoke so much [ __ ] no M
Nebraska yeah I hate it so much it's so
godamn lame when I buy some hash and
that [ __ ] don't melt it just turns into
a black biscuit on the net
Hill talking about no M Nebraska
Nebraska Nebraska
neas got the no Nebraska yeah you know
we got so much [ __ ] no melt
[ __ ]
Braska no
Nebraska we got the no Nebraska
yeah we've got that [ __ ] big jar of
no
Nebraska no
Nebraska got the no Mount Nebraska
Nebraska I've got to [ __ ] get rid all
of this no Mount
Nebraska no M
nebras it just makes me sick I just want
to get rid off all of it get rid of
it somebody please take my no
Nebraska no M
Nebraska
yeah
no
Nebraska this uh PSA has been brought to
you by the great Boys At turpex
catch them on iTunes under turpy boys
their new album will be out soon no melt
Nebraska keep it turpy I'm just going to
start the show with that usually I've
got an intro song and [ __ ] but I'm just
going to roll with it from right there
that was
awesome I'm really I'm really excited
that you have that recorded because I'm
going to use that in our store I'm going
to play that in the butt room that means
you're going to play my podcast a lot
cuz it's the only version of it that
will be available you're only going to
let me have that one I bet that was
awesome wow uh welcome to the show
everybody uh I'm flabbergasted and
thrown off Pace by that but that's the
greatest way to start a podcast ever
that's that's pretty much how you got to
do it in life you know you got to do
something unexpected you didn't know you
didn't know my boys had voices like that
that's like true that's like true Sirens
of the 7 I'm kind of turned on you know
I've got all kinds of emotions going on
over here I did not want it to stop at
all ever the only thing we want to stop
hey man we could do that for about four
hours and we haven't done it before
we'll do the outro for four hours we'll
just eat that hey yeah we got our uh we
got our special bread song that we just
made up special bread song new strain
you know exclusive genetics you know
called The Bread the bread the bread do
I want to know the cross it's it's the
it's a secret it's a secret I will I
will say before we get off topic we do
want to make sure we say little you're
we need to end the no melt Nebraska like
the Nebraska needs to stop in this state
we need stop stop making no melt
Nebraska it's not about the no melt it's
about the Melt get back on the J mik
thank you get back on the J we're going
to need to make a glossery of terms to
with the podcast but if you're not with
it you're not with it today guys so
basically let me explain what no Mount
Nebraska is let's start it off with that
well let's introduce you before you
explain ladies and gentlemen uh speaking
on the mic right now that is about to
give us a lesson in no melt Nebraska is
Jordan from turpex you don't know about
turpex you got to find out uh I have
been dabbing mad turpex for the past uh
two or three weeks and uh turpex has put
a smile on my face I just dabed some
chem dog nectar I'm lit up so all right
here I'm going to turn it back over to
Jordan no no melt Nebraska let's hear it
again okay so no melt Nebraska is
basically
any hash that doesn't melt essentially
you know what I mean because basically
if you were to imagine making hash in
Nebraska it would be melting most of it
would probably not be very good I think
it was just we were thinking where's the
state that has the least melty hash yeah
I think that that is exactly where it
came from it ended being Nebraska and it
it is true it's you know it's about the
hash that doesn't melt you just call it
Nebraska and then the song was derived
when uh my friend Jordan here came home
with a bunch of of uh no Nebraska yeah
had a uh had a had somebody come down um
back when we lived in Northern
California came down from mesino was
talking for weeks about this awesome
amazing granddaddy per bubble has that
he was going to be bringing down and let
me tell you when he brought that
down turned into turned into straight
biscuits on the uh straight biscuits on
the it on the nail and instead of
getting a bubble you just get no nothing
really happens just kind yeah it just
kind of sits there
and goes to a light brown you don't
really get any smoke in the piece or
anything you're just like burn the face
I'm making does not convey on radio at
all but I I'm making this fa like if
you've ever smelled burnt hair I'm
making the face that happens when you
smell burnt hair our buddy John John
just walked in he's getting we're
fighting
r
j I [ __ ] love this group of people
shout
out so I've got a dab for you over here
also after you take dab that full melt
dab or mostly melt dab kind of melt yeah
there's and if I will say this for
everybody you know if you don't
understand all of the verbiage
nomenclatures going on today definitely
write in to the grow from your heart
podcast and ask for a definition well my
name's Richard and I don't understand
what that nomenclature word is that you
just said and I'm frankly I'm offended
no well not everybody can be on the
level I'm pretty sure it's verbiage not
verbiage verbiage it's verbiage ver
verbi there's a verb I stand correct all
right Captain
grammar that's the Nature Boy Ric Flair
to my mostly left over here I'm going to
say what that like 11:00 you about the
11:30 position over there I'd like to
say you know 1137 I'm going to give you
11:30 because that's 420 plus 710 there
we go that is my buddy hunt that's the
Grammy gby over there how you doing
brother been I am ecstatic to finally be
on the podcast after months of [ __ ]
talking about it and getting called out
by my boy I for not listening and trying
to listen and playing it at our shop and
doing everything I finally [ __ ] here
spitting grammar on the mic finally here
I'm actually here I am in I am the TP
man I'm in the turp Mansion I call it
the turpy trap house it's kind of a pig
invaded dud no you haven't been to my
house I've invaded their uh dining area
I stepped on their dog uh I've made
myself home
here yeah he lit he literally just you
know walked in kicked the dog grabbed
the email and set up a mic and we're the
dog was asking for a kicking dude that
that that dog came right back and tried
to hump your ass I just want everybody
to know that he likes it rough man I
guess so uh he probably smelled the ham
wallet you know what I'm saying y oh
yeah to sneak in the word ham wallet do
you get points for that got a couple if
you guys want any more ham ham wallet
pocket moose knuckle ninja foot spit
Viper this is going to be a grimy show
that's why we brought our friend the
grimy Gatsby they only bring me for a
reason that's to not act my age I want
to thank you for getting you set this up
this is your fault that all this chaos
is here on the show and I appreciate it
thanks a lot and I'm also going to give
a huge Shameless plug to uh green and
healthy cannabis on 212 South 21st
Street in Colorado Springs oh much love
for sure uh I know I do work for a
dispensary right in peblo but they don't
have the turpex and I come up to green
and healthy cannabis to get the turpex
definitely and also also the schula oh
yeah man that schula that that schula is
raw boy it's almost as raw as the bra if
you're ever in Colorado Springs 212
South 21st Street uh in between Colorado
and simmeron we're always there waiting
for you great con come on through ample
parking your freshest buds
John John's a sweet dude he'll hook you
up real good he is the man oh yeah I
always treat everyone very good good
timing dude right on for showing up
right as we started the show that was
glorious yeah it wasn't a great time I
tried to stall to wa for you you know
but then that song happened and I had to
just you know song Just lured me in you
got to grow with it you got called in by
the song I'm wondering if I can to put
this guitar away no man you got to keep
that out you're going to use that since
you're playing the guitar introduce
yourself dude cuz we I I don't remember
your name and I'm you just kind of you
these guys just merged out of the video
game room a few minutes ago they're like
a [ __ ] you got a real podcast and they
came and join
GG fam is thick and thorough bro I love
it well welcome to the crew introduce
yourself to the show please yeah I'm
Daniel glad to be here on the show
tonight I'm the one they call
flare like like Ric Flare like woo like
that flare yeah I like that flare he
like the Nature Boy Boy on that bread
like throwing figure fours on them boy
yeah all right dog I'm over here smoking
a blunt I barely smoke blunts happens
when you're in the trap house from
sometimes you got to take it back to 16
you now you want want you both mics man
man we're going to get lit up all right
joints blunts dabs it's going to be a
great podcast I wrote down well hunt
wrote down a few topics he's going to be
the OCD guy in the group most of the
time I wish I could read your writing
dude yeah man you want to hit my inhaler
beat you all to it you get it to it yeah
so yeah Hunt is hunt you know that's a
another topic hunt was recently
diagnosed with asthma how's that going
for you oh I can't walk upstairs that
fast no more glest dude I know temp
temporary asthma with bronchitis right
now so I'm like off all the [ __ ]
pieces and [ __ ] that sounds like a hand
wallet problem yeah definitely
definitely part of the spinning Viper
Club
yeah is your is your ham wall getting a
little Sandy and rough well not not
anymore itrated I was weezing I was
weezing and coffee all those no yeah the
Nebraska will get you dude you were up
in a helicopter jumping out of a
helicopter onto a 1400 foot Mountain on
skis 1400 no I was two weeks ago I was
yeah I might be high and not know how to
count zeros you're right it's only 1,200
feet high what I'm I'm from Ohio but I
think it's higher than
that um yeah I was just in Silverton
like two weeks ago doing a bunch of heli
drops and skiing 13,000 foot Cliffs with
bronchitis uh yeah I had bronchitis
acute bronchitis at that point yeah
still jumping out of the heli and
getting down still taking dabs whatever
you did last week you're a [ __ ] my
buddy hunt was on top of a 14,000 foot
mountain jumping out of a helicopter on
skis and [ __ ] 5T a pow and now he has
asthma
right don't try this at home he's
hitting an inhaler he does three or four
dabs and goes to the inhaler that's kind
of cheating bro I mean yeah but you know
I want you to live it's all right get
head just like Schwarzenegger did can I
hit that boy you want to hit that [ __ ]
let me hit that I got that arbutin all
OG player as long as you feel good does
it does it help you out oh definitely
yeah lace up another [ __ ] hot nail
for
me all right Mark
Wahlberg where oh yo yeah actually Mark
wber is coming in later right coming to
the show so H since you invited me here
I want to definitely make sure to take
some time to rep all your companies uh I
know you're the grimy Gatsby tell tell
me give you a couple seconds to Hype up
the Gatsby tell me about that yeah so I
I own a company that's called Grammy
Gatsby uh the Grammy gatsby. comom if
you want to check it out it's a media
and lifestyle website um and since
that's been started years ago there's
now like a large portfolio of awesome
people and brands that make up a
gigantic Network all across the country
so we have uh green and healthy wellness
down in Colorado Springs where there's a
dispensary Apotheca cannabis T topicals
and lotions which is apana yeah straight
up all the dudes in the room the whole
turpex Squad how I get down you know I
get I get I have my own moniker here
called The Gatherer with the turpex crew
CU That's How We Do It um brought a
party tonight definitely you know
brought the homies in um there 50 60
people in the other room there's like 34
34 down here and then the VIP is sold
out at 50 we call this the camp um
they're all just up there packaging
grams is all they're doing right exactly
exactly um but no there's other like the
Cannabis Grand crew is a big you know
know super high Echelon um limited to
500 people and its event that travels
all over the country that I help produce
um there's Smokey brand which is Smoky
socks and Smoky clothing Rock the SMY
socks you know custom sublimated socks
and sublimated clothing plus knitted
stuff and we sore stuff for you know all
kinds of unbelievable Brands so we can
get just about anything we want printed
on some socks right anything that you
want on a sock anything you want on a
shirt pretty much anything that you want
in concentrate form anything you want in
topicals anything you want on a shelf
anything you need uh we're I'm just now
working on this 3D printing company
that's going to start up in Denver
pretty soon so it's kind of like you
know whatever comes through and how we
can do it to maximize the whole network
I'm going to make a uh a personal
request for some Apotheca I've got a
friend who um she's got bad skin okay
and she would love a cannabis product or
a more organic healthy product to help
her clear up her blemishes dop so let's
get apana on that one and Super salver
Body Butter we have it at the shop okay
I know something was available no yeah
we make some already um it does rashes
irritations Cuts Burns blisters any of
that kind of stuff we'll we'll do what
we got to do any you touch that nail
like a w would you know you get that
burn on your finger yeah go stick that
sucker in some APO man you need a nail
here's a here's a rig for you shout out
to the Mad Rob rig you asked for a dab a
minute ago and I just shined you on CU I
was talking yeah you were just like you
know keep eating what yeah just keep
talking keep talking we'll give you a
dad when I'm ready when you're good when
you say something worth it I'll give you
dad like a reward you're a good dog I
feel you I feel you but uh yeah I mean
it's um if you go to the website you
know follow us on Instagram at gramy
Gatsby but it's a um it's just a
gigantic network of people much like iie
and turpex and everything else that we
do it's you know trying to be as
Community Based and making sure people
are getting forward and being positive
and there's tons of Brands I I mean the
guys that are in the room are probably
the most important ones because this is
how we all make it happen nice that
bread that bread that bread I heard
there's just wait
for don't open the can we talk about the
key does anybody know about the key yeah
we can talk about the key yeah um tell
me about the key in 2010 um I started
grimy gats being Aspen and we only have
about 2500 locals in Aspen some maybe
3,000 now I don't know I've left since
then but uh in Aspen it was this thing
where like all these people always had
parties and cool [ __ ] happening and for
Grammy Gatsby I wanted to be something
special so we would throw a party every
week called Gatsby's Garden shout out I
you know big up all the grow um but we
would do Gatsby's Garden every Tuesday
at a revolving bar and the people that
were like truly homies and people that
like were respected we would hook them
up with the skull key open your parment
right by the mic yeah dud right by the
bike um sorry but uh know we had the
skull key made that we got like 3,000
skull keys and so a lot of the guys in
the room all have one of the skull key
but the thought was is that you know the
skull key opens up every single door in
the Gatsby mansion allows you to go to
all the parties um so initially it was
started that the bouncers and Aspen if
you showed them the key wouldn't check
your ID or make you stand in line so our
parties were you know instantly a little
bit more Hoy toyy for the locals because
they could just walk right in and Shine
off in front of people since then it's
now evolved into you know people all
over the world have this little skull
key on their keychain that's a very nice
connection Point um and you know when
when we have events there's a lot of
keys in the room and when the keys are
out by themselves at least they know
we're all together it's pretty cool yeah
it's dope it's admirable it's kind of a
neat little thing yeah it's branding
and how how does one earn a key yeah
where's my key so I wasn't going to ask
that but I'm glad they stepped up for
most of the keys now are only handed out
at the
dojo they used to be shoes off secret
knock shoes off secret KN Circle thank
you fam is fam shoes off secret not Dojo
temps down TPS up drum circle TPS down
temps up yep all day
you know it was like marketing and
branding and this cool little thing that
I could do and now it's you know I have
I've broken one since then and have
people send them to me and all kinds of
just crazy [ __ ] so it's cool to like
you know I think you have a key right I
do not have a key damn but uh you'll get
one yeah I know we the dojo you know
what I haven't been to your new house
bro you moved and I haven't been there
don't tell nobody well we live aund and
something miles apart you can come by we
meet up in the springs shout out to
Colorado Springs you've been super kind
to me
7119 down on that Co Springs baby West
Side coming at you
# white
people aliens aliens # no free
time man you got uh everybody in this
room is a social media monster yeah for
sure there's a lot of it right I mean
everybody likes to sit down on that [ __ ]
you guys I feel like social media is
what brought my uh my business you know
I I did it on accident I was like I'm
gonna start a little seed company and I
put it up on social media little seed
and then suddenly it was like you've got
one of the known seed companies on and
it was all social media do you guys
notice that from like like being a hash
company do you guys see that a lot
Instagram's a huge Instagram huge
platform how many followers does turpex
have just curious 21, 21,000 yeah see
that's killing it that's more than me i'
uh probably at 13,000 by the time this
airs that's close to there that's great
yeah we've been building that uh that
number for almost what two or three
years at this point three years almost
so yeah definitely about three years
yeah what's the exact turpex account so
they can find it uh turpex Co t e r PX
Co o is there _ anywhere no no nice just
turpex Co you guys find them checking
out check them out great hash pictures
also make sure you follow green and
healthy cannabis what is their uh you
guys changed that Instagram or something
didn't you we um we're at Green and
healthy 719 all right haters GNA hate
man Haters Gonna Hate hater going to
ain't got kicked off twice hate us cuz
they're Ain us Yeah we actually yeah we
had three accounts deleted now we're up
to like you know 1,500 and how'd you get
your accounts deleted what you do uh I
don't know man Instagram's all about
that non-life sometimes we trying to get
please don't do it to me Instagram I've
been posting just got a new camera and
my pictures my game has increased please
don't squish me speaking of haters dude
you wanted uh you reminded me you asked
me when I got here why they made me
change the name yes uh I'll tell you
again because a lot of people are new to
the show uh yeah it used to be I gr cult
I gr culture right culture yeah yeah IG
gr like based on the iPhone and the iMac
and the I cult that it all is was IG gr
culture because you listen on your
iPhone but there's an educational entity
that does agricultural educational
seminars or some kind of [ __ ] for
colleges oh he goes for the inhaler
the whole room looked at me like say
something about it say something about
it you all heard it I know it's recorded
is that that Al beol yeah that alol OG
player yeah he's getting all [ __ ] up
over there but they didn't want me
relating cannabis to their organization
so they kindly were like please don't
you know and I didn't want to steal
someone else's name and we're all
growing from our heart here big UPS in
respect for that that's you you got to
do what you got to do I don't want to if
that's their name I don't want to steal
it I don't want you know I know I will
tell you man thanks thank that new logo
is [ __ ] crisp with the readouts and
the you know it's good so shout out to
website called Fiverr f i r r uh some
young kid in Bangladesh made the Avatar
of me and then another guy in Bangladesh
pieced the two together and made me the
logo was like 40 bucks how much you 40
40 bucks bucks for everything yeah I was
going to say a young young yeah sound
sounds sounds like all those callers
that you get tele marketing and whatever
right he probably does tech support by
day and from bang Bangladesh about to
say I was about to look at you and be
like are you going to throw out a
Bangladesh accent and did not know how
that would happen I was going to B was
just going to sound like an Indian
that's racist you know not good we're
not racist I think we already got racist
just by just by talking about the cheap
labor wages in other we're not racist
over here you're the one paying we just
run a labor camp and all right we're
talking about social media so how many
how many social medias is the Grammy
Gatsby have or not Medias how many
followers I don't know we're probably
like 3,500 or something like that and we
run about 10 different accounts for
other people as well that are probably
way larger than we are wow but yeah I
mean you want to look at like like it's
just like having a website or anything
else like you got to have you know
content is King as they say and it's
quality and consistency you want to have
the right branding you want to have your
[ __ ] together you're not trying to put
up pictures of brick walls or other
kinds of you know stuff like that or all
kinds of weird things like you really
want to have it together so that it
actually looks like what the brand needs
to be like and then that way you can
expose it and I you know I will tell you
the one thing that I've learned over the
years doing it often is that your
audience needs to be able to watch your
story like how you said you know you
blew up on Instagram or how these guys
have gone from you know Santa Cruz to
and stuff they want to be a part of that
experience I knew of turpex before they
ever had a Colorado presence because of
their cup winnings and Instagram stuff
like shout out turpex shout out yeah who
shout out who TP what speaking of turpex
uh somebody just passed a rig to me and
I've got a big chunk of Kim dog here so
I'm GNA do this let's uh what other
topics dude I opened I brought sorry oh
I got all choked up I'm I brought a
bottle of Dr Pepper into the room and
Hunt he's doing it again he's like
collapsing with with wilt what's going
on bro what's with the Dr Pepper this
this is something I will let some of the
other guys in the room talk about first
but there is I don't drink alcohol I
don't do a lot of things but there's one
thing about 23 flavors that makes me get
a chubby that's that's what I'm saying
bro yeah when I first when I first moved
out here in men hunt this guy pretty
much most every time I saw him he had a
Dr Pepper in one of his hands but then
he you know he had to start getting all
healthy and everything like that now
he's eating kale salads yeah he actually
got me on it too you know what I'm
saying and fuing ruthless you know we we
we put the Dr Peppers away for a while
so it's just hard for him to sit here at
this table and watch you enjoy jelly
beans lip balm [ __ ] drinks they make
all kinds of stuff with the 23 flavor
turp lip balm who saw that shot anybody
see that Perfection left-handed bro
Lefty shot right there so count yeah
okay well thanks
go watch you drool you've looked at my
bottle a couple times it doesn't even I
can even it's like orange cookies I can
just smell it and be happy how long has
it been
uh probably like a week oh that's all
that's all you make you cheated I'm
being honest yeah you know I've cheated
bro I've been sitting up there something
about the 23 TS I can't even smoke I've
only had like two Dr Peppers since we we
gave them up even in Vegas I did not no
really nope oh you know they have that
[ __ ] luxury Dr Pepper in Vegas broe
the last one I had was that uh the Sonic
WWE Smackdown [ __ ] Johnny Rand Jun
over here dude I will tell you though if
you go to Sonic and get that cubed ice
[ __ ] and you get some Dr ice is special
isn't it that ice is something great
yeah one of our partners is hooked on
Sonic hooked on Sonic hashfi by Sonic
Fiel by Sonic fuel by jaw Fel by street
tacos no but that 23 flavor things is
like a nice easy topic to get into
though because yeah get your nail All
Fired out because we got to talk about
TPS anyways I that's the next uh topic
because I was going to give TP you got
to talk about Apotheca and the gasby I
was going to give these guys some time I
hear in just in random conversation that
there are several badass new products
coming out in the future through the
turpex line a couple of them got my
attention of course I asked this while
Jordan's taking a mean dab oh it's all
good I I'll I'll pass that go cough out
some answers here I'm good um yeah you
know we're we've been doing some
experimenting lately um definitely got
some cool new things that we're going to
be bringing out here pretty soon we're
going to have some uh some electronic
cigarettes that are going to be coming
out pre-filled and not the standard you
know poly you know PG or VG or whatever
the [ __ ] people are cutting their
cutting their oil with whatever you want
to call it you know but you want to tell
us what you're going to use um there's
going to be a couple different things
there's definitely going to be some some
just regular BHO pens um that are
available and you know it's all going to
be stuff from the garden that we have uh
connected to our processing center so
it'll all be stuff that we're you know
cultivating specifically for its end
purpose of you know being a delicious
electronic cigarette product grown for
extract instead of just being rejected
material yeah not only that we're we've
got some edibles that are going to start
coming out here pretty soon um I'm
pretty excited about that we've had a
couple people working on them pretty
hard things there are some things I will
even say we cannot say on air about the
Edibles coming out because there's [ __ ]
about to hit the fan one day I can't I
can't let him talk about all those yeah
yeah another another big thing is that
we're gonna be going wreck soon too so
yeah that's uh that's one of the biggest
things that we've been working on lately
so you got turack is not available
recreationally no as of right now our
processing center is in uh Colorado
Springs which obviously as you know is
banned any recreational businesses so to
uh get you guys down in at the spot in
PUO he'd be a great addition to that for
sure well yeah definitely uh we're
hoping by April 1st to be processing
recreationally so we we'd love to be
running your gear gear too up there for
sure that'd be so nice I'd like to see
that IR genetic collabo turfex get down
GL sloy keep it Keep it Gangster you
know what I'm saying that's right well
you guys actually have some of my
genetics in the garden day turpex you're
just trying to throw out hashtags huh
your goal is to just say as many
hashtags on the show as you can right I
mean I I'm the sound bite gatherer so
what are you guys trying to talk about I
keep it too heavy I keep it too light
I'll get in the mic all day hash
advertising hash TP
team yeah hash bring the stash back I
just got called out on my beard yo they
oh you missed the Flanders mustache
absolutely man yeah we were all crushed
when he shave that your badge picture is
hilarious I can't take you seriously
Alec Baldwin I literally have yeah I
have sweaty
balls I I definitely have I have a
straight handlebar curled mustache up in
that one that I grew for months to try
to get it ready and the best story about
that one I told the boys but uh when I
got my picture taken at the me the
little lady that works the computer
literally looked at me and she was like
how long I was like like a couple months
she was like can I touch it I was like
she reached over and combed my w broom
yeah yeah you look like you look like a
a men's wreck softball coach W broom
yeah I was going to let it fly I just
wasn't going to touch it those things
are better if you just let them
pass all right so we hyped up TPX a
little bit what's uh we you mentioned a
bunch of products what's your favorite
one the most that you're most excited
about that you want to Hype
up that's question does mean give me a
dab is that what H me with a I was like
thought was like giving me sign language
to say which one of these things he was
excited
about that'll throw you off you got you
got to wipe your fingers off after you
do that dude I don't even want to touch
you
now um I would say don't have a dab over
here I'm sorry don't worry about it I
got we we have everybody in the room
we're good I would say we're pretty
excited about the uh the Edibles coming
out you know that's something that we've
been working on for a while but we just
didn't want to you know possibly some
tarp Dr yeah we didn't want to hit the
market before you know we really had
everything figured out especially with
how restrictive everything is out here
with the rules for the rules keep
changing every week nobody's trying to
shoot ropes like Peter North on that
yeah they hit Edibles pretty hard with
that milligram
thing I think I win I think I win a dab
on that one I definitely silenced the
whole room where's it
yeah so yeah I mean the Edibles are
going to be on point once we can
actually say there's going to and I will
say I will go a little bit more in depth
on some things there's going to be like
yeah my troll my troll hand is [ __ ]
big don't get me on comments cuz I'll
get going um no but we're going to have
some great Edibles coming through at the
shop and obviously with all the new
products they have coming to you I mean
you have an unbelievable way to kind of
get a comprehensive medication on you
can ingest you can smoke you can you
know have something for the go you can
drink and especially with us you know
being able to cultivate strains
specifically for extracts you know we're
hunting through some new CBD strains
here pretty soon um we've already got
we've already got a couple but you know
we've got some that are going to be
truly truly unique turpion profiles on a
lot of [ __ ] that we're looking for I
threw down something I think should be
high in CBD if it comes through for you
guys dope T across across should be high
in CBD the uglier plants will be higher
in CBD is what I think yeah that's a
great way to describe it more that like
bamboo H yeah yeah those those were the
CBD plants not that you Bo I mean people
that are at home grown hemp rope calling
it cannabis it's okay too oops sure
mids mids mids all right turpex Edibles
how long until you think I can have some
turpex edibles and is it going to be
like um chocolatey stuff is
it grandma do we tell them about Grandma
no don't spill any beans I'm just
curious I'm just trying to was a show my
jobs to ask questions um you can't wear
your headphones and take a dab what is
that about I'd say like you can't you
you don't have to I was just [ __ ]
with you cuz it was weird it's like
turning down the radio so you can see
better we've got a we've got a few
things that we're making this week we're
sending everything to get lab tested
before it actually hits the Shelf cuz
you know we don't want any you want to
give 500 milligrams on accident no watch
me do a Marino Dow cuz I can handle that
but you know most most people cannot
yeah if you guys if you guys can take
the 1200 00 milligram Challenge in a day
we'd love we'd love to hang out explain
the 12200 milligram challenge to me uh
so kind of like no melt Nebraska can we
get can we get a little bit of guitar
behind the yeah I'll try I'll try to go
with it um but yeah like uh I mean the
1200 milligram challenge is is is much
like no melt Nebraska in a sense where
the name kind of gives it away but
there's a lot more in depth about your
passion for the actual event so you know
you want to start off probably with
maybe 400 to 800 milligram and slowly
work your way up to 12 and then at that
point you go outside and put your hands
up in the air and scream up to J thank
you and have a great day it's it's
basically like like any other mental or
physical challenge it's something that
you need to work yourself up to you know
you can't just jump in at 12200
milligrams I I did a couple days at 2500
M can I get a sponsor can I get a
sponsor for this yeah mean I need
somebody to throw down um I need 1,200
and then I need 800 so now we're at
2,000 and then I need 600 you want to
step yourself up yeah I want to do like
I want to do it like a 300 I think I can
do I've done 350 I've eaten a 350
milligram tell you that the way that I
have I have found best to to embibe the
1200 milligrams is straight capsules and
you open the capsules up and take them
while they're half half open okay and
then you just pretty much you know you
just jump right in like Aladdin's carpet
see the the the last time we were
preparing for the the milligram the
12200 milligram challenge it I was
actually pretty disappointed because I
was you know talking hell of [ __ ] on
everybody because I had been training
really hard like I was waking up every
day and just slamming a thou you know
putting a eating a th000 milligrams for
breakfast you know what I'm saying then
having another couple hundred for lunch
you know what I'm saying I was ready by
the time that happened everybody else
had been eating so many capsules too
training for the training for the
challenge that it was just like [ __ ]
wasn't going well business-wise for
anybody yeah you definitely have a very
relaxed State of Mind the one homie the
one homie in Washington who was going to
be doing it with us he broke like two
mother ship minis in a week or some [ __ ]
like that I believe the exact story was
that he knocked over his Mothership mini
bubbler while he was trying to go to
sleep and also had like a tornado of
money blowing around on on his patio or
some [ __ ] so yeah I mean that's what I'm
saying is it's not like you want to go
straight to the black diamonds at the
mountain and throw yourself down 1200 is
serious 1200 is no J we wanted to make
sure we were over a th000 um and if you
really want to get intense you try to
hit 2500 yeah that just sounds room
again so that's like that's like the gr
dab of Edibles is what we're doing
pretty much yeah yeah and well also it's
like if you if you don't smoke those are
obviously good ways to do it if you're
really trying to get you know some sort
of sedation for me it was just the fact
that like I don't have anxiety and I'm
extremely focused and let's be real if
you're trying to like never get sick you
know what I'm saying as we know cannabis
canc can cure everything pretty much so
if you eat that [ __ ] you're going to be
[ __ ] awesome that was the other
thought right is that like we figured if
we could do like 1,00 Mig for a month
there was no way that we would ever have
any pathogens cancers [ __ ] like
there's no way anything even get into us
cuz we're just super saturating our
cannaboid system in our lift noes yeah
so I need a sponsor somebody throw down
like 2 200 pills or 2500 Mill pill got
figure out how that works but I mean at
some point we'll take care of you Jeff
between between all parties in the room
I'm sure we've got we got
some we are not liable for what happens
after you hit 12 bro I don't as long as
none of them are real high CBD have I
told you guys about my CBD Adventures
Have you listened to the episode with
CBD no you guys are all extra extract
artists what do you guys call yourselves
now it's extract artist the term anymore
is there a is there a word to
use okay everyone goes silent um I
remember extract artist love that term I
don't like that term I don't know we're
not crazy about that term so you guys
are just hash guys right just you're Tex
all right so these you guys are hash
guys you know we started doing this [ __ ]
because we love it and you guys are
going to love this this is the
appropriate group I've noticed if I
smoke too much CBD I can't bust a nut
really yeah you go you go full drunk W
dick yeah well no no it works it's like
it's still [ __ ] yeah it just won't
there's no end it's birth control for
[ __ ] men yeah yeah yeah I have not
been smoking enough CB you know did you
just nut too fast just he just gets it
done he's he's done yeah I just you know
I I haven't smoked enough CBDs to really
perform that kind of research on myself
guess I went to a dispensary I had a a
chick friend who was actually on this
going to go you know smoke a bunch of
CBD and beat his dick yeah that's kind
of how it happened we went to the
dispensary and bought a bunch of CBD
medicine and we smoked out and we went
to the house and tried to [ __ ] shag
and there was no it was fun dude we're
both like yeah but like an hour of just
sweating on each other I looked at her I
was like I don't think like I don't
think just two WS walking around in the
room looking it out dude yeah nice
little W out for the day how do you
think that
smelled about as good as his story about
[ __ ] in his buddy's VW bus
yeah that did happen
we won't get into that there's another
podcast for that one I I have never
found that with CBDs but I I mean I
don't know maybe I I think it's the same
thing I don't I don't tend to to lean
towards the CBDs as much as I'm looking
for thcv tell I'm going to try it yeah
right yeah bunch of sativa go jerk off
see how long it takes wait 24 hours
smoke a bunch of CBD orb go try to whack
one out and see if it's just like 34s of
the way there I mean I mean what ratio
is this I mean this might be something
patentable it was exactly it was
actually the canonic it was like
21 CD or something yeah it was one of
those strains 21 to1 yeah something like
that bringing the opp what Happ what
happens if GW Pharma is patenting a 21
21 caregivers in Colorado
Springs yeah they G Pharma was like oh
what bad that no one will ever come
again I wonder what happens when you hit
if you hit like an 80 to1 ratio I wonder
if you just like turn into like titanium
Superman cop what I was talking to a
nerd nurse and she said I think she's a
paramedic or something and she said that
there is an electrical response in your
brain that causes a seizure and that
same electrical response in your brain
is responsible for your orgasm it's like
an electrical firing and when you smoke
CBD it turns that off that's why you
don't have a seizure well they coat that
that receptor probably you're coating
your your freaking [ __ ] receptor too it's
the same thing shutting it down dude
you're literally muting your [ __ ]
receptor you're just putting like a
cover over it so that it just can't oh
it's like get in an elevator with no
13th floor yeah
the government's going to get a hold of
that and use it for [ __ ]
overpopulation something and yeah yep
but that's just something I discovered
thought we'd share well I will tell you
if you do the I know they grow a lot of
hemp in China and they use that [ __ ] and
it ain't working over there so it is not
working give John John a microphone John
John so you're saying CBDs will actually
make you last longer yes much longer I
couldn't I couldn't come at all tell you
the truth I need to smoke more CBD some
people need to be getting on them CBDs
then yeah if you're a minute man then
get up on the CBD get up on the [ __ ]
CB dizzles yep smoke that [ __ ] let's be
honest we've all been under the minute
before Oh there's been times yeah yeah
you
know sometimes I'm proud what did you
say first one's always
easy it's about getting back up after
you fall every time warm up just take a
v girl you know you'll be good I mean I
will tell you if you do the 1200
milligram challenge you'll probably have
the same effect yeah I I've noticed that
for I don't know if I'll be able to pay
attention long enough to even care yeah
tug tug tug I want to play
Xbox you know you're getting old when
you get bored jerking off yeah [ __ ] man
this is
stupid again and again and again the
first one was easy all right uh [ __ ]
we've gotten way off course here um
always happens 420 is coming up and I've
been told that there is a Cannabis Cup
Booth well there there is some things in
the work obviously we talked earlier
about all the different brands but uh
Brands Smokey brand one of the um big
badass clothing companies that I help
work with um they've decided to kind of
do this uh Road show every year so I'll
be you know Manning up and running their
production for the Denver Cannabis Cup
coming up Seattle San Fran LA and then
we'll be doing um what is it agenda and
Magic uh AEG big Gallery we'll be doing
a like varieties of like high-end
fashion all the way down to cannabis
cups to Glass shows but um this Cannabis
Cup in Denver we will have a smokey
brand Booth that'll be a really large
island and there's probably like four or
five brands that I'm not able to say yet
that'll be in it um there will be
appearances from the turpex boys and
Apotheca and iy genetics and dudit
damsel um shout out to damel but I don't
think I don't think there's going to be
a um there's not going to be a big thing
you guys will be appearing it won't be
your boo I'm not sure if we're going to
do a booth yeah the me unfortunately is
uh we're waiting for some rules to come
out about that so for sure yeah all all
the brands that will be in our booth at
Smoky Brands though won't be licensed
cannabis Brands so we'll have all kinds
of clothing brands and glass Brands and
all kinds of different product no
smokable consumable cannabis product
they will be they will have their own
smokable consumable product but you can
as a Meed licensed business I don't
believe you're going to be able to have
anything going on there I think High
Times just canceled the medical side of
it too right yeah I'm not sure was so to
hear that yeah definitely it's hearsay
but yeah there's definitely a bunch of
different rumors going on and that's why
I'm saying it you know there's a bunch
of brands that I will say once they
announce but it won't be any of like the
state
cannabis brands that we have in Colorado
it'll be more of the you know Fashion
Glass fate pens probably different stuff
like that that'll be at the booth but
you know all of the homies and the GG F
will be there dabbing out and having a
great time homies yeah for sure great
most of the people in the room right now
all be getting down um along with you
know some suicide girls and some other
people like that hey now hey now Suicide
Girls come on # Suicide Girls oh look
who's here yes people just keep
strolling in yeah shout out to more
turpex crew shout out shout out be there
I'll be at the the Cannabis Cup Booth
I'll be at the cup Roman around so find
me guys I'll be at the uh the booth what
what's your booth called uh it's going
to be the SMY brand Booth we don't have
our location yet they haven't come out
with the map but you know as soon as you
get there if you want to grab there be
Smokey socks all over they've got a big
pot leaf as a logo Smokey socks we'll
have a bunch of clothes we'll have a
bunch of um all kinds of [ __ ] set up
there'll be obviously there'll be a VIP
inside GG fam nice Sho shoes off secret
knock time for party so yeah roster Jeff
will be up there I probably won't have
any seeds because honestly I'm going to
a I don't want to sound like a dick
there's a private party Friday night
between a bunch of seed breeders and
Traders and true bunch of invite only
and my seeds will probably be eaten up
then the only seeds he'll be giving away
are the ones he's picking up for me on
Friday
night
yeah you mean you've got a surplus of iy
seeds
somewhere there might be a couple packs
in my backpack when I start actually uh
there might be a couple in there right
now guys who knows you never know we we
definitely the dubb wise the black
cherry cam I mean are we supposed to say
the other ones that aren't oh you can
talk about yeah if I've given you
anything you can talk about them that
Tor the toror grape Snapper is that what
it is a Tora across to King Snapper
grapes uh King Kim grape Snapper OG whoa
yeah that's the one that's the mouthful
it's yeah it needs real pretty much if
you're really if you're in a new state
if you're in whatever you're trying to
do if you can find the way to get some
beans I genetics is probably a company
that you should have in your garden I
appreciate that for sure definitely yeah
I I work hard to keep stuff going I'm
actually working on the black cherry
chem F2 right now I'm actually
harvesting I did the feno hunt to find
the female that I want to breed with and
I'm harvesting them now think I chose
the right [ __ ] good I've got a purple
one if you need any if you need anybody
else to uh help you uh verify
selections I will say that you know one
of the biggest ones that we all talk
about is the Lemon Jeffrey because
that's you know the one hitter Jeffrey
Jeff well well well there arguments I've
crossed the lemon Jeffrey to the
Grateful Dog and there AR arents over
what the name is going to be I know
anybody want to throw out some yeah the
room
King give John John a mic for a second
Old King Joffrey Game of Thrones yeah
see that's what okay that's why my buddy
said that all right somebody else told
me that I didn't get the reference there
the Joffrey cha he was a real [ __ ]
King yeah well that that's me ended up
I'm a [ __ ] # spoilers they ended up
poisoning him hey
man I slung him out there spoilers do
your thing that's cool I like it
controversy on the show it's all
good there's tons of I mean I don't know
the the lemon is so prevalent it depends
like you were saying what we got we got
to taste it you know that's what I'm
thinking well it's hanging up I would
love a taste it's hanging up well I'll
let you taste it oh really hanging up
right now it's hanging up it's upside
down it's deafed it's going to get that
final Trim a couple days in a jar right
now it's looking like that 70s Bush god
dude God yes here's the question is is
it going to make some fo milk or some
Nebraska you know uh I don't [ __ ] around
and it's going to make some uh turack
shatter or some live res that's what I
was looking some Garden of Weeden live
that's what I was looking for yeah
that's all I flux with if it's not if I
I can make my own hash I don't have my
own V oven luckily I've Got Friends that
let me use their V I can make some
decent hash but uh Garden of Weeden
Shout Out Boys local they live five
minutes away from me that's my homies
they make most of my hash for me and
since nobody's had a harvest for a
minute and we are hash heads and we
smoked all our hash it's been turpex is
my second reliable yeah sh shout out to
Garden of Weeden and irie everybody
coming up from peblo that comes to the
shop we appreciate it yeah we sent a lot
of people up there we need to work out
some sort of affiliate program we need
to start getting some credit yeah we
need to figure out a hashtag for them to
use when they come in right yeah fi by J
by just start got got to get that wreck
stuff going for your spot so that's the
truth get them down there yep true well
I said on another show if you guys are
in Denver or if you're in peblo drive to
Springs and go get this hash cuz it's
worth a 45 minute drive I do it every
week I'm up here once a week usually on
a Thursday that's true I got to start
coming on Fridays cuz it's dut day bro
oh yeah that is H we do Dill Donuts
every Friday morning man D made us do it
we play hip-hop all day we have Amy's
Donuts in the lobby for all the people
that come through while they last I will
tell they go quickly I got there they
were I should I should have waited to
deliver that new drop I I delivered a
new drop of flavors over there at close
tonight I should have came right when
they open tomorrow so I could have got
first pick of them Donuts me Amy yeah
big up shout out Amy's Donuts here in
the donuts is fire they keep us laced up
with everything from that Elvis with
banana chips on it to the blueberry
icing with the rainbow stripe um all
kinds of [ __ ] got quit got a cookie
butter one they got aie cookie butter
half cookie butter half chocolate they
have cotton candies so you're on that
healthy tip but you'll eat the donuts
John John is my proof here I've only had
one dut this whole month one donut on
that healthy [ __ ] you're looking good
bro you're getting all swole not not yet
I still got bronchitis in an inhale you
guys make fun of me so yeah I usually
eat about two of them though you better
get # sad face #
fatty # I will tell you we we as a staff
we get in there early on Friday morning
cuz it's Dilla Donuts man you put on
some J dilla and you let you know
Quasimoto and doom play wolfing down
some [ __ ] sugar at 8:00 in the
morning I mean things get productive you
guys are doing cartwheels when I get in
there slam Red Bull get after it yeah
pretty much yeah stop in the shop guys
check it out it's a cool place I don't
shop I go to like three dispensaries on
the planet and this is one of them we we
appreciate all the love I mean you you
guys down there in Pueblo and especially
like you
know yeah oh that is the thing bro come
down cuz that boy be on that schoa they
got that shoa boy that schoa that good
we do have we do have some good we're
waiting for um we're waiting for our
masterfully grown crop to come in and
that'll be you know in then probably
like two months but right now we have
great flowers and everything on the
Shelf we have an unbelievable
concentrate selection sometimes we're up
to like 24 different flavors of
concentrates right now I think we're at
like 13 that Durban Poison I shouldn't
even it
dude we have Chuck Norris is gone bro it
was gone in his day yeah gone as [ __ ] we
do have the Gary buy OG on the shelf
right now though musy duck butter coming
soon duck butter what's the one that I
want to know about this name uh Drake's
hanker shief you should probably put the
Nature Boy Ric Flair on the mic cuz
that's his name that he came up with let
this actually knows what's up with the
tur get up on the top rope and let tell
me about this
[ __ ]
um dead silence you put him on the spot
and [ __ ] him up this blue dream and
white
widow it's actually based on the video
game Uncharted you see because he's
Drake is an adventurer and he has a
handkerchief and no oh the real story
this is what happened this is what
happened that got it out of him though
that got it out of him this is what
happened it was some [ __ ] it was some
flow
and it was some flow and some blue
dream cross and so we thought you know
people are gonna cry when they [ __ ]
hit this
sh and so we just said [ __ ] I mean who's
who's like cries a lot we're like Drake
[ __ ] was playing maybe on Pandora or
something and just I don't know it was
not playing on Pandora maybe I will say
I think that's the only concentrate we
will ever see that has the word
handkerchief in it yeah and the name
Drake I hope yeah you you pretty much
said what I said when I saw the drop I
was like wow really now we got to
explain what genetics Drake h is
every I like the story and you're right
because # [ __ ] Blue Dream [ __ ] blue
dream and flow and flow and flow I know
you guys out I know you guys out there
with that [ __ ] DJ shortcut and all
kinds of other [ __ ] and whatever
else and talk about that blue dream [ __ ]
let's talk about that for a second
because since moving to [ __ ] Colorado
I've seen more flow or [ __ ] that smells
or tastes exactly like [ __ ] flow than
I've seen ever in my [ __ ] life what
is up with that is that the bomb [ __ ]
out here they don't they don't like cush
they don't like per yeah where's the
cush it grows uh the dog's trying to go
outside okay it's cool I think I mean I
think a lot of it is the fact that like
that blue dream just blows up like a
balloon for people that don't know what
they're doing as yeah you could gr the
[ __ ] out blue dream uh the flow is super
easy to grow here it grows outdoors
really quickly dud trying to get laid
with your chick buy them the blue Dre
Blue Dream the the girls love the blue
my God I [ __ ] love Blue Dream yeah
and if you're if you're a mediocre
grower and you need to pull some weight
uh BL Blue Dream is for you yeah yeah if
if you've never grown weed if you've
never grown weed before and you're about
[Music]
what I think the flow the flow that goes
around here actually came from DJ Short
gave that cut to Ed Rosenthal who passed
it around to a few people out here and
my friend Tom uh had a dispensary here
and a dispensary in peblo and he spread
that out through his dispensaries a lot
and it also went through other sources
I'm not saying he put it all over for
sure but that cut I actually think is
DJ's floa and not Flo I think back in
the 1940s when they eradicated this back
in the day they should have done that to
Blue Dream definitely Blue Dream should
never exist so I crossed the blue dream
to the Greatful dog and I call it the
blue healer and uh it fixed Blue Dream
did it yeah well it made the uh made
much larger Grateful Dog nuggets and it
comes out a lot like Grateful Dog just
better harvests okay so you can't polish
a turd you can polish a turd yes now the
part that sucks is I have to keep a
mother PL of Blue Dream in the all the
time so actually we should get off of
Blue Dream and get onto some other
strains that are probably better I mean
I know that we all dislike certain stuff
what what do you got that's coming down
the pipeline I'm making a I've been
working on this F2 of black cherry Kim
um I think you see I'm gonna say a name
that I've never said on the show but I
think if I say it then nobody could
steal it from me because it'll be out
there I'm gonna hit a dead head OG plant
with black cherry Kim pollen and I want
to call it Cherry Garcia because I think
that's cool as [ __ ] copyright Cherry
Garcia I'll spell it different it'll be
cool I would I would definitely be down
to taste those turs yeah on those uh I'm
trying to find a name for that lemon
Jeffrey Grateful Dog I'm working on I
want to work for I'm looking for an
arise mail plant right now I want to
start using the arise as my breeding
staple that'll be my next boy that goes
for a long time okay it'll be like my
new stud for the next couple of years
what are the TPS like on that guy uh
it's a Golden Goat cross to daybreaker
so it's sweet cush I like the daybreaker
the daybreaker is a great plant yeah and
the anything you put to the Golden Goat
makes resin like it just resin comes out
of that [ __ ] so yeah that male will
make everything resiny and
stanky so I want to talk about something
real quick that's the new thing going on
all on the social we going to talk about
this rosin Tex what are your thoughts um
I haven't tried it
yet I have not tried it actually I have
an interview we're ahead of ourselves in
recording but I've recorded an episode
that I've left a blank spot to throw in
an interview with soil grown so that I
can learn a bit about it so hopefully in
the last episode that got tossed in
there but the interview is supposed to
happen tomorrow when I get home so this
is nice yeah this is awkward podast
TR and [ __ ] with my head trying to do
that too that's what CBD can do also
time yes yes so so hold on with the
rosin Tech that shit's been around since
like the [ __ ] 60s and the 70s just
like a lot of the other stuff it's not
necessarily going to you know they say
go ahead sorry I'm out of the lube you
want to know what it is what is it you
take your weed you put it in a piece of
parchment paper and Fold It Up you take
weed you take [ __ ] and then you hit
you either hair press it or people are
using a t-shirt press like and in the
60s and 70s that's what would happen
back in the day is they would take that
shitty weed and t-shirt press it and be
able to extract something they wouldn't
call bubble hash that would sell for
more and I know that from my time being
a cultivator in Tijuana so nice yeah uh
but that's a story for a different day
yeah we'll get on that note after the
asthma completely solventless like
there's no solvent in there not even
water so that's kind of an Tech it's
activating and expressing it as it's
heating it so you are still losing some
potency if it gets hot so
I had a hairer I'd try it right now
right yeah are you activating it though
uh it is becoming decarbed and yeah when
you're heating it cuz they're using like
100 degrees or something and I think 106
is where decarbing starts right around
there I mean I I I have nothing against
it but it doesn't really do much it I
mean it does it melts and it gets high
and all that stuff but it's not the same
tpine profile marijuana R&amp;D specialist I
think we should try it okay you should
definitely I'd love to see some locals
do it so that I could take a dab of it
and talk about it on the show there you
yeah well and there you have it
obviously
now somebody go to the beauty supply
store and pick up a hair straightener
I'm on it yeah I was at Walgreens today
and I saw like a whole [ __ ] aisle of
them and I almost they're going to be
gone in the next couple days you you
took a couple seconds and looked at them
all I really did remember when Bed Bath
and Beyond put the dab torches the
little no stick mats and uh turkey
basters all in the same area and uh
Pyrex dishes it was all in one little
they're like dab guys here you go all
set it's like a computer program they
they you know they know what people buy
at the same time and then they put it
together Yep they're gonna buy a
controller a game and a headset them all
next to each other they say it seems
like people are buying a lot of torches
and turkey bases at the same time we
should put them together damn Jew I
think that's important I'm allowed to
say that because I'm a Jew yes yes you
are Jordan you'll be okay I I'm
interested to see what happens next as
opposed to like going back into like the
r TS and all the other [ __ ] of the CO2
and all the ice water and I I got a call
from a friend today he is working on
some sort of large scale version of a
hair straightener t-shirt press
situation cuz he's like dude this shit's
dude bro bro right sure this is it man
it's been the big thing lately on the
social media it's all people want to
talk about and his page has blown up
he's got mad followers right mad mad
followers in this episode I just
randomly thought about this I put took a
note in my head uh happy birthday to to
rob the dude this episode drops right
before your birthday or yeah like right
around your birthday happy birthday Rob
Happy Birthday Happy Birthday Rob Happy
Birthday Rob yeah I hope you're
listening to this episode bro I know you
don't get a lot of time you're out there
at the bowling alley playing with your
balls here at 1015 happy birthday happy
birthday to rob the dud let's get back
to the show Rob the
dud [ __ ] awesome this has this has
been way too much fun this seon we took
some uh we took some show notes and Hunt
wrote down the phrase getting globby and
put little marks by it with or no slabby
I can't you're getting
slobby we're getting slobby we are
getting
slobby let's congregate and get
slabby I'm goingon to pass you the rig
so you can get
slobby slabby obviously it worked got
what I asked for I guess did it work I
got you I got you that was good get your
slabby over there man slab I can
actually kind of tell that story tra
them like monkeys the first time I met
Mr Hunt was at a Cannabis Cup in Denver
and he came up to me and my partner
Shane and he's like what are you guys
doing I'm like nothing he's like I think
we should congregate and get
slobby and it stuck now people all over
the world are going to say let's
congregate and get slabby that's how it
works man bless Big Ups you know drum
circle style actually kind of turned
into a joke at the it actually kind of
turned into a joke at the processing
facility too whenever you know cuz we
run stuff for 70 different centers or so
and some you know sometimes we get some
[ __ ] that just yields terribly so the
guy we're getting slob the guy whenever
whenever we run like a thousand G column
and there's just Bas you know there's
virtually nothing in there [ __ ]
homeboy you yell out from the back we
are getting
slobby and you know you know and then
you know it's yeah it's kind of like you
know when all the Hooters chicks come up
and sing Happy Birthday to you and all
the same stuff you know you got to have
the same [ __ ] going down a long time ago
I went to guitar Center and I bought a
piece of equipment called a compressor
yeah and I've never been happier that I
bought that because you did not blow out
the rest of my equipment just
now I did not know that that was even
something I had to be worried no no no
that's my job to think about and it
[ __ ] this compressor just paid for
its damn self that was awesome thank you
compressor got one you know what I'm
saying it did just doesn't let that all
that microphone get to all of here it's
limit it just compress you guys when
when you're getting slabby you do want
to get it up on like
okay slab time Sunday Sunday Sunday
we're taking slab Sports F the couch or
you can go steady globin slab fans right
right before the show gets off the rails
I'm going to do two commercials because
I actually promise everyone will do
these ads really quickly we're going to
go like this this podcast is brought to
you by hyro indor growing supplies H
grow Ender growing supplies has two
locations to serve Colorado visit the
Denver store 6271 Beach Street or check
out no did I say that right yeah I did
uh visit the PLO location 618 East 4
Street in beautiful PUO Colorado guys
when you're checking out at high grow
tell them you listen to The Grow from
your podcast guess what commercial
pricing dope boom don't forget hyro hro
indoor growing supplies there's a shop
in Denver there's a shop in Pueblo
either way you're looking at it you guys
got to drive an hour from Colorado
Springs you just got delivered [ __ ]
water bottles that's an epic podcast
shout out to John John for the water
bottle delivery shout out to shny Hey
where's mine shny my new favorite Bud
tender well we got to go to hyro
obviously right go to hyro Dude tell
my we were talking about these guys
earlier Rocky Mountain worm company the
organic portions this episode we're
brought to you by my good friends at the
Rocky Mountain worm company shout out to
Allan and Jay and Sean and everybody
over there uh visit the Rocky Mountain
worm company in Colorado Springs for
fresh worm castings African
nightcrawlers red wigglers come on let's
hear some dirty jokes all your organic
soil amendments go there go there go
there you can check them out Rocky
Mountain worm company.com or 411 Diana
Street in Colorado Springs Colorado make
sure you tell those guys you heard them
heard about them through the podcast and
and just to be on point with that on
point to Allan and the boys we were
talking about y'all before the show too
cuz I was saying that's impressive [ __ ]
that you guys got going over there no
pun intended literally good [ __ ] yeah
it's good [ __ ] over there we're JT and
the boys JT and the boys I'm not sure
what that means the lookout the Lookout
boys I got lost there but I'm just going
to forb be a blond be a blond about it I
got a dab on the Dabber here um what
else you guys get slabby we went over
all your notes I went I'm ready to let
it get a little bit looser it's why I
read the commercials oh [ __ ] yeah that's
what I'm saying these guys have been
sitting over here like little kids
behaving them behaving themselves we got
uh two four five grown men in the room
plus a guy that snuck away cuz he's too
shy for the podcast and a guitar you can
play some guitar dude guitar yeah let's
get the guitar back going I think it's
probably maybe it's time for another
song I don't know I song will I take a
dab let's let's talk for another few
seconds I'm going to take a dab uh with
you and then we'll break into song Break
you guys can take a dab together I'll um
just like Joey P man I think I think
this is probably time to you know give a
little shout out to Dr Pepper for all
the sponsoring that they do for us also
[ __ ] dude [ __ ] that I had to pay for
this bottle don't shout they're not at
all talk about
they don't get a shout out on here but
obviously we need the um we need to give
a little bit of a talk about you know
the stiiven and wherewithal of everybody
absolutely because uh sometimes out
there we're noticing that some of you
wooks are slacking slipping on your
pimping as they say yeah okay so I'm
going got to keep your pimp strong I'm
going go like this on you no ashy pimp
pans right yeah you don't if you're
going to bring an ashy pimp pan for the
low down lowball price you better make
sure that [ __ ] is
Frosty okay so back to it we're going to
get into this we're going to get in
I say half the time Hunt's saying [ __ ]
yep whatever the [ __ ] that means this is
going to be a long episode you guys just
[ __ ] hang in there we're going to
touch we're going to touch on this wook
Chic stuff that i' be seeing around all
these them dudes with like 35 hat pins
home boys that don't have no girls but
drive a rental car and have slabs I was
going to say you got got seven mother
ships in a coil rig but you got 82 Honda
you still you still up in Mama's
basement asking for bacon every morning
but you got like 35 [ __ ] rigs in the
basement that you kick it on and like
you get on the forarms and get down
[ __ ] mad pendes with with [ __ ]
Opals and yeah and I'm not and I'm you
know hey and I'll get down with you like
I'm not harshing I'm not trying to harsh
anybody's mellow on the west coast of
the East Coast or any [ __ ] if you
want to get down on the [ __ ]
pendy Rigs and you want to wear all that
crap it's cool I'm just saying that when
you become a grown ass man and you want
to get grown ass man [ __ ] you got to
put that [ __ ] in a box and move it to
the left like Beyonce that's all I'm
trying to say dude whatever the [ __ ]
that means dab with me bro dab with me
bro oh we're we're we're dabbing to
Cheers
shout out Joey P if you haven't heard of
him look him up hash man [ __ ]
dope yep definitely these guys are
getting down they're doing like the
whole wedding Cross Your Arms together
and take each other's [ __ ] dab it's
cute yeah they're getting slobby I think
that's illegal at Springs you don't be
jealous bro don't be jealous peanut
butter and jealous over there are you
yeah peanut butter and jalous I'm
getting all a jelly
monster straight up Cooks all up in your
tur baby that's how it goes though this
has been one of my favorite episodes to
record and I hate to say that to all my
homies back at home that record with me
but you guys brought something to the
table that hasn't been brought to the
table for for a while there's definitely
a weird thing in this house um I'm
actually sitting next to my business
partner and my father as well as my
friend um
yeah [ __ ] just got weird I'm confused
I'm looking around the room there's
nobody here old enough to be your father
so unless there's an n in the the room
that doesn't make any sense I'm talking
about Jordan he's my he's my father oh
that your father yeah I've been
nicknamed dad you know by pretty much
everybody in the so are you like the are
you the turpex king basically are you
the king say the king but I would say
the you know fatherly figure you know
the Godfather no that's Little Anthony
junor Jr from Brooklyn that comes in
every now you know more like you know
the the guy who you call when you you
know your your battery is dead you need
your car jumps and you need your car
jumps Fountain that's not me you know
what I mean I'm the good I'm the good
son I'm the good son I I would imagine
no but you're the good son but I've also
a mic also had I can't hear him at all
without the mic I've also had to you
know sit there and have discussions
umol about birth control yeah you know
that got shouted out from the other
[ __ ] room by the way he's like the
Brian Epstein of turpex # Beatles
reference yes yes I'm not sure yeah okay
it's all right he was the manager The
Beatles and then once he died they all
fell apart and blamed it on Yoko yeah uh
does the dude other room want to be on
the show at all any desire I doubt it
doubt it he's getting down on some turbs
over there but I would say I mean
hopefully I mean I was trying to put
together a star studded cast for this so
we could get a repe performance oh you
guys will be back bro like [ __ ] we made
it dude shout out to hunt for helping me
carry my gear because this [ __ ] was too
heavy I couldn't get it out of the car
by
myself anytime you need production or
you need me to line up some Talent bro
you just give me a call that's what we
do what kind of talent you got bro who
do you need whatever you sh out name and
I'll try to make a gather get them all
here let's get them they don't call him
The Gatherer for nothing we need to get
uh we need to get Addy back on the show
he was on episode number two I sucked at
podcasting he'll be in town for the
Cannabis Cup uh shout out to the guy
that doesn't want to come in the room
he's he's still getting some love told
he told me one time he's like no I don't
want to do that like I could tell he was
like nope I want to be in the backgr
he's about 17 dabs in relaxing after
being under lights all day yeah so shout
out he deserves the time bro we're going
to get serious for half a second we were
talking today at the shop about being
under high-intensity discharge lights oh
yeah for sure definitely um hunt taught
me something I never thought about guys
cover your skin up in The Grow rooms if
you're if you're in your own personal
grow you're probably all right but if
you're in like a room with like 20 or 30
or 40 or like I work with there's 120
lights in some of the places uh cover
your skin up cover the top of your head
wear some glasses definitely people are
getting melanoma people are seeing weird
[ __ ] on their heads are getting like
signs of sunburn their hair is falling
out and [ __ ] uh you're going to go blind
in there get some good glasses uh I
didn't even think of that I only think
about the glasses uh cover up your skin
cover your hands no for sure yeah it's
definitely um you got to think about
exposure sunscreen is that work I don't
know if it's maybe that's a really good
question I'm not I don't I'm not a
dermatologist or a sunscreen producer so
I don't know or a scientist yeah just
guys AR scientist I just play one on the
internet yeah it's um it's definitely
something that's been talked about here
there you know obviously it's the
exposure rate that you're in you know if
you're in a grow room for six to eight
hours a day um it's definitely great you
know it's great to cover I have tattoos
so that's why I choose that's that's why
I choose to use um I use long sleeves
and hats and glasses and all that stuff
because then my ink doesn't fade and I
don't have to worry about all the other
stuff but I have heard some from some of
my homies that are in um the Cali ear in
Asel they get down you know solid dude
if you guys are tatted up if you're
tatted up if you're those sexy tattoo
models sick tats bro damn he is tatted
up just tatt it up sh up I'm solid his
pwes are a lot of manmat for he's got
where his pubes should be there's a
tattoo for Thursday night it's a tattoo
of pubes but you can see the difference
though I can see the difference in your
arm tattoos and your body tattoos like
from having a shirt and where you're
exposed like the dude's tatted guys and
you can I I know what you have to go
through at the me to be an owner of a
dispensary and I can only imagine they
documented he saw there was a whole a
whole page of your
tattoos because I've seen other stories
of like they did each leg tto I was
actually like do you think you should
formal formalize this or you know and he
was like No just writing it on piece of
paper man it's good enough yeah I was
like I'm not really trying to I mean
they as they asked for all of your your
tattoos and what they are and all that
kind of stuff but yeah I mean I
literally had to sit down and figure it
all out so I just went by body part and
I just told him all the body parts that
were tattooed which is pretty much
everyone other than you know a couple
ass cheeks I got a $100 bill on my dick
cuz I like to play with my money oh guys
if you want to find out if that's true
come to the Cannabis Grand crew in
aspect this November hash weener
tattoo no no no oh actually I can to
that the the next cannabis Grand crew is
May 30th in Seattle Washington cannabis
Grand crew.com if you want to check it
out and come party yes I can't make that
one I'm sorry that's Washington I can't
cap 500 people and it's um it's going to
be a great panel people unless uh the
Grammy Gatsby is paying for that [ __ ]
you know I'm flying yeah yeah you know
if I'm flying 2500 milligram yeah dude
well I'd rather go to the crew so you
know you fly me out there and give me a
hotel room and we'll go I need to get
sponsored on that 2500 milligrams too
see I'll donate my 25 over there and
then I'll just go out there to Seattle
see I'm getting worked over on the show
by I don't even know what's happening
right on for inviting me
nice hasham fam fam is fam Grammy gats
all day long all right so I hear a
guitar just went Brink and we promised a
song after a dab what happened the bread
song going to come out today is this the
first Global release of the bread song
we've been going for an hour so did this
one on Call of Duty for like an hour
doesn't count doesn't count n there some
people heard it there's some 12y olds on
Call of Duty that got got the brn of
that one live stream yeah really but I
mean we haven't practiced it in a while
we can we can try to lay something down
but I probably got muted like 5 seconds
into it so maybe that's why I quit using
I don't even play anymore because it's
just everyone trolling everyone yeah I
play We wer even playing I was just
singing yeah oh actually you know what
else before you get into the song though
I mean you guys you guys did like a nice
little pretty facelift over at turbex
with the logo on the website coming and
yes we did we did um that actually just
got to me today and uh changed it on in
stagram so check that out and yeah I
think it's definitely a lot better and I
guess the the website's going to have
all the places where we sell turpex
right yeah I was going to ask if there
was a bunch of places you guys knew of
where folks can get it but it's only
medical so I didn't want to tease all
the out of Staters yeah I'll still tease
all out of homeboy sitting here might as
well just say green and healthy wellness
yeah go there go there I was there for
they're in the room I hung out for what
literally I hung up for somewhere
between an hour 30 and 40 minutes maybe
an hour today and uh half the customers
that showed up or recreational people
hoping to shop and you had to turn them
away and that sucks we hope got pass
that [ __ ] yeah you know if you are in
Colorado Springs you know we would
really appreciate it if you have the
chance you know tell the people that you
can about the shop also if you feel like
it um and you're in support of the
Cannabis movement you know obviously
tell your local representative what's
going on because we don't have any wreck
cannabis other than you know Denver and
some other places like that so yeah or
just get your card for Now sucks but
that's or just if you need wreck go
drive down to peblo and see Mr Jeff go
down to the spot come on down to the SP
I want to try something come on down oh
we're trying new stuff sports fans
getting slabby getting slabby oh it
didn't work see I thought
it
slabby yeah I thought I'd get a chorus
of monkeys but taking a
slabby wanted to try that I just want to
that's why you opened up the paper was
to drop the getting I didn't want to say
getting globby again on accident I
wanted to slaby I will I will tell you
if you're in the right situation in an
event and you yell out getting slabby
you will find out where the tpy crew is
yes you will happens to me often now
that shit's going to happen you'll be at
the cup and some random kid from [ __ ]
Noel Nebraska is going to get
slabber that's one of my homies in
distress and you guys will go run and
just be some kid with 45 hat pins and a
Mothership rig walking around knock off
Mother Ship knock off mother knock off
Mother Ship what's with the mothership
hype anyway I don't know but I just I
just sold mine for three you know almost
three times what I paid for it back in
2012 so I was pretty happy about that
the the hype is the fact that they're
hard to get and a lot of the people that
are seen as you know the top OG triple
OG OG of to be heady bro you got to have
a Mothership dude all right that's kind
of this rig hits pretty well and it was
not it didn't cost my car I've hit that
thing numerous times and I like it yeah
you look you had to use your inhaler
sweetheart yeah bring it back over here
bring that [ __ ] back over here F and
drip I I just I just sold I just sold my
mother ship for 10 months
rent son yeah damn yeah that was like a
pair of Jordans you know was all that
that little rig was cuz I bought this
one them 11 breads from the blower
instead of uh instead of getting it from
some random distributor mad Rob shout
out mad Rob again shout out 719 719
719 coming at you Garden of the Gods
this is not my shatter it was passed to
me and I was told here hit this so
there's that and there's carb cap
that'll make it all work shout out to
task Highly Educated titanium task Rock
man making Highly Educated titanium
number one in the
biz you know that's good sorry about all
the verbal diarrhea over here that's not
my ash but I'd love to see you glob that
yeah you he's going to do a I'm not
taking you to the Y tonight I already
told you man we have to get you an
oxygen tank along with that [ __ ]
inhaler be Mr burnson all the way down
the hallway with that [ __ ] does anybody
know CPU are in this room I got my
inhaler I was certified like four years
ago it's probably hadn't changed that
much no just stomp on that middle part
of his chest until he breathes again
it's to be grandpa is CPR be like I need
that Bad Moon Rising and that c isn't
that CPR no no different band oh that's
CCR band yeah CC that's CC that was that
was good though was a nice try I can't
believe you actually grabbed the
microphone for that cuz I had it I was
ready yeah we do I do need to say this
though I love I love kicking it with
Jeff because he goes to comedy shows he
has awesome sense of humor but the
homeboy's timing is impeccable with most
of his [ __ ] when he's dropping it well
thank you thank you the take out your
retainer bit I wish we were recording
for that great he was about to take a
little hit of it his was albuterol cuz
he was choking he was wheezing asked him
if you had to pull out his inhaler to
hit
it or pull out his retainer sorry I'm
high yeah that was a psych out like
basball right there little [ __ ] it's
good when I'm on it but when I'm not boy
it's sloppy you're off right after I
gave you a compliment about
timing globu all getting
globby that rescues it all right there
don't forget when you're out there by
yourself and you don't know what to do
it's it's temp temps down TPS up temps
down TPS up get slabby let that nail
cool down a little bit drop that nail
drop that dab on the nail drop that nut
on it put drop your nuts on there try it
out and then put them in a pathana and
then put those in apothec and that's how
you know the nails right APO and then
you put the dab on there and you get a
little pube taste and a little turpex
yeah it's delish yeah it's like no melt
mixed with
turpex no no ball Nevada no
no ball sac turps sack turps W TPS
purple cush purple cush told you I the
first one told you I was going it's
verbal diarrhea I'm telling you it's a
symptom time to CU the guitar guar I
think we've had enough dabs that it's
probably bread song yeah I've smoked
more in this hour sitting here talking
to you guys than I have in the grow from
your heart podcast happens we dab it out
usually my dabs uh somebody has got to
Hoist the microphone in front of the
guitar so that we can get some audio you
remember this one pop unless somebody's
got a uh you know it son if you got a
quarter inch cable I could jack you
straight in I
do we
could it's getting the odd the seexual
in here jacking him straight in we'll
just we'll just mic you up I don't know
where it is just mic him up we I turn up
the G and Mike you up little Johnny with
the Banger Johnny
Johnny you didn't do it hash super puns
this has been a a TP tasting
episode so before we hazy up in this
room now before we get out of control
with music I'm really going to thank you
guys like truly before we get all
ridiculous dude [ __ ] thanks this was
awesome this is one of my better
episodes we're going to get a lot of
listen this is a great show it's been
fun I try to create this it's hard to
get this fun vibe on the show we get
everyone too high and with this many
people is super exciting I don't I mean
being high or whatever I just had a
[ __ ] dope time kicking it if you ever
want to come back over to the [ __ ] T
turp trap house to get down we're here
I'm going to leave the gear and we'll
just record again tomorrow oh okay
Jordan by me fine are you ready to jam
I'm ready son Paul's a big fat
[Music]
[ __ ] where you keeping all the
briad did you hear what I
said start over start over take it from
the top take it from the top hash
[Music]
restart try try not to make me laugh
guys all right serious this is
serious pause for the slab pause for the
slab hash slab it and daing you guys
good good wait that by far the hardest
I've laughed in a [ __ ] long time on
that one when you went in did you hear
what I said I just snot it out my nose
and my [ __ ]
[Laughter]
mustache this is going to be a fun one
all right where you keeping all the
bread by JT and the boys
[Music]
where you keeping all the
bread did you hear what I said where are
you keeping on my [ __ ]
bread hey did you hear what I said I'm
looking for that [ __ ] bread
I got bread yeah he's got bread not the
kind that you eat but the kind that you
smoke I just want some
bread did you hear what I said I just
want that [ __ ] bread I want
bread he wants
bread you didn't even listen to a
[ __ ] word I said I won't breing
where are you keeping all the bread
where you keeping all the
bread where you keeping all the
bread keeping all the bread what I
say did you even hear a single [ __ ]
word I said I won't
breay where you keeping all the bread
where you keeping all the bread man I
want that bread
[Music]
that that literally was straight off the
World Police
soundtrack that was one of the best
things I [ __ ] heard turned my
microphone off cuz I was laughing so
hard I was snorting into the [ __ ] mic
told that first one you hit I [ __ ]
blew it all over my mustache that one
was good I was [ __ ] crying dude
Nature Boy Ric Flair was over here
holding his tears
in at least someone kept their tears in
should we make a song about the podcast
right now yeah just like a song about
freestyles yeah Frey just like off the
cuff you're intro songs you want to talk
about dabbing or is it going to be about
it's going to be about everybody should
be about from your heart I might sing
about you I might read a little bit of a
script it's got to be grow from the
heart I'm just gonna I'm just gonna be
able to back you up man and play the
strings that's good man yeah let me uh
shout out to Dan on the stream you play
for a minute I'll read a couple things
to end up the show and then you guys
could just sing us on the way out guys
everybody thanks for listening cuz it
was [ __ ] fun these guys are going to
play a little bit of a music thing and
then I'm going to talk over it and then
we'll let them finish it out I just I
just want to say thanks for everybody
listening also if you ever come to any
one of our companies or our stores we
all have this much fun every day every
day all day I just want to say thanks
for yeah when you show up gives you a
hug and tells you he loves you when he
comes to the sh to the shop we love you
to awesome that that's one thing I can
definitely say we are all incredibly
fortunate to be doing something that we
love every day and we try to have as
much fun as possible every day and that
is pretty [ __ ] awesome thanks Jeff
for having us out [ __ ] really super
awesome podcast thank you oh man thanks
for playing guitar good time come visit
us we' love to see you yes uh visit John
visit John John tip tip the John's AKA
AKA nug tendo with two G's on Instagram
is our man John randles Jr y Johnny
Rand
J The Crowd Goes Crazy play some guitar
bro play some
guitar all right what's your Instagram
so everyone can find you Grammy Gatsby
what's your Instagram bro erore Jeter
Eric E r i
k I'm John John at nendo
2gs I'm I'm droppy hash mik drop sorry I
can't I can't play and talk at the same
time I got at turpex Co I don't have a
personal one that's cool it's we'll
follow jpex Co same same deal for me
cool cool uh I genetics follow all of us
so uh now uh yeah thanks for listening
to the show I'll be back in a couple of
more days with another podcast I'm going
to talk about a Bashi bucket if you guys
aren't down with the bokashi bucket
you'll figure it out I've got an email
from a listener about ladybugs we'll
talk about that don't forget to check
out our sponsors Rocky Mountain worm
company and hyro indoor growing supplies
uh if you're interested in sponsoring
the podcast or if you have a product
you'd like me to review or some edibles
you'd like me to sample for you uh send
me an email it's grow fromy yourart
hotmail.com I'll get you all the info
you need uh if you have something you
want to say on social media you can hit
me up it's gfyh podcast I had to think
about that I forgot it uh find me on
Facebook don't forget every show show is
available on iTunes Stitcher and iy
genetics color.com dude the donation
button I added a donation button to the
podcast page on iy genetics color.com
people have been donating money I
appreciate that so much I promised I
would go to a specific cause it's going
to that cause that will end in May and
then after that I'll figure out a new
cause for that but I [ __ ] appreciate
that from the bottom of my heart thanks
for throwing down um yeah uh follow I
genetics on Instagram super huge shout
out to my ninja spins until uh next time
you guys take a fat dab and give your
mom a hug for me here goes a song from
our friends with the turpex
crew we're growing from our hearts we're
growing from our
hearts we're going to start that one
from the top again do it however you
want I love
it growing from our hearts we're growing
from our
hearts got I je With That Big W
dick taking dab videos like a dab
chick then we
[Music]
go yeah
yeah grow from your heart we've got
crimey
Gatsby what the [ __ ] is he saying half
the
time I don't
know that's why we're run a podcast show
and not the
radio hash # hey
hey [ __ ] then we got the turpex
crew we are crazy singing these songs
for you sing somebody want to take a
selfie with
me
selfelf we are growing from our heart
got the best podcast in Colorado Springs
Colorado Springs getting slabby don't
forget get
weblo that's a
place that's about an hour from here and
I'm kind of scared to go
[Music]
there because I'm unfamiliar with it but
I'm going to go there soon to check out
Rost Jeff's new Rex
spot [ __ ] yeah going to go by and out
that lemon Jeffy pot it's grown from
[Music]
his you know that it's grown from his
heart grown from his
heart going to switch it
up it up got to grow from your
heart yeah toow shout out to choir
School your home got to grow from your
home heart