welcome back
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rasta jeff and it's time for
episode 591
of the grow from your heart podcast you
know i like to start this show off by
talking about what i'm smoking
today i've been taking dabs of bounce
live batter
this is a blend of headbanger and secret
cush mints
on the package the flavor is described
as sour gas
and pine we've talked about this
concentrate on the podcast before
i'm a big fan of the sour gassy pine
flavors and aromas
i also think those flavors and aromas
are always accompanied by a really nice
buzz on the back of the package it says
it contains 68.17 percent thc
and non-detectable amounts of cbd so big
shout out to the bounce
live batter in this episode i'm going to
do a couple of updates from a previous
episode
i'm also going to read a couple of
patreon questions before we get there
let's do a few shout outs
to a few members of the 710 club of
course the 710 club are the folks who
support us on patreon at the 7
and 10 cent a month level or higher so
with no further ado let's start off with
the big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out to my friend karen
crawford
let's follow that up with a big thank
you shout out to 716 vibes
i want to send a thank you shout out to
grow man stan let's send a thank you
shout out to dr
dendro i've always got a big special
thank you shout out for a fellow
podcaster let's send a thank you shout
out to max scrim and ruby
i want to send a thank you shout out to
josiah w let's send a big thank you
shout out to pack northwest
dan i want to send a thank you shout out
to smokeyj1360
let's send a big thank you shout out to
our fellow cannabis friends oh so jay
and last but certainly not least let's
send a big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out to my buddy tonto
big thank you and big shout out to
everybody who supports the show on
patreon
if you're not already supporting the
show and you'd like to learn how to do
so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need
will be right there on the screen and of
course i did include a link in the show
notes
and in the video description to make it
nice and easy for
all of my friends all right speaking of
thank you
i want to send a big thank you to
everybody who supported us on the black
friday sale that's right if you
supported ire genetics in the irie
genetics web store
thank you i had everything on sale for
uh 20 off and you guys took
great advantage of that sale so thank
you also shout out to everybody who took
advantage of the sales
at seedshearnow.com and at the other
vendors
i had a record week at seedshearnow.com
so thank you for all of that support i
do appreciate it
speaking of support i encourage you to
sign up for the
newsletter at iregenetics.com that's
right i've got an updated website
on that updated website there is a spot
where you can sign up for a newsletter
if you go to iregenetics.com sign up for
the newsletter
you will get a message every time i do a
sale
at seedshearnow.com or one of the other
vendors you'll also get a message every
time i do a sale in the etsy store
i'll try to send you a message every
time i add new merchandise to the etsy
store
i will do my best to keep you updated
with the new mailing list
i do also apologize for the old mailing
list at which i failed
miserably i asked a bunch of people to
email me at a certain email address
and i said that i would add add you to
the emailing list
unfortunately google thought that that
was a big spam list and it would never
work for me i couldn't figure it out
and i failed so i apologize but the new
mailing list does go through mailchimp
and it works beautifully
so i encourage you and i invite you to
sign up for the newsletter
that way you don't miss any of the sales
any of the events you can stay up to
date with all things
grow from your heart podcast all things
i read genetics
all things ross to jeff at
iriegenetics.com
all right this is the part of the show
where we where we work our way into
patreon messages
in a previous episode i talked about
changing our timer for daylight savings
time and i asked for feedback
i got a couple of great messages i chose
three of them for today's episode
this one goes just like this it says hey
ross to jeff
when it comes to daylight savings time i
personally change my life and my
schedule
and continue on with the regular 12 12.
then once my flowering plants have
finished
i change the cycle back to my preferred
time
years ago i would change the timer and
the night hours
i would extend the dark period for one
hour that day
or night before to compensate for
daylight savings time
now it just feels better for me to allow
them to continue
as scheduled and change my routine for
them yes that is probably the way to go
it goes on to say the last thing these
plants need is more stress
humans care about daylight savings time
plants most likely think it is
ridiculous that is absolutely right
uh time is a human construct time is an
invention time is imaginary
um i always say that but then think
about payday if i don't pay you for your
time you're gonna be [ __ ] about time
but
time is imaginary time is made up the
plants don't care what the clock says
the plants are worried about did the sun
come up and did the sun go down
that's how they know what time it was
that is all they are worried about so
you were absolutely correct the last
thing they need is more uh
stress and yes we did invent time that
is a human construct so you are right
the plants probably think that daylight
savings time is
ridiculous i want to send a special
thank you shout out to our buddy jh
thank you for listening and thank you
for sending me an update
about your daylight savings time i got
another message right in front of me
it comes from our friend michael s and
it says i just let it ride
i set up my light cycle with daylight
savings time in mind so here's a person
that is planning and thinking ahead
it says even with the hour time change i
can still get in there
before i leave in the morning before the
lights go out and it's back on when i
get home from work
much love rasta jeff and thank you for
everything
you do so he said that the lights are on
uh they're they you can get in there and
work on them before you leave for work
and it's back on when you get home from
work
dude are you gone for 12 hours at work
that's a long day
i understand that you might be a grower
you might be growing at work also
big shout out to our buddy michael s for
also
adjusting to the plants and keeping the
plants happy i see a theme happening
here in these messages
i do have one more message this one came
from el herbalog
and it says hey rosta jeff i adjust my
life and my growth schedule for the
benefit of my plants
i see a trend here you guys three out of
three all these people adjust their
lives
to the schedule of the plants they don't
adjust their plants to the schedule of
their lives
kind of shows the passion in these
growers it says i admit that i forgot
about daylight savings time but i
changed my dam alarm to wake up an hour
earlier
great podcast great content i appreciate
the positive vibe
keep it ivory brother from el herba log
i think that's how you say that lerby
log l herbalog
either way thank you for the great
message thank you for the update and i
will keep
up the positive vibe and the great
content and i will for sure
keep it irie thank you to our buddy erba
log
and big shout out to everybody who sent
me a message i know i only read three of
them on today's podcast
but i saw a theme everybody is adjusting
their life
to the plants not adjusting the plants
to their lives so
that shows some dedication and some
commitment to our gardens
all right let's work our way into some
fresh content here
this is a question that comes from our
friend flavormaker a longtime listener a
longtime supporter
what up flavor maker i hope you're well
bro thank you for the great content
this question goes i've got a grow
question
i've got an led i've got a t5 led
2 bar sunblaze light so this is a it's
an
led t5 light which sounds like uh it's a
combo light
it's an led a t5 led bulb and a
sun blaze two bar fixture so there are
two of these
led t5 bulbs and a sun blaze fixture
it's a lot of words for just one light
it goes on to say
and germination week one to two how high
overhead do people average so the
question here
is how high above the plants in weeks
one and two
would i hang my t5 led
two bar sun blaze light it says are
bleaching and burning
issues will there be recovery did i
alter the outcome by stressing them at
birth
then it says i definitely see variations
among three different breeders
i feel embarrassed asking this but we
all get better on micro topics like this
never be embarrassed to ask a question
that's what i'm here for i've probably
made the mistake that i can prevent you
from making i've probably seen somebody
make the mistake that you're about to
make
so never be afraid to ask a question uh
the stupidest question is the one you
didn't ask and then that mistake you
made was a stupid mistake because you
didn't ask the stupid question
let me get myself back on track those
dabs are working you guys
uh it says i learn uh the smallest
changes can have huge adverse outcomes
that is very true in cannabis
and something you do today you're not
gonna see the outcome for seven to ten
days
and then you don't get to actually see
the real outcome for maybe nine weeks
so yes small things uh do have huge
outcomes it says from soil density
light and environmental all things have
a huge effect anyway feel free to share
or just help with the question above
thanks man
well i'm doing both i'm going to share
and i'm going to help you with your
question
i didn't know much about the t5 led
sunblaze lighting i actually had to do
some research on that i'm not familiar
with that product
everything i read and everything that
makes sense to me says to keep that
light
between 12 and 24 inches above your
canopy
a lot of the things said 18 inches is
ideal
some things said 12 some said go as high
as 24
so between 12 and 24 seems ideal about
18 inches makes sense to me
what i would do put your bot your light
18 to 24 inches above your plant i'm
guessing that's about here from the
table
18 or 24 inches above the plant you want
this so give yourself a couple inches
for the plant you got to raise that up
okay 18 to 24 inches above the plant pay
attention to that plant
does the plant look like it wants more
light is it lifting up
if the leaves go up if they're praying
it may want more light
if the leaves start curling and going
down it may be getting too much light
if the leaves get droopy it has had
enough light and it wants a little bit
of a break
you could probably raise that light up
and give it a little bit
less ppfd a little bit less humiles
per joule wouldn't be a bad idea for
that plant so
the main the main thing you have to do
is watch the plant
put that light above the plant watch how
the plant responds
put your hand right above the plant just
touch the top of the plant leave your
hand there
does it feel like your hand is getting a
burn does it feel uncomfortable does it
feel like a sunburn
if your hand doesn't want to stay there
either does the plant
if you can leave your hand there and be
like yeah that's fine the plant will
probably agree with you
you have to watch the plant though over
time that plant may say
hey i've had enough of that light you
may want to raise that light or turn it
down or i'm going to react to you
the first thing it will do the leaves
will start to kind of claw down
they'll just kind of just instead of
being nice and turgid and they have that
almost a taco almost a canoe when
they're just right
they'll start to droop just a little bit
and then if you give them too much light
they'll droop even they'll claw a little
bit and if you give them too much light
they'll droop
so they'll claw down and then they will
droop that is saying hey i've had way
too much light i'm having issues
one of the most obvious signs you may
see is leaf twisting but that is a sign
of way too much light way too intense
which i don't think you'll get from
these little two bars
so my advice to you is to start about 24
inches
above the canopy slowly raise it down to
about 18 inches
and pay attention to the plants as they
get bigger as they get more stout
they'll be able to photosynthesize more
they'll want and they'll be able to take
more light so just lower that light down
don't go past 12 inches from everything
i read because that is when you will
experience the next thing you talked
about
burning and bleaching uh these led
lights do have the potential to burn
and bleach our plants if we get them too
close so
keep that 12 inch distance at least
focus a little bit higher while the
plants are smaller
and i think that will keep you safe
unfortunately i have not used these
specific lights
most of what i talk about on the show is
first hand experience i had to research
this
so i'm giving you second-hand advice
uh using logic and uh research
that's all i've got for you on that
let's keep going there's more
it says anyway oh i think i wrapped it
up feel free to use this
or just help with the questions above i
hope i answered your question
uh 18 to 24 inches i would start about
24 work it down to 18.
don't go closer than those 12 inches
because on my research
that is where we start getting the
burning the bleaching
and the issues all right flavor maker i
want to thank you for the great question
let me know how your plants are looking
if you've got a follow-up let me know i
want to know how high above that canopy
you've got the plants
and how it's working for you again the
plants are the boss if the plants are
responding negatively
raise or lower that [ __ ] light i
could be wrong we could be wrong
that plant could be an anomaly adjust to
the plants i love
meters i love gauges i love toys i love
advice i love all that stuff but the
main
thing about this is watching the plants
we are in a relationship with the plants
the only way you're going to make a
relationship work is by watching the
thing you're in a relationship with
and adjusting to that you can message me
and say hey what would i do
and i could give you advice and tell you
what to do but you have to watch how the
plant responds to that and if i'm wrong
i could be wrong that plant may want
something different you've got to pay
attention to the plants the meters may
say
put it when you get a meter when you get
equipment they're always recommended
ranges all the growers myself the
podcast
the internet we've all got recommended
ranges your plant may say
[ __ ] your recommended range i'm a weirdo
i want a ph of 9. the plant's not ever
going to want a ph of 9 but maybe
there's one plant out there that thrives
one cannabis plant that wants that ph of
9. we've got to give it that
who cares what the meters say who cares
what the internet says
that plant wants something weird i'm a
weird dude i like to eat and drink
random [ __ ] that most people probably
wouldn't enjoy drink a gang of kombucha
most people would say i don't want that
much kombucha i do
i'm an anomaly i would be happy with it
so maybe your plants are weirdos maybe
they're anomalies just like me
maybe you got to feed them a little bit
differently adjust them a little bit
differently
always pay attention to the plants i've
rambled long enough about that
let's get into a new email this one says
yo ross to jeff how are you
i heard you mention it one time to
increase the lights on time
toward the end of the flowering phase so
increase the lights on times
how i should have read that increase the
lights on time toward the end of the
flowering phase
if you don't mind me asking could you
please give me another rundown on that
i'm in the last stages of flowering and
i want to try this
thank you so much for all of your
knowledge i'm such a better grower
thanks to you that means a lot to me i'm
glad you're a better grower
from listening to me that means you took
my advice and you actually used it
so shout out to you as well i'm glad
you're improving and i'm glad you're
seeing improvement
it says i'm growing a rise for the third
run and i look forward to purchasing
more
i haven't been smoking for eight months
now because i've been on probation oh
man
um i want to see pictures of your arise
and i can't wait to smoke with you when
you're off of probation
it says that's about to end now and i'll
be able to smoke all of the aries i've
been drawing and
curing oh man i'm excited for that for
you this one came from our friend reggae
in my head
and he signed it with love and respect
uh that is a great email i'm going to
talk about this but let me
read another one because i had two
people send me basically the same
question
and i'm going to cover the one answer
with both of the both of these emails
with one answer
it says ross to jeff thanks for the grow
knowledge and the positive vibes
i'm starting week eight of flower in
prohibition land the trikes are starting
to become cloudy
on the dude grow show they mention
flipping back to 1806
from 1212 during the last week of flower
they say it will increase terps smell
and taste does
this work then they list a little bit
about their growth setup
it says i've been i have a weaker light
and it seems i'm about a week behind on
flowering compared to the recommended
eight weeks
when a breeder recommends eight weeks
they always mean nine weeks eight weeks
is a good selling point
always expect nine weeks it goes on to
say
the trikes are telling me they have
about a week to go so i thought about
going to the 18-6 like
schedule what are your thoughts i also
plan to reveg
this is why i wanted to add this one it
says i also wanted to
re-veg a few smaller branches and take
clones after harvest
will the 18-6 schedule have a negative
effect on the clones
uh thanks dude peace love and good
health
i don't know if they want their name
said but uh shout out to our friend zach
uh so that's a great question we've got
two messages about basically the same
thing
with a couple of different details so
let's talk about this
a little bit what am i talking about
when i say turn the timer back on to 18
six at the end of flower that sounds
completely absurd we've had these plants
on 12 12
for eight or nine weeks at this point
and i'm saying turn the timer back
to 18 hours on and six hours off
for the last seven to ten days of flower
now why would i want to do that to our
plants that is crazy right
let's think about what makes our plants
grow what makes our plants grow the main
thing that makes our plants happen the
main source of energy is
light they want that photon energy they
want to photosynthesize
we give them light they use that light
for life
energy so i think by turning the lights
on
for the last seven to ten days of flower
we give them more light energy i feel
like the plants beef up
they get bulkier they get more dense
they
kind of ripen up a little bit better and
also i think the harvest weight is
heavier you're giving them more light
hours per day you're giving them six
more hours per day
for seven to ten days that's up to 60
more hours of light time
i see a lot of growth at the end of the
light cycle a lot of the plants we grow
bulk up right at the end i say don't cut
these too early
because that last two weeks is when it
really packs on the weight
so if we turn that light cycle onto 18 6
during that same bulking period
they get a lot of light energy and
they're able to beef up now people are
going to say
aren't they going to something's going
to go wrong they're going to re-veg or
they're going to start to have problems
no
they're not because in 7 to 10 days
we're going to cut them down
we're going to start flushing the same
time that we do this light change
start flushing change the light back to
18 6
and pay close attention to the trichomes
and pay attention to the top buds of the
plants
the minute you see new nubby weird
growth coming out of there
harvest that is your first sign of reeve
edge it is time to cut that plant down
you probably won't see that for 12 to 14
days
some plants will take 16 17 days to show
you any signs of reveg
so i feel like that last 7 10 14 days
throw it on 18 6 and they will really
beef up at the end now the part about
terps where was i the part about terps
and what else does it increase
smell and taste i don't think that comes
with the 12 12.
that is not why i do or that's not why i
do the 18 6. i apologize
the reason i do the 18 6 is for denser
buds
bigger buds it basically makes them beef
up and they also ripen up more quickly
they're getting more light they just
ripen more quickly i don't think it has
anything to do
with aroma and flavor the terps and
aroma and flavor can be increased by
harvesting
after a long dark period you don't have
to have a extremely long dark period but
if you do a 12 hour dark period a lot of
people like to throw the plants
in a 24-hour dark period that is where
you can develop more terps
the daylight kind of the sun the light
are bright lights
they break down the terps the plants
produce more terpenes in the dark period
so if you can catch them right before
they start photosynthesizing
that is when the most terps are present
so that is the idea
behind cutting them down and the dark
after an extended dark period that is
where
uh the terps come in so i think you may
have crossed two different things
if not uh that is what i think you got
that from that's where that comes from
the 18 6 is more for density more for
faster riping
ripening so yes i do fully encourage and
that is a trick that i kept
i've known that for a little while a lot
of us in the growing industry have known
that for a minute
we just keep it under our belts we don't
talk a lot about that is a breeder it's
a trick that i can use
to speed up rooms i can get more
breeding projects going it really helps
me out
but yes the last 7 to 10 maybe 14 days
you can turn your light timer back on
for 18 hours on
and six hours off and it will increase
the performance of your plants you'll
get a better harvest weight
you'll get denser buds and they will
ripen up a little bit more quickly
under that light cycle and you should be
flushing at that time anyway
so if they do show you any signs of
revenge too early chop them down
immediately
now there was another part to this
question it said i want to re-veg
a few smaller branches and take clones
after harvest will the 18-6 schedule
have a negative effect on the clones no
the 18-6 schedule
will have a wonderful effect on your
reveg
and your clones that is exactly what you
want you're giving yourself
a head start most of the time people
harvest their plants and they leave a
couple of buds
and then they say now i'm going to
re-veg these buds and they put it back
under 24 hours or 18 sixths of light
you're already 10 days ahead of that
your plant has been under 18
6 of light for 7 10 maybe 14 days
before you harvested most of the buds
now you took off the big part you just
left a couple of little buds leave like
three or four or maybe five thumb size
buds at the bottom that's all you need
to re-veg
and they're already having a head start
they're already seven to ten
fourteen days into the edge process how
we re-veg is just by turning the lights
back on
to a vegetative cycle and patiently
waiting so you've already started that
now you're flushing
it's about time to cut down you'll
harvest almost everything like i said
before
leave three to five little thumb size
nuggets then we want to
start feeding a high nitrogen diet again
go back to your vegetative diet
that'll trigger those plants to go back
into the vegetative stage
let them grow they're gonna start
spitting out
weird dill looking leaves like leaves
like a dill plant
it's going to be really strange looking
leaves for a little while they'll be
twisted they'll be claw-liked
they'll be different colors they'll have
variegations they'll be mutations
then one day it'll spit out a new shoot
that looks like just a [ __ ] baby
clone came out of that plant
and you'll feel like you've been blessed
you'll look at it and you'll go ah
it's got this brand new shoot coming
right out of it clone that let it get
big enough
maybe wait for two or three of those to
happen and clone those
make a clone out of that shoot let that
shoot root
once that shoot is rooted pot it grow it
up a little bit
take clones from that plant and use that
one
as your clone donor and now work with
those new clones you want to kind of
grow it
let all those hormones get kind of
realigned before we start running that
plan again so cut a clone of it
grow out that clone then use that clone
as your new clone donor it may slow you
down a little bit
but in my opinion that's the best way to
preserve the genetics keep them healthy
and not experience any sort of loss or
degradation or the words that we don't
use because they're not real anymore
i've done a full podcast episode on the
word that i'm not going to use
all right so i want to thank you both my
voice is starting to skip i'm going to
grab a drink
all right guys thank you for being
patient with me while i hydrated i want
to thank my buddy zack and my buddy
reggae in my head both for the great
messages i hope i helped you out
yes i do encourage that 18 6 at the end
of flower that will
bulk up and beef up your crop and it
will set you on the path for success
for reveg it's the same thing that we
would do in a reveg
uh you're just cutting down part of the
plant when it's ready leave the
the rest of it there to grow for you
then in a couple of weeks you'll have
fresh shoots
a few weeks from there you'll have brand
new plants all right i want to thank you
guys both for the great message
i look forward to some sort of an update
from both of you how did this work for
you did you notice
a fatter harvest weight did you notice a
denser bud did you notice that things
finished up a little bit more quickly
for you
send me some feedback you've got the
email address i look forward to hearing
from you
all right ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls pimps and hoes friends and foes
smokers and growers
clone cutters and pollen chuckers all
you wonderful cannabis growers out there
i want to thank you again for listening
to another episode of the grow from your
heart podcast
if you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
and you would like to make a financial
contribution to the show all you have to
do is visit www www.patreon.com forward
slash grow from your heart
all of the information you need will be
right there on the screen and don't
forget i did include a link in the show
notes and the video description
for all of my friends i also encourage
you
to check out the website
iriegenetics.com
also don't forget to join that mailing
list
also there is a help tab on the website
if you go to iregenetics.com
there is a grow help tab i ask a few key
questions on there
fill out that little help form let me
know what your grow question is
send it to me i will do my best to get
to you as soon as possible
i may use your question here on the
podcast
i look forward to hearing from you
ladies and gentlemen that is all i've
got for you for this episode
i need to get a drink i need to get some
food i want to thank you again for
hanging out i'll be back in a couple of
days with fresh new content
i want to give a huge shout out to my
buddy reifer matniss
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me