welcome back podcast world i'm your host
my friends call me rasta jeff and it is
time for episode 593
of the grow from your heart podcast you
know i like to start this show off by
talking about what i'm smoking
today i've been taking dabs of chem dog
d t 1000 live batter
this is a blend of chem dog d and t 1000
on the package the flavor is described
as gas
lavender and grapes you may know that
i'm not a big fan of lavender flavors
and aromas but luckily
it comes through with sort of a perfumey
floral sort of aroma and flavor
and the mix is dominated by that gassy
grape flavor
and i do enjoy that on the back of the
package it says it contains
69.81 thc and non-detectable amounts of
cbd
perfect for a podcast concentrate so big
shout out to the chem dog d
t 1000 live batter
in this episode i'm going to read an
email about foliar feeding our plants
before we get there let's do a few shout
outs to a few of the folks in the 710
club
let's start off with the big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to a longtime supporter and a good
friend
let's send a special thank you shout out
to my buddy john bendit
let's follow that up with a thank you
shout out to zach let's send a thank you
shout out to jake
let's follow that up with a fakie shout
out to matt then let's jump into a thank
you shout out to my buddy godfather
kush i want to send a fist bump to my
buddy dave's not here
i've always got a thank you shout out
from my buddy terp burglar
let's send a special grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out to dr
dendro
i want to send a thank you shout out to
smokey j let's follow that up with a
thank you shout out to dayron t
i want to send a special thank you shout
out and a fist bump to my buddy the
basta
and last but certainly not least let's
send a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to my buddy
north north terps big thanks and big
shout out to everybody who supports the
show on patreon
if you are not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need will be
right there on the screen and i did
include a link in the show notes and in
the video description
to make it super easy for all of my
friends all right thank you guys for all
of the continued patreon support it does
mean a lot to me
i've said it before without all the
patreon support i wouldn't have all this
fancy lighting i wouldn't have the fancy
new camera
wouldn't even have the fancy new
computer and there is an even better
computer on the way
because when i bought a 4k camera this
computer said
that's cute i can barely handle that so
there's a new computer coming so thank
you
to everybody for the patreon support it
does mean a lot to me and it does keep
the show coming to you
for free there are a lot of folks who
are not able to contribute to patreon
that is completely understandable the
folks who do contribute are keeping this
show coming to
everybody for free thank you all right
where are we going to go from there i
did a recent episode about tester
applications and tester expectations
that's right if you want to run test
seats for me
there is a process to submit an
application to become a tester
big thank you to everybody who submitted
a tester application
i got an overwhelming response an
overwhelming amount of applications were
submitted
i am trying to catch up on all of those
with that being said
do not stop sending them i am
overwhelmed i'm overloaded but i want
more
keep me working keep me busy keep me
digging through those applications
please continue to send in your tester
applications if you are interested in
testing
one of the main things in that episode
was being able to follow instructions
uh there were very specific instructions
on how to submit a testing application
if you did not follow those instructions
i probably did not notice your
application there was one way to submit
that application
make sure you do it that way all of the
other ways will be ignored
sorry to be rude about it that's just
you got to be able to follow
instructions and if i've got you in my
email then it's easier to find you i'm
not going to look across all of the
social media platforms to find tester
applications
send them to me in one spot or listen to
the episode again
you'll figure it out also that help tab
on my website
i've added a grow help tab on
iregenetics.com if you go to
iregenetics.com
there is a tab that simply says grow
help when you click on that grow help
tab it will ask you
about seven or eight key questions it
basically asks
uh what is the temperature and humidity
of your grow environment what was the
last
feed and ph and uh ec of your last
feeding
so i can get a few details about what's
happening in your grow before i even try
to answer your question so you go to the
grow help tab
you'll fill out a little questionnaire
tell me the temperature tell me the
humidity tell me what you fed tell me
the ph and ec of that feed
then tell me what's wrong with your
plants this will save us both a few
steps
a lot of people like to email me and
they say bro here's what's wrong with my
plants
and then i've got like seven or eight
follow-up questions just to go from what
they asked
instead of having to ask those questions
they're already there on the sheet
so you're going to tell me so many key
points you're going to give me so many
hints to help me diagnose your problem
i'm basically just giving you a little
checkup i'm like when you go to the
doctor checking your temperature
looking in your ears looking in your
nose checking out your throat looking
for obvious [ __ ]
maybe i can diagnose problems from those
small obvious details so i'm going to
ask you to fill out that questionnaire
then you send me then there's a little
part that says what's your problem
what's going on when you grow
fill that out send it to me it comes to
my email i will read that
i've gotten a lot of great questions and
a lot of great content for the podcast
from that grow help tab so thank you
also if you feel like you have not been
replied to or responded to in a timely
manner
i do apologize like i said a moment ago
i have been
overwhelmed in a good way with tester
applications and grow help questions
i love it i appreciate it it keeps me
busy it keeps me working
i will get to all of them please don't
feel like i'm ignoring you uh
irie genetics is a one-man operation the
grow from your heart podcast is a
one-man operation
if mike's not on the show if i don't
have a guest this is just a solo
one-man operation uh team ross to jeff
is
i do have the irie army i've got a lot
of helpers doing things like that but
packaging the seeds breeding the seeds
doing the podcast it's all just me
all of the emails are all me so please
be patient
that is what i'm trying to say but with
all of that being said
keep that tester applications keep the
grow questions keep it all coming
also one more thing to talk about on the
website iregenetics.com
there is a spot to sign up for a mailing
list for a newsletter that's right
it's very easy to find on the website
scroll down there's a spot to type in
your email address put in a good email
address
you will get an auto respond from my
mailchimp it basically says hey thank
you for signing up
that is how you know it worked that's
how i know you signed up then
when i do special deals at a vendor like
seeds herenow.com
you will get an uh a newsletter excuse
me for stuttering i've got a lot of my
brain
you will get a notification a newsletter
for things like sales at
seedshearnow.com
for new strain releases exclusive strain
releases maybe i'll do
uh i just put out a new strain that
nobody knew was even coming
it showed up at seeds herenow.com for
the black friday sale
the people on the newsletter knew that
that was coming so you can
uh stay tuned for exclusive drops uh
re-releases a lot of people ask me when
stuff will be restocked at certain
places
uh sometimes i include that in the
newsletter i try not to overload you but
i do try to keep you in the loop
i'm doing about once a month right now
it may increase to once a week if it
doesn't annoy people
you let me know how many updates you
want if it becomes annoying let me know
i'd rather settle down than lose you as
a follower and as a friend
so that's where we are sign up for the
mailchimp
uh then you'll get uh you'll stay in
touch with the newsletter uh you'll get
updates from all things roster
jeff then uh where else was i the help
tab send me your questions and also
the tester applications don't stop but
also if i don't keep up with you right
away i apologize it is just me
where are we gonna go from there oh i've
got one more thing to ask for before we
jump into some of these grow
questions i would like a cool little
logo i don't ask you for a lot but i
would like a cool little logo just to
put right about
here where is it going to go right about
there on the screen i'm not sure how i'm
going to edit this but
right about here on the screen it would
be cool if it just said gfyhtv
and had a cool little red yellow and
green rasta colored logo maybe
something like that maybe just something
real simple that i can just
drag into the video every time and put
it right there on the bottom right
corner
i just think it would look cool make me
look super official uh maybe
i don't know it doesn't have to be red
yellow and green you're the artist you
get creative i'll pay you for it
if more than one person submits it i'll
rotate them out put them on the bottom
of the screen give you some credit and
the credits at the end of the show
i'll give you a gift i'll pay you in
cash whatever we gots to do
gfyhtv i want a little logo for the
bottom of the screen right here you know
what i'm talking about
you know exactly what i want if you do a
red yellow and green rasta colored logo
it is traditional that the red goes on
the bottom please let's just stay
respectful
to the rasta tradition all right i did
say that was it before we jumped into
the
grow question so let's work our way
right into a couple of questions
i have gotten this question from
multiple people from multiple formats
and i've seen this asked all over social
media
so it is time to address this one again
i talk about this often
probably once every three to six months
i've got to remind people of this
people ask quite a bit when i am growing
from seed
and the seed pack says that the seeds
are going to take 70 days in flower
is that or they're going to take 70 days
is that going to take 70 days from the
day i plant it or from
the day that i put it into flour unless
they're autoflower plants
the 70 days is the flowering time that's
how long you should expect them to be in
flour you can veg them as long as you
want
you can veg them for a day you can veg
them for
three weeks six weeks you can veg them
for nine months if you've got the space
and you know how to do that
what we're putting on there as the time
on the back of the package is the
flowering time
unless you are working with autoflowers
and that should be clearly indicated on
the package
if you're working with autoflowers that
time that's listed on there
is the anticipated predicted time from
start to finish but
if you were working with regular photo
period or feminized photo period seeds
that time that we list on the back the
flowering time is from the day
is the flowering time not the full grow
time now here's another thing i want to
clarify
that flowering time starts from the day
you turn the light cycle to 12-12
not from when you start seeing bud
development that's about day 12 day 14
day 17 the flowering cycle
officially begins the day you
or somebody else turns the light cycle
to 1212 and of course this is in an
indoor grow environment you flip that
light cycle to 12 12.
that's day one of flower you write that
down on the calendar as day one
if you're looking at a pack of seeds and
they say we finish in 63 to 70 days
day one starts right there expect that
pack of seeds to be done in 63 to
75-ish days as breeders we really try to
label the packages clearly and tell you
how long to expect we give you a time
frame these are plants there is nature
we are putting plants in different
environments i'm not exactly sure what's
going to happen in your environment i'm
not sure what you're going to do to them
to speed them up or slow them down
but from our testing from what we have
seen through research with most of these
plants
that is the time frame we have seen so
i'm going to get myself back on track
back to the point
when we say flowering time is 70 days we
mean that is from the day
you turn your timer from if it's 24 on
and 0 off or 18 6 or whatever your
vegetative cycle is
now when you put it on 12 12 that is day
one of flower that's when your 70 day
flowering time begins
not when you see the pistols not when
you see bud development
how that's a guess there's no that could
be
you might not have seen it right away
and then do you start flowering counting
flower when you write when you see the
pistols or when they're nubby or when
they're growing out
how do you [ __ ] do that why not just
do it we know when day one is it's
because we changed
the [ __ ] light cycle ourselves let's
not guess let's not put so much guessing
into it let's narrow down
um what are they called variables let's
narrow down the variables
and know that day one was the day that
we put that [ __ ] into flower
and then start counting from there keep
a mark of it know that
it was maybe you've got five or six
plants in there harvest won it if it
says day 70
cut one down at 68 one at 69 one at 70
one at 71 and one at 72 and see what the
difference is or go even more staggered
with your harvest
go 65 70 75 80.
see what happens that stuff is fun to do
but my main point is
the flowering time day one starts when
you flip the timer not when you start
seeing
those little fuzzies all right that was
a great question i see it often
trust me you will hear about that again
on the show because it gets asked
very very frequently all right let's
move into a more advanced question this
one is about foliar feeding
this one comes from uh let's see they
want their name said i'm not sure they
want their name said
we're going to not do that part it goes
like this it says hey ross to jeff
on the breeder panel yesterday you
sounded awesome and your mic
was booming so what they're referring to
is i was on a breeder panel on cannabuzz
we did a live breeder panel uh you were
able to chat with the
the breeders while they were on the
panel you could watch uh on cannabis
check out cannabis you guys i'm going to
be doing
another panel on cannabis
i think i don't know that i should
announce this yet it's not set in stone
but to the best of my knowledge i'm
going to make it happen on december 19th
here we go
this is my commitment this is how we
commit to [ __ ] jr i'm in dude i'm saying
it now on a show
can't back out now december 19th i will
be doing a
live panel a live show on cannabis
uh jr and q grows will be interviewing
me
there will be a question and answer
panel and i may even bring a couple of
my friends on
uh from cannabis to join me on zoom and
hang out we may
uh let them ask questions we may do some
chat and some bullshitting we may even
take some dabs together
so december 19th on cannabis it will be
in the afternoon time i don't think
we've set a solid time yet
it should be a one to two hour show
that's usually what we like to do
if you're not already on cannabis uh
you're [ __ ] up you're sleeping get on
cannabis it is a free application
it's available on whatever kind of phone
you've got it's available on your ipad
you can get it on the computer i think
it works best on the phone
go to your app store download canon buzz
c-a-n-n-a-b-u-z-z
log in create yourself a username i'm
irie underscore genetics give me a
follow click like on all my stuff that's
all you got to do
then pay attention saturday december
19th there will be an irie genetics
cannabis
live show i think it's going to be a
great time i don't know what they've got
in store for me yet i'm going to be
prepared no matter what happens as a
breeder as a podcaster
i'm ready ask me questions let's get it
on i'm ready to be there and have a good
time
and i'm just going to relax because i am
not hosting the show so it should be
great
ask me questions let's hang out let's
take some dabs cannabis december
19th um and the mic is booming yes thank
you
um that was before i got this mic i
think so uh we are double booming at
this point
it goes on to say you can always tell
you put a lot of time effort and money
into your sound quality and it's noticed
and appreciated
ah dude thank you um there was a lot of
funding to get this microphone all this
equipment
there is so many there are so many
things in this chain to make all this
work
and i've said it before without patreon
i probably would not have happened
so thank you to everybody for the
patreon contributions i'm glad you guys
are noticing
the increase in audio quality video
quality production quality
i want you to see that i care you guys
definitely take good care of me on
patreon
you are you bought all this stuff and i
want you to see that i appreciate it i
didn't just take all of your patreon
funding and
uh buy a new truck you know i bought
podcasting stuff with that
and i'm also trying to put a lot more
time and energy into the podcast because
this is fun
now that i'm learning all this gear i
don't know it's like when you have new
toys when you get a new
video game or you get a new toy you want
to go play with your new toys and video
games if you've got a new rig you want
to take extra
dabs i just feel like i want to podcast
more because i've got all this cool
[ __ ] the only thing slowing me down is
this computer and i've got a new one
coming
thanks to patreon so i am high and
rambly shout out to the chem dog dt 1000
live batter it seems to be working
take some dabs at that where were we
we're in this episode in this email and
it says
uh thank you for all the information you
put out there my question
is what nutrients and supplements do you
find
more effective or effective as a foliar
spray instead of the standard
root drench that is a great question it
says i've read that kelp
humboldt honey and calmag can be more
effective as a foliar spray
uh yes that is accurate and we're going
to talk about why
and how some of those things are more
effective as a foliar spray before we do
that let's talk about foliar feeding
why would we fully feed our plants what
is foliar feeding
foliar feeding is exactly what it sounds
like you mix a light dose of nutrients
into a spray bottle or a sprayer however
you're applying your sprays
my spray applications are much larger in
a commercial grow than they are on a
private grow
in a commercial grill i mix up a five
gallon bucket or maybe even larger
of my foliar spray if it's a pesticide
if it's a booster spray
i mix up a five gallon bucket and i use
a [ __ ] paint sprayer
to just douse all of the plants with
that spray in my personal grow
i use a small just a little like a
little windex looking [ __ ] spray
bottle
it's a big difference so it's the same
effect it's the same idea no matter
where you
are you want to mix up a light nutrient
solution
you need a strategy if you're going to
feed the plants fully early
if you're going to foliar feed the
plants i don't know the wordage there
but if you're going to feed them by
full the foliar method you need to have
a strategy you can't just go mixing up
newts and spray them in there
because they're going to get on the
leaves this is way different than
feeding them
to the root zone there's no buffer
you're going straight on to the plant so
you need a strategy
but i basically mix up a light nutrient
solution and i spray it onto the plants
when i do this
the lights are off that is a very
important thing i find it very important
to always spray with the lights off
some products do say you can spray with
the lights on i still don't do it
i just like to turn the lights off when
i'm fully feeding
i feel like those little bubbles that
land on the plants on the leaves
think about when you were a little kid
and used to burn ants with the
magnifying glass or you could catch [ __ ]
on fire with the magnifying glass
it is the same exact method the sun or
the grow light comes down
it hits that bubble the bubble's got
that little arc that arc creates uh some
sort of refractory i'm not a light and
sun scientist but we'll get there
i create some sort of a thing that makes
it works like a magnifying glass just
when you used to hold the
[ __ ] the sun and the magnifying glass
just right it would create a hot spot on
whatever
that light will come down and do the
same thing to that bubble of foliar
spray and it'll put little burn spots on
your plants
those don't go away they look like other
problems they'll make you panic you'll
think you've got bugs or some sort of
deficiency when really all it was
was just a little water burn so foliar
feeding
is very important to be done in the dark
now why would we do it because we can
apply
specific nutrients to the plant at
specific times
and sometimes we've already watered the
plants and they may be wet
if you've got a seven gallon pot when
you water that plant it may be wet for
three to four maybe five days depending
on the size of the plant the environment
of the room
you may have a nutrient deficiency
you're chasing you can't water in more
nutrients but we can
foliar feed some nutrients into the
plant there are a lot of nutrients
that work very well being foliar fed
some are more effective than others
we will touch on that in just a moment i
want to make sure that i am keeping up
with my notes
so we can provide nutrients directly to
the leaves if we're chasing a deficiency
we can absolutely
provide most nutrients directly to the
leaves and not have to feed it through
the root zone it's more faster acting
you can watch it work it also you won't
lock out your roots if your plants are
already wet like i said
you don't have to keep watering [ __ ] in
and you're not going to lock out the
roots by over
feeding it's just another opportunity to
provide
nutrients to our plants now you did say
that you read that kelp
humboldt honey and calmag were effective
as foliar spray
i'm going to leave humboldt honey out of
this mix because that is a
product with a lot of things in it i
think that would be safer to
apply to the root zone it's got some
things in there that may clog up your
plants and it may be more problematic if
you're doing it and it works
keep doing it i just wouldn't do that as
a foliar feed
the kelp and the calmag absolutely do
and will work wonderfully
as a foliar fee let's talk about why i
believe
calmag is a great foliar fed nutrient
calmag is what is known as as an
immobile nutrient
it can't move itself around in the plant
normally if the plant sensed a
deficiency in a nutrient
up in one part of the plant older leaves
that are kind of dying off and that are
going to expire would say
hey we're going to die let's send some
of our mobile nutrients up to that other
part of the leaves
so that they can survive and be strong
and healthy since i'm going to go
we'll just pass the spoon right on up so
calmag
cannot do that calmag does not have that
ability calmag is very
a very heavy nutrient that is why it is
sold in a different bottle
than all of your other nutrients if you
put the calmag in the bottle
with the other nutrients basically it's
heavier it would fall to the bottom
in solution it wouldn't stay in the
solution it would always be that [ __ ] at
the bottom of the jar
you'd be stirring and shaking and it
would just be the the coffee grounds in
your nutrient solution all the time
so calmag is a non or an immobile
nutrient is what we call that
so we can foliar feed that directly to
the plants
and that will help you rapidly correct a
calmag deficiency
so that is one thing that is great for a
foliar feed calmac
calcium works as a great foliar feed
it's hard to find it is
harder to find a straight calcium
product but calmag works
as an effective foliar feed whichever
brand of calmag you are using
will probably work well uh kelp why does
kelp work well kelp has a lot of
hormones in it
kelp has a lot of phytonutrients and
they're all bioavailable to the plant
by foliar spray those nutrients are
mobile nutrients so you'll spray those
to the plant
and the plant if you don't overdo it
you'll spray that onto the plant and
it'll go oh
maybe this leaf over here doesn't have
enough nitrogen let's move that over
here and this new
leaf over here needs a little bit of
phosphorus let's move that over here
so the plants will move those mobile
nutrients around as
needed so that's basically kelp there
are a lot of things in kelp i'm not
going to dig too deeply into that could
be an episode on its own as well as
calmag
could be a full episode on its own i
want to make sure to stay on track here
where are we going from here um
nitrogen nitrogen works as a great
foliar feed you can mix up a small
amount of your base nutrient if your
plants are getting a little bit yellow
and you can't feed them enough
that's called chasing the nitrogen
golden goat
golden goat crosses a rise crosses ah
lemon jeffrey sometimes will become
nitrogen deficient
early in flower like week two or three
of flower you'll say why is that [ __ ]
going yellow on me
already a really good easy way to
correct that
is a foliar feed of nitrogen take your
vegetative base nutrient and mix up
i don't know what brand you're using so
i'm not even going to make a
recommendation
way less than what you would use when
you're feeding it to the root zone
maybe like a quarter maybe a fifth maybe
even less
mix up some of that base nutrient
because your base nutrient is high in
nitrogen
mix up your base nutrient into a bottle
give it a good shake so it's nice and uh
distributed in there emulsified might be
the word i want
and your feed that to your plant that
will get the nitrogen
into your leaves the leaves will say hey
this is a mobile nutrient
it'll move it all around to where it
needs to be that will help you chase and
correct
a nitrogen deficiency you can do the
same with phosphorus and potassium
keep in mind that as you increase
phosphorus you do run the risk of a
calmag deficiency they work together so
just keep that sort of stuff in mind all
right now let's talk about other things
that i do foliar feed the plants
kelp is great calmag works beautifully
to correct a deficiency
you can absolutely feed the npk
through the leaves you can watch it move
around i feel like if you spray it in
the dark
give it like two hours for everything to
dry when you go back you can see those
plants have greened up a little bit at
least i feel like i can i've got a
really good relationship with my plants
i can see their reactions it's like
watching the look on people's faces if
you walk in the room
and you just say a certain word if you
just say cheesecake if you walk in the
word and say cheesecake people make a
certain face
if you walk in the room and you say fart
they make a different face
i can see my plants respond in the same
way that's the kind of relationship
i have got with my plants so i feel like
after i fully feed them i can walk in
there and absolutely see
results within just a few hours now
let's talk about another product i
really like
a product called push push is a great
product
they do not pay me they don't give me
anything to talk about it i think it's a
great product it is from
the same folks that make veg bloom they
are called hydroponic research you can
find them online
uh hydroponic dash research it might be
dotnet
not com anyway push is a great product
product um it contains uh kelp
it's got uh silica in there and it's got
another acid that i cannot remember the
name of and i did not write it down
however it works wonderfully for the
plants
uh i think recharge makes the plants go
kaboom at the root zone level
and push is recharge for the top of the
plants that is push for the leaves or
that is recharge for the leaves
so i think push is a great product
something about foliar feeding
always use low doses you can definitely
burn your plants by foliar feeding you
can absolutely apply too much
and unlike when you overfeed the root
zone there's
it's harder much harder to recover i
said unlike when so unlike when you over
feed the root zone
you don't have a lot of opportunity for
recovery there's no chance to fix your
mistake if you over feed the root zone
they start showing you they go i'm gonna
kind of brown up over here i'm gonna get
kind of
my nails done and burn up at the tips
you've got time to react
you can flush that soil you can feed it
something different
when you sprayed it on there you just
spray painted problems onto your plants
if you overfed it
so be very careful start with low doses
you can work your way up
but you can't work your way down from a
burn maybe if you're new at full you're
feeding don't go in there and spray the
entire [ __ ] crop all at one time
maybe spray one plant see how it reacts
maybe spray two plants
see how they react learn on a couple
don't destroy
everything have a couple of test dummies
in there experiment before you go hard
on the entire room
i've said it before always spray in the
dark some companies will tell you that
their product is safe to spray when the
lights are on
i don't believe it please don't do that
i've seen terrible burns on plants
i don't think you should spray people
are going to argue with me
over this and that is just fine this is
my opinion
i would not spray microbe products in an
organic
grow if you're doing a tlo system if
you're running labs and other things
like that
do that stuff in your no-till and
organic environment
if you are running i run a very
commercial
style grow there's not a lot of uh tlo
love happening in my grow it's
cocoa and salts and pesticide sprays
and foliar sprays for boosts in my
environment i would not recommend
microbe sprays that does give you the
opportunity for more problems
in colorado we have to pet we have to
pass
microbe testing all of our buds not all
of our buds
a sample from every batch is sent to a
lab
those buds are tested for the presence
of yeast and mold if we are spraying
products
like uh i'm not even gonna say any
specific products if we're spraying
microbe products on our plants we're
increasing the opportunity to fail
those microbe testings so unless you are
running some sort of organic no-till
living soil you know what i'm talking
about you organic hippies if you're
running that sort of stuff
then i do encourage you do your your
crazy sprays
if you're not familiar with that and
you're not running that type of grow
i do not encourage it i would not do
that that will set yourself
up for problems where are we when you
follow your spray you're going to
increase the humidity of your room
um that may not be the best idea maybe
have your exhaust fans and dehumidifier
on
you're going to have to clean your
dehumidifier more often if you're foliar
feeding
because some of that funky [ __ ] will end
up in the air those nutrients will end
up in your dehumidifier filter
clean that uh where are we what am i
going for mix
well when you're mixing up your foliar
feed i've said it
shake the [ __ ] out of that spray or just
shake it make sure it's all mixed up in
there
you don't want to feed the the bottom
stuff is heavier the cow mag will be at
the bottom the nitrogen will be up at
the top you don't want to feed like that
mix it up really well also use some sort
of a wetting
agent when you are applying foliar feeds
and or pesticides
something like cocoa wet works really
well wet betty works just fine if you
want to use that brand
or a couple of drops of organic dish
soap would do the same thing
what this does is this makes it spread
and stick to your leaves a little bit
better
the longer the stuff spreads and sticks
to your leaves the more available it is
it will just run off and drip onto the
floor that way you didn't just follow
your feed the floor and waste all your
product
it's stuck to the plants um i feel like
i've got something else i wanted to say
on that
i don't know where it went um okay
i'm just gonna act like i remembered
what i was saying because i really don't
um you're gonna make small bubbles so i
recommend
that you wear protective equipment
always wear personal protective
equipment
always absolutely wear goggles if you're
going to use a paint sprayer if you're
going to use a sprayer put some sort of
mask on
i recommend some sort of a respirator
especially with the paint sprayer
you're creating micro bubbles of what
are we spraying
phosphorus potassium calmag do you want
to breathe in
little bubbles of calmag i don't know
that that's really good for any part of
your body
so please wear personal protective
equipment
when spraying anything if you're
spraying a pesticide if you're spraying
a boost if you're just spraying water
put on some personal protective
equipment i know that sounds silly
we don't want to breathe in these
bubbles you guys you don't want to
breathe that stuff in
we smoke this cannabis we want to keep
our lungs healthy we smoke the dabs
your lungs are important dude let's do
what we can to protect those
um pesticides and
foliar feeds there is nothing wrong with
mixing
a foliar feed in with the pesticide if
you're applying a routine pesticide
you can add push to that pesticide
application it says on the bottle of
push do not mix with any other products
do not mix with pesticides guess what
i've done it a lot of times i've done it
countless times i've done it with a lot
of different nutrients and i never see
any adverse reactions
i kind of feel like it's drinking it's
kind of like drinking vodka and orange
juice
one of them is gonna [ __ ] ruin my
body but at the other time i got so much
vitamin c that i feel
good about it i don't really drink vodka
and orange juice but
i feel like if you're going to spray a
pesticide to the plant that's going to
kind of beat up the plant a little bit
stress that plant out
why not add some push to it and you can
kind of negate the damage give it a
boost
maybe we'll level out get rid of the
bugs boost the plants all at the same
time
so you can apply both at the same time
many people will tell you to ph or
foliar feed research
that one you don't want acid rain on our
plants
that doesn't sound like any fun for
anybody always have a strategy
always have a strategy i've written that
down a couple of times
why are you follow your feeding don't
just go in there and willy-nilly start
spraying [ __ ] around
have a strategy what are you spraying
for what is your goal
are you trying to give them a boost are
you trying to correct something are you
trying to prevent something if it's a
pesticide spray
if it's a foliar feed always have a
strategy
then as soon as you are done spraying
write down
exactly what you sprayed what was in the
mix how much of it was in the mix
how many gallons were applied which
plants were applied did you only spray
the veg did you only spray the flour did
you only spray the large veg the small
veg the pre-flower
write down everything you sprayed write
down the time and date
if you used a pesticide write down the
re-entry time so you know when you can
go back in there
this should be standard for every grow
this is required by
law in a commercial grow environment by
law
by department of agriculture law by
department of health law
and i'm pretty sure there's some other
people that would probably whip your ass
and give you a ticket if you didn't do
it
you were required to keep documentation
of everything that was sprayed on those
plants every pesticide application
is required to be documented by law and
i think you have to keep it in a folder
for two to three years
so we use a department of agriculture
approved spreadsheet
we write down everything that was
[ __ ] sprayed the date the time the
amount the product
there is a number a an epa number on the
bottle that we have to include on that
spreadsheet
your initials your med badge number your
department of agriculture certification
number
what time it was sprayed what time the
spraying ended and the re-entry interval
all of that is required to be written on
a sheet every time we spray something
in any grow a pesticide not a booster i
could spray push and not have to write
it down but if i put a pesticide in
there
i would have to write that down for the
department of agriculture
anything i spray i write down in my own
personal grow log that way if something
goes wrong or if something goes right
i can look back and say what the [ __ ]
happened in here
if i spray something today and in like
three or four days i walk in there and
the plants look [ __ ] decrepid
i can look back at my notes and i can
say everything that i fed was normal
oh it was the new feed i fed them i
sprayed them this [ __ ] thing
and they went ape [ __ ] or i can say why
do my plants look
happy those buds have never been beefier
the plants have never prayed like that
what did i do i can look back and say
oh it's this new product i sprayed that
every three days instead of every five
days this time
and the plants [ __ ] loved it so keep
good notes on what you're doing
you can always adjust and change your
strategy based on your research that is
a scientific method that's building a
relationship with your plants
that's understanding the products you're
using that is becoming a solid grower so
do that stuff
don't spray big chunky buds if the buds
are getting big
you may want to stop spraying i usually
quit spraying around day 21 i may hit
them with one final pesticide spray
one final booster spray at day 21 just
to get them going
then i avoid spraying if at all possible
understand that it does rain outside
you've got chunky buds outside if you're
growing outdoors the water the rain the
mist the fog are going to hit those
plants
yes there's a lot of airflow and air
moving out there but the plants are
resilient to moisture if you do run into
problems
if you do have issues there are products
that you can apply
early in flower as buds are developing
but be very careful be very specific do
your research
and understand what you are applying to
these plants unless it is necessary
please don't spray them
keep in mind i said that they are
resilient they are resistant the
trichomes do work to keep the water off
the plants
but they also work like a sponge if
you're going to spray them just mist
them
get the the booster or the pesticide or
the mildew remover whatever you have to
put on there
get that on there but don't saturate
those buds we don't want to wet up the
spongy buds
cause ourselves more problems that's
when you've got to weigh your options do
i want to spray them or do i just want
to accept the problem i've got
that's when you've got thinking to do so
foliar feeding is a really good way to
provide
specific nutrients to our plants without
over watering or causing a lockout it is
a good way to chase a problem if you see
a nitrogen deficiency you can absolutely
mix up some of your vegetative nutrients
give it a foliar feed maybe apply it
two or three days apart do it two or
three times you'll absolutely see
results if you need to go harder
go harder like i said earlier start your
foliar feed light
use less than you think you need and
increase you can't unfeed it but you can
feed it more
it's already deficient so feed it more
if you need to but don't burn it by
trying to fix it all in one spray
it's like painting a couple of light
coats may work better than one thick
coat
and it works great because you don't
have to keep watering in
you've already watered the roots are
doing their thing move the nutrients
around
now you got to just get that calmag
where it needs to be by spraying it
so i think that is my ah my foliar
feed episode i hope i answered your
question i hope i gave you some useful
information
thank you for the great email if you've
got any more questions i would love to
hear from you you know my email address
is grow from your heart at hotmail.com
ladies and gentlemen boys and girls if
you feel like this episode was
educational informative and or
entertaining
and you'd like to make a financial
contribution to the show again all you
have to do is visit www.patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart
all of the information you need to
support the show will be right there on
the screen
big thank you to everybody who supports
the podcast
again make sure you follow us on
cannabis i've talked about cannabis
before
cannabis is a free social media
application it is very cannabis friendly
you cannot buy sell trade or deal
cannabis on cannabis
but you can post your grow photos you
can post your if you're one of those
people who likes to take dab videos and
do the duck face at the end
go ahead let's post that up on cannabis
join the cannabis community if you've
got a grow
question you can post a picture of your
plants on cannabis and say hey what the
[ __ ] is wrong
so many great growers will chime in and
give you very
useful advice on cannabis join us on
cannabis i look forward to seeing
you also don't forget to visit my
website iriegenetics.com
you can get these sweet irie genetics
lemon jeffree shirts there's an orange
gasm shirt
there is a golden goat shirt there's an
irie genetics logo t-shirt up there
there
is a grow from your heart podcast
t-shirt available
and i do have a couple of more tricks up
my sleeve just waiting for printing and
shipping because things are weird
during the coved times all right you
guys that is all i've got for you for
this episode
i want to thank everybody for hanging
out for another great episode i had a
good time
i hope you had a good time i'll be back
in a couple of days with fresh new
content i want to give a giant shout out
to my buddy pedro's grow room and until
next time take a fat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
roster jeff you bad [ __ ]