all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rosta jeff and this is episode
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to talk about
failed breeding projects
i'm also going to talk about nutrient
spiking toward the end of flower
before we get there let's do a few shout
outs to a few of the folks who support
the show
on patreon let's start off with the big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to my friend gramps memel
let's send a thank you shout out to
blackbird76 i want to send a thank you
shout out to pac northwest
dan let's send a thank you shout out to
ned denver i want to send a special
thank you shout out to matt
h let's send a big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to tart and
mike
let's send a big thank you shout out to
captain mojo i've always got a thank you
shout out from my friend green tongue
let's send a thank you shout out to dtom
420 and last but certainly not least
let's send a big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out
to my friend ziggy's garden big thanks
and big shout out to everybody who
supports the show on patreon
if you are not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need will be
right there on the screen
and of course i did include a link in
the show notes and the video description
to make it super easy for all of my
friends
speaking of patreon patreon was broken
for a couple of days and it kept telling
me that i had
99 unread messages i think i have caught
up and answered all of my patreon
messages at the time of this recording
if you feel like i have not read your
message or answered your question
please resend your question give me a
little reminder give me a little nudge i
will get your question on the show i
will
answer your message i do apologize
patreon was tripping for a couple of
days
and i'm trying to catch up and correct
all of that if i missed you please just
reach out again
and i promise you i will get back to you
alright also one more correction
i was listening to the dude gross show
with scotty real
the dude and of course guru holding it
down and scotty reel did mention that i
got a lung infection
from mixing soil with guano in it
however
that was not me that that happened to i
was commenting on somebody else's post
in a facebook group which scottie and i
are both members of
and somebody in that group had a lung
infection i commented
scotty read it saw my name i think he
attached it to me and he said on the
show that i had a lung infection
uh that wasn't me so anybody who sent me
the uh the well wishes
and the words of encouragement for my
lung infection thank you
but that was not me i went ahead and i
mentally
forwarded that off to the person who
needed the love and care
because they do deserve some support
while they are sick but it wasn't me
so uh thank you to the community who
sent me messages and shout out to scotty
that wasn't me bro anyway let's move
forward with the show
i did say that i wanted to talk about
some plant stuff i do have one more
important topic to talk about it is
winter time
here in colorado it is cold as
well you know what i'm gonna say it's
cold as [ __ ] out here in colorado i was
gonna not even say it but
i'm just gonna say it's cold as [ __ ]
dude it is so cold today
uh i was walking across the kitchen and
my feet were freezing on the tile
had to get some socks and it made me
think of something
i need to tell you guys to get your
plants off of the floor
in the winter time it is never a good
idea to have your plants on the cold
ground on the cold floor
that ground is super cold my toes my
feet were cold and purple
i didn't like it i'm sure if you've got
plants on the floor
during the winter time they are not
happy with you they're not going to
drink as much as they should they're not
going to eat as much as they should
they won't cycle the way that they
should their metabolism won't function
the way that they should
you will see funky coloring you will see
nutrient issues
it will look like you've got a ph
problem you'll start getting purple
stems purple and goldish colored leaves
that is because your plants are simply
too damn
cold it may feel like the room is great
the relative humidity the temperature
may be just fine your
vpd may be dialed in but feel the
temperature of that floor put your bare
hand on the floor put your bare foot on
the floor
if you say [ __ ] that's cold your plants
have been sitting there all day and
haven't had a chance to move
and it was only colder during the dark
cycle so if it's cold during your
daytime cycle it is absolutely colder
during the night cycle
that light's not getting down there it's
not penetrating the canopy enough to
warm up the ground
so it is always a good idea to get your
plants up off of that cold floor
there are several ways to do it a very
common way is to just buy extra pots if
you're using a three gallon pot
get another three gallon pot flip it
upside down set your plant right on top
of there
you did just eat up about 10 to 12
inches of your floor space of your
ceiling height
but the plants are now off of the floor
they're not going to freeze
another common way to uh correct this to
remedy this is to just get a tray
a lot of people will buy the four by
four botanicare tray or the three by six
tray
build a little cinder block table lift
that up off the ground put a five gallon
bucket underneath it so you could drain
all your water into there pull the
bucket out dump that somehow
that is a great way to get the plants up
off the floor in a commercial
environment i definitely recommend
long sliding greenhouse tables those are
the way to go
do what fits your budget some people
simply use a pallet some people will
take a cinder block and put the plants
on a cinder block
whatever works for you will be great
that fits your budget
maybe it's not aesthetically pleasing
maybe you've got to go a little more
pricey just to keep the garden
up for appearances if that's what you're
into but my point is
get those plants up off the ground
you're pouring water into them they're
sitting on the cold concrete that water
gets super cold
your plants are getting pissed off if
you wouldn't want to put your hand your
feet or maybe even your balls in that
water
or on that floor don't do it to your
plants the plants can't go put on some
socks they can't the plants can't grab a
pair of shoes
the plants can't crank up the heat
they're [ __ ] they've got to deal with
what you give them
they're your responsibility keep your
baby's feet warm all right
where do we go from there let's talk
about a failed
breeding project i've got a great email
here in front of me this one came from
our friend
marco esquandolas ry ry
rocco the message says hey ross to jeff
i never miss a podcast and i really
appreciate it
hey i really appreciate you listening to
every podcast episode that does mean a
lot to me
it says i hope you do more strain
specific
episodes if you've been listening to the
show for a while you know that i do like
to highlight some of the strains that i
have bred
i've kind of taken a break from that
because i've got so much uh so many
patreon messages and so much listener
generated content
that it is more uh responsible of me to
answer your questions
than to simply advertise my brand and my
products i feel is more uh
more important for me to help you than
advertise my stuff if you've got a
question about a specific strain i will
do a strain report on it but
i've held off on those for a minute i've
got a couple written i just need to
throw them out let me stay focused
this one says it would also be really
cool to hear about one of your breeding
experiments that did not work
very well for instance i reversed a
leonardo
and i crossed a bunch of your strains
but the resulting crosses were no better
than the parents
so that's not successful that is a very
good point
when you were breeding you do need to
have a goal you need to have some
standards
the idea is to improve upon canada's
cannabis when we are breeding we don't
want to just
make seeds just to make seeds we don't
want to make more reproduction [ __ ] we
want to make
winners if you got two sixes you better
make a seven or an eight out of that if
you got two sixes i hope you can make a
12.
just not how things work all the time
let me stay focused it goes on to say
the orange gasm to leo was strong stable
and frosty
so a great gift for first time growers
but once the growers get
serious we will get them more irie
originals
uh be well and best wishes feel free to
use my and then he says my name
uh i'm just going to call you marco s
gwandolas because i like that
shout out to my buddy marco escondolas
run like an antelope my friend
let's talk about some failed breeding
projects
i've been breeding for a long time and
i've put out there are probably 50
strains on my website right now there's
probably closer to 75 or 100 strains
that you can read about that i have
created that i have released there on my
website
i've done a lot of work that being said
if there are 75 on the website
there are probably another 25 to 50 that
i never
even released there are probably 10 or
15 that i threw
large batches of seeds away because
oh excuse me i'm gonna do i edit that or
not probably not let's take a drink and
keep moving
there are large batches of seeds that i
threw away because i did not feel like
those plants those seeds that breeding
project lived up to my expectations
and it did not improve upon cannabis it
didn't move cannabis forward
if that was a genetic dice roll i went
backwards three steps
i wasn't happy with outcome i took plant
a and plant b and like
i said before maybe they were both
sevens or eights i wanted to make nines
and tens
i came out with more sixes and sevens
and that's not acceptable so i have
thrown [ __ ] away
let's talk about some of those projects
i have talked about
the lemon og project that i worked with
let me take a sip of this water
all right we'll keep going now i got a
clone of a lemon og
plant and i love that plant it tasted
amazing
it had a really nice balanced buzz to it
it grew very well i never had a problem
with it in the garden
i never got mites and never got mildew
it would clone very easily
you could top it it would make a bunch
of branches you could leave it untopped
it'd grow a big old giant glory bud
that was a great [ __ ] plan i thought
it would be amazing
to breed to it so i had a male i don't
remember which male i used at that time
i reversed it i reversed the lemon kush
uh the lemon og kush got reversed is
what i did
and i pollinated a bunch of [ __ ] with
that lemon kush and
everything that came from there was
complete garbage
it was not good at all some of the
plants would grow
with great vigor they would put on a
bunch of weight big fat buds but then
when you smoke it
there was zero absolute zero buzz
came from any of the offspring from that
lemon og breeding project
i think i pollinated two or three
different plants we grew them out
we smoked them and everybody went that
tastes good and it smells good but
i'm not high at all so in my opinion
that was a failed breeding project of
course we didn't take it to a lab
there could have been cbd in there there
could have been uh cb
thcv cbg there could have been a lot of
other
cannabinoids it wasn't giving us the
head buzz that we were looking for
the familiar stone feeling you get when
you smoke weed we weren't getting any of
that
it was kind of like making you wish you
would have gotten stoned because it was
like smoking weed light
you'd smoke and just go well my lungs
burn and i coughed and there's a roach
and there's smoke in the air but
i don't feel [ __ ] from that so that was
a failed breeding project in my opinion
we aren't machines uh nobody was looking
for cbd
uh cbg thcv we wanted to get high so
in my opinion that was a failed breeding
experiment it didn't make cannabis go
forward
um i think and you're gonna a lot of
people are gonna have a varying opinion
i think nightmares kind of sucked
i released nightmares we ran it we
tested it it did a great job in testing
um then i saw later on down the line
that it wasn't
i was seeing other phenotypes and other
uh plant structures that i didn't see
in testing i guess we didn't test enough
maybe uh new
environments gave us new things but
that's when i really started testing a
little bit harder was when i saw that
night nurse
wasn't what i thought it was she was
cool for me she was cool in a couple of
local grows
she kicked ass in a commercial grove
when i saw her go to other uh
smaller grows it was when she went under
leds and ceramic metal halides the night
nurse just it wasn't a good plant
in my opinion i should not have put that
one out i have discontinued i'll never
make more of that
i think i gave the last bit of seeds
away just to have them uh
gone and people know what they've got
like told them that plant's kind of
problematic it's not the best and they
said i want that it's got my attention
so they've got it in my opinion that was
not one of the best
um i made king kim grape stomper
f2s and they were [ __ ] wild
there was no uniformity in there if you
grew 10 seeds
you got 10 different plants out of that
batch of seeds so that that was a failed
experiment in my opinion i wanted to
lock in certain traits of the king kim
grape stomper og
and i did not i unleashed the beast i
[ __ ] unlocked something to where
every single phenotype was wildly vastly
different
uh there were tall skinny plants in
there there were tall fat plants in
there there were short skinny plants
there were short fat plants
there were sativa crazy sativa looking
plants in that mix there were heavy
heavy
indica plants in that mix i don't know
what i did it wasn't what i wanted
sometimes you expect that nf2 you will
expect uh
variety wild variation you'll also see
in an f2 you will see where
they strongly outperform the parents you
get a lot of improved
traits from those but they don't have
the vigor they may have the potency you
may see different phenotypes but they
start losing that vigor
so f2 showed a lot of wild traits that i
was not prepared for i abandoned that
project i did not move forward with it
i thought that was a [ __ ] mess i gave
that up
um where else are we gonna talk about
testing
uh oh platinum og i bred the grateful
dog
to platinum og uh the seeds were big and
fat they were stout
everything looked healthy everything was
fine none of the seeds would germinate
so that was a failure in my opinion
other seeds that came from that same
round of breeding
all germinated just fine they all grew
with great vigor
they harvested well they went to market
they went on the website and got
advertised and sold
but that platinum uh the platinum og too
grateful dog
was terrible that never germinated i did
not get one sprout out of the entire
batch of seeds
so in my opinion that was a major
failure that whole plant worth of seeds
[ __ ] nothing happened um breeding to
the mac
sometimes can be not a hundred percent
failure but not
a great success when i pollinate the mac
i've pollinated the mac with a couple of
different things
i get very very minimal minimal seeds
from the mac pollination if i hit it
within a rise male
if i hit it with king solomon at just
the right time i can get some seeds out
of her
i've gotten 25 seeds in one harvest
that's the best i've done
the first time i tried i got six not
60 not 600 not 6000 but
six the plant next to it gave me about 2
000 seeds
the mac plant i got six so
in my opinion breeding with the mac
sometimes is not the best success
kind of a failure but the offspring that
come from those good seeds are amazing
so i don't know that that is a complete
failure
um a long time ago i reversed golden
goat
and pollinated a headband cut with the
reversed golden goat pollen
i don't know what happened that headband
plant that received the pollen
shriveled and died within two days other
plants in the room
were successful those seeds made it to
fruition i've grown the seeds i've sold
the seeds
for some reason that headband plant was
like [ __ ] you
i'm not taking your pollen it just
shriveled up and it died i've never seen
it i've never had that happen before
and i didn't try it again i figured that
that was a one-time thing and if it did
that to me
i wasn't going to waste my opportunity
or my time or my plans or my money or my
space trying that project again i let
that one go i do have more notes let me
keep myself
on track here some reversals completely
suck
sometimes trying to reverse plants is a
pain in the ass some plants don't
reverse well
i've talked about reversing that is when
i treat a female plant
with a product that i make myself i make
my own silver thiosulfate i apply that
to a plant
in very specific intervals durations
and dilutions i think those are the
words i'm looking for and
most of the time i can create a
female plant that will produce pollen
sacs and those pollen sacs are feminized
and i can use that to make
uh female seeds however sometimes those
reversals don't make much pollen if any
pollen
at all you've got to learn the female
plant
when you start spraying a female plant
it'll react in different ways
so i will get multiple clones of the
same plant and treat them with different
sprays and find out what works the best
but sometimes i can't get those plants
to reverse properly some plants just
don't want to reverse
sometimes they're stubborn they don't
give you a lot of they're real stingy
they don't give you a lot of a lot of
pollen
so sometimes the reversals are a pain in
the ass
uh testing is really where i try to find
all of those
issues i try to i grow them myself most
of the time i'm being honest with you
right now the jack the rippers
uh the jack the ripper blueberry cookies
i'm letting tanasi get the very first
testers out of those
i don't have room i don't have time i
don't have space i want to get them out
you guys are testing those for me i've
got great faith in those
uh they went to close friends and family
before they went out
so they got one round of testing they've
passed that round of testing they're
going out to the public testers now
once i know that the public is good with
those then i will put them out but the
testing is what
really reveals the uh the success or
failure rate
in a breeding project so if i can grow
it
that's cool like i said the night nurse
i knew the male plant i knew the female
plant
i knew what to expect from that plant
the close group they could grow it
really well when it got out to other
lighting and other environments
that wasn't as stellar as i expected so
the testing would have revealed that if
we had done more testing on it which is
in turn caused me to step up my testing
eye test much more thoroughly now
i've evolved a lot as a grower as a
breeder as a business person so
um that is my brief rant on failed
breeding projects i have had a lot of
success but for every
successful breeding project there was
some sort of failure behind it that
inspired me to do better taught me how
to do things more correctly
just move me forward so learn from your
mistakes there are always going to be
failures in breeding
uh breeding is kind of like a it's a
crapshoot it's a dice roll
you're putting a bunch of pieces
together and hoping that they land
together
you've got the ingredients here you've
got the ingredients here but you don't
get to pick exactly
how much of each ingredient goes into
the mix so you've got to hope for the
best and sometimes
we create a big bag of [ __ ] and then
it's our responsibility as a breeder to
throw that [ __ ] away
flush it down the toilet feed it to the
birds maybe sprout the sprouts and eat
the sprouts if you're into that sort of
thing
but they are not meant to be put in
anybody's cannabis garden
get rid of those set yourself and your
fellow growers up for
success all right marco esquandolas i
feel like i answered that
question that was a fun one thank you
for getting me ranting on that i do
enjoy breeding and talking about
breeding so that was a lot of fun
i've got one more message here let's not
waste a lot of time let's jump right
into this one this one comes from
jason j in northern california and it
goes like this
hey rasta jeff i've been growing for
years and have great success
now with cocoa i auto water five times a
day in arrow pots
from a 30 gallon res i do not flush
weekly and this new system cranks
so that is a reference to another
episode when we were talking about
weekly flushing
this listener does not flush on a weekly
basis in coco
and let's see did they say it cranks yes
their system
cranks it says like you said if you
flush
they miss a feed and when you're in
cocoa they want every feeding that you
give them so you don't want to flush and
miss a feed
uh it says if you do flush just flush
the pot by hand
don't drain the res and do all that mess
i can flush a plant and not even
interrupt its feeding schedule
i'm confused why people have trouble
with flushing or even do it at all mid
grow i don't know why people flush mid
grow i see people on social media say
ah i'm about to switch from veg to
flower how hard should i flush
or it's the end of my normal feeding
week i'm going to flush
that's unnecessary you are stopping the
plants from eating
one solid meal you only get so many
feedings for these plants
if you go if they're nine weeks that's
63 days if you feed them every day that
is 63 feedings
if you flush them once a week that is
nine feedings they did not get
that's a percentage i don't do the math
there for me i'm not focused on that
that's a percentage of feedings that you
did not get that is performance lost
from your plants
so don't flush unnecessarily don't flush
excessively
if you didn't [ __ ] anything up there's
nothing to flush out now it says my
question
is i'm learning more about pk spiking
and calcium ramping in flour
i'm confident enough to know to try
these techniques but i could use a
little guidance on when to spike pk
and so on when should i start spiking my
pk if i choose to do so
and you guys pk is phosphorus and
potassium
i will say npk a lot in the future i
mean nitrogen phosphorus and potassium
so pk is phosphorus and potassium
or is it potassium and phosphorus i
think i was right the first time never
second guess yourself
uh it says i've heard this talked about
much on any i have not heard this talked
about on any podcast
so i hope you can help me i also want to
try some soluble
homemade calcium inputs char some egg
shells to their carbon form dissolve in
vinegar and eventually
you have calcium phosphate basically
there's a little more to it now i'm
rambling yes you are my friend but it
says i love what you do brother and keep
it up
from jason j in northern colorado did i
say california the first time i think i
misread that and said
uh our buddy jay is in northern colorado
shout out to my buddies up north i hope
you are warm because it's freaking cold
and snowy today you're probably getting
beat up up there
so the question here is about ramping up
and increasing phosphorus and potassium
later in flour and why would somebody
want to do that
as the flowering cycle goes on our
plants don't want as much nitrogen too
much nitrogen and flour will make your
plants grow stretchy
they won't get the bud set you're hoping
for so we want to taper off the nitrogen
in turn we want to increase phosphorus
and potassium that is what builds fat
buds
that's what gives us big strong plants
so our listener
our friend jason is asking when do i do
this
increase when do i start this don't do
anything too extreme
always kind of ramp up slowly don't go
from like
so many ppms or ec of phosphorus and
potassium don't double it the next day
just taper your way up slowly elevate
uh work your way up until you see that
the plants are showing you that they've
had enough the way to see that they're
getting enough nutrients
is to look for what i call the nails
getting done the tips of the leaves will
look just like they went to the
manicurist and got their fingernails
painted
see a little leaf burn a little leaf
burn little tips
little burns on the leaf tips damn that
was a lot of words my brain wouldn't put
into a sentence
little burns on the leaf tips that look
like the fingernails got done
are the first signs that you are pushing
that plant a little bit too hard with
nutrients
when you see that you can either stick
with the amount of nutrients you were
giving the plant
because you're not roasting it you're
not toasting it you're pushing it right
to the stressful point
or you can dial back just a little bit i
myself i like to see just a touch of
newt burn
i want to push them right to the limit
until i see that little itty bitty sign
of hey
that's a little bit too much when they
say hey that's a little bit too much i
say
well you're taking it so let's just keep
giving it to you and i give it to them
at that strength until the end
so taper up slowly but let's talk about
when
to do it increase p and k slowly
over weeks three through seven if you're
going to harvest a week nine you want to
start flushing at the end of week seven
so slowly ramp it up start at week three
slowly ramp up until week seven maybe
max out at week six and keep going at
week six maybe max out of week five
but see what those plants want have a
goal have a strategy don't just think
you're gonna go in there and increase
things and
the plants are gonna get bigger when you
start increasing your phosphorus and
potassium
you may also throw your calmag out of
whack so you may need to
gently increase the calcium and
magnesium as well
is it the phosphorous or the potassium
let's see potassium
and calmag will mess with each other if
you give one
too much calcium it'll mess up your
phosphorus uptake or your potassium
uptake if you give too much potassium
it will mess with your calmag uptake so
pay attention to those ratios
so slowly increase nutrients over weeks
three through seven
and then right before you flush hit them
with that winter frost one time
that'll give you that last big fat dose
of npk
and that should give you a big fat
harvest but like i keep saying don't
boost them too hard
right away because you will burn them so
watch the leaf tips for info the leaf
tips will tell you everything you need
to know
if they start getting crispy then
they're getting burned if you start
seeing yellow splotches in the middle
you may be overdoing it with the calcium
if you see
little camouflage looking patterns up
here you may be under doing the calcium
so pay attention to the leaves
they will give you all of the
information that you need now here is
something very important
write down everything that you do write
down either your ec
or your ppms of your feeding solution
you are changing things
this is a time to take notes if this
goes well you're going to want to
remember exactly what you did
if this goes terribly wrong you're going
to want to remember
exactly what you did so take a lot of
notes
write down it week 3 day 23 i added this
much npk
at this ec or this ppm write down how
many how many milliliters of each bottle
you used
like i said this could go beautifully or
this could go terribly
you want documentation and if it goes
perfectly you're going to want to repeat
it
so if you've got the notes written down
you've got repeatable results you could
just follow that recipe
do it all over again i keep saying this
the
most important part is to watch the
plants for feedback
feed them watch them you're in cocoa
you're going to get a reaction within 48
hours
you will know if those plants are happy
or angry with you very quickly
also test your runoff if those plants
are giving you
real high runoff numbers or real low
runoff numbers
and you can see if they are or are not
responding to the feedings you can
adjust from there
if they're giving you real high runoffs
that means you've got too much nutrients
in there
if they're giving you real low runoff
numbers you may be able to feed a little
bit higher
all right where are we from there you
talked about the
um oh this is going to be very strain
and very plant dependent
so you have to watch each plant i know
that golden goat crosses
you can npk the [ __ ] out of them at the
end but if you feed
the uh i'm not even going to mention
that plant there was a plant in a
commercial grow
that if we fed it too much at the end it
would just go crazy it wouldn't even
grow it would start growing in a circle
instead of growing one big bud it would
just start putting little popcorn buds
in a spiral up the stem that plants suck
to grow
so that's all about the plants it is all
very strain specific but
slowly start increasing your phosphorus
and potassium around week three
slowly build that up until week seven
then hit it with the
winter frost then start flushing from
there
and you should have excellent results
pay attention to the plants take a lot
of notes remember
the meters are great the toys are great
but the plants are always the boss
now for that organic part of your
question you said char up some eggshells
to their carbon form dissolve them in
vinegar
and basically you have calcium phosphate
that is not my area of expertise i'm not
going to act like i know
anything about that i am a bottled salt
grower
um this is not my realm i invite you to
join us on embracing organics and we can
talk about
making your calcium supplement from your
vinegar and eggshells
that is the appropriate place for that
conversation not to blow you off but i'm
going to be honest and say that's not my
area
not my expertise i don't want to give
you bad advice join us on embracing
organics
thursday nights on youtube i'm in
colorado so it is mountain time you're
in mountain time
it is 7 p.m mountain time in colorado
on youtube simply search for embracing
organics give us a subscribe
i'm not on every episode but when i'm
there it's a good time and still check
out the episodes when i'm not
those guys have a lot to teach and
you've got a lot to learn
all right i feel like i've been rambling
for quite a few minutes here i have no
idea how long this podcast has been
going but
i feel like i've done my job for the day
so this is time to wrap up the show
i want to thank you for listening i want
to thank everybody for the great emails
and the great questions
please don't stop keep the questions
coming my email address is grow from
your heart at hotmail.com
i would love to hear from you also if
you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
and you'd like to make a financial
contribution to the show all you have to
do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information to sign up and
support the show will be right there on
the screen
and again thank you for the continued
support i am blown away
at how much you guys are supporting the
show sending me words of encouragement
emails messages social media
interactions it's amazing to me that
this little show
has gotten this far i started off by
talking into a microphone with no video
and here we are 4k video lighting lights
behind me
this is amazing to me thank you i
appreciate it couldn't have done it
without you
wouldn't have done it without you it
might be a sign of mental illness if i
did this without you
all right you guys i want to thank you
again for listening please check out my
website
at iregenetics.com there is a spot to
sign up for a newsletter
just type in your email address every
time i put a new strain out every time i
make an update
i did make a special announcement
through the newsletter today i'll tell
you about it right now
if you've got the newsletter you've
already heard this but on saturday
december 19th
i will be doing a cana buzz irie
christmas
special that's right it happens at 2 p.m
pacific time
i think that's 1 p.m mountain time check
your calendar check your clock
check your schedule but at 2 pm
california time
i will be on cannabis doing an irie
christmas
celebration join me i'll be giving away
packs of seeds
our friends q grows and j.r token will
be interviewing me
i plan to bring a couple of friends on
the show not
friends that will be here friends from
zoom we'll bring them on they'll be able
to hang out with us
jump in the chat maybe we'll bring you
on the show you can ask me a question
maybe we can hang out for a moment on
the zoom during the live show
whatever happens i invite you to join us
on cannabis december 19th
at 2 p.m pacific standard time for a
very
irie christmas special cannot wait i'm
going to give away some seeds
we're going to hang out it's going to be
a irie jolly old time
what else have i got for you oh that's
where i was sign up for that mailing
list
go to the website iregenetics.com type
in your mailing address
sign up you will get notified every time
i do a special like the cannabis event
you'll get notified every time i put new
merchandise in the web store
there's new shirts up you guys go check
them out and you'll get notified
whenever i do a sale or a redrop
at one of the vendors so stay updated i
will try not to overload you with
messages but i want to keep you in the
loop so thank you
for interacting with me uh ladies and
gentlemen boys and girls that is all
i've got for this episode i want to
thank you one more time for hanging out
thanks again to everybody who sends me
all the
great content great questions and
messages i'll be back in a couple of
days with fresh new content
i want to give a giant shout out to my
friend john bendit and until next time
take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me