are you ready i'm ready let's do this
welcome back podcast world i'm your host
my friends call me rasta jeff and this
is episode 595
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to read a message
from a veteran
and then we're going to focus on a
message from our friend tonto that asks
about recycling soil
before we get there let's do a few shout
outs to a few members of the 710 club
of course the 710 club are the folks who
support us on patreon
at the 7 and 10 cent inlet level or
higher so with no
further ado let's start off with the big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to my buddy mike
let's follow that up with a thank you
shout out to aaron i want to send a
thank you shout out to kurt z
i've always got a special thank you
shout out for my buddy adhd grower
i want to send a big thank you shout out
to my buddy og purple thumb
let's send a thank you shout out to my
friend north north terps i want to send
a thank you shout out to josiah w
let's send a big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to my friend
steven smith
let's send a big thank you shout out to
a longtime supporter tree star meadow
and last but certainly not least let's
send a big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out
to my friend caribou heart genetics
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show
if you are not supporting the show on
patreon and you would like to learn how
to do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need will be
right there on the screen and of course
i do include that link in the show notes
and in the video description
to make it super easy for all of my
friends
all right i am coming to you on a cold
colorado evening i was out doing some
holiday shopping today and there was a
uh a very intense vibe out there there's
a lot of weird energy out there today
uh the past couple of weeks have been
very intense i wanted to remind you to
not let that [ __ ] get to you you guys if
you're out there doing your holiday
shopping if you're doing whatever you
need to do and life is getting to you
shake it off remember it's the holiday
season everybody is stressed to the
limit
it's been a weird year for everybody
don't let that little tiny bit of [ __ ]
tip you at the end of the year
we're gonna get a fresh new year here
pretty soon hopefully we're gonna get
some sort of a [ __ ] break
2020 is almost over 2021 is going to be
a fresh start there's only a few more
days left of this year
then maybe we can get rid of this
[ __ ] curse or whatever happened to us
in 2020
my point is don't let all that [ __ ]
get to you you guys keep your head up
stay positive
give gifts from your heart love from
your heart be compassionate
stay a good person in these times of
stress and these weird times that is
when we find out who the good people are
so don't be a [ __ ] don't let this
stress get to you
i understand it can be overwhelming it
could be a [ __ ] lot right now people
are weird people are rude
there are a lot of weird obstacles we've
got to deal with all of our christmas
gifts are going to be late because the
male is basically
[ __ ] stuck right now so don't let
that get to you it's gonna
it's going to affect you emotionally
spiritually shake it off
take a fat dab smoke a bowl give
somebody a hug
hang out with me on a podcast get that
[ __ ] out of your system let's have a
good time
all right where are we going from there
i think it is time to give my friend
ez057 a big thank you shout out
i've been getting a lot of messages from
people who've been following the show
for a long time
and they say hey bro i really miss the
rasta flag in your podcast
when i rebuilt the studio i got a lot of
brand new equipment we painted the walls
i didn't feel it was appropriate to hang
the rasta flag back on the wall i love
the flag i love the rasta culture
rastafari through and through but the
flag was a little bit
uh maybe a little bit juvenile for the
podcast so i took it down and i did not
re-hang it it is hung somewhere else
where i see it every day
i get to see my rasta flag but it's not
up for the show i felt like when i
upgraded the show i wanted something a
little bit classier i wasn't sure what
was going to go up on the wall
and our friend ez057 took initiative and
sent me a wonderful gift i'm sure you
can see behind me
we've got the irie genetics logo it says
ire genetics premium seeds it's got my
red yellow and green colors
that is the logo that comes on my seed
packaging i was blown away when i opened
it it was
better than i could even imagine and
then when i hung it up and it fit
perfectly behind me the lights hit it
the whole room just went ah so big shout
out to our buddy ez057 for the beautiful
irie genetics premium seed
decoration that is hung up right behind
me i'm gonna tip my head out of the way
just for a moment so you can see it
if you were listening to the podcast on
an audio format this is one of the times
i highly encourage you to check out the
youtube video because i'm gonna move my
stoned ass out of the way and let you
look at this cool artwork for just a
moment so check it out shout out to
ez057
look how smooth that is you guys it's
got the irie genetics up top it says
premium seeds down here on the bottom
it's got the cross in the middle it's
got my colors on it
the pattern in the background stands out
real bold i think it looks great
thank you big thanks to the artist who
created the logo and then big thanks to
ez057
for printing it and having it sent to me
it's on canvas
it's really professional it's really
high quality i was blown the [ __ ] away
that's the first christmas gift i've
received this year so thank you brother
i do appreciate it
where are we gonna go from there new
camera settings
i don't know if you notice but i notice
it i am recording with a brand new
camera setting i'm still learning this
sony a64 cam
uh if you love or hate this camera
setting let me know
i don't know what it's going to look
like until i start doing color
correcting
what i see on my little screen there is
always different compared to what i see
on my big screen
there will be some color correcting some
editing to be done the bottom line is
i'm using a new setting if you hate it
let me know
if you love it let me know i may take
your feedback i may just keep doing my
own thing but i'd like to know what you
think
i'd like to know if you liked it before
or now or just give me some feedback i'm
still learning this equipment
your input means a lot to me you're the
one watching so let me know what you
think
where are we going from there the next
important thing to talk about is
cannabis
if you're following me on cannabis you
know that cannabis has recently changed
the way they do their direct messaging
until yesterday you were able to direct
message anybody else on the cannabis app
let me back up cannabis is a free
application available for your android
or apple device
it's a cannabis friendly social media
application you can't buy sell
or trade cannabis there but you can post
your cannabis related content you can
post your dab videos
you can post your garden pictures post
all kinds of cannabis related content
and unlike many of the other popular
social media platforms you will not be
scrutinized
however if you do go posting a bunch of
booty pics and a bunch of porn and stuff
they will politely ask you to stop doing
that because that is not what the app is
for
some people have taken advantage of the
app they have found some loopholes
and they begin direct messaging people
and asking for money and sending porn
and a bunch of spam so
cannabis was forced to minimize the
direct messaging interactions what they
have done is now you can only message
somebody
if you are mutually mutually following
each other which means i have to follow
you
and you have to follow me if we want to
direct message each other
i no offense to anybody's account i
don't want to follow all 30 000 of the
people on cannabis that makes my feed a
mess
we are selective about who we follow
because we want to see certain pictures
that's what social media is for i want
to see certain things
it's not that i don't want to see your
picks it's just i'm more focused on
certain people's content it's curated
content for what i like
i don't want to be required to follow i
think there are about 30 to 40 000 users
on cannabis
i'm not going to follow 40 000 people i
was following about 60 because i enjoy
those accounts it's a new app they're
still building accounts
my point is i cannot direct message with
you unless we are mutually following
each other so it is
drastically and greatly limited the
amount of interactions i can have
on cannabis i'm not ignoring you i'm not
blocking you i'm not dodging you
that is a feature that had to be turned
on on cannabis to protect the cannabis
community i will admit
i was upset i was frustrated at first i
felt like i was being [ __ ] blocked
i felt like a lot of my interactions
were going to be limited i felt like i
kind of abandoned my community
i've got an open door policy if you send
me a message on cannabis it may take me
a couple of days
but i will reply to that message up
until now now i won't even get your
message
but i feel like i blocked off a large
member of my community i was
on cannabis from the beginning a lot of
people really appreciated the
interactions we were having there
and now those interactions are not
possible it was
necessary at first i was upset now i
understand it was necessary our
community was
at risk people were getting spammed
people were getting scammed
uh there was content happening that we
did not support or promote or condone on
cannabis
so corrections needed to be made this is
only temporary
the development team is working on new
things to get us around this problem but
until then
we're going to have to minimize the way
we message each other this may not
affect a lot of users
uh i have a larger account than many uh
folks on there so my account was
affected more by this
but it will affect everybody who was
relying on me for a grow question if we
were having a conversation or something
we can't communicate now so that has
limited us i do apologize there is a way
around
this until this is fixed if you've got
an urgent grow question that you were
going to ask me on cannabis
all you have to do is send me an email
my email address of course is grow from
your heart
at hotmail.com that will get to me also
i am getting a ton of emails from the
help tab
on the website i am not ignoring you
it's the christmas season it's the
holiday season
i'm simply overwhelmed by all of those
messages and
christmas shopping and life and family
stuff
i'm not ignoring anybody i love all of
you like my own children like my own
pets
i will answer all of those messages just
be patient with me please there are
thousands of you and there's one of me
i'm doing my best to get to all of you
you all mean the world to me without
each and every one of you this wouldn't
be the success it is i wouldn't be
successful my show wouldn't be
successful my brand wouldn't be crushing
it
so i do appreciate love and respect all
of you but you've got to be patient with
me please
i will get to you so if you can't
message me on cannabis please do not
abandon cannabis people are saying i'm
ditching the service because of this
don't do that
this is a temporary problem that will
have a real solution and things will be
much better once that solution comes
i know that cannabis is working on quite
a few updates that are coming in the
future the development team
takes some time to get stuff going it
costs money to do things all of this
stuff
and covet is slowing everything down so
once they get the
messaging fixed also another feature
that is coming is uh
the live chat i can do a live video on
cannabis and i can go talk and i can
hang out but you guys cannot chat and
interact with me
in the future that will be interactive
i'll be able to see the comments you're
leaving and i can reply to them just
like that other app that i use on
mondays
so please don't abandon cannabis i know
it's frustrating
to be limited i know there are some
weird things happening don't get
frustrated and ditch us now
now is when we need you please stick
around so just simply email me at
growfromyourheart hotmail.com
i will get back to you it's going to
take me a moment because i've got
thousands of messages in my inbox i will
answer every single one of them
individually i don't have a secretary
i don't have an intern i don't have a
social media person
it is me i read genetics is me the girl
from your heart podcast is me
and you guys so we've got to work
together it's all us together
so let's work together be patient with
me guys i do love you and i'm going to
get to your messages
um if you feel like the message was
super urgent message me again get it to
the top of the list
uh please don't just keep doing that
though if your garden is in [ __ ] dire
trouble message me again we'll get you
going
also um i want to send a big thank you
to
jostafari on the last episode i said
that i wanted a little logo this little
logo that is right here i don't know
where it is yet because it's not in the
video yet obviously right it'll be there
after editing
but the little logo that's right about
here that looks super slick on the
screen right now that came from our
friend jostafari
thank you for the the very quick
submission i think i pressed go on that
episode and as soon as it launched to
itunes and youtube
justify was like oh you wanted a logo
here you go bro so big shout out bro i
do appreciate you
you do amazing work i got a lot of
submissions i'm going to cycle through
all of them
uh jostafar i was right on top and i
loved it so his is going up today
i will cycle through all of the
submissions i got i'll put a bunch of
different
logos up on the screen over time we'll
see which one sticks the best and we
will continue to use that one for the
long term
but i'm going to audition them slowly
thank you to
everybody who sent me cool little gfyhtv
logos some people sent multiple options
some people did edits and corrections
super cool thank you i appreciate it
this time we're going to use
ja stefari's little logo right here on
the screen thank you bro that means a
lot to me
all right um where are we gonna go from
there i wrote mid
topic this isn't the main topic this is
the pre main topic
uh recently somebody was saying that if
cannabis was going to minimize messaging
maybe we should do
discord and then i opened up my message
box and i got this message we're just
going to jump right into it it goes
oh i got the wrong one on top of the
paper here let me fix that
it's all right i'm only human this one
goes like this it says hey jeff
i am a patreon contributor of the 710
club and i'm listening to episode 586.
i am a disabled veteran with ptsd from
deployments in the army
uh thank you for your service my friend
it says i am the opposite of most of
your veteran emails i am not looking for
someone to help me out
rather i am looking to help out other
veterans in your group
this is in reference to i asked uh so
a while back we asked to get help for a
grow light for a veteran in need
and um our friends at black sail market
shout out to keith from black sail
market
keith was able to donate a light to a
disabled veteran
in need and that veteran got seeds and a
light and a lot of useful advice
and they are now growing with a canon
led light
thanks to a very uh generous
contribution from our friend at black
sail market
so this veteran wants to kind of
continue that trend
it says growing this plant the past few
years has saved my life
and helped me to stop drinking non-stop
i understand that to be quite honest
with you before i got my medical
marijuana card
i was a sloppy drunk when i got my
medical marijuana card i told myself if
i get this card and i can go to the weed
store every day and buy as much cannabis
as i want there's no reason to drink
and at that point i quit drinking so in
a similar sense
cannabis saved my life because if i
would have kept drinking i would be
dead or in jail or would have hurt
somebody i probably would have gotten a
dui by now it would have gotten in a
fight i would have done something stupid
with as much as i drank
i'm six foot five and nearly 200 pounds
me and whiskey were good friends and
that [ __ ] did not work out very well
toward the end of the night
uh so yeah i do agree with you that uh
quitting alcohol and switching over to
cannabis full-time
probably saved both of our lives so uh
it's good to hear that brother i'm glad
you were
alcohol-free and i'm glad you're on team
cannabis with us it says i wonder if the
dgc could help get a discord group
started
for your podcast too that's a good
platform for a lot of us to chat
and get help from each other i'm a
successful home grower in prohibition
land
looking forward to possibly linking up
with other veteran
growers stay lifted from our friend pro
brewer home grower so you might be
making some beer which is still cool if
you're
making some beers and consuming it
responsibly that's just fine do your
thing there as long as you're not
drinking to [ __ ] black out and to
cause problems and get away from
problems
then you're cool but i really enjoy this
message
i love that a veteran is reaching out to
help other veterans i think that that is
really cool
this is where the grow from your heart
podcast and the ire army come into play
one of our good friends was kind enough
to create us
a irie genetics grow from your heart
irie army
discord page i don't know what the
correct terminology is for discord
i am learning discord i spent a couple
hours on there today
there's a lot going on on that app but
there are also a lot of cool people on
that app the irie genetics grow from
your heart group is growing quite
rapidly
big shout out to our friend greybeard
greybeard took the initiative
to create the irie genetics irie army
grow from your heart discord page
channel whatever it is
it was created by greybeard he did it
all then sent me a message and said hey
i did this i hope you're cool with that
join us and i was like bro i asked for
that
so thank you big salute to greybeard
that does mean a lot to me also shout
out to lemur priest
the captain and commander of the ire
army for being the main moderator
in the discord group so where i am
headed with this
is i am now part of a discord group
there's an irie genetics irie army grow
from your heart discord group that does
exist
as soon as i read this message i sent a
little message to lemur priest and it
said hey bro
we need to get a group in the discord
group that helps get gear
to veterans so now by the time you hear
this message on discord
this will be a thing join us on discord
make an account
find the irie genetics irie army grow
from your heart group
and jump in i'm still learning the app i
know that as you scroll you will see a
spot that says
grow gear for vets click on that that
will take you to the feed where you can
talk to people who are in need
or have gear to donate to veterans i
also
do intend to create a facebook group for
the same purpose it doesn't have a name
yet
i'm in talks i'm making sure i'm going
to do this legally i'm talking to my
accountant and a paralegal
making sure that i don't get myself in
any trouble just by starting the group
if something goes wrong it could land on
me so i'm going to find my legal
boundaries there
then i will start the facebook group to
help get veterans gear
it will be something about the grow from
your heart gear for vets
something like that will be in the
facebook group name i will make that
um by the time this episode comes out
that will be completed i have a phone
call tomorrow that will let me know what
i need to do
so uh big shout out to graybeard for
starting
the discord shout out to lemur priest
for
kind of moderating that big shout out to
everybody who already joined the discord
when i was on there today there was a
bunch of people
and then big super shout out to our
friend pro brewer home
grower for being a veteran and wanting
to reach out and help
other vets that is really super cool so
you guys join the discord group
find the facebook group that i will make
i've got to find the legal guidelines
and see how much trouble i can and
cannot get in by doing this
but i will make the group it will happen
and we will get some gear
into the hands of veterans in need these
people served our country
like i've said before i don't agree with
war i don't think shooting people and
bombing people is cool
but if somebody's got to do it i have
huge respect for the people that put
their lives on the line they sign up to
go do that
because if you start throwing grenades
at me and shooting at me i'm running
that way
these gentlemen and ladies they're
running that way into the [ __ ] fire
that is [ __ ] brave that is honorable
that is commendable
they've done a lot of work let's get
them some gear let's get them growing so
they can treat their
anxiety depression ptsd and not drink
themselves into a stupor
not dole themselves out with a bunch of
pills let's help the people who keep us
free
free freedom all right now let's move
into
did i cover all of that oh i'm going to
need volunteers i'm going to need
volunteers for this facebook group like
i've said before
i'm simply overloaded i'm trying to
interact with all of the messages i try
to be responsible for a lot of things
i am in constant go mode i'm not
complaining i love it that's
idle hands or the devil's playground
especially me when i get bored
i'm good at [ __ ] up so i try to stay
busy keep myself out of trouble
however i will need volunteers to help
me run this facebook group
it's going to be kind of an autonomous
thing once i create it introduce a few
people i want to be able to step back
and let the group
do its thing people give gear people
receive gear
so i may need volunteers to help
moderate help run that
let me know if you're interested send me
an email at growfromyourheart
hotmail.com or join the group and let me
know that you are interested
we may need help verifying veterans that
may be one thing that we need to do
we'll need help connecting veterans
we'll need people with gear if you've
got gear that you want to give away
or donate or if you're a company that is
willing to donate equipment
we could use lighting of course lights
are usually the most expensive things to
get to growers
then we can use nutrients we can use
soil we can use everything that you
can donate for a grow i'm sure that
there is somebody out there
who needs that for their setup so help
us out you guys please
help us out on the discord and on the
grow from your heart
gear for vets facebook group i think
that is what i've got for that part big
shout out to jesse also jessie
uh our friend jesse has been on the show
before actually just set up another
veteran
with another light so we've already got
two lights and two veterans gardens
and we haven't even started the grow
from your heart gear for vets program
yet so thank you guys for all of that
support
let's move forward to the next message
once again big shout out to my veteran
friend
pro brewer home grower i do appreciate
the support and thank you
for trying to help out your fellow vets
and thank you once again for your
service
uh let's move to a next message this one
comes from another person who is a
veteran i didn't do that on purpose but
i've seen photos of this young man in
his uniform
this one just comes from tonto and it
goes just like this it says hey
my name is and i'm not going to read
your real name brother um
let's see my name is tonto from alberto
alberta canada
thanks to all of the hard work and audio
material you have put out there at zero
cost to everyone which has given me
the confidence and knowledge to switch
from legal companies in canada
to a home medical cultivation there's a
lot in that first sentence there shout
out to our friend tonto
uh he gets a lot of shout outs on the
show great person beautiful family
um he said thanks for all of the hard
work and audio material
and video material tonto please check
out the video uh check out youtube
subscribe to the youtube channel
that helps me out a lot but at zero cost
yes i put this out
absolutely free i do ask for patreon
contributions but if you're not able to
contribute i don't block you i don't shy
you away i still encourage you to listen
and better your grow better yourself
the people that pay for the patreon
contributions they are covering
you also so thank you to them uh let me
keep going it says i recently received
my grow license from health canada
and i can legally grow 25 plants
bro that is nice here in colorado we get
six recreational plants and if you're a
medical marijuana patient you get six
more so we're allowed 12 plants per
household
there's no tricks you can do to get more
we used to be able to play some tricks
and
run some numbers and do some things and
get some more they shut us down on all
that so 25 is a good number bro
that would be awesome it says no words
or amount of money can show my
uh gratitude for sharing so much
knowledge with the community
uh bro this right here is what does it
this interaction is what uh pays me back
you saying thank you
you sending me pictures of the grow and
of the family and how happy you are with
the success you're having
that stuff pays me back so don't worry
uh too much about trying to pay me
and you do contribute to patreon so you
are paying me but still you don't owe me
anything
this is a beautiful relationship uh it
says your podcast is my number one way
to consume and absorb information so
from the bottom of my bottom of my heart
thank you for for providing a foundation
of knowledge for me
to build on dude those statements that
people send me like that
that is currency to me you were uh
you're knocking off all the
[ __ ] holiday stress that i had all
the shopping [ __ ] i had to deal with
all the
[ __ ] standing in line all the rushing
around all the
you wash that all away with these types
of compliments so thank you that stuff
is
currency that is payment that recharges
my soul that's nutrients
so thank you um i'm gonna keep going it
says i hope that you and yours are doing
well and safe in this time of
uncertainty
in our world history it is so weird
right now bro
i am well my daughter's well my mom as
well i think everybody directly around
us is pretty good i hope you're well too
i think we're doing all right but thank
you it says i know a lot of people
have been and will continue to be hit
very hard by coveting yes
my town is uh infected half the people
around here
i just said that i'm well my mom is well
and my daughter as well
but we all know five or six or ten
people who all have coveted and we all
know somebody who has passed from covet
at this point so yes
it is getting hit very hard it says i am
very fortunate to be in my current
situation which has left me
better off than most uh isn't it great
when people realize that they are better
off than most and it's such a good
feeling
to see you're like man i'm doing pretty
good for myself and to acknowledge that
you're doing better off than most if
that's a compassionate thing
i'm rambling today but we're gonna stay
focused it says but to show my support
and thanks
i have increased my patreon subscription
although small it still helps
i am sure uh tonto you're a family man
and just the fact that you are able to
contribute at all and you
volunteered to do so that means a lot to
me so don't ever feel like your
contribution is little
nobody out there feel like your
contribution is little some people give
a dollar some people give a hundred
dollars
ah i love the people that give me a
dollar as much as the people who give me
one hundred dollars some of those people
that give me a dollar
may have two dollars and they gave me
one of them some of those people that
have a hundred dollars
may have a hundred and one and they gave
me a hundred of them that means a lot to
me
just one dollar and a hundred dollars i
know it probably feels weird to the
people who gave me 100 to say that
you mean as much to me if you gave me
one or if you gave me a hundred i
appreciate love and respect you just the
same
but i do see the different contributions
i don't try to judge you for it i
appreciate it all
uh that just sounds weird because now
the people that gave me more feel like i
don't respect them more but
uh don't worry i think they get it i'm
going to try to talk myself out of this
circle
um let's jump back into the email that's
a good way to do it uh it says i do have
a couple of questions
i was hoping you could answer these for
me i have searched the internet for
answers but the information wasn't
available and yes when you do find the
information
you're going to find one article that
contradicts the article that you thought
was working and then another article
that will really spin your mind and give
you different ideas
so the internet can be really
challenging to find new information i'm
glad you reached out to me because i can
give you real advice
it says i didn't trust the internet and
there was no real source for the
information
you have mentioned in your episodes that
you remove any large fan leaves with a
purple stem
i'm curious as to why because that is
the first time i heard it and i've been
curious since i heard it
i've been doing a bit more defoliation
every grow as i get more confident
okay so the question is in a recent
episode i've said to
when you are defoliating to defoliate
any leaf with a purple stem
and our friend tonto is asking why i
take off the leaves with the purple
stems
the main basic reason that i say remove
the leaves with the purple stems
is that is a very trainable task if i
say
all right guys we're going to our gals
guys and gals grow team
we're going to defoliate this whole room
today i want you to go in and take off
every leaf with a purple pedial that is
really easy to follow that's a really
easy guideline a really easy instruction
you can visually see
purple pedial break it off not purple
keep moving purple
break it off and it makes it real easy
real trainable
for anybody to understand that now why
do i want those
leaves gone is the next part of this
question usually
if the leaf has developed a purple
petiole or pedial however you want to
pronounce it
that is probably a big enough leaf that
it is blocking something beneath it
and that bud site below should be
getting the light that this big leaf is
blocking so if you got a big leaf here
you got a bud development here this
pedial is probably purple
go ahead and pull that leaf off that
light is now going to hit this bud this
bud's going to get those uh
the ppfd that photon energy and that bud
will grow bigger and fatter
so that is why i remove those big leaves
with the purple pedials those are older
leaves
they are thicker they're probably uh if
you're going to get a deficiency or a
problem
those are the leaves that it's going to
show up on first those are where the
spider mites the powdery mildew go first
if we get rid of those leaves that are
those are less hotels for bugs
less opportunities for powdery mildew
and those are the oldest and biggest
leaves that are blocking the light
so there are several reasons why i'm
taking those out of there mainly
to stop blocking the light and also it
will help with
humidity problems and a giant grow we
get a lot of respiration and
transpiration in a giant grow
without that many leaves you're not
releasing that much moisture into the
air
it will help you out and we're also
mitigating bug problems at the same time
so the reason i say purple petioles is
because those are the bigger leaves
and those are the older leaves and those
are most likely the leaves
blocking my developing bud sites i hope
i made that one clear for you
because there are more parts to this
question it says could you
explain or point to me a podcast about
reusing soil
i'd like to be more eco-friendly and
save a bit i would like to reuse my soil
if there are not too many cons to doing
so
okay recycling and reusing soil can be
very cost effective it can also be very
dangerous
if you had any problems in your grill if
you saw one bug i don't care if it was a
thrip a spider mite or a fungus gnat
i would reconsider recycling the soil
and not do that
if you did not have any problems in your
grow through the entire grow
then you can consider recycling the soil
in part of your message you do tell me
that you were using
hp pro mix with added perlite one of the
first things that comes to mind is
if you do recycle that soil it's going
to be dead there's nothing in there it
is basically
just a little bag of dirt to hold your
roots there's no living stuff in there
because
at the end of your last cycle you should
have flushed heavily
you removed all of the bottled nutrients
all the built up salts
all the stuff that was in that soil you
have washed it out you've basically got
a bag of dirt at this point
there's nothing living in there if
you're using the pro mix you've washed
all that stuff out so
the very first thing i would recommend
is you need to reactivate that soil with
some microbes
i would put probably some recharge in
there big shout out to scotty reel
i would put some recharge in that soil i
would honestly uh
rinse out that soil so let me back up
get your harvest your plants
you've got your soil you got your three
or five gallon pot do you tell me what
size pots you use
um doesn't look like it you've got your
pots of soil
dump those pots of soil into a big
container uh remove
the big root balls if you can get as
much of the big stuff out of there as
you can
get a claw type thing and just break it
up i forget with the that claw looking
thing use two of those with both hands
and just get in there break all that
soil up the best you can pull out all
the big root balls
then when you re-pop the pots i would
water them
before you even put plants in there mix
up a batch of water
and put the recommended amount of
recharge in that water and water
that through your plants also maybe put
some enzymes in that same mix what we're
doing now is we're reactivating that
water
we're going to get some microbial life
into that soil if you put some enzymes
in there
those enzymes will help break down all
the old dead decaying [ __ ] that is left
behind from your old plants
it will actually turn that stuff into
usable food for your new plants that go
in there
so i would cut down the plants pull out
the root balls
break up the dirt put it into a
container stir it up real good get it
all mixed
maybe consider adding a percentage of
fresh
soil to this mix i say that because that
old soil is burnt it's dead there's
nothing in there
maybe add some fresh soil add some more
perlite just to give it a little bit of
life
so then once you've got that all mixed
in put it into your pots i don't know if
you're using threes fives or sevens but
put it into the pots
then water those pots with recharge and
enzymes that is going to reactivate your
soil and revitalize your soil
now you are back to that original pro
mix because that pro-mix is sold with
mycorrhizal mix
inside of there so you need to add
something to get you back to ground zero
so we've got it all cleaned up uh we've
got it re-uh
my code we've got an enzyme to start
cleaning stuff out i think that is going
to work safely for you
in my opinion that is probably the most
effective and efficient way to do it
make sure that you flushed heavily
before you harvested make sure you get
all those root balls out of there
put some micros in there put some
enzymes in there before you plant your
plants water it once
maybe water it twice let it dry then do
your normal transplant method
but if you had any bugs any problems i
would not do this
this is much much easier in cocoa than
it is
in soil or soilless mix in cocoa cocoa
doesn't hold anything
you can run a bunch of water through the
cocoa and all the nutrients all the
stuff will strip right out of there
then you can measure the ec or the ph or
the ppms of the water that's coming out
and you can tell there's nothing left in
there
that's not as easy in soil or dirt but i
think
you will be successful i know you're a
smart guy so i'm sure you will know
this is probably good soil to recycle or
bad soil to recycle
you can tell if you had bugs if you had
problems that's when you're not going to
want to do it if it looks healthy if it
feels good in your hands
go ahead and do it if it doesn't feel
good to your hands if it doesn't feel
good in your heart
avoid it i think you will know better
where do we go from there because there
are more parts to this question
all right the next part of the message
says during covet 19 my access to ro
water from the store could be restricted
if the situation arises that i cannot
get ro would the calcium buildup do any
harm in my veg tint
or would it just build white powder on
everything
that's a really good question honestly i
do not use ro water in my personal grows
i don't use ro water in most of my
commercial grows
here in colorado we've got pretty good
pretty clean water
at the commercial grows i use a big boy
filter that's all i use it is not ro
in a personal grow i use it straight
from the hose so
i am not using ro water and i do not
experience any issues
auro water kind of makes things a little
bit more challenging because it's harder
to
adjust the ph there's no buffering in
there so i think you will be
just fine if you are not able to get to
your ro water especially if you're using
the
hp pro mix and the nutrients you listed
there will be
no problems not using the ro water you
may need to
adjust the amount of calmag you were
feeding the plants because that calmag
is and the calcium is actually in the
oral water
but i don't think it will make a huge
difference pay attention to that
there is more it says i don't know if
you have an answer for this
but i remember hearing on one episode
not to mix liquid add-ons with organics
i'm currently using gaia greens
all-purpose with dry
dry amendments i would would i be able
to use liquid karma without doing any
harm
is there even is there any cons to
mixing
the two um i think you will be okay
liquid karma in with that organic mix
the thing to think about when you are
working with organics and bottled
nutrients
is whatever is in that bottle is
chelated and buffered
and really concentrated and who knows if
i don't know if the product you are
using
is going to kill off your organic some
of the buffers
some of the you're from canada so there
are chelates in canada
in uh the states it's shalatian we say
chile
chelate i don't know the words are
different up there i just confused my
own brain
but uh worry about the uh the salt
nutrients
destroying your mycos if you're using a
lot of organic stuff those bottled salt
nutrients can wreak havoc
on your organics it all depends on what
products you are using together some
things will work together some things
will not
it is always best though in my opinion
if you're going to run organics
stick with organics if you're going to
use synthetics stick with the synthetics
because
there may be you may just be killing off
one thing by adding the other
i am not a chemistry expert organic
chemistry is not my area of expertise
i am not the organic grower i do the
bottles and salts so i know that there's
no problem in my mix
however liquid karma is a very gentle
product that is seabird guano that is
kelp
uh there are a couple other things that
i can't remember in there but they are
uh they're basically organic
ingredients and i do not foresee a
problem by mixing the liquid karma
in with your gaia products gaia products
right
yes gaia greens okay so there should not
be a problem with that
um i feel like i've covered you do list
the details of your grow
we don't need to cover that because i
think i've answered your questions
tonto wraps it up with lastly i am very
excited to tell you
that i've ordered some of your genetics
boy am i excited to see your grow
with my genetics in there it says i
picked up some orange gasm
shout out to the orange gasm if you're
not if you're watching the video you can
see i'm wearing the orange gasm t-shirt
you can get that on my website
at iriegenetics.com click on the i think
it says irestore
click on that get yourself an orange
gasm t-shirt there are orange-gasm
shirts
lemon jeffrey t-shirts there are golden
goat shirts on the website
there's an irie genetics logo t-shirt
there is a grow from your heart podcast
t-shirt up there
and maybe just maybe by the time this
episode airs or a couple of days shortly
thereafter
there will be brand new irie army
t-shirts available on the website the
new irie army t-shirts are gray
they're on the way they're supposed to
be here monday however
shipping is basically at a standstill
right now all the tracking numbers have
just stopped updating
i am rambling now but get yourself some
irie genetics t-shirts and i will get
back into tonto's message
tonto has got uh orange gasm lemon
jeffrey and strawberry starburst coming
i will start posting pics most likely
around the fall
i heard you last night on instagram
saying no one ever follows through and i
will yes a lot of people say hey i'm
growing this strain and i say send me
pictures bro and i don't get pictures of
it uh that's cool
a few people do send me amazing pics it
looks like tanto's going to send me some
great pictures and i cannot wait it says
uh where are we they won't be the last
but i will i do have intentions oh they
won't be the best but i will
bro pictures are pictures they may be
amazing who knows what you're gonna send
me
it does say i do have intentions of
starting my first breeding project
sometime
next year so once again from the bottom
of my heart thank you for all that you
do for this community and arming us new
growers with knowledge
if you are ever up in canada please let
me know
from your friend tonto hey tonto
i may come visit you one day up there in
canada i've never been to canada
i would love to go check it out i need
to go visit my friend the dude there are
a couple of growers up there that have
invited me
so one day bro you may need to uh clear
off some couch space
a lot of couch space i'm like six five
dude but i'm narrow so i just need one
couch space
grab some space cause i may need some
place to crash one day get to smoke some
of that great canadian herb with you
hey tonto thank you for the great
message i hope i answered all of your
questions i feel like i was quite
rambling and going quite fast but i feel
like this was a good fun podcast
i want to wish you a happy holidays
brother you and your whole family a
happy holidays
i hope everything goes well for you up
there in canadia if you've got any more
questions
please do reach out if anybody else out
there has any questions corrections
comments or concerns you can reach out
as well
my email address is grow from your heart
hotmail.com and i do look forward to
hearing from you
please do not be shy also make sure to
check out the website at iregenetics.com
all things ire genetics rasta jeff grow
from your heart it will all be right
there on the website you can find seed
vendors you can find shirts
you can find the podcast you can find a
contact me tab there's a grow help tab
a lot of people have taken advantage of
that grow help tab if you've got a grow
question
there are a few questions that i ask you
on that website like what is the
temperature of your room what's the
humidity of your room what are you
feeding the plants what was the ph of
your last feed
the reason i ask you those questions is
because when you say hey ross to jeff my
plant turned yellow what's wrong
i'm going to send you another email that
asks you all of those questions anyway
and now i've skipped us both a step
you've got to tell me the details of
your room and of your problem before you
can even send me the question
that makes it easier for both of us so
take advantage of the grow help tab
on iriegenetics.com send me your grow
questions
i will answer your questions and if it's
a really good question but i feel like
other people may
learn something from i will use it right
here on the podcast i may keep you
anonymous there's an option to give me
your name on there
let me know what you think also patreon
if you feel like this episode was
educational informative and or
entertaining and you'd like to make a
financial contribution to the show
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
of course all of the information you
need to sign up and support the show is
right there
on the screen and i did put a link in
the show notes and the video description
to make it super easy for all of my
stoner
and working friends i don't know if
you're busy i don't know if you're
dabbing i don't know if you're driving
don't reach into your pocket and get out
your phone right now do it when you're
parked do it when you're safe
do it when you're not gonna get fired
all right you guys this was a fun show i
had a good time i look forward to
recording the next
episode i'll be back in a couple of days
with fresh new content i want to give a
giant shout out to my buddy willy's
armpit and until next time take a fat
dab and give your mom a hug for me