happy holidays you bad [ __ ] i'm
rasta jeff and this is episode 596 of
the grow from your heart podcast
this is the christmas eve episode i hope
you're sipping some hot cocoa
i hope you got to eat some good food i
hope you're surrounded by beautiful
people
i hope you got all of the gifts you
asked for and most importantly i hope
your eyes are as red as my
santa hat i want to start off this show
by saying thank you
christmas is the season of giving and i
have been spoiled with generosity i am
overwhelmed with the
generosity and support which i have
received from my community recently
so thank you it all started off with
this beautiful irie genetics logo here
behind me thanks to ez057 for sending me
that artwork
that was the first christmas gift i
received from the listeners and it means
a lot to me so thank you
then that was followed up by a pair of
custom grow from your heart podcast
drumsticks i do not know who this came
from
i got a package in the mail today and
all that was in the package
was these drumsticks they're wrapped in
a little
sleeve here to keep them together it
says do a fat dab and give your mom a
hug for me on one stick
and the other one says the grow from
your heart podcast with irie genetics
i don't know who sent these to me but
this is a beautiful
gift this means the world to me
podcasting growing cannabis and playing
the drums
are probably three of my top favorite
things that i can talk about in public
so thank you i truly appreciate this
gift this is
[ __ ] perfect and it means a lot to me
this will be displayed where i see it
quite often because i really like this
so from the bottom of my
big roster man heart thank you this is a
great gift i just want to know who sent
it
there was nothing in the package except
these drumsticks there was not a thank
you
oh you're welcome there was not a
christmas card no receipt
i just know where it came from i came
from the per uh the company that makes
it
no details on who sent it to me so if
you sent me this
thank you and send me a little note so i
know who to say thank you to
also i don't know if this person wants
their name set on the air
i got a beautiful gift in the p.o box
today this is a handmade
a hand knitted hat that will fit my
dreadlocks i can wear this in a couple
of different styles i could fit the
dreads up in there
or i could flip it up and have it more
beanie style like the santa hat that i'm
wearing
this is a beautiful gift i really
appreciate this because i can tell this
was handmade
for me it's big for my big old head and
it is my
uh my chosen colors you can tell if you
watch the show a lot you know i wear a
lot of blues and a lot of grays
this is blue and gray this is going to
match most of my outfit kind of looks
good with the shirt that i'm wearing
today that was not planned at all
so big thank you shout out to the friend
who sent me this i don't know if you
want me to say your name on the podcast
but i do appreciate you this is
beautiful it's nice and soft nice and
cozy it's going to fit me very well
and it smells amazing it's got some
essential oils in it so it's got a nice
aroma to it
nice lemongrass flavor should keep me
nice and calm when i wear it
thank you these gifts do mean the world
to me
it means a lot that you guys are
compelled and inspired to send me gifts
we've never met in person
you only know me through the show or
through social media and to get gifts in
the mail from you
is overwhelming and it means a lot to me
so seriously thank you guys i tell a lot
of jokes i'm kind of a smart ass quite
often
this time i'm being a hundred percent
serious thank you these gifts
mean a lot they put a huge smile on my
face so thank you
happy holidays happy hanukkah merry
christmas
happy kwanzaa whatever it is you
celebrate thank you
and happy holiday to you for all of the
support where do we go from there
i also want to say thank you to
everybody who gave me feedback
on the last episode i did use a
different camera setting on the last
episode i felt like that video came out
beautifully i do like the camera
settings i like those adjustments i've
got the lights right where i need them
i think we've got the podcast kind of
dialed in now it's time to decorate
around here and do a little bit of stuff
like that but thank you for all of the
feedback all of the support
i really like the way that video came
out this video will be edited on the
brand new
mac mini the mac mini finally made it
here so this video will be the first one
that i edit on that mac mini
i'm going to throw this video into
imovie my old editing software and see
how much faster
the editing process is in imovie just
because i want to compare the two
computers
once i see how much more quickly i can
process an imovie
then i get to learn final cut pro so
expect some
video edits and improvements in the
video here in the near future
also also excuse me for that also bear
with me and be patient with me while i
learn final cut pro
i've opened up that application one time
and there's a lot going on so i've got a
lot to learn
have no fear i'm good at learning
programs you guys have watched me evolve
and watch me learn
full-on video podcasting over the course
of
six or eight months so there's been a
lot of changes and there will continue
to be more changes and improvements i am
not afraid
we're just going to get better from here
so thank you for all of the words of
encouragement and all of the uh the
feedback on the last episode and i'm
looking for that again
in the future because i'm going to
continue to make changes
if anything falls apart if the audio
quality goes to [ __ ] if the video starts
sucking if you don't like the show
because i'm not living up to my
standards
say something i rely on you guys to give
me feedback if you say hey bro that
video was sloppy
let me know check me keep me in check i
count on you guys for that there are
some of you
who are not shy you'll send me messages
immediately and let me know what you
don't like
um i'm confident in who i am and what
i'm doing and if you have
constructive criticism i take it very
well if you're just gonna tell me that
i'm ugly and to get some sun and [ __ ]
like that keep that to yourself i know i
need some sun bro it's winter time it's
cold i'd love some sun
sell me a bag of sunshine i'll [ __ ]
rub it all over my face but it's like
20 degrees out there so sun is hard to
get right now i know i'm pale and pasty
bro
don't get don't get shy anywhere don't
get whatever let's keep moving uh send
me words of encouragement don't keep
telling me i'm pasty i already know that
but thank you
also thanks to everybody who watched the
cana buzz
very irie christmas special we got a
huge response on cannabis to the irie
genetics rosted jeff
very irie christmas special that is
still available on cannabiz
shout out to q grows shout out to j.r
token they did a wonderful job
interviewing me on that show a lot of
great questions
i feel like i did a very good job myself
not to toot my own horn i feel like i've
evolved so far as a podcaster that i'm
so comfortable on a microphone
that when i didn't have to host that
show when i was just chilling out
answering questions
i feel like i really got to have a good
time hang out with my friends so
shout out once again to q groves and j.r
token from cannabuzz and also thanks to
everybody
who watched the cannabis very irie
christmas
special also big shout out to everybody
who has joined cana buzz in the past uh
weekend or so
we're seeing a huge spike in cannabis
users and members
and i appreciate you jumping on i feel
like i i'm not gonna take a lot of
credit but i mean i talk about it a lot
i've been trying to get people moving
so thank you for finally following me
over to cannabaz
instagram has been shutting down
accounts instagram has been deleting
posts
they're at it again once in a while
instagram just decides they need to
clean up their [ __ ]
they go through and delete a bunch of
cannabis content they're also deleting a
bunch of booty pics
that's not relevant but instagram is
cleaning up so it is time to jump over
to cano buzz join me on canon buzz
cannabis is a free
social media application where we
encourage you to post your cannabis
content you can't buy sell or trade
cannabis over there but you can
post your dab videos you could post your
plant pictures you could post your
uh your but your dried and cured bud
shots
anything cannabis related you can post
that on cannabis and we will not
scrutinize you we encourage it we want
to see it uh instagram would have shut
you down
we want all that stuff that instagram
would have shut you down for so join us
on cannabis
like i said you can't buy sell or trade
cannabis but you can get great advice
you can be part of a great community
join the buzz find us on canada buzz
where do we go from there
my notes are scrambled because i did not
go in order and i just heard a weird
noise in my house that we're gonna hope
wasn't too disastrous i hope it didn't
come through in the microphone
no idea what that was we're gonna find
out in like an hour what happened here
um the cannabis special i gave away some
prizes on the cannabis
special those prizes uh other than one
order that i don't have your address yet
if you're watching this i need your
address please
um if you haven't sent your address from
the cannabis contest
please send me your address i'll get
your last prize out all of those prices
have been sent
they are in the mail please be patient
the mail is broken right now the postal
service the ups and the united states
postal service are receiving
60 and of an increase in package
deliveries this year
we can't go shopping we can't do most of
our own shopping we can't deliver gifts
ourselves
because of this weird coveted situation
so the post office and the ups
and dhl and fedex are doing all of that
stuff for us
but [ __ ] is running behind please be
uh polite passionate patient courteous
with all of the mail carriers
and delivery people even the grocery
people who are bringing your groceries
even grubhub
they deserve an extra high five an extra
tip
at least a little extra patience with
them right now deliveries are going to
be late things are going to be weird
please be patient if you're waiting on a
package in the mail
don't stroke out over it don't have a
panic attack it's in
jazz hands now it will get there when
it's supposed to get there
everything is a mess all the tracking
numbers i've been looking at say your
package has been sitting at this place
for three days
so everything is at a standstill
everything is challenging right now
please
what i'm getting at is in the christmas
time and the covid time we all need to
be a little bit more patient more
compassionate
with each other with ourselves with
those that are around us especially the
people that are doing a service for us
we've gotten used to just expecting the
mail to come we take that for granted
the mail person the mail carrier has a
family also they want to go home and
smoke a bowl just as bad as you do
they got [ __ ] to do they're overwhelmed
let's not be a dick to them
uh let's try to tip them and give them a
bonus where we can if we're able to
in these weird times to make life easier
for everybody right now we don't need to
make [ __ ] harder
life is hard enough right now speaking
of making life easier if you do
celebrate christmas don't forget to
leave out some milk and cookies and a
fat dab for santa claus
that's always good karma for next year
where we where are we going from there
i've got so much stuff written down and
i'm way off track on my notes here
disc discord on the last episode i
talked about some friends of ours that
created an irie genetics discord page
a lot of people then said how do i get
to that honestly i am brand new to
discord
and i haven't spent a lot of time on
there because i'm overwhelmed myself
with podcasting with the grow
with holiday stuff just have a lot going
on i'm not complaining i like being busy
being busy means that
uh i've got stuff to do i've got an
income i got a job a lot of people don't
have that
but i have not been on the discord a lot
i am brand new to discord i am learning
it just like you are
the thing i can do to help you is i will
include the discord link
in this podcast video description so
many people asked me how do i find
discord
when i posted the last show i didn't
know how to find discord so
uh now i've got a link for you i'll put
that in the show notes you will be able
to get to that part
all right i do have a lot more rambling
to do but this is the part where i'm
going to give shout outs to the 710 club
of course the 710 club
are the folks who support the show on
patreon at seven dollars and 10 cent a
month or higher
so let's start off with the big grow
from your heart podcast shout out
to a new supporter with a very unique
name a name i will never forget
let's send a big shout out to our friend
boner soldier
yes boner soldier shout out boner
soldier my first question
was was that major boner commander boner
captain boner
you can have way too much fun with that
shout out to our friend boner soldier
let's follow that one up with a big
shout out to jesse gross shout out jesse
uh not just a podcast supporter but a
real
true friend uh jesse and i have known
each other for years that dude's from
around here
we had a really cool conversation the
other day uh don't
don't ever think you're not in my
history book jesse when i write about
cannabis history you are part of that
you're from my neighborhood we are
pioneers together brother big shout out
to jesse gross
let's follow that up with a thank you
shout out to frank buckley i want to
send a thank you shout out to ryan
waters i hope i said that correctly it
could be riven waters riven waters
however you say it i got nothing but
love and respect for you thank you for
the support
let's follow that up with a thank you
shout out to nuggletron i don't know
what a knuggletron is but i want one for
christmas
listen to thank you shout out to dolan
let's send a thank you shout out to
trium up
opie7420
i want to send a thank you shout out to
virus smurf let's send a thank you shout
out to levity loveday
and last but certainly not least let's
send a big thank you shout out to my
friend
d brazil big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who supports the show on
patreon
of course if you're not already
supporting the show all you have to do
is visit www dot
patreon forward slash grow from your
heart there are a lot of different tiers
at which you can support the show
find the tier that cert suits your
budget the best sign up
and contribute to the podcast and i'll
give you a shout out on the show
if you join the 710 club or higher also
if you want to get your messages to me
directly
patreon is the best way to get those
messages
on the podcast i read the patreon
messages first just to be fair
all right thank you guys for all the
patreon support that does mean a lot to
me
especially during these holidays you
guys need to buy gifts for your kids
your family
your mama some of you your baby mama
some of your baby daddy
some of your side chick and your side
dude you got a lot of gifts to buy
and if you're still able to contribute
to the podcast that is awesome of you
thank you i know that money is expensive
i know that things are rough out there
money isn't as abundant as it used to be
so thank you i do know that people are
struggling i do know that people are
working hard for their money
you got to go somewhere you don't want
to be and deal with people you don't
want to deal with and get told what to
do
by somebody you probably don't want to
hear some [ __ ] from you probably
just want to go home and play the new
xbox or play the new playstation and
take a couple of dabs
spend some time with your family play
with your puppy or whatever you're going
to do
i get it you're stuck at work to make
the money and then you spend some of
that money
on my podcast i understand that is not
lost on me
i appreciate the hell out of that thank
you
big thank you straight faced big eyes
thank you that stuff does mean a lot to
me i know that money
is expensive you got to give them your
time the only way to get money is to
work
and working isn't fun that's why it's
called work we'd rather be having fun
right so thank you
for giving me the money that you worked
for i do appreciate that
i try to put it back into the show you
can see the fancy lights behind the
camera you can see the dope ass camera
that i've got
we painted i got a new computer you guys
have bought me
two computers patreon has bought two
computers that sounds crazy right
i said on a long a long time ago like
two years ago i said hey this computer's
taking a [ __ ] and it's hard to produce a
podcast
and i'm getting frustrated patreon
contributions started pouring in
i was able to pay for this macbook right
here with patreon contributions i walked
in i said this is my budget
and they said this is the computer you
want for that budget and i said let's do
it
this computer has lasted two years and
it is amazing it works very well
i upgraded to the 4k camera when i
started dumping those 4k videos into
this computer this computer started
smoking and making
weird noises it was like hey i'm a good
computer but you're asking a lot of me
so i did some research i talked to a few
of our tech nerds
shout out to reefer matinus uh shout out
to tony shout out to a lot of people
that helped me out but they guided me
toward
the mac mini with the m1 chip so
yesterday in the mail
i received a mac mini with an m1 chip it
is set up now
i think it's probably downloading
updates as we speak but by the time we
get done here i'll get to go play with
that i'm going to edit this video
in that machine like i talked about
before so that was
from you guys you guys covered the cost
of that new mac so thank you without you
that would not have happened i would
have to dug into my pocket and pulled
that out and right now that might not be
in the budget
because it's christmas time and i got to
get gifts for all those people we talked
about before
um so thank you uh patreon does mean a
lot to me your support does mean a lot
to me without you
we wouldn't have seen these upgrades the
paint the lights the microphone this mic
was not cheap you guys i'm not trying to
brag about cost but the joe rogan mike
is you gotta you gotta buy into that
club
all right where are we going from here
let's get serious 2021
is coming you guys 2020 kinda for a lot
of people 2020 kind of sucked real bad
i'm very blessed that i stayed uh i
didn't sink i didn't climb to the top i
kind of stayed even keeled i tried to
keep my head to myself
uh keep my head together and not let
myself get out of control
but a lot of people had a rough 2021.
this year is almost
over i'm hoping that this was the year
of [ __ ] i don't know 2020 is almost
over i don't know what i said i'm
reading and talking at the same time
i'm only human i'm gonna make some
mistakes but 2020 is almost over
2021 is coming up brand new hopefully
it's not jinxed or cursed or whatever
the [ __ ] happened to this year
hopefully we get a fresh new year what
i'm getting at is
you got to be good all year you can't
just be good around christmas time and
hope for some good christmas karma we
need to be good people
365 days a year when i was talking about
being nice to the postal workers
to the postmates folks to the grubhub
drivers do that
24 hours a day 365 days a year and see
how good
you feel as a person when you're nicer
to other people this weird little thing
in the world comes back and makes the
world
nicer to you well i did a podcast for
free i gave out a bunch of information i
was super nice to a bunch of people look
i got a dope ass hat i got a cool
painting and i got some brand new
drumsticks out of the deal
just for being nice to people karma goes
in circles you guys
so i know sometimes you just want to
cuss somebody out sometimes you want to
[ __ ] kick something sometimes you
just want to throw some dishes at
somebody
what's that going to do it's going to
create that negative loop let's be a
good person let's try to shake all that
[ __ ] off
let's go into 2020 with the most
positive outlook positive attitude we
can have
because when you laugh at the dumb [ __ ]
the dumb [ __ ] laughs back and goes
you're right i can't get to you
you're right and then you create a
little force field a little bubble of
goodness around yourself
and that little bubble of goodness it
only lets in goodness and it's
contagious also
if you rub up against some [ __ ] with
your goodness you got the opportunity
to shine that [ __ ] with your
goodness and the [ __ ] can't get near
you
mike used to call it my jaw bubble mike
noticed that i've got a little
protective karmic bubble around me
because i do my best to be a good person
i'm not [ __ ] perfect you guys
i told somebody to [ __ ] themselves in a
text message the other day because
they deserved it so i'm not perfect i'll
say what needs to be said but i do try
to be
the best person i can be at all times
now with that being said
uh 2021 is a fresh year coming up now is
the time to set some goals
by the time you're listening to this
you've got a week until there's a brand
new calendar year we're gonna turn
2020 right behind us it's going to be on
the back of the calendar we're going to
look 2021 right in the face
let's have some goals let's have some
preparations um
what are you going to do in 21 2021 what
didn't you accomplish in 2020 what did
you [ __ ] up in 2020 what did you suck at
this year
let's do that better next year let's set
some goals have some accomplishments
also while you're setting those goals
and looking for accomplishments
and ways to realize that you are making
progress in your life set some goals and
then you know you're moving forward if
you don't have a goal
you may just stand still and not even
know it if you're gonna if you're
doing something at level five let's get
to six or seven next year if you're
doing it a seven let's be level 10
by the end of 2021 let's improve
ourselves this year
also with that being said we've got to
adjust
and adapt to this new way of life 2021
is not going to be like 2019 it's not
going to be like 2020.
a lot of people keep saying i want the
world to get back to normal
and i hate to be that guy but this is
the new normal if you're waiting for
things to go back like they were
you're [ __ ] stuck and it's never
going to be that way i hate to tell you
that i hate to be that guy
but this is the new world and we've got
to adjust and adapt to what the world
is now all of your old plans it is okay
now
to go back and look at your goals and
plans and scratch that [ __ ] out and say
well covet and replan everything it may
be necessary to do that
so don't think that things are going to
go back to the way they were
we may get a vaccine some people will
take it some won't some are going to
have
[ __ ] conspiracy theories about it i'm
not even going to tell you where i stand
on that because i don't want the emails
but it's not going to be like it was we
will get the vaccine some people will
get treated but there's always going to
be a weirdness
that stemmed from this situation the
world will not be what it was
that's my opinion i'm getting older i
feel like i've got some foresight
i've been watching i've been paying
attention and i don't think things are
ever going to be
like they were before so when you are
writing your goals when you're setting
your plans and your expectations for
remember that 2019 [ __ ] is not the same
2021 is gonna be way different because
2020 was
[ __ ] weird so set yourself up for
success
in 2021 let's make some goals let's make
some plans
do you have personal goals do you have
financial goals do you have business
goals
do you have career goals do you have
family goals are you helping somebody
else reach their goals
maybe you're helping maybe you're a
husband helping a wife start a new
business maybe you're a wife helping a
husband
maybe you're a parent helping a child
develop something new
maybe you and your best friend are going
to start a new business be the best
partner and supportive person you can be
in 2021 let's help each other out let's
be prepared
let's get our [ __ ] together and help
everybody i feel like i'm rambling
but we've got to have a plan do you have
some financial goals do you have goals
for what you're going to do do you have
garden goals how many crops are you
going to turn in your grow room
in 2021 if it takes you 60 days to run a
crop in there that's two months you
should get six crops out of that right
it's going to take you a little longer
than 60 days because most of our plants
go 63 65
should get 5.7 crops out of that room
right how are you going to make that
happen
how are you going to veg and flower and
then have more plants in veg to fill
that flower as soon as it comes down
let's make some grow room goals and
schedules
before the year starts we've got a week
to work on this it's going to kick in in
seven days from the time you hear this
so let's start getting prepared now not
only garden goals what are you going to
learn
are you what are you going to what did
you suck at this year were you not a
good cloner
were you not good at identifying males
are you not good at scrogging
are you not good at putting up a trellis
let's get better at those things
in 2021 so set yourself up for success
improve in 2021 and have some sort of a
plan and some sort of a goal without
plans and goals i've said this
we don't move forward and if we do move
forward how do we even know
there's nothing to base it on nothing to
judge it on nothing to guide it on
set yourself up for success and have
some sort of a goal
all right you guys i think i've covered
all of the important notes i do have
some sad news
that i saved here for the end of the
podcast um
i've been following a person for a
really long time on social media
before social media was a thing this
person was a huge member of the forums
this person as a bin has been a big and
an important member of the cannabis
community and has often been overlooked
but i want to give a huge uh moment of
silence and a moment of respect
to a man known as bog the bushy old
grower
unfortunately uh damn i'm gonna cry
bushy old grower passed away recently
you guys
and bushy old grower was a very
inspiring grower he's known as bog seeds
bog genetics
if you've smoked boggle gum that is from
bog a lot of the things
that bog made were bred into the current
strains now
so i'm gonna give a short moment of
silence on a podcast here for bog and
then i'll tell you what we're gonna do
for boggs family right after that here's
a moment of silence for my friend bogg
rest in peace bushy old grower we'll
never forget you all right now what we
need to do is a community
sorry that shook me up what we need to
do is a community we need to help out
mrs bogg there were a lot of medical
expenses left behind there were funeral
costs left behind
and mrs bogg is alone so there is a
gofundme page
for mrs bogg i will include that link in
the show notes in the video description
so we can get that
excuse me i'm gonna cry for a second but
i'm okay
i didn't prepare that so that was that
was [ __ ] uh
real you guys that was what that was so
thank you for joining me for that but
there will be a link in the show
so that we can get mrs bogg some funding
and some support because
uh she's all alone now imagine being
married to somebody for 50 years and
they're gone
uh you're not gonna know what to do so
you're gonna need some help so let's
give mrs bogg
some help damn that was harder to do
than i thought it would be but
that's real merry christmas you bad
[ __ ] let's get out of that
um i want to wrap up this podcast that's
why i saved that for the end
um where are we going to go from there
if you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
and you'd like to make that financial
contribution to the show once again all
you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
what i'm going to say is if you want to
contribute this month let's send that
seven
dollars and ten cents or that four
dollars and twenty cents or that hundred
bucks
let's send that to mrs bogg this month
i'm okay i'm fine
uh mrs bogg needs a hug and some funding
so follow the gofundme
in my video description and let's help
her out
i'm sorry i'm crying you guys talk about
dead people on the show it gets to me
especially people that inspired us and
[ __ ] that's important uh you would
always see bog at the event he had
he had a booth at every cannabis cup he
was there the old guy with the ponytail
and sometimes he had a beard sometimes
he didn't he had his wife with him it
was just bog and mrs bogg at the booth
that's the guy we lost so that was a big
part of the community
a big part he wasn't as uh outspoken and
popular on social media because he was
an older dude that he was
before social media that wasn't like his
thing but when he did go on there he
always had a smile always had a good
attitude
i was always a good dude and always
encouraged us to breed with his gear
and would tell you which plants to breed
with like don't use that one use that
one
it was a really good dude so shout out
to bog shout out to mrs bogg
uh sorry you're gone and let's do our
best to support mrs bogg because being a
widow has got to be
one of the most challenging things ever
all right patreon.com forward slash grow
from your heart or
use that gofundme that i did put in the
link to help out mrs bogg
if you've got any questions corrections
comments concerns words of encouragement
uh anything like that i love hearing
that my email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com
do not be shy send me anything you'd
like to know i'll answer your questions
i'll help you out give you
guidance that's what i'm here for uh be
patient though there's just one of me
and there are
thousands of you i'm backed up on
messages but i do about twice a week
i take a fat dab and i just sit in front
of the computer and i try to answer as
many as i can
until until my add kicks and honestly uh
answering emails is one of the most
boring things for my brain to do but i
have to focus in and do it i try you
guys i really try
but then i find myself i just get up and
walk away and i'm in the garden suddenly
and i'm like oh i was answering emails
add 80d you just saw add in full effect
um also don't forget to visit my website
iregenetics.com
all things roster jeff iriegenetics grow
from your heart will be there
iriegenetics.com check it out
all right you guys that was my quick
christmas episode i feel like i covered
a lot of ground
uh we went from smiles to cries right
back to smiles thank you for joining me
for that i'm not gonna edit any of this
show this is going out just like it is
i'm gonna go put it in the new macbook
and earn the new mac and see
what uh garage or imovie does to it see
how long it takes me to post it
then i'm gonna hopefully get some more
podcasts done on that machine
i'm rambly but this was a great show
it's time for me to take some dabs it's
time for you to get back to your family
if you're not hanging out with some
family jump on a zoom video hang out
with some friends i'm sure that eagle is
on right now you could go watch
eagle he never signs out if eagle's not
on fumidora is on
somebody is on zoom on youtube right now
you can watch them join us
i may be in somebody's chat right now
hanging out just as well late at night i
jump in those chats and i hang out
it is such a good time all right it's
time for me to go cause i'm obviously
rambling and need a dab
uh i want to send a big shout out to my
friend bog and until next time take a
fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me