all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rasta jeff and this is episode
597 of the grow from your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to talk about
a few winter tips and tricks
before we get there let's do a few shout
outs to a few of the folks who support
the show
on patreon let's start off with the big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to my buddy roz and ryan
let's send a thank you shout out to atc
fool i want to send a thank you shout
out to robert
i've always got a big thank you shout
out and a fist bump for my buddy ez057
i want to send a special thank you to
papa z i want to send a big thank you
shout out to my buddy kenna organic
illinois
let's send a thank you shout out to a
longtime supporter let's say thank you
to my buddy mister
i want to send a big thank you shout out
to my friend glenn geroni
let's send a special thank you shout out
to the kianacrat i want to send a big
thank you to jake
i want to send a giant thank you shout
out to my buddy the big sexy dank
and last but certainly not least let's
send a big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out to a new supporter
let's say thank you and welcome to coach
steve
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who supports the show on
patreon
if you're not already supporting the
show and you'd like to learn how to do
so all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need to
support the show will be right there on
the screen
of course i did include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it nice and easy
for all of my friends who may be driving
or working or maybe in the cubicle
let's not get you fired let's not get
you in a car crash today maybe you're in
the garden
maybe you're trying to write down ppms
in ec let's not get distracted
follow that link when you've got a
chance patreon.com forward slash
grow from your heart while i'm thinking
about it before we get too far i want to
send a big
special thank you to everybody who
supported mrs bogg on the go fund me in
the last episode i mentioned that we did
lose
a cannabis soldier rest in peace bog i
did ask for support for mrs bogg through
the gofundme page big thank you to
everybody who contributed to that
gofundme page i got a lot of response to
that
got a lot of great messages got a lot of
encouragement most importantly we got
mrs bogg a lot of help and a lot of
funding
so thank you that does mean a lot to see
the outpouring of support from the
cannabis community
thank you i appreciate it and miss bogg
mrs bogg truly
does appreciate the support all right
where do we go from there
let's jump right into the main topic of
this episode it is a nice
cold colorado evening i think the uh the
monitor said it was 17 degrees outside
when i looked at the security cameras
that is frosty cold i wanted to update
a thing i said on a previous episode in
a previous episode i mentioned
getting your plants up off of the grow
room floor that grow room floor is super
cold in the winter
i could be super cold in the winter i'm
not sure where you are or what you're
doing
my grow room floor is really cold in the
winter time so it's always a good idea
to get my plants up off of the floor a
lot of people will use a pallet a lot of
people use a cinder block some people
use another pot flipped upside down
as long as we are getting those pods up
off the ground so the root zone isn't
super cold we are giving our plants
a little bit of help or setting
ourselves up for success
think about that cold pot sitting on the
floor it's nice and cold then we pour
water into it that water makes it even
colder the plant can't go anywhere
it's going to get pissed off so let's
get those plants up off the floor
and keep them nice and warm something
that i was inspired by that
episode was to tell you to put your ez
cloner or your turbo cloner on that cold
floor
uh just to give you an idea of what i'm
talking about if you're not following
along
a lot of us use a turbo cloner or an ez
cloner or a power cloner to make our
clones it is a clone machine
you fill a reservoir with water you put
a pump inside of that reservoir that
reservoir has a manifold
with multiple sprayers that spray water
at an upward angle toward the bottom of
our plants
it's got a lid on it you fill the lid
with clones the bottoms of the clones
hang down into that spraying area
they get misted with that water and they
make roots
the pump inside of that cloner will heat
up the water
quite rapidly in a normal environment i
would run that
pump for about 50 minutes and then turn
it off for 10 minutes so every hour it
gets a 10 minute rest cycle
to let the heat of that water cool down
the water is getting heated by the pump
the water is naturally warm because it's
in that grow that warm grow area
so it's going to heat up quite quickly
inside that little reservoir
a way we can avoid that in the winter is
to simply take that clone machine and
put it on
our cold grow room floor that will keep
that water nice and cool that will
mitigate some of the heat created by
that pump and that will keep your clones
nice and happy
this will also prevent in a little bit
of the evaporation of the water you
won't have to adjust your ph and your ec
as frequently
so that will help you out make sure to
check the ec and the ph of your cloner
on a daily basis make sure you add clear
res every five days
but if the water is a little cooler it
won't evaporate as much
so we won't need to make as many
critical adjustments
something to pay attention to is don't
let it get too cold i think 69 degrees
and above is good
for our water and our turbo cloner and
for our plants in general
you may want to go a little higher you
may want to go a little cooler but
my rule of thumb is 69 degrees is as
cool as i want to go
i don't want to go much cooler than that
that will start slowing down the root
development and the health of your
plants so
the first tip for the winter is if you
are using an easy cloner or a clone
machine
and the water is heating up too rapidly
take that clone machine and set it
right on the cold grow room floor that
cold is free
it's right there waiting for you and it
is there to solve a problem so this
episode is going to be about
uh using the things in our grow room
that we've already got
to create the best environment and best
conditions we can with what we've got
we've spent a lot of money on equipment
we've spent a lot of time planning this
out
let's try to learn to adapt to each
season and use the gear wisely to get
the best outcomes in our grow room
another big tip i've got for you the
water coming out of the faucet in the
winter is going to be cold the pipes are
outside underground it's cold as [ __ ]
out there that water is going to come
out of the
the faucet really cold it's going to be
in the 40s and 50s maybe in the 60s
depending on
how cold it is in your environment
everything i'm saying is fahrenheit by
the way i am in america we go by
fahrenheit if you're in canada or
somewhere else
you can adjust you got to do the math i
do apologize i'm speaking in fahrenheit
terms today let me make that clear
so the water coming out of the faucet in
the winter is going to be 60 degrees
i've said before we don't want to feed
the plants anything that's 69 degrees or
cooler
so why not fill your reservoir up today
before you've got to water in the
morning drag the reservoir into the grow
room
put it underneath the grow lights it
doesn't have to go right under the
lights where the plants are if you've
got some extra space in your grow
environment for your reservoir
roll that reservoir right into the grow
room and let it get heated up by the
grow room overnight that way when we go
in there to water
you've got water that is the same
temperature as the room
in which the plants are in that way
we're not giving them any shock not
giving them any problems
not dipping their feet in that cold
water be nice to your plants you expect
a positive outcome from them
let's not torture them by pouring icy
cold water
over their feets alright so fill up that
reservoir the night before the day
before if possible
and let it get warmed up if you can't
get it warm enough by the time you need
to use it i recommend an aquarium heater
you can get those glass aquarium heaters
drop it right in the water plug it in
set yourself a timer put your most of
the good the blue lab ec and ph meters
have a thermometer on there
just drop that in there let it float
around when you're walking around the
ground doing your chores just check on
it give it a little stir
see what the ph of that or the
temperature of that water is
then when it's heated up appropriately
unplug the heater clean the heater off
they gather a lot of sediment clean them
off
put it away save it for next time always
adjust the ph after the water is at room
temperature right before you feed it to
the plants
if it's cold the water will get warm and
the ph will change if it's hot it will
cool down and the ph will change
adjust the ph when it is at the
temperature at which you are going to
feed it to the plants
it will be that ph when it goes into
your plants at that time don't adjust it
when it's cold because it will fluctuate
don't adjust it when it's hot because it
will fluctuate
when it adjusts to room temperature so
adjust your ph at room temperature
then feed it to your plants now here are
a couple of other
useful tips and tricks to do with
ducting and venting in the grow room it
is nice and cold
perhaps you've got two grow spaces
perhaps you've got a flowering space
that runs for 12 hours on and 12 hours
off
then you've probably got a veg space
that runs for 16 on
8 off or 18 on and 6 off maybe 24 on if
you're one of those people
i do a 19 and 5 because that makes my
mother plants grow and i'm sure that the
big mother plants won't
try to autoflower on me if they're
getting root bound or something and it
does give them four hours to sleep
i recommend at least a four hour sleep
period or gives them five hours my math
was terrible there
i recommend some sleep period for your
plants it lets your plants sleep it lets
the
the root zone and the microbes happen in
the dark zone all that activity happens
in the night time
so let them sleep get some night time
also it gives your equipment some rest
all those lights have been running all
day all of your fans your blowers
everything has been running
if you can turn a few things off for a
four hour for a four hour period
you're saving electricity you're saving
time on your equipment which will give
you longevity out of that equipment
and like i said everything wants a nap
if i ran you for 24 hours a day and
never gave you any dark time
you may show some kind of signs of
psycho eventually some psychosis some
some craziness will come out of you so
everything wants a nap give those plants
a little nap give your gear a nap
utilize the nap time of your gear what
i'm getting at is when the flower room
goes off in the winter time it may get a
bit cold in there
when those lights shut off the
temperatures will drop
something i do is i duct the heat from
my veg room
into the flower room at night time so i
can keep that flower room
a little bit warmer than it would be
without heat that way i don't have to
buy a heater to put in there
i'm using the heat that's already being
created in one room by the lights that
are constantly on
i'm just dumping that heat right into
another room so learn to utilize
the heat that you don't want in one area
put it in another area that way you can
keep one room cool
one room will be at the right
temperature and you don't have to buy a
heater to keep that flower ring
room cool something else i do sometimes
if it's the right temperature if it
works out just right i will duct the
heat
from the flowering room into a portion
of my home
and spread that out throughout the house
to keep the entire house warm if you've
got a smaller house this will work
beautifully
a couple or a few thousand watt lights
will heat up a room quite quickly if
you've got a 10 by 10 room with 4 000
watt lights you're cranking out a bunch
of heat
instead of ducting that stuff right
outside of the house duct that into your
bedroom duct that into your living room
duct it into the basement and let it
rise into the rest of the house heat
rises
think about moving that warm air around
you can save yourself on hvac costs
heating
ventilation air conditioning costs can
go down if you learn how to duct the air
that you're already creating duct that
warm air to a useful
spot of the house to the grow wherever
you need it learn to move that air
around and utilize it that way we don't
have to spend more money on heat
there's already heat let's use it let's
get warm with it
so you can duck that heat straight from
either your flower room or your bedroom
right into your house right into your
bedroom if you've got a bedroom that
gets kind of cold at night
if your basement doesn't get warm enough
if part of the house doesn't get warm
enough
run that ducting right to there and just
duct that heat into
the coldest part of the house warm
yourself up it's kind of like recycling
you're saving money
and it's grow room heat that needs to go
somewhere anyway send it some more
useful
what else can we do there is humidity to
be dealt with
a lot of times the flower room will make
a lot of humidity you got big flowering
plants in there
you got a bunch of humidity going on you
just fed if you've got four
lights in there you got four seven
gallon pots per light that's going to be
a lot of humidity when you water those
plants maybe you got more in there maybe
you got less
we're going to create humidity my point
is let's learn to duct that humidity
from the flowering room into the
vegetative room the veg room loves high
humidity you're not going to run into
nearly as many problems with a veg room
with high humidity
as you would a flowering room with high
humidity so let's put a blower at the
top of the room
or a duct at the top of the room that'll
suck all that humidity because the
humidity is at the top
let's suck that heat and humidity out of
that room and move it right into the veg
space
all you need is a four inch blower and
some ducting if you want to use a
humidistat that will tell you how much
humidity is in the room
you can set a humidistat to say when it
gets to 70 or 80
humidity i'm just guessing random
numbers it's got a dial on it when you
get it to that when it hits that setting
it'll kick on and it will move your
humidity when it gets past that
threshold it'll turn it right off it's a
switch that plugs into the wall you turn
a dial
you set it to the amount you want then
you plug your blower into there
there's a sensor that hangs in the
middle of the room and it says oh 80
humidity i better turn on this blower
and it'll blow that duct
it'll blow that uh air right through the
duct right into your bedroom and now
your bedroom gets a little extra
humidity and you don't cause problems in
the flowering area
it's all about utilizing what is already
there with minimal equipment this will
save you problems this will save you
money
you probably bought a bunch of excess
gear that you didn't need anyway because
people get excited when they build their
grows let's learn to use that
to our advantage um also
a lot of people this is kind of old
school tech but a lot of people are
still doing the old school tech a lot of
people have
ducted lights vented lights so you've
got a light
i'm going to try to explain this the
best i can you got a light fixture that
hangs from the ceiling
it is a square fixture the bottom part
has glass under it so there's a bulb
inside of there but instead of sealing
that bottom we put glass in there so the
light can shine through the glass and
illuminate the grow room
they put a hole on one side of the box
and a hole on the other side of the box
and we can run ducting across that that
way we can move the heat away from the
light it doesn't enter our grow space
and we can duct that light that heat
wherever we need it
a lot of times you'll put several of
those lights in a chain you put a blower
at one end
you blow a carbon filter a blower uh
ducting and then your light chain
however many lights you're going to put
and then you do ducting right outside of
your grow facility right out of the room
right out of the window however you're
gonna do it
duck that air outside so then the air
goes over your lights and outside
that way you're cooling off the lights
none of that light heat is heating up
your grow space right
why not turn that blower around and suck
that cool air
over your lights to cool the lights even
more at that point i would duct the
i would do a complete loop i would have
air coming in from outside
going over my lights then it would do a
u-turn one into the room and go right
back across the room
go through all the other ducting every
over every light then it would go out
it would go right against the wall and
that duct would go right out of a hole
i use the blue foam insulation to cover
windows and you can drill
six-inch holes through that foam
insulation very easily and run your
ducting right through that so i would
create a continuous loop
that way none of that heat from your
lights makes it to your grow
and you can cool those lights rapidly by
pulling that
17 degree air over those light bulbs
that'll cool it very very quickly don't
introduce
that 17 degree air into your grow room
right away
then you'll start getting frost and
icicles and that will encourage you to
get
powdery mildew but if you can reverse
the duct and keep that loop
and get the air over the lights and
right back out that will rapidly cool
those grow lights
a lot of times it's going to get too
cold in your grow room
what's to stop you from hanging more
lights most of the time the thing
stopping us from putting up more lights
is heat it's winter time let's put up
more lights don't buy a heater don't put
a heater in there that is a waste
more light is the way to go the light
will create the heat for you
put more lights in there and warm up
that grow room with more whites of
course if you want to do a heater do
that
you may need a heater in the night cycle
if you don't have a way to keep it warm
if you don't have another room to dump
the heat
into there but instead of buying a
heater i almost
always buy another grow light something
else to think about is our light
schedule
are we running the lights at the
appropriate time electricity is overall
cheaper at night time during off-peak
hours your electricity is cheaper
everybody's working everybody's hustling
and bustling everyone's at the store at
the office doing stuff
from like eight to six in the day eight
in the morning to six in the evening
everybody's busy doing [ __ ] electricity
is much more expensive than
i think around eight or nine o'clock
your electricity price will drop
it will reduce a little bit let's run
more of our electrical components
during that off-peak hour then it's a
little bit cheaper to run all of your
equipment
also it's colder than when the sun goes
down it gets cold outside
let's turn on the lights while it's cold
outside to keep that grow room cold
during the coldest part of the day
then when the lights go off during the
day it's not super cold
outside because we got the sun helping
us out a little bit we can use
that uh cheaper lighting the cheaper
electricity
and the sun competition and the lights
as heat use it all together
to create a cheaper more efficient grow
environment
you can do that a lot of times we'll do
that in the summer because it's too damn
hot during the day to run the grow
lights because you're competing with the
sun your air conditioner is trying to
cool that room you got lights and the
sun to fight with
it's going to get real hot in there run
your lights during the night time during
the
summer also run them during the night
time during the winter because it gets
so cold in the dark time
and the night time that you want those
lights to heat up your space i hope that
made sense because i jumbled my words
trying to say that
it made sense to me one thing that is
helpful
these colder temperatures are going to
provide beautiful
colors for our plants if you do get that
grow room a little bit colder in your
night cycle
especially toward the very end of flower
that flush phase if you can get it a
little bit cold in there
that is going to turn your plants the
leaves will get purple they'll turn red
they'll get yellow fall colors
i really find beauty in those fall
winter colors when the plants are
finishing
that always comes from my winter crop my
some of my best photos are my winter
crops a lot of people say
that their crop around halloween is
always the best indoor crop that they
pull it's so easy
because we're not competing with all the
heat from the sun we're not getting as
much humidity because it's not as hot
this is prime opportunity for a
beautiful winter crop
uh where am i gonna go from here i'm
gonna quickly skim skim my notes make
sure i didn't skip anything because i'm
on a roll
where are we all right here we are
um another thing i want to talk about
this is not a seasonal related this is a
trick that i learned
i think i learned this one i'm gonna
give credit where credit is due i think
the very first time i ever saw this was
my friend colin gordon from the ethos
collective is who showed me this
uh if you are getting big giant chunky
buds in your grow room and this works
for any environment
uh wintertime summer time this is for
big chunky buds in a humid room
if you're getting big fat colas big fat
buds in your grow room
you get the opportunity for powdery
mildew or bud mold
uh more likely bud mold is what i should
have said in the middle of those big
buds you got a big
[ __ ] gallon milk jug size bud you've
got a bunch of miniature buds growing up
a stick and they're all kind of
gathering up the middle of that stick
uh i take i could take i would recommend
you take
popsicle sticks or tongue depressors and
kind of
peel that bud off of the stick a little
bit don't break it just pull it back
from the stick you can grab
one little bud on a giant cola you can
pull those buds off and put a popsicle
stick in there or a tongue depressor in
there
let the bud rest up against the stem
again and now you're going to create air
space between the bud
and the stem and the other buds on that
stem and you will
drastically reduce your opportunity to
get bud mold in the middle of that
gigantic bud
i'm going to try to explain that one
more time just to make sure i get it
clear you got a big cola
it's growing it's not really one big bud
it is multiple buds growing really well
together on one big stock is what you've
got there when you got that big cola it
looks like a big glory bud
once it gets to the grow once it gets to
the dispensary environment it's going to
get cut down into little buds that's a
bunch of little buds on one stick so you
got your big stick
you got a bunch of little medium sized
buds growing off of it
so you got a stick with the chunky
nugget growing off and a chunky nugget
growing off and a nugget
you can just pull that nugget out and
down a little
bit and slide a popsicle stick in there
or a tongue depressor in there
and let it close on there and hold the
stick itself and you will create
air space now we're just creating we're
putting a little gap between the other
buds and the stick
we can create some airflow in there
think about all the moisture that is
trapped in there think about all the
microbial activity that could develop
inside of that tight
uh space your buds are kind of spongy
they hold a lot of moisture there's not
a lot of airflow so let's open them up
make sure we got a fan in there and that
popsicle stick tongue depressor trick
may
prevent some of the moldy buds that i've
seen happening in commercial
environments you guys are striving for
those giant buds and you're getting them
and then at harvest time we realize [ __ ]
this is all moldy in the middle
i can tell you that i chopped down a
white rhino plant this was probably 10
years ago
and mike will testify to this i chopped
down a white rhino plant
that had a top cola the size of two
2-liter soda bottles the bud was
probably 30 inches tall i can't even
reach as tall as it was the entire plant
was just this one cola
and it was as big around as a two liter
soda bottle
all the way up it was huge and girthy we
were completely excited about that we
took so many pictures
we've never grown anything like that
i've never done anything like that again
because once we harvested it we started
cutting it apart and the entire middle
of that whole plant was moldy right up
the middle so all of that product went
into a big-ass trash can and it went out
to the trash it was gone it was
destroyed
that was considered waste at that point
the way i could have prevented that
was obviously a little bit more airflow
but how am i going to get air moving
inside of that big giant donkey dick of
a bud
i had to open up those buds a little bit
put some tongue depressors or popsicle
sticks in there
or something non-porous that isn't going
to hold moisture you can use something
plastic if you've got it
tongue depressors and popsicle sticks
are readily available they're very
affordable
you can break them in half you can get
two uses out of one popsicle stick
just spread them around your buds that
will really help you out i know that
sounds random and chaotic to a lot of
people but if you've got a big grow
that's at risk of losing product to uh
bud rot
especially outdoors and in a big grow in
a humid humid area
this will be very useful to you all
right i'm going to skim one more time
make sure i got all my notes i feel like
i covered everything
i don't want to go too quickly the water
is cold
exhaust your heat move the humidity um
don't feed the plants too cold of water
run the lights during the
night or day depending on your
environment add more lights to keep it
warm
lower temperatures are going to get your
plants colors popsicle sticks for giant
buds
i really think i covered all of my notes
i want to thank you guys for hanging out
for a quick short grow from your heart
podcast episode
we're right between holidays here so
don't hold it against me that i gave you
a quick short episode as soon as these
holidays are over as soon as 2020
one kicks in we'll be right back on our
normal schedule
you guys be ready you got a brand new
year coming up set some goals
have some plans we're gonna talk about
that stuff in the next episode
um if you feel like this episode was
educational informative and or
entertaining and you'd like to make a
financial contribution to the show
once again all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the info you need to support the
show is right there on the screen once
again big thank you
to everybody who has supported the
podcast we had a wonderful year on
patreon
thank you i do appreciate all of the
support also make sure you check out my
website iregenetics.com
all things grow from your heart all
things ire genetics all things rosta
jeff are right there
on iregenetics.com
also check us out on cannabis you guys i
recently
surpassed by the time this episode comes
out i will be at 50
000 cannabis followers by the time this
episode airs
i should have 50 000 cannabis followers
that is amazing that's tremendous
i recently surpassed my instagram
following i've blown my instagram
following out of the water 50 000
followers means a lot to me on cannabis
if you're not already following
download cannabis it's a free social
media application i talk about it a lot
it's available on your android or apple
cell phone mobile device
uh it's free go to your app store give
it a download create an account
log in give me a follow click like on a
bunch of my pictures
and check it out join the community and
catch the buzz on
can a buzz also if you've got any
questions corrections comments or
concerns i would love to hear from you
my email address is
grow from your heart at hotmail.com
don't be shy send me your questions send
me your grow updates
let me know any mistakes or corrections
you need to make mistakes i made
corrections you need to make you can
message me about that one if you want
um i think that's all i've got for you i
want to thank you for hanging out i hope
you have a wonderful safe new year
if you're drinking don't be driving if
you're driving don't be drinking take
care of those around you
keep a good eye out on everybody i want
everybody to make it into 2021.
2020 was rough you guys let's set
ourselves up for success in 2021 and
have a good year
together take care of yourselves take
care of everybody around you
uh grow from your heart don't be a dick
i think that's all i've got for you
ladies and gentlemen i'll be back
on new year's the next episode comes out
on new year's eve
i look forward to joining you then i
want to give a giant shout out to my
friend farmer john
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
you