I don't know about you guys but I've
been walking around singing Noble
Nebraska for like a week now yeah yep
Nebraska yeah it's a yeah the only
downfall is they used a lot of inside
jokes you know like and they tried to
explain him to the best of the ability
but it's it's more one of those things
you had to bend there's getting no I was
just laughing every time they would say
something like ham wallet or so that the
ham wall at the beginning was I don't it
got pushed off like it wasn't anything
and the idea I was letting [ __ ] just
slide by because the more I was like ah
[ __ ] the more it came out it is fun to
do but it was fun just letting some [ __ ]
slide too and you you would hear one of
them like every everyone throughout the
podcast like you edit this right like
just a little bit you're like no no I
just yeah I'm too lazy for that [ __ ]
recorded three hours with those guys and
I just cut out an hour and 20 right out
of the middle they started playing no
message and I was like I'm gonna record
from here you guys are getting recorded
they didn't know I'd been recording for
like a full hour kind of like you guys
don't realize I've been recording for at
least a minute hey you guys already do a
podcast I'm ready let's do this I'm
gonna drop an intro song
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 60 of the
growth from your heart podcast your
source for cannabis news education and
conversation if you're a new grower if
you're a professional grower if you're a
new smoker or a veteran dabber if you're
a cannabis activists or even someone
who's just curious about the current
state of cannabis this my friends is the
podcast for you I'm your host Rasta Jeff
thanks again for joining me as always I
have to send a huge big thank you shout
out to the mystic roots band thanks to
say thanks for letting me use their
music on the show big huge thanks to Kat
coot and the entire mystic roots crew so
we're hanging out today I got Mike and
Adam at the table how you boys doing
good man good good good I'm DTF oh I'm
dab the [ __ ] out today bend a bit on
Sumter pack shatter I also got some
black cherry Kim shatter from the garden
of Weeden it's been a good day when when
what day is it that you're not dab the
[ __ ] out though I mean um early in the
day really uh early in the early in the
Merlin yeah I don't know people I
surprisingly don't dab early in the
morning I'm not an early-morning dabber
I try to wait until I at least get a few
things done yeah I mean I've come over
here a couple times and it's like 7:10
you know first one of the day yeah you
gotta do work before you dad out I get
uh if I dad too early I get lazy I just
wanna go right back to bed and then if I
dab during work when I'm trying to get a
lot of [ __ ] done I just get out of focus
I'll do the same thing to myself a
flower yeah right just try to wait and
reward yourself a little if I Grateful
dog right after breakfast like it's
gonna be a real good day yeah yeah my
buddy Mitch Inasa shout out Mitch he
said that when you're dab in every hour
becomes 45 minutes of productive time so
then I kind of believe him I would have
agree I would argue with that between
sativa and indica you know I'm saying
you're a real big sativa guy and usually
if I come over hangar real ripped-off
sativa dad's I don't go home and look
good know I'm like what can we clean
where where do we need to I kind of get
that way but I end up doing some useless
[ __ ] like something they didn't even
need to be don't like my desk is
organized yeah completely organized all
the dishes are perfectly clean in the
kitchen but it was useless I should have
been doing way different stuff at the
time yeah without a good sativa though
the spring clean that just happened at
my house would not have
and true that sure a lot of stuff got
extra attention that it definitely did
deserve like all of my books didn't need
to be pulled out and dusted and put back
on a shelf but it happened yeah see that
that's the [ __ ] that some damsel do -
yeah that was a little too much - diva
when I catch myself tchen I'll take a
DAB and then I don't know how I do it
but I'm on Instagram suddenly I don't
know what happened I'm standing just in
the middle of a hallway or in the middle
of the kitchen or just flowing around
you yeah and I just Instagram and like
the [ __ ] and don't even know it
like what was going on here and my head
a minute ago and what am I supposed to
be doing so I don't dad during the day
sometimes but when I do bro uh a dad
once I start dabbing it's game on
keep your dabs per hour high once you
scratch bro
DPH deep that sounds dirty don't say
like that don't say like that because
we're gonna talk about I've got some
news articles I want to read we're gonna
talk about some Jamaican stuff I'm gonna
mention something about ladybugs that'll
listener emailed me about and if we have
time I might talk about my Bo Kashi
bucket I'm not sure how far we're gonna
get with all the news articles that I
found one thing I do want to mention
it's our birthday what what episode 16
is the one-year anniversary of the
podcast thanks Mike great man I was
wondering when this was actually
actually know how you were gonna do it
this will be out like March 29th I think
and I think today the 28th is the day
that the first episode was ever released
awesome so let's all seek some tabs for
the birthday and then shoot some
commercials all righty um I'll give you
guys the option I've got some SF vog
I've got Gorilla Glue and I've got
lemonade which one should we dad here
you already know that I'm gonna pitch
towards the sfv because it is a it is a
dank strain from tarp X and mmm yeah you
said laminated my tongue to the thing
all right well that's the one I haven't
tasted yet so I mean surely by the end
of the show we're gonna dab all three
let's start with the sfv and then we got
to give Mike little baby dabs but we'll
start with a sfv um this is the San
Fernando Valley Kush made popular though
I don't even know uh it's really popular
from the Cali connection is who put out
the seeds but people are going to be
like they didn't make it popular but
they put out the seeds of the sfv and
it's a great breeding strain it tastes
good
super-nice hi Tirpitz blasted extracted
this and everything Terp x does is
quality they change their labels i like
their new logo shoutout also check out
their new website and they do out of a
job dude I have been driving around in
my car and just randomly like I've got
Tourette's I'm like no man Nebraska for
the past seven to ten days really oh man
my wife has no idea
my wife is good but she has no idea what
it is but she's definitely heard it like
every every time I'm sitting and they're
hitting the bowl it's it just it comes
out whether there's no melt or not um so
yeah I've got maybe another day before I
get the deadpan look for my night stop
pause the song explain what the [ __ ] are
they talking about save time I've heard
this is it no yeah as I was setting up
for the podcast I was reading a news
article and Mike just I'm gonna give you
a listen and hit play what are you
giving me an oh [ __ ] okay he's playing
the know melt theme song and they struck
in my head man I've got it you got a
play to get out of your head right yeah
you download it to your phone don't you
see you have it forever yep you haven't
forever yeah that would be there's that
song number three on your phone cuz I
know your playlist I've got like most of
the episodes of the podcast that I have
that new afroman cut uh uh because I got
high because that's just that's the only
song on your phone right only song I'm
gonna put some order back to this show
uh the SM Gavin tastes delicious
it may be coffee little that's my fault
is a big dab it tastes really uh it's
earthy cushy
maybe a hint of coffee ah yeah it's got
a good nice earthy cushy flavor I
definitely approve I like it uh it's not
a sativa that's for sure it made my eyes
go boom and it made me get a little slow
I approve I approve I'm gonna have to
smoke a sativa here in a minute so I'm
glasses uh interested in this lemonade
my new favorite turf extreme at least
this run this time I spoke quite a bit
of sfe between the water ashen was thick
on what the buddies well my buddy smoke
you know yeah the last I got for grant I
got four flavors last time I got the
lemonade I got the Kim dog got the girl
igloo and the one I got was the chemin G
Oh
and that Kenji was it's gone now if that
tells anything right it was my favorite
dude it was so sure so that Lecter was
good then that was it was definitely
delicious the flavor on it was insane
everyone this is pretty killer too with
the flavor of that coming stuff I didn't
know I noticed through this like I mean
I didn't just hack off of that and when
a huge dad but this had been a um an
idea it made me feel in it idea it made
me feel good
so I was yeah I'm nice and mellow now I
definitely have heavy eyes I've noticed
that I don't get the eye high from dabs
like I used to when I would smoke just
flowers in red or um you know neat that
your eyes just get droopy and they just
feel like [ __ ] back in the day to dry
so just get so happy and everyone would
look at you and be like you're so high
bro open your eyes you know I can't uh
dads seem to make me bug-eyed like it's
so intense that I'm like oh I'm on edge
with it odor and I kind of Miss the eye
high and I'm getting that from this SME
right now alright while I'm dabbed out
of [ __ ] did everybody get a DAB you got
one right now you're not coughing dude
what happened appropriately-sized Deb
yeah Mike's got to take dabs for ants
over there honey disc we've been
rambling for a minute I do need to do
two commercials
somebody's gonna shut up the bird a
lesson right this podcast is brought to
me by our good friends at hydro indoor
growing supplies I grow and our growing
supplies has two locations to serve
Colorado visit the Denver store 62 71
Beach Street or check out the Pueblo
location 618 East 4th Street in
beautiful Pueblo Colorado check out high
growth for competitive pricing and a
great selection of indoor grow supplies
check this out guys when you go to high
grill indoor growing supplies when
you're checking out tell them I listen
to the girl from your heart podcast
they're gonna give you commercial
pricing on everything you purchase
you're gonna pay the same amount that I
pay you're gonna pay what atom pays
you're gonna pay what Mike pays you're
gonna pay what Jesse pays and Jesse
works there we love a deal we get a
better discount than Jesse gets and he's
the manager at the joint and I'm gonna
be honest like you don't need a discount
there we are the best price thing in
town be part of that you said we are the
team well I'm just I think we all kind
of are a part of high grow because we
all love burn and burn to this he's my
brother man Jesse's our brother but
burns a young lady who weighs like a
hundred pounds and they get a truck
dropped off and they just throw the
truck out there and they're like here's
all your [ __ ] burn and so we
lever and we wall grab a pile of soil or
whatever we can move for so yeah we're
all part of team Hydra I can call us
that community was what I would say yeah
and they let us have our meetings back
there from the next Grill meeting April
26th at hydro indoor growing supplies I
think the meeting will start at 6
o'clock I will have something prepared I
will speak about something I don't know
what it'll be yet Jesse and I will
collaborate and talk about what needs to
be discussed if you've got an idea and
you're coming to the meeting let me know
what you'd like me to talk about the Gro
meeting April 26th at Highgrove indoor
growing supplies I'll talk about that
more in the future keep reminding you
guys and I felt like the last meeting
like a lot of stuff has talked about
pretense but then when it came down to
who's got any questions everybody was
maybe a little embarrassed to speak up
in front of the crowd and it wasn't it's
because you're in a community growers
and I don't think that should be the
place to be embarrassed that's the place
to get help true I mean yeah but nobody
wanted to show that they were yellow
belts when there were fifth degree black
belt in the room absolute lot of talent
there it would have been rough to be the
first kid to say I've got a question
speech recommended that we write down
questions and put them in a hat and that
way nobody knows who yeah I nobody knows
who brought us that the silly ask
question we do does not abuse you're
gonna get a lot of that yeah but well
act we gotta treat them the whole reason
that meeting is to spread knowledge to
everybody I had training was only one
man yep all right one more commercial
the organic portions of this episode are
sponsored by my great friends at the
rocky mountain worm company what's up J
I hope you're listening
here's your advertisement bro visit the
rocky mountain worm company in Colorado
Springs for fresh worm castings African
night crawlers red wigglers and all of
your organic soil amendments the Rocky
Mountain worm company has dragonfly
earth medicine products in stock now
Rocky Mountain one company will ship to
your door you can get the same worm
castings once again that I use that
Jesse uses that Adam uses that Sean uses
that half of Pueblo uses right now that
most of Colorado Springs is using you
get those showing up yeah we kind of
helped them out with that so shout out
to the Rocky Mountain worm company you
can get them shipped right to your door
check out Rocky Mountain worm company
com you can get all the same [ __ ] I'm
using the prices are amazing the
products are great if you visit the
store at 4:11 Tijuana Street and
Colorado Springs make sure you tell them
you heard about them through the podcast
up shake their hand be cool them those
guys are friendly they're not just
businesspeople they are community
members of the grill community and the
hype on that stuff is real life is real
bro ah it is
Mike's here mike has the excuse my
coughing there we go I'm better Mike has
the privilege of taking my old soil out
of the pot and putting it into the
recycling bin for soil it's a serious
privilege [ __ ] do your tay mover yeah
I get to play with dirt all day did you
see and in the past 20 pasta we have
harvested have you seen a massive
increase in my root mass yeah the the
amount of root material in these pots is
insane lately people I've been I've been
breaking up dirt pots for sighs [ __ ]
disgustingly long in my time now I think
about it but uh everybody's been
breaking over old pot and had like a
handful of little tiny sad-ass root
there and lately you've got to smash the
root ball against the wall for a little
bit just to give it some dirt back it's
been intense and they're not in there
any longer you're gonna say we just let
them grow more time now they're actually
in there shorter because I ran this crop
really quickly I wanted to get something
that's kind of cropped up they're not
getting root bound there's just an
insane amount of incredibly healthy root
material and see that's kind of what I
was pointing at is like if you're using
that would it be better to kind of
transplant more you know more often or
just because we own a larger pot would
have been helpful but it wasn't
necessary it wasn't to that point a
larger pot from the get-go
I wouldn't necessarily say transplanting
more frequently would be a good thing
there's a lot of stress yeah but you
know we've gotten it down not to brag on
ourselves where you can transplant some
[ __ ] where there's like zero stress
where the plants are even happier
they're like oh that was great
all right they asked you to stretch a
little more at the right yeah so once
you guys get comfortable I like to go
myself I go from the cloner into a cup
actually I've been introduced to a new
product that I really like it's just
called a clone cup you can order them I
check them out on Instagram I don't
order to order them they were kicked
down to me as a gift for a trial a trial
and I really like them they're harder
than a normal cup they're a little
bigger than a normal cup they're raised
a little and they've got holes where
they can drain a little bit better so
the clone cup company I really like
those if you guys
and I could use like 90 of them be cool
something let's read out follow colors
were slipping yeah
so I go well the solar cups you got to
poke him yourself and they squeeze
together when you try to scoop dirt into
them these cups I'm saying that's hard
you can wash them and reuse them you
don't have to keep going to Walmart
comes from home yeah you know so I go
from the cloner into that cup and then I
let it get kind of kind of close to
rootbound in that cup but not I just
want to see the thick roots on the
outside if I picked up the dirt I want
to see roots but I don't let the plants
start to stretch in there and then I go
to a three gallon and then sometimes if
I'm doing like a breeding Fino hunt I'll
run them in three all flower them out in
the three gallon when they're real short
if I'm going bigger I'll throw them into
a 7 gallon and flower mount in a 7 and I
went the same amount of time I just
added grow Kashi worm castings the
dragonfly Earth medicine root dust the
black one I can't think of the name the
battle's not over here just simple stuff
like that and I did a little bit of fish
Hydra slate and I've started to cut out
the OGT I'm not using OGT now dude my
roots were huge yeah
SuperDuper huge I could have used a
bigger pot but I don't think it was
necessary I think I did the right amount
of - they weren't root bound but the
roots were spaghetti like I just know
that since we've started using them
having them in cups is almost like is it
is it okay today is it okay today yeah
you know it's you're literally it you
have to be on your stuff because if you
leave them they're gonna Scotts way
quick and that's I mean regular plants
do but with the worm casting it is it's
figure sad so I'm gonna go how to order
a little bit I know I said I had a bunch
of news but since we're talking about
all this organic stuff another thing
that I've noticed that has really
contributed to the improvement in my
plants I use it in my bedroom I use it
in my flowering room everything but the
clones gets it the clones get it now as
soon as they go into the dirt I feed at
this Shawn gave me something called a
bow Kashi bucket the Bokashi bucket is
basically a five gallon bucket with a
piece of piece of plastic as a catch or
a shelf in there then that shelf has
holes in it and then underneath that
shelf is a spigot and the idea is that
you throw we'll talk about more in a
minute with more detail but you throw
your chute in there
and it starts to get funky and then you
can turn the spigot and get the [ __ ] out
is why that little shelf is in there you
get juice out of it juice juice nasty
it's like a miniature compost pile
juicer okay so best way didn't set up
like a Gatorade great a great way
because I was going way I'm taking way a
different way so you take the Bo Kashi
bucket and when I got mine I put the
little shelf in there it's got a little
shelf that you put down some of them
have it pre affixed there's different
models of the bucket that you get so
there's a little shelf in there with
holes in it I put down a thin layer of
newspaper just one sheet of newspaper so
that I made more of a screen and then I
put a small layer of the Bo Kashi down
it comes with some powdered stuff called
bo khosh II I sprinkled about a handful
of that on the screen and then what you
do is you just put I put I'm a
vegetarian
and every banana that I eat has a banana
peel every strawberry that I eat has
that little the leafy part at the end of
it there are some strawberries that come
in the package that are inedible every
time you eat an onion the way I clean my
onion is I chop each end off of the
onion and then I can get that onion skin
right off of it and so I've got an end
of each one or each end of it and the
onion skin and then I clean it that ends
and the skin go into my little bowl and
then once I've got this bowl filled I
throw all my banana peels my eggshells
my onion ends my carrots that got funky
the celery that I forgot around coffee
grounds are you have to dry them set
them out and let them dry first if
you're gonna do that but I do my yerba
mate' that I've cooked or that I've used
and my coffee grounds gotta set them on
a paper towel and let them dry for like
48 hours you don't want to put too much
moisture in there um I could explain why
but it's too much to go in so anything
fruit or veggie what else can go in
there you can put on meat and dairy in
there
kanya you can put your meat and dairy
products and bread in there I choose not
to put I don't eat any meat or dairy and
I only put a little bit of it'll be
weird if your steaks cup or if your
plants got pork chops and steak and you
didn't right yeah yeah
and that just doesn't even happen in
this house there right no that comes
here and I just put the vegetables in
the fruits and [ __ ] in there and
although like some grapes and so there's
apple cores and potato peels so you put
they say to put a two inch layer of food
waste in there and then sprinkle a
handful of the Bokashi and then another
two-inch layer and sprinkle a handful of
Bokashi
to open it very often I throw all of my
scraps into a bowl and once the Bowl has
starts to stink up the kitchen then I
put that in the book ah she bucket right
uh Mike you've been here when I open the
bucket
yeah I don't recommend going full work
and keeping it in your kitchen like some
people but they're just don't open it up
- put this down when you pop the lid on
that sucker it is right it would where
you can smell the magic work we're
fermenting banana peels apple cores
grapes there are eggshells in there uh
well there's avocados in there like
everything that juice that comes out of
the novels yeah so you keep putting your
keep packing your fruit and vegetables
in there or your food waste you can put
your bacon and eggs in there if you want
to all your food waste can go in there
then you pack it down with this little
packer and keep sprinkling in the coffee
and then you seal it right and then
after about it took me about ten days
about ten days you unscrew the spigot
that's on there and I put a mason jar
underneath it and this juice comes out
and it starts off clear and kind of pink
or orange ish and it smells like oh it
is like the bar trash can they got
thrown up in and left in the Sun I feel
like it should be a game in the podcast
you should just have the jar sitting
here and people dig what is this and you
should just be I don't know the jar is
sitting you can see that I can see the
jar and I don't want no part of it I
don't know this game is stuff that comes
the juice that comes out of there I
throw that into a thing of clean water
with a bubbler and it bubbles up real
good and it makes the stinkiest funky
[ __ ] and I feed that to my plants and I
can see them dance around we have a
lantern AutoKey in our bucket yeah yeah
cuz these nutjobs a quick hole and just
slide the tube through and just that's
the end of that story loop it's a the
plants love of people but good god it's
right yeah it is stinky it's definitely
sent a real delicate stomach ball kasha
so and not be for you but it's the
plants of loving it so more details I'll
fill it up is almost to the top now I
feel like I've got one more good dump of
my bowl of banana peeled ate a lot of
bananas you guys have a banana addiction
I think they're really good for me and
they give me a lot of energy and they're
healthy and they're organic
even like a million ways I mean the [ __ ]
out of banana
so shout out some bananas but I've got
one more dump into there and then once I
dump that bowl into there I'm out of
coffee so I won't even be able to put
more Kosh in there I'll seal it and let
it seal for about 14 days and everything
that's in there is essentially pickling
it's like fermenting and pickling in
there and I'll pull out juice out of
there I'll get a lot of that I call it
Kashi juice I'll probably get five six
maybe eight to ten depending on how I
don't know how soggy the top layer is
gonna get I'll get eight to ten jars
hopefully of that Kashi juice out of
there and then I will take two large
kiddie pools of soil and I will put half
of that Kashi bucket on the bottom of
one kiddie pool and half of the Kashi
bucket on another kiddie pool and cover
that up with store bag soil and mix that
[ __ ] in and then in like 14 to 21 days
we'll have some dank composted soil
I just watched Mike eyes like
immediately go pointed in words like
wait a minute didn't I say I'm the one
that messes so easy
yeah you just wait for that bath time
okay to kiddie pools one one with grow
Kashi Brokaw she yep and then the other
with oh it's I know it let's get about
worm castings - I just love it it's
worth there won't be any worm castings
in there just yet but in the future
there will be castings out of that same
soil yes indeed yes and that soil will
get that'll just be the base like we'll
only need a little bit of that soil per
the regular soil mixing bin we'll just
cut it down yeah and it'll make some
dank soil there'd be a lot of microbes
in there new yeah Mike does not look
excited though so between the word we're
close to ruin like that day yeah yeah
just wear something you don't like
between the worm castings the grow Kashi
what else are we use in fish hydro
slates and the dragonfly Earth medicine
you should see the roots on my plants
and the veg growth happening in my
plants there are other things that we
still have to supplement and stuff but
my roots are amazing I'm super impressed
and I'm making my own [ __ ] I can make
with a handful of worm castings with one
jar of that Kashi tea with 15 scoops of
grow Kashi which sounds like a lot it's
10 scoops of grow Kashi there's never
enough
no I really can't hurt yourself I mean
you can but and if you want to use
molasses it's like just like five ounces
if you don't want to use molasses you
don't need it but you could make I made
25 gallons of nutrients with just that
right there and it was amazing it was
totally amazing green plants green happy
plants all my veggies all my clothes
that got put into new pots they all got
fed that and they look completely happy
they love life everything is pretty much
been switched over to organic so it's
yeah so that's a good way you guys to
recycle all of your garden stuff that's
a good way are all your garden stuff all
your waste all your food waste what the
heck happened to my papers they all
landed the wrong order they're backwards
and it's weird I'm confused
do any more mom still [ __ ] sit around
I'm gonna try to fix it without anybody
noticing right so just take your food
scraps and throw it in there and you can
make your own nutrients guys we can save
the world one one drink at a time one
food at time one yeah
I've sent three people to put with these
hobb paper towels and Kleenex and stuff
in there too because the Fitz paper it
will biodegrade in there I know you
looked at me like that's disgusting but
I mean it's rotten banana no thank you
how it's already patreon gross yeah it's
gross but it's not is little I'm not
looking forward to smelling the
industrial-sized one there's a video
it's not the I was looking for the Gro
kashi web site I couldn't find theirs
there's another guy that does it in
55-gallon drums and heels arms Oh
sitting there picture in a row of
55-gallon drums and the big bull size
but that clean don't smell he's dumping
it into five-gallon buckets and missing
a portion of each one yeah all of his
feet no you don't smell it at that point
what's what's that town to the east of
here
you know what the town talking about
we're just cows like crammed into fences
they sell them there something I don't
know it was horrible you could taste cow
yummy that's kind of how it really
smells it really is kind of a kind of
cow boopie all right so I received an
email let me where the heck here is my
phone I have to find this email sister
ladybugs I've been heard about this is
the ladybug email I want to talk about I
learned a little bit about emails I'm
searching for this message
here it is so I learned a little bit
about emails huh
those are the words that just came well
that's right I'm multitasking don't
laugh at me or [ __ ]
do you know yesterday bro I got hit in
the head so hard that I don't remember
half of my evening I'm not even joking
ah
we're at a friend's house who did you
deserve it no I was an accident
there's I did it to myself so it's even
funnier there are two stairs that dip
down into this other part of these
people's house
and right above the stairs there's a
like a [ __ ] there's a beam I had thing
like a [ __ ] what is like a face
smashed the head Smasher yeah dude
there's like a decorative awning thing
there and architect was that are you a
tall people I don't I don't remember
hitting it I did not feel it all I
remember is getting up off the ground
and Shaun looking to be going to tar you
okay I was like I think so
and I continued on has never had that
problem like concedes to my I can't I
was going to pick up a chair so I went
got the chair and took it to where I was
getting when I set it down
I felt drunk I was like I am [ __ ] up
right now everything was gray
it's missus like you wanted dad a little
disgust big one dude I felt weird all
night I had someone come hang out with
me last night and they were like you're
like loopy and I was like I told you I
got hit in the head hard like dude it
was so crazy smack my ass look Facemash
I'm like I don't even I didn't feel it I
didn't feel it didn't hurt until like
when I sat down later because I got hit
so hard
I just went out my body was like she DP
like I was on the floor it's Vince's
house it's just laying there there's
like we've all had one of those I was
good dude it was pretty good it happens
a lot in this town there's a lot of
short everybody was struck pretty
worried about me look on their faces
dude it was loud like they all stood up
and [ __ ] like what the [ __ ] was that it
was good what the hell was I gonna talk
about ladybugs I'm way distracted yes
and I feel like I had a head injury
again yeah
so this dude he asked me not to say his
name there's parts of this email that I
won't read because some of it was just
for me but he opens with first of all
thanks for the awesome pod love years
style and mystic roots were a perfect
fit for bed music you're welcome to read
this on the pod but please don't mention
my real name just used vape dad on
reddit very active in our slash trees
then he talked about his soil where he
is and then he says
I was reading a book called cannabis
cultivation the other day at Barnes &amp;
Noble and they recommended putting
ladybugs in our greenhouse to fight a
feeds and caterpillars and a whole
assortment of pests
so in researching organic growing for no
other reason than I like the all-natural
aspect of it thinking thinking like this
I was wondering would it be a good idea
to raise loose ladybugs in your grow
room
what could they hurt in the stages of
growth if anything or could these be
Nature's pest control for those aspiring
to care give this may be a dumb question
but I just wanted to ask a live person
with some real quantifiable growing
experience again thanks for the pot and
keep it up it's a really beautiful thing
you're doing by the way I hope you get
invited to the Joe Rogan experience pod
one day but I know your plants would
miss you thanks for all the great free
grow info much love vape dad because
they say his real name that that email
at all I don't know okay so I just want
her to make sure that I did not I'm
pretty high but it don't think you did
either I don't think so so many cool
things
dude you're welcome for all the free
grow info I am proud and happy to do
that my goal is to a quick run all the
mids start [ __ ] eliminating all the
no Mountain Nebraska you know been
growing everybody needs to be drawn
high-quality cannabis and all I have to
do is talking to a microphone so I'm
really excited to do that you're very
welcome
um Joe Rogan experience podcast dude if
I got there I don't know what I would do
I'd be super stoked to do it just sit
there in grid into the mud that's
probably what I would do I'd love to be
on that show with Ari and Joey Diaz and
Joe Rogan I'd be the hate the hate that
come from the head oh man [ __ ] you
haters but I'd love to be on that mom so
let's get to the point here and dude you
said this may be a dumb question no dumb
questions bro never no dumb questions
Dom you've got to start somewhere I had
training wheels at one point and now I'm
doing wheelies and you just got to start
somewhere there are no dumb questions um
my theory on ladybugs and Michael
probably back me up on this a long time
ago I did what I thought was cute and I
went to the hydro store and I bought a
thousand ladybugs yeah I've been
thinking about your experiment while you
were reading the email opened up the
container and let them fly about the
Grove
they were cute I got out the camera and
took pictures of ladybugs [ __ ] on my
plants and she's really cool yep it
didn't it see Adams
yep they've been there they sell 300
thorns so I went out and then the next
day I released what was it 1,500
something of it yeah it looked like the
envelope the t-shirt from Amazon shows
up yeah you just open that [ __ ] and
don't so the next morning I find if I
released 1500 of them the next morning
there were 50 alive in that [ __ ] uh
they find all your fans they fly up into
your lights yep so here's something that
Sean taught me uh credit to Sean king
Cola he taught me this and I'm gonna
butcher it because I had a head injury
that night ladybugs don't see in the
same spectrum as humans ladybugs see a
UV spectrum that it's only provided by
the light so when we take a ladybug and
we put it in a grow room all it sees is
a grow light and it all it doesn't see
it it's confused now and it wants to get
toward the light that it can see and
it's warm the warmth and so it flies
into your hoods it flies into your fans
and you get to sweep them all up and
they smell terrible yeah I spent months
cleaning lady bugs out of every little
corner and looking cranny in that
[ __ ] Grove and then you'd find him in
weird places randomly - and they didn't
do much there are predatory mites that
are worth it their work indoors but I
don't think that ladybugs uh praying
mantis or cool indoors they don't run
away and ladybugs are also hard to find
migratory creatures they want to take
off they don't want to be there they
want to go and they want to fly away and
they want to eat and they want to fly
away yeah so in my honest opinion I
would say no on the ladybugs in an
indoor situation if you have a
greenhouse or an outdoor situation and
you're ready to keep you're gonna have
to keep adding to them and you're also
going to have to feed them they do
require food even if there are a fins
and [ __ ] they're like you don't want to
eat hummus and falafel all day you need
to change so you got to provide them
some kind of food so keep that in mind
if you're going to use them in an
outdoor or greenhouse situation but
indoors I would not do the ladybugs and
then that food could also bring other
pests that's very likely very likely at
this point I tell people to release them
around their to their Gro not in their
grow room at this point so like sprinkle
them in the front and back
yard it don't bother with them otherwise
just as like an extra preventive measure
and the thing about the Mantis is I've
been in a few pet stores here in
Colorado like you guys carry mantas and
I'm expecting to like see a whole we you
know fish tank full of mantises and like
y'all take 30 of them it's it's funny
you got a room you gotta order them but
they'll send you eggs and then you gotta
let the eggs hatch yeah yeah yeah
there's a website I think you have Toto
calm ARB ico calm go there are Bicol
organics do they've got all kinds of
great [ __ ] they'll send you bugs they'll
send you nematodes some of it is
seasonal so you might not be able to get
everything but organic pest control at
its finest they don't pay me to say that
I just like sharing useful [ __ ] with
people we've been gone 32 minutes I'd
like to go about 45 maybe an hour at the
most and I also want to read some news
articles so you guys want to get into
the news I do but we can make a teacher
so the next dad though you thinking so I
kind of agree with you I like the way
Mike thinks my his on I'm gonna take a
drink here um we're gonna dab some
lemonade from Terp ex I think was it
John John that recommended this to us
lutely all right I'm gonna somebody talk
for a second he did uh when I was down
there he didn't he had not had a sample
of the review yet so he couldn't really
give me an honest opinion but the name
was enticing but names can be misleading
sometimes we all know about the name
game okay uh yeah so it was interesting
hearing about where the handkerchief
came from and that was deficit I'm a
gamer I'm Mike's a gamer that was a
pretty [ __ ] funny story because I
didn't get it I'm not really a big
Uncharted fan but that was [ __ ]
hilarious like John John you're the man
dude thanks for being on the podcast I'm
gonna go back up I want to go to the
trippy mansion the trippy boy trap house
shoot kind of on a semi frequent basis
and do a podcast up there so John John
you need to be there again at the next
episode we'll give you your own mic and
one mic that was being passed around
because there were a lot of people that
are dude there and you hear voices would
come in and yeah yeah one guy would come
in here my name is Bill and I just want
to say dad's on dad said he would leave
and like Larry would come and even
I don't know half the people they just
wanted to get in on [ __ ] so that go
ahead Mike oh no it's just I've loved
that episode it's you do a lot of cool
[ __ ] but most of the time you know I
give a [ __ ] about wanting to go with
that I was do that episode was like damn
why wasn't I there yeah yeah no I
haven't taken anybody to that place I'm
hot in the trunk next time you put my
little sore spots you know you got sneak
away friends you guys are Davin and
everyone in the house freaks out because
there's weird white guy the front yard
just staring at the house that's just me
you can come next time and you could be
the producer there it is I'll teach you
how to hook up all the gear that I don't
do sir yeah until you're ready this is
my producer mm-hmm what's much that's a
I would I would stake producer yeah
producer sounds good that's an official
bro yeah you can have a suit and a tie
and no one would give you any [ __ ] who's
he that's my lawyer yeah I don't wear a
tie at City Council I'm not wearing one
of the [ __ ] traffic okay all right
I'm gonna take my first dab of this
lemonade from turf baggies big shout-out
to turf ex well I should taste it huh
cuz what if it's terrible right away
Michele highly downstair like you Jordan
you're on that you're on the money right
now here you go you're on the line I've
uh I watched a couple there the guys are
on the podcast the old world videos that
they did on YouTube and stuff they used
to be on it all the time and I guess I
got busy I mean you could obviously tell
it picked up businesses picked up from
back in the day and they all got
obviously these [ __ ] dishes
everywhere dude I bet those boys are
busy as [ __ ] yeah yeah are these black
sure packs containers yeah popular yeah
when you pull out one of these people
know what you got um tasty definitely
tasty lemon candy with uh it's another
flavor that I can't yet describe it'll
hit me in a minute but it's definitely a
sativa high ah because my head is going
and it made my eyes wobbly which is
something that only a couple of other
strains have ever done wobbly eyed
sativa hit all right here we go Tim how
big was it
that was weird still sounds weird is
that one of us there's a video
oh there we go oh my bad no this is just
the email cord sorry guys that's what
happens when the email core touches the
microphone or the headphone jack
if you guys heard it all they did we
sound like robots for a minute there
I'll try to fix it I'll fix it in post I
put half of the tomorrow's it definitely
has the high limit terpene there yeah
some candy so the name is worthy the
candy yeah the name is worthy that's
definitely some lemonade I just gotta go
back for a little mini flavor yeah he's
I can taste it looks like a wine
connoisseur enjoy God sip it yeah help
him out his angle he'll be hung up on
that don't smoke tobacco people there
yeah there it is there's the sa yeah
dude that was pretty smooth you just
worked the email cord the mic cable the
e the car cab a little multitasking I
can't handle this much [ __ ] lungs hmm
yeah can bokor tonight we all just took
the same sized abs I took a bigger dab
than that and didn't choke tobacco
tobacco's fault say no to cigarettes my
friends say no to cigarettes butts down
dad's up yeah there you go
that sounds kind of weird all right
let's do some news we're in 37 minutes
let's just do a couple of these news
articles we'll save a couple for maybe
Wednesday or something oh this one
caught my attention I actually want to
give a big shout-out to one of my
Facebook friends Mike Ali
we used to call him by Callie it could
be Michael Halle but he's from Boston
he's a Masshole he's a cool ass dude to
tell you the truth he knows what's up
with cannabis he's educated he's smart
he didn't can separate the [ __ ] from
the truth you should be more known in
our cannabis community and I want to
give him a shout-out right now he
probably doesn't listen to the show in
any way but huge shout out to Mike by
calli you do a good job where I
appreciate all your Facebook posts I see
how much you try to help and participate
with our community and I [ __ ]
appreciate it so shout out that's where
I found out about this story but it says
pot pesticide contamination in Denver
grows the articles by William breeds and
it says I'm going to choke here in a
second cuz I took a huge dab but just
bear with me 6 marijuana grows in Denver
were ordered to quarantine possibly
destroy plant harvest after Denver Fire
Department officials determined that the
grow facilities weren't using chemicals
properly
[Music]
i traits are not the lab the harder I
tried Nazi the worse it was Mike just
moved away from the microphone his knees
but head-butted the mic stand with his
knees now [ __ ] glorious just a little
head but I wish there was video for that
alright so they're not using chemicals
properly bugs and pass for a fact of
life for commercial growers but dealing
with them appropriately is important
because eventually humans will consume
the pot earlier this month the city of
Denver released a bulletin warning grows
our warning grows about the improper use
of pesticides because the fire
department's recent discovery the city
has ordered all licensed pot grows in
the city to send in pesticide reports by
April first pesticides and agricultural
chemicals must be used in accordance
with the product label and with all
applicable federal state and local laws
and regulations improper use of
pesticides on marijuana can raise
serious public health concerns the
bulletin reads the catch is that the
federal agency in charge of regulating
pesticide use the Environmental
Protection Agency doesn't have
acceptable levels for use on cannabis
since cannabis is illegal on a federal
level the Colorado Department of
Agriculture lacks official guidelines to
beyond suggesting that growers not use
any pesticides that haven't been
specifically tested labeled and assigned
to set tolerance for pot growing now
anybody that's listened to this podcast
for more than three or four episodes
already knows what my solution to part
of this problem is the environmental
protection agency does not have
acceptable levels for use on cannabis
since cannabis is illegal on a federal
level let's think about this solution
anybody legalize cannabis yes see that's
your first step that will make this a
little bit easier it with legalization
comes product safety people all right Oh
more was that the CDA does have an
unofficial list of pesticides that can
be used on unspecified crops that are
intended for human consumption however
Oh consumption however I kind of read
that weird my fault and the state
marijuana Enforcement Division has a
strict list of allowed pesticides as
well as instructions for how grow owners
have to store and dispose of them state
law also requires that shops write up
standard operating operating procedures
for all pesticide applications in Denver
dispensaries will now be required to
submit a list of every pesticide used
and how much of it
is used copies of those records must be
kept in the facility where the marijuana
has grown
additionally grows must send lists of
pesticides and information on their
safety to the Denver Fire Department and
a sign must be placed on the door of
every grill room listing any and all
pesticides used those businesses that
don't comply could faced fine could face
fines and closures and let me tell you I
work with the dispensary and I'm there
on a daily base mi daily basis the past
couple of weeks dude they are not joking
when they say they're going to find you
or close you they will come in that day
they will find the violation that day
they will write a ten thousand dollar
fine and they will close your shop down
right on the spot and related it's here
leave you're closed I've seen it happen
not the spot that I represent but I've
seen it happen to another place when
people don't get the the amount of
regulation and oversight that this
industry operates on remedy is massive
yeah when I'm hanging out near the bud
room I'll hear people it's been a long
time since anyone said it but you'll
hear people or people that don't have an
ID that want to get in can you just let
me in just once it's like dude this is a
billion dollar operation I don't know
exactly but I mean it's [ __ ] more
money than you could even imagine we're
gonna risk all of our business for one
dude to sneak through without his ID
every operation in town you can call a
million dollar business yeah it's all on
camera I saw the price list for just
some of the grow equipment that I
ordered the other day I was like you
know we need like 30 of these and then
like that's this much I was like order
it but oh my god all right that's a
house like we just spent a house on
fan's what the hell okay I want to get
more into this article it says the city
also says that the Denver Department of
Public Health and Environment will be
inspecting cultivation sites as well as
infused product manufacturing sites so
what was happening you guys you heard
the article there were some shops in
Denver some grows in Denver that were
using chemicals that should not have
been being used on the cannabis that
they were selling to the public and it's
my bad that the shops that were busting
out those $75 and $99 ounces it's
probably those guys probably their
decision bonds on the phone yeah yeah
the ones that you see in the back of the
magazines and stuff you
those are man that's terrible that
they're doing that and there's a pit the
picture of this article makes it the
best there is a picture of a guy in like
a Breaking Bad suit with the full-on gas
mask toting weed out is pouring a bottle
of monsanto chemicals into another
container and it's completely unrelated
to anything to do with the article it's
just a period I picture is all it is and
what I'll turn the computer this way you
gotta lean this way I've got too many
things plugged in but look at this [ __ ]
full-on Breaking Bad suit chemical into
chemical nothing to do with cannabis or
this article it looks like glue it looks
like he's pouring glue well Eagle 20
looks like that if you've ever seen
Eagle 20 and I kind of assumed we talked
about it friends and I Eagle 20 was
probably one of the products being used
in all of this [ __ ] if I read it
right the shops that have their crops
quarantined right now turn themselves in
essentially like they handed in their
form that was due April 1
oh wow and when that they started
looking out they're like hey wait that's
on the whatever Lister ah see I've been
read that far this is the only article
I've seen about it there was another big
change with hash the other day where
they're like we scheduled it or
something like that too wasn't there
do you get that was article no I do not
time I'm sorry's in it I'm sorry well
we'll look for that one on another
episode wasn't even just being a
smartass to you sorry did you hear about
this one thing though I'm not there to
talk about it come with Italy no I don't
know this is our course not even a News
correspondent Adam gasket shows up
unfair I buy some high [ __ ] and I'm
prepared good to see you it's actually
on Instagram okay but but but I'm not
even gonna be able to find itself so
this article is super long so much time
I've got I might skip this one and we
might give you guys a Wednesday episode
I've got a little over here Roger how
far are we going 45 minutes and we're
not gonna do this super long article
we're gonna save that this one I'm
excited about wah wah you guys are gonna
be like what is a Lube more Lube no no
if you guys wanna he's referring to the
Floria episode you guys this is not a
weird bromance going on here all right
so I scroll down to the cannabis and
this article is by David McFadden of The
Associated Press um there's a picture of
Bunny Wailer lighting up a big old bowl
in front of a picture of King Haile
Selassie I and
to the right of him is King highest
haile selassie I and the Queen sitting
right next to him
great shot so I'll get into I get to the
point historic new ganja laws in Jamaica
for Rastafari religious use comma MMJ
program so Kingston Jamaica marijuana
has been pervasive but illegal in
Jamaica for decades consumed as a
medicinal herb Puft is a sacrament by
Rastafarians and sung about in the
islands famed reggae music after many
years of dialogue about the culturally
entrenched drug and him bought
emboldened what and emboldened by
changes to drug laws in US states
Jamaica's Parliament on Tuesday Tuesday
night gave final approval to enact
decriminalizing small amounts of pot and
establishing a licensing agency to
regulate a lawful medical marijuana
industry yes we got medical marijuana in
Jamaica welcome to the club the historic
commitments paved the way for a cannabis
licensing authority to be established to
deal with regulating and cultivating and
distributing and distribution of
marijuana for medical and scientific
purposes both houses of Jamaica's
legislature have approved this
legislation what's so funny bro that
Mountain Dew was a big yeah power to it
he held that far from the mics and it
was still like a shotgun in my ears that
was good
I know people from the south bill that's
a good kind of mountain dude when a beer
opens like that it's like that's a good
can of bearish gonna be a good kind of
beer right here that's one of them
special Mountain Dews and I think I'm
thinking Mountain Dew yeah see it's been
over a year since I've had Mountain Dew
I think yeah that's probably since I was
16 I was like getting off crack though
my body went through a withdrawal for a
minute there I've heard the regular do
and the faux do at home just in case I
run out of the regular yeah he does make
his own he's got the little fizz machine
so in a victory for religious freedom
adherence to the homegrown Rastafari
spiritual movement can now freely use
marijuana for sacramental purposes for
the first time on the tropical land yes
I Rastafari
the law makes possession of up to two
ounces of marijuana a petty offense that
could result in a ticket but not a
criminal record cultivation of that
don't sound legal what might
I like that well they've got medical
marijuana now and dude before if you got
call of cannabis in Jamaica know for
sure days in a Jamaican jail and seven
days in a Jamaican jail I'd probably
rather take 45 days in a Pueblo jail to
tell you the truth like it's not gonna
be anything fun you sleep on the cement
floor with the rats and you don't get no
food so it yeah what else is do all
right so uh what two ounces petty
offense you don't go to jail that's way
better five or fewer plants on any
premises would be permitted it'll be
five ganja plants now a tourists who are
prescribed medical marijuana abroad will
soon be able to apply for permits
authorizing them to legally buy small
amounts of Jamaican wheat or ganja as it
is known locally that's [ __ ] brilliant
marketing on behalf of the government
say fifteen bucks so that you fill your
prescription while you're right I don't
oh god what's ailing I don't have to
bring it with me on the boat but yeah I
can buy it why I'm there yep not bring
it back on your boat you know but that's
gonna be reggae cruise that's on being a
great cruise I don't know if anybody saw
my Instagram and Facebook post about
reggae cruise but in November I think
there's the biggest cruise with like 20
of my favorite reggae artists and
they're going to Jamaica and I think
there's going to be even more fun now
okay on Wednesday colorado-based United
cannabis Corp said it has launched a
partnership with Jamaican agencies to
launch a marijuana research and
development facility on the island that
they hope will lead at ins and medical
cannabis products
Peter bunting the islands national
security minister said the legislation
does not mean Jamaica plans to soften it
stands on transnational drug trafficking
or cultivation of illegal plots Jamaica
has long been considered the Caribbeans
largest supplier of pot to the US and
regional islands the passage of this
legislation does not create a
free-for-all in the growing transporting
dealing or exporting of ganja security
forces will continue to rigorously
enforce Jamaican law with our
international treaty obligations bunting
said in Parliament william brownfield
the u.s. assistant secretary for
counter-narcotics
Affairs damn glad that's not my job
that'd be a lot of work hi I'm William
brownfield the US assistant secretary a
cot X Affairs I'm not the judge business
area genetics yeah
dad so this dude told The Associated
Press days before the vote that Jamaican
laws of course to make his own business
and Jamaica's and Jamaica sovereign
decision but he noted that the
trafficking of marijuana into the US
remains against the law we expect the
Jamaica and all states party to the UN
drug conventions will uphold their
obligations including a firm commitment
to combatting and dismantling criminal
organizations involved in drug drug
trafficking he told AP in an email um
once again you guys how do we stop
illegal cannabis trafficking make
immediately legalize it it's the only
answer that does any sense at all truth
what we need to do is buy a small plane
at first then we fly people straight
from Colorado to Jamaica for a trip we
just gonna have to stop somewhere in the
middle floor
the smaller the plane the more
frequently stopped I'm telling you now
if it's gonna be a working Joe my god I
don't know I'm just gonna keep reading
before Adam crashes a plane in a fantasy
yep
just saying anybody's got the money from
Colorado Jamaica why this is we've legal
both uh so anyway debated debate has
long raged in Jamaica over relaxing laws
prohibiting ganja but previous calls to
decriminalize small amounts of marijuana
fizzled out because officials feared
they would bring sanctions from
Washington Jamaican officials now have
high hopes that the island can become a
player in the nasca medical marijuana
industry health tourism and the
development of innovative pot derived
items local scientists already have a
history of creating marijuana derived
products such as kennesaw which helps
relieve pressure in the eyes of
glucomannan a local scientists in
Jamaica you know some dude with
dreadlocks it on a five gallon bucket
taken from lash well if I've seen quite
a few people that are moving down that
way as well a lot of popular people yeah
I know you have to a lot of our friends
went on a trip there just recently oh
really yeah a lot of our friend well is
a couple months back but as soon as this
happened when it was like coming up they
went there and helped them put this [ __ ]
in
place nice some people see details like
a D way uh okay shot as in Addison
tomorrow what's up mother
I think you from up there in Denver
River Rock area and stuff like that
alright I'm gonna keep reading so uh
where were I Commerce Minister Anthony
hi Alton said the cannabis industry
holds great potential for Jamaica where
marijuana has long been grown illegally
on mountainsides and marshes the move by
Jamaican lawmakers adds to an
international trend of easing
restrictions on marijuana for medical or
personal use more than 20 US states
allow some form of medical marijuana and
last year Colorado and Washington
legalized personal use on Tuesday Alaska
B Alaska became the third US state to
legalize the recreational use of
marijuana for adults in the Americas
Europe Uruguay last year became the
first nation to create a legal marijuana
market in Argentina personal possession
of marijuana was decriminalized under a
2009 Supreme Court ruling that jail time
for small amounts of drugs violates the
country's constitution that's [ __ ]
cool
Iowa and jilly permits use of medical
marijuana details of Jamaica's Licensing
Authority and its hope for medical
marijuana sector will need to be refined
in upcoming months but for now Jamaican
cannabis Crusaders applauded the
amendments this is a big step in the
right direction but there's still a lot
of work to do said Delano cyber right
director of the cannabis commercial and
medical task force so big up to Jamaica
taken steps in the right right direction
so much more traveling and tourism is
gonna happen there because people go
there and get your medical marijuana now
well if they charge everybody five bucks
to fifteen bucks or whatever to be able
to legally consume will not have to
worry about it while they're there
that's gonna be millions for the
government just up taxes along
California's like the only warm place
that it's semi legal so like all those
in the summer we get 300 days of
sunshine here yeah but it's it's hot
yeah is get pretty damn you know and I
mean being closer to the equator I'm
sure it's hot but that Beach sure does
health all right yeah so Jamaica would
be do yeah would be yeah I can't wait
for that to happen I don't know when it
goes into effect but I want to go visit
now and go take some dabs in Jamaica I
wonder if that's possible scare the
living [ __ ]
further down there already a large boys
got dreads at a blowtorch get him back
I've got a couple more things that I
want to share with you guys that was
enough news I feel like um we did the
ladybug thing
hey somebody sent me an email about
fermentation and your fermentation
methods I'm going to address that but
I'm wanting to do it when Sean's here
Shauna is the guy to talk to about
fermentations let's see I got to do some
shoutouts I wanna give a big shout-out
to vigor lover thanks for the t-shirt
that is [ __ ] sweet hashtag mids
admits Linds happy birthday I don't know
if you listen to the podcast I hope you
do it's your birthday happy birthday
girl James Holt dude you sent me a
compliment on Facebook and I told you
thanks for listening you didn't seem to
take me seriously like you seemed like I
was kind of [ __ ] you around but no I
was [ __ ] not condescending at all
when I said that like I meant all of
that and so I hope you listen to this
and I hope you took me seriously because
uh you're one of the most badass
professional guitar players like not
even saying Europe your professional
your demeanor the way you do [ __ ] you're
a professional and for you to compliment
me like that just meant a lot to me so I
wasn't even being a prick about it I was
[ __ ] totally serious dude that blew
my mind that you listen and that you
complimented me also big shout out to
Michael he's moving back to Ross
Carolina or Ohio to get a real job and
handle business I'm gonna miss you is
cool having you around here I like
talking about glass with you I miss
about it not Mike okay yeah yeah there's
a lot of us yeah there's a lot of mics
and uh Colorado bearded dabbers Michael
okay yeah he's moving back home he's got
to take care of some things so I'm gonna
miss you bro but uh sure I'll see you
again man it's except to hang up the
beards a dad dab oral dude he trimmed up
the beard he looks good
looking good thanks good thank you guys
for listening to the one year episode
dude you guys thanks for coming I call
these guys like a half hour ago as like
you wanna come over to do a podcast
they're like yeah we do he's dropping
dimes what was that that's my ring oh
man you're pulling off your wedding ring
while you're on the show satima dad's
maybe going out after this or what I'm
just kidding guys there will be a
growers meeting April 26th at hydro
indoor growing supplies prepare for the
cup cough
[Music]
[Laughter]
like yeah you're gonna get up there like
because this cut ass up the Cannabis Cup
is coming yeah I can't wait for that
guys I'll be hanging out at the Cannabis
Cup I hope to see everybody there
everybody there do you guys have any uh
shout outs to give or anything like that
come look at my paper I think I covered
everything on a cover uh Jesse Jesse
shot at the Jesse I just gross for sure
thank you no gross who you gotta tell me
off the air who tank you know gross
jumper who that is follow me I know that
they're part of your crew because I see
my genetics coming up on stuff all of
them alright tell you that alright I'll
let you know yeah let me know alright
how about you I don't know nothing
how about that oh that's my answer well
you can use it you shout out to anyone
who comments online there you go I like
San feeds the show that's pretty cool
yeah um but Andrew yeah the comments
have gotten better and better man like I
mean I understand that everybody wants
to just be like great show but you know
like the last comment was really great
it was writing the did I read the yeah
[ __ ] reading that from his cubicle
while he's at work listening while he's
at work in his cubicle that's awesome
I appreciate that we've taken notes from
pot plants and [ __ ] hey Damon I miss I
know I don't miss having a cubicle job I
did that once it was awesome kinda have
a cubicle jobs and I'm just a much more
cuffed my cubicles awesome there's an
email and my Kubica something to dream
for mixing equipment over here alright
guys we're gonna wrap up the show I'll
be back I think of these boys don't mind
hanging out for another 30 minutes we
right kick out a Wednesday episode for
you I got two more news articles
recording gears already warmed up the
emails hot we might just keep recording
here but we're gonna wrap up this
episode thanks for listening uh we'll be
back don't forget to check out the
sponsors the Rocky Mountain Company
hydro indoor growing supplies if you're
interested in sponsoring the podcast or
if you have a product that you'd like me
to review send me an email let's grow
from your heart at hotmail.com
I'll get you all the information you
need if you've got something to say
you're not into the social media thing
you can email me it's grow from your
heart at hotmail.com
don't forget that the show is available
on iTunes stitcher and every single
episode is archived on I read genetics
Colorado calm don't forget about that
donation button on the page it's I read
genetics Colorado calm
go to the girl from a heart podcast tab
at the top there's a donation button
that goes directly to my PayPal account
you guys I'll never charge you money for
the podcast the show will always be free
but if you do feel like making a
donation
I would totally appreciate it I'll give
you a thumbs up I'll give you a
shout-out on the show to people made
contributions and I think I said thanks
if not I'll make sure to do that on the
next episode I don't have my phone
it's not on the right screen to find
that I don't waste time it's on the
fritz
Judi I went to go buy a new iPhone today
and I spent probably three hours to find
out that the phone I want is an hour
north of here and I have to drive there
to get it so tomorrow that's our mission
you guys want to go to lunch or
something let's do that we're on all the
social media sites just search for me on
whatever you use on Twitter it's @g fyh
podcast dude follow
I read genetics on Instagram do it lots
of dope cannabis pictures I got a new
camera I've been putting up some sweet
photography it is hardcore now yeah it
definitely went up yeah and since the
the new buds and stuff I haven't started
working like full full-time at the spot
yet until I do you can catch me on bong
TV randomly like 3:00 in the morning
shut up to the bong TV crew shout-out to
DS DS is in the process of copywriting a
songs they came up through I don't I
want to sing a line from it right now so
badly but I don't want to ruin it until
it's copyrighted
so once that's out we'll play it on the
podcast would be [ __ ] awesome it'll
probably be late spring early summer
before the songs done we'll play it on
the show shout out DS I hope you listen
to this one I will post a link to this
on blogtv shout out to the bong TV crew
also a big shout out to my ninja Spence
shout out to you guys for showing up
shout out to you guys for listening
until next time take a phat dab give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you