[Music]
welcome back podcast world i'm your host
my friends call me rasta jeff and this
is episode
600 of the grow from your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to talk about
properly selecting a phenotype for your
garden
before we get there let's do a few shout
outs to a few members of the 710 club
of course the 710 club or the folks who
support us on patreon
at the 7 and 10 cent a month level or
higher so with no further ado let's give
a big grow from your heart podcast thank
you shout out to the painted lady
let's follow that up with a big thank
you shout out to terp burglar i want to
send a thank you shout out to grant m
i've always got a big thank you shout
out for dayron t let's send a big thank
you to girls grow too
i want to send a special thank you to
ryan waters i've got a big shout out for
caribou heart genetics
let's send a big thank you for brian c i
want to send a big thank you shout out
to jeffrey
i've always got a big thank you shout
out for triumph let's end a big grow
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out to levity love day
and last but certainly not least let's
send a big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out to my buddy jesse
gross
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who supports the show on
patreon
if you're not already supporting the
show on patreon and you like to learn
how to do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need to support
the show will be right there on the
screen
and of course i did include a link in
the show notes and in the video
description
to make it nice and easy for everybody
who's working or driving
or got their hands full in the garden
all right ladies and gentlemen welcome
600 episodes i can't believe i have made
it to episode 600 not a big celebration
in this show
but holy [ __ ] we did it big thanks to
everybody who has supported me
if this is your first episode jumping in
or if you've been here since the
beginning or if you jumped in somewhere
in the middle
thank you i do appreciate all of the
interaction all of the support all of
the words of encouragement all of the
emails
i even appreciate all the hate mail all
that does is motivate me a little bit
more
so thank you also big thank you to
everybody who supports the show on
patreon i want to send you a special
thank you shout out right now
it does not go unnoticed you did improve
the show drastically
so thank you to everybody and to all of
the patreon contributors 600 episodes
you guys i never imagined it would get
this far
and honestly i see no end in sight you
guys are only sending me better content
better questions the interactions are
much better
uh you guys are becoming better growers
i've got to see people
evolve as growers from the knowledge
they've learned from this show so thank
you
this does mean a lot to me and i do not
plan on stopping
i'm glad that all of the holiday
[ __ ] is over we are back to normal
here things are calming down
the podcast will kind of settle down
we'll get back to the normal podcasting
schedule
i didn't miss an episode but i know that
some of the episodes were short some of
them were brief
i have been skipping the patreon
questions there is a reason for that
i feel like everybody was on vacation
they were on a christmas holiday
and a lot of people weren't able to
listen to the podcast uh however their
regularly
scheduled podcasting listening was
happening they may have had a lot of
family around they may not have been at
work they may have been off schedule
just like i was
so i didn't put your patreon questions
in the past few episodes because i
didn't want to waste those questions and
people miss them
so that is why the patreon stuff has
been getting skipped in the next few
episodes
we will focus heavily on patreon content
that way the people that did pay for
those questions they won't miss it
they'll get their answers
and they also got their time with their
family during the holidays i hope i made
that nice and clear i think i said that
in another show
wanted to make sure you understand why
the patreon questions have been getting
overlooked for a couple of shows
now let's jump into the main topic of
today's podcast this may be a quick show
but in the last episode i did talk about
running our plants on an 18-6
light schedule at the end of flower if
you didn't listen to the last episode
i'll recap that and tell you why i
recommend that
most of us put our plants on a 12 12
flowering light cycle that means the
plants are the lights are on for 12
hours a day
they're off for 12 hours a day this
triggers our plants to go into flower
that is basic grow knowledge a lot of
people will do an 11
13 cycle that came from dj short that 11
13 cycle
in my opinion in dj short's opinion as
well will give us better
phenotypical expression if we're looking
for different phenotypes
from a package of seeds we want to see
the variations from this seed and this
seed a little more
defined that 11 13 cycle in my opinion
in dj's experience
will show us more variation more
potential from each plant
so if you're running a population of
plants you may not want
the one that grows real tall and skinny
you may not want the one that's real
short and stout you may want the one
that's right in the middle
we run a phenol hunt to find the one
that is perfect for us
in that 11 13 schedule you may see more
expression from your plants
now let's jump to the 18 6 part the
reason i recommend
to turn our timer back to 18-6 for the
last seven to ten days of flower
is because light is the number one
source of energy for our plants
light contributes encourages growth
contributes to all of the photosynthesis
of our plants
when the plants are awake they're
photosynthesizing they're getting
beefier and fatter and they're growing
with that more light energy if you go
from 12 12 to 18
six you're getting six more hours of
light every day that's that much more
light energy they'll get bigger they'll
get beefier they'll get fatter
and also they may ripen up a little bit
earlier because of that extra light
now a lot of people are going to say
won't that [ __ ] my plants up if i run
them on 18 6 at the end
your plants eventually will start to
re-veg
but we're flushing and preparing for
harvest already
so if we see any sign of that reveg
happening we chop down right then
usually that reveg is going to take 14
to 20 days to begin the process
we're going to cut down 10 to 14 days in
this process
we should never get to the point of
reveg now
here's something that i should mention
if you're doing a phenol hunt
don't do this 18-6 stuff a phenol hunt
should be ran
as a phenohunt we want that to be done
scientifically if this is your first
time with a strain if you're doing a
phenohunt if you've never run this clone
before
don't do the 18.6 we need to learn our
plants the first time we run them
we're just getting introduced to these
plants we just met this plant we need to
learn it see what it likes don't do that
18-6 at the end because you don't even
know how long the plant should take to
flower
how do you know when to initiate 18-6
how do you know when to initiate flush
if you don't even know how long these
plants take to flower so
when you have a new plant if it's a
seedling if it's a clone
don't do a bunch of random experiments
to it run your first plant under
scientific
expectations scientific conditions do
everything the same
to your new plants you may be growing a
plant that could be
absolutely the best plant ever but you
did some experiment to it
that thwarted its growth that slowed
down its potential and it was your fault
that that plant didn't get to the best
it could be
and now you're gonna call it because you
think it's a runt or you think it's
shitty
you're the one that did some weird [ __ ]
to it and caused that problem
so let's give these plants the
opportunity set the plants up for
success just like we do ourselves give
the plants the opportunity
to shine treat your new plants
scientifically have a regimen for new
plants don't try new experiments
don't think i got these new seeds i'm
gonna switch to a different soil this
time
what how do you know what to expect from
that soil how do you know what to expect
from those plants
what if those seeds grow like [ __ ] maybe
it's that new soil what if they grow
amazingly maybe it's that new soil
let's not have too many variables for
new plants
and also don't expect too much from that
first run this first run is not going to
be gold we are learning the plants you
should have
quality plants a quality harvest but
that second and third run is when you're
really looking
to reach goals and break limits and have
impressive cannabis
that first run it's the first date don't
expect to
everybody doesn't put out on the first
date the first date is not always
successful
we need a couple of dates a couple of
experiences to get to know this lady
and make sure we satisfy this lady so
that it can satisfy us
get to learn your plans um
when we're finding we're looking for
phenotypes here we're looking for the
males we're looking for the females if
you're running from seed you could have
a male seed
let's not do a bunch of experiments and
a bunch of training and lollipopping
to a male plant you could have a boy in
there let's focus on females
we're learning the harvest times of
these plants we're learning nutrient
preferences do they need a lot of calmag
do they need a lot of nitrogen
do they get mad if you get them too much
cow mag some plants don't want a lot of
calmag later in flower
we've got to learn these plants the
first time we're running them
we've got to learn temperature and
humidity and vpd
preferences i've got some plants that
want it really really dry i've got some
plants that would prefer a really moist
climate
i've got some plants that i only water
every other time when i water the rest
of my garden because they prefer a
really really
dry soil base so it's all about learning
that plant if you're running a bunch of
plants all at once can you learn each
plant individually
i don't know if you really can so the
first time you're running a plant let's
focus if it's a seedling
if it's a batch of seeds if it's a clone
let's focus on learning that plant
before we do a bunch of crazy tricks and
[ __ ] to it
let's not get too scientific too
experimental you need to learn
when to harvest that plant how do you
know when to start flushing that plant
how do you know
if you're going to do 18.6 how do you
know when to start that we don't know
any of that stuff the first time we're
running plants so
my advice to you is the first time
you're running it build a relationship
with that plant let that plant show you
what it wants to do before you force
things upon
that plant um also a lot of times when
it's the first time i run a plant
if the breeder said it'll be done in 60
days i'm going to go
70. i want to see what happens at the
end of flower
a lot of plants will beef up at the end
of flower they'll put on that extra bit
of weight
then we add that 18 6 once we know the
plant and we can get that extra
extra bit of weight but how do you know
what the plant does naturally if we
don't run it once
without doing a bunch of tricks and
crazy weird [ __ ] to it
let that plant be itself let it grow for
the final hunt
once you've selected a keeper then you
can manipulate it you can [ __ ] with it
you can do all of your weird magic that
you want to do to it
you can impose your will on it but the
first time let that plant show you what
it does
um some plants frost up at the end if we
cut it down too early if we don't let
that plant go that extra 10 days
we may not even know that it gets super
frosty at the end
some plants put on beautiful colors
toward the end of flower and if you cut
it down at day 63
and that color happens at day 70 you may
never know it
so the first time you're running a plant
i would recommend going a little bit
longer and not messing with it let it go
5 10 maybe 12 extra days based on what
the breeder says
i know you're in a hurry i know you want
to get this crop down but
this is not the last crop you're going
to grow hopefully hopefully this is
the first crop and hopefully it's the
first date and if that first date goes
well you get a second date
by the third and fourth date you've got
some sort of rapport some sort of
relationship you've learned each other
do that with your plants let's not
expect the plants to put out on the
first date
let's learn them develop a relationship
learn what that plant wants so we can
satisfy that plant before we expect it
to satisfy us that being said
the first time we're running seeds let's
not veg them forever
i see people running brand new seeds in
seven gallon pots and they flip it into
flour
after like 60 days of vegging and
they're pissed off that they've got a
male
bro we should have found out way before
then if we had males or females don't
waste time and space and energy on big
ass
plants if you don't even know if you've
got a male or a female
that first run should be a small test
phenohunt
run this is an audition don't spend all
your money all your time all your energy
all your space
on the very first run that is not a
successful way to do it you're going to
disappoint yourself
if you've got 10 seeds probably five of
them are males so if you don't put them
in small pots and identify the males
early
you're already wasting space five of
them are going to get eliminated maybe
six of them
i've seen people come up with three
females from a pack of 10 before it's
all about the numbers game
most likely you're going to get 50 50.
so expect 50
of your plants to be cold before we even
get into the flowering phase
then what if you got a bunch of junk
what you're so you're gonna get
five males then maybe you get five
females hopefully
then you've got two phenotypes that are
gonna be like oh man those are the ones
there's always one that's real tall one
that's real short one that smells real
good
one that's super frosty and then one
that's kind of got all the traits but
you wish it had one trait a little bit
more
so there's always that gamble when it
comes to phenol hunt you've got to find
the one that you want is what i'm
getting at
find the plant that you want don't waste
a bunch of time
growing males don't waste a bunch of
time doing experiments and [ __ ]
get them growing flower them find the
keeper have a clone of that then the
next time you run
that's when we're going to start doing
tricks that's when we start manipulating
we've got the plant we want
we've got the keeper for our grow now we
can do tricks to it but
let the plants show you who they are
before you start manipulating them
in that first run now here's something
that a lot of people have been asking me
a lot of questions about
and i've kind of changed the direction i
go when i give advice on this
a lot of people say hey i bought a pack
of this strain and they've got my seeds
and they want to say which phenotype am
i looking for
i don't know i don't know which
phenotype you're looking for because i
don't know what kind of grow you've got
i don't know what kind of smoke you're
expecting
i don't know i don't know what you want
i know that you may have a pack of lemon
jeffree
there are a couple of desirable
phenotypes in there but if i say you
want the one that grows in 70 days
that smells like lemon candy that takes
a lot of nutrients and gets real tall
i may be setting you up for failure
because maybe your grow has a short
ceiling height and now the phenotype
that i want is not going to work in your
grow
so the whole idea of buying a pack of
seeds and doing that final hunt is
finding the phenotype that works best
for you uh you don't want to go to
dinner with me i'm a vegetarian
i like spicy food and i drink a lot of
kombucha unless you're into spicy food
in kombucha you don't want me ordering
your meal
when we go to the restaurant we want the
we both wanted italian food that's why
we went to the italian restaurant we've
got a guideline here we know that
there's italian food in there
now we've got to narrow it down off the
menu and get the italian food for me and
the italian food for you
don't make me pick your italian food
like i may pick
white sauce and real garlicky pasta and
you may have just been
right in the mood for a red sauce and
something a little more not garlicy
what's the word for it anyway
more acidic with that red sauce is what
you were in the mood for we may want
completely different things and they
both fall under the umbrella
of lemon jeffrey they both fall under
the umbrella of italian food
so you make your selection don't let me
choose for you
i'll give you recommendations and ideas
of what to look for
but that phenotype is not up to me that
is up to you that is up to your garden
do you want the one that
takes 70 days to grow because i like
those longer finishing plants i think
they get a little more potency i think
they put on more weight
i appreciate a long flowering plant
maybe you're too impatient maybe you
need that 60-day finisher
so don't rely on me to select a
phenotype for you
grow the plants the one that screams and
sings at you is the one that you want
it's a lot like dating you're going to
find the one you'll know
if it's not the one for you you guys
will let each other know if it is the
one for you you're going to feel it
you're going to know it
so base your phenotypical selections off
of the plants that work best for you
not best for me i've done a lot of work
to narrow down the phenotypes that are
going to come out in the out of the
seeds
i've given you a lot of guidance on what
to expect now you've got to select the
phenotype
that works best for you and i've said
this a moment ago this first run with
the plants
is an audition run this is not the last
run you get with these plants this is
the first date
let's grow them let's see if we even get
along let's see how the outcome goes at
the end of the flowering cycle
chop them down smoke them there might be
one in there that is amazing there might
be four out of those 10 that are useless
to you
you will know exactly which one you want
grow that one again
that is when we're going to start doing
all of the tricks
that's when you can run the 11 13 light
cycle if you want to that's when you can
run the 186 light cycle if you want to
that's when you can lollipop them that's
when you can trellis them that's when
you can work them into a net
but let's not waste all that time space
and energy on brand new plants that we
don't even know
what we're messing with we could have
all males we could have a bunch of
hermaphrodites we could have a bunch of
weird mutant plants or you could have
amazing
keepers so that is my quick rant on
phenotypical selection
this is going to be a quick episode i'm
not going to ramble on and add more to
it unnecessarily
i am going to thank you for listening to
600 episodes of the grow from your heart
podcast thank you for tagging along this
far
if you've got any questions corrections
comments or concerns i would love to
hear from you
my email address is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com
don't be shy if you feel like this
episode was educational informative or
entertaining and you'd like to make a
financial contribution to the show
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart of course there is a link in
the notes and the video description
to make it nice and easy stay up to date
with all things rosta jeff and all
things irie genetics all things grow
from your heart by visiting
iriegenetics.com that's my official
website
there's a grow help tab on there there's
a contact us tab on there
there are so many tabs on there anything
you need to keep tabs on rosta jeff is
at iriegenetics.com
ladies and gentlemen i want to thank you
for listening i'll be back in a couple
of days with fresh new content
let's send a big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to my buddy
crazyhands and until next time take a
fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me