all right here we go welcome back
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rasta jeff and this is episode
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to answer a
patreon message from our friend mister
before we get there let's do a few shout
outs to a few members of the 710 club
of course the 710 club are the folks who
support us on patreon
at the 7 and 10 cent a month level or
higher so with no further ado let's
start off with the big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out
to my buddy dave's not here let's send a
big thank you shout out to ecstasy smoke
i want to send a big thank you shout out
to blackbird76
let's send a big thank you to my buddy
716 vibes let's send a big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to grow man stan
let's follow that up with a big thank
you shout out to frugal rock i want to
send a big thank you to steven d
smith i want to send a big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to our buddy gramps memel
let's send a big thank you shout out to
a longtime supporter let's send a big
thank you to john bendit
let's send a big thank you to paparoni i
want to send a big thank you shout out
to robert
and last but certainly not least let's
send a big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out
to our friend fish ganja guy big thanks
and big shout out to everybody who
supports the show on patreon if you are
not already supporting the show and
you'd like to learn how to do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need to
support the show will be right there on
the screen
and of course i did include a link in
the show notes and in the video
description to make it nice and easy
for all of my friends who might be
driving or working or have their hands
full
in some way thank you guys for all the
patreon support i do appreciate it
today's
podcast does come from a patreon
contributor uh they did send me a very
nice set of questions
so with no further ado let's just jump
right into it this one comes from our
friend mister
and it says growers love and greetings
and salutations to you
white mike and all of the irie army big
salute to the full irie army
thank you for joining us mister this is
a great question it goes on to say
what a year i have developed a pair of
green thumbs
i celebrated being a 20-year cancer
survivor congratulations brother
it says i was 24 when i was diagnosed
i'm glad you're making it this far
keep killing it if we can do anything
let us know it goes on it says i
continue my life journey
now having over 18 months without any
form of pain pills
so it sounds like with cannabis we have
eliminated pain pills from mr's life and
it has been over 18 months
congratulations that is a huge
improvement in life that's a huge step
keep going like i said before if you
need anything just let us know we'll do
our best to help you out
now it says my questions this month are
vast and various let's turn down some of
this music and get right to mister's
questions because he does have a lot of
them this could take a minute it says
for 2021 i'm i am interested in
obtaining a cannabis
horticultural certificate something like
oaksterdam live or an online class
and i'm interested in your thoughts
about a novice cultivator
or someone wanting to get into the
cannabis industry and looking into any
cannabis college that is a great
question there are a lot of online uh
cannabis education programs available uh
during coven i'm sure all of them are
online before covid you could go to
cloverleaf you could go to oaksterdam
there are a couple other accredited
cannabis universities which you could
attend
and get a cannabis education you can get
a general cannabis education then they
do have
more focused classes where you can learn
about bud tending cultivating
the back end of the business the tax end
of the business the legal aspects of the
business
they will teach you so many things in
these college classes
i am all about continuing education i'm
here to educate
i'm here to teach people i'm all about
furthering your education broadening
your horizons
setting yourself up for success uh
education is key
however sometimes those places will
teach you bad habits
so go to those classes with an open mind
understand that the things they are not
teaching you are not the only way to do
things that is a problem i see a lot of
cultivators have
that come from those types of facilities
or come from even college courses
or another facility they were taught
that this is how i cut clones
so this is the only way we can cut
clones
and if you come to work for me you're
going to cut clones the way i teach you
and the way they taught you in amsterdam
may be way different and i don't want to
hear you arguing with me that well in
amsterdam we did are at oaksterdam we
did it this way
i'm gonna fire you because i don't care
we do it this way at my girl and it
works this way
i'll listen to you once uh we did it
this way at oaksterdam
cool i've heard you now quit trying to
change our ways and let's do it the way
we've written sops for
and the way we've got it dialed in here
in this cultivation facility so i do
like the schooling
but keep an open mind that it is not the
only way to do things what they teach
you there is a way to do things
you'll get a very vast and deep
understanding of the plants of the plant
functions of ways to take care of the
plants
the processes of the plants uh
environmental tips and all kinds of
things
that i probably don't even know but at
the same time
i like to be able to train somebody that
comes into a facility
to work in my facility the way i need it
done a little bit of plant knowledge is
cool but if you go to one of those
universities and learn too much
you know just enough to [ __ ] something
up in micro so
if you do go to that remember that
you're not getting the
uh the total 100 only way answer you're
getting a very good education but you've
got to keep yourself open-minded that
there are other things to learn
if you do go to something like that i
recommend focusing on something find
your niche in cannabis what are you
going to do
everybody starts off they want to become
a good grower they understand the plants
then they understand the environment
then we all kind of branch off into our
own direction i obviously became
a breeder and a podcaster some other
people are really good in the grow
also became hvac technicians some people
also became electricians
some people also become carpenters some
people are really good at cloning some
people are all about
pheno hunting find your niche in the
cannabis industry and if you can focus
your classes on that that will
definitely help you out
maybe learn about pesticides and
pesticide applications
learn everything you can about pests be
the pest guy the guy that eradicates
problems
i said a moment ago maybe learn about
hvac or electricity or even be a plumber
or maybe you need to learn about the the
tax laws
and the back end of the business all the
technical stuff all the uh the
accounting and the bookkeeping and all
that stuff maybe you need to learn all
the logistics of that part
maybe you're a salesman maybe you're in
sales in the cannabis industry
whatever you do find your niche and try
to find the cannabis schooling that will
dial in
your niche and give you a solid uh
foundation
and some more to shine if you want so it
sounds like you're trying to get into
the industry
what are you going to do to shine in the
industry do you have a goal do you have
something you can bring to the industry
are you a salesperson are you a
craftsperson are you a plumber
an electrician an hvac tech or do you
simply want to grow the cannabis find
what you want to do
and get those classes and specialize in
that stuff but then when you go to work
for somebody
don't be so stubborn that we have to
fire you i've had amazing
cultivators work in cultivation
facilities with me i've worked with some
amazing cultivators
and i've had to fire them because i
catch them doing it their way and not
our way
your way works in your garden but i've
got a strategy i've got the map
with the key and the legend and the
starting point and the ending point i've
got that on paper
and if we don't follow my map we're not
all going to get to the same goal
so if you're doing your weird [ __ ] in my
garden i come in i'm like hey why did
this happen you're like oh i decided i
would top the plants and do this
we weren't going to top those plants i
had a strategy now you just [ __ ] up
the whole garden keep in mind that
you've got to go adapt to somebody
else's grow once you're hired it will
give you a solid foundation if you want
to run your own stuff this is a good way
to start
you'll get a full education that way but
keep in mind there's always more to
learn
once you think you've learned it all
that's when you [ __ ] yourself from
learning anymore so
um you asked my thoughts about these non
novice cultivator or someone wanting to
get into the industry and looking into
any cannabis college i think i covered
that
do it educate yourself but keep in mind
you did not learn everything and you've
got to be open to the teachings i'm
going to give you the training i'm going
to give you
when you work with me alright there is
another question it says
i am a cannabis cup virgin
any word about the status of cannabis
cups in 2021
this question brings up a thought on
judging these events
what was the criteria used to judge the
cannabis entries at these events
also a couple thoughts on possible ways
to prevent someone
buying or swaying votes is using oh
another way of swaying that is by using
a double-blind panel approach
then there's my favorite a veterans only
panel a veterans only panel would be
pretty awesome
if you got like the veterans choice or
something at one of those events that
would be a cool new category to add to
it
and the only people able to vote in that
were the veterans that'd be [ __ ]
pretty cool i like that category
if i ever do throw a cup or i'm involved
in a cup i will mention a veterans only
category
veterans choice uh yeah veterans choice
we get to try all the veterans get to
trial decided i mean to include myself
in that
the veterans get to try all of the
samples that were donated and the
veterans get to say sample 42 was the
winner
i like that veterans choice award that's
kind of cool now let me focus on the
question because i
am a little bit rambly today it says
um any word on the status of cannabis
cups in 2021
so far no word uh no updates on any
events like that i think everybody is
waiting
a lot of people are waiting for a
vaccine and word from
our [ __ ] government we don't even
know what we're allowed to do what we
can do at this time
so i don't see any cannabis events in
2021 coming up
especially consumption events i think it
will be a very long time before we are
smoking
anything together in a room together uh
i am on the fence about how i feel about
the future of events with covet and
everything
part of me wants to get out there and
see all of my friends and
smoke and high five everybody i'm a
business person i want to take my booth
to the businesses where business happens
and meet all of my people that's my
favorite part of the events i get to
meet all of you that have been listening
you come up and you're like ross jeff
i've been listening to the show and
thank you and that
recharges me for the next year i would
love to have all of that also i don't
know that i want to get some weird
[ __ ] disease and get sick and get
other people sick
anyway i'm gonna get away from that
political talk because we hear enough
about that [ __ ] but i don't think there
are going to be any events in 2021 that
i am aware of
i did see a couple of things in a couple
of places but i will not be attending
them and they were very small
events compared to like cannabis cups
and things but there are very tiny smoke
gatherings happening but i'll be
avoiding those for
the time being um judging these events
um i do have some notes on that let's
see let me jump into my notes
judging uh it's been long rumored that
many of the larger cups are for sale to
be quite honest with you you do hear
any event you go to anything where
there's a prize you always hear
that the cups the prizes and the awards
are for sale and i did say rumored it is
a rumor it's hearsay allegedly that some
of those cups are for sale
with that being said i know people
personally who have sat
uh not at this table but at the table
that used to be in this spot
that have sat here who have won cannabis
cups from high times
and have won other uh first place awards
from other prestigious
uh cannabis and concentrate events and
competitions
and i know that those people that won
simply
don't have the money to buy an award so
i feel like those people won those
awards fair and square
i know them i know their business i'm
friends with them
i know what allegedly it would cost to
win a cup and i know they don't have
that kind of money so
i know that my friends won those
categories fair and square they won
those events
but sometimes some of the bigger ones
it is questionable i don't want to point
any fingers or anything but it has
definitely been questionable sometimes
you see the guys with
the larger booths uh the largest
presents
they win and it seems like they just
threw a bunch of money at the event in
the event went well yeah you gave us
enough money to host this whole event so
we're just gonna give you the awards
sometimes that's what it feels like
allegedly i have no evidence toward that
i'm gonna talk myself out of that hole
really quickly now um
ideally judging is based on categories
and subcategories
so you're gonna have uh obviously a
flower category right and that's buds
flowers buds dried buds uh people are
gonna have a flower category in that
category you're gonna find indica
you're gonna find a sativa and you're
gonna find a hybrid category
then you're gonna judge those categories
on
basically looks smell flavor aromas
the buzz you get from that when you
smoke it how the how does it burn how is
the burn ability does the ash come out
chunky and black does the ash come out
nice and white
did it burn your throat when you smoked
it did it make you cough did it give you
weird cottonmouth
did it have a weird flavor to it a lot
of that is going to matter then
also we're going to give it give it to a
lab and let the lab test it
i agree and disagree with labs testing
our cannabis for competitions because
i didn't grow my flower for a machine to
smoke it i don't really care what the
gas chromatography or liquid
chromatography machine says
i care what you say when you smoke it
i've never seen a computer
take a rip off a joint and go damn that
was good
[ __ ] or nah that's not as good but i've
seen some of my friends hit a joint and
go
that's not bad and i've seen them hit
another joint and go damn that's the one
those are the ones we're trying to
impress i'm not worried too much about
the machines but they do send samples to
the lab
they do terpene analysis they do thc and
cbd analysis they also check for
pesticides
and heavy metals and then they announce
all of that along with the winners
oftentimes they will do a highest
terpene winner which is done with the
labs they'll do a highest thc winner
which is done with the lab tests
so that's another criteria for testing
so it starts off with the flower
category
then it breaks down into subcategories
you got your indica your sativa your
hybrid
and then we judge those based on the
criteria that i spoke of
in some events they will do an indoor
category an outdoor category
a greenhouse category and a fully
organic category as well
i don't know what's to stop people from
saying that their indoor was grown
outdoor their outdoor was grown indoor
hopefully everyone's just honest with
that but those are other opportunities
and other categories that are available
another thing you see at the events a
lot is concentrates
we judge concentrates there's a
concentrate competition usually
uh best concentrate highest uh cbd
concentrate
and then a lot of these also there is a
a crowd's choice or a
crowd favorite they give that a war out
as well so when they do the concentrates
we basically judge it off of what it
looks like what it smells like what it
tastes like
um then the buzz is very important
because you're smoking
40 samples in a day did two of them
stick out to you did one get you
super buzz compared to the others that's
something you're looking for
then how does it react when you put it
on the banger on the nail however you
consume it
does it sparkle up did it splatter up
did it make a bunch of weird noises did
it sizzle
uh did it leave any char or residue on
the banger that is something to think
about i like a
a good clean looking concentrate i know
what it's supposed to look like a nice
color a nice texture a good aroma
i want it to burn nicely on the rig i
don't want it to leave any residue
i don't want it to taste funny i don't
want it to leave any weird aftertaste
i wanted to have good pleasant uh only
cannabis derived terpenes left
terpenes they leave good flavors in my
mouth is all i want to taste at the end
of that i don't want any
weird additives or weird flavor
enhancers or anything i don't want it to
leave weird [ __ ] on my banger
i want my rig to be clean and ready for
another dab after that dab
that is a winning concentrate if i hit
it and i go damn that tastes good i'm
high as [ __ ]
and my rig isn't all dirty from it
that's a good concentrate right there so
that's what we're looking for when it
comes to judging judging concentrates
you will find several categories of
concentrates based on
your uh your location the region of the
event
in some newer places you're gonna get
like solvent and non-solvent
concentrates that's what you're gonna
find
and that's gonna be um solvent is
anything like bho
or uh hexane or propane derived
concentrates
that's all solvent derived concentrates
when they say non-solvent
that does include water hash and sift
and any type of bubble hash and maybe
even prestash at this point would go
into there
now let me give a disclaimer i did just
say that non-solvent hash is water hash
and people are going
to say but rosta jeff water is a solvent
our friend nika t
taught us that in the process of making
bubble hash water is not used as a
solvent because it is not dissolving the
trichomes it is used as an agitator
a separating agent and it is washing the
trichomes from the product so yes i do
understand the science that water is a
solvent
in this case the product we are using is
not water soluble so it is not being a
solvent type product in this option
it is washing is being used as an
agitator as a separating
agent a little bit different than a
solvent there so it does count as a
non-solvent product
shout out to nicotine for teaching us
the difference between solvent and
non-solvent concentrates
and why water is not a solvent all right
also
in that category you may see diamonds
you may see sauce you may see a lot of
other different types of concentrates i
said based on based on your location and
your region
here in colorado we've had legalization
for quite a while
the race is on we've all been trying to
find the best concentrates everyone's
trying to make the best concentrates
so here you're gonna see different
categories because it's available
maybe in a newer market all the
concentrates haven't evolved because
legalization hasn't been there the
technology hasn't been there
people haven't been striving and
learning as much so you may just find
smaller options you'll get your solvent
and non-solvent concentrates
also you may see uh carts
cartridges cartridges filled with
concentrates you'll find your best car
your highest terp car
and highest thc and cbd carts will be
available
at a lot of the competitions now because
cartridges are becoming very popular i
think cartridges
are about 50 to 70 percent of sales here
in colorado
uh so there are a lot of carts out there
carts are getting real popular
also you will see edibles they will have
the best edible and highest
cbd edible at the cannabis cups that's
another competition that they will have
also they will have best overall cbd
product is something you'll also see
so those are a lot of the con the
categories that you see at a cannabis
cup i'm gonna make sure i covered your
questions
um what are the criteria yeah we smoke
it we look at it we make sure it's
enjoyable basically
uh ways to prevent someone buying or
swaying votes
unfortunately i don't know that that
does not happen and i don't know how to
stop it
the best way to do it is to make
everything based on public votes
but we've seen what happens with voting
and
welcome to 2021 we're just going to move
forward from that statement um
uh the veterans panel that's a [ __ ]
cool idea like i said before i agree
with the veterans panel
i would put you on the veterans panel
and i would make sure that we had
plenty of good concentrates for the
veterans and then you guys would leave
with all the leftovers
and all these competitions usually the
people that throw it leave with the
leftovers
we'll send it home with the veterans all
right that is part two of a
long question let's jump into part three
and see how far we get through this
i may have to save a couple for another
episode because this is getting quite
long
number three on mister's question says
your thoughts about kovid's impact on
the cannabis industry and the future of
cannabis cups
are you noticing any pandemic proof
aspects in the industry
in the cannabis business or community um
so
my thoughts on kovid's impact on the
cannabis industry and the future of cups
the impact on the industry we have been
selling
record numbers of cannabis people when
they were stuck at home during
quarantine
when they couldn't go out and do things
people were smoking tremendous amounts
of cannabis so
in the industry uh we saw a lot of
cannabis sold now
uh the future of cannabis cups i said
before i don't know how long until
people are going to be comfortable
especially myself going out
and smoking and doing stuff like that
i'd love to get out there
but i've got mixed emotions um an event
would draw a large crowd
and large crowds are kind of what we're
against so i wouldn't be there for a
while
um also at the start of the pandemic a
lot of people started growing
so a lot of people started buying seeds
i don't want to say that anything is
recession-proof
but it feels like when things go things
go weird
people turn to things that make them
feel better and cannabis is one of the
things that makes people feel better
also people had to think about their
budgets they can't buy as much cannabis
they want to smoke more
they turn to growing so i did see an
influx of
new growers and seed buyers at the start
so
i can't say anything's recession proof
but the seed business did not slow down
we are still adjusting uh nothing is
stable at this point so
i don't want to say that the industry is
recession proof i don't want to say that
the seed business will keep going but as
the adjustment has happened things have
been well for
my end of the industry but what works
this month uh may not work next month we
one day we're able to go eat at
restaurants the next day we're not
allowed to eat at restaurants one day
we're allowed to shop in the dispensary
the next day we have to do it outside
things are weird so i don't know um the
whole idea of job security
disappeared so i don't know things are
kind of weird like kind of rambling on
that one
um podcasting seems to be pandemic proof
you asked if there's anything
pandemic proof in the cannabis industry
the only thing i can think of that has
been
pandemic proof is podcasting i have not
missed a single episode
i have stepped up the quality of my show
i've stepped up the uh everything the
gear the technology the
show is way better i've been trying to
put more time energy and effort into the
show
since we can't go anywhere i'm gonna be
here so i think the
podcast has basically been pandemic
proof as long as
i don't get sick as long as i don't get
the covet the show must go
on i'll still come record with kovid
because i can cough right into the damn
microphone in the camera and you guys
will be safe
uh knock on wood a lot to make sure i
don't get the the vid but
i've also been protecting myself making
sure i don't but um
i think that the pandemic the only thing
is pandy proof here
is podcasting and i don't want to jinx
myself so let's move forward from that
let's see question number four explain
how you personally develop a sense and
taste
profile for your strains i says for
example my strain smells like wet
diapers dirty feet stored next to
mothballs and an old gasoline canister
bro that sounds like something i would
say you've been listening to the show so
how do i explain
my flavors and aromas um basically
i have got a very strong ah
aroma memory bank i guess is the way to
put that
and i associate aromas and flavors and
foods
with places and times and locations and
people
i think that our aroma our sense of
smell
is very uh very strong and it has a very
long memory
i don't forget smells and aromas i can
forget names i can forget faces i can
forget directions to places i can forget
what i'm saying in the middle of a
sentence
but if i smell something like oh that's
that's that perfume that grandma used to
wear called this from this year and she
wore it at that one event and i'll never
forget the smell
grandma and that event just because of
aromas i know that was a really weird
example to pick
but just trying to try to pick something
random smells will trigger memories for
me and they don't go away
and they're really vivid in my nose and
i almost
sounds i may sound like i need mental
help maybe i do i almost
smell in colors that's why the red pill
and blue pill got called red pill and
blue pill
that's why a lot of my strain names have
colors in the names
that's why they're related to fruits
that have a color that you'll recognize
i smell in color as weird as that may
sound
ah it sounds weird as i say it but i
smell in color i smell
visually if i smell like this weird dank
musty smell
i can see the the basement where i used
to learn the drums
like weird [ __ ] like that i can just i
can my so
what i'm doing when i'm telling you that
this smells or this
this product tastes or smells like uh
dirty feet stored next to mothballs in
an old gasoline container
what i'm basically doing is i'm smoking
it and i'm going
huh there's this flavor what is that oh
that's mothballs
okay mothballs then i exhale what is
that oh it left gas
and like dryness on my tongue so it
tastes like mothballs
and chalky gas that's just what my brain
associated those flavors with
and also i'm trying to find familiar
words for you
things that you have eaten smelled
smoked drank tasted
that i can relate that flavor to you so
that when you smoke it you can go
holy [ __ ] that does taste like oranges
and dirty feet something that you're
familiar with something that my brain is
familiar with
and just try to articulate that from uh
just from
my mental memory i've got a rolodex of
flavors and aromas in my nose that i
will never forget
and when i smell them i can recall them
quite quickly you could probably
blindfold me and take me to a few places
i've been quite often
and just let me go in there and smell it
and i could probably tell you where i am
there are a couple of commercial grows
in colorado
that when i walk into them i can smell
that grow
very specifically i know that sounds
crazy but i know the smell
of i'm not even going to say the names
of the few of the cultivation facilities
but they've all got a very
distinct smell and if i walked in you
blindfolded me i could say oh we're over
here at this place
and i can say oh we're over here at this
place by the smell of the facility
maybe it's crazy maybe it's bionic uh
whatever it is i think it's a blessing
as a seed breeder
to be able to identify flavors and
aromas in that manner
all right i'm going to keep moving
forward there are two more questions i'm
going to fit them both in it says
number five is there anything to
harvesting by the full moon lunar cycle
or is this faux grow science
there are two major solar events in 2021
have you observed these types of
celestial events having any beneficial
effects on a harvest
my first response to this was no because
i'm not a hippie
but honestly i grow indoors on an indoor
commercial production cultivation
schedule
and i don't even know if it's sunshine
or rainy or
snowy or daylight or nighttime or an
eclipse
or a riot or a fire outside when i'm
working in the cultivation facility
it is the lights come on at this time
the lights go off at this time the
plants are on this schedule
i don't know what's going on with the
sun and the moon
and the hippie lunar calendar i don't
have any clue what's happening i don't
pay any attention to that
if i had an outdoor grow i would
probably adjust and learn
that hippie science stuff i would do all
of that if i had an outdoor girl but
being an indoor farmer
i do not pay any any attention to any of
that stuff
um if you've got hate mail for that or
any questions or updates for that my
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
i'd love to hear from anybody who's got
input on that honestly being an indoor
cultivator
running on a commercial cultivation
schedule the sun the moon
lunar cycles eclipses that doesn't make
any difference in my grow
i like to go watch the eclipses myself
i'll check them out
but the grow i don't think the grow
cares at all
um all right the last part number six
and lastly
uh you mentioned someone's name i'm not
gonna say their name somebody dropped
off some presents early
for my divas i'm using two of these
items already i've got a
handheld infrared thermometer and a
desktop monthly planner that monthly
planner
will be invaluable it's one of the best
things you can have
then it says my question is about the
infrared thermometer
this thermometer has a laser used for
pinpoint accuracy however i'm wondering
if said laser can damage the leaves even
if
the grow lights are on after all we're
not supposed to look into that same
laser
do you implement an infrared thermometer
if so
where on the plant do you take your
readings
i do not think that the infrared dot on
that thermometer is going to disrupt
your plants in any way
uh as long as you don't hit it in the
plant's eye and i don't know where the
plants eyes are
i don't think they have rods and cones
to worry about i think they've got
uh we're not even going to go into that
what all that shit's called i was going
to go down a long rabbit hole we're
going to skip that
they've got leaves uh you can put that
red dot on the leaves and i think it
will tell you the leaf surface
temperature of those leaves without
doing any damage
where do i take those readings i don't
play with the infrared thermometer quite
often i don't find it to be completely
necessary
uh but i would hit about the top of the
canopy where the lights are shining and
then about a third of the way down
and then toward the bottom just to have
a nice comparison what's happening at
different points of the room
and you will notice that the leaf
surface temperature will be vastly
different
than the air temperature of the room
especially when using leds
i'm not going to go too far into that
because i do have somebody that i want
to get on the show to teach us about
that a little bit
but when you're using leds the leaf
surface temperature will be drastically
different when you're using
metal halide or hps lights so that is
something to think about
but i check in about three different
spots up at the top where the light's
really intense
down in the middle where the light's not
so intense and then down lower
where we're not getting much light right
right at the top of where we defoliated
that's where i would check also and see
make a note of it write down what the
temperature is on your leaf surface
temperature and see if things go wrong
or if things go right see if that leaf
surface temperature
had anything to do with it all right
mister this was a long
and great email we took up the whole
episode with this one
thank you for the great contribution uh
thank you for the patreon support
and most of all thank you for your
service like i've said before if we can
do anything for you
uh the grow from your heart crew the
irie army crew we've all got your back
just reach out
let us know what we can do for you we've
already proven that we're here to help
you out
um let's see um what else do we have it
says thank you for all your time
effort and all that you do for our
community roster jeff have a safe and
ire december everybody i'm already
writing down my questions for my january
letter we're gonna have to break that
one up into a couple of episodes
uh it says lastly a hand salute to all
of my fellow veteran growers yes big
shout out to all of the veteran growers
out there
then it says regardless if you're a
novice a noob or
uh if you're a novice or a noob you are
still a veteran grower it's a big shout
out
sounds like mister's uh sending a lot of
love in this uh message
then it says peace love and a truly
happy new year to all
my growers love hugs and respect from
mr thank you mister i do appreciate it
big shout out i look forward to
january's
uh message like i said i may break that
one down into a couple
of episodes because this one did get
quite long and you stole the show today
buddy thank you for all the support bro
uh i do enjoy seeing you uh in the
premieres you guys
when the show drops on youtube it
happens on sunday night at midnight
which is monday morning sunday night
monday morning
at midnight and also wednesday night
into thursday morning at midnight
i do the shows on youtube at 12 o'clock
i premiere them
the show is not live i've had a few
people say hey i love watching your live
shows at midnight it's fun hanging out
with you
it is not live it is pre-recorded but it
does drop at midnight
and i do hang out in the premiere and
chat with the folks uh sometimes i'm
working on other projects and just kind
of side chatting with you guys sometimes
i'm fully focused on hanging out taking
dabs and chatting
but it's always good to see everybody in
there and it is super great to see mr
pop in
in every episode in every premiere thank
you for being there bro
uh it's good to know that you're always
part of the irie army uh and again let
me know if we can do anything because i
love your support
all right you guys i feel like this
episode got really long really quickly
big shout out to our buddy mr
if anybody out there has any questions
corrections comments or concerns
again i would love to hear from you my
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
don't be shy reach out let me know what
you think of the show ask your questions
send your corrections comments concerns
i'm not shy you don't be shy either
also if you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
and you'd like to make a financial
contribution to the show all you have to
do is visit www.patreon.com forward
slash grow from your heart
all of the information you need will be
right there on the screen and of course
there is a link in the show notes and in
the video
description don't forget to visit my
website iriegenetics.com
all things irie genetics all things grow
from your heart all things rosta jeff
are right there on the website
at iregenetics.com click on that merch
tab
and you can actually get taken right to
my web store where you can get these
sweet
irie army t-shirts there are only a few
left so i will have to restock
get them before the first batch is gone
because it is taking quite a bit of time
to get shirts made right now shirts are
unavailable we can't get shirts we can't
get blank shirts to print on so grab
them before they disappear
i think that is all i've got for you for
this episode i'll be back in just a
couple of days with fresh new content
i want to thank you again for listening
to episode 601 of the grow from your
heart podcast
i want to give a giant shout out to my
buddy ez057
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
you