all right here we go welcome back
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rosta jeff
and this is episode 602 of the grow from
your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to talk about
making your own silver thiosulfate spray
to reverse your plants to make feminized
seeds
before we get there let's do a few shout
outs to a few of the folks who support
the show on patreon
let's start off with the big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to our new friend colin hughes
let's send a big thank you shout out to
robert s i want to send a big thank you
shout out to freedom
farms let's send a big thank you shout
out to owen g crossman
i want to send a big thank you shout out
to our buddy redbeard let's send a big
thank you shout out to learning and
burning
i want to send a special thank you shout
out to our new friend dz from detroit
let's send a big fist bump and a grow
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out to our friend gaiuty grows
let's send a big thank you shout out to
tart and mike i want to send a special
thank you to pack northwest dan
and last but certainly not least let's
send a big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out
to tree star meadow big thanks and big
shout out to everybody who supports the
show on patreon
if you are not already supporting the
show and you'd like to learn how to do
so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need to support
the show
is right there on the screen and of
course i did include a link in the show
notes
and in the video description to make it
nice and easy for all of my friends
maybe you're driving maybe you're
working
maybe you got your hands full be safe
get to that link
when it is time all right ladies and
gentlemen without a whole bunch of
chatter
i do want to apologize for the monday
episode being late i have not missed a
monday
and i think five or six maybe seven
years worth of podcasting i've never
missed
a monday this monday the show was
delayed it wasn't
i came out on monday still but it was
barely monday in the mountain time zone
when it came out there was a technical
difficulty with my website where the
uh podcast is posted i had to contact a
couple of people to try to help me
i was left with a couple of baffled
faces eventually i contacted the web
hosting service
and they were able to get me fixed up it
took a couple of hours on the phone
some head scratching some click and some
punching away we got it solved so
big shout out to everybody who let me
know that the podcast was late
big shout out to everybody who is
concerned uh people that reminded me hey
bro it's monday there's no podcast on
itunes
i know i was scrambling big shout out to
the web hosting company i was going to
say their name
i don't want to say their name because i
don't want you to know where the podcast
is hosted
uh it's just safer that way for
everybody but big shout out to the web
hosting company that was able to get my
website
uh back up get the uh service going for
everybody
and big shout out to everybody who
wanted to remind me that the show was
like that is my point here
um it was up on youtube on time so
technically we were not late at all i
did have something to show
that i really did do a podcast it was
there we did
a premiere on monday on youtube i hope
you joined us and if you didn't join us
for the next premiere
every time i do an episode i do the
premiere it is monday night at midnight
or
thursday night at midnight it's actually
sunday night rolling into monday or
wednesday night rolling into thursday
that's when i premiere the episodes is
at 12 o'clock midnight
uh mountain time i don't know your time
zone but join me in the mountain time
i know why do i do it late at night
because that way the podcast is there
for everybody in the morning and i can
still stay up late that night and hang
out in the premiere
i think 12 o'clock work works
beautifully i am [ __ ] rambling we're
gonna get out of these rambles and we're
gonna work ourselves
into some emails i've got one quick
patreon message before we talk about
making our own silver thio sulfate
solution
uh this message comes from patreon it
comes from our good friend girls grow
too shout out to girls grow too hope
everything is doing marvelously in your
garden
i'm gonna catch my breath and read this
message it says
um you mentioned you taste in colors you
may have what is called
synesthesia it's a real thing and when
you mentioned it i wanted to tell you
uh the show keeps getting better thanks
for all the continued work you do
cheers to 2021 so
in a previous episode i mentioned that i
think i smell in colors
and i've been told that that's an
official thing it looks like i've been
diagnosed with
synesthesia i'm not crazy my mother had
me tested
um big thank you for the great uh update
of the
diagnosis i guess we can say i'm gonna
read more about that and now i don't
feel like i am as crazy
trust me i still feel crazy but that's
one more thing we don't have to worry
about
all right let's get to the point of this
podcast this is going to be a short
episode
but i promise you this is going to be a
very valuable episode for a lot of
people
so with no further ado let's get into
this great question that came from our
friend joe
and it goes a lot like this it says
what's up ross to jeff i saw you on the
dude gross show before
and i had to check out your podcast big
shout out to all of my friends in the
dgc
shout out to the dude grows crew big
shout out to scotty real
shout out to the dude shout out to guru
and big shout out to everybody
behind the scenes that makes that show
happen i understand there are a lot of
people
that make that show the wonderful
production it is big shout out to each
and every one of the people
behind the scenes as well they get
overlooked quite a bit
big shout out to the dgc gang i'm glad
you found me through the dude grows crew
it's ahead to check out your podcast
thank you for all of the knowledge
and for keeping it simple for us stoners
i like to explain things in a way that
everybody can understand some people
learn from this angle some learn from
this angle i make sure to deliver
my teachings from a lot of angles i did
not like school i loved learning but i
didn't enjoy school
that may sound redundant but i'm not
good at sitting in a classroom
looking at a chalkboard or now it's a
dry erase board i guess and listening to
some boring ass person
drone on for eight hours a day that was
not for me i understand that learning
uh can be totally boring for some people
and i try to keep it entertaining i try
to keep it fun
try to tell a couple of jokes in there
so i'm glad you find it uh that i'm
keeping it simple
for the stoners i try to keep everybody
involved if you're a new grower if
you're an advanced girl if you're a pro
grower that's
always been my slogan i try to have
something for you
it says i have a question about silver
thiosulfate
if you recommend a certain brand also
when to spray
and how often to spray and how you
dilute your spray i know you said
different strains will require different
solutions and intervals
i just want a good starting point or a
reference to go off of thanks again big
respect and of course this comes from
our buddy joe
joe thank you for the great question
there is a lot to talk about here
what joe is asking about is uh a silver
thiosulfate solution which would be used
to reverse
a plant that reversed plant would then
create pollen
and that pollen would then create
feminized seeds i have talked
in great detail about feminized seeds on
other episodes i'll include a link to
the other feminized seed episode in the
show notes
but basically what we're going to do is
take a female plant
and we're going to treat it with this
solution that will cause this plant to
create pollen sacs which only contain
female chromosomes because it's a true
female plant we have tested that solid
uh it's a female it will make uh pollen
with female chromosomes we put that on
another female plant the seeds that come
from there are
all females the way that we do that is
with a silver
thiosulfate solution now our friend joe
asked what brand
do i use there are a lot of reversal
products out there on the market there
are a lot of companies making pre-mixed
silver thiosulfate solutions
there are a lot of options i make my own
i buy silver nitrate
what do i buy i wrote it down because i
want to make sure i get it right i
bought silver nitrate and i buy sodium
thiosulfate in separate containers they
are dry powdered forms
and i make my own silver thiosulfate
solution
this will work on ninety percent of the
plants you are trying to reverse
most of the products on the market are
overpriced and unnecessary when you can
make your own silver thiosulfate
for about 13 for probably a hundred
gallons you don't need to make that much
at a time you only need about
a half a gallon at a time is probably
the most i've ever needed
so you don't need to make a lot at a
time and you don't need a lot of product
to make it you don't need a lot of money
if you do have plants that are a little
bit stubborn there is one product out
there
that i'm not going to say is overpriced
if you've got some stubborn plants that
won't reverse
that one reversal spray may be worth the
money but otherwise i would say
make your own silver thiosulfate i'm
going to teach you guys how to be
self-sufficient
i want you self-sufficient and always so
you're going to get some gold from me
today
today we're going to talk about making
our own silver thiosulfate solution i'm
going to clear my throat really quickly
and then we will move forward
all right excuse me i felt it was better
to get that out of the way instead of
just keep doing it
all right here we go we're going to make
our own silver thiosulfate solution to
reverse our plants the first thing we
need is
distilled water i highly recommend
distilled water
distilled water is easy to get it's very
affordable it's probably two bucks for a
gallon
you can probably get it at the gas
station or the grocery store right down
the street from wherever you are so we
start off with distilled water
then like i said before we need silver
nitrate
we also need sodium thiosulfate these
products are both
readily available on the internet a very
short google
search will find these products for you
don't spend too much they are very
affordable products
the most expensive part will probably be
shipping
they're going to ask you all kinds of
questions some of the websites ask more
questions some websites don't ask any
questions
this these products could be used for
photography there is a wide range of
uses for these products if they ask a
lot of questions maybe you don't use
that website find the website that
doesn't ask you what you're using it for
find a website that i don't know where
you are find a website in your country
so you don't have to ship these products
over the border so that you get them
more quickly
um something i'm going to jump in this
is not in my notes but i feel like i do
need to say this anytime i talk about
mixing or
touching dangerous products wear the
appropriate
protective personal protective equipment
wear the appropriate personal protective
equipment
these products are caustic you don't
want to breathe in silver nitrate or
sodium thiosulfate
it's very fine particles if you're new
at this please
protect yourself if you're experienced
at this please protect yourself wear a
respirator
maybe even some goggles wear some gloves
please protect yourself i know you're
going to say that's extreme
but i'm teaching you how to do something
i need to teach you how to protect
yourself please
protect yourself when making these
products so you're going to get
distilled water you will need
silver nitrate you will need sodium
thiosulfate
you'll need a couple of containers i
prefer glass containers glass vessels
we're going to put 500 milliliters in
one container
of water of distilled water in one
container and 500 milliliters of
distilled water in another container
then we're going to pour those two
containers of water
into one vessel of water so we need two
containers that will hold 500
milliliters each and we need another
vessel which will hold at least one
liter of water a thousand milliliters is
going to going to go into this next
container
so the way that we do it the way that i
do it is i will take
one half of a gram of silver nitrate
i'll repeat that
one half a gram 0.5 of a gram of silver
nitrate
and i will drop that into 500
milliliters of distilled water
and stir it until it is completely
dissolved it shouldn't take too long
then i will take a separate jar
or container of distilled water this is
jar number two or jar b
500 milliliters of distilled water to
that jar i will add
two and a half grams of sodium
thiosulfate powder
2.5 grams of sodium thiosulfate
to the 500 milliliters of distilled
water
now i've got my jar a and my jar b i've
got my my silver nitrate my sodium
thiosulfate jars that are separate
we've stirred them both up i use a
butter knife to stir them honestly
because it's metal nothing's going to
stick to it it's non-porous
i use i use the butter knife i pull it
out i clean it stir the other one with
the butter knife
that's what i use honestly then like i
mentioned a moment ago
we will take those two bottles those two
jars of solution
and pour them into the one container in
most cases you would mix
uh one into the other i honestly since
my containers are full at this time i've
got a bigger vessel here
i pour them both into there kind of at
the same time and stir them with the
butter knife after they're poured into
there
now you have got a silver thiosulfate
solution that is a 100 ratio do not
spray that 100
concentrate onto the plants we need to
dilute that solution let's jump into
that part now
we've got our one uh a liter of silver
thiosulfate solution in our large vessel
this is when i get a spray bottle just a
basic spray bottle i get them from uline
you can get them from the dollar store
uh what's that other place harbor
freight's got them all the time just a
basic spray bottle you'd put a window
cleaner in it and spray the window
spray the window and wipe it down that's
the exact type of spray bottle i'm
talking about
maybe something depending on how many
plants you're spraying you may want
something bigger
the small squirt pump spray bottle works
just fine for what i'm doing
so then i will take uh this is where it
comes into
uh adjusting for the plant i will start
with a
one to nine dilution i will use one part
silver thiosulfate and nine parts
distilled water so i'm diluting it one
to nine
one part of the silver thiosulfate
solution nine parts distilled
water so if my spray bottle will hold a
thousand milliliters
i put 100 milliliters of silver
thiosulfate solution in there
then i top it off with 900 milliliters
of clean water
uh the distilled water then i shake the
[ __ ] out of it to make sure i've got a
nice mix in there
and i've got a thousand milliliters and
a spray bottle this is when we start
treating the plants
see how easy it was to make the silver's
thiosulfate solution that's why i don't
want you guys paying
so much money for these products you get
500 milliliters of something
and you got to spray it way often you
don't have enough of the solution it's
not going to work and it was way
overpriced
don't buy into those products like i
said there's one product that is worth
it
if you're having a hard time reversing
plants but otherwise don't spend that
expensive money
because most of the time silver
thiosulfate will do it and it's very
affordable you'll be amazed
at how affordable this project will be
it's like 13 bucks and you can make
gallons and gallons of this stuff so
we've used a half a gram of silver
nitrate
two and a half grams of sodium
thiosulfate that's in our liter of water
it's all mixed up together
we've mixed uh we've diluted that into
our spray bottle we've got 100
milliliters of sts
900 milliliters of uh the distilled
water
in a spray bottle now it is time to
start spraying the plant
uh let me jump back into the message and
make sure i'm getting all the things you
asked for a certain brand
okay when to spray is the next part of
the question here when to spray
is a very important part of this
equation
i spray about a week before i put the
flat the plant into flour
so if i'm going to put the plant into
flour on the seventh i will spray it on
the first
today i'm recording on a wednesday if i
wanted to flip my plants on wednesday
i would spray them on wednesday so pull
that plant that you plan on flipping
out of the room don't do it in the room
with the rest of the plants don't think
you can control the spray don't be a
dumb ass don't be a smart ass
take the plant out of the room spray it
with the silver thiosulfate solution
spray it to run off i like to spray it
till it's really running off
also don't just spray the leaves with
the solution
spray the stem spray the stalks get the
entire plant with the silver thiosulfate
we want to get as much of the silver
into the plant
the sodium thiosulfate is a carrier
agent the silver actually gets into the
plant
and causes the reaction which i spoke
about in the feminized seed episode not
going to go too far into that right now
so pull that plant out spray it when it
is completely dry
you can put it back in the grow room
then you wait a week then we put all of
the plants into flower
maybe not all of them that is another
issue that you've got to think about
it's going to take
somewhere between 25 and 35 days
for this plant to produce pollen we want
the female plants closer
to day 23 to 30 ish when they get pollen
so time that out you may want to put
this boy into flower a little bit
earlier
get him head started or this girl that
is going to be a boy
that's a reversed female is technically
what it is we may want to get
him her into flower a little bit more
early than the other females
let's get back on track with the plant
we are spraying we're going to spray a
plant
spray on a week before flower day then
move it to the flower room on flower day
spray it again the first day of flower
so whatever day you flip the lights
spray that plant again that days pull
it out of the room spray it to run off
then we're going to spray that plant
every three days so on day one
day four day seven ten thirteen and so
on every three days you wanna spray that
plant
i sprayed the plants approximately seven
to nine
times including that first initial spray
something's clicking when i move and i
apologize if you can hear it in the
recording i think it's my headphone
cable
uh it's driving me nuts i'm hoping it's
not driving you crazy so we're going to
spray the plants seven to nine times
some plants that take longer to flower
some plants that are more stubborn will
get 10 or 11 sprays
this comes with learning the plant this
comes with learning
the dilution of the solution and the
frequency of how often to spray that
plant
i wish that this 90 percent diluted uh
solution would work on every plant with
seven sprays
but we're working with cannabis plants
we're working with living things they
are picky
some plants you can spray them with a
really strong solution
a couple of times and they'll reverse
very well some of them you have to spray
them a lot of times with a very diluted
solution and they'll reverse better
the only way to learn this is by doing
it to the plants
if you have a plant that you have chosen
to be your pollen donor that you're
going to reverse
i recommend taking several clones of
that plant and treating it with
different dilutions of the solution
treat it with a 90
treat it with an eighty percent treat it
with the or the eight to one
or a nine to one and then an eight to
two and a seven to three
just start increasing the potency of
your mix
or start increasing the frequency of
your sprays
then see how the plants react you will
see in the end which plant makes
the most pollen that's kind of what
we're looking for which plant makes the
most pollen
the only way to really tell if this
project was successful is to grow out
the seeds
which you produce so let me recap just
to make sure i got everything
because i'm going kind of quickly um
we're going to spray
about a week before flip then we're
going to spray again
on day one and then every three days so
day one day four
seven ten continue until about day 22
ish
sometimes if the plant doesn't look like
it is reversed or if it's not doing what
i want it to do
i will continue the spraying i'll
continue to spray it
maybe nine to 11 times just depending on
the plant some of the longer flowering
plants
some of the more stubborn plants will
get more sprays out of me
uh if you over spray the plants will not
produce pollen they'll simply make
pollen sacks that open up and nothing
comes out they fizzle out and the plants
kind of dry up and look like [ __ ] you
won't get any pollen
sometimes you'll spray them and
immediately the leaves
will just crinkle up and look like
complete [ __ ] by the time you put it
back in the grow room those leaves are
turning brown
you've over sprayed the plant doesn't
want that heavy of a dilution
so then you've got to lighten it up and
you've got to spray more frequently
and then you've got to pay attention to
those leaves sometimes the plants don't
react at all you spray it and you go i
wonder if that's even doing anything
and then about 21 24 days in you start
going oh look it's starting to make
balls it's starting to make male plants
sometimes it takes even longer so it's
all about the plant it's learning that
female plant that you are trying to
reverse we are really doing a lot to
this plant we are changing the hormones
of this plant to make it do something it
was never intended to do
so be patient with it and you've got to
adjust to the plan i say this
all the time the plants are the boss i
wish i had an sop that i could say
spray it at 90 percent at one o'clock on
friday do it again at 2 30 on thursday
and then feed it a cookie and everything
will go magically but again these are
plants this is science
uh this is biology this is horticulture
and nature there are a lot of variables
to work with here
a lot of it depends on the female plant
like the breeding of the female plant
what are the genetics in there
if the plant can reverse too easily
maybe you don't want to work with it so
make sure you've got a solid tested
female
a very important part is that you use
solid tested genetics don't use any
hermaphrodites or you're going to make
more plants with more intersex traits
and that's just going to mess up
everybody's grow nobody wants that so
select good plants
test your progeny and if you can't get a
plant to reverse
that's when it's time to start thinking
about that more expensive
reversal spray you guys i feel like i
went super quickly over that but i feel
like i covered all of the things we need
to cover
make the solution and start spraying
don't get the solution on the other
plants
also sometimes the silver thiosulfate
solution
will leave a purple stain behind so if
you're spraying against a wall
maybe you don't want that wall to turn
purple maybe put something down put some
newspaper behind it or something
but spray until that plant runs off then
put it back in the room once it's dry
don't get the other plants wet
i think i covered it all you guys i
don't want to ramble and go back over
anything unnecessarily because i feel
like i repeat myself a lot
uh that's so that everybody can learn i
do want to thank my friend joe let's
read the email one more time and make
sure we covered everything
uh how do you spray how do you dilute it
different strains take different
solutions and different intervals
i think i covered that you're gonna have
to experiment with the plant so i
recommend taking clones of the same
plant
and just treating them all differently
and take a lot of notes when you do that
otherwise you don't know what you did
you don't have anything to reference
later to see what worked for you
all right that is my lesson on making
your own silver thiosulfate solution to
reverse your plants
i hope you learned something if you
found this episode educational
informative or entertaining
if you'd like to support the show
financially all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information to support the
show is right there on the screen
if you've got any uh edits corrections
comments questions concerns
i would love to hear from you my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
don't be shy also make sure you check
out the website all things roster jeff
all things irie genetics all things grow
from your heart are right there
at ire genetics ladies and gentlemen my
voice is burning out so it is time to
wrap up the show
i want to thank you again for listening
i'll be back in just a couple of days
with fresh new content
i want to give a giant shout out to my
good friend lemur priest and until next
time take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
you