all right here we go welcome back
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rosta jeff
and this is episode 603 of the grow from
your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to talk a
little bit about light leaks i'm also
going to talk about properly watering
our plants
before we get there let's do a few shout
outs to a few members of the 710 club
of course the 710 club are the folks who
support us on patreon
at the 7.10 a month level or higher so
with no further ado let's start off with
the big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out to girls grow too
let's send a big thank you shout out to
bongstein bear
i want to send a special thank you shout
out to greenvet88224
let's send a big special girl from your
heart podcast thank you shout out to
grow can advocate
i want to send a big thank you shout out
and a high five to jackie daytona
let's send a big thank you shout out and
a fist bump to my buddy guido
listen to big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to zachsen
let's follow that up with a big thank
you shout out to brian p i want to send
a big special thank you shout out to my
buddy alabama man
let's send a grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to jg
and last but certainly not least let's
send a big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out high five and a fist
bump
to my buddy kurt zee big thanks and big
shout out to everybody who supports the
show on patreon
if you are not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need to
support the show will be right there on
the screen
and of course i did include a link in
the show notes and the video description
to make it nice and easy for everybody
who's got their hands full maybe you're
driving
maybe you're working maybe you're in the
garden wait until you're parked
wait till you're on a break wait till
you're safe to log in and support the
patreon channel
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart
all right i hope you guys are having a
wonderful morning evening night time
whatever time it is wherever you are i
hope you're warm i hope you're safe
i hope you're smoking something
delicious maybe you're hanging out with
somebody beautiful
i hope it is a great day wherever you
are i'm coming to you from a
cold colorado evening it is super cold
here i'm not going to complain about the
weather for too long
let's jump right into the main topic of
today's
podcast it has been brought to my
attention that i talk about
light leaks on this podcast quite
frequently
i've also been told that i have never
told you what a light leak
officially is so we're going to start
off by talking about light leaks in
today's episode
let's talk about it let's jump right
into it what is a light leak
when we are growing cannabis plants
those plants do need a dark
cycle to flower if we want to initiate
the flowering period
of cannabis plants of photoperiod
cannabis plants if you've got
autoflowers
this is a different story however i'm
going to talk about photoperiod cannabis
plants for this example when we're
growing photo period cannabis plants
those plants require an amount of time
of uninterrupted
total darkness and i mean complete total
darkness if you can see your hand in
front of your face
it is too bright in that room i need you
to stand in that room for a few minutes
and let your eyes adjust
and once your eyes adjust put your hand
in front of your face and if you can see
your hand
there is too much light in there we need
complete total
darkness so during the 12 12-hour
dark cycle which we give our plants to
initiate them to flower most people do a
12 hours on
12 hours off cycle that's a 24-hour day
they're awake for 12 hours they sleep
for 12 hours
that 12-hour uninterrupted dark period
will trigger our plants to go into
flower
now it is very important that we do not
interrupt
that dark cycle that is what i call a
light leak when we get light
into the night cycle of the plants we
don't want to wake the plants up we
don't want to disrupt their sleep cycle
if we disrupt that sleep cycle we can
cause problems with the plants we can
cause minor problems
or we can cause major problems depending
on when these light leaks happen
depending on how long
how often they happen that will depend
also it'll depend on the genetics do
those genetics have a tendency to have
problems
due to light leaks or not but the things
we can see
if we do cause light leaks in our grow
can be things like
intersex traits we can trigger the
plants to throw intersex traits
normally in nature once the sun goes
down it's [ __ ] dark until the sun
comes up
what would happen if one day the sun
came up in the middle of the night
your whole rhythm your whole life would
freak out you would go into panic mode
imagine if some lights come on in the
middle of the night in the grow room
they're going to go into panic mode
they're going to say why is the sun
coming up
i don't know what to do that weird
stress that weird panic mode
often causes plants to throw intersex
traits
the plants want to survive their goal is
to reproduce so they can be grown next
year cannabis plants are annuals
they last one season they produce seeds
if they're pollinated
then they are gone we aren't going to
pollinate these plants that's not our
intention
but if we do give them some stress they
may decide hey the end is near or
something's wrong i better do what i can
do
to make sure i have self-preservation so
i can continue my genetics
so then it will show intersex traits it
will make male parts it will make female
parts
it will pollinate itself and we will
have seeded hermaphroditic plants
that's not something we want so let's
not get light leaks into the grow room
once those lights go off
leave the lights off don't go in that
grow room don't go in there and take
pictures
don't turn on a white to show one of
your friends leave them
in the dark let them sleep we can cause
intersex traits
we can also cause them to not flower at
all
if you've got a light shining into your
grow room when you think it is the dark
cycle
those plants just won't go into flower
you will have turned your timer to 12
12 you'll be waiting and waiting and
waiting it's usually about
10 to 14 maybe 12-ish days in when we
start seeing the plants actually showing
us that they are in flower you may not
see that
so if you've been in flower for 14 15 16
days and you're not seeing any signs of
flower
there is a light leak in that room
you're getting white when it should be
dark
also something else that can happen
depending on when the light
leaks the light interruptions do happen
you can re-veg
your plants your plants can be in flower
for a number of weeks
and then something goes wrong to where
you are getting a light leak that you
don't even know about
now you're getting extra light those
plants may go back into the vegetative
stage and they won't even finish
flowering
you'll have these weird funky looking
buds and you'll have plants with twisted
world leaves
and you'll be like what the heck is
going on in there that's when we're
gonna do a test and you should do this
test
long before you get to this point but
here's how to test if you have a light
leak
go in the grow room turn off all of the
lights
you got to hang out in that room for 5
10 maybe 15 minutes and allow your
eyeballs to adjust to that total
pitch black dark room now at this point
hold your hand in front of your face
if you can see your hand or any movement
i'm white and pasty
any light is going to reflect off of my
hand if i see any light in that room
it is too much light we need
100 percent pitch black total darkness
in this night period so when i say a
light leak
i am talking about an interruption of
the dark cycle
it could be opening the door and getting
light from the other room in there
it could be a hole in some of your
ducting or a hole in your tent that is
letting light from the other room
blatantly into there you're going to see
that lightly cause a hermaphroditic
issue
right where the light is hitting your
bud that one little bud is going to
throw male flowers
and it may pollinate it may create seeds
so be very careful when it comes to
light leaks we do not want light leaks
in our grow
i think i've talked about light leaks a
lot we want to stand in the grow room
and make sure it is totally dark
if it is not totally dark we need to
correct that
something you may notice is that some of
the equipment
in your grow room may be putting off
lights
some of the grow equipment that we buy
has blue led lighting on it some of it
has red lighting on it
the only light that is acceptable in
that grow room
is a green led light since plants are
green
they are not affected by green light
they just reflect the green light they
don't even see it they know it's they
don't even know it's there
so if you've got a green led light that
is the only light that is acceptable in
your grow
a lot of us have equipment with a power
light when you plug it in this little
light comes on
if you've got a red light if you've got
a blue light on any of your equipment
it is time to get some black duct tape
or something similar
and cover that light up we do not need
any lights happening in our grow
while the plants are trying to sleep
cover up
all those lights if you've got a green
light that light will be acceptable
if it is an led we can use green leds
but don't use
a white light with a green painted
bubble over it that is still going to
cause problems the light coming out is
not really green it's got a green bubble
it's not green light so if you're using
any sort of lights in there it should be
a green led with green diodes
not green bulbs not painted green bulbs
we actually want green
light not green glass to keep those
plants in
an uninterrupted dark cycle something
that was brought to my attention
is if you are using an ac infinity fan
speed controller sometimes those will
come
on the little controller box with the
numbers on it sometimes that comes on
randomly so you may think that that
controller is off there's a little
button to turn off the lights
it's been brought to my attention that
occasionally that thing will light up
during the dark cycle and when you go in
the grow room the next day that light is
on and you had no idea that that was on
so if you've got the ac infinity fan
speed controller with the display on it
you may want to make a little light
baffle you can simply get something like
a piece of cardboard
a piece of a piece of a shoe box and
just cut a little flap and tape that
flap right over it's where you can lift
it up
you can adjust and look at your clock
settings and look what you need to
adjust
put the flap right back down maybe
you've got another creative method of
doing so but
let's cover all of the equipment that is
putting off
led red blue purple lighting in our grow
room we do not need that lighting in
there that is going to cause us problems
if it is a green led that is acceptable
now i understand sometimes we do need to
go in the grow room
during the dark cycle and work maybe
something happened maybe you're
hanging out and you heard a word heard a
weird bumping noise or maybe the air
conditioner didn't come on
or maybe you forgot something in there
maybe you left your phone in there
also if it is the dark period don't be
in there with your phone
that counts as light i've seen people in
the grow room
and they're like i'll just use my light
as a flashlight and i won't disrupt the
plants bro that's a light
that that is light the plants are waking
up from that so
don't answer your phone don't use your
phone as a flashlight in the grow room
in the dark period
if you're going to go in the grow during
a dark period
i highly recommend having green led
lights as your work lights
it is a good idea just to replace every
bulb in there with a green light
and you can't just use green light bulbs
they need to actually be putting out
green light be very careful about that
some of the painted bulbs i don't trust
i would definitely prefer
a green diode led light so
if you're going to work in there get
yourself a green light a lot of people
wear the headlamp with the green
headlamp on it
that way the light is shining wherever
you're looking you can highlight your
space
that is cool it kind of makes me feel
weird in there like that i would rather
have the green leds above the
above me so that i can see the room just
something creepy about not being able to
see
over here but only being able to see in
front of me in the dark messes with my
perception and
ah just feels kind of creepy to be
honest with you i'm not afraid of the
dark
maybe i'm afraid of the dark my point is
do not interrupt that dark cycle
when you interrupt that dark cycle that
is what i am calling a light leak it is
fully dark in there
now we've got some light coming in that
is a light leak it's just like having
uh an aquarium with a leak the water is
getting out or the water is getting in
we're getting air or i'm sorry we're
getting light in or out when we don't
want it
that is a light leak and it can cause
great problems to your garden
depending on your genetics a small light
leak could be
seriously detrimental or a small light
leak maybe just a tiny problem but
let's avoid all of the problems we can
by understanding light leaks
and avoiding them i think i covered that
quite well they'll cause hermaphrodites
they'll cause your plants not to flower
and they can also cause your plant to go
into a reveg situation pay attention
that some of your equipment
may have lights on it a lot of the fans
we buy with the timer
if you can set a timer on your fan it's
probably got a red light on it
you've got to go and put some tape over
that some of the extension cords we buy
have lights on them they got the little
on off switch and it's either red or
blue or whatever
you don't want that light switch with
that little switch the on off switch
with the light on it
you don't want that some of the power
strips that we buy
light up when we plug them in they're
clear thin plat
thin clear plastic that's what i meant
when you plug it in the whole strip
lights up
get rid of that piece of [ __ ] we don't
want that in there get a dark
colored power strip a black one so the
light won't shine through it
a lot of them have a little light on the
end to indicate that they're giving you
power
take a screwdriver and [ __ ] puncture
that light bulb or put some tape over it
or drill through it or get some pliers
and pull it out
ruin that light bulb we don't need extra
light in there the only light we want is
from our grow lights
unless again it is a green led light
i feel like i covered that part
excessively i think i made my point
light leaks are when we get light in in
the dark period and it disrupts our
plants
the next thing i want to touch on is
watering
technique the other day i was helping
somebody
do a consultation for a grow and i said
just show me what you do in here and i
just kind of hang out while they do
their thing
and i learn what is going wrong in their
grow by watching what they're doing
and i watch this person get their
watering container they just scoop water
up out of a bucket
and then they poured the water basically
down the stock of the plant
right into the middle of the pot they
got a seven gallon pot that's full of uh
it was a soilless mix so they got uh
just it's filled with the soilless mix
uh seven gallons of media they got a
good sized plant coming out of there
and they are watering the direct center
of the plant
so you got this big seven gallon pot and
they just poured i'm gonna guess a seven
gallon pot is
18 inches around that's my guess that's
close enough even if i'm wrong
they watered a four to six inch circle
in the middle
now what about all this other 14 10
inches
on the outside that didn't get water
that's where all of our roots are
growing
we want to fill that entire pot with
roots if you don't provide water to that
outer edge
how is it going to get wet what are the
roots going to do they're not going to
grow out there you're just going to have
i bet that my friends plants only have
root balls
that are probably 8 to 10 inches around
and the depth of the pot
when most people could achieve a full
root bound pot that whole pot should be
filled with roots by the time this plant
is done but if you're not watering it
those roots will not go there there's no
reason they're just dry it's like ah
it's dry over there let's stay over here
where it's wet because he's only
watering in the middle so think about
this
look at the shape of an untopped
untrained unmanipulated cannabis plant
if you visualize that plant in your head
it's shaped like a christmas tree right
it's
skinny at the top and it gets wider as
it goes down think about the shape of
the leaves the leaves are hanging down a
little bit
kind of acting like shingles on a roof
that one leaf hangs down at an angle
and if water were to land on the top of
the plant the water would run down that
top leaf
and then it would fall onto another leaf
and it would run
down and as it runs down it is also
moving outward because the branches are
getting wider the leaves are wider
it runs down and out down and out until
it gets to the bottom because of gravity
where is that water going to end up if
we picture water falling from above on a
cannabis plant
if you really think about it everything
directly underneath the plant will
remain
dry unless we get enough water what's
going to happen is the area right around
the plant
where those leaves stretch out too all
of that is going to get heavily
saturated with water
then those roots are going to say look
at all this water out here and they're
going to grow and they're going to
expand
and they're going to keep stretching out
until they don't see any more water
what's going to happen in your container
is they're going to go right up to the
wall
and they're going to circle back around
and they're going to keep circling in
there and you will fill that entire
container
with big fat white roots and big fat
white roots will give you big
fat green fruits if you've got a big fat
healthy root system
you can create a bigger fatter healthier
plant so
when you are watering my point of this
is don't water the very center of the
plant
water the outside edge of the plant if
you've got a new plant a baby plant
that's just adjusting to its space
yes water in the middle where the plant
is but as it grows
as the roots grow as the root mass
expands water outward
water more of that space where the fresh
roots are you may need to
increase the amount of water my buddy
was only pouring enough water in
to actually water the area where the
plant probably exists
i told him if he watered the entire
thing and got about 10 to 20 percent
runoff
the roots would grow more rapidly more
vigorous vigorously
and it would just fill and occupy that
entire plant which would give them a
healthier happier plant which produces
bigger fatter buds and that's
what we are all after right if you're
going to do it do it right
so stop watering the dead center of the
plant and let's start watering outward
so that all of those roots can get some
moisture and get a little bit of a drink
i've got one more quick thing i want to
rant about and then we're going to wrap
this one up
something i saw on social media was
somebody asking about a new brand of
soil they can buy
because this brand that they have been
buying is riddled with bugs
they wanted to blame the brand of soil
and then a couple of people wanted to
back them up on the facebook feed
because that's how social media works
but i want to say that you cannot blame
any brand of soil for having bugs in it
because
all brands of soil can potentially and
probably do
have bugs in there it's not happening at
the factory it's not happening
where the soil is made it could be but
most likely it's happening
somewhere in shipping or in a storage
dock i'm sure that the people that make
that soil do their best to keep it
bug-free they want you to have success
but these bags of soil are made in bulk
they're made in mass
they've got to sit on a dock or in a
warehouse or somewhere
i've been to a few grow stores where
they store the soil
in the backyard just right on the dirt
in the backyard
and there will be a stack of your
favorite soil
just two pallets of it stacked up eight
feet tall
then right next to that will be two
pallets stacked up eight feet tall of my
favorite soil
then right next to that will be another
soil that neither one of us have ever
heard of
but it's stacked up eight feet tall on
two pallets and it's all out in the
backyard
of this grow store or out in the
backyard of this warehouse because they
can't store it all indoors
and soil can be stored outdoors that's
safe they got a fence no one's gonna
steal it
but when all that [ __ ] is sitting
outdoors that's when it is getting
bugs and do you think that the bugs are
going to just say i want
this dirt they're going to go no there's
a home over here there's a home here and
there's a home here
they're going to get into all those bags
of dirt and then what are they going to
do they're going to breed
they've got a comfy environment they're
in a bag it's nice and cozy in there
it's warm it's dry
they're going to start partying they're
going to want to eat they're going to
want to hump and they're going to
reproduce
maybe there were only bugs in pile a at
the beginning but after a little bit of
eating and reproducing they wanted to go
find more people to eat and reproduce
with
now they're in pile two now they're in
pile three so the bugs are not in one
specific brand of soil or soilless mix
the bugs are moving around in all of the
brands of soil and soilless makes it's
happening
in the warehouse it's happening in the
dock it's happening in transport it's
happening in shipping
there are so many opportunities for
these bugs to jump into the soil bags
and we cannot blame the soil company
it's happening
it may not even happen anywhere near the
soil company it may have happened at the
grow store that sold it to you
which is as far down the line from the
company as you can get so let's stop
blaming the companies
for having bugs in the soil or soilless
mix that is something that you
should expect from all companies and
as a farmer it is your responsibility
to make sure there are no pests and if
there are pests it's your responsibility
to treat appropriately to ensure that
those pests don't infest our garden that
is the responsibility of
the gardener i can't put a bag of dirt
in a bag
and ship it across the country on a
truck and have it sit in a dock
and promise you that no bugs can get to
that that is impossible
therefore it is the growers
responsibility
to make sure that the things we put into
our garden are clean
and safe and pest free so inspect your
soil
if you get soil and you see things
flying out of it you've obviously got
some fungus gnats
you can't see a lot of the insects until
it's too late but
pay close attention if you do see any
soil-borne pests it is time to treat
that soil
a lot of people wonder how can i get the
bugs out of my soil there are several
ways to do that
the most common uh you can use predator
bugs that is very common
the most common way to get rid of most
bugs in a commercial environment
is to use bt bacillus thuringiensis i
hope i said that right i do not have
that printed anywhere
but that is the most common way to get
rid of most pests in soil
that product is available in many
different forms uh
mosquito dunks are very affordable there
are these products called mosquito dunks
you can find them
at your local hardware stores target
probably has them
the grocery store probably has them they
come on a red package
with yellow writing yellow and white
writing and it simply says mosquito dunk
they look like a
a little donut or a shitty cookie but do
not eat them
it is a beneficial fungus and i think
they are delivered on
it's i think it's like ground corn or
some sort of a uh
some sort of a i forgot what it is now
some sort of a grain but it's dried and
it's got
this bacteria on it so you get these
donut shaped discs
and i usually put them in a paper uh in
a
baggie and i wrap the baggie in a
newspaper and i crush it with the hammer
i don't beat the [ __ ] out of it i don't
want to break the baggie and
rupture the paper i just want to hit it
hard enough to crumble it up into a dust
then i put that dust into my water that
i'm going to water my plants
and then i water that through the soil
and that puts the bt
into my soil and that will destroy
eradicate
most of the bugs that come with your
soil
if the bt doesn't get rid of them that's
when i recommend doing either
an evergreen or botanic garden max
soil dredge you can mix up the
appropriate amount of pesticide
depending on which pesticide you've
chosen to use
mix that up with some water and simply
feed that through your plants until you
get
slight runoff now you've got that
pesticide in there in the root zone
hopefully your plants are nice and
healthy you didn't cause too much damage
it will only take a day or two for them
to recover continue on with your normal
watering cycle
and hopefully one or two soil dredges
of either botanic garden max or
evergreen will eradicate
almost any soil-borne pest
also you may want to spray at the same
time if you think you've got a soil
borne pest
if you think you've got thrips in there
if you think you got spider mites spray
at the same time as you do your dredge
hit them from all angles that way those
bugs have nowhere to go
and you win but we have got to stop
blaming
soil companies cocoa companies for
sabotaging our gardens because we got
bugs in a bag of soil
expect the bugs in the back of soil they
should be there that's what happens in
shipping and transport and storage
expect that it's your responsibility as
the gardener to get rid of that
all right i'm gonna take a sip and i'm
gonna talk about one more thing
here we go sips water
the other thing i want to talk about is
rinsing our cocoa when you get bags of
cocoa
that cocoa has been it came from another
country probably malaysia thailand
something like that
that cocoa came on a boat who knows when
they packed up that cocoa
if they use salt water or if it was on a
boat that got a lot of condensation
sometimes the cocoa we get is filled
with
salt so we need to rinse the cocoa
before we use it we've got several ways
of doing that
you can put all of your cocoa into a
giant container and just hose it down
and just rinse it until you get runoff
or you can put it in the pots that
you're going to plant your plants into
you can mix it with perlite you can put
the perlite and the amendments in there
then you can put it directly into your
pots your threes your fives or your
sevens
whatever you're using then rinse that
while it's in the pot until you get
plenty of runoff
i would almost check to see what the
ppms or ec of that runoff is
get it super low make sure there's not a
lot of salt in there before we put our
plants in there
if you did not rinse your cocoa and you
put your plants in the cocoa and you
were seeing
weird problems with your plants if
they're getting kind of clawy if they're
the leaves are going different
directions you're getting world leaves
or if you're getting odd colors you're
getting
crispiness it's probably because there
was a bunch of salt
in that cocoa and the plants are pissed
off they need to get rinsed out
they just ate all of the salt just
imagine what your mouth tastes like if
you were just
buried in salt so now we've got to
hydrate the plants get the salt out of
there
and start feeding them an appropriate
diet that's all it's going to mess with
your
your ph your ec and the overall health
of your plants
so please rinse your cocoa before using
it
some of the higher end brands don't
require as much rinsing but i still do
recommend a quick rinse
whatever brand you choose to use
all right i think that is all i've got
for you for this episode i know it was
short i know it was quick
i'll be back in just a couple of days
with fresh new content i'm going to get
back onto all of those patreon questions
and those do make for long episodes so
have no fear we'll get some long
episodes coming up
really soon probably the next show all
right i want to thank you guys again for
hanging out
if you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
and you'd like to make a financial
contribution to the show all you have to
do is visit www.patreon.com forward
slash grow from your heart
all of the information you need is right
there on the screen of course if you've
got any
corrections comments questions or
concerns you can send me an email
my email address is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com
don't forget to visit the website at
iregenetics.com
everything i read genetics grow from
your heart rasta jeff is all right there
at iriegenetics.com
all right that's all i've got for you
thank you again for listening i'll be
back in a couple of days with fresh new
content
i want to give a big shout out to my
buddy graybeard and until next time take
a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
you