welcome to the show podcast world i'm
your host my friends call me rasta jeff
and this is episode 604 of the grow from
your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to read a few
patreon messages before we get there
let's do a few shout outs to a few
members of the 710 club
of course the 710 club are the folks who
support us on patreon
at the 7.10 a month level or higher so
with no further ado let's start off with
the big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out
to our friend 13spark13 let's send a big
thank you shout out to dabsquatch
i want to send a big thank you shout out
to zozo j i want to send a special thank
you to noah n
let's send a big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to our
friend brian p
let's send a big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out and a fist
bump
to my buddy the terp burglar let's send
a big thank you shout out to mike multi
let's send a big thank you shout out to
the big sexy dank let's send a special
thank you shout out to bong steen bear
i want to send a big high five and a
fist bump to mr mean green eight
and last but certainly not least let's
send a big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out
to our friend danky dave big thanks and
big shout out to everybody who supports
the show on patreon
if you're not already supporting the
show and you'd like to learn how to do
so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need to
support the show will be right there on
the screen
of course i did include that link in the
show notes and in the video description
because i know a lot of you are
listening while you're driving to work
maybe you're working
don't get yourself in a car crash don't
get yourself fired you can support the
show later
at patreon.com forward slash grow
from your heart while i'm talking about
patreon let me
talk about something i posted to patreon
it has been brought to my attention that
sometimes
when i do shout outs i'm not shouting
out the name you would prefer sometimes
i'm doing the wrong name
because that is what you signed up for
on patreon if you would like me to give
you a shout out at a different name
all you have to do is send me a patreon
message or an email
and just say hey ross to jeff i signed
up on patreon i'm using 13 spark 13 on
patreon i would prefer that you call me
this
and i will make sure to use your
preferred name for shout outs on the
podcast
honestly one person has already
corrected me and hey bro
uh i lost the note i don't know where i
put that note so you're gonna have to
send that to me again
and let me know what you'd like me to
call you for the shout outs on the show
so just send me a message on patreon or
send me an email at grow from your heart
hotmail.com i will make sure to make a
spreadsheet make some sort of notes
that say this person wants to be called
this and i'll do my best to remember
when i give you shout outs on the show i
try to respect people's privacy and also
give you the shout outs you asked for so
thank you for the support help me i'll
help you out all right
i said i was going to read a few patreon
messages let's not waste
too much time let's jump right into the
patreon messages
for this show the first one comes from
do they want their name said
they didn't sign it with their full name
so we're not going to read their name
this one goes like this it says hey
rosta jeff i hope you're doing well
brother i'm a huge fan of the podcast
i am great and thank you for listening
it goes on to say i was wondering about
durbin poison
seeds i was always told it was a plant
only
but i'm seeing seeds for sale online
could imposter seeds
be a real thing so he said plant only
but the actual phrase
that we will use in the industry or in
the cannabis scene in the community
would be clone only durbin poison was
what was known as a clone only there are
plenty of plants out there that are
clone only and i talk about clone only
plants all the time let me tell you what
clone only plant means
in my uh definition in our scene so
something
that say i breed a plant let's just say
that i took i want to talk about
something i've never released and never
put out that way it's actually clone
only
let's say i took a golden goat female
and reversed it
made a male out of the golden goat then
i pollinate the l.a kush
i've got golden gar la cushed a golden
goat at this point it's a femme seed
i find a plant that i really really love
i keep that one plant
then i don't grow any more of the seeds
or i toss all of the other plants that i
grew
that one la cush to golden goat is now
clone only because it's the only one
if i don't release any seeds of it if i
don't have a male of that plant
the only way that that plant is
available is through clone
only so that becomes what's known as a
clone only
strains like girl scout cookies that is
a clone only the forum cut the thin mint
cut whatever you want to call them
that is a clone only gorilla glue number
four
is a clone only that's why it's got the
number four at the end of it
josie wells had a few gorilla glue
phenotypes he selected the number four
there weren't any more seeds after that
so there could be no more breeding to
make more of those plants
there was number four there was number
seven i believe there was another number
that was a keeper they chose to go with
the number four
so gorilla glue number four got spread
out that was a clone only
there was no male of the gorilla glue to
breed with you don't have a male how are
you to make seeds of that
that are not a gorilla glue outcrosser
or something other than something i'll
talk about in a moment
but a clone only is something that a
breeder made and never released
seeds of it he only released she may
have also only released
a clone of that plant so it is a clone
only there are no seeds put out there
now we're going to talk about things
that make it possible for you to have
that in a seed form
i make feminized seeds golden goat is a
clone only
until i came around and made feminized
seeds of the golden goat that's really
easy to make
unadulterated golden goat feminized
seeds that are not
imposter seeds what i did i took the
original golden goat clone only popular
clone
i treat it with a solution which i
talked about in a very recent episode
i treat it with silver thiosulfate a
number of times on a schedule and a
specific ratio in dilution
that creates feminized pollen i then put
that feminized pollen on another clone
of the golden goat and i'm not
adulterating the genetics it is golden
goat to golden go
the seeds that come out are
unadulterated golden goat s
wands i have self that golden goat i
have made feminized seeds
so it is possible to make feminized
seeds of a clone only strain that is
possible
and very likely especially with
something like durban poison
i'm not sure how much durbin poison was
cloned only that's kind of a
an african land race it's got a lot of
rumors and myths and legends around it
i'm sure there are a lot of seeds of
that available if you're privy to where
to look for those sort of things if you
know who to ask especially if you're
from the durban area i'm sure those
seeds are abundant
um so they could be impostors but it is
impo it is possible
that they are feminized seeds and they
are true
durban poison also it is likely that
they are real durbin poison seeds
uh i think ed rosenthal was putting out
durbin poison seeds through scentsy seed
company
several years ago ed might not have been
involved in that but i do remember ed
and scentsy seed company or somebody
putting out the durbin poison seeds a
long time ago
my memory is a little foggy on some
things there's a lot going on in there
so it could be real durbin poison seeds
they could be feminized seeds
or another option is it could be a back
cross
let me talk about back cross for a
moment i made golden goat feminized
seeds
many people are not fond of running
feminized seeds they think that they are
going to be problematic
or they are just more into the natural
male female seeds
those people also wanted golden goat
seeds in their garden
so the best thing for me to do to was to
make
golden goat bx a bat cross that is
attempting to make
a replica of the original golden goat
but i've got to adulterate it by
introducing a male
into the equation so i took a male plant
that was
vastly different in every way from the
original golden goat
and i pollinated that male plant where i
pollinated the golden goat with that
male plant
now i've got something that is basically
if you're gonna think in colors
one was red and one was blue so when we
cross them
when i'm looking for the red phenotype
that represents the golden goat it was
going to be very easy
for me to identify their traits were so
different they were red and blue they
were black and white
it was very easy for me to tell the
difference in the progeny when i grew
them out
so i grew out the plants that came from
that cross that
it was a daybreaker male is what i used
and it's a different day breaker
uh we're gonna avoid that whole rabbit
hole there that's a daybreaker male i
use the daybreaker to pollinate the
golden goat
that made the first round of seeds those
seeds
been made i found a male in that batch
of seeds i do know what i'm saying i got
lost for a second
i found a male in that batch of seeds
that looked identical to the female
golden goat i've already got
so daybreaker male pollinated the golden
goat female seeds came out of that
i used those seeds to search for a male
that looked
exactly like the original golden goat it
grew
the same height the same width it had
the same branching structure
the leaves were exactly the same size
and shape
the serrations on the leaves were
exactly the same it reacted the same way
to calmac deficiencies it reacted the
same way to being topped and manipulated
so this plant was basically a mirror of
the female golden goat but it was a boy
so at that point i took that boy and
pollinated the original golden go
my intention now was that these boy
genetics and these female genetics are
so strongly golden goat that what i
create
is going to be a large percent golden
goat very dominant very it's like a
replica of the original golden go and i
was successful
because the way that i went about that
first crossing was by making a very
obvious outcross
so i would know what i was looking for
in the males so that is a back cross you
take a male
you adulterate the original cross then
you find a male from that progeny and
pollinate the female the original female
in an attempt to recreate the original
cross and that's what i've done with the
golden goat back cross one
my next method would be to run those
seeds again and find another
from that bx1 run those seeds and find a
male that again represents that golden
goat female
and pollinate one more time that would
increase the likelihood
of getting that perfect golden goat
phenotype out of a pack of seeds
so it is very likely that those durbin
poison seeds are
real um i would check with the breeder
hopefully that's a reputable breeder
that you are working with but
the durban poison has been around in
commercial environments in the
underground cultivation scene in the
gray market in the free market
for quite a while so it is quite
possible that that one is
out there and available but if you see
people trying to sell you something like
golden goat number four
regular seeds that's when you need to
question things when you see them
selling
girl scout cookies regular seeds that's
when you question things those are
clone only plants and again a clone only
is something the breeder only put
that clone out of we never put out any
other seeds we never put out a male
you can't reproduce it it is clone only
not available
in seed form all right let me keep
myself moving
i feel like i've got a good flow going
this next question
comes from it says use the name baz what
up baz thank you for the great message
it says oh they've got a this one came
from the website where we've got a grow
help tab let me
tell you about the grow help tab if you
go to iriegenetics.com
there's a tab that says grow help click
on that tab fill out a few short
questions tell me what's wrong with the
plants
and i will do my best to help you out
here is one of those questions
from the grow help tab our friend baz is
growing a strain called crystal candy
they're growing it indoors under led
lights they're in veg
they're growing in soil they've got a
lot of details here i've read the
question those details are not going to
matter because i already know the answer
to your question
the problem it says the leaves are
drooping
the last few hours of the light cycle
when the lights come back
on the plants seem fine this is a thing
known as the daily
light integral those plants know that
the light is going to go off in a little
bit they're kind of programmed
they know the light comes on at this
time and the light goes off at that time
and they're starting to say hey hey bro
hey sis it's probably bedtime we should
start calming down we should get some
tea
start reading a book and settle down for
the night start finding a blanket and a
pillow and start chilling out they know
that the daily light integral they've
got first of all they know the light is
gonna go off the next thing is they've
gotten enough light they're saying hey
that's all the light i'm gonna take for
today i don't need more photons i can't
photosynthesize anymore
i've taken what i can get so your plants
are getting enough light and they also
know that sleepy time is coming up so
they're just chilling out
they're just getting lazy they're taking
a little bit of a break it is nothing to
be alarmed about
the reason that it looks good right when
they wake up is because now they're
awake they're ready to start working
again
you may be able to dial back a little
bit of light you may be able to reduce
the amount of ppfd that these plants are
getting
if your plant if your lights are
dimmable you may be able to dim it just
a little bit maybe raise it just a
little bit
or maybe reduce the amount of light
hours you were giving these plants i
know you don't want them to go into
flower too early
but that may help you out because they
are getting enough light you don't want
to waste electricity
if they're already telling you hey bro
i'm ready to go to bed if it's like a
solid
hour before you turn off those lights
you may be able to adjust
if it's like 30 minutes then i may just
leave it the way it is because they're
saying hey i know it's night time
we're gonna go to sleepy time now
nothing to worry about it's uh kind of a
good sign it says you got a healthy
garden going on
and they're on a good schedule and they
know what to do for you so thank you for
the great question my friend baz
hope i helped you out don't freak out
don't change anything
maybe just adjust a little bit of
lighting so you don't waste any
electricity all right this one comes
from our friend alabama man and this one
was from patreon
it is a two-part question the first one
says mr rasta jeff
most of your strains share the word tall
in their description
starting with your shortest variety can
you please name the five shortest plants
in your lineup do you have a shorteth
a short-ish arthritis painkiller
that is a really great question and i
replied with unfortunately most of what
i breed is like a uh
a sativa dominant kind of a skinny leaf
a thin
leaf kind of a hybrid of mostly sativa
dominant genetics
and most of them are going to get quite
tall on you for shorter plants i would
probably recommend
prana morning dew uh and then i may say
something like um what was the other one
i recommended prana
and morning do and sometimes the orange
gasm will stay short if you don't veg
for too long
but that's oh sun kiss is the other one
i would recommend also
those are what i've got for shorter
although they are going to get tall
if you want to prevent too tall of a
plant that's when you got to work on
canopy control
you can keep anything short if you scrog
it down learn how to work a scrog canopy
uh maybe a two or three layer scrog the
first one is to spread them out instead
of getting them growing up tall
you just put that scrog down and make
them go straight out then you let them
grow up a little bit into that that
second one is to kind of support the
buds and the third one is to really give
you some support for tall colas
but you can run anything if you scrog it
down learn to work it manipulate it bend
it over
you can figure that part out arthritis
i think the arise is great for arthritis
although it's going to get kind of tall
on you
i would say maybe try morning dew that
is going to be a great all-around
indica sativa hybrid that will give you
some nice pain relief
shouldn't get too tall on you all right
there is a second part of
the question and it says mr jeff would
there be any benefit realized if a
grower saved the pollen from a male
plant of a regular pack of irish seeds
and then used that pollen on selected
buds of a female
plant i get free seeds for my trouble
but would those seeds
be stable mirrors of each plant this is
a great question
uh so they are asking if they took
pollen
from a male plant from a regular pack of
seeds so you got a regular pack of seeds
you find a boy
you collect the pollen you are on the
path to breeding already
later use that pollen on select buds of
a different female plant
that is what you do that is how we start
making new crosses uh you may make
gold or you may make something that
isn't gold you may make something that
is mediocre and okay
or you may make a bunch of hemp seeds
that you end up wanting to throw away
uh likelihood of that happening if
you're using ire crosses
you're very likely going to have good
success because i've done good work
before you i've set you so up for
success by selecting good breeding
plants
i bred with them sent them along to you
they're good breeding stock
so yes basically you would get good free
seeds
now the question here is would those
seeds be stable
mirrors of each parent that kind of
depends on the breeding stock which you
start with
you started with if you start with pure
irie genetics
you may breed yourself into what we call
a bottleneck
most of what i breed has got a rise in
it it's got that king solomon in there
so if you breed uh if you bread the a
rise to strawberry starburst
you're going to get a lot of a rise
dominant stuff if you breed
strawberry starburst and blue raspberry
truffle there are two arise parents in
there you're going to get some arise
dominant traits
but if you take that the male and put it
on something that doesn't have the same
parent in there yes you are opening up
a lot of options for great breeding now
are you going to get
mirrors of the parents you will find
some phenotypes
that look just like the mommy plant
you'll find some phenotypes that look
just like the daddy plant then you will
find some phenotypes that are the
perfect 50 50 mix of both of those
plants
then you're going to find everything in
the middle of those also
depending on how large of a population
of seeds you can run
that's when you're going to start seeing
the variation you can make
quite a few seeds in very small plants
just by pollinating one branch or
growing just little tiny plants and
pollinating them
you can make plenty of seeds for
yourself to experiment with
so stable mirrors of each parent you're
going to see
phenotypes like the mom phenotypes like
the dad you're going to see 50 50 mixes
then you're going to see everything in
between something that's a little more
mommy but looks like daddy something's a
little bit more daddy that looks like
mommy
it depends on which traits in those
plants are dominant and recessive and
which
pop up more often now what you're also
going to see
is representations of the grandparents
so the mom plant also has a mom and dad
the dad plant also has a mom and dad
you're going to see
varieties of those popping up and if you
know what the grandparents are it's more
obvious you know what to look for
i see those things because i've got the
whole family tree going i've created
them i've bred them i worked with them
for so long that i can identify
grandparents and great grandparents in
the progeny so you will see
uh yes stable parent stable mirrors of
each parent but you're gonna see
random representations of grandparents
and everything in between
it's all about which plants you select
some things
give you wild phenotype variation and
some
are very uniform from the first cross if
you get wild variation
pick your favorite female and your
favorite male out of the population and
breed them
and then do it again and do it again and
you'll narrow down to the traits that
you're looking for
so um you may find stable mirrors of
each parent but you're also going to
find
uh outliers you're gonna find things
that look like mommy things that look
like daddy
like i keep saying that 50 50 and then
grandparents and then maybe
just maybe you will find some
grandparents
there in that mix all right ladies and
gentlemen boys and girls pimps and hoes
friends and foes
smokers growers clone cutters paul and
chuckers all you beautiful people out
there in cannabis world i want to thank
you again for listening to another
episode of the grow from your heart
podcast i feel like this episode went by
quite quickly
i answered three messages maybe i should
have tried to do four
no need to ramble and make extra time
out of a podcast it's all about quality
over quantity i'll be back in a couple
of days with fresh new content i'll try
to make that one longer
i just wrote down three messages and
went through them quickly i do apologize
uh like i said before if you want your
name corrected in the shout outs
send me a message on patreon or send me
an email grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
also if you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
maybe you learned something maybe you
laughed a couple of times ah maybe you
just want to send me a couple of bucks
for my time
all you have to do is visit
forward www.patreon.com grow from your
heart all of the information you need to
support the show is right there on the
screen
once again thank you to everybody who
supports the show it does mean a lot to
me
big salute to the irie army big shout
out to the 710 club
thank you guys thank each and every one
of you also make sure you support my
website
iregenetics.com all things ire genetics
all things grow from your heart
everything rosta jeff is right there at
iregenetics.com check it out visit the
website uh sign up for the newsletter
also don't forget about that grow help
tab if you've got some questions or have
some concerns for your grow
all you got to do is fill out that
little grow help tab that'll send it
right to my email i'll do my best to get
that on the show
and help you out if you've got any
questions corrections comments or
concerns once again my email address is
grow from your heart at hotmail.com
don't be shy
i would love to hear from you get your
questions on the show let me help you
out
ladies and gentlemen that is all i've
got for you for this episode you know
i'll be back in just a couple of days
with fresh new content
i want to give a shout out to my friend
known as f1p and until next time take a
fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
you