welcome back podcast world i'm your host
my friends call me rasta jeff
and this is episode 606 of the grow from
your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to do an
update on my silver thio sulfate recipe
i'm also going to read a few grow
questions but before we get there let's
do a few shout outs to a few members
of the 710 club of course the 710 club
are the folks who support us on patreon
at the 7 and 10 cent a month level or
higher so with no further ado let's
start off with the big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out
to my friend blackhawksfan let's send a
special thank you shout out to justice
smokin
let's follow that up with a thank you
shout out to alabama man let's send a
big thank you shout out to matt h and
trium up
let's send a special thank you to levity
love day let's send a big high five and
a thank you shout out to a long time
supporter how about a big shout out to
nomi by my guacamole
let's follow that one with a big shout
out to smokeyj1360
i want to send a special thank you shout
out to stone trout bomb
and last but certainly not least let's
send a big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out to
caribou heart genetics big thanks and
big shout out to everybody who continues
to support the show on patreon
if you're not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need to
support the show will be right there on
the screen
and of course i did include a link in
the show notes and in the video
description
to make it nice and easy for all of my
friends
all right big thanks to everybody who
supports us on patreon
i do have a couple of things to talk
about before we get to the email portion
of the show
the first question i wanted to answer is
why do i post
the premiere on youtube at midnight
that's right
this podcast comes out on mid at
midnight on sunday night into monday
morning
or at midnight on wednesday night into
thursday morning
and there's a good reason for that many
people have said hey i want to hang out
and watch the premiere on youtube
but i can't do it because it is simply
too late which i understand we have a
nice group that hangs out on the patreon
or on the
youtube premiere uh if you're not aware
when the video does premiere there is a
chat that goes along with the video
we hang out we chat live i hang out with
the people in the chat i take some dabs
and answer their questions in the chat
it's a nice little crew that hangs out
in there
uh many people want to hang out but
unfortunately it is just too late for
them
let me explain to you why i post the
video at midnight
this podcast started off as a as an
audio only format there was no video
when this podcast first started
i was putting the show up at midnight on
sunday night or into monday morning
so that when people got up for work on
monday they had something
to brighten their day many people have
to drive to work they don't feel like
driving many people have to make some
sort of a commute to work they don't
feel like making
a lot of people have to go to a job they
don't want to be at many people have a
job they enjoy but listening to the grow
from
your heart podcast on a monday morning
will always make your day better
so my goal was to have the podcast
available for everybody
monday morning if you're on the east
coast getting up real early it's already
there it came out at midnight so it's up
probably i guess that's two or three
o'clock on the east coast if you're
getting up for work at 4 or 4 35 in the
morning
the show was there waiting also 12
o'clock
gave me the opportunity to make sure
that the show posted successfully
back in the day there would be some
technical issues and i wouldn't get the
show posted properly
i'd have to run to my computer do some
adjustments fix some file names or file
numbers or whatever needed to be
corrected
in uh the website service then that
would get the show posted
now i'm more confident that the show
will work at midnight but i didn't feel
like changing the time for a couple of
reasons
i am available at midnight i'm available
to be there in the premiere
i also think that midnight was a fair
time to release the show so i apologize
if you're on the east coast or somewhere
else and you can't catch the premiere on
youtube but that was my intention
was to get the show up at midnight so
that everybody can watch it the next day
it'll be ready for you no matter what
time you get up
i've considered changing the time for
the premiere but it doesn't seem fair
to the people who have been joining me
since the beginning and also it doesn't
work perfectly for my schedule i don't
know that i can be available
before midnight on a sunday night i know
that sunday night
at midnight i'm available everybody else
is in bed everyone else is getting ready
for work
i've got the house to myself some time
to hang out i know that i can get there
for those premieres
so i apologize if you're unable to make
the premiere at midnight
and that is my reasoning behind doing it
at midnight
also a lot of people say they missed the
live show at midnight it's not really
live it's pre-recorded i'm recording
uh it's tuesday afternoon right now when
i'm recording this show will come out
wednesday at midnight thursday
morning-ish
a lot of people say they wish they could
join the live it is not a live show it
is just a live premiere
the video plays i'm sitting in front of
my computer at home
watching on youtube just like you but
i'm involved in the chat hopefully just
like you
that was a really long explanation as to
why i post the premieres at midnight but
that
is why there was a reason to it there
was a method to my madness
it started off as an audio show there
was never a video there was never a
premiere
the audio came out at midnight so
everybody could listen on their drive to
work on monday
uh then it became a video show and i
just never changed the time that's
simply what happened
i like being free at midnight i can hang
out in the chat also if there's a
technical issue
i can repair it at midnight i've got
time to myself i'm basically alone at
midnight most of the time
everybody else is sleeping i've got the
house to myself so midnight was perfect
for me i apologize if it doesn't work
for you
if that doesn't work for you maybe you
can catch me on my
monday night instagram live show every
monday
around 7 10 mountain time i go on
instagram live and i hang out
i listen to some music i chat with the
entire audience there are
usually about 50 to 75 people that come
into my instagram live video
and if you ask a question on the ig live
i do my best to answer it on the fly
i don't have any notes i don't have any
preparation i don't have any warning
it is kind of like stump the breeder
stump the grower or just hang out with
the dabber
however you want to do it i invite you
monday at 7
10 p.m mountain time that's colorado
time i don't know where you are i don't
know your time zone
you're to have to do some time zone
conversions but
monday at 7 00 pm mountain time i am on
instagram i use irie underscore genetics
as my instagram name
follow that account watch for me to pop
up mondays around
7 10. all right i feel like that took a
long time to get over that brief note
i've got one more thing i want to talk
about before we get into the emails
i got a message from my friend
crazyhandgroves and it simply says i
would just love a shout out sometime and
maybe a little bit of help to grow
my channel well here you go crazy hands
i've got a friend named crazyhandsgross
who is a great grower he's a great
person and i invite you
to check out his youtube channel it is
not as intense and in-depth as my
channel
it's a little more light-hearted it's a
little more fun it's a little laid back
but i do think that my friend crazy
hands grows
does deserve your subscription so go
check out my buddy crazy hands grows
crazy hand grows on youtube let me make
sure it's crazy hands or crazy hand
it's just crazy hand grows go give them
a subscribe on youtube
let them know rasta jeff sent you
support the community there's no need
to just watch my videos we can watch
everyone's go check out crazyhand grows
on youtube
shout out to my buddy crazyhand alright
where are we going from there
let's talk about the silver thio sulfate
update in a previous episode i talked
about making our own
feminized seed reversal spray i listened
back to it during the premiere
and i realized i may have skipped a
couple of minor details
everything i told you will work you'll
be successful with the advice and the
plan i gave you but here are a few more
things that may
set you up for better success with your
silver thiosulfate
um get the powdered silver thiosulfate
mix the
uh the sodium nitrate and the uh
thiosulfate which ones
are what are they called here the silver
nitrate and the sodium thiosulfate
get the powdered versions a couple of
people said they found the liquid
version on amazon or somewhere else
get the powdered version i don't like
the chunks i don't like the big parts
i like the fine powder so get those
powders
those powders should be white when you
open them up
if they are a dark color they are
starting to degrade i would not
recommend using the darker colored
powders if they've turned dark on you
if they've gotten brown or gray do not
use those they should be pure white
in my experience they've always been
pure white i find lower quality
less results when i use darker colored
materials
also if the water turns dark when you
mix the solution
something has gone wrong you've got some
contaminants and particulates in there
the water should stay clear when you
start mixing everything up it'll go dark
when you put the [ __ ] in right away
because you just added stuff to it but
once it all dissolves
it should be clear i highly recommend
that you use glass containers anytime
you're pouring the water into anything
doing any mixing
use a glass container and i said in the
episode that i use a butter knife
for stirring the butter knife is metal
nothing's going to stick to it
i'm not going to add anything i'm not
going to take anything out of my mix
it's non-porous
it doesn't have other [ __ ] on it so use
clean
glass containers clean them thoroughly
use clean glass containers and use
something metal or sterile for stirring
i use the butter knife simply because i
have it
it's sitting around it's right in the
kitchen i can clean it very well
nothing sticks to it it's non-porous use
glass and metal if possible
then i highly recommend using distilled
water i don't know if i went over that
in the last episode i highly recommend
distilled water
we're trying to mix up a solution here
so we can add certain things to our
plants we don't need other
elements other chemicals other variables
in our mix we're trying to make silver
thiosulfate
not silver thiosulfate plus whatever was
in the water you started with or
whatever was stuck to your previous
container
do everything super clean all right so
the best way to store your silver
thiosulfate here's something i did not
cover
it stores separately it stores better
separately
i said to mix the one powder into 500 ml
of water and another powder into 500
milliliters of water
if you're not going to use all of the
solution you're making it is
easily stored by not mixing those two
together it will last longer if you
don't mix parts a and b
if you have mixed parts a and b they
will still store just fine but you get a
longer
shelf life in my opinion if you do not
mix them
so keep parts a and part b separately
mix them when needed
then dilute and use as needed if you've
already mixed them that is just fine
that will store just as well but not for
as long in my opinion over time it will
begin to degrade
it won't be as potent it won't work as
well on your plants for reversal
so it stores better non-mixed
don't mix the two containers together or
if you can just keep the concentrates
stored together
that works well also every time you
start adding more together
it seems to degrade more quickly so if
you can keep the two jars separate
that's your best bet you can mix them
and have one jar that's a good bet
once you've gone to diluting it for
spray that is when you start degrading
the product more rapidly
store it in a cool dry dark place
i put mine and it's in the glass jars i
put those glass jars in a brown paper
bag
i label them so everybody knows what it
is and i stick that in the back of the
refrigerator
it's cold it's dark it's dry they're
sealed up nothing's going to get in
there
make sure nobody drinks your silver
thiosulfate
solution if you live with other people
especially children
do everything you need to do to protect
your household from
contaminating themselves by drinking
silver thiosulfate
i don't know what will happen to a
person if they drink that i don't want
to find out
i know that silver is not good for you
in large doses some people say to use
colloidal silver
i'm way off track here anyway make sure
you protect yourself and your family so
nobody consumes
your silver thiosulfate a mix or b mix
or
the combined solution light does degrade
the quality of your silver thiosulfate
solution if you've got it diluted
non-diluted mixed
however you've got it keep it dark
because the light will
cause the product to degrade it will not
be as good of a product
also wear gloves and long sleeves when
you're spraying this
also maybe put down some newspaper
underneath the plant when you're going
to spray if you've got a strong
non-diluted mix sometimes it will turn
uh white walls will turn a little bit
purple
your skin will get some weird dots on it
you can contaminate things with the
silver thiosulfate
so that is my update i wanted to come in
and say dark colored materials are bad
dark water is bad always use glass
containers
always use something non-porous and
clean for stirring
i recommend highly recommend using
distilled water
store them separately if possible if
you've already mixed it that's okay
it will still store the stuff is so
cheap that you can just make a bunch
more
don't even worry about it it's really
affordable get the products use the
distilled water
store it uh non-dilute if you can if
you've already mixed it together that's
fine
keep it in the fridge keep it nice and
cool and always do your best
to keep it dark and most importantly
label the [ __ ] out of it little kids
can't read
so even if you do write silver
thiosulfate don't drink this
the little kids may still get in the
fridge one day they may drink it
do everything you can to prevent that
that is your responsibility be a
responsible adult responsible grower
responsible parent responsible human
being let's not damage
injure make anybody sick while we're
attempting to grow good cannabis
medicine all right that is my update on
that part
now it is time to jump into the email
portion of
today's episode the first email on my
screen
comes from greenvet 88224.
shout out to greenvet88224 this one came
from patreon
and the question goes just like this it
says i thought of a question
i've read online that softened water is
unhealthy for our plants
cannabis plants included yes that is
absolutely true
it says is this true even when using
liquid nutrients
yes sir that is true it says i use ro
water
i buy the water but the water at my grow
site is softened
with a ppm reading of 185 is the issue
that the water is softened with salt
thanks i love the podcast from and they
signed it with their real name i don't
know if they want their real name right
on the air
you know who you are thank you for the
great message and of course thank you
for your service
and for the patreon support this one
goes and i said service because they
call themselves green vet
88224 i hope you're a veteran either way
you are a
ganja veteran or a military veteran
thank you for that service
um they're asking about uh water
softener a lot of people get water from
a well
or they've got to use a water softener
it says i use ro water but the water
at my grow site is softened with a ppm
of 185
um water softeners are water
is softened by softened i said that
really oddly but you're getting it
water is softened by using salts they
actually use sodium and potassium
to soften the water and at the same time
it removes
the calcium and the magnesium so that is
not good for our plants because
that sodium is basically like drinking
salt water
so it makes our plants think that they
are in a drought they're getting water
but they're not getting hydrated
they keep drinking that water they're
not hydrating themselves they're saying
hey i'm thirsty
i should be getting hydrated but they're
just sucking down salt water
and getting saltier and saltier and over
time that will dehydrate
and destroy our plants the sodium will
dry out the plants
it's a lot like being in the ocean and
dying of thirst there's no fresh water
there
you've got to clean up that water all
that salt water is not good for you your
body can't process it it's not hydrating
you in any way it's just salting you up
so
um yes uh the softened water is
unhealthy
for your plants it says that you've got
ro water i would stick with the ro water
is what i would do it's a little bit
more challenging it needs to be buffered
it's harder to keep the ph
but it is not salty as [ __ ] and it's not
going to kill your plants so
the question is is this true even when
using liquid nutrients absolutely
this is true even when using liquid
nutrients be careful with that softened
water
because i don't want you to dehydrate
your plants make them all
salty we're trying to grow fine grade
cannabis
not salty hemp trees all right thank you
for the great question
i'm gonna keep moving forward because i
feel like i've got a good flow
this one came from our friend what's the
name they want me to call them i'm just
gonna call you xavier what's up bro i
hope you're doing well
the message says my man rosta jeff happy
new year bro happy new year to you as
well
it goes on to say i hope the start of
your year is going excellent
my year has been great i'm really
excited to move on from 2020 and see
what we can do with 2021 we've got a
bunch of fresh new starts
and honestly i am excited about it all
right it says unfortunately i'm starting
my new year
with sick plants that's okay uh it says
i'm embarrassed to admit it
uh don't ever be embarrassed to admit
that you've got sick plants things go
wrong in nature things happen
especially in the garden especially when
you're learning admitting it is a huge
step
so you've admitted you got a problem now
we can work on solving it
it says my once beautiful morning dew
plants in seedlings
have started showing the ugliest
downward clawing and they are so
droopy so they are downward clawing and
they're super droopy
i can think of a lot of things that will
cause that we will narrow it down it
says even the veins of the leaves
look very pronounced and swollen all
right that's given me a couple more
ideas
i feel like i've over watered in this
case i'm not sure
i'm going to say you've over watered if
it is clawing it's a little bit too
watered if it's droopy and it's been
watered it's probably over watered
that thick vein you see is a little bit
of osmotic pressure possibly
there's just too much moisture that leaf
is trying to move that water around has
nowhere to go it can't let the air i
can't let the water out through the leaf
that quickly
the plants are struggling it said i feed
once a week every friday
i don't feed as much because it seems
like this peat based soil i use takes
forever to
dry um well you just got to adjust
to the drying time of that plant as it
gets bigger your plants are small now
i've seen the pictures
as they get bigger that dry time will
decrease they'll dry out more quickly
because the plants will be eating more
the roots will be larger
there'll be more processing happening in
your rhizosphere
so your watering time will increase but
now i am certain of it that you're over
watering
and watering too frequently you've got
to let them dry out a little bit more
than what you've been doing
before you water the next time don't be
so eager uh don't think they've got to
be thirsty they got to be hungry
because they'll let you know when
they're hungry and thirsty they're
letting you know that you've been over
watering them by giving you the claw the
thick vein
and the droopiness uh it says my plants
are all between five and nine inches
tall
my two plants are in two of my plants
are in one gallon pots and the others
are in six
gallon or six solo cups so yeah i'm
going to assume that you're over
watering these small plants because
they're brand new and you're eager to
get nutrients to them you just want to
feed them and get them bigger
i'm going to assume that you're over
watering it also says i grow under led
purple lighting my last feed was at 600
ppms i used advanced nutrients and
recharge
that all sounds like it's going to work
my humidity is between 50 and 60 percent
uh that's good for now it may need to go
down soon it says my daytime temp is
about 78 to 81 that's gonna work for you
my nighttime temp is 68 to 73.
uh that's not too bad as long as you're
not getting too much of a swing
in your nighttime to daytime temperature
i said how do i get my plants
back to normal okay i looked at some
pictures here there were pictures
included in this
the pots you are using are simply too
large you've got small plants you've
said that
some are in solo cups the plants that
are in
the one gallon pots those should still
be in solo
cups those plants weren't ready to be
transplanted you've got a little tiny
root zone and a big
container and you're just watering that
whole container and that little root
zone is saying that's a lot of water i
didn't need all that
so your first thing is that the pots are
too big the second thing is that they
are
too wet when i looked at your photos i
didn't see anything in there for
drainage i don't see enough perlite i
don't see any persolite
uh but i do see some weird rocks on the
top of the plants i asked about the
rocks
uh you said you were using those to
support the plant i would get rid of
those rocks immediately
i don't know what you're when you're
watering those rocks have minerals
they're dirty they got salts on them
you're watering something from those
rocks into your plant
that's highly unnecessary i would pull
the rocks out and i would put a stick in
there to support that plant that will
help you out
also i can tell by looking at the
pictures and i will include a photo here
uh for the audience that is watching
visually i'll drop in a photo right
about now so you guys can see what i'm
talking about
but uh those plants have been overfed
they are too small for the amount of
nutrients you're trying to give them
so they need some time to dry and they
don't need as much food i would let them
dry
give them more time between feedings
more dry time between feedings
i would reduce the amount of nitrogen
and i would definitely remove
those rocks from the grow those are a
few things that should get your plants
back on track and i was fortunate enough
to be back in contact with our friend
xavier
he followed our advice and guess what
you guys his plants
look amazing now he's no longer
embarrassed he's got a healthy crop back
on track
to get 2021 under control so thank you
for the great message xavier i'm glad i
was able to help you out
i hope i'm able to drop that photo here
in the video uh you guys comment let me
know what you think of the photo
and if you've got any questions about
your grow please include some photos
because that really did help me out all
right xavier i hope we answered your
question
i'm excited to see your garden back in
track i'm gonna clear my throat and
we're gonna move on to the next
message
all right this next message came from
the website there is a help tab
on the website simply go to
iriegenetics.com
you will find the grow help tab on that
tab i do ask one two three
four five six seven eight nine ten
eleven twelve thirteen fourteen fifteen
sixty
i ask you sixteen basic questions before
you're able to ask ask the real question
i wanna know what strain you're growing
where you're growing it what kind of
lights you're using and then i ask a few
details of your grow
then i let you ask me a grow question
here is the grow help tab they came from
our friend
do they want their name used yes this is
from robert
and it says they're growing wedding cake
they're growing it indoors they're
growing under an hps light they're in
flower they're in week seven
they're growing in cocoa the last feed
was water
enzymes and shine sounds like a great
feed the ph was 6.0 i would raise that
up just a little bit
the ppm or ec was 300 the daytime temp
is 76
night time temp is 64. i would
uh warm it up just a little bit it says
nighttime
relative humidity is 55 on our daytime
relative humidity is 55 nighttime
humidity 55
it says the problem is my air
conditioner took a crap
oh that is always a bummer when the air
conditioner takes a crap you got to
scramble and get a new one
it says i cannot get it fixed for a few
days due to the holiday
and coved seasons i understand that
completely
it says my question is is 75 to 77
degrees daytime temps and 65 degree
nighttime temps and humidity
and humidity around 55 gonna hurt the
grow if those conditions stay for five
to seven days then back to normal
which would be around 73 at night and 65
or 73 during the day
and 65 at night with 40 relative
humidity
um i don't think your plants are going
to see any problem
with 75 to 77 degrees i think they're
going to enjoy that
i think you could run that temperature
all the time and they would be just fine
i like 77 degrees in the grow room 77 is
really nice
the plants are comfortable i am
comfortable uh however in a commercial
environment i've seen that they get up
to about 81 and they seem to perform
a little more quickly sometimes so i
don't think you're going to see
any problems with the temperature excuse
me for the throat clearing
i do think that maybe your humidity may
be a little bit high
so while you are down with your air
conditioner and you're getting the
higher humidity
maybe consider adding another fan or two
maybe consider
watering just a little bit less or less
frequently
just to keep that uh humidity down a
little bit if you don't put as much
water in the room
that much water cannot get into the air
so that is something i would consider
maybe water just a little bit less but
overall
i see zero problems rising from this
couple of
degrees difference i actually think that
they may benefit from it pay attention
to them
and see if you like this lower
temperature compared to your usual
higher temperature this may be something
you adjust to and you can save a few
bucks
or they may like the higher temperature
not the lower temperature i apologize
that's rarely the case
um they may want to be a little bit
warmer like you're getting them so pay
attention
and see how they react to the higher
temps it'll only be a couple of days
maybe a week or so but you may notice
they grow a little bit more quickly
you get more vigor out of them with that
warmer temperature although you are
fighting that higher humidity
i'm not sure how they're going to do
with that but it won't be too long
you're not going to get bud mold or
anything like that that at that point in
flower with that much humidity
any higher humidity i would be concerned
but pay attention don't let it get too
high
all right i feel like i've answered that
question more than thoroughly let's send
a big thank you shout out to our friend
robert for the great message
if you've got any more questions i would
love to hear from you
all right let's move into the last
message on today's episode this one
actually came from youtube
and it came from our friend fresh baked
and it says
hey ross to jeff i thought let's see i
thought age had to do a little bit with
pre-flowers
from my experience topping early has
seemed to make them flower
later have you seen this as well i
haven't thought about
root bound being the trigger and it
makes sense i usually hesitate to up pot
from one gallons until i see them all
right
so the question here is about pre-flower
our friend is saying that
they topped their plants and they are
wondering if topping the plants
will create pre-flower will cause
pre-flower to appear
later in the cycle i've got a good
answer for this
the short answer is yes topping your
plants
can encourage your plants to pre-flower
a little bit later
and let me explain why cannabis plants
are apical dominant meaning they want
one top
bud they want one piece to grow up to
the top
that one bud its goal is to reach up to
the top and get pollinated usually male
plants grow taller than the females
the boys will be up above the girls the
male plant will be just a few inches
maybe a foot higher depending on your
environment and genetics
when pollen starts to fall it goes down
so that female plant that's right below
it right next to it that top apical
dominant bud
is going to get pollinated so it's got
one bud always competing to be up at the
top it wants to make that one
big giant it's a big sex organ it's
looking to get that one big sex organ
pollinated it's like here i am
coat me and pollen so i can make seeds
and i can continue my
future i can continue for more
generations so
that plant wants to naturally make an
apical dominant top
when you cut out that top what happens
the hormones that are in that top are no
longer there
and the plant goes hey i'm not ready for
puberty you just took off my parts that
were growing that were older
they were ready to go into puberty i'm
gonna be a little teenager again
and i don't have any of my pre-flower my
maturity my puberty parts
so you just remove the apical dominant
top from that plant
you took out a lot of auxins and
cytokinins the hormones have been moved
around in that plant
all of those branches that are down
lower that are left they go hey
the president is gone there's a chance
for me to be the president now
and they all start trying to work their
way up to the top they want to be the
new king they want to be the new
president they want to be the new leader
they don't know that there are seven
eight other branches
nine other branches trying to get up
there to the top to be the leader as
well so they all start taking off
those new branches don't have the
hormones that that old branch had you
cut those developed those built up
hormones
right out of the plant now the plant
thinks it's a youngster again
and it's going i'm not ready for puberty
it's going to grow a little bit longer
until it can move those hormones around
once the oxens have developed and moved
around again it'll say
oh now it might be time to start
spitting out some pre-flowers
now is the time to flower also you did
mention that being root bound
will help with that yes if you don't
transplant them soon enough they will
still show
their pre-flower but if you have them in
ideal conditions with a big enough pot
they're not getting root bound
you top them they won't show pre-flower
as early because
you have removed those hormones from
that apical dominant top
and now all your lowers are competing to
be the new top and those hormones
simply are not there they're in
competition they're young
they're [ __ ] rampant they're trying
to get up there and be the new lion king
the new president the new head of the
table the new top blood
so that is exactly why in my opinion
from my experience
uh you don't see pre-flower as early
when you top
your plants all right that was a great
question thank you for that one
if you've got any more questions
corrections comments or concerns i'd
love to hear from you
my email address is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com of course the best way to
get your show
your questions on the show is through
patreon check out patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart
of course if you've got any uh if you
want to know anything about irie
genetics rosta jeff the grow from your
heart podcast i do recommend you check
out
iriegenetics.com all things roster jeff
all things irie genetics all things grow
from your heart will be right there
at iregenetics.com
all right i think that is all i've got
for you for this episode i want to thank
you guys again for hanging out
i had a good time on this show i felt
like i had a good flow i hope you guys
are staying warm i hope you're staying
safe i'll be back in just a couple of
days with fresh new content
i want to give a big shout out to my
buddy mr bagseed and until next time
take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you