[Music]
all right here we go welcome back
podcast world
i'm your host my friends call me rasta
jeff and this is episode 607
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to read a couple
of patreon messages
before we get there let's do a few shout
outs to a few members of the 710 club
of course the 710 club are the folks who
support us on patreon
at the 7 and 10 cent a month level or
higher so with no further ado let's
start off with the big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out
to my friend billy podunk let's send a
big thank you shout out to rosta green
thumb
i want to send a special thank you shout
out to dank groves let's send a big
thank you shout out to trollin
i want to send a big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out to my
friend mind's eye open
let's send a big thank you shout out to
dear dabi i want to send a special thank
you to stephen f
let's send a big girl from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to a
longtime supporter let's send a thank
you to my friend gramps memel
let's send a big thank you shout out to
kojaks i want to send a special thank
you shout out to don't tread on me420
and last but certainly not least let's
send a big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out to my good friend
jesse groves
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who supports the show on
patreon
if you're not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need will be
right there on the screen and of course
i did include a link in the show notes
and in the video description
to make it super easy for all of my
friends
once again you guys really thank you for
all of the patreon support
i also want to thank everybody who
supported my friend
crazy hand grows on the last episode i
asked you guys to go follow and visit my
friend crazyhandgrowsonyoutube
crazyhand sent me a great message saying
how excited he was about his new
followers
so i want to send a thank you from crazy
and myself thank you guys for supporting
other members of the community
in this episode i'm going to ask you to
follow another friend of mine
i highly recommend you check out
reclining with ryvan ryven waters has a
new channel
he is newly disabled he's adjusting to
his new life and it is very interesting
and entertaining to watch
so i invite you guys to check out riven
reclining with rivan on youtube
give him a follow support a few more
members of the community
all right what else are we going to talk
about i got a lot of comments and
messages lately
about how many times am i going to
adjust this microphone during the
podcast
the answer is as many as i need to i've
got notes on a computer
i've got notes on paper i've got
headphones on i can hear exactly what's
going on in the show
i'm doing microphone adjustments based
on where i'm looking i'm getting the mic
out of my field of view
but as i change my position of my face i
want to move the mic as close to my
mouth as i can to keep it sounding good
trying to be a professional broadcaster
that's why i got the fancy mic arm so i
can keep this bad dog right on my face
so how many times am i going to move
this mic as many as i [ __ ] need to
i'm going to make the show sound good if
it drives you crazy i do apologize but
i'm trying to keep it
uh when i read the computer i need it
kind of here when i read the paper i got
to move it lower to get it out of the
out of the view of the paper so that's
what's happening i'm not completely
crazy just a little bit like i said in a
previous episode my mother had me tested
we know i'm not crazy anyway that's why
i'm adjusting the mic so
uh erratically there is a method to my
mic
adjusting madness sorry if it drives you
crazy trying to get it out of my field
of view
also try to keep myself i can hear
exactly how much of me is coming through
these headphones i notice when i talk
right here it sounds real good you get
it about here it kind of fade off a
little bit so
that's why i'm playing with the mic so
much you can tell the mic arm needs a
little
i need some viagra or some tightening
it's getting a little droopy today
this show is not brought to you by
bluetooth so we won't go there
let me get myself back on track what are
we going to do with this part of the
show this is where we are going to work
into the
emails and patreon messages part of the
show
the first question on today's episode
came from the grow
help tab on the irie genetics website
that's right if you go to my website
iriegenetics.com you will find a grow
help
tab on that tab if you click there you
will be asked i think we determined
there are 16 preliminary questions we
ask your name
what name to use on the podcast if i
give you a shout out we ask what strain
you're growing
then we ask a few details about the grow
then we allow you to ask a question
about your grow so this first question
came from the grow help tab
on iregenetics.com and it goes a lot
like this this one they want the name on
the podcast to be
uh they want to be called jonathan they
are growing leonardo the blueberry
cookies s1 from ire genetics they're
growing indoors
under a high pressure sodium bulb they
are in flower they're in week three of
flour they're growing in cocoa
they're using here's the list of
nutrients in their last feed
they are using gh flora series they used
armor sci
calmag micro grow bloom
cool bloom floralicious plus diamond
next
diamond nectar and black strap molasses
that is a lot of nutrients
um that's a lot of nutrients in one feed
it says the ph of the last feeding was
6.0
i would bring that up to at least six
two maybe six
four uh somewhere in that range would be
uh better for your plants to absorb and
uptake some of those nutrients
the ppm or the ec of the last feeding
was 600 that's
uh with all those nutrients in there
that may be acceptable there was a lot
of [ __ ] in there though but you didn't
use a lot of it it looks like
the daytime temperature is 75 to 78
which is acceptable nighttime temps
70-72 here is where we get to the
question or
problem part of this message it says hey
ross to jeff i just want to thank you
again for all that you do for the
community
and myself you are very welcome uh thank
you for thanking me that is like
recharge
uh you're giving me a little nutrients
here to keep me going so thank you for
that
it says last year i grew your orange
gasm which were some really great
genetics thank you that is one of my
favorite plants
it's really fun to grow i recommend that
for everybody growers of all skill level
all environments the orange gasm is a
champ i'm glad it went well for you
it said the smell was so sweet and the
plant structure was phenomenal
topped and scrogged that is a resilient
plant you can top it you can scrog it
you can let it grow with the giant glory
cola it does a lot of great [ __ ]
it goes on to say i'm now growing your
leonardo
to hopefully get some more color in the
garden i'm in week three of flour and
the tips of my leaves are slightly
discolored and burnt
i feed with every watering i feed one
gallon at 600 ppms every other day with
runoff so i was wondering if i should do
one of these three options
so the problem is that the leaf tips are
getting a little bit burnt i call that
getting your nails done
if you picture the leave as a giant hand
the fingernail tips they're getting a
little bit done they're just starting to
get their nails painted
that is a sign that you may be feeding
just a little bit too much
or is that the sign that you're pushing
them just enough that's the decision you
need to make does it look problematic
or is it like um like if you look at an
athlete and they're like sweating and
they look like they need a [ __ ] break
do your plants look like they're getting
worked out and they're right at the
point of like oh
feel the burn or are they like oh [ __ ]
feel the burn which one is it
that's the decision you need to make
there uh so they're getting their nails
done
one thing i did notice is that's a lot
of nutrients and you are feeding
uh you're in week three of flour and
you're feeding the grow and bloom
i don't know enough about the gh flora
series to know
if the grow and bloom are both required
but i wouldn't assume with most
lines that by week 3 they would ask you
to use the grow bottle and the bloom
bottle
you may be doubling up on some things
you may be getting more nitrogen than
necessary
but big disclaimer i don't know this
nutrient line i don't know their
nutrient calculator so if it says to use
the grow along with the bloom do that
but by now in most lines i would have
abandoned that grow nutrient we don't
need this much nitrogen
you may be doubling up on phosphorus and
potassium and getting
a whole lot of nitrogen which you don't
need so that may be one thing you could
adjust
just from reading your list of nutrients
i don't know that i would
feed them that many things all at once
if you're feeding multiple times a week
i would go with your base nutrients your
calmag maybe the armor sci
every time and then i would switch up
like the cool bloom and the floralicious
i would do those on different days uh
but that that's what i would do
if it's working for you bro you keep
doing your thing i'm just saying that's
a lot of [ __ ] to feed it all at one time
even though your ppms are only 600
it still seems like a lot of things to
go in there in one day i'm gonna get on
to the
uh three options which you have
presented which uh you think may help
cure
your uh nails from getting too burnt it
says i was wondering if i should do one
of these three options should i keep
feeding as i've been doing
if the plants don't look like they are
super distressed if they're just getting
their nails done
you're pushing them right to the limit
you're going to get a huge
fat harvest super fat chunky buds don't
push them too hard
keep doing what you're doing and as long
as you flush properly and cure and dry
them properly they should taste good at
the end
the other option is feed with have
strength ppms once or twice to do a
light flush of the cocoa
uh you're in coco so um just one quick
flush would be enough and i would
probably do
i wouldn't even do half strength ppms
that's not even a flush that's just a
weak feed i would just do water one time
until you get like 20 to that 20 runoff
is fair
which i don't know that that's necessary
unless they're really getting cooked
then it says feed only once or twice uh
feed only water once or twice to flush
the cocoa
yeah if you're gonna do a flush don't
put any nutrients in there
that's just uh i don't know it's what's
the word they're counter productive
you're trying to flush and you're giving
it nutrients at the same time so that's
not gonna help you
i would go with either option number one
or option number two keep feeding as you
have been
maybe no excuse me for that i'm not even
going to edit that
maybe spread out the feedings give like
i said give one bottle on one day and
the other bottle the next day
but with your ppms being at 600 of your
ec uh ppm zcc being at 600 i think
you're going to be okay with what you're
doing
so just pay attention to those leaves
maybe reduce the feeding just a little
bit
maybe separate some of the bottles on
different days but as long as the plants
aren't looking pissed off
keep doing what you're doing if they do
get too pissed off reduce the feeding a
little bit
if they stop eating if they look like
they've stalled out on you that's when i
would give them
one flush and i would use i think the
armor don't use the armor sci
i don't see an enzyme product in here i
would flush one time with an enzymatic
product
and then i would continue to feed
instead of 600 ppms maybe hit 500 and
see how they respond to that but i think
your plants are going to be okay
unless this burn is getting really
really ridiculous i would continue
to do what you're doing said also if you
can bring sean or one of the organic
guys back on the show again
uh from the beginning uh we would love
we would be awesome we'd love to
eventually give organic growing a try
i would love to get some of the more
organic guys on the show
uh also make sure you check out
embracing organics if you're not already
watching the embracing organics podcast
we they talk a lot about organic growing
embracing organics is a cannabis growing
podcast
it is live on youtube uh it is 7 p.m
mountain time on thursday that's when we
go live however the show is left up it
goes
up to youtube and stays up forever so
you can go to youtube right now
and search for embracing organics i am
not the host of the show i'm a guest a
panel member on the show
we bring on a lot of other people we
talk about organic growing we talk about
all types of growing
but you can learn a lot about organics
on the embracing organics podcast
and once we get some things settled in
with the pandemic and all this stuff i
do plan on adding another microphone to
the table
and we will get some folks to come talk
about organics we may just have to get
some people to zoom in if you're an
organic growing expert and you'd like to
be on a podcast send me an email
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com all right we're going to
keep moving hey bro thank you for the
great message
uh and let me know how this goes give me
an update in a week or so and let me
know what your plans look like let me
know what you chose to do
maybe include a picture send me an email
with a photo of these plants and we can
make better decisions on what to do
i'm sure you saw the last episode i
actually dropped a photo in to show you
the plant i was talking about
i'm trying to improve the show and that
is a great way to do it so send me some
pics
i'll put them in the podcast uh where do
we go from there i've got another great
message
this one says yo rasta jeff i'm really
enjoying the show even more so
since you switched to being on camera
instead of just having a static screen
podcast format thank you we've gone
through a couple of different iterations
of the video show now
we had the flag behind us in the old
crusty white wall
then we moved to the office where we had
the sneakers behind us now we got a new
painted set with a fresh new backdrop
and some brand new lighting
so thank you for noticing that i'm
making some improvement putting some
effort into the show
spending that patreon money here on the
podcast thank you for noticing that and
i'm glad it keeps your attention a
little bit better
it says i have a question about selfing
and of course selfing is when we
uh take a plant and we cut a clone of
that same plant we reverse one with a
silver thiosulfate solution
that plant will then create female
pollen you put that female pollen
on a clone of the same plant to make
seeds that are s-ones
that is selfing we're going to talk more
about that in the message but it says
i have a question about selfing if you
take a male and a female of the same
strain and you make seeds you get an f2
with a lot of variation right
that is accurate a male and a female of
the same strain you make seeds
you get an f2 with a lot of variation
that is accurate
whereas f or as s1 seeds this is where
we're gonna have some
some different conversation whereas with
s1 seeds
should show a lot less variation because
all of the genes are from the same plant
what if you grew out two females of the
same strain
from seed reverse one and breed them
will you get the same type of variation
as an f2 and would it be called an s2 or
would you just call them feminized
f2s thanks for all of the knowledge
thank you from spankynuts420 this is a
great question there are some things to
uh
to think about here so let's kind of
outline what he's trying to do here what
our listener is trying to ask about they
want to grow a pack of seeds
in that pack of seeds there are going to
be multiple phenotypes they want to find
a phenotype number one that's a female
and phenotype number two that's a female
they've got two different phenotypes so
that's a good start for this
uh what if we took two females at the
same strain reverse one of them
and then put the pollen on the other one
um
that is sort of an s2 now that i'm going
to call that an
r1 um that might be like an r1
inbred line i'm gonna call i don't know
what the official name for that is
because we don't do that nobody really
does that sort of stuff i've done
something like that and never knew what
to call it
uh it's not a self because in my
in my vocabulary the way that i see the
word self is it's got to be on
the same plan it's got to be a clone of
the same thing
so this is going to be an r1 but it's
going to be
i'm just going to pick a strain i'm
going to call it spanky's nuts 420 og
that's the strain we're working with
this is going to be a spanky's
nuts 420 og r1
it's a reversal because we used
technically two different plants they
may be the same
the same strain the same genetics the
same all that but they are different
phenotypes so we're going to see uh
different representations in the progeny
you're going to see a little bit of this
phenotype
and a little bit of this phenotype even
though they're the same strain
they are different plants it's like uh
it's like taking two different plants
they have the same parents so you're not
gonna see as much uh weird grandparent
expression you may see some crazy crazy
uh recessive great-grandparent genes
expressed in that
but um i don't think we would call that
an s2 i think that would be an r1 or
some sort of an r1 inbred project is
what that would be i would just call it
an r1
and explain to people i wouldn't label
it like uh
spanky's nuts 420 number one cross two
spanky's nuts 420 number two
uh and then just label it as an r1
because that is a reversal
i think that's the way we would do that
let me make sure i covered this question
let's see best ones would show a lot
less variation what if you grab two
females of the same strain reverse one
and breathe them well you get the same
type of variation all right
so um i think not as much variation as
the f2
because there aren't as many options um
with the f2 you know what the mom and
the dad are gonna look like you're gonna
see mom and dad options
and the grandparents definitely give you
more options we don't have uh basically
different grandparents here
so that recessive trait that pops up
from the grandparents
it's going to be very uh very similar
but you may see great grandparents is
what i think i was alluding to earlier
you may see weird great-grandparents
traits come out of that that you have no
idea
what you're expecting there uh maybe
great great-grandparents may be
expressed in that when you go
playing with genetics like this this is
when we open up weird stuff that's why
the f2 shows a lot of variation the f1
comes with a lot of vigor
the f2 we really start opening up
variation uh
f3 hopefully you've done selection to
start narrowing that down
when we're working with fems we don't
have as many uh many
pieces to our puzzles many colors to our
palette as many ingredients to our
recipe
so you shouldn't open as many things but
that's when you start seeing background
things pop up that you never expected
this is
a fun project it's something that you
should do if you haven't already done
this
uh do it bro and tell me how this goes i
would love to do it for you but i
honestly don't have time
or space so i think you're gonna see
variation but it's going to be
less variation and you may see great
grandparents at first i said
grandparents but then i had to
had to draw the family tree in my head
and talk it out you may see great
grandparents
uh come through in some of the rare
phenotypes but it's technically not an
s one because you're using different
plants so that is a
an r1 i hope i'm saying that correctly
it's an r1 it's a reversal
and you'll see uh number one and number
two in there but it's
gonna be you're gonna get a lot of them
that look 50 50 of number one and number
two
a lot that look like number one a lot
look like number two but then you're
gonna see
some outliers that look like whatever
that strain was crossed with you're
gonna get some weirdness there then you
may get some real mutants out of it too
because you're playing with feminized
genetics uh that's a really fun
conversation that i would like to open
up with other people i wish this was a
live chat i had some more people on
there
if you've got input feedback questions
corrections comments concerns on this
topic i would love to hear it
again my email address is grow
fromyourheart hotmail.com
all right i've got one more email this
one could get kinda long because there
are a lot of details to this one
this one is a question about tds ec
and ppms what are all of those things
what does all of that stuff mean
i tried to make some notes so that we
can keep this one concise
the question came from our friend
sequoia organic farms it says
hey ross to jeff i'm a new supporter
from colorado check us out we are
sequoia organic farms
they spell sequoia differently than you
probably assume it's s
e q u o y a h
and then organic farms the traditional
way it's all one word
it goes on to say i can't tell you
enough how much your knowledge means to
everyone thank you bro i appreciate that
says thank you for all of the positive
energy and keep killing the game
ah thank you bro just being me trying to
do what i do trying to get these seeds
and the message out to the people that
need it
thank you for noticing the hard work it
says it's people like you
who inspire people like me to tell you
the truth bro it's people like you
who inspire people like me so keep it
going we'll keep it going back and forth
it says i do have a quick question for
you that i hope you can
uh talk about on the podcast i do
apologize if you've already covered this
in a previous episode
uh that is okay if i already have with
600 episodes i realize people
probably don't go back and listen to all
if they've got a question it's probably
easier just to redo it and since we're
on this brand new
awesome video format why not have a new
episode on the old topics on the video
format anyway so if you already asked it
or if it's already been covered that's
okay i'm gonna re-answer it for you
it says can you dive into the specifics
of ppm
tds and ec what are they
and what are their relations all right
there are multiple parts to this
question
i'm not gonna answer all three i'll read
them quickly for you though it says i'm
an organic no-till
living soil grower i would love some
tips on how to specifically water
peat-based super soils i seem to be an
over waterer
my advice to that you already know that
you're an over waterer
wait another day bro wait until that
plant looks like it's thirsty it will
let you know it will tell you
then water it that's easy enough um then
it says
any organic references to increase
yields would be awesome maybe a
whole organic episode i did invite
somebody to come on and do some organics
and once again i'll recommend the
embracing organic show
um then i'm not your organic expert but
for
organic i think i can recommend budswell
i think budswell is an organic product
and i think that will help with your
bloom booster situation check out bud
swell the liquid
make sure that's organic before you use
it do not take my word for it i'm giving
you a disclaimer right now
not a hundred percent sure but that's
what i would recommend if it is organic
do that
now let's get into the part of the
question you actually wanted some help
with that i'm able to provide help for
let's talk about what are tds ppms and
ec what do all these letters mean
tds is actually what we are measuring
when we measure
ppm and ec tds simply stands for
total dissolved solids and there are a
couple of ways to measure
the total dissolved solids in a solution
so what we're going to do we're going to
have a solution
up a container of water and nutrients
that is our solution in this case
we want to know how much nutrient is in
our water the water if you've got ro
water
it should be zero ppms uh zero ec
so there are zero total dissolved solids
in there now we're gonna add our
nutrients into it
and there are several reasons why it's
good to know what your ec
or your ppms are first of all if you're
burning the plants like our one listener
may be doing
we can see what the tds is the ppms and
we can
lower that or if we're getting a perfect
crop we can see that it was perfect we
can write that down and we can repeat
that
or if the plants need new more nutrients
we can write down that 600 was a little
low
let's give it 700 next time so it's a
good it's a good gauge a good guide a
good reference point
and it can teach you a lot about your
plants and what they're uptaking
so let's talk a little bit more
specifically about what these things are
tds is the
total amount of dissolved solids in your
bucket with your water how many
dissolved solids are in there the units
of measure the common units of measure
of those total dissolved solids are
ppms and ec ppm stands for
particles per million so we've got this
many
particles of nutrients per million
particles of water in that solution
tds or no i'm sorry ec stands for
electrical
conductivity let's talk about electrical
conductivity
electrical conductivity is and i got
this from the internet shout out to
google
it says electrical conductivity is the
measurement of the ability
of something to conduct electricity i
know that sounds very basic it sounds
kind of redundant
electrical conductivity is the ability
to conduct electricity
the salts that we use for fertilizers do
have the ability to conduct electricity
uh all those salts you add in there are
conductive to electricity is what i'm
saying
the ec measures how much electricity
they are able to conduct it's not like
you can plug in a light with them that's
very small amounts of
electrical conductivity but that is what
the ec stands for
ppm excuse me with that let me fix my
voice and try that again
i'm not a 12 year old i promise ppm
meters particles
per million meters actually measure nec
and do a mathematical equation and
convert that to ppm
so in my opinion ec is much more
reliable
than particles per million it's more
used in science it's more used in large
scale application
you'll more likely see ec as a unit of
measurement
over particles per million so also there
are different conversion
rates just like the imperial and metric
system
there are different conversions so in
different regions different countries
different continents
uh particles per million will be
converted differently to ec
in their conversion calculator they use
a different number to do the conversion
unless you know where your nutrient
company is basing their conversion on
your ppm recommendations may be way off
so particles per million are telling us
how much stuff is in that water
electrical conductivity is basically
telling us how much stuff is in that
water but more specifically
and that makes it easier to remember to
notate
how much nutrient is in our solution you
may be mixing in five or six
different uh products into your solution
you can always
take your ec meter start off and see
what your starting water ec is if you're
using ro it's going to be zero if you're
using tap water you're going to have a
few
uh ppms or a little bit of ec in that
water
now add your nitrogen or your base
nutrient stir your ec meter around in
there
and you can see what your particles per
million or your electrical conductivity
level of
your base nutrient is a lot of people
like to measure the ec
and particles per million of their cal
mag a lot of plants are very critical on
how much calmac they
use this is a really good way to dial in
exactly
how much calmag or calcium or magnesium
or whatever
individual bottled nutrient you've got
you can definitely measure out exactly
how much of that is going
into your solution by measuring your ec
and your ppm
while you are adding that product to the
reservoir you can actually have the
meter
in the reservoir pour it in there see
what it is before you pour it and see
what it is after you pour it now you
know
i've got 600 ppms of nitrogen now you
can pour in your calmag if your goal is
particles per million of the calmag
bottle pour that in until you see 800
ppms of stuff or
whatever number you want on your ec
screen you can do exactly how much of
each
nutrient bottle you want at that rate so
i highly recommend using ec
i write down the ec of my solution
before it goes into the plants i write
down the ec of my solution that runs out
of my plants i also write down the ph
of that solution before i feed it and
what comes out of the bottom of the
plants
i also write down every single nutrient
that went into that nutrient solution
if i put 100 ml of one thing 80 mls of
another
20 mls of another and then a bunch of
grams of recharge
i write that all down on a spreadsheet
then i write down my ec
in my ppm's in my phn and then i write
down
the ec out and the ph out so i've got a
good documentation of what happened
then if something goes wrong i can look
back in my feed chart
i can look at the plants i can look at
my paperwork and that helps me
kind of decide kind of determine kind of
decipher what may have gone wrong
through a process of elimination
maybe we sprayed something that's
written down also maybe we defoliated
too heavily that's written down also but
i take a lot of notes
uh i use the ec as a reference guide i
always write down my ec
of my solution in and out then we can
use that data like i said earlier
to either correct an issue or to repeat
success
if you've got a problem the numbers will
tell you maybe where your problem
happened you can see
the ph coming out was a little funky the
ec coming out was a little funky it was
too high too low
maybe one of them went one way one with
the other that'll tell you what's
happening
with your runoff the runoff reports or a
whole nother podcast i think i may have
done that if not i need to do an updated
version
uh even if i did i should probably do an
updated version but you can use that
data
to either correct or adjust or mimic
your previous results and when you're
working with standard operating
procedures in a large scale environment
repeatable results are what we're after
if we nail this crop
we definitely want to nail that crop
next time get a bonus uh reach potency
goals reach harvest weights everybody
gets a bonus
everybody's after a bonus check all the
patients get a better product
that's what happens when we take good
notes so it's my recommendation to stick
with
electrical conductivity as it is a
little bit more accurate
uh when you're measuring each nutrient
you can do your ppms that way if you
want to it is easier to tell
the numbers are uh more they're uh
you're using like 600
700 800 when you're using the ec it's
going to be like 0.8.9
so it's easier to use the other scale as
you're measuring each thing individually
overall go with the ec find your zone
find what your plants love
stick with that and repeat it all right
ladies and gentlemen boys and girls
pimps and hoes friends and foes smokers
growers clone cutters paul and chuckers
all you beautiful growers and smokers
out there i want to thank each and every
one of you for joining me for another
episode
if you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
maybe you had a good time maybe you
learned something i'd like you to
support the show financially you can do
so by visiting
forward www.patreon.com grow from your
heart all of the information you need
will be right there on the screen
once again big shout out to everybody
who has continued to support the show on
patreon i truly appreciate
all of your support again if you've got
any questions corrections comments or
concerns my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com you know i would love to
hear from you
also all things ire genetics all things
rosta jeff
all things grow from your heart podcast
are listed on my website
iregenetics.com i invite you and
encourage you to check out the website
uh the merchandise is on the website
seed vendor links are on the website
there's the grow help tab on there
there's a newsletter sign up spot
so many wonderful things on my website
iriegenetics.com
give it a scroll check it out i'm
constantly doing minor upgrades minor
updates on there
uh you may have missed some of the most
recent updates or possibly some
merchandise drops
all right i think that is all i've got
for you for this episode my voice is
telling me that it is time to wrap it up
for the night i want to thank you again
for listening
i want to give a giant shout out to my
friend keith at blacksail market
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you