welcome back podcast world i'm your host
my friends call me rasta jeff
and this is episode 609 of the grow from
your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to read a few
grow questions before we get there
let's do a few shout outs to a few
members of the 710 club of course the
710 club are the folks who support us on
patreon
at the 7 and 10 a month level or higher
so with no further ado let's start off
with the big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out
to girls grow too let's send a special
thank you to smoke and dog
let's send a big shout out to north
north terps let's send a special thank
you to ned denver
let's send a big high five to lefty's
farm let's send a big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out to
captain mojo
i want to send a special thank you to
josiah w i want to send a big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to adhd grower
let's send a special thank you to jackie
d i want to send a big thank you shout
out to guido
let's send a big thank you shout out to
13 spark 13
and last but certainly not least let's
send a big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out
to my new friend mobius grows big thanks
and big shout out to everyone who
supports the show on patreon
if you're not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need will be
right there on the screen and of course
there is that link in the show notes
and in the video description to make it
nice and easy
for all of my friends alright guys big
thanks to everyone who supports us on
patreon thank you guys for watching
let's start off with a great update a
couple of episodes back
i shared a photo of our friend xavier's
plant xavier's plants were
struggling they needed some help we gave
them some advice on the show
and guess what i've gotten an update and
the plants look
beautiful i'll drop in a picture
probably right about here
and i'll show you what the plants look
like now good job to my friend xavier
you pulled through you fixed them you
didn't panic you followed instructions
and the plants
look beautiful shout out my dude good
job
where are we gonna go from there oh that
reminds me on the
irie genetics website there is a grow
help tab that's what i'm trying
to say a grow help tab on the ire
genetics website go to iregenetics.com
you will find a
tab that says grow help if you click on
that tab we ask you
about 16 basic questions we ask what
you're growing
what strain are you indoors or outdoors
what type of lighting are you using
just a few basic questions to give me an
idea of how to better answer your
question
then we allow you to ask a detailed
we have recently added a photo section
to that grow help tab big shout out to
my web guy thank you bro i do appreciate
that i asked for it on the podcast
i got an email earlier today said hey
check this out
there it was a photo and a grow question
i do appreciate that
that will help you guys that will help
me that will help me help you
so big shout out and thanks to my web
guy for all the support dude you are
fast or impressive
i owe you a big one also you guys now
when you go to the grow help tab you can
attach your
grow photos that will help me diagnose
your problems quite a bit
and be forewarned there's a good chance
i'll display your photo right about here
on the podcast where do we go from that
part of the show
i've got a lot of great emails i don't
know if i need to waste too much time
rambling about a bunch of stuff today
let's jump right into these grow
questions here i feel like i covered the
notes in the business part of the show
i've got a question that came from
patreon this one comes from our friend
papa z
it says what up rosta jeff papa z here
several weeks ago i sent an email for a
seed tester application as did a lot of
people i did an episode asking
for people who wanted to be testers of
my seeds and my new creations of my
genetics
i got a lot of uh tester applications
this says i never heard anything back
but my
question is this before i even get to
the question
i got an overwhelming amount of tester
applications i'm still finding them i'm
still going through them they are now
moved to a folder that says tester
applications
i've sent out quite a few tester seeds
i'm still going through them if you
haven't gotten testers if you haven't
gotten a response
don't take it personally don't take it
as a rejection i'm always going to be
making new things i'm always going to
need testers
at different levels for different
projects so don't be shy
uh don't feel like you've gotten turned
down you still may get selected out of
that tester pull
uh we're always hiring is kind of the
attitude here anyway let me jump into
the question it says what could i do
to what could i do differently to make
me a better candidate for you to choose
me
to test for you i believe in always
growing with the intent of each run
being better than the last
so i would like to know what areas i'm
lacking in as i want to be the best
grower possible and i love your gear
much love and once again thanks for
everything you do for all of us growers
trying to become
better um i can't say anything
specifically that you can do
to be a better candidate as a tester i
need all different kinds of testers i
need i need testers of all
skill levels i need some people that are
better as photographers than growers i
need some people that are real
analytical and send me over detailed
reports on what they fed them
some people just send me a picture every
week and that's basically what i get
some people send me a report on what
they fed it what they did to it
i get a lot of varying reports i expect
a few different things but i know that
humans are going to do things their way
so by giving my seeds out to a bunch of
people who do things their way i get a
lot of great feedback people find their
niche
uh their way their spot how to be a
tester for me and they just do what they
do the best so
to be a good tester i would say do what
you do the best i need someone that can
communicate that's one of the things i
really look forward to
i send out a lot of seeds and i've said
it before about
three out of every 10 back packs of
tester seeds i send
the testers just lose communication
eventually maybe they get the seeds they
don't even reply once they've got them
maybe they say hey thanks for the seeds
and that's all i get from them or they
send me a couple of weeks of reports and
then they fade off
but my point is uh sometimes i send out
testers i don't even get communication
so be able to communicate with me
take some photos let me know what's
going on that's basically what i asked
for for my testers
for you specifically i don't have
anything that i could tell you to make
you a better tester however i did
respond to you
and i did let you know that being a
patreon contributor shows me that you've
been around for a while
uh having longitude having been around
the group definitely helps you out there
may be a little bit of favoritism being
played in that sort of thing but if i've
seen your name a lot
i've seen your photos i know your
long-term irie army that does help
new people are welcome don't think i'm
just sticking to the old folks
i find some great testers and these new
random friends we're making
however i don't have any specific advice
for you but do message me back i did
send you a message on patreon
we'll talk more about getting you some
test seed since you have been a long
time
patreon supporter again you guys if i
have not read your uh tester application
if i haven't not agreed to send you
seeds
still don't be discouraged don't be shy
listen to that tester episode if you
haven't listened to it and you're still
interested in being a tester
still keep sending in the tester apps i
will get to them
i'm just going through looking at
pictures choosing what i need for now
i don't always need the exact same thing
like i said sometimes i need the guys
with
the super detailed and gals with the
super detailed
uh dirt notes i get a lot of notes from
one person about what's in their soil
they're running organic living soil
i get to know everything about that i
haven't gotten any details on the plants
but i know what's in the dirt every week
some people tell me
uh every micro mole of light that is
happening to the plants i get just a lot
of varying different things
and that gives me a lot of data so every
scientist is going to do their own
experiment
that kind of still falls in my
guidelines my expectations
and it works out for me very well so be
the best grower you could be
be able to have repeatable processes
that's the sort of stuff i look for
if you're not just doing crazy random
experiments with every batch i'd like to
see some sort of continuity some sort of
process
a standard operating procedure would be
ideal
and the ability to communicate and speak
well and talk to me well is great so you
seem to have those skills
so we will be in touch big shout out to
my friend papa z you guys don't feel
like you're getting
blown off if i have not answered your
tester application email
there were a lot of them i get a lot of
emails there's only one of me
please do remember there are a lot of
you i've got close to 6 000
subscribers here on youtube i've got uh
53 000 followers on cannabis
uh 30 something thousand on instagram
i i stay busy plus the seed companies
and everybody else i interact with i
have a lot of emails i'm not making
excuses i love it don't ever stop
i think i work best when i've got some
pressure on me uh no diamonds no
pressure no diamonds is that what they
say
if i have time to chill i [ __ ] chill
that's no good
all right i'm gonna get refocused we're
gonna keep reading messages here on the
podcast because this
is a great a message this one comes from
our friend alabama man what's up dude i
see your name on the patreon quite a bit
thank you for the continued patreon
support i sure do appreciate it
big love big respect big fist bump let's
get right into this one it says
here's a couple of questions for future
shows concerning ire genetics
just in case you don't know some people
may not even be aware not only am i a
podcaster here to help you learn how to
grow
i'm also a seed breeder i'm the sole
proprietor soul breeder for ire genetics
premium seeds that's right i make seeds
regular feminized seeds we're well known
for the arise
lemon jeffrey orange gasm a lot of great
stuff comes from i say our it's me but
say auri say artists make company sound
professional and it's ours there's a lot
of people out there that do help me
behind the scenes and stuff shout out to
the packaging crew
they know who they are but i read
genetics premium seeds is all me i'm the
breeder sole proprietor founder i am
irie genetics premium seeds that's me
check us out at iregenetics.com
now we can talk about what this person
is more asking about they say concerning
ire genetics they're going to focus on
my seed brand here it says
what factors influence a decision to
retire
a strain so you'll notice that on some
of the vending websites some on some
spots on my website it says that this
train
strain has been discontinued or retired
what influences my decision to
discontinue or retire a strain there are
a lot of things that go into that
um a lot of it is uh honestly
does it sell sometimes i will make a
strain it will be hot fire i'll think
it's gonna sell like crazy i'll have
thousands of seeds of it
i'll market it the way that i normally
do advertise the way i do do my strategy
give it out to a bunch of great growers
that take great photos
spread it around the world go to sell it
and
there's no steam that strain just
doesn't go anywhere so i've got bags of
that seed sitting around when it comes
time to make more seeds guess what i
don't make more of
that [ __ ] uh it's just uh a lot of it is
what sells
unfortunately that's what uh it's a
business it's a seed company so that's
what drives a lot of decisions is
business what sells
if something is not selling and i've got
bags of it sitting around
uh it's i'm not gonna make any more of
it there's no need so
that's the bottom line honestly well we
talk about grow from your heart and
everything but as a seed breeder
i breed with love grow for my heart but
when it comes to keeping inventory and
deciding what to remake
the bottom line is what sells and what
seeds are going to sit there i don't
want to have a bunch of useless seeds
that nobody wants
so bottom line is what sells another
thing is
the mother plant makes a big decision
let's talk about a strain a couple of
strains i have recently
retired or discontinued let's talk about
the rocksteady
rocksteady was part of the tmnt line
rocksteady came from the durbin poison
female
uh also what came from that the uh the
dragon punch came from the
uh the durbin poison female plant both
of those strains have been retired
because that mother plant was a pain in
the ass to keep in the garden that
durbin poison plant
did not she just didn't fit the program
the other plants liked a certain light
cycle a certain feeding regimen a
certain vpd
and that durbin poison plant did not
want to participate
that little [ __ ] wanted its own vpd its
own feeding regimen its own details
and i can't have a prima donna in my
garden like that if i'm trying to run a
schedule and uh
just the way i'm trying to do it it
didn't work so
that led to all of the subsequent
breeding projects from that
plant being abandoned and discontinued
so the rocksteady is gone
the double dragon is gone and that's
because i did not like working with that
mother plant
another thing that determines on if i
keep it in the breeding stable or not is
uh how many seeds does it make a lot of
plants give me
a generous amount of seeds the mac sucks
at giving me seeds
if i put and this these are just
hypothetical numbers i'm going to make
up some numbers here
if i put a strawberry starburst plant
right here
and a mac one plant right here and i
pollinate them both equally with a king
solomon plant
if this strawberry starburst plant were
to make a thousand seeds i'm just making
up a number
this mac one plant may give me five
maybe 20 seeds if i'm absolutely lucky
oh excuse me for that i've tried to
pollinate the mac at different times
i've tried to pollinate the mac at
different intervals i've tried different
tricks to pollinate the mac plant
and it's just stingy it doesn't want to
give me enough seeds to make it worth my
production time so
when i'm breeding i just put one little
small plant at the back of the room
in the room and let it get hit with
pollen and if it makes seeds it does and
i'm excited and if not that's what we
[ __ ] expected and we just smoked the
mack buds the way they are
so a lot of it is how many seeds does a
plant produce
also does the mother plant just
basically fit in the program i talked
about that durbin poison if it doesn't
fit the program it's got to go
i've got a certain way i run my grow a
certain schedule a certain style
it's like i'm just gonna pick a brand
this is a volkswagen shop and if you
bring in ferrari parts
they gotta go dude they're great parts
but they just don't fit on my volkswagen
maybe they do i'm not the engineer here
but you guys get what i'm saying right
um
yeah so if it doesn't fit the program
it's just got to go so it's all about
the mother plant may get it tossed out
sales if you guys aren't into it if you
guys aren't buying those seeds there's
no need for me to keep it going i will
retire it
production and then a big thing is uh
the market
i'm trying to i get bored of things
honestly i've got add you could tell by
watching this podcast i've got a little
bit of the add there
i get bored of growing smoking breeding
playing working with all the same [ __ ]
forever
and also uh added to that we are limited
by the amount of plants we are allowed
to have here in colorado i can have six
because of my recreational rights here
in colorado i'm allowed six
extra because my medical cannabis rights
here in colorado
that limits me to 12 plants in my grow
so imagine
trying to breed having 12 plants you
select your very favorite keepers and
then you've got a few that you can
pollinate
i'm only allowed to have so many so that
means that the
only the best of the best are able to
stick around i've got to get rid of some
stuff
and anytime i want to bring in something
new that means that something else has
to go
so hopefully i've got a friend around
here with the grow that's got some empty
space and they can run a few things and
help me select stuff
then we run a pack of seeds finally keep
her out of that and their legal six
plant grow
then i decide which one of my babies i
got a colon get rid of that is a
challenge
cut that [ __ ] down bring the keeper
from the other grow add that right to
the numbers we're still
still staying at the legal amounts
everybody's in their legal numbers
that's how things have to go so
sometimes uh it's just all about how
many plants we're allowed to have also
it's all about moving forward
uh once so the irie army the people who
buy ire genetic seeds
there's a very nice occult if you will
of people who if i put out a pack of
seeds i'm sure i can sell this many
then there are other people who find me
through websites and new customers and
whatever you want to call them new
clients that develop over time but i've
got a nice little core of people who
will buy so many then there's a fringe
and then there's the new customers
once the core has got them they kind of
stop selling it's like a baseball card
once the all the collectors have the
baseball cards
they don't sell anymore so then it's
time for me to make new baseball cards
find the new hit
player and that is part of uh being a
seed company i'm always making new
things finding new stuff keeping
cannabis evolving
i like to breed brand new things and
then go back and find that brand new
[ __ ] and breed that back to some of my
older school stuff just to revive that
and keep new stuff coming
as a a seed breeder a business person uh
a cannabis connoisseur uh a passionate
botanist i guess you might want to call
me
i am a person with [ __ ] adult
attention disorder or whatever you want
to call that
i just have to have new things new
breeding projects new plants
can't sit still i think when i sit still
that's said it earlier when i sit still
that's when i get bored i cause problems
for
not necessarily problems but you know
that's when you end up [ __ ] in a
[ __ ] battle on facebook or something
wasting your time
the uh idle hands or the devil's
playground is what i think i'm trying to
say so i keep myself busy
uh focused on the business focused on
breeding focused on plants
uh that's how my brain works so uh that
is a big
factor on what decides to retire a
strain
sales are the bottom line how do you
guys react to it
also if i discover that somebody else
has the same strain name as me
i will just stop making that strain i
don't want to compete with anybody i
don't want to piss anybody off if
that person that man that woman used
that name they deserve the right to that
name i don't want to step on their toes
if i made a faux pas a cannabis mistake
a breeder mistake
and i didn't do my due diligence and
researching that name
i will simply retire my cross just to
show that i
uh respect the other person they're
breeding their selections their names
their game
cannabis in general so that's another
reason why [ __ ] gets retired sometimes
simply because of the name
the mother plant has a lot to do with it
the female plant
uh the production from that female plant
has a lot to do with it
i feel like i'm repeating myself
sometimes i realize
that ah feminize crosses it's a pain in
the ass to make a lot of feminized
crosses sometimes i realize i got myself
in over my head and i just simply don't
want to make that anymore
uh because the plant doesn't make enough
also sometimes
and you guys all know what i'm talking
about here sometimes i name strains
after a bunch of famous cartoon
characters
and they get way more popular than i
anticipated it would ever get and then i
fear that i'm going to get a cease and
desist letter and they're going to sue
me
that may be why a few strains got
retired here you guys probably know
which ones i'm talking about if you
followed along but
that is why some things get discontinued
and retired there are several reasons
a lot of it is just basic business what
sells and what doesn't
sometimes the names are used sometimes i
fear that cease and desist letter
all right there is a second part to this
question i hope i can cover this one as
well as i did the first part
it says concerning pheno hunting this
will be good i love pheno hunting let's
say what a phenohunt is pheno hunt is
when you've got a package of seeds
a number of seeds a population and you
were growing them
to select the phenotype from that batch
of seeds
that performs best for your needs it
could be your medical needs
your recreational needs your hustling
market needs i don't know if you're
selling it smoking it trading it
pressing it but the one that fits your
needs your grow your desires the best
you were trying to find the phenotype
out of a package of seeds because
when you're growing from seed there will
be variation you'll find different
phenotypes that's what we call the
variants
different phenos different expressions
so you want to find the one that works
best for you that is a phenohunt we do
that by growing them out
take a clone finish the plants smoke
grow them smoke them
find which one you like the best then
you got a clone of each one kept back
you can do it all over again now uh
that's a phenohunt and the quick way it
says
when growing out a pack of 10 seeds by
what week
from germination have you made your
decision to cull
a pair for breeding so the question is
basically if i've got a 10 pack of seeds
that i plan to breed with
how far into the how far from
germination
do i select breeders and do i start
removing things
from the gene pool that's a very good
question
uh and it's got there's no solid answer
there's a lot of variation to that
sometimes i'll see early on that uh that
plant right there
is really slow and shitty and just
doesn't do
uh so the main part of breeding i guess
let me back up the main part of breeding
is having a goal what are you what are
you trying to do
uh if you're trying to make pizza you
need pizza ingredients if you're trying
to make
uh what's something if you're trying to
make a [ __ ] pumpkin pie you need
vastly different ingredients so
if i'm growing a plant trying to make
pizza and it's showing me pumpkin pie
trades
why keep it around that one goes early
but if i'm seeing hints of pizza over
here on these traits
then i'll keep those pizza plants
because i'm trying to make me some pizza
so that is a big part of it find what my
goal is
then just get rid of the plants that
don't reach the goal basically
then we'll look for the mutants the
weirdos the oddities
just things that are obviously not what
i want maybe that one like i said
earlier grows too slow
maybe it's too finicky maybe it doesn't
want enough water maybe
it's super thirsty and it wants a whole
bunch of water uh that plant those
plants will slowly get cold
sometimes sometimes it's really early
really really early sometimes it's
the middle of the veg phase a lot of
times i can spot the boys from the girls
because the boys get real tall if i'm
not looking for boys
sometimes i'll just take the liberty to
toss that super tall plant also is too
tall
probably didn't fit the [ __ ] breeding
program i start watching the structure
of the plan you can tell that early in
veg
three four maybe five weeks into veg you
can tell what you're working with by the
shape the structure
uh start giving it some stem rubs see
what it can handle if it can't handle my
rooms my regimen my
way of growing it's gotta go so that can
happen
all the way through veg sometimes up
into flower sometimes i don't
even decide that they've got to go until
flower sometimes you don't see
i look for bud set doesn't start making
big chunky buzz does it make small
spindly buds does it take a long time
to kick into flower does it stretch a
whole bunch does it do the dreaded
intersex trait
if it does that it goes immediately i
can find an intersex straight a week
to a flower or week nine a flower and
we're just gonna chop that [ __ ] down
and get rid of it and not do it again
so i got all the way up till sometimes
we don't decide that we're going to cull
something for a breeding project or make
a final decision
until we actually smoke the finished
product you got to grow them
finish them dry them cure them smoke
them
then make your final decision a lot of
times i'll grow in larger batches of 10
i had some commercial facilities going
where we could grow larger numbers you'd
grow quite a few
you'd narrow it down to the top two
three maybe the top
five and grow those again because the
first time we just did a sample run
didn't do anything fancy we just did a
phenol hunt everything got the same
treatment
now we know that that one plant could
have used more calmag that one likes
more nitrogen
so we'll run the top three or five again
and see which one stands out from that
dry them cure them smoke them do it all
over again so sometimes
i can call them early if they're funky
if they're ugly not doing what i want
they gotta go early uh sometimes middle
of veg
sometimes early flower sometimes laden
flower it just kind of depends
uh a lot of times i will make it's more
uh more common for me to make decisions
on what i really want to keep
uh kind of laid in veg i can see it i
just oh i like the structure of that
little girl right there that plant's
gonna be a boy
i'm gonna put them in a room together
those are gonna be beautiful
sometimes i can just see it i just get a
hint i just get a vibe i get a feeling
from these plants
sometimes however we've gotta smoke them
and sit in a room and go
man number three tastes really good but
number four gives me a really good buzz
but number five
really produced a lot more so you got
things to think about as a commercial
grower
so sometimes we don't know until the end
then
then let me go even a step further
sometimes we don't know until we have
extracted it what's the purpose of this
plant
i'm a dabber i like to smoke batters and
concentrates
why not do some extraction and then
decide which one makes the best extracts
maybe that flavor
and that potency maybe they switch
places once you run it through the
extraction equipment maybe the one that
tasted better
is now more potent maybe the one that
was more potent now tastes better after
you run it through the extraction
equipment maybe one phenotype
really dumps out the trichomes and puts
out a lot of concentrates when you press
it squish it wash it run it whatever
you're gonna do
then if that's our goal that will be our
phenotypical selection there
so um that i know that's a really
open-ended answer
uh but also let me add even more onto
that long-winded open-ended answer
sometimes um so you said for a breeding
program
we are simply selecting plants that are
going to be bred with we're looking for
the boy
um i have a really tight criteria on
looking for boys i've talked about
i can eliminate boys quickly if they
don't fit my criteria i know more
what doesn't fit for boys i could just
be like no that's not going to work
that's not going to work
so we've got our boys in one room now
that's a different uh conversation we've
got our girls we smoke and finish the
girls
now we've got three females that we're
considering pollinating with our
selected male
now we've got to pollinate and grow them
and
then see which of those phenotypes
produce the best
offspring that's where we are now with
the jack the ripper f2 i pollinated
multiple females with one male
i've sent it out that sent out the
testers with clear indicators there's
numbers uh two four and five
and possibly number three i don't know
if number three has been sent out for
testing yet
uh it just didn't look like one of the
keepers i did not keep that one for
continued generations
but uh we sent out two four and five for
testing and now we will find out if
the jack the ripper from this male one
male
pollinated multiple females will find
out which of the females performs better
and we'll put those to market maybe i'll
put both of them out we'll call it
jtrf2 number four and jtrf2 number two
and we'll simply market both of them
maybe we'll do some inbreeding like we
talked about on a previous episode
i am going to correct some of those
terms we spoke of also
but sometimes i don't make my final
selections until i see
what the seeds do that come from that so
right now i've got the jack the ripper
number two
and number four female on deck in a grow
space somewhere
once we determine which progeny is
better i'll call one of those and i'll
keep the one that makes the best
offspring
so um that has gone really far the
plants have been
uh dried cured smoked then regrown
pollinated
um tested and they are still in testing
once the testing batches some of the
first rounds of the blueberry cookies
to jack the ripper and jack the ripper
f2s are coming down this week and being
tested i'm super excited for that
they're coming down and getting smoked
really soon
once they get smoked and we decide which
one was better then i can eliminate the
parent of the one i don't like the most
so
there were multiple cycles gone through
while i kept both of those parents
around just to see
which worked best you guys that's why
seeds are not super cheap sometimes
it looks like we're just making two
plants [ __ ] but there's a lot of
selection going
when it's done properly there's a lot of
care selection preparation into it
then there's time to make the seeds
after the seeds are made they've got to
be separated sorted
sorted packaged sent out tested
thoroughly thoroughly tested
i pay for every package i sent out to
test out of my pocket that's
eight bucks worth of shipping every time
a package goes out i sent out a lot of
those
uh they got to be tested then we've got
to market them then you got to repackage
them up for sales you got to send them
out to the vendors
uh then you got to make more seeds
because once they're tested people see
the pictures from the testers they get
hot
that's why seeds are not cheap because
there's a lot of work that goes on in
the background we don't just get two
plants to make them [ __ ] and put out
seeds if we're doing it correctly
there's a lot of forethought a lot of
testing a lot of r d goes into it
um let's see where are we on this i
think i answered most of this one
sometimes i call them early sometimes in
veg sometimes in flowers sometimes you
gotta smoke them
sometimes you gotta dab them sometimes
you gotta breed with them
see which one works the best then keep
the keeper get rid of the non-keeper
sometimes i'll do that with a male also
when i was looking for solomon i went
through
a lot of seeds to find solomon i was
really picky i didn't see what i wanted
exactly in a male plant
finally i found it and i feel like i
made the right selection you guys
because
solomon is a bad mo fro all right ladies
and gentlemen boys and girls pimps and
hoes friends and foes smokers growers
clone cutters paul and chuckers
all you beautiful cannabis advocates and
consumers out there i want to thank you
guys all for joining me for another
episode of the grow from your heart
podcast
i really had fun on this episode i hope
you had as much fun as i did
if you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
maybe you just like to toss me a couple
of bucks because you learned something
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash girl from
your heart
all of the information you need to
support the show will be right there on
the screen of course
there is a link in the show notes and
the video description to make it super
easy
for all of my friends also
um what was i gonna say after that what
comes next the uh email address holy
[ __ ] i got lost there
email if you've got any questions
corrections comments or concerns i'd
love to hear from you
the email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com of course don't
forget to visit the website
iregenetics.com all things ire genetics
premium seeds all things grow from your
heart podcast
all things rasta jeff the etsy store
vendor links everything is set up right
there on iregenetics.com
give it a visit check it out grab
yourself a new i uh grow from your heart
coffee mug what grow from your heart
coffee mugs yes they are live on the
store now
go grab one they are very limited check
them out
you guys had a lot of fun you know i'll
be back in just a couple of days with
fresh new content
i want to give a giant shout out to my
buddy og purple thumb and until next
time take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
this
you