oh it's up cannabis community it's time
for episode number 61 of the girl from
your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
okay yeah
are you still record yeah literally
turned off every switch and put his
headset down like something just wake
the [ __ ] out started I dunno now but at
the time I was like oh god head injury
recently and I don't know if that's
coming back touch that should not ever
touch and dude it made the most painful
sound across the street I feel like
you've been here we're gonna need to put
some duct tape or something
this over to here and we'll try to
prevent that because dude that was crazy
man dude so I've heard the noise but
neither me nor Mike harden just you slid
right across my input right here just
right across there looked like it was in
my ears and I felt like it was happening
in my body guys welcome to the girl from
yard podcast
[Music]
holy crap we're gonna we're gonna have a
live happy Wednesday there's gonna be a
Wednesday episode you guys started to
play before I had a crazy great
technical issues from the mystic roots
band I owe them a shout-out I'm Way off
rhythm let's read a podcast ad and we
will get into the show here Mike don't
spit that Mountain Dew on the computer
open it on the mic let's take a DAB
that's a good Mountain Dew oh hi called
hi growing or growing supplies they have
great prices on growing equipment well
organized well organized shelves and a
couple of beautiful clerks I don't know
what they're called their sales
associates and Jesse's included in that
yeah and Adam helps load the truck
sometimes so he's beautiful as well yeah
supplies hi grow indoor growing spies if
you're in Denver go to the Denver
location it's 62 71 Beach Street if
you're in Pueblo check them out it's 618
East 4th Street in Pueblo Colorado no
[ __ ] you guys I wouldn't represent a
company on my podcast that I didn't love
with my heart hydro is my friends
they've got a great great store if you
tell them you're listening to the
podcast they'll give you a fatty body
discount they will give you commercial
pricing on your entire order and it's
fat it'll save you money it's such a
huge deal
oh man is this gorilla glue nice yeah
we're about to take some gorilla glue
dabs but before I do that I got to read
this next one also big huge shout out
much love to our friends at the rocky
mountain worm company like I said before
no [ __ ] I only rep companies that
on the show and I use the Rocky Mountain
one company products check them out
they've got dragonfly earth medicine
they've got worm castings they've got
sea crop they have got fish Hydra slates
they've got everything you need if you
ask they'll probably give you a tour of
the worm farm you can see how the worms
are made it's pretty cool it's 411
Tijuana Street and Colorado Springs
Colorado if you don't want to travel or
if you're out of state they will mail
you worm castings they will mail you
dragonfly earth medicine they will ship
to your front door I think you can get
live worms or worm I forgot what they're
called Carlos here pew-pew man the baby
was something like that I don't have the
website pulled up I should build that
[ __ ] to your door and you can use all
the [ __ ] that I'm using Mike dude teach
you about microphone stands headbutt
them you cannot fight with it it is your
friend just keeping that red thing in
your face where we need it cool [ __ ] you
have to sponsor the show I do do way
better ads on Monday episodes this is
when they have Wednesday we're getting a
little funky today we're having a good
time we had an equipment error right at
the beginning of the show so it's gonna
be a chaotic episode I want to go 30
minutes or so if you want to sponsor the
show send me an email to grow from your
heart at hotmail.com I'll get you all
that information look at you all squared
up if you got a product you want me to
test out we like testing out new [ __ ] on
the show we need more email we need an
official email of the show I think yeah
this one was a gift and a hookup for my
good friend Gideon emo tech so shout out
to the Gmail here so I'll be real
specific white Mike needs an email white
Mike himself needs an email you would
never leave the house
you would have no reason to come over
here anymore seriously I've seriously
been considering an inverter for my car
for the email app dude I saw that online
and I cringed a little less on Instagram
Yeah right it's I know if I have a
passenger that can hold on to it so
nobody gets burned it'll be awesome but
if you put it in the cup holder
it's your elbows gonna hit right there
you're gonna need some Apothic and a
pain dream it's only a matter of time
for some [ __ ] [ __ ] it burst into
flames yeah it's gonna be that one guy
the rooms are for everybody but hey
until that guy if anybody got my go-to
reference you got a high five
PC you baby oh the gorilla huh dude it's
tasty shut up the trip ex I'm Davin they
don't sponsor the show or anything but I
got some tasty tur pecs Gorilla Glue
shatter from green and healthy wellness
they sponsor my happiness yeah this
smile has been brought to you by the
friends at tur pecks and green and
healthy wellness that was well put sir
shout out to hunt in his womb broom hey
get that meat wallet tight man you guys
are pulling out all the stops
[Music]
I've got three news articles all we have
to do is get through three news articles
and then we can have fun guys I read
commercials and such yeah so let's get
down to it let's I gotta click doing the
clickety clicks tastes delicious hey
Mike when you set that down make sure
you uh put that right on my cable here
my body told me get up walk away like
just take off your headphones and walk
away from that bad that's how I feel
when you're over there like heating it
up and scraping the email you know they
clean the top this yeah you seemed to
save that [ __ ] when I come over and it's
like how he loves this [ __ ] what this is
this is Adams favorite I wish I could
write all right I'm gonna read a news
article it says one surprising downside
of marijuana legalization major energy
use and then there's a picture we got
three to five no like seven or eight
lights hanging in a little growth
facility here with the ballast up on the
ceiling just to kind of show you a nice
little visual of electricity being ran
and then it says oh this article I
better give some credit here who Chris
Mooney from the Washington Post wrote
this he says across the country there's
a growing trend toward the legalization
of marijuana four states Oregon
Washington Colorado Alaska have voted to
allow people to possess limited amounts
of marijuana for personal use and also
to let producers apply for licenses to
produce and sell it
DC also just voted to allow voted to
allow personal possession all of this on
top of the 23 states that allow it for
medical reasons in some states we just
read two different articles that gave me
different numbers on that didn't we one
said 21 said 23 maybe they were taken at
different times maybe they're dabbing
also hit dabs is the the way this gets
counted up is confusing because there's
Senza that second Sanjay Gupta special
there's been a whole bunch of CBD only
states across the south is sudo medical
how you count that if you count that the
numbers law he was just about 25 now the
guy that was making the big fuss in New
Jersey was just in the news today one go
back at it like Blood Money Christie
being all fat and crazy
that's that should be just used to be
the governor of Florida - so I mean like
after his brother or something
he's just an art man never gonna be
President order in the court in some
states where businesses
are also now legally cultivating and
producing marijuana a mainstream inner
industry is emerging marijuana sales
totaled 700 million dollars in Colorado
last year for instance yeah you spend uh
the first three months that I was here
yeah I posted a picture on Twitter the
only time I bought legal pot last year
it was on January 1st so I could exact
sixty bucks so that was me yep about 125
on the first at the greener side
dispensary but I bought a lot of this
shatter from green and healthy lately
yeah 2015 is gonna be a different tale
almost black cherry chem done I ran a
lot of black cherry Kevin in his tasty
very tasty it's a little heavy on the
indica side so for daytime it's a little
bit much sometimes alright but let's see
700 million dollars in Colorado a last
year for instance but there's a
surprising catch it turns out that
indoor marijuana growth in particular a
cultivation method often favored in the
industry for many reasons usings uses a
surprising amount of energy
indeed the level of power use appears to
be so significant that one scholar is
now suggesting that as the industry
grows states and localities should take
advantage of marijuana licensing
procedures to also regulate the
industry's use energy use and greenhouse
gas emissions damn hippie this new
industry
let's see given that this is a new
industry that is going to be pretty
highly regulated I felt like the state
and local policy makers have a unique
opportunity to incorporate energy usage
and climate assessments into their state
marijuana licensing fees says Gina
Warren a professor at the Texas A&amp;M
University School of Law whose paper
titled regulating pot to save the polar
bear energy and climate impacts of the
marijuana industry will soon appear in
the Columbia Journal of environmental
laws wow that's catch that this is hot
and polar bears in the same close
together
I just saw a polar bear like running
through a field of pot like it was yeah
I just thought that that was like an
obstacle of a sentence to get through
the entire paragraph is one sense let's
see if there's a comma a comma so I
wrote a ellipse and then another comma
and then a period yeah there's so much
punctuated that's that yeah yeah good
writing props the published statistics
on energy use from indoor marijuana
production will blow your mind whether
or not you use this stuff in a 2012
study of carbon footprint of indoor
cannabis production published in the
journal inter energy policy researcher
Evan Mills noted that on occasion
previous unrecognized spheres of energy
used to come to light and marijuana is a
textbook example the study estimated
that indoor cannabis both legal and
illegal uses six billion dollars worth
of electricity every year amounting to
one percent of overall US electricity
and in some production intensive states
like California it was much higher three
percent Mills found Ivan read into this
article much further but I'm going to
assume that Colorado is gonna hit like
5% of that because we're killing it on
the indoor grows the only thing that
would hold Colorado back from that would
be there is less people here then some
it's the percentage of our overall usage
yeah yeah so one average kilogram of
final product is associated with 4,600
kilograms of carbon dioxide emissions to
the atmosphere or that of 3 million
average u.s. cars when aggregated across
all national production roll mills the
reason is simply the technique the
technology required specific energy uses
include high intensity lighting
dehumidification remove to remove water
vapor and avoid mold formation space
heating or cooling during non
illuminated periods and drying
preheating of irrigation water
generation of carbon dioxide by burning
fossil fuel and ventilation and air
conditioning to remove waste heat
Wright's Mills that's a well researched
they did all that math and they haven't
figured out how much carbon tax the
plant sent back out there
mmm there's an well no but there's
another side of that coin depends on the
plant you know I agree with this article
Foley I'm just saying there's like
there's a there's a little bit of
subtraction that needs to be done before
we freak out a little true that she
keeps on going and she says Oh outdoor
production also has environmental
consequences it has been charged with
deforestation and high levels of water
and pesticide use
but as pot becomes more legal and
mainstream notes warrant outdoor
producers will have to abide by
pre-existing in their environmental laws
just like everyone else in effect that
means indoor production the chief
climate change that makes indoor
production the chief climate change and
energy concern according to Warren's
article while underground indoor
marijuana production already consumed
the plenty of energy legalization will
increase energy use even further as the
industry grows so will its negative
externality she writes which is why
she's proposing that all states that
legalize marijuana use should also
require the growing industry to power
itself cleanly and it's not without
precedent
starting in October of this year Boulder
County and Colorado will require many
facilities to directly offset 100
percent of electricity propane and
natural gas consumption the renewables
or other means that's a fun challenge
now yeah Warren says she's not picking
on the marijuana industry with her
proposals it's just that well we don't
often have new industries appear that
use a lot of energy and are likely to be
highly regulated as they become legal I
think it could actually be a marketing
tool for the industry says Warren
because if you have people who are
purchasing the product who are the type
of individual who cares about the
environment then they would gravitate
toward the green marijuana production
what she's saying makes sense because we
are sucking up a lot of power and I've
thought about it I don't know how to do
it maybe somebody can send me an email
or something one thing I want to do I
consider myself a pro grower I could
grow you can give me a plant that's half
dead and then in 90 days I'll give you
some tasty ass buds out of it I can
overcome those problems in a grow room
now I want some guidance on how to
lessen my carbon footprint I recycle my
soil but still I have to run lights for
12 hours on a 12 hours off there's no
are there other things we can do to kind
of lessen our carbon footprint if you
guys know send me ideas you can tweet
them to me
it's at G fyh podcast you can email me
it's girl from your heart at hotmail.com
yeah well I want to see I want to know
how there's all kinds it seems an
argument right now I mean you would try
to find those cannabis cultivators would
start looking for places like wine but
yeah you know places they would right
next to rivers where they can have a
water bill oh we're talking about like
my pre-existing indoor grow like people
that have a home grow or a small
warehouse grow like I want to find out
ways that people like us like you you've
got a trap house grow I want to see you
a way that you can kind of make a little
less in your electricity bill just save
you however much it is maybe cut 10% of
that off absolutely well you could
definitely do that with solar you know
I'm saying like you're you're just
cutting out the hundred dollars that it
takes to run your house would be a
hundred dollars less over a year that
would add up you know tremendously
that's 15 to you know quite a bit a
hundred dollars just watch do you try to
do bad right now right now it's twelve
dollars but I'm just saying like you
know the local application of this is
the city of Pueblo just required
everybody growing doors you can't grow
outside not in any fashion this year in
Pablo that's kind of silly hopefully in
a year we'll have green house rules down
here but yet they cut it off and but not
until the very end no you're talking
about the card six persons in my own
backyard it no legal is really if you're
not on the game yeah b-positive legal
the Sun is not there looking for more
illegal pot grows here and now more than
they were before we have legalized
cannabis to tell you the truth because
now they want to regulate the [ __ ] out
of it before they didn't have time now
it's an issue all right I want to read
which one do we want to do this one do
you want to do the which one the good
one well they're both good brother
no just [ __ ] with you do you want to
read the one written by they're both
written by the same person
sweet we'll do that Accardo baja no
Kristen want
is writing a lot do you want to do the
one about racism drop in call from the
cannabis to treat by Kristen Wyatt of
The Associated Press
Alaska it says the legalization of
marijuana in Colorado hasn't solved the
racial disparities in enforcement the
drug policy performers had hoped to end
with blacks still far more likely than
whites to be charged with pot related
crimes a new report says the report
issued Wednesday by the Perl
legalization drug policy Alliance showed
that marijuana arrests in Colorado all
but stopped after voters made the drug
legal in small amounts for those 21 and
older but the report noted continuing
racial disparities involving the
marijuana crimes that remain including
public use in possession in excess of
the ounce limit study the study examined
drug arrests in all 64 Colorado counties
for two years before and after
legalization in 2012 the total number of
charges for pot possession distribution
and cultivation plummeted by almost 95%
from about thirty nine thousand two
thousand tend to just over two thousand
last year that's if it only takes an
hour of the cops time that's 37 cop
hours 37,000 37,000 cop hours we just
reallocated - [ __ ] that's worth
something usable yeah they can be out
solving a crime any crime looking for
your bike that got stolen yep looking
for something the bad happened I don't
even want to create crimes in my head I
have to say it has been nice like not
worrying about the bag to Tim my pocket
yeah only crime most marijuana consumers
like trough traffic infractions don't
weed like it's literally the only
problem is once you pull me over it's
like here's the bag yeah hope it smells
good in here a lot of money for that
here you can have my sweater give me
five minutes and then when you come back
tell me it smells like weed yeah all
right so I'm gonna keep reading cuz we
want to get through a couple articles
even after legalization blacks were more
likely twice as likely
oh sorry I read that wrong blacks were
more than I've stuttered because
Wordsworth we're saying blacks to
American would be the correct term
is a little harsh when I ran into but
I'm not a member of the PC squad I
didn't write this article so if you want
to complain that we're calling Africans
raid it when you got those two guys did
that not me I found it slightly
even after legalization african-american
folks were more than twice as likely as
White's and whites this just oddly
written you tell us community is that us
or in the dabs or is it how it's written
we the racist waters they are they
blacks were also more much more likely
to be charged with illegal cultivation
of pot or possession of more than an
ounce legalization that for the long
time issues that law enforcement had
with the black and brown community said
art way Colorado director for the drug
policy Alliance still the drop-off and
overall arrest is good news for
minorities said Tony Newman also of the
drug policy Alliance despite the
uprising racial disparities the massive
drops and arrests have been enormous ly
beneficial to people of color Newman
said is this is this my system or I
think we stopped referring to people by
the general you know the term that I
related to in there I can't even now
I've just based on a already pastor yeah
it was the all right the analysis did
not break out data for Colorado's
largest ethnic minority Latinos that's
because data comes from the National
incident based reporting system system
which does not tally numbers for Latinos
one of the region's top officials for
coordinating drug enforcement table
Gorman of the Rocky Mountain high
intensity drug trafficking area program
insisted that officers are not rape
racially profiling pot users no they're
not there is calling on blacks and
whites
that's all they're doing it's not a
profile to general rape laws weapon was
a racist there are other factors going
on here that we need to address racial
disparities did ease somewhat for
marijuana distribution charges blacks
accounted for about 22% of such arrests
in 2010 and around 18% in 2014 the
arrest data got a mixed response from
the regional head of the n-double a-c-p
did the head of the n-double a-c-p know
that you were calling them blacks when
you wrote this on the overall decrease
in arrests charges and cases ignore is
enormous ly beneficial to communities of
color who bore the brunt of marijuana
prohibition rosemary Harris little said
in a statement however we are concerned
with the rise in a disparity for the
charge of public consumption and chat
and challenged law enforcement to ensure
this reality is not a discriminatory in
any manner wow that was hard to read I
in 2014 the years the year Colorado's
recreational marijuana stores opened
blacks were three point nine percent of
the population but accounted for nine
point two percent of pop possession
arrests for illegal marijuana
cultivation this disparities didn't just
persist they got much worse in 2010
White's in Colorado were slightly more
likely than blacks to be arrested for
growing pot after legalization the
arrests rate for whites dropped into
matically but ticked up for blacks in
2014 the arrest rate for blacks was
roughly two point five times higher
there's a lot more of this article but
I'm not gonna read it it's almost done
but we get the point I don't like the
way it's written and I just got a lot of
really good information but it seems
like it was written really really fast
by someone who wasn't really thinking to
meet that deadline in the 60s well
they're still called I really like that
reporter but yeah this strikes me as a
little bit odd do you Mike tell me do
you just like all of his workers it's a
it's a lady
she's got a porter inside of the
Colorado marijuana's take a drink of
this water and then we're gonna read
another article written by the same
person and we're gonna try to [ __ ]
see like something like if we read in
public you wouldn't want to say it full
throat it was just gonna ask you would
you say that out loud at the mall
like probably not but she's very that's
how she would state it in a courtroom
you know I mean our politics I mean
let's just be real though no civil
rights person I don't I don't even want
to be called the whites over here I the
whites and they're not the blacks
[Music]
because I long hair and that means you
get pole but you're still a person
that's why I was trying
[Music]
yeah but crime in the arrests are down a
lot but it's still high for black stay
off my facebook I'm sitting there June
in the math of my head that's roughly
22,000 people of color that didn't get a
rest or [ __ ] with last year but still
the data is so screwed up like we really
need to restructure most of how we
enforce the laws I want your opinion on
that article the people that are
listening tweet me email me you know how
to do it I said it earlier what your
opinion was it oddly written in a racist
tone like I didn't like the way that is
it racist to say it that way I didn't
like it I didn't like it so I abandon
we're gonna read another article this
for the conference says Colorado bill
seeks to standardize marijuana testing
um what I've noticed is a lot of people
in Colorado don't trust the testing
facilities anymore because we'll take a
test to one lab and it will come out at
22 percent you could take another test
to another lab and they'll come out of
29 percent and of course everyone's
gonna start going to the lab that gets
higher tests because you want to be able
to brag about higher results so it's
there's no real standard for the testing
lab so we can all just open our own lab
pretty much and be like I got the test
laughs is an email or a printed piece of
paper so you get a PDF and then you
don't worry about if those high-dollar
people couldn't pay more for better
testing routes so Colorado is moving to
establish another marijuana first the
first government standards for marijuana
testing a bill approved by its first
committee in the state legislature on
Thursday would create a statewide
laboratory standard for the state's 18
pot testing labs currently the labs are
certified by the state health
authorities but they don't have uniform
rules for testing pot potency
homogeneity and contaminants as required
by state law lab owners say they need
the standards because different labs now
produce very different results existing
pot tests generally just look for
whether the drug whether the drug is
present not how strong it is in most
industries there are long established
long established processes said Ian
behringer owner of a pot testing lab
called rm3 however for cannabis like
most of the industry we're making up the
rules as we go along I'm glad he admits
that now the labs can currently be used
or did I click there we go
the labs can currently be used by
licensed marijuana producers the bill
was amended to remove lab access to
private individuals and industrial hemp
growers now covered in separate bills
still pending in the legislature which
kind of bars me from getting my cannabis
tested now the stuff that I used to draw
up my private girl for my patients I was
able to take that to the lab and get it
tested and we could see what was in
there and I think we all need access to
that I don't understand why they cut us
off this is not only that this is the
latest step in a dance that's been going
on for 10 years
like I remember we didn't have testing
labs because the existing labs that had
the equipment and the know-how are
banned from working with candidates
because they all require FDA and federal
licenses yeah so we had to build these
from the ground up I didn't know there
were 18 of them in the state that's
pretty cool okay yeah so it says a
separate bill advanced Thursday in a
Senate committee would allow industrial
hemp growers to use the labs to Colorado
currently allows farmers to grow hip
marijuana's non-intoxicating cousin but
only if the plants fall below a
threshold for the plants intoxicating
ingredient THC it's not an ingredient
however the farmers can take their
plants to a lab to make sure they're
meeting the standard the testing bill
creates what's called a reference
library a standard set of protocols for
testing
the lab owner said the state needs to
essentially referee all the
methodologies that were using we all
understand the need to reveal the
special sauce we've been using to
further the industry behringer said the
bill now heads to a separate committee
before consideration by the full house
full house I just watch that I agree
this needs to happen do we need to know
this is huge it's one of the beautiful
parts of legalization is it's it's like
everything else these guys are the
regulators they need to be regulated if
people the testing labs for sure need to
know what they're doing they'll be using
the same equipment playing by the same
rules we're gonna start seeing reality
in our testing but you can spot [ __ ]
on the shelf if you're us like I know
your flower doesn't have 40% THC the big
claims they have a 30% strain and I've
seen it and it's mids it is not 30% it's
definitely not there yeah I know about
the National remember the guy that was
all hyped up about his 29% yeah yeah I
think so yeah the apple pie strain and
we both took one look at it we both look
at him we both looked at us and it was
like we tried not to giggle we all saw
you - there's pokerface right then
definitely it was mids everyone knows
when you [ __ ] the bed to have just
saying like but now with these testing
labs if we get them all standardized and
regulated then we won't have to worry
like if you're like this hash was tested
super clean and super high in potency
I'm like what where'd you get it done
did you get it at the place that you pay
a lot more and they just give you really
high reasonably small yeah did you go to
the place it's reputable like if you got
a test it steep hill I trust you but I
don't know any of the other places steep
hill gave me a tour of their facility
and showed me what's going on
they blew my mind all the other places
you just give them a sample and they
drive away and send you an email later
they're not there they're 100% cannabis
to correct or yeah that's all they test
is red so do you edibles in your right
absolutely
toy like oh yeah we got we got science
stuff in here it's more important as we
just required that all edible dosing be
pretty much perfect
yeah you guys remember how that first
regulatory check went through yeah that
was like episode six I think that was a
long time ago we talked about that THC
and they had zero at appear what's going
on kick a man for the [ __ ] up last year
but yeah there are a whole bunch of
companies that couldn't make it in then
we had new rules that require that only
ten milligrams of THC are in each easily
identifiable segment which meant no more
450 milligrams of Snickers Mountain
medicine bar so delicious somebody
showed me one the other day the fridge
almost out of the challenge you don't
just want to drop down didn't really get
done for a month something you gotta
work up to I don't know if you want to
do it guys we're gonna wrap up the show
we do the news articles I want to talk
about the growers meeting that is coming
up at hydro indoor growing supplies you
guys want to be at this you guys want to
come hey I made it the last one it was
fantastic we didn't get a lot of talked
about but the community was we was
definitely got red eyed yeah it was a
bonding experience so come on out you
guys to high grow indoor growing
supplies on April 26th I think it starts
at 6 o'clock I am going to put together
a presentation and I will talk I'm not
sure about what yeah
I've got 26 days to figure it out start
sending your questions people yeah send
me some emails send me all that good
stuff we'll get it figured out I'll do a
grow lesson like 30 or 40 minutes it'll
turn into an hour with questions I like
it so if you guys have any topic you
want me to talk about about on the show
or at the meeting you can send them to
me it's a girl from a hard hotmail.com
I've said that a lot of times you guys
have any shoutouts you want to do before
we wrap it up boys oh good
this week it's been a fun hump day yeah
yeah hump day hump day dabs what night
is it really it's actually Friday night
isn't it it's Friday night three dudes
on a Friday night recording a podcast in
my kitchen yep right now guys can't hear
it but there's a big party raging behind
us but it's not with water I'm a friend
know Mike Scott Mountain Dew he's living
I had a bean free root beer that doesn't
count as caffeine like it might as well
be flavored water all right I'm gonna
close a show because we're just
documenting do another episode I'll be
back probably I'll be back Monday for
sure with a solid episode for you put
together a lot of a lot of stuff don't
forget to check out the sponsors rocky
mountain worm company i grow indoor
growing supplies if you're interested in
sponsoring the show send me an email
score from a heart at hotmail.com if you
have something you want to say you can
email me anything just tell me girl calm
don't forget that every episode is
available on iTunes and stitcher and I
read genetics Colorado calm don't forget
about the donation button its I read
genetics Colorado calm and then you
click on the girl from your heart
podcasts tab then you click on that
donation button and then I - clicks
$1,000,000 yep and then lots and then
you hit donate and then because it's
grown from your heart I'll pay a whole
bunch of
and then we'll throw the hugest dad
party for another we're gonna do that
right after the show ends here we'll
play some outro music we'll take dad's
logging goes on
guys I'll never charge you for the
podcast I know I'm talking about a
donation page I'm never gonna charge you
it's there if there's a page cause yeah
that's gonna end soon and I don't want
to keep advertising it because deadlines
for that for donations for that man by
the time this episode goes up so I don't
want to say that but there is a good
cause there's a good cause to
nominations of 102 donations totaling a
hundred dollars will go to cause I
mentioned before yeah yeah the first
cause April 1st or May 1st but we are
collecting money for my daughter to go
on an educational adventure in Hawaii
she's a bright kid she deserves this
quite a bit only like 30 kids in the
whole nation where you're qualified for
real I'm obviously well my phone just
reset and having a note on there I was
gonna read at the end of the show there
goes that I know you don't but yes so
that's where the funding is going it's
going on my kid oh I'm trying to get her
to Hawaii it's gonna cost like four or
five thousand bucks for this trip and
yeah hi REE genetics is a small business
and I can't just pull that out of my ass
to tell you the truth there are other
things that require they're required
like a plane ticket also just like the
the class itself yeah you can't drive to
Hawaii yeah that'd be fun maybe uh if
you have ever driven to Hawaii we want
you on the show that's gonna we'll have
to find another worthy cause for that
and I need some new microphone covers
here these things are getting a little
funky and spitting into these for a
while there are a couple of adapters
we've been kind of abusive with the show
so that it'll quit making that
Terminator sound I'd be cool all right
anyway cuz we're on all the social media
sites search for me find me follow me be
my friend I love it if you really want
to hook it up go to the I read genetics
Colorado website join the web forum
create an account there I'm on there
semi frequently I try to get on there
like every Monday night post pictures of
the garden if you have questions I
definitely communicate with everybody on
there I like it I like it follow I read
genetics on Instagram I
host some pretty quality cannabis
photography I like it I got to give a
big shout out to these boys for hanging
out this is the second episode in a row
we've recorded tonight
my throat's blown out you can hear it
right now son for a big dab in a drink
thanks guys
I got around a fire all night last night
so it's what you burned down big shots
made into spits you guys thanks again
for listening until next time take a big
fat dab of Sumter packs and give your
mom a hug for me