all right here we go welcome back
podcast world
i'm your host my friends call me rasta
jeff and this is episode 610
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode my buddy mike is going to
join me to talk about federal
legalization
before we get there let's do a few shout
outs to a few of the folks who support
the show on patreon
let's start off with the big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to my buddy indica b
let's send a thank you shout out to sam
heads let's send a thank you shout out
to kurt zee and zo so j
let's send a big thank you shout out to
my buddy tonto let's send a thank you
shout out to dinky dave
listen to big girl from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to my buddy
glenn jeroni
let's follow that up the thank you shout
out to coach steve and mr
and last but certainly not least let's
send a big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out
to my buddy noah n big thanks and big
shout out to everybody who supports the
show on patreon
if you're not already supporting the
show and you'd like to learn how to do
so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need will be
right there on the screen and of course
i did include that link in the show
notes and the video description
to make it nice and easy for all of my
friends now it is my turn to turn the
mic
over to my good friend mike so he can
say thanks to all of his patreon friends
welcome to the show mike
what's up man how are you doing
everybody
oh good to be back good to be back
it's good to have you on here bro it is
good to have you on here i know you just
took a monster dab right before we
pressed record
but are there any feeling a little
scrambling i could see it on your face
that's why i'm trying to buy you a
moment here before i expect you to do
sure
definitely some folks i'd love to throw
some shout outs to
um that support me on patreon uh thank
you to all the people that support me on
patreon and the people that support the
show
we could definitely not do this without
all of you
um some specific shout outs this month i
want to say
uh thank you very much to learning and
burning farmer z
og purple thumb richard the grow from
your heart podcast
and chris thank you all so very much for
supporting me
um yeah i just
i'm blown away by by all the support we
get i love you guys thank you very much
isn't it cool that we talk into a
microphone we talk to each other here on
camera and then people want to support
us financially i think it's a beautiful
thing
thank you i do appreciate it as well
mike's all dabbed out and choked up from
a dab but
we do mean it from the bottom of our
coughing little hearts thank you guys
for all that patreon support
if i do look distracted uh i do have the
zoom meeting here i'm looking at mike
here the cameras here
the notes are here the dab rig's over
here uh the pipe is here
a lot of pieces of motion yeah and i
don't know where my brain is so all
these pieces are moving it's going to
happen we're going to make a podcast out
of it thank you guys for joining us
uh dude welcome to the show mike i know
we got your patreon shout outs out of
the way it's been a minute and a half
i'm so glad to be back
we just uh we've had a hell of a time
getting our schedules lined up
yes uh no we succeeded today yes i'm not
even gonna say how many uh
failed and bailed attempts we've had on
trying to record in the past few
weekends or weeks but we're here and i'm
excited so that's what counts that's
what matters
yeah looking good in that new irie
genetics hoodie there buddy
loving it y'all i'm glad that you were
able to uh check that merch store y'all
it's
great gear or if you're uh even if
you're local save some shipping money
and just will socially distance just hit
up
jeff well yeah we'll meet you in a
parking lot we'll use the t-shirt cannon
and just shoot it from my car to yours
right into your car window maybe i can
shoot it right at you where i shoot it
on you if we do it just try it shoot
your new t-shirt onto you with the
t-shirt cannon that's [ __ ] weird
uh looking good bro i'm glad you came by
and picked that up it was good seeing
you
um so let's jump right into it no need
to uh to dick around
we can get talkative so let's just get
talkative on a subject
the i wrote down politicians and the
government yup
have been teased again they doing [ __ ]
uh not only
are they getting their house invaded
they're up to other [ __ ] as well
uh i'm not even going there couldn't
resist uh these fine folks
are taunting us and teasing us with the
idea with the allure of
federal cannabis legalization so i
thought it would be a good time to have
mike back
on talk about this mike is i'm kind of
the grow guy for sure got my gross stuff
reading stuff
mostly figured out like i've proven in a
past episode i do make some mistakes and
say some silly [ __ ]
however most the time i got the gross to
figure out mike is my uh political guy
my educational guy
uh my news guy so i brought him on to
talk about this federal
legalization opportunity figure out
what's going to happen what could what
might what won't happen mike is the good
guy for that
um the first thing i wanted to mention
the first thing i know we brought mike
on so that i could talk
exactly the first thing i wanted to talk
about though is uh the coolest thing
people are going to be let out of prison
in some states people are already
being let out already cannabis crimes if
you're in prison for cannabis possession
or something involving cannabis people
are being let out
that's amazing to me dude that is super
cool
uh it's fantastic whether that's part of
the federal legalization bill we'll see
um hopefully it is uh cory booker is one
of the three main
people um leading this charge right now
or at least
leading this tease right now um and i
know that it's something near and dear
to his heart so
we might see some of that coming down
the pipe federally but it's definitely
happening in different
different states around the country it's
beautiful to see it's not happening in
your state
right your governor yeah especially if
you have legal cannabis there and there
are still i'm going to say that a lot
this episode
you are all right it's going to that
might just be the name of the episode
but if you're in a legal cannabis state
and there are still people locked up for
cannabis crimes there
what's the word mike when we start
letting people out for things that they
did in the past what's the word they're
the term for that
humanity yeah okay there's a technical
prison word the legal term
um yeah i've been written that's better
something like that you get [ __ ]
freedom bro you get let out of prison
uh because what you did wasn't a crime
and the rules have changed where now we
feel that it's more humane exactly to
let you out and let you go back
play with your family be with your
friends so i think it's beautiful we're
out here smoking
there are dispensaries why should people
be in jail for something that
some 19 year old girl is [ __ ] doing
right over the counter and making a job
and making tax money doing it when
there's guys there or other women also
in jail for [ __ ] doing exactly what
people are doing at the store now so i
think it's great that people are going
to get freed that's beautiful
it it's definitely hard to defend
keeping someone in jail for selling pot
when they have stores on the corner
absolutely that are paying for schools
and it just doesn't make any sense so
um states like colorado and washington
that didn't lead with some of that in
our laws are going back
retroactively now in correcting that
continued mistake that we left on the
books
other states i think illinois is one
that they're uh
made that a main piece of their law and
they're at least trying
um and there's a ton of states not just
federally right now which is sort of the
main
focus of the show but there are a lot of
individual states that have dragged
their feet on
medical and recreational legalization
that are now saying
all right everybody around us has
already done it if you have you know
only have to drive two states over to
get it it doesn't make sense so we don't
have it here too
absolutely yeah and i read one i can't
remember which politician but it was a
southern red state
prohibition state politician whose quote
was
if they'll drive to the next state over
to get fireworks
they're going to drive the the next
state over to buy cannabis
that we might as well just have it here
yeah and it's
it it's a little sillier than that in
reality because there's already plenty
of
marijuana for sale everywhere everywhere
but
not everybody has a hookup not legally i
like to use my mom as an example my mom
doesn't shop at the dispatch she's my
mom she wouldn't need the shop but
if my mom wanted to buy cannabis i
wouldn't want her to go
find one of the guys in the hood i'd
much rather her go to the store
she's gonna get what she pays for with a
receipt
uh i like to say that it's gonna be lab
tested and clean and all that but with
the dispensary reports we've been seeing
that could be a totally different
episode but
yeah so i agree that if my mom had to
had a life-threatening condition
somebody in her position they'd drive
uh two hours or four hours to another
state to get it other than go
plenty of people doing it yeah it's
easier for her to risk getting arrested
and crossing state lines than it is to
go
into the hood and and i keep keep saying
the hood just to put the mental image in
there
i love that argument i used to make um
in front of city council regularly
the people who everyone agree should
have
ready access to cannabis like uh
somebody's grandma with cancer was
always my example
everybody agrees that she should have
access to it
everybody kind of understands that she
might not be able to grow it herself
everybody understands that if she goes
to her doctor and gets that diagnosis
it's unreasonable to say just suffer
through the chemo for nine months while
you learn to grow your first crop
and then maybe enjoy some relief almost
a year down the road
maybe you'll have reasonable to grow the
crop while you're going through chemo
maybe you'll uh have a successful crop
you know like yeah so many maybes in
there
all right michael let's get this back
she was always my example for like why
we should have a store everywhere though
yeah
yeah there were uh working at that
dispensary in 2007 and 2008 showed me so
many people that were shining examples
of why
medical cannabis should be widely
available and affordable
for people we were trying to hook
everybody up the best we could and we
were a profitable business while still
giving away
large quantities of product so i know
that it's all the new licensing and [ __ ]
but still
we were doing it all right i want to put
us back on track i do have some
questions here
uh and i can kind of segue into this uh
what else happens if we federally
legalize mike you're my guy to ask all
these silly questions so
right now literally everything's up in
the air um
the democrats have control of the the
presidency
the house and the senate um
and you have to get all three of those
to agree to pass any new law like
federal legalization
so they built hotels on park place and
boardwalk basically
yeah and the hotels the pro the
the the hitch here is democrats suck
with power
um their first idea is always let's take
all the republican ideas first
and that usually leads to getting little
to nothing done
and that's what i'm afraid is gonna
happen here it's still sort of
monumental
that this upfront
in a new presidential term they're
already talking about stuff that's this
culture worry like we're also 40 years
too late on this but as far as politics
is concerned especially in the us
legalizing cannabis is oh my god i can't
believe you're bringing that up that's
insane
whereas everybody in the public is like
this has made sense for 30 years now it
should have happened right
30 years ago well they're at least
talking about it
the upside is a lot a lot of people are
interested in it
and nothing's set yet they haven't said
what they think it'll look like if
they're talking about just moving
cannabis from schedule one to schedule
three
if they're talking about descheduling it
off the um
narcotics list completely all of that
changes what's possible on the ground
where we interact with people
they could just move it to schedule from
schedule 1 to schedule 3
which would mean better access to
medical research
doctors would be potentially able to
actually conduct human trials
so we could give people better dosages
develop better designer drugs to treat
different ailments
but it wouldn't really allow for the
anybody can grow cannabis and sell it to
their friend without incurring
the wrath of the local police department
um type legalization that we all know
should exist
that was going to be it should be like
tomatoes kind of guy
right like a little it should be kept a
little secure than tomatoes because like
if an animal or a human gets into it
like it can lead to some problems
especially if it's like a kid or a dog
or whatever but yeah
um and that's less true with tomatoes
like is all so like just put a better
fence around it to keep
little kids and dogs out of it but
that's probably not going to happen
politically at least not anytime
soon i think the best we can hope for
is a system kind of like colorado's
where it's a little too
expensive to get in and it's much more
restrictive than it should be but
it's a hell of a lot better than
everything that's come before right
just stop arresting people for having
cannabis in a lot of places would be a
huge step
start letting people out of prison would
be a huge step then let us grow our own
medicine would be huge
the numbers are astronomical i mean
we're still arresting
like half a million or more people a
year for cannabis crimes
and that's like growing moving
consuming distributing
basic [ __ ] with any product it's how
we've been living for the last
20 years how many law enforcement still
how many law enforcement hours were
required to make those that many
yeah what could those cops be doing with
that many hours that's a different
episode but still
i did the math in colorado it worked out
to like
entire years so like a whole cop's
career
you could dedicate to other stuff like
the numbers get really big
really fast when you start doing the all
right it's two hours per arrest and
we did 750 000 arrests this year
the that's a million and a half cop
hours
and then you add in the cop the court
the detention officer the parole officer
the urine test people
the money for all of that and what we
could have done with that
that would have helped us a lot more
right
like the when you start talking to
politicians that
aren't interested in legalization or
think it's a dumb idea
and you start presenting some of the
numbers you know well in our state
here's how many people we arrest and
here's how much that can cost us and
what if we use that money to
unfuck up the roads or build schools
or do drug treatment or
homeless outreach or cleaning buildings
[ __ ] crap yeah like it's sort of
endless the list of
needs that your area doesn't matter
where in the us
you are your area needs a lot of stuff
bad
and if you go to the city council
meetings or
um town halls you'll hear that
continuously
we here's the problem it's gonna cost 10
bucks to fix it
we only have three bucks only 80 cents
can go towards that problem
that's how everything goes and if you
can stand up and go i know a way that we
could bring
in 40 million dollars a year
everybody stops and goes how you like
pot
and they kind of giggle and go show me
the numbers yeah and you do and all of a
sudden you've got five people who are
against you this morning
arguing with you tonight yep yep how do
we get it going
which brings me back to write some
lettuce there we go
um your senators your house of
representative
members if you don't know who they are
you can google it really fast
um emailing them is super easy
um for example i could google john
hickenlooper
it would come up with his name it would
show me he's a senator for colorado
i click send him an email it opens up a
box i just type what i want and click
send hour and a half later i get a form
email back saying
the office has received your email we
appreciate your correspondence
maybe two weeks later you get an email
from a staffer that says
he's interested in this issue here's how
end of email it's sort of
arbitrary especially if it's just one
person doing it
but if 10 000 people all send an email
that's what they end up talking about at
every meeting
was your inbox flooded with people
emailing about federal legalization
again
yep what do they all want well they all
say we definitely have to let everybody
who's been arrested for
cannabis crimes go let them all out
just no parole no probation just i'm
sorry
so write those letters what everything
else we want you gonna interrupt
anything you want give me five things
that you want for your federal
legalization i'm gonna interrupt you and
just derail this and let's see what mike
wants five days
yeah oh first let everybody go everybody
you caught up and hassled over cannabis
let them go
um two make that not a probable cause
for [ __ ] all ever again
i never want to see another video or
have
an interaction with law enforcement that
starts getting escalated with
i detect the smell of cannabis or i
detect the smell of burning marijuana
like i just i never want to hear those
words ever again
um i want to see cannabis stores in all
50 states
um and i'd really really really
like some of the money to go to youth
programs okay
that's all cool i like that i can expect
i can respect all of that i'm in just a
good way to
just kind of ask you what you thought
federal would be awesome
i'm hoping like i'm really hoping places
like colorado that went overboard with
our rules and regs
dial them way back with federal
legalization
i'm like there's no reason we should
have a an eighth store cap across our
city
right or a full-on moratorium on new
cannabis businesses in the county
or 32 layers of paper packaging before i
could take a dab
yep or all the licensing
like some of that shit's necessary like
i don't want the extraction people
randomly blowing up a whole
seven people right like i don't want
that to happen a bunch of times and so
let's make sure the fire department
gets in there first and make sure
everything's safe and up to code and the
walls aren't [ __ ]
ply board and you know but
for the most part like
do i like tomatoes do it like craft
breweries
that's you know model i like it's like
craft beer
i i'd like to say it's cannabis is
a flower it's a medicine and it's an
intoxicant
and we sell flowers medicines and
intoxicants every [ __ ] day in every
city on every street corner
we can figure out a way to comfortably
just
produce and distribute cannabis we just
gotta stop pretending it's that hard and
just do it
we're pretty good at it here in colorado
mike you and i put a lot of cannabis out
uh allegedly before cannabis was doing
stuff a lot of our
alter egos may have allegedly had a lot
of cannabis happening and then we got in
the legal market and
exponentially multiplied the amount of
cannabis we're putting out there we
had a good time in the legal market the
gray market in the legal markets were
like when the period of time where
states were afraid to make rules
um people forget the history really fast
when
colorado was just medical
the feds were saying i dare you
to allow this i [ __ ] dare you
they were still raiding dispensaries
left and right with
federal agents where the dea would show
up and smash everything and take
everything
and some people would end up in jail for
the night and then nothing
because the the locals knew that they
couldn't get a jury to convict
and so the feds would just seize
everything and go away and it was
like getting robbed but you couldn't
call the cops because it was the federal
police that robbed you
yep um there was a lot of that there was
uh the cert or the drugs are the united
states saying he would take a doctor's
ability to prescribe
narcotics yeah if that doctor talked
not recommended not prescribed
just discussed with the patient
the use of cannabis for their ailment
just discussed
just [ __ ] talked about i'm sorry for
kirsten so watch this episode
face off dude i say [ __ ] a lot on my
show i'm on a roll and i've
really missed the show you keep rolling
i've got questions and i've abandoned
them
you're just doing your thing and i like
it let me just go out and smoke this
bowl
we're we really have a shot right now
and if everybody
is it's super easy all you got to do is
shoot off a couple emails you can do it
as stone as you'd like to be you can
include
i'd really like you to add this to the
legalization proposal or i'd really like
you to stay away from this
um anything you want just please email
your elected representative
state federal all of them especially if
you're still in a prohibition state
there's a lot of places where
cannabis is just as illegal as it was
when we were teenagers
and that's crazy it's 20 21.
the fact that some people can drive to
the corner store and grab
an ounce of herb and go home and other
people
can go to jail for decades
for having that ounce for sale it's just
insane okay
three grams of the finest concentrates
on the planet right here in front of me
and if we drove
uh 10 hours that way this would be
completely
completely a major crime and if
if you all start having these
discussions conversations with
elected representatives in your area and
you get any pushback
by all means send the show an email and
we'll do episodes on
oh they said this tell them that yeah
there we go
uh mike's robot that's my wheelhouse
that's what i love to do that's what i
did for a living for a long time before
covid made me a
a hermit all of us are hermits now bro
kova did that to us i know
some of us embraced it and made a video
podcast for our friends
this you definitely embraced it the new
studio space is amazing
there's a little aside y'all i got over
there to check it out recently and it's
fantastic thank you bro i want to put
another microphone on the other side
here as soon as we're allowed to play
together
i'll get another one of these joe rogan
mics his crazy ass wants to get me over
there in 4k
y'all i am not ready yeah you're ready
bro don't worry you look good right
there no one's going to say anything
and uh if they do no whatever let me
acknowledge them
this is the best part about the internet
man all the haters yeah
shout out to the haters you know who you
are all right mike
uh let's put the show back on track i do
have a bunch of questions
anything you want to just keep ranting
on do you want to keep going or do you
want me to try to throw away these
questions
when i apologize for cursing i sort of
lost the thread and then i took another
hit off this pen and now we're here
yeah i took a hit off my bowl here and
got lost as well that's why we're trying
to regroup now here
we go um so i know everything is up in
the air nothing has been solved there's
no
uh real [ __ ] rules there's not even a
proposal or a bill yet yeah as
that paranoid guy who has always been
like uh i
i liked the black market because i
thought when i knew that when
legalization came here in
colorado that it would be cool at first
and then it would be over
regulated man and that's the word we all
like to use it's just the paranoid
conspiracy theory [ __ ] wookiee that's
just straight up what we did that's an
accurate description of life in
colorado's cannabis market
well no i'm paranoid and do you think
that
i've got two questions here this could
go to uh do you think this will be the
lead to
like the dispensary taking over the
dispensaries and the grows and the
entire cannabis market and then that
will lead to
who we will consider the devil of
cannabis do you think that will be
monsanto getting in
to grow the cannabis for the government
that's my paranoia
um well the government already grows
cannabis they like the university of
mississippi
have you seen the [ __ ] that they grow
there dude that stuff is terrible yo you
uh people at the university of
mississippi if you would like some
lessons on how to grow quality campus
i've seen your gardens i've seen what
you do
but that's [ __ ] weak dude i can
absolutely step up your game
i wouldn't even charge you i just want
credit you paid for me to get there
i'll come increase your [ __ ] total
production
everything will be 70 percent better by
the time i leave i don't even want any
pay i want full credit maybe we'll do a
podcast maybe
run some cameras through that [ __ ] or
something just to show that i was there
you know what i mean that's all i just
want the credit
but just yeah sucks dude i may need to
bring mike as my uh backup guy to take
notes and help me out and [ __ ] he's my
handler because i've got this add issue
but
uh yeah you're gonna need someone like
me explain to the government you're not
to be arrested that's the truth
i gotta bring mike as my legal backup
but you guys hire me i'll help you out
all right mike let's keep going now the
government does grow weed but that [ __ ]
sucks and they need [ __ ] husbands
super bad it's it's so bad i almost
think it's a ploy like they have to keep
giving researchers dog
food because if they had real product
they would see the medical benefits like
the rest of us do
right um but they're straight up cutting
plants out of the ground and shoving
them through wood chippers and calling
that fine herb
um i know a shop that does that so i
wish
that was an exaggeration or hyperbole
um but uh
the major corporations will 100 percent
get involved they already are in canada
in a major way that's going to be my
next questions marlboro
is really a company
and uh they already have a substantial
investment in
canada um
i want to say it's budweiser it might be
a different beer of their tear though
i don't pay too much attention to canada
but canada marijuana investments
but the anti-cannabis crowd often
references these which is why i know it
is a talking point
but expect all of them to jump in
personally i'm not worried because i
know a couple things about cannabis that
they don't
one of those things is if you get the
thc percentage above
a certain point it will [ __ ] up a mass
production rolling machine like you will
not believe oh yeah
cannabis and tobacco are wildly
different plants
people that don't consume either assume
they're the same
with just slightly different effects as
a lover of both
they are wildly different and the
production and distribution
of them is also wildly different because
of that
hey that's a good time to interrupt you
and congratulate you on a year of being
cigarette free bro i didn't tell you
you're in some days age now but thank
you very much
i'm so proud i've made it this far with
zero tobacco no blunt wraps no
vape hits no nothing congrats bro good
job really that that does mean a lot to
a lot of people out there good job
um and if you're curious cannabis world
i can take way better hits yeah these
pens
i used to get like a tiny little your
drinks way too hot
level sip out of them and then i would
cough
like i was trying to cough up a lung it
was so bad
um i'd get ripped that way it would just
take 30 coughing fits
now i you see me on the show if you're
watching it on youtube
at the start of the show rip it
continuously he took a dab at the start
of the show and was able to recover
through the before i was done rambling
through the intro so that was impressive
used to turn colors and [ __ ]
different shades of purple
but yeah you can really feel
how it in the lungs the year off tobacco
for sure
congrats buddy i'm proud of you i really
am thank you i know we totally derailed
the show to congratulate you
stroke your ego a little bit there but
i'm proud of you and excited for you
this had to be a ramble cast i was gone
for too long we both knew it was gonna
go off the rails repeatedly anybody
still enjoying this
knew it was too and they're cheering
every time it does oh we've been going
for probably like
30-ish minutes or so they're still
listening and they they like it when we
ramble the dab at the beginning took
away my ability to judge time i can't
tell if we've been here for five minutes
or three hours
uh i've got so many timers and things
happening on so many different devices
here that it's ridiculous
yeah i was setting up for a podcast i
was like bye i got a camera there i got
a macbook and lights and the ipad and
there's just so many things for this
show
i'm not i forgot how to zoom i haven't
done a zoom show in a minute it was kind
of fun
all right mike i want to put it back on
the rails what are the chances of us
getting homegrows if they do federally
legalize cannabis or do you think
pretty good okay that's gonna that would
be something the feds would
almost 100 percent leave up to the
states that's cool
um and that's sort of what we want
in a good federal legalization is a lot
of
their answers to questions like that are
going i don't [ __ ] care let the
states choose
so um and so it's going to end up
looking kind of like the liquor market
if
if i had to predict where states like
utah are
much more conservative with who can
produce it who can ship it who can sell
it and
states like um
louisiana can be much more
liberal with who can grow it sell it
distribute it all of that
it just depends on where you are and
what the locals want
um personally i'd i'd really like to see
like the craft beer industry anybody
with like eight grand and some good
credit
can get started in the industry i'd love
to to it to be at that level
but like i really think it needs
inspections and [ __ ] i don't know how
many people that listen to this show
saw there was a big report on baby food
that just came out
and if you if you think oh baby food
like if you sell baby food if that's
your bread and butter like you really
give a [ __ ] about what's in your product
but they're big business so guess what
they care about money
and that's all they care about and it
turns out that they've been feeding kids
horrible things for a long time and
getting away with it
um because it's profitable to do so
and so if the baby food company is going
to put [ __ ] in their food and sell it to
you
the cannabis company is going to of
course yeah
and as much as i
i always pretended when it was the black
market that
oh yeah this dude's all organic like
it's totally hippie grown
and it was all just a marketing thing
that i was told by whoever happened to
be so good to me that time
um and it was a comforting lie that we
all liked to tell each other and believe
but it was always [ __ ]
like any time you went to the grocery
store and asked a question they were
like oh
spray this toxic [ __ ] on it and you'll
be fine yep no you don't
they don't even mention ppe i was gonna
say dude i went there was a grow store i
won't mention them but they recommended
me probably 20 different products sold
them to me 20 different times never once
told me
never tried to sell me gloves a mask a
respirator a tyvek suit never
just a bunch of different not only is
that wildly irresponsible that's just
shitty salesmanship
yeah like if it comes in a three-piece
set sell the three-piece set
so mike will this be uh legalization or
decriminalization
if there we get this federal movement
here totally up in the air still
okay um all right my guess is if it
moves forward at all
it will be a half step or a quarter step
like federal decriminalization
which honestly wouldn't be that bad if
the feds just said we're out of it
i'd really like the feds not to special
tax it
yeah they just did a regular tax level
on it they didn't add anything because
it was cannabis that'd be great
colorado went way heavy on the taxes
yeah
a lot of places went worse but it keeps
the black market thriving when you over
tax it it keeps the free market the free
market there's no taxes there
um one of my questions was and i know
this isn't going to happen like uh
you don't know what's going to happen
this is still up in the air but what do
you think uh
this will do for legal uh for a medical
and recreational weed
huge leaps forward okay will there still
be two different markets or do you think
it all just become
weed it'll be it'll end up evening out
um one of the things i really
really look forward to is there are a
bunch of people in my life that are like
plus and only a few of them were
cannabis friendly in their youth most of
them
it was literally a blockade
to financial stability
for a lot of them and so they just chose
to not to
pretend like it didn't exist from the
time they were 19 until they were in
their 60s and 70s
and a doctor brought it up and so
federal legalization is going to lead to
clinical trials that lead to them
getting
far superior medicines um
and that might just mean
go get a gummy that's five milligrams
thc
50 milligram cbd you know what i mean it
might not be
go get prozac or whatever the cannabis
drug name ends up being
marinol um is the terrible one now but
uh that's really exciting and so that
aspect of the medical market is
definitely going to stick around
i don't think it will be half separated
like it always has been here in colorado
where
um you have to get a med card to shop in
this particular market
i think the production and distribution
pieces will blend completely together
all right that's kind of what i prefer
having them separate here is just
silly and annoying it's a way to uh
the excuse was to make sure that the
patients got their medicine and that the
rest was available for recreational
users so they were always taken care of
but
it made a lot of sense and we didn't
we it's not like we're casting a magic
spell and just
starting from where we are it's first we
had
full prohibition and then we were
medical with no rules for a long time
and yeah
now we're here and we had to respect
that that process
happened as it advanced and so keeping
the two markets separate made a lot of
sense but
if it's legal in all 50 states to some
degree
having it separated like we do here in
colorado doesn't make a lot of sense
especially when a lot of the rules here
in colorado get re-examined
is right now their rules are wildly
different and that's why there's still a
medical market at all
uh yeah way different isn't it weird
yeah i'm currently without a medical
cannabis card i just i've been so busy i
haven't seen it it's just a show
i can get it i definitely haven't been
able to get to a doctor's appointment
like that
i can get in stores you can't get into
just because i've got this little
it's not even a paper now it's a [ __ ]
pdf on my phone so yeah
i've been playing with a lot of edibles
and i have to eat a
larger physical quantity of the product
to get the dosage i need
then you can medically it's just silly
yeah that hundred milligram limit at the
rec stores and eight grams of
concentrates is the limit so i can get
four edibles and four grams or eight
concentrates or
uh eight edibles but that's all i can i
know a lot of people are going well dude
that's a lot of [ __ ] yeah but
what if i just want to go once a week
then that's that's my weekly allowance
and then if anybody comes over and
you come dab the limits at all i think
are going away
because the limits aren't there
for any logical reason once it's
cannabis is legal in all 50 states and
available in all 50 states
right like the limits meant to keeping
you from buying 100
of everything and taking them to
arkansas and selling them
yeah if there's already stores in
arkansas that have the same [ __ ] on the
shelf for roughly the same price that's
not a job anymore
and so the rules that make that job
harder
can all go away um i'd like them to keep
some of the rules because a lot of them
are good some of them make sense
if you look at the um
robbery data at least this was true it's
probably still true because the reasons
it was true before made a lot of sense i
just haven't checked in like the last
year and a half
but cannabis businesses get robbed way
less than like
banks gas stations liquor stores
um jc penney's and it's because
part of legalization was you have to put
cameras everywhere that have to be
everywhere there are so many when you
pull up to the store
it's like smile you're on high def
camera
yeah we've been able to uh yeah you can
look so if somebody's in the parking lot
smoking in the dispensary
parking lot they're smoking a cigarette
we can zoom in and see if it's a
cigarette or a joint we're able to look
very closely from just inside the store
just by zooming in to see what you're
smoking out there so be careful
don't get yourself or us in trouble
please yep and that's
like that rule is annoying as a
prospective business owner because the
infrastructure for that kind of system
is pricey
and it's an added cost to a new business
but
from the security standpoint and from uh
it really helped us push legalization
forward because colorado and washington
did [ __ ] like this and he kept the
robbery numbers down
yeah that seed to sale and all the
cameras and there's a security guard an
armed security guard at most
dispensaries
all the pieces matter um i think a lot
of the necessity for the armed security
guard is going to go away
part of the reason cannabis costs so
much is because it's not legal
everywhere
yes and the prohibition markup is
massive
yep and now that it's not illegal
there's no reason for it to be expensive
tomatoes aren't expensive because we
could just
have them grow them toss them at people
and i mean just like everything else
there's a price that
all the steak we can produce gets sold
at because it's reasonable and same
thing with cars and shoes and everything
else and
it's the same thing with cannabis it's
good there's gonna be a price
fluctuation that's wild for a while and
then it'll settle out
and that'll be you know the people that
produce cannabis
produce this much and the people that
consume consume this much and
this is how much money changes hands and
i think a lot of people are going to be
happy as [ __ ] with that system
i think a lot about existing i never
thought we would get here i'm kind of
blown away that the last couple months
have played out like they have
it's exciting dude it's been an exciting
time the past just everything going on
has been exciting
do you think we'll see surprises do you
think we'll see decline in sales in
legal states
because the other states will have it i
mean we're not going to sell as much
because
uh texas is coming to get it and
missouri won't be coming to get it
they're already legal now a lot of them
aren't going to produce it though okay
um it's sort of like everything else
there's a place
that grows oranges and a place that
grows pineapples and
places that are known for wine and
colorado
and oregon washington california
we've already got a foothold and like
good luck [ __ ] finding an affording
grow space in manhattan
yeah that's very true but for a really
reasonable price i can ship
container loads of cannabis to manhattan
and i bet my shipping price is lower
than your grow cost
all right and i think that's going to be
true in a lot of places
um i think a lot of cannabis is headed
outdoors
and i'm really excited about that
because one of the downsides to
legalization
was we finally got to see
the power consumption and like when
everybody moved into giant warehouses in
denver
they had been very closely monitoring
their power consumption
on a couple of green energy initiatives
and when legalization hit
and the building boom took place those
numbers
skyrocketed and it was funny because
nobody understood what was happening for
a minute because nobody really believed
the cannabis was
market was that big um it's funny the
dea has been telling people about it
every year since we were teenagers
but no one listened or no one really
understood the numbers
when you say stuff like 40 billion it's
so big people can't comprehend it
and so they just sort of nod along when
the number gets that big
but when you really do the math and
think about it it gets astronomical
quick
and it we blew how many transformers in
colorado blew up the next two years dude
how many blew up behind a cultivation
that we managed
oh excuse me i'm burping that's it i
need a dab burp um
it was just common for a while colorado
had to really increase its
infrastructure
um and improve our electrical grid
because
of all the extra demand and i'm
kind of excited to see a lot of that
move outdoors a lot of that moved to
greenhouses hoop houses
being around all of that electricity i
think i can feel it when i walk
toward the grow buildings that have 100
500 lights so there's 250
000 watts of flowering lights in there
plus what [ __ ]
30 60 90 120 tons of [ __ ] cooling on
the roof plus all the fans
uh plus all the moving [ __ ] watering
pumps and [ __ ] there's a lot you can
feel
i like to be able to feel the plant
energy a little bit when you walk in
there you don't feel that it all you
feel transformers and three-phase power
that's all you feel is hum the bigger
the bigger the grow gets like outside
cannabis
is a cleaner like it takes bad [ __ ] out
of the air and soil
and gives us back an awesome flower
but inside it you're you're totally
killing that
that benefit yeah but we can it's just
one of the downsides i also
think indoor herb tends to be a lot
better it's gonna save
you five points and crops and there's no
bird [ __ ] we didn't get hail rain snow
sleet bird [ __ ] yeah we didn't get all
that random [ __ ] on there but
uh john made the sun so the sun is uh
and we're all trying to mimic the sun
we're just trying to rebuild everything
inside that's already outside you hang a
light
that's gonna change where it's grown how
it's grown
um like there's major shock waves that
will go through the industry with
federal legalization
um talk for a long time i'm gonna take a
dab
this the the shock waves that i'm
thinking about didn't happen so much in
canada
because canada's frozen a lot of the
year and so they
their outdoor grocery season is specific
it's short
um indoors definitely the way to go here
in the states that's not true
um and there's a [ __ ] ton of farmland
that is
wrongly purposed um not to mention
cannabis is a very profitable crop
and so i'm guessing there'll be a lot of
farmers that
don't have any business getting into the
cannabis industry
just like they were here with business
owners that bought in without taking the
time to hire people that knew what they
were doing
oh we saw the hemp industry ruined
people's lives the past couple of years
doing the same game
yep um they forget that you have to
cultivate
a distribution market um for hemp
it's uh we're already wearing all the
hemp shirts we want
not to be a dick about it but uh
we need more products for the hemp
industry but with cannabis that market
is already
there the demand is already there and
the demand is growing
especially as more medical uses um get
discovered and more people get told hey
go try this for your ailments and the
stigma goes away and more people
are not as afraid and they're ready to
do it now they're
finding that as an alternative to the
other medicines we talked about earlier
they don't have to take the chemo
medicine their
other medicine the one medicine to make
some [ __ ] and the other medicine that
makes them
not [ __ ] the one that makes them pee and
they're the one that makes them not leak
you maybe stop taking one or three of
those like it cracks me up
i get like i'm my whole family knows
that this is
where i've chosen like this is the hill
i chose to die on a long time ago
and for a while like they chuckled and
then they were just like oh
like he could have been a banker and
been written super rich
right instead he did this and that's
weird um but he seems happy
and now like one by one they're shooting
me messages
like so i've got this thing and then
my doctor was like try some medical
cannabis and i don't know what he meant
by that he said sav what's a sav like
are
is it is it a strain or strand is what
you just say um but
i chuckled because it's happened to a
half dozen of them now
and that market is exploding
if you look at the marijuana use went
way up in colorado type articles
when you get into the numbers it's
the over 55 crowd that just retired from
a job that's randomly drug test or
threatened to for 30 years
and then their doctor said oh yeah that
that ailment sounds miserable
why don't you go smoke weed about it and
the symptoms will go away
and they tried it and now they're in
love with it
that's where the big increases are and
so when
that gets combined with
outdoor growing and all 50 states coming
online the last of them coming online
kind of at the same time
like those shock waves are going to
ripple for a while y'all
oh i love the uh i love the little old
lady that just discovered cannabis
she's like a cute old lady and she's
like my doctor showed me how to smoke
weed or told me to smoke weed
and so i bought some and like when i was
a bud tender and worked at the
dispensary those are my favorites
they're so enthusiastic about cannabis
and they're like kind of secretive about
it because they don't want their nephews
and uncles to know
but their [ __ ] nephews and uncles
shop at the same dispensary that they do
and they're all trying to like make sure
nobody knows and [ __ ]
it was just i loved those little old
ladies that were so enthusiastic and i
feel so much
better and i eat the edibles and i rub
it on my elbows and i give some to my
dog
i used to love those little old ladies
bro they were really one of my favorite
customers
i i always loved showing them around the
sales floor and like
oh you don't want to smoke it you can
eat it you don't want to eat it you can
rub it into your shoulder
yep um yeah we have it in an ice cream
like it was just fun to kind of take him
around
but i always my mind always goes back to
there was a documentary or
um i think it was a documentary where
they followed around it might have been
one of the sanjay gupta specials
a couple of patients that were trying
out medical cannabis for the first
time and one of them was like this 50s
or 60s
veteran i think navy vet and
he went to the dispensary and bought
like an eighth
and bought up a glass pipe i know where
you're going and went home
and sat down on the couch and like just
ripped a chunk off the top of the bud
and stuffed it in the pipe and then
tried to light it from underneath and
like
to cook it from underneath and kept
burning his hand
for three or four times and the whole
time i'm watching this i'm [ __ ]
horrified because
there's no way in hell that if that guy
hasn't been around cannabis
that much for real that the cameraman
statistically
if that guy was that clueless there's no
way the cameraman was
also that clueless it's just not
statistically possible you know the
camera dude's not supposed to get
involved and that dude was uh that's how
you smoke
other drugs bro the way that guy was
lighting that so he's been wrong
before yeah um was kind of my guess
but if you've been around something that
you consumed that way
how the [ __ ] do you not know how to hit
a bowl of weed
right like how is that possible i've
seen that documentary and i laughed at
that too and i was like that guy does
other drugs that's what i do
like his fourth hit he gets it right um
and my guess was
that they showed the lighting of the
pipe from underneath and a couple of
anti-drug images um
but uh oh yeah yeah when older people
would come in
i would always sort of like so what's
your familiarity level with the plant
like please tell me so that i know who
i'm dealing with that i can
appropriately educate you so that you
don't hurt yourself or someone else
like don't burn your hand or
eat two chocolate bars and get behind
the wheel
yeah or try to just do anything after
two of those chocolate bars
all right mike i do need to start
wrapping up the show here we've been
going for close to an hour but i've got
one more
question on my list of uh federal
legalization
topics here write your senators you guys
yes please do write your senators uh
right easy to find
write them again write them once a month
maybe once every two weeks and let them
know that you do support
the federal legalization of cannabis
let's do it uh be professional don't
curse don't use profanity
just kindly just politely let them know
hey my name is rasta jeff and i think
that we
are going to be like foreign
but mike my question for you is um
if we do have federal legalization of
cannabis does that mean
bro that we get to have cannabis events
again like if it's legal like beer does
that mean since we've got beer at the
fair
and there's bars on every corner oh man
come on i just want you to tell me yes
that one of these days we can go
on absolutely bad friends again
hopes and dreams yeah um colorado before
the pandemic was in the process
of discussion they're discussing rules
and regulations for
consumption clubs and had just
started issuing licenses and then
everybody
just hit a big red stop on all of that
because
it doesn't make sense to put to be
licensing
businesses where you can go consume
cannabis
with your friends if you can't go to
businesses or
be with your friends yeah um
they hit pause but it made sense like
there's other [ __ ] on their plate
and the way small businesses are right
now like can you imagine
just paying rent oh hell no until this
is over um for a business that hasn't
even had a chance to open yet
and won't until this is totally over
yeah it would be closed by now
yeah bankrupt yep
and apparently landlords still really
want their money for retail space which
is why everybody's closing so
um but i i'm desperate for it i'm i want
cannabis cups i want cushcons i want
indo expos
i want cannabis sections at county fairs
yeah
um i want i mean
everything's short of sign spinners i
want it all
yeah uh just like we have a ball there's
no reason we couldn't have it
just like we have a bar where we can go
see some shitty classic rock band on the
weekend right across the street and go
listen to somebody play [ __ ] mustang
sally and born to be wild
and drink [ __ ] liquor until we get
[ __ ] until we [ __ ] puke
why can't we go somewhere right across
the street and sit at a booth and
[ __ ] take a few dabs and listen to
some bob marley and some fish
like i think we should all be able to
have a good time does it have to be fish
well i'll let you play some 311 on the
jukebox too bro
it's uh just give me a cannabis
friendly space outside um
give me put up a roof deck that's what
they kept talking about in denver
because apparently i don't know if i
don't know if the listeners are aware
but if you see somebody smoking a joint
i guess it makes you high too i don't
know
but they seem really worried that it'd
be really good i would see people
smoking weed
so they were talking about doing
consumption at venues
open air on roof decks they kept saying
roof decks
which seems sort of nuts to me like do
you really want stoned people three
floors up
fenced in like maybe things [ __ ] through
and just let us be in the parking lot
for a minute i don't know
but but uh hopefully some of that
the nonsense goes away with federal
legislation that's my big hope
especially in places like colorado like
if i was in arkansas i would just be
tits up happy that
this was happening at all yeah because
otherwise it probably wasn't going to
happen in your neck of the woods for a
long time
um but if everybody else gets to why not
us too
this is going to be this yeah that's it
and even the very last state to legalize
get it right down the street why can't
we get it here i agree with it
had i prepared for this show more i
would have a list of all the places that
are talking about legalization in one
form or another but it's a
long list right now pretty much
everybody that's not in on it
yet is talking about it in a major way
the last two elections were shake-ups
and they shook up towards legalization
excellent keep shaking keep shaking it
i'm excited dude i hope we'll get
federal legalization that would help uh
a lot of things for a lot of people and
it'd make things a lot more fun than
when the
the vid is it's gonna be really funny
gaiden has to sign that law
like it'll be really funny if president
biden has to sign that law
for a lot of reasons i don't care i hope
he does
i hope he has to sign it real soon yeah
the sooner the better
all right mike let's start wrapping this
up i do need to get uh some liquid on
the throat here and start wrapping up
the podcast
why don't you tell people how they can
find you on social media and remind them
about your patreon
uh you can find me at on twitter at
nemopunk15 you can find me on
facebook at pueblo for sensible cannabis
laws
uh you can find me on patreon if you'd
like to support me in the show
at patreon.com forward slash white mike
thank you for having me back on but
hopefully we get to do this
much more often yeah dude this is great
your background looks good your mic
sounded beautiful uh you had a great
a lot of stuff to say tonight i didn't
have to say much i just sat back and let
you go some of my favorite shows
just chilling major upgrades happened in
my recording space while i was away
um electrical improvements gear was
purchased
yeah and uh i'm real comfortable right
now so
let's do this more often nice hell yeah
dude i'm down uh every
every we'll do this every wednesday no
i'm just kidding i wish we could do this
once a week that was good
all right i'm on your schedule you say
when i would be so happy if my life was
in a place where i could admit to like
a regular weeknight event anything
it'd be [ __ ] fantastic i promise you
that
one night a week you're gonna get thrown
up on i can almost guarantee you that in
your life that's my life
i can guarantee i thought it was gonna
be tonight it seemed like it was gonna
be that type of night tonight because i
had committed to trying to do this show
but i ducked the bunch i think nice good
work buddy good work
um uh where was i gonna go my patreon
that's what is next if you feel like
this episode was educational informative
or entertaining and you'd like to
support the show
uh all you'd like all you have to do is
visit www.www.patreon.com forward slash
grow from your heart
of course all the info is right there on
the screen do make sure to support mike
patreon.com forward slash white mike
help him out i get a lot of patreon love
send mike some patreon love as well um
also if you've got any uh corrections
comments questions or concerns i'd love
to hear from you
my email address is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com don't be shy let me know
what's on your mind
also check out the website
iriegenetics.com
all things grow from your heart all
things rasta jeff all things irie
genetics are there
at iregenetics.com you can grab that
cool hoodie that mike's wearing there's
a bunch of sweet ivory genetics gear
grow from your heart podcast gear
stickers a cool ass coffee mug
yeah there you go mike showing off the
shirt looking good on you you didn't
mess up your backdrop at all doing that
that's [ __ ] funny i'll edit that out
of the show don't worry we'll just put
me on the screen nobody'll know what
even happened
that was a great way to end the show all
right ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls pimps and hoes friends and foes
smokers growers clone cutters and pollen
chuckers
i want to thank you once again for
listening to the podcast we're going to
wrap this silly [ __ ] up
um who do i have a shout out for i want
to give a giant shout out to my friend
the kinecrat
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me