all right here we go welcome back
podcast world
i'm your host my friends call me rasta
jeff and this is episode
611 of the grow from your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to answer a
couple of grow questions before we get
there let's do a few shout outs to a few
members of the 710 club
of course the 710 club are the folks who
support us on patreon
at the seven dollar and ten cent a month
level or higher so with no further ado
let's start off with the big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to our friend colton bridge let's send a
thank you shout out to anthony a
let's send a big thank you shout out to
our friend bob let's send a thank you
shout out to dank groves
let's send a big shout out to jg let's
send a special thank you shout out to
bongstein bear
let's send a big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to single t
let's send a thank you shout out to
guido let's send a big thank you shout
out to noah n
let's send a big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shot it's a mr mean
green eight let's send a big thank you
shout out to 716 vibes
and last but certainly not least let's
send a big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out
to our friend gaiuty gross big thanks
and big shout out to everybody who
supports the show on patreon
if you are not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need will be
right there on the screen and you know i
did put a link in the show notes
and in the video description to make it
super easy for all of my
friends really you guys thank you for
all of the continued
patreon support i do appreciate that
where are we going to go from here let's
start off with talking about
leds big shout out to my friend keith at
black sale market
i have switched my own personal breeding
area
to all complete led lighting that's
right i am now running all
complete canon leds in all of my
personal grow spaces
and i am loving it the plants look
mostly happy we're going to talk about
that in a moment it is all grower error
the plants look mostly happy i'm seeing
a lot of robust growth in most areas of
the grow space
i am really satisfied the electricity
bill has gone down
the amount of cooling i need the amount
of ducting and ventilation i need has
gone down
so i am impressed and uh ecstatic with
my new
uh led lights my canon leds from black
sail market
big shout out to my friends at black
sail market check them out and use
coupon code roster jeff
uh that will help you out just a little
bit keith did not pay me for that
ad or anything i'm just giving him a
shout out because i do
love the lights the plants look great in
most areas
let me do a disclaimer i did [ __ ] up
there is an error in one part of my grow
area
i messed up i let the plants get a
little bit too tall
they got a little bit too close to that
led light guess what
they're starting to yellow up just a
little bit but it is a learning
experience i knew exactly what was
causing it
the plants just looked yellow and i was
like what is going on and then i thought
about it and i looked around and i said
they're just too close to the new light
that is the only variable in the room
so when we are learning to work with new
lights
we may want to keep them a little bit
higher that's something that i messed up
there is a learning curve
what i've done to uh fix that is just
turn down the lights they are 315 or 325
watts when you start
i simply cranked them down to 240 the
plants are recovering they're greening
back up they're looking good
i topped them just to get that main top
out of the way turn the lights down
hit them with a little foliar foliar
feet of base nutrients i put a little
uh push in there as well the plants are
back on track everybody looks happy but
there was a little bit of a learning
curve ah there are a few things to talk
about there
i love the led lights but if you're
going to use them make sure they are the
appropriate distance away
from your plants that's something we
should talk about also uh
don't be afraid to uh learn you guys i
made a mistake and my plants are kind of
yellowed out and i had to recover from
that but guess what
i learned that lesson i only have to
learn that once we're past
that where do we go from here um i have
seen a lot of people on social media
having a heartbreak over discovering
that their gigantic plants
are now males they put these big ass
plants into males and they are
heartbroken i keep seeing this on social
media
i talked about this in outdoor season uh
it was
kind of looked over and i realized that
people don't really go back and listen
to old episodes
so that one is gone people are not
listening to that anymore
so let's kind of talk about sexing our
cannabis plants
that way when you're growing these big
giant plants
you don't discover later on after
spending time
money energy nutrients uh whatever
you're putting into it you don't waste
all this time
money energy nutrients space space is
expensive on growing a male plant
a responsible farmer uh tests for sex
before
investing all of this time space energy
and money into a plant that we're going
to have to chop down
and throw away if you're a new grower
that can be really heartbreaking a lot
of times you just spent all of your
money
on new seeds on new equipment and now
you find out that that plant is a male
and you've grown it way too big there
are ways to prevent that
let's talk about how to quickly and uh
responsibly
find out if we are growing male or
female plants before we get them into
the grow space
uh if you spend a month vegging that
you've watered it
if you water it three times a week you
probably watered 12 times you put
nutrients in there
you spent time phd the water you've got
a light running for a month maybe two
months at this point
that's going to cost you money that soil
cost you money just having that space
wasted technically is costing you money
if that gross base is not producing
it is an expense at that time so if we
could find out if our plants are males
or females much more quickly
that would be beneficial one thing i
want to touch on that i did not write on
my notes here
is the quickest way to sex them is a sex
test we have science now
you can easily order these little cards
from a testing lab
you can rub a leaf onto the testing card
all you need is some of the juice from
the plant to transfer onto the card
you fold the card back up you mark that
plant plant number 9653
you mark the card 9653 and you mail that
card into the testing lab
they will tell you if that plant is a
male or a female that is
the quickest most efficient way to
identify male and female plants in your
grow
of course if the plant is male and
you're not looking to breed then you can
get rid of it at that point
you've only got female plants to work
with you've bought yourself more space
you're not going to waste time watering
that male plant that you didn't need
you're not going to up pot that thing
into a bigger plant
because this should happen when they're
in tiny pots either people say that cups
are for beer but
i know a lot of people i'm guilty of it
myself i grow in beer cups
i think beer cups are a great place for
little clones little starter plants
also in a commercial facility i use four
and six inch net pots
so little plants get them real tiny then
do the sex test on the card just rub
pull off a leaf rub it on there
send it in they will let you know in
just a couple of weeks
depending on how busy the lab is how far
away the lab is they'll let you know
very quickly
if you've got male or female plants that
is the quickest way
to determine if you've got male or
female plants it does cost you a little
bit of money
however if you've only got small space
and you're trying to go quickly maybe
that little bit of money is worth it
some people like to spend that money on
those things people allocate their money
for different ways if you've got the
funds go for it now
if you've only got one room and you were
trying to find the sex of your plant
how can you do that without disrupting
your grow too much
um one room one light here's what i
would do i would sprout some seeds
i would grow them they would be in they
would really be very tiny they would be
in beer cups they'd be in six inch net
pots i've said that before
no bigger than a one gallon pot at this
time i don't want to waste a lot of
space first of all i don't want to waste
a lot of
soil i don't want to waste a lot of
nutrients i don't want to waste a lot of
water i don't want to waste a lot of
light and electricity
i don't need to be wasteful here so i'm
going to pot a
like a 10 pack we'll just say we'll do a
10 pack of seeds i'm allowed to have 12
plants
so a 10 pack keeps me safe i'm going to
pop 10 seeds right
i'm going to veg them out until they are
6 or 8
ish inches tall then at that point i'm
going to put them
into 12 12 lighting i'm going to put
them into flour
right so i'm gonna let them grow for
maybe a week maybe two weeks then i'm
going to put them into flour
in about 7 10 maybe 14 days
these plants will definitely have shown
me if they are males or females
now at that point like i said earlier if
i'm not breeding i'm going to chop down
all the male plants i'm going to get
those out of the room
i'm going to take those little tiny six
inch net pots and i'm going to throw
that dirt away or recycle that dirt
whatever i choose to do
now i've only wasted a couple of six
inch net pots worth of space i've only
wasted two
maybe three or four or five weeks worth
of growth of light watering
air space air time real estate in the
grow i haven't wasted a whole bunch of
time and we didn't need two rooms
to determine the sex of these plants so
we're going to grow them until they are
big enough that we think they can
uh that's ready to flip them just two
weeks is good enough get them six
eight ten inches tall then flip them put
them on 12 12.
then once they've showed you their sex
we are going to put them back
on an 18-6 light cycle 18 on six hours
off or
if you really want to you can put them
on a 24-hour on and zero off light cycle
and they will go back into a vegetative
stage if you don't let them flower too
long
if you're good at identifying the sex as
soon as you see that sex
that sex part that male part that female
part that is when
you put them back into the vegetative
stage so that is a really quick way
to determine sex of your plants if
you've only got one room
if you have got two separate areas here
is
the most ideal way or another really
ideal way this is the way that i myself
personally
sex my plants in a commercial
environment i may pay for the lab
testing to have those sent in just
because
that saves us a lot of time the week
that it takes us to send and get that
test back
is well worth the two weeks that it
takes us to find out if they're males or
females in flower
so we'll just do the little the rub test
send them in that is very quick but
here's how i do it in my personal grow
if you've got a clone and a flower or
possibly two or three separate areas
available
this is how i would do it i would grow
the plants
i would get them into that six inch net
pot then as soon as they're big enough
maybe a one gallon pot
as soon as they are big enough to get
one maybe three clones i don't know how
good at cloning you are if you're a
really good cloner
take three clones if you're not good at
it one clone should be good and or if
you're really good at it i'm not sure
what i said i'm talking i don't have
much notes here so this is all freestyle
keep that in mind
um if you are super good at cloning take
one clone if you're not super good at it
take three that way you've got a backup
plan i like to take the top
when that plant starts to grow the main
top will shoot out that is your first
clone to take right there
so get a clone of that plant let it grow
a little bit more and get the two very
bottom branches as soon as
not the little shitty branches on the
bottom but the two main branches that
are big enough to take a clone off of
clone those off of there now you got
three clones in the cloner
now you've also got the original donor
plant we're going to call that the donor
plant at this time
these are all the same genetics it's all
the same thing you've got the mother
plant the donor plant
and three clones now you've got an
option you can
put the clone dome under a 12 12 light
and those plants will show you sex in 7
12 maybe 14 days at the very latest
you've got little tiny clones in a clone
dome
they're going to start showing you sex
now you can say you got to label your
clones
you got plant a plant b plant c you got
to label your clones a b and c
now if clone a shows you that it's
female plant a
is a female if clone b shows you that
it's a male you got to get rid of that
clone
and unless you're breeding plan on
chucking some pollen making some seeds
get rid of plant number b also so that
is a quick way you can put that tray of
clones
directly under 1212 lighting and it will
let you know
what is a male and female in there or
another option you can let those clones
root
let them develop roots pot them into
some medium if you want to go right into
beer cups or your six inch net pots or
four inch
square pots or one gallon pots however
you want to do it pot those bad dogs by
this time your other plants are getting
bigger you've still got that donor plant
the mother plant
hanging out in the veg room you've still
got that bad [ __ ] it may need to be up
potted do a three or five gallon pot by
now
it's getting bushy it's giving you a
couple of clones you may need to clean
up the bottom of it by now
so you've got these bigger plants and
you've got clones you can let the clones
root
and then you've got two options at this
point you can put those clones into dirt
and put them under 12 12 and have a
small crop you can let them veg a little
longer put them
under 1212 and have a small crop or if
you're sure they're all going to live
you've got
one of plant a one of plant b one of
plants c one of all of your plants if
you did a ten pack of seeds you got all
10 of them
you got a clone of all 10 in the cloner
you got all 10 of these big plants over
here
that's when you can decide to move those
bigger plants into the flower room
and keep those clones back as your
mother plants or your genetic preserve
if that's what you want to call it
that's your
your new nursery those will become your
new mother plants
some people really like to have that
plant that came from seed
as their keeper mother plant they want
that original plant that's sprouted from
the seed as their keeper other people
don't mind keeping a clone of it
as the keeper i don't see a problem
either way
the way that i do it i'll tell you how i
do it i cut the top i put that top in
the cloner
as soon as i see roots on that bad [ __ ]
i move the other plants into the
flowering room
they're going to flower it's going to
take them about 12 to 14 days to kick
into flower
it'll take about the same amount of time
for my clones over here to make roots
so by the time they're in flower they're
kicking out flowers they're pre-flowers
these plants are ready to go into their
beer cups or six inch net pots
now i've got a copy of everything that i
just moved into the flower room i've got
a fresh copy of it
now i know what the males and females
are because in a few days
these big plants in about 12 14 days
these big plants are going to show me
what are males and females
i'll chop down those bigger plants
they're not as big as some people
that'll let them go by now but now
i'll chop down those big plants crowd
all the others together and then i'll
get rid of those cups but that is the
way i do it i put the bigger ones into
the flower room because they're already
bigger they're already ready already why
am i going to wait
i don't insist on having that rooted
seed plant as the mother i use a clone
i use that clone will go into the mother
room it'll get bigger
i'll cut clones from it and then guess
what it goes into the flower room just
generation after generation
of cutting clones into the flower room
so sexting the way that i do it let me
recap
i pop my seeds i grow them as soon as
they're big enough to get a clone
i get a clone i put that pot that plant
now goes into a three gallon pot
i've probably got 10 of them now i move
all 10 of those into the flower room
i have my thing my cloner filled with 10
clones
these start to flower these start to
root i will know
in about 10 to 14 days if these are
males or females i'll pull the males and
i'll pull the corresponding clones
now these are in flower and i've got
more plants that are working as mother
slash veg plants to keep my cycles going
i'm already in flower with one batch and
i've already set up for veg
and mother plants for the next batch
that is the way that i do sexting let me
check my notes
i went really quickly and i didn't look
at the notes very much
run the clone run the big plant deciding
so deciding which one you want to run
and what to keep is your strategy but i
just told you which one i do
i put the big one into flour because
it's already ready already we've been
vegging it
uh hopefully you've been taking care of
it for the whole time that the other
clones have been rooting
so that's the way that the if you are
waiting for those clones to root that's
what i want to touch on if you're not
really good at cloning if you're not
super successful with your clones
maybe wait until these clones make roots
before you move these other plants into
the flower room
if you do it too early you can take
clones from plants that are early in the
flower but i don't recommend it it makes
some things go wonky
but uh just wait just hold off don't
move these into flour until these have
roots
is a good part of the strategy but that
big plant is already vegged out so
generally i will move that into the
flowering room a lot of people do prefer
like i said to keep that original seeded
plant as the mother plant
however i don't find it necessary
as long as your clone cutting technique
and clone care is good you'll still have
those solid genetics forever
you'll be able to move that original
seed in there you got your clones
put that clone into a pot a pot that cut
clones from that
repeat that cycle that's how you get a
nice perpetual grow going
all right taking a look at the notes i
think i covered everything
yes all right we covered all of that
that is how i sex my plants early
the reason for doing this like i said
earlier so you don't end up with a plant
that you have
scrogged out and done a bunch of work to
it for weeks and weeks and weeks and
then you find out that you've got a male
if you've got a scrog you've got a scrog
net all filled up when you cut out that
one plant out of that net you've got a
whole bunch of empty wasted space
you could have just found out if you had
males or females maybe it does slow you
down a little bit maybe it is an extra
step but these extra steps are what set
us up for success
we have to do these extra steps keep in
mind i say this a lot when i talk about
pheno hunting and sexing
this isn't the last run with these
genetics this is the very first run we
are learning here
also hopefully this is not your last
crop you're just learning here we're
going to get to run these plants
again and again and again and the more
you run them the more you're going to
get more comfortable with them
what do you do what are you what's your
job where do you go what do you do all
day
what's your hobby what's something that
to some people what is something you do
that would probably scare the [ __ ] out
of them
i've grown cannabis for let's not even
talk about how many years i've been
doing that some of them may be illegal
i've also been playing the drums since i
was a teenager i'm about to turn 42
years old i think
i got drums for my 14th birthday you do
the math there
something i could be really comfortable
at if we were at a club
and a rock and roll band said hey our
drummer just
cannot play i'm not even going to kill
the drummer in my mind i said our
drummer
see my mouth won't even let me say it in
my mind i was going to say our drummer
just died
and then they're like we need a drummer
that could play i just put my hands up
and go you got sticks bro is there
sticks in a drum set
i can fill in for that a lot of people
would just completely [ __ ] their pants
they're not comfortable walking up on
stage and going i'll do this what songs
are we going to play kind of hum the
song at me and we'll play it
like i have no problem doing that that's
that's cool that's something i'm fine
with but a lot of people
i say go get up on that stage and play
the drums they just start [ __ ] they
start sweating they get shaky they get
nervous
that is where i shine so you will be
that way in the grow room over time
grow a few crops read a lot about your
plants kill a few plants you're gonna
have to [ __ ] up a few plants to learn
how do you know their limits how do you
know what they can and cannot take if
you don't push a few of them to their
limits so
uh get in there and do it and then
you'll get as comfortable as i am in the
grow the reason i'm so comfortable
is because i've been doing it every
single day for longer than i should
admit
i talked about earlier on a podcast with
mike on the previous episode
we had a dispensary in 2008 i was
growing on a commercial level
in 2007 and 2008. that's how many plants
crops run cycles that's how long i've
been doing this so that's why i'm so
comfortable and you'll get there too
just get in the grow learn read pay
attention take notes be passionate
be mindful and have purpose anything
you're doing in that garden
have purpose for what you're doing don't
do it because
don't do it because rasta jeff said so
don't do it because somebody else on the
internet said so don't do it because
your brother's uncle's cousin did it and
got good results
be mindful be thoughtful have a strategy
know why and what you're doing and think
about whatever you do today in the
garden
isn't going to you'll see it today if
you get in there and do some silly [ __ ]
you may see it today but really you're
not going to see results
think about the results in 3 5 7 10
14 21 30 days from now think about what
it's going to do
to the top and bottom of the plant how
will it affect the overall
performance of the entire crop not just
this one plant is it good for the whole
[ __ ] grow room
pay attention to things like that have a
lot of forethought have some strategery
when you're in there playing around in
the grow yeah when you top the plants
you're going to see that today
if you drop a light on it and crush a
plant you'll see that today
full your feed you may not notice that
until the lights come on tomorrow or the
next light cycle
if you over fed some weird nutrient if
you didn't ph properly
that's slowly going to progress over
time that's why we take a lot of notes
and pay a lot of attention
but think about all of the [ __ ] you do
to your plants today
you may not notice any outcome for two
to three days so if you're going to do
several things to the plants maybe space
those out by a few days
so that you know what is working and
what is not working have some sort of
control
have some standard operating procedures
some sort of strategy here
that's what i'm talking about all right
i've got one more thing i want to talk
about before we start wrapping up this
podcast i did get quite chatty today
where are we going to go oh this
question is can i keep a femme
seed as a mother plant um yes the quick
answer to that is
yes i see that on the internet a lot
people are talking about feminized seeds
being
inferior to regular seeds people talk
about they are prone to hermaphroditism
that you can't keep them as a mother
plant my question is
why couldn't you keep a feminized seed
as a mother plant it grows just like a
regular seed
other than that plant not containing
that seed never hit
that seed that female plant never got
any male pollen there no male
chromosomes other than that male
chromosome
there's no difference uh than any other
seed
any other plant it's a female plant it's
a cannabis plant
a lot of my uh great crosses are made
from feminized seeds so you can
keep a mother plant of a femme seed and
the next question is can you breed with
the feminized mother plant
absolutely you can let's talk about
morning dew
morning dew the grateful dog was a
feminized seed i made a feminized plant
it was the grateful dog that grateful
dog gets pollinated by an arise male
the seeds that come from that are
morning dew
regular seeds that grateful dog plant
is kept as a mother plant i've got to
keep it perpetually if i want to cross
to it i've got a few things that i cross
to it
so it's got to stick around so i do keep
a mother it is a feminized seed
and i keep a mother of it constantly
that is one that is always in the garden
it's been there
uh since the uh we're not even going to
say how long that's been around
probably 2008-ish i think that's been in
the garden 2008 2009
that one's been around for quite a while
that exact version of it
um so yes you can keep a feminized seed
as a mother planet is no different than
all of your other plants
the only difference is it was a
feminized seed once it grows it is the
same
exact thing if it was done correctly
it's it works just like any other plant
the next part of that question was can i
breed to that feminized mother plant
yes absolutely um morning dew comes from
a feminized
female plant uh lemon sunrise comes
lemon jeffrey is feminized seeds right
lemon jeff is only available in femme
seeds because the golden goat is only
clone only so there's no male so i've
got to reverse it to make the lemon
jeffree
so lemon jeffree is only available in
femme seeds
you guys have noticed that i make lemon
sunrise regular seeds
that is the arise to the lemon jeffree
so that is a breeding project
of a feminized plant that is pollinated
by a regular male
and it just makes regular male female
seeds so
to wrap that up you absolutely can keep
a female
a feminized plant as a mother and you
can absolutely breed and outbreed
two feminized plants all right you guys
i think that was about 30 minutes i want
to thank you guys for hanging out with
me
if you feel like this episode was
educational informative and or
entertaining and you'd like to make a
financial contribution to the show
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need to
support the show will be right there on
the screen
once again i did include a link in the
show notes and the video description
to make it super easy for all of my
friends if you've got any questions
corrections comments or concerns
you know i would love to hear from you
my email address is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com don't be shy send me your
feedback let me know what you're
thinking
also oh excuse me if you heard that also
i do invite you to
visit the website iriegenetics.com
all things ire genetics all things grow
from your heart everything rosted jeff
is right there at iregenetics.com
there is a grow help tab on
iregenetics.com if you've got any
questions about your plants click on
that grow help tab we ask you a few
preliminary questions i guess you can
call them kind of screen you a little
bit
we added a tab where you can include a
photo so you ask your questions
i will look at the uh photos and answer
your questions
here on the podcast so make sure you
check out the grow help tab on my
website
at iregenetics.com
all right i think that is all i've got
for you i'll be back in just a couple of
days with fresh new content
i want to give a giant shout out to my
friend zackson starker and until next
time take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
you