all right welcome back podcast world i'm
your host my friends call me rasta jeff
and this is episode 612 of the grow from
your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to read a few
grow questions before we get there
let's do a few shout outs to a few
members of the 710 club
of course the 710 club are the folks who
support us on patreon
at the seven dollar and ten cent a month
level or higher
so with no further ado let's start off
with the big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to redbeard
and jackie daytona let's send a special
thank you shout out to tart and mike
and colin let's send a big thank you
shout out to ryan waters and black
hippie
let's send a special thank you shout out
to my good friend jessie gross
let's send a thank you shout out to a
longtime supporter gramps memel
let's send a thank you shout out to
levity love day and last but certainly
not least
let's send a big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to my friend
adhd grower big thanks and big shout out
to everybody who continues to support
the show on patreon
if you are not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need will be
right there on the screen and of course
there is a link in the show notes or the
video
description to make it nice and easy for
all of my friends who have got their
hands full
or need a reminder in the future ladies
and gentlemen welcome to the show
i am coming to you on a frosty cold
colorado evening
we have been seeing negative numbers in
the temperatures it is ridiculously cold
i hope you are warm
i hope you are safe i hope you have got
power wherever you are
a lot of places right now do not have
electricity people are freezing
people are cold people are hungry i hope
you're warm safe dry
all of the important [ __ ] most
importantly i hope you are smoking
something completely delicious i hope
your eyes are nice and red hope you're
having a wonderful
morning daytime nighttime evening time
whatever time it is wherever you are
i hope it's close to 7 10 or 4
20. i'm awful rambly in this episode
that may work out to your advantage
i wanted to talk about i walked into the
grow room uh just a couple of days ago
it was super [ __ ] cold
and i looked at the ceiling and i
thought is there a leak upstairs because
there were water bubbles all over my
ceiling it looked like i had a little
bit of
water coming down the wall uh on the
poly uh the panda film that's on the
floor
there was a little bit of water in one
corner i got real paranoid really
quickly i thought what the [ __ ] happened
where's all this water coming from
i turned off anything that made a lot of
noise and i listened for water running
there's no water running
it dawned on me that it's [ __ ]
negative 17 degrees outside and it's
75 degrees in that grow space uh there
might be some condensation forming in
some places i was a little bit freaked
out i've never seen that happen
in my grow space before i thought i had
a leak or a flood or some major [ __ ]
problems
turns out it was condensation all that
warmth and the outside cold air meeting
ah that is a potential for powdery
mildew that's a potential for some
problem so i did increase my airflow i
did increase the
uh the amount of air going out of that
room i'm really doing what i can but in
these temperatures and these times right
now this is crazy this is one of the
coldest winters
i can remember as a grower so shout out
to all the folks that have been
struggling and cold winter grows for a
long time
uh this is a good reminder to get your
plants up off the ground i've talked
about that before if you're in a cold
environment get your plants up off the
ground they don't want to be
sitting on that cold floor with water in
there that's going to make them not eat
not feed
not grow but not perform they're going
to be pissed off so
it's cold you guys that is what i'm
saying it's [ __ ] cold
uh adjust your grow room accordingly
make sure you're not getting
condensation make sure you're not
screwing up your grow
uh here in the winter time use that cold
to your advantage but don't cause
yourself any problems where else are we
gonna go from there
oh i want to give a giant
congratulations let me look directly
into the camera here
i want to give a giant congratulations
to two of my good friends
big congratulations to giant mike and
the dab and queen
on your marriage congratulations guys
i'm proud of you i'm excited for you i'm
happy for you
i don't know what else to say but shout
out to giant mike and the dabbing queen
on their marriage congratulations you
guys it's good to see two beautiful
people
attached uh you guys belong together
i've met you i've hung out with you
no doubt in my mind you two are meant to
be together uh congrats guys i hope that
goes well forever for the rest of all of
our lives for eternity
uh love you guys big respect can't wait
to see you and take some celebratory
dabs
whenever we're allowed i don't know how
long that's gonna be we may have to
break some rules guys this may be cause
for breaking some rules don't send me
hatemail don't send me email that's just
how [ __ ] goes we've been on lockdown for
a [ __ ] year you guys i want to take
some dabs with my friends don't get mad
at me for thinking about it
every man's got his fantasy also ah
so congrats to giant mike and the
dabbing queen on their marriage now let
me give a disclaimer
i said giant mike not white mike white
mike has been married for quite some
years
uh he's got a lovely wife i'm not going
to drop her name on here
but mike white mike that comes on the
show has been chained down for quite
some time he's got
a lovely wife two kids so uh congrats a
long time ago on your wedding buddy but
that's not the mic i'm talking about so
you guys don't send that mike
wedding congratulations that'll be
confusing he won't know what the [ __ ]
you're talking about but
uh shout out to white mike also shout
out to mrs
white mike i'm not gonna drop her name
on the show she probably would
appreciate that but
once again congrats to the official
giant mike and the deb and queen
on the marriage i told you i was
rambling you guys it's your fault
you showed up no it's not your fault i
took the dabs not you
where are we gonna go from here how do
we pull this [ __ ] out of the weeds
we go right to the email section uh this
part of the podcast is where i'm going
to answer grow questions these grow
questions came
from uh this one came from the grow help
tab on my website if you visit my
website iriegenetics.com
there's a spot where it says grow help
you can ask your grow questions
we ask a short list of preliminary
questions we ask you basic things like
what strain are you growing are you
growing indoors or outdoors what kind of
lights are you using
just a few things to give me some hints
at what can solve your problem
just it makes it easier for me it's like
going to the doctor they want to know
your blood pressure your heart rate your
temperature how much you weigh
a few basic questions before you even
see the doc just to give me a hint
this is like giving the doctor a few
couple of basic questions before we get
to see the patient
uh we're gonna jump right to that part
sorry i'm so rambly today you guys i
took some dabs
uh what did i dab it was bubblegum
tkd1000
and it [ __ ] worked um just because
some people ask what am i dabbing some
people don't care to hear it
this one came from that grow help tab if
you go to iregenetics.com click on the
grow help tab
fill out the little grow help tab it
will send you the part where you can ask
a question
this one came from our friend i put in
here name to use on the podcast they did
not answer that part so we're not going
to say their name
we're going to skip that the strain
they're growing is motor breath number
15. they're growing it indoors
under led lighting they're in the
vegetative stage of growth
they're about four weeks into veg
they're growing in cocoa
the last feed was at the time of this
email it was today february 10th
the ph of that feeding was 6.1 so far
we're doing
good i would have maybe gone up a little
higher on the ph but so far
so good uh p pm or ec of the last
feeding was 700 we're all in the right
ranges there
daytime temperature 68 to 70 you could
come up a little bit
but it's cold as [ __ ] i'm not mad at you
for being a little bit cold
uh it's cold as [ __ ] in my grove spaces
right now too can't do much about it but
plug in more lights
gonna run out of lights in space pretty
soon here nighttime temperatures 64 to
66 that is acceptable
relative humidity is sixty percent
nighttime 55 percent that's acceptable
within
acceptable range there uh where do we go
from here
uh the problem hey man i love your
content so this is my second grow first
grow had almost no issues
but on this one i'm having droopy fan
leave now droopy fan leaves can be a lot
of signs of a lot of different things
there is a picture included we'll i'll
add that here in just a moment
uh the droopy fan leaves are on the old
and new growth i'm growing
in the basement intense i know my temps
have been kind of cold
so that's an indicator right there but
i'm having trouble pinpointing this
issue i'm a legal caregiver so i'm
worried because my patients are
depending on me
to pump out the dank like i did last run
um it's your second grow and you're a
caregiver
you got a little bit of cart before the
horse syndrome there uh i would master
growing not master it but at least get
comfortable at it get really good at it
before you've got a lot of people
relying on you
i appreciate and respect what you're
doing but uh
get good at this before you get too many
people relying on you too much
that's none of my business i guess but
that's my advice as a as a caregiver
i've been a caregiver was a caregiver
since the beginning of the medical stuff
here in colorado
my advices get good before you get
people relying on you that way
you're never worried about your patients
anyway let me get back on track it says
my nutrients are house and garden
i'm also using recharge i'm definitely
not underwatering but i know i'm
watering less often
this run than last it's cold so they're
probably not drinking as much
i do have a picture here that's going to
give me some details and help me out
i hand water at 10 to 20 runoff when the
pots get light i have a 480 watt led
quantum board in each tent
with infinity t6 inline fans any help is
greatly
appreciated all right i've got the the
photo here in my laptop
i'm going to jump to that real quickly i
just have a lot going on here so i can
tell by looking at this photo that i'm
going to post
right about here in the video there are
several hints here as to what's going
wrong
in this photo the first thing that i can
see is that
if you look at the bottom in the little
catch tray the saucer in which the
pot is sitting there's quite a bit of
standing water in that pot
and the condition of that pot the outer
moisture here on the outside of the pot
the color of that runoff water inside of
that pot of the saucer
the condition of the saucer indicate to
me that this plant
sits in water too often so it's being
over watered
it's sitting in that over watering for
too long it's sitting in this water at
the bottom of the tray for too long
and it's cold basically you're putting
this plant's feet
maybe it's balls in cold water imagine
if i just sat you
let me fix my hat so you could see my
face here imagine if i just sat you
your feet your toes your balls in cold
water all day
long and just made you deal with it that
is kind of what you're doing to this
plant
so i think the main issue is that it is
simply over
watered the secondary issue that it's
sitting in that water for too long
your third issue which is just
compounding everything else is that that
cold water in which it is sitting
is cold you do have them up on those
little tiny risers
but that water is still getting cold
there's nothing to stop that water from
getting a little bit chilly
so they're unhappy with that water i'm
looking to see what else i can see by
your picture
i think if you got the temperature under
control in there and stopped over
watering i think that those plants would
be
less droopy in my opinion the main thing
causing this droop is over water
the second thing is they're sitting in
that stagnant water for too long
the third thing is they are probably a
little bit too cold that water's too
cold the plants are overall too cold
another reason which will lead to plants
doing a droop like this
however i don't think this is what's
happening here but this is a possibility
for other people with droopy leaves
sometimes
when your plants reach their daily light
integral they will
just take a break they'll just droop
their leaves down that means they've had
enough light daily light integral dli
like basically if you're at work and
you're done and you're tired and you
lean against the wall and you go
ah that's what the plants are doing
they've been working all day
they don't have a wall to lean against
they just go [ __ ] i'm tired they just
put their leaves down and they take a
little bit of a break
they're telling you i've had my daily
light integral
unless you want to keep me on so that i
don't flower you could possibly reduce
the light you could reduce the amount of
lumens i'm getting
you could do changes based on what
you're seeing on those plants but
what i think is happening here honestly
is it's a basic over water which is
compounding into multiple issues
because of the environment let me read
my notes make sure i didn't miss
anything on the notes
you do have lots of standing water it's
probably cold get them up off the floor
you do have those little tiny risers
that may be sufficient i don't know i
don't know how cold that floor is you
said you're in the basement in a tent
that floor may be getting colder than
you're anticipating you may want to
double or triple triple those little
risers maybe get another pot flip the
pot upside down put it on there
that may help you out honestly i think
the main issue
is the over water and the cold water
sitting in there
all right big thanks to my friend who
did not include their name i do
appreciate the content
let me know how it goes when you dry
those plants out a little bit and one
recommendation i can make while i'm
thinking about it
you seem to be over watering your plants
i've done a podcast episode
called water tech one through five i
don't recall the episode number right
off the top of my head but
through the magic of technology i'll
drop that episode number right about
here
in the video that way you guys can watch
one through five water tech it's just an
audio podcast there's a video that goes
with it i think it's just my face or a
static screen
some sort of image it's an older show
but that will give you great advice
on how to water these plants without so
many issues uh and i would do something
about that standing water
you're getting 10 to 20 runoff but it's
just sitting in that tray
and that's not ideal i would maybe get a
shop vac and suck that out
or maybe i don't know you got to do
something about that standing water
shop vac is probably the ideal way if
you raise them up off of something
uh up off the ground onto something you
can put a container underneath there
and with that plastic saucer that you're
using you can kind of push the edge of
it like your finger with your finger
and make like a spout like on a pitcher
like a t pitcher you could just make
that little corner
and the water will pour right out of
there into a vessel that you could slide
underneath but i would get the water out
of there
that would help you out one through five
water tech once again that episode
number should be right about
here-ish that'll help you out all right
i'm going to move on
to the next question in today's episode
this one
comes from our friend z nice and easy
and it says sir i've heard a bucket of
bro science
stating that taking clones from clones
from clones and so on
degrades the quality is this true
thanks and keep it up so what this
person is asking is
if i have got a plant and i cut a clone
of that plant
and i grow that plant that plant is now
going to become this hand for those who
are watching the video i've got this
plant
i cut this part off i've got two plants
now right
eventually this one's going to go away
and i've only got plant number two now i
guess we're gonna call it which is just
a clone of
plant number one so eventually i'm gonna
cut clones off of plant number two
and i'm gonna put plant number two in
the flower room i'm gonna use the clones
which are now clone number three and i'm
gonna keep those around i'll keep one as
a mom plant eventually i'll throw
some of those in the flower room some
more along the line i'll have to cut
clones off of number three and make
clone number four
and clone number three will get too
tired i'll need to refresh it
so in the long run if you do it
correctly
if you follow standard operating
procedures
if your donor plants do not get any
stress or overwhelming stress or
overwhelming diseases or overwhelming
pest
pressure in most cases you will not see
any change in those genetics it will be
the same plant you will not degrade the
quality on those genetics in any way
it will still be the same thing if you
follow standard operating procedures
and you use healthy donor plants and you
take clones properly
you transplant them and you care for
them in a proper manner they will not
degrade in any way
i recently got rid of my flow mother
plant
no offense to flow i just had grown that
i bred it to everything it was time for
that to be retired
uh as a colorado cannabis grower with
the personal grow i'm very limited to
the amount of plants i'm allowed to play
with
i've been growing flow since 2007.
i think in 2019 or 2020
i finally decided to let it go so i had
that plant
for over 10 years over 10 years and the
only way i could do that
was by cutting a clone of it every time
that bigger plant got tired got ugly got
out of shape
i just cut a clone of that get that
clone root it get that going
i probably went through 20 different
clone generations of that flow plant big
shout out to my friends at metamar for
getting me that clone
that came there's rumor that that came
from
ed rosenthal through tom sexton then to
me
i don't know if i should have said all
those names but that's the rumor so that
clone
that i went from dj short to ed
rosenthal to tom to myself
is the rumor where that clone went it
got spread all over colorado i wasn't
the only one with it but
it was a great cut i kept it from 2007
i bred everything to it uh i cloned it a
bunch of times
so i got it from that person i bred to
it i grew i just keep repeating the same
[ __ ] but i had it for 10 years finally i
got tired of it everything smelled like
flow in my life for a little while
i smoked it i consumed it i dabbed it
eventually you got to get rid of things
like i said a moment ago i'm a breeder
i'm in colorado i'm limited by plants i
wanted to make new things i wanted to
make
new creations unfortunately the flow
plant is one of the things that had to
go but
until then i kept that bad [ __ ] around
for over 10 years
by cutting a clone of it it moved with
me i moved to
two different houses with that plant i
had a plant
i had a crop of flow right i had a
mother plant and i had a crop of flow in
flower
and i thought should i gotta move when
this crop is over so i just cut a tray
of all of my mother plants
like ten of every mother plant in the
tray of clones put them in the car
moved set up the new grow space put
those new clones in their new home
and that's how the new clones got moved
to the new spot so that flow has
survived two
moves of different houses it's been
moved all around the country
so no in the long run the short answer
ah is
no there will not be any change if
things are done properly i need to
repeat that the mother plant needs to be
happy
there needs to be no uh viral pressure
no pest pressure no stress
uh just needs to be a healthy plant that
hasn't been worked out
and then you need to take clones
properly transplant them properly
then you should have quality copies of
copies of copies
if you do it correctly it's not like
multiplicity where they keep coming out
a little dumber
it's not like the copy machine where
they keep getting a little bit diluted
if you do it correctly they should come
out just fine let me adjust the irie
army beanie here it keeps crawling into
my eyes
trying to keep my face visible and be
professional
all right let's keep going we do have a
couple more minutes here on this podcast
episode
this question also came from the grow
help tab this one came from they want us
to use the name
nb shout out to my new friend nb thank
you for the great question
it says they are growing granddaddy
perps and
why east farms horchata there's a string
called horchata that sounds good
i like horchata they're growing at
indoors under led lighting the plants
are in veg
they're in a soilless mix i like these
details so far
they're using floraflex bloom one bloom
two the ec is 1.7 the ph is 6.4
daytime temperature 75 degrees nighttime
temperature 65 degrees
uh where are we relative humidity 40 day
and night
here is the part that says the problem
it says hello rosta jeff thank you for
your podcast i've learned
so much you're very welcome and thank
you for the great content you are
contributing to the show right now and i
appreciate that
it says i was running a 4x2 flower tint
while simultaneously
running a veg tent so we got a flower
tent and a veg tent
i decided to save on electricity and
bring the veg plants into the flower
tent for a few hours a day
so you're moving plants from one room to
another to save on electricity
are you really saving electricity by
cramming all of your plants into one
space those plants may
want the space you may be better off
just leaving them in the other room
after we see the problem you ran into we
determined you may be better off just
leaving them in the other room overall
but
um i understand you want to bring them
in there and use that space but
hopefully your flower spaces full all
that light is being used and you want to
give those plants the veg plants as much
light as they can get i don't know your
situation that's just my assumption
i would leave them where they are so
they can get all that light
anyway it goes on it says i just noticed
that one of the flowering plants
seems to be a hermaphrodite oh the
dreaded intersex plant those are always
a
[ __ ] scare it says i realize the
power strip had a small light bulb in it
thanks to your light leak episode i
realized i assumed that was the cause
that could definitely be the cause any
sort of light leak may do it
says am i in danger of pollinating the
vegging plants
the veg plants are all in week four they
spend two to three hours in a
flower tim i realize this was a mistake
should i pop some new seeds or wait
three months for more disappointing
results all right
i've got a very simple answer to this
one
the simple answer to this one is you
have nothing to worry about uh the
flowering plants in your tent i hope
nobody saw me spin on the microphone
just now
if you did i apologize i'm human [ __ ]
happens not even gonna edit that
if you've got other plants which are in
flower in that tent
the flowering plants are at risk of
being pollinated and having seeds in
them
the other plants which are somewhere
between
21 and about 35 days in flower those do
risk being pollinated maybe a little
later you won't get too many seeds
the pistils are shriveling up they're
not super pollinatable right now but
if they're at peak pollination times and
that hermaphrodite popped up
you may see some pollination on the
other plants which are in
flower you did not ask about flowering
plants what you asked about is are your
vegetative plants going to get seeded
the simple answer is no not at all
those plants have not reached sexual
maturity they are not putting out their
sex organs yet
the parts which they need to receive
pollen to produce seeds
are not even existent on those plants
yet so uh
no you do not have anything to worry
about those vegetative plants
will not receive pollen they will not be
pollinated you've got a long way to go
before you have to worry about that the
thing you should do
is make sure you deal with that
hermaphroditic plant in some way are you
going to get rid of it are you going to
pluck the nanners out
you're going to isolate it what's going
to happen with that freak of nature
then once that crop is done and that
herm is out of there you need to
thoroughly
clean that room make sure there's no
pollen in there water will deactivate
your pollen
get in there and just spray everything
maybe cover up the lights maybe hand
wipe the lights or something but
we got to get in there and get a lot of
water in the room and deactivate all of
the pollen that may have been released
so the short answer to your question is
you have nothing to worry about
because vegetative plants don't have the
appropriate parts to receive
pollen so no they will not get
pollinated the parts of your plants that
receive pollen
when you put them into flour and they
start making the dandelion parts the
little pistols the hairs
the stigmas that is where the pollen
lands that's what will get your plants
pregnant and get them seeded
so at this time you don't have anything
to worry about big shout out to my new
friend
nb i hope your granddaddy perp and your
horchata go well
i hope i answered your question if
you've got any more questions please
follow up love to help you out big shout
out all right where are we going from
there i've got a couple more messages
let's find this is the one
that i want a rat here all right this
one says what's up rosted jeff
i've got a quick question that i think
may be valuable to the listeners and
definitely to me
i've heard you mention on a few episodes
that you use salt based nutrients to
grow yes i do i mostly use new
millennium bottle nutrients
a lot of times i also use veg bloom
powdered nutrients
in the personal grow i use one mix and a
commercial grow i use another mix but
those are the main bases
yes salt based nutrients i'm a bottled
grower not the organic guy
it works better in a commercial
environment in my opinion
for what i'm doing for my budget for my
space
and also for training grotex
it's just easier to have bottles that i
can say put this many milliliters of
this at this day and this many mils
so i do use the bottled nutrients it
goes on to say
i'm assuming you are breeding everything
with those same
salt-based nutrients that is accurate
says is there any scientific evidence
that shows when breeding with salt-based
nutrients
there are any discrepancies in a future
grower using those seeds in super soil
without salt-based nutrients
um i have my seeds tested
excuse me i have my seeds tested in all
types of environments
in living soil and soil and hydroponics
and rock wool
and cocoa i have them ran organically
non-organically
i have them grown with love and grown
with abuse and i don't see
any difference in the organic to
non-organic production when it comes to
how viable that seed is they all
germinate well they all grow well
i haven't seen any difference in that to
tell you the honest truth
um the thing you're talking about is
called epigenetics
and that's in let me take a quick drink
here my voice is crackling you guys
don't want to hear that we're just going
to take a drink and deal with it on the
show
it's better than hearing that nonsense
excuse me for one moment
all right i'm freshened up now
let me start by saying i have no
qualifications or
uh i don't i am just talking out of my
ass right now but this is what i think
uh for that to be a factor we have to
think about what did the breeder
of these seeds before me do whoever made
the mother plant and the father plant
that i used what did they do
and then whoever made the mother plant
and the father plant of that one
what type of soil or soilless mix or
media did they use
because evolutionary things like this
aren't going to happen over
one cycle in my opinion i started this
by saying i don't know what the [ __ ] i'm
talking about but
as i think about it evolution isn't
gonna happen just by me
maybe it is i paul and chuck i do
breeding i'm changing things evolution
is happening
by me selecting things but i don't think
that i'm
imprinting the plant the seeds enough
with one cycle
in my breeding mix i don't think the
plant knows
it may know the plant knows i don't
think the seed knows
that i'm growing in salts and i don't
think it's going to make a difference
but
i could be completely wrong keep in mind
i said i started this by saying i don't
have the scientific
background the education on this topic i
know that it's epigenetics is what we're
talking about
but i think that it's going to take more
generations than just my one breeding
round
to really make a difference in that
topic
i wish i had more details and info on
that honestly i don't have that
education i haven't gone to school
i probably need some more deep science
than what i've got for that i kind of
i've got a lot of bro science people uh
people kind of diss me sometimes because
i obviously i'm not a college student i
don't do the college thing i'm not
educated from any
uh botanical school no horticultural
degree or anything like that what i've
got though
is a lot of experience i've been growing
since before i should admit it
i've been around a lot of plants i've
had a lot of crops i've grown in
commercial
private environments uh so i don't have
the schooling
to really talk about this sort of stuff
i could teach you about plants i could
spot a deficiency from across the room
i can tell you which branch needs to be
trellised a little bit more from
across a [ __ ] 75-foot grow space but
this is not really
um my area of expertise so i don't want
to talk too much out my ass
in my opinion though i think that this
would take more generations of breeding
so
if i bread a sub cool strain and
a let's pick somebody else that's a dna
genetic strain
subcool bread in super soil i don't know
what dna genetics
bred in so we got super soil on one side
we're just going to say
that i'm just making this up i don't
know what they did the dna genetics
bread and cocoa they're advanced guys
they're hip cats
they probably did breed in cocoa so now
we got one guy breeding in
super soil one guy breeding and cocoa we
got seeds that came from super soil
seeds that came from cocoa i grew those
i selected plants now i'm breeding those
in a soilless mix they've come from
three different
environments to tell you the truth
already plus like i said before what did
whoever sub cool got his seeds from or
whatever what were they bred from
so i don't think my one step is going to
do enough evolutionary uh
epigenetic evolutionary change to really
make any decision on if there will be a
difference on future grows in
different media that was a really long
way to say that but
i had a lot to say and it's my podcast
all right there is more to this it says
is this genetic
drift let me think about that ah no i
don't think that is the definition of
genetic drift
i've defined genetic drift on another
episode and that is not what it is
it says i hope this makes sense and is
not a stupid question
no not a stupid question at all great
question i wish i had more information
for you i wish i could answer this more
thoroughly
i'm sure in the comment section on
youtube somebody
will chime in with some brilliant [ __ ]
about this anytime
i am a little bit lost or make a little
bit of a mistake there are a lot of
brilliant friends of mine that gently
and politely remind me and update me and
give me information they educate me
which is
i do not feel uh any shame in being
educated
updated enlightened excuse me they sure
they will share all kinds of great
information with us so check out the
youtube comments
and somebody will have more to say about
this i'm sure
uh also while i'm thinking about it
shout out to my friend f1p
for the great update on f1 crosses good
information there i'd love to talk more
about that
all right it says i appreciate the high
quality info and the well-produced audio
you're a gem brother then they sign it
from dilly danks
hey dilly danks thank you for the great
question thank you for the compliments
and most importantly thank you for
listening to the grow from your heart
podcast if you ever have more questions
i'd love to help you out
hopefully i've got more info on your
next
question all right ladies and gentlemen
boys and girls pimps and hoes friends
and foes
smokers growers clone cutters pollen
chuckers
dreadheads and comb heads i hope
everybody out there had a great time
listening to episode
612 of the grow from your heart podcast
i had a good time doing this episode
felt like i'm getting really comfortable
behind the mic uh it's about time right
612 episodes i just got super stoned and
sat down and started talking
and it all worked out today thank you
guys for hanging out
um if you've got any questions
corrections comments or concerns i'd
love to hear from you
the email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com don't be shy
also don't forget about the grow help
tab on my website at iregenetics.com
if you feel like this episode was
educational informative and or
entertaining
and you would like to make a financial
contribution to the show once again all
you have to do is visit
forward www.patreon.com grow from your
heart all of the information you need
will be right there on the screen
and once again big fist bump big salute
big shout out to
everybody who supports the show on
patreon i truly do
appreciate all of the love all right you
guys that's all i've got for you for
this episode
i'll be back in just a couple of days
with fresh new content i want to give a
big shout out to our dear friend john
bendit
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
foreign