[Music]
welcome back podcast world i'm your host
my friends call me rasta jeff
and this is episode 613 of the grow from
your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to answer a
patreon question about dabbing
before we get there let's do a few shout
outs to a few members of the 710 club
of course the 710 club are the folks who
support us on patreon
at the 7 and 10 cent a month level or
higher so with no further ado let's
start off with the big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out
to girls grow too let's send a big thank
you to lefty and ned denver
let's send a thank you to adhd grower
and pack northwest dan
let's send a big thank you shout out to
caribou heart genetics at north north
terps
let's send a thank you shout out to the
bafsta let's send a big thank you to kes
burton let's send a special thank you
shout out to don't tread on me 420
and last but certainly not least let's
wrap it up with the big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out
to our friend captainmojo big thanks and
big shout out to everybody who supports
the show on patreon
if you are not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need will be
right there on the screen and i did
include a link in the show notes
and in the video description to make it
super easy for all of my friends
and really thank you guys for all of the
continued patreon support
most of this podcast episode does come
from patreon questions
so let's just jump right into it this
patreon member did ask to remain
anonymous
so this doesn't come from uh anybody
with a specific name
it says hey rosta jeff you only consume
dabs and i understand
does dabbing require oh and it says and
i understand so that makes more sense
that way it says
does dabbing require less cleanup and is
dabbing more expensive than smoking
flour
that's a great question if you do notice
on the show most of the live shows i'm
on most video feeds that i'm on i do
talk about dabbing i don't talk much
about smoking flour
i do prefer to smoke mostly dabs
i feel like to catch the buzz that i
need from smoking flour i would have to
just be smoking from the bong
all day long i don't have time for that
that's not super healthy for my lungs
i don't need to be consuming a bunch of
chlorophyll and green leafy matter
i can get everything i need in a big fat
dab if i take
about a dab every hour maybe every two
hours depends on what i'm doing that's
an ideal world you know if i'm hanging
out
doing work around here if i'm somewhere
else then you don't get to do dabs every
hour two hours maybe it's every four to
six
hours but in an ideal world i would just
have to take a dab every hour maybe
every two hours
as tour if i were smoking flowers i
would smoke until my throat was harsh my
voice was dry
my lungs were coughing up also i find
that smoking flour makes my eyes much
more red
than smoking concentrates so being a
podcaster being somebody who
works with other people uh teaching
people kind of
in a boss situation most of the time i
can't be
uh real scratchy voiced real coffee
lunged all the time real red-eyed and i
can't be
going to the car to take a bong rip
every [ __ ] 20 minutes
so we get a break about every two hours
in a real work environment so i pull a
big fat dab about every two hours
allegedly i don't know if i'm working
for you maybe i'm not smoking dabs wink
wink
uh but so you will notice that i do
prefer to smoke concentrates
over the flowers however i have been
smoking a lot of flowers lately i've got
some
great blue raspberry truffle flowers
that were grown by a friend i got some
good nepali girl flowers
i ran into some good double dose flowers
so i'm stocked up on good flowers right
now i've been rolling
uh king-sized joints joints the size of
my middle finger and
uh during the super bowl i didn't watch
the game i watched the tom
uh tom segura bert kreischer uh was the
companion to the super bowl i watched
that instead of watching the super bowl
but that day
smoked a big old giant joint during the
super bowl anyway i digress i'm rambling
you are correct i don't smoke a lot of
flour on camera on video
but i do smoke some flour if you watch
the video with mike and i that i
recently put up
i smoked a couple of bowls during that
video so i do smoke flower but the main
part of the question
uh is dabbing less cleanup i don't know
about that there is
uh i guess everything is sticky is the
bottom line when it comes to dabbing
you've got a jar of concentrates you
stick a little tool into that jar of
concentrates
now that tool is sticky you put that
into the banger
you put a carb cap on the banger now
you've got a sticky dabber and a sticky
banger
you got to set those down somewhere when
you put them down
that surface becomes sticky so a lot of
times my elbows and my hoodie sleeves
are sticky because the table and desk
around me
are perpetually [ __ ] sticky so
i don't know that it's cleaner and less
cleanup than smoking flowers there's no
ashtray which i prefer
i don't have to scrape out a bowl i
don't have to scrape my bong scrape my
pipe clean my pipe as often
uh dabbing doesn't make that black funky
residue the tarry like [ __ ]
but i don't know about cleaner
everything is [ __ ] sticky so
we use a slick mat to put down on the
table so that after you take a dab you
can put your tools on there
uh but then you got to clean that up
with alcohol if you were dabbing
uh what i used to call insert dabs or a
bucket dabs
you've got a thicker banger and you heat
that up you put your dab inside of
another bucket that looks like a thimble
and you drop that inside of that banger
so that you don't roast it kind of a
double boil or a sort of the idea there
but that way requires a whole another
setup of cleaning you need a thing of
alcohol and
you gotta clean it immediately or it
just gets too sticky so i don't know
about cleaner or less cleanup
everything is i keep saying everything
is [ __ ] sticky there was a point in
time
when i wanted to name the studio sticky
knob
studios it sounds a little bit obscene
which is right up my alley but the idea
was that everything
was [ __ ] sticky all my knobs my
computer gear the table
uh sticky table studios was an option i
just went with gfyh studio girl from
your heart studio
it works out quite well but everything
is sticky when you're dabbing so
um then it says is dabbing more
expensive than smoking
flour oh also another thing that i was
gonna say the rig
water isn't so bad compared to bong
water
if you cle if you keep your rig water
fairly clean it's not nearly as bad as
bong water
when you spill it a bunch of funky shits
not going to come spilling out
the rig water the water inside of your
rig if your rig is just dedicated to
smoking dabs
the water that pours out if you don't
get big chunks of reclaim and oil just
pouring out when you spill it
it won't smell as bad it may actually
smell kind of good sometimes when i
clean my rig i dump out the water
it smells like whatever the last few
dabs i took were and sometimes it's
really [ __ ] delicious so uh rig water
is not as bad as bong water if
you keep them separate if you're smoking
flowers and dabs through the same piece
that water is going to smell terrible
and you are a [ __ ] savage you need to
get i don't i can't say need i recommend
you would get two separate devices that
way you can enjoy the flavor and terps
of those dabs
and enjoy the essence of that flower
through two different pieces
that's a totally different podcast is
dabbing more expensive than smoking
flour
the initial setup to smoke dabs
could be can be a little bit expensive
there are some hurdles there to getting
into smoking flour
to smoking concentrates when you smoke
flour you get a bag of weed or now it's
a medicine jar filled with weed
and you need a pipe or some rolling
papers and a lighter and you're [ __ ]
smoking weed that's no
no problem then you get into the
accessories something to scrape it out
or an ashtray maybe you get a bong
something fancy to carry your pipe in
but it doesn't go too far from there
there's not too much fancy [ __ ] when it
comes to taking dabs there is a lot of
equipment
involved you need a banger uh you need a
rig you need a rig first of all and a
banger that's your first combo
uh the banger is what the dab goes into
you neither need like a banger a nail
ah there's something called a terp
slurper there's a honey bucket
there are all kinds of different
variable nails it's the piece that the
dab actually goes on to the piece that
gets heated
then you need a rig to put that onto
that's the part that you smoke through
it the water go
it goes through the water then it goes
up to your face the glass piece you
smoke through that is your rig
so you need a nail a banger a bucket a
rig
then you probably need a carb cap to cap
that banger your bucket
uh your turp slurper whatever you chose
to go with i just like a normal club
banger that's what i use uh then you're
probably going to need a torch to heat
that banger
so now you're looking at anywhere from a
hundred to
thousands thousands of dollars for a rig
we're going to talk about that in a
minute in a minute i do kind of have
some notes
so you need a rig a banger a torch a
carb cap you need a dabber you need
something to stick in the concentrates
and transfer the dab from the
concentrate to the banger
then you're going to need oh other
things that you're going to need q-tips
why do we need q-tips
after you take a dab that [ __ ] banger
is going to be filthy you're going to
want to clean it out i like to use a
q-tip just get in there and wipe it out
a little bit
then if you're super cool you need
something fancy you can't just throw the
q-tips on the table you need something
fancy to throw the q-tips in so you need
a
little fancy trash can for your q-tips
then also
you need a q-tip holder they can't just
come out of the [ __ ] plastic
container
you need matching glass q-tip holders
and q-tip trash cans that's something if
you're super cool if you're a heady boy
if you're hyped up
if you're going out in public and people
are gonna see you that's the [ __ ] you
gotta have we'll talk about that in a
minute then you need
that slick mat that i talked about a
minute ago something to set all your
sticky [ __ ] on then a lot of people like
to buy
some sort of a a mood mat a dab pad
something thick sort of like a mouse pad
they're
basically repurposed mouse pads made out
of that thin rubbery type stuff i don't
know what it is honestly
uh it's a mouse pad and they cut them
into you can get them cut into all kinds
of shapes every brand out there's got
their logo eventually you'll see the
roster jeff dab mat
the rig mat the rig pad the mood mat um
but that is to set your rig on so that
you don't have to set your expensive
thousand dollar rig back down on the
hardwood table
every time you take a dab you got that
soft little surface you don't hear tink
tink every time you set your rig down
just feels nice so there are a lot of
things to buy
to get into dabbing so once you're over
the entry hurdles
then it's not expensive per se to take
dabs it's no more expensive than smoking
flour once you're into it
like i said you can get yourself a cheap
rig for probably 75 to 100 bucks maybe a
little bit cheaper depending on where
you are but then they go all the way up
to thousands and thousands of dollars
there are rigs that i drool over
that are in the five and ten thousand
dollar price range
uh you can get a banger depends on where
you go where you are who you know what
store you shop at
probably about 30 to 50 bucks for a good
banger you can get them for 300 bucks
it's all about what you want to spend
the entry level 30 40
high quality [ __ ] three five maybe a
thousand dollars for a banger i know it
sounds ridiculous we're gonna talk about
that in a minute
a torch anywhere from 50 to 100 bucks
for a torch don't be afraid to spend 80
to 100
on a torch a dabber you could buy a lot
of different devices for a dabber
i take bigger dabs than most folks so i
use
i use a bigger dabber than most people
it's a happy daddy dabber
i think it's called the glob father
shout out to our friends at happy daddy
i don't think they're doing things
anymore but shout out
shout out to my buddy uh hope you're
well buddy
uh anyway we're not gonna go too far
into that then you need a carb cap a
carb cap can be anywhere you can get a
clear one
for like 20 bucks or you can get a fancy
one like i keep saying
three five maybe seven or nine hundred
maybe a thousand dollars if you want a
mother ship carb cap they could be 2 500
bucks
uh they're not even called card caps
they got their own special name
uh so things can be cheap things can get
really expensive a dab mat can be
anywhere from 30 to 100 bucks q-tips
get the q-tips don't buy normal q-tips
to clean your dab rig they're going to
melt in the banger if you're trying to
clean it if that oil is still hot
get glob mobs glob mops something like
that
something that's kind of aimed for the
dabbers they're a little bit thicker a
little more industrial strength i think
they're honestly made
uh for the cosmetic industry that's not
my alley
uh but get the better q-tips uh then
that q-tip holder bro you got to get a
fancy head eq tip holder
then um let's talk about the prices
of dabs versus flour once you've got all
that gear the prices aren't too far
apart
buying like an eighth of flower versus i
don't know where you live i don't know
what [ __ ] costs where you are honestly
um here right now in colorado you can
get an ounce of weed for anywhere
between 90 to 240 bucks
uh the quality will vary based on your
price just like you should expect the 90
ounce looks like a 90 ounce the 240
looks like a 240
ounce uh it's what you would expect here
in colorado
these grams depending on who you are
where you are one gram of this is my
uh concentrate of choice today the
garlic banger number nine from green dot
they don't pay me to say that they don't
advertise with me they don't i don't
uh we don't have any deals i pay cash
for this [ __ ] i am friends at the
dispensary i was actually
the first person to buy recreational
cannabis in this county
so i was from this dispensary the same
ownership
so i've got a little bit of a vip
friends and family discount that does
help me out not tremendously i'm not
complaining i do get a little bit of a
discount
it's like 10 percent which is it goes a
far away when you're buying 300 bucks
worth of concentrates but
um they don't advertise with me they
don't pay me it's just what i like i
love garlic terps this is a good brand
quality product
it's in my price point i think these are
40 or 45 dollars
without any discounts so you can get an
ounce
for about uh around you know 240 if you
want to get that top shelf [ __ ] if you
want to get some stuff that
is not you don't want to show it off on
instagram or anything it's going to be
like 80 90 maybe 100 bucks
a gram of top shelf concentrate 45 bucks
maybe
maybe you can find it for 35 somewhere
between 35 and 50 out the door is what
you should expect for a top shelf
concentrate
so i don't know about the price
difference because ah i would smoke
a lot of flour you would have to be
blowing a bong hit
in each ear while i take a bong hit
through my face
and maybe do bong hits through other
aurify at the same time
to get me nearly as high as i can get
off of one dab of this garlic banger
live batter so or it's uh actually this
one's full spectrum extract
it's got a real nice punch to it uh
crystals and sauce diamonds and sauce
so uh cost-effective it just kind of
depends on what you prefer
there are more affordable concentrates
just like there are more affordable
flours there are also
more expensive concentrates i just
prefer the green dot
and they don't pay me to say that i paid
cash for this today
that's what i chose to buy uh with my
own pocket money uh so
also tip your bud tinder when you're
buying [ __ ] you guys that [ __ ] tip
jar was not full enough today for how
many cars were in the parking lot
stuff that tip jar so is dabbing more
expensive than smoking flour
i don't think so if you are the type of
person
that likes to just have a pipe in your
hand have a bowl and just be puffing on
something all the time
maybe ah maybe the flour will get
expensive because
i like to take a dab and then maybe i
take a dab and then i
wait an hour maybe two hours for another
dab honestly i'll take two or three dabs
and then wait an hour or two for another
one but i'm just chilling i'm not
you know i like to have that pipe in my
hand i just carry my bowl around and hit
a bowl occasionally
it's nice to know that if you're just
sitting there watching a netflix video
or a youtube video you don't have to get
out the torch and
heat up the [ __ ] dab nail and do all
that work you could just pick up your
lighter pick up your ball
take a couple of quick puffs off the
bowl and just enhance the buzz that
you've already
got it kind of keeps it going keeps
riding it so if you're the kind of
person that likes to keep talking on
something
you may go through all of your
concentrates super quickly but if you're
the kind of person they can just take a
dab every hour a dab every two hours and
they're not gigantic dabs it could be
more
cost effective now i was joking earlier
about all of that fancy equipment why do
people have
three thousand dollar rigs why do people
buy custom-made torches why do people
buy
a thousand dollar carb cap what the [ __ ]
there's a thirty dollar carb cap sitting
right there on the shelf
why would i buy the one that's twelve
hundred dollars and [ __ ] purple and
faceted and has all kinds of different
colors
of glass in it they're both glass
they're going to do the same thing it
has become a cultural thing
to that's a way to flex to show off a
lot of people wear
chains a lot of people drive fast cars
some of us like to wear fancy shoes
a lot of people prefer to show off that
they're doing okay by
having a really fancy glass setup it's
something we do uh so a lot of us we do
it often
all day every day it's something we're
passionate about you can definitely say
i'm passionate about consuming cannabis
and consuming concentrates
so it only makes sense to have and in
rastafari we call it the chalice that's
my chalice that's part of my ceremony
part of my connection with the most i
job part of my connection with you
so why not have something that's ornate
and decorative and makes me smile when i
see it
so that's why a lot of people spend
extravagant extraordinary money
on a rig that is shaped like their
favorite cartoon character or that's got
their favorite color scheme or
is orange and has crazy spirals on it
and it's just the way that they like it
or maybe a lot of times it's just an
artist that they are buying from
is very well known and has a good
reputation uh just like if you wanted to
buy a really fancy painting from an
artist that's well known you're going to
pay extra money for it
if you want to buy a painting from me
it's a dollar because nobody knows who
the [ __ ] i am my paintings are cheap
so the glass game and art goes just like
that some people want to have nice [ __ ]
just to show you that they're doing okay
some people will
just save all their money for that one
real nice ornate
[ __ ] rig so that's what they've got
they got a nice rig a nice carb cap in
their smoke session their smoke ceremony
is top notch they're smoking the best
concentrates they can
through the best piece they can ah
that's just what a lot of people do
i myself i prefer a rig that is not
super ornate i've got a couple of rigs a
few rigs that are quite decorated
they've got
i've got one with a really stylish star
of david on the back i [ __ ] love
it however i'm afraid that i'm gonna
bump it on something and break that star
of david off i'm gonna pass it to a
buddy
and it's gonna get broken and i'm gonna
be heartbroken because it's beautiful
artwork which
that's what happens when you're using
glass but my favorite rig
is what i call functional scientific
glass
it has got a spot for your banger to go
it's got a down stem that splits off two
directions it percolates on two sides
it's a small rig that fits in the palm
of my hand with the mouthpiece that goes
straight to my
face that's what we call a side car and
then the mouthpiece is flared out like a
like a [ __ ] exhaust pipe or a trumpet
it doesn't have one of those
uh like a peepee shaped mouthpiece you
got to make a funky lip uh funky lip
shape to try to hit it
it's flared out and i really think that
i get a better dab because my mouth fits
better on it i don't have to make a
funky face
i take monstrous dabs compared to a lot
of people bigger dabs than you should
and with the smaller uh the peepee shape
and the phallic kind of shaped
mouthpieces
i get a lot of build up around my lips
when i take a dab of a fat dab of
concentrates with that flared mouthpiece
i don't get that effect because there's
more surface area for that dab to get
through i don't get all sticky lips so
ah that's some rants on why we buy
expensive rigs rig preferences
uh people just they're trying to flex a
lot of young kids a lot of
[ __ ] other folks are just saying hey
look i did all right one month or a
couple of months i saved up or
i just [ __ ] maxed out the credit card
and i got this rig i'm gonna set it on
the table and everyone's going to go ooh
ah then we're all going to dab out of it
we've got a really ornate
piece that we could be proud of also you
can support and show off one of your
favorite artists
so um dabbing prices versus flower
prices
that's debatable um you could buy topper
bottom shelf product i mean you can get
top shelf product or bottom shelf
product when it comes to dabs or when it
comes to flowers
i've seen people buy bottom shelf
concentrates and complain that that
store sell shitty product
if you go to any store and you buy the
bottom shelf [ __ ] expect bottom shelf
[ __ ]
if that's concentrates or flowers don't
complain about that also
um if you're buying pens pens can get a
little bit expensive the cartridges
are like 30 to 50 or something bucks
for a i think it's a half a gram it's
0.5 of whatever's in there it's a liquid
unit of measurement i don't remember
that measurement wasn't prepared for
that
those can get expensive quite quickly
however i love how discreet they are
if i were gonna be in a place where we
really aren't supposed to smoke or
consume products
i could just say i've got to go to the
bathroom and i can allegedly possibly
take
three to four good rips off of a pen one
in the hallway
two while i'm taking a piss and one in
the hallway on the way back
and i can get fairly ripped off of a pen
if you got to go to a concert you don't
want to take the dab torch or your
joints and [ __ ] into the concert
a couple of pens take those right on in
you can smoke with a pen so the pins are
semi-cost effective for what they are i
think they're great for their price if
you get a good battery and a good
cartridge that you can replace
uh they're cost effective for what they
are for their advantage if you're a
casual smoker
if you're not a heavy dabber those pins
will get you [ __ ] up i like to do
double pins i call it the double dragon
put a pin in each side of my mouth and
hit two pins at the same time so you get
a big fat cloud
that [ __ ] gets expensive also there is
wax
wax is cheap if you're buying a shatter
or wax
that [ __ ] should be like 15 maybe 12 15
maybe 22
a gram depending where you are that's
very affordable
there is also sho solventless honey oil
that shits anywhere from 85 to 150
dollars a gram
if you want some of what they call percy
rosin personal rosin from some companies
will run you 150 dollars
per gram so it depends on how hard you
want to flex with your equipment
and your products if you want to buy
affordable stuff and just be satisfied
you can do that if you want to throw
your whole wallet and your whole [ __ ]
paycheck
at the dispensary and at the [ __ ]
glass store that is also
an option i'm going to take a sip of
this marvelous coconut pineapple juice
out of this beautiful grow from your
heart rig and then we will continue this
show sips tea
oh that is delicious and tropical and
refreshing all at the same time
so i think that covers up that part of
this episode let's move on to the next
part of this question
it says you hardly ever talk about what
you're dabbing on before the show
anymore is that by
choice uh there are a couple of reasons
that factored into that
politely i touched on this a moment ago
nobody pays me to advertise for their
product
nobody uh i get a little bit of a
discount from my friends at the
dispensary shout out to my friends at
the colorado cannabis exchange
they are actually the ones that hook me
up and give me good deals
none of the concentrate companies uh
reached out or replied when i talked
about doing a sponsorship deal or an
advertising deal
i said hey i'm smoking your [ __ ] on 600
podcasts would you like to work out a
deal maybe just
help me with concentrates or something
like that i didn't get a reaction
and um i just chose to if they're not
going to respond i'm not going to give
them a boost on every episode it just
seems fair that way
i still enjoy the concentrates i'm still
smoking them so that's my polite way of
saying uh nobody wanted to do an
advertising deal so they're not going to
get free advertising
uh maybe that's a capitalist attitude
but that is uh
advertising is expensive and they were
getting it for free to be quite honest
with you
so uh that is honestly i try to be
completely honest and transparent that
is a [ __ ] completely honest
answer part of why i stopped talking
about what i'm smoking because there's
always the same brand i just told you
who i enjoy
i like to smoke green dot labs i like
there i prefer their batter
the live batter is my favorite i will
smoke the full spectrum extract if
that's what you give me
ah but i prefer the batter so um also i
didn't think anybody really cared i got
a
couple of comments like hey bro nobody
cares what you're [ __ ] smoking can we
just move on with the podcast
and if people don't care what i'm
talking about then there's no sense in
talking about it so i just moved on with
the podcast
um yeah and i guess uh another thing i
was gonna mention
i've been taking less dabs i don't know
if you notice i clear my throat less on
the podcast my throat is less itchy
i feel like the show is better the show
has only been 25 to 32 minutes long
lately
because i don't spend [ __ ] six extra
minutes talking about dumb [ __ ] because
i'm too high
so uh in my opinion the show has been
better with less dabs i've been more
functional when i'm not dabbing
uh super hard before the show i used to
take like [ __ ] six dabs before the
show don't get me wrong i took two or
three fatty dabs tonight before i did
this podcast
but i didn't try to dab myself into a
[ __ ] coma like i used to do so
that is also part of why i don't talk
about why or what i'm dabbing so much
uh honest answer nobody's paying me for
the free advertising they've been
getting for multiple episodes
i didn't think anybody gave a [ __ ] and
i've been dabbing less i actually took
a couple of uh dabbing days off
i thought it would be good for me i went
to the doctor just for a regular checkup
i had a cold that lasted a couple of
days i went to go make sure that i was
okay during this season which we are in
you know
the dog's like nah you're young and
healthy we talked about the things i do
the doctor said are you addicted to
cannabis and i said i don't
think so the doctor said do me a favor
give me three days without cannabis and
i said i'll see your three days i'll
give you five
and the doc said game on i went three
days
and i was like that was easy i didn't
smoke a single dab i didn't eat any
edibles i'm [ __ ] living large i went
five days
and i was like this is a good time i
think i'm gonna try to go seven full
days without smoking
and i went seven full days without
smoking when i got to seven days i
decided let's go
ten days and there's just something in
my brain uh something in me clicked and
i was like well let's do 10 days and at
day 11
i was like 10 days was cool i can do 11.
and i thought the challenge was 3 i made
it 11 on day 12 i took a dab
and i got high you guys i was
high school high i had to chill out on
the couch for a couple of minutes i had
to regroup i had to recoup i had to
recover
i had to write my name down on a [ __ ]
piece of paper and keep looking at it
just to remember who the [ __ ] i was
it was a really good time so i realized
at that point when dabs weren't
affecting me like i could take
[ __ ] three fat dabs and do whatever
you needed done
if we're at work and you're like hey
corporate called we need you to talk to
him i could be hitting the dab rig and
blow out my dab and talk to corporate
you know what i mean i could talk to
whatever i could
do whatever i shouldn't talk about some
of the physical activities that i did
like
uh with machinery and driving equipment
and stuff but
allegedly i could still do all that [ __ ]
just fine which meant something after
i took 11 days off and took a dab that
nearly incapacitated me
maybe i was overdoing it maybe i was
just dabbing too hard
since i took my little break i feel like
i'm working back
up to where i was honestly so i took
another couple of day breaks and then i
would smoke for like a week and then
take a day or two off
now that i've been taking little breaks
i get much higher my buzz is much more
enjoyable it sticks around for a little
bit longer
it comes on a little bit stronger so
sometimes i'll blow out that dab and my
eyes get heavy and i'm like oh
[ __ ] i need a minute gotta grab onto the
table and make sure i don't float away
or something like that
but i think it was really advantageous
to take that little bit of a dab break
so i
was dabbing a little bit less is one of
the reasons why you didn't hear me
talking about what i'm dabbing on the
show i think it was good for me uh the
doctor said give me three days i was
like i'll see your three and give you
five
uh something in my brain like the
challenge i went 11 days without a dab
day 11 we got [ __ ] wrecked you guys
and then it taught me a lot about myself
it taught me that maybe i'm not smoking
medicinally maybe i'm not smoking
recreationally
maybe i'm just smoking [ __ ]
habitually it's not even about chasing
the buzz it's not even about feeling
good it's not even keeping myself
healthy
it's just when i'm sitting here editing
a podcast or writing a podcast or
watching a youtube video i got some time
to kill
what are you gonna do take a dab the the
hardest thing was after i would eat a
fat meal
was to not go take a big fat dab after i
ate because that's one of my favorite
things
do you finish up a meal put the dishes
in the sink clean yourself up
go take a fat drink or something to get
all that spicy out of your mouth because
i ate a lot of spicy food
chill out for a minute and then you look
at whoever you're with and you go
you're ready for some dabs and everybody
goes [ __ ] yeah and you're heading to
wherever you take dabs you go get the
rig and you take some dabs
i'm sure you got some sort of routine
like that that was the hardest part for
me
was not dabbing after every single
[ __ ] meal that i put in my face
i am running out of time but there are
more parts to this question let me keep
moving
um oh let me see it's on the next next
page here uh it says since
dabbing concentrates are sometimes as
high as 70
does that ruin your tolerance of smoking
flour at all or do you still get a buzz
like i mentioned before
tolerance breaks are key now yes i am
getting stoned again when i smoke flour
and i like to smoke flour because i'm a
breeder i'll breed some stuff i'll grow
it out then i get to select which
phenotype gets me the better buzz
that has a lot to do with what gets
selected for next breeding projects gets
moved forward with so
i like to smoke those flowers which
means i need to be able to feel the
effect taste the
aromas and flavors and enjoy that flower
to make good decisions with breeding so
uh what's the question again i got so
stoned i forgot uh do you still get a
buzz from smoking flower yes because i
do take tolerance breaks and it's a bit
of a different buzz i say that
a lot of times dabbing will make me bug
i got this beanie over my face right now
but dabbing makes me like woo i'm high
i'm so high
but smoking good flour makes my eyes
heavy and makes me like oh
i'm stoned and so in the evening in the
night time when i'm chilling out i like
to carry around that bowl and just hit
on a bowl or whatever
if you're doing shaving getting in the
shower editing a podcast i got the dab
rig and the bowl next to me so i can hit
that bowl smoke those flowers
get myself nice and chilled out nice and
mellow i like to be mellow
and i mentioned earlier i like that
comfort of just carrying a bowl around
with me
uh just having that bowl maybe it's
because i've been a pothead for [ __ ]
20 something 30 something years i guess
i just knowing that i've got that bowl
even if i'm not going to smoke it right
now
but just knowing that this is here
whenever i decide just to smoke this
bowl
i can just take a couple of puffs all i
got to do is put this one thing in my
pocket with this other thing in my
pocket and flick one and rub it on the
other one
i got a lighter i got a bowl we can be
stoned whenever we want to
that's just a nice so uh security
feeling it's like having a security
blanket right there in my pocket
i just pull it out get stoned whenever i
want to so
uh concentrates are as high as 70
percent some are like in the 80s bro
uh this one here 83 this one here
70.90 uh so we got some high ranking
concentrates this one is the bubblegum
t1000 uh this is the live batter
uh great tasting gummy nice and stoney
today that one and the garlic banger
have had me
in a nice buzz today all right i think
that is all i've got time for today you
guys actually have to wrap up i have
some other things that i have to do here
in the next
six minutes so if you feel like this
episode was educational informative and
or entertaining and you'd like to
support the show financially
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com
uh all the information you need will be
right there it's patreon.com forward
slash grow from your heart that's where
i got lost
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart all of the information you need to
support the show is right there on the
screen
once again big thank you for everybody
to everybody who supports the podcast
i truly do appreciate all of that
support every contribution means a lot
to me
if you've got any questions corrections
comments or concerns i would love to
hear from you
my email address is grow fromyourheart
hotmail.com
don't be shy send me an email reach out
also check out the website
iregenetics.com
you will find everything rasta jeff
everything i read genetics everything
grow from your heart
right there at iregenetics.com there is
a
vendor link you can find places to get
irie genetics
there's an irish store where you can
find these sweet irie army hoodies let
me move the microphone momentarily
what what brand new
what that's right and get these irie
army hoodies check out iregenetics.com
there's also a grow help
tab i'm sure you guys have heard me read
the grow help questions from the grow
help tab if you've listened to the show
before
there's a help tab we ask you a few
preliminary
screening questions about your plants
about your growth and we give you an
opportunity to ask a question about your
plants
you can even attach pictures then i will
find your message i will find your
photos and i will answer your question
here on the podcast sometimes i just
email you back if it's something quick
a lot of times i print it out we do it
right here on the show so check out the
website iriegenetics.com
get your merch get your irie genetics
get your grow questions answered
also sign up for the mailing list lots
of fun [ __ ] happening
on the website i'll say it one more time
so it sticks in your brain ire
genetics all right also follow us on
canadabuzz cannabis is a free
social media application you cannot buy
sell or trade cannabis on cannabis
but we do encourage you to post your
cannabis related content
that's right you can post all you guys
that are afraid to post your garden
photos or your dab videos
or your bong rip videos or your fresh
rosin squish videos
on instagram you can freely post that
on cannabis they will not we will not
take down your video we will not take
down your post
we will not chastise you uh we will not
treat you like a criminal
for enjoying supporting and endorsing
the cannabis plant that helps us all
so i invite you to join us on cannabis
it is a free application available on
your android or apple mobile device
simply go to whatever apple store you
use type in the word canna buzz
c-a-n-n-a-b-u-z-z
download the app log in create yourself
a username
check us out on cannabis join the
community catch the buzz i think you
will enjoy it
on cannabuzz all right that is all i've
got for you ladies and gentlemen you
know i'll be back in just a couple of
days with fresh new content
i want to give a giant shout out to my
friend smoke what and until next time
take a fat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you