welcome to the show podcast world
i'm your host my friends call me rasta
jeff and this is episode
614 of the grow from your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to answer a
couple of patreon questions
before we get there let's do a few shout
outs to a few members of the 710 club
of course the 710 club are the folks who
support us on patreon
at the seven dollar and ten cent a month
level or higher so let's start off with
the big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out to our friend frugal
rock
let's send a big thank you shout out to
the big sexy dink and brendan groves
grow man stan and craig compton
let's send a big thank you shout out to
the red eyed optimist and kanna reaper
dz from detroit let's send a special
thank you to ez057
let's send a big thank you shout out to
brian p and blackhawks fan
and let's wrap it up with the big grow
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out
to my friend just a smokin
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon
if you are not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need to
support the show will be right there on
the screen and of course i did include a
link
in the show notes and the video
description to make it nice and easy
for all of my friends before we jump
into the email portion of this show
i want to do a couple of shout outs to a
couple of special friends i owe a giant
shout out to my friends greybeard
lemur priest and stabby mcmotherfucking
stab wood
big thanks and big shout out to those
gentlemen and everybody else
who supports us on the discord channel i
will admit
i'm not on the discord channel very
often there's a lot going on on discord
uh it's a lot for my eyes to follow for
my brain to follow on on a phone screen
so i don't do discord as much as i
should i could be there more honestly
i'm not there often
but those three gentlemen i just
mentioned before they run the irie
genetics the irie army the grow from
your heart
basically everything rosta jeff involved
they run the discord channel for me
and they have recently done a few
upgrades several people have done
have given some financial contributions
to upgrade the discord server
thank you guys i appreciate that i will
be there more often if you're going to
make it fancy and special
i need to show up if you're going to do
that i need to be there i wanted to make
sure to stop and do a big shout out
to the gentleman who made it happen
greybeard lemur and stabby
and also excuse me also send
a big thank you to everybody who
contributed financially to the discord
and also a big thanks to everybody
who just hangs out joins uh mingles
whatever you do on discord
thank you for being there thank you for
being a part of the irie
genetics discord channel discord feed
discord link
whatever you hip kids want to call it
i'm glad you're there i'll be there more
often
all right let's quit rambling because i
can do that all damn night you guys know
that let's jump into the email portion
of this episode i've got a message here
from patreon
from a person who would rather not be
identified their question goes
just like this we'll jump right into it
with hey mr rosted jeff i got a mr rosta
jeff out of you that's great
uh this is my first attempt at growing
out a male plant
for pollen collection that is always a
fun project i love growing out male
plants
i love doing a male phenohunt when i'm
searching for a male plant to breed with
i will grow out packs of seeds
and i'll find the female out of there
just like you guys do but i will also
find
a stellar amazing keeper male out of
there i will flower out my male plants
uh sometimes i'll flower them out to
like week nine or ten just to see
exactly what they do i want to see what
the blood structure looks like
see how they react to some abuse some
problems some issues
check out aromas and flavors look for
colors see how things change over time
when i'm growing those males
i love to do a nice male fino hunt so
let's uh read more of this message it
says
it is my understanding that a male plant
will bloom just like a female
plant should cycle so i'm going to
switch to 1212 and
wait uh that is exactly what you need to
do the male plants work just like the
female plants they are photosynthetic
photosensitive just like the uh the
female plants it's the same plant you
just got boys and girls
so yes once you put them under 12 12
about 10 14 maybe 17 days later you will
definitely see that that plant is in
flower it will start producing pollen
uh you are collecting pollen right yeah
so you're going to
i would recommend that before you put it
into flour you have something in place
to start collecting the pollen maybe if
you've got a big piece of glass you can
set that
plant on put the pot right on a big
piece of glass and let the pollen rain
down on the glass that works
some people will take the pot and build
you take a paper plate
and cut a slit down the middle and then
you wrap that around the base of the
plant and the pollen will fall into the
paper plate
that depends on how big your plant is ah
i've used a 22 inch kick drum head
to collect pollen uh one time i did that
and all of the [ __ ] static
electricity on the kick drum head i'm a
drummer i got bass drum heads laying
around
i used the wrong damn drum head and all
the static made the pollen
uh move away from the drum head so as it
fell it did some weird static reaction
it all landed outside but
uh get creative on things you can
collect the pollen and start thinking
about that before you're into flower
you don't want to be moving that plant
around jostling it a bunch once it does
start dumping pollen
uh because then you'll really knock a
lot of pollen out of it it'll be easier
to collect if you just
already have your collection plan in
place so uh where do we go from there
switch it to 1212 and wait that's
absolutely what you do
it will start dropping pollen you'll
notice that like i said a moment ago
around day seven you'll start seeing sex
around day 10
it'll start making pollen sacks around
day 12 they'll start swelling
around day 14 through 17 they'll start
popping open possibly
by day 21 they'll definitely be popping
open and dropping pollen
they will continue to drop pollen for
several weeks
up to week 9 week 10 depending on your
life cycle
the vigor and health of your plant but
they will keep on going
that first pollen in my opinion is not
the most viable the most active pollen
you want that little bit later pollen
uh pre-pollen that's all i'm going to
say you can fill in the joke there
you want the viable active pollen that
comes out later
all right so the next part of the
question is when should i begin and end
my pollen collection
i've already said that you should have
your pollen collection devices
uh in place early so you've got your uh
your
your kick drum hedge your paper plate uh
your glass your mirror whatever you're
gonna collect that pollen on
if that is already in place you're going
to collect pollen as soon as it starts
falling
in my opinion some of the better pollen
is the later falling pollen so just let
it all fall
and you'll gather a little bit of the
pre pollen and you'll get a bunch of the
good pollen
all on your collection vessel there it
will all be great if you're going to do
a method where maybe you've got a
container and you use something to tap
the pollen into the container
i would wait until you see it really
drop in pollen it'll be
sprinkling a little bit and then you'll
see those male clusters they'll just go
kapow
you'll know you'll say well [ __ ] all the
male flowers look like they're opening
it it's time to collect that pollen
at that point get the main top of that
plant have whatever you're collecting it
into if it's a pie plate or a shoe box
or whatever you're using
and just tip that plant over and just
give it a little jostle and pollen will
go
all over the place you're going to get a
lot of pollen turn off the fans
don't have a lot of blowers going on uh
be wearing clothing that you can change
quickly or maybe minimal clothing
uh maybe just a t-shirt maybe no t-shirt
if you can head right to the shower if
you got some dreadlocks
have those things tied up the pollen uh
so you're gonna collect the pollen
tap that pollen into a container uh
where do we go i've got two directions i
want to go
the pollen is going to be very viable
and very potent
be careful when you go into your grow
room with your female plants
water will deactivate this pollen so if
you're going into your grow room spray
yourself
down with water change your clothes you
should be safe but maybe spray those
female plants in there before you as you
enter
spray them with the with the water that
way the water will deactivate
their pollen receivers and they won't
get pollinated
but water will mostly deactivate the
pollen if it comes in contact with it
you just have to make sure the water
contacts the pollen
talking about water you've got your
pollen in a collection vessel
we need to get all of the male flowers
and chunky male parts out
of that pollen i would start by
spreading it out as thin as you can
sometimes i use tweezers depending on
how much pollen i'm storing
i've also used different sifting
techniques i've used pantyhose on top of
a jar
i've used a flower sifter before get the
male parts out of the pollen is the main
part here and keep the pollen as dry as
you can keep it i said it a moment ago
water and moisture destroy pollen so
before you store your pollen airtight
into any container make sure that it is
completely 100 dry we want to dry this
[ __ ] out of it
i leave it sitting now i cover it with a
paper towel i'll leave the container
open it's just covered so that nothing
else gets into it
no wind will disrupt it but then all the
air can escape all the moisture can
escape once it is super crispy dry
i scrape it up with the credit card i
put it into a container with
a silicate packet you do not want the
thing you do not want
the the botanic the uh what's it called
i can't think of the humidity pack you
don't want the
the bovita that's the word my brain
wouldn't [ __ ] think of you don't want
a boveda pack
or a moisture pack you want a desiccant
pack that will suck out all of the
moisture you do not want
any moisture in your seeds once you've
got them sealed up
or dried then you can seal them up store
them in a cool dry dark place
that is how i would store the pollen so
let me make sure i'm answering the
questions put it on 12 12 yes it will
begin to flower
i'm going to switch to a 12 12 light
cycle and wait when should i begin and
end my pollen collection uh if you've
got your pie plates or your drum heads
in place it will begin collecting pollen
uh early uh that pollen will be viable i
just recommend that later pollen so
collect pollen for a period of time
and you'll have plenty of good pollen in
the mix there um
when should i end my pollen collection
once you've got enough uh if you're only
going to make a small batch of seeds you
only need
a small like a half a dram if you know
what a dram container is
a half a dram will create plenty of
seeds a full drum will make a lot of
seeds
any more than that you can really
pollinate the [ __ ] out of a room so
it just just depends on uh how many
seeds you want to make but let it go
uh maybe let it go like four or five
weeks into a drop in pollen if you can
and see the difference in the colors of
that early
pollen and the later pollen and watch it
change feel the dustiness
ah feel the grittiness it may change
from like baby powder to a more sandy
texture as the
the plants start dropping pollen later
in the game um
but then again make sure you clean
yourself up before you go in that girl
room if you've got grill plants and
flour because
that's when you do risk uh pollinating
plants you don't want pollinated
all right so i feel like i've answered
most of this uh when should i end my
pollen collection you've probably got
enough pollen
after like a week or so of collecting
pollen if you're gonna manually collect
it you could probably get it two or
three times it will keep reproducing
pollen
so you could tap it out collect it give
it four or five days tap it out collect
it
give it four or five days do it again or
just let it keep on growing there are a
lot of great methods for collecting
pollen
um it says surely the mail would be done
for my purposes well before say
week eight of a normal flowering cycle
yes ah they will be done
they could be done well before week
eight i save 14 days
to get in that's two weeks two weeks of
pollen collection another week just to
be fun
we're only at like five weeks total into
flower there so you could collect enough
pollen in that amount of time i may go a
little bit longer just to
just to have enough pollen because i do
larger pollinations than you're probably
doing
um i feel like i have rambled my way
through this question quite a bit i like
giving a lot of attention to the patreon
questions
i just feel like they deserve the extra
time and attention uh
let's see yeah i think i covered you bro
uh throw that [ __ ] in 12 12 and start
collecting pollen and then
have a strategy why did you select this
male
is it just the boy you've got sometimes
we do what we can do with what we've got
i understand but
did you select this male for a purpose
does he hold a trait that you desire to
pass on to your progeny
or does it just have a cool name that
you want to mix in with another name or
something i'm just curious why you've
chosen this male that is one of the most
important parts of breeding
then the second question why have you
selected the females with which you have
chosen to breed
i could just be because we are working
with what we've got but
is there some selection happening do you
think that this male will provide
something to this female structure
is this female lacking something the
male can fix is the female lacking
or the you know what i'm trying to say
bro is there a rhyme to your reason
are you just putting two people on a
date so they can sport [ __ ] or do you
have a breeding plan
in mind that is my main question as long
as it's well thought out
i think it will turn out very well then
the next fun part bro once you pollinate
all these plants you gotta finish them
out
then the real fun is cleaning the seeds
out of the weed
that's always a good time if you make as
many seeds as i do that'll take you a
minute then you get to grow out a bunch
of the seeds that you just made that is
so much fun
don't give out any of these seeds until
you've tested them out you've got to
grow them yourself
if you do give them to your friends make
sure they know that they're tester seeds
that you haven't grown them enough to
know if they're problematic
hermaphroditic
straight up mutants if they got terrible
germination ratios
if you got bad male to female ratios ah
if they throw bananas in week seven or
something
discover all of that stuff before you go
shipping them out to
your friends all right to my anonymous
friend who uh helps us out on patreon
thank you for all the support i do
appreciate seeing you pop up in the
message
if you've got any more questions please
do feel free to shoot them my way
on the patreon all right i've got a
couple more messages here in front of me
let's jump right to
uh let's do this one here this is going
to be a fun one this one
says uh do they want their name said oh
it's squirrel master and i learned where
a squirrel master came from
uh cool name super big shout out i like
that uh let's keep going it says i love
the show bro
keep it up i promise you i will bro 614
episodes
uh no reason to stop so i will keep
rocking and rolling thank you for the
encouragement
says i do have another question for you
i know in flower
most people do say that day one is when
they switch to 12 12. so
that is it says most people i'm going to
say that is the general
rule of thumb when it comes to growing
cannabis we switch to 12
12 that is day one of the flowering
cycle
a lot of people say do i wait until i
see pistols do i wait and tell
that no you are in control that is your
grow room you
decide that that is the day one of
flower the day
you flip that plant that light cycle to
12 12. so as a breeder
i'm putting on my packages these seeds
will take nine to 11 weeks to flower
that starts the day you flip the lights
that is what i'm talking about so
you should follow the guy who made the
seed packages and the standard that way
you should follow our advice in my
opinion
maybe i'm not the king or the authority
or something but i would recommend you
follow the breeders advice since we put
the recommendation on the seeds we made
yeah but then again uh a lot of breeders
i could be guilty of this too because of
phenotypes and grow rooms and [ __ ] but a
lot of people will tell you this will
finish in four weeks just so that you'll
buy it you know what i mean but
uh still try to take that breeders
recommendation and it does start on
the day you flip to 12 12. not when you
see pistols not when you see pre-flowers
not when the buds are setting not when
the trichomes pop up
it is the day you change the timer so i
know in flower most people say day one
is when we switch to 12 12. i'm gonna
say that that is when all people
should say uh that day one of flowers
but when does vegetative
growth start from what i've read it
seems like most people veg for about
four weeks
but what is officially day one of vag is
it the day the sprouts pop up out of the
ground
i would say that's the seedling stage
you have to go through seedling
then you go through veg actually i do
two different veg stages we'll touch on
that in a moment
or is it after two or three nodes grow
or when
also should day one of veg be the first
feeding or should i wait or have already
started feeding them thanks for your
help that's gonna play into part of what
i was talking about a second ago with
two different sizes of veg
so the seedling phase until you've got
like some true leaves
some real growth going on ah then i
would just say you're in a seedling
stage
once you've got a plant that you are uh
confident in that you think is uh so
it's just like taking home a little baby
when you take home a brand new baby for
that first week or so
you were just checking it just randomly
because it
you're it's not going to i don't mean to
scare anybody out there that's got a new
baby but
when you're a new parent you're just
checking on the baby is it breathing it
did it die
like you're just [ __ ] freaked out so
you're like that with a new baby plant
also right
once that like feeling of oh it's going
to live i've actually got this plant
i'm going to say that that's when you're
officially out of the seedling stage and
in a veg stage
for most people most people may live in
that [ __ ] freaked out isn't gonna
survive
stage the whole entire time excuse me
but once it's got its first set of true
leaves
uh not those little [ __ ] leaves that
grow little tiny ones not those little
weak ones that pop
out at first but that true set of
serrated leaves with all of the fingers
on it
that's when i'm gonna say you were
officially in veg now that is my opinion
uh i run a commercial grow i get to
decide when day one of veg is and when
seedling phase ends and when so another
thing i want to talk about is i run
two different veg phases so i start with
i generally don't start with the ceiling
in a commercial grow i'll start with the
clone
so let's just hypothetically say we go
from seedling phase that's probably
about two weeks or so
depending on your environment the type
of lights you're using
how vigorous your seeds are it's going
to be about two two and a half maybe
three weeks of seedling stage
then we're in what i would do is small
veg that's when i'm using either a four
inch nursery pot maybe a four or six
inch net pot those are my small veg
plants they get fed
a little bit lighter of a mix i'm more
focused on roots
and just establishing a plant getting
the root nice and healthy and getting it
going
i'm working on feeding at npk microbes
enzymes
uh mostly things uh to get like
lightning start and recharge things to
get those roots
really go and shebang then i transplant
into
a depending on where i'm at what i'm
doing sometimes a two sometimes a three
sometimes a five gallon pot at this
point i am in what i call large veg
so i've gone from my clone phase which
is a two week phase in the cloner
that goes into my four inch net pot or
my four inch nursery or my six inch net
pot
or i had my cloning phase which is just
about two weeks the same amount of time
as my
cloning phase that i say clone my
ceiling phase i'm not sure what i'm
saying i'm trying to say all this on the
fly i've got minimal notes you guys i
hope you know this is all coming out of
the top of my head
i've got a two-week either veg or
seedling phase then i go into a small
veg phase and a four or six inch maybe
an eight inch pot
then i go into my one three or five
gallon pot depending on
the environment the grow that i'm
working in the personal grow commercial
grow greenhouse grow depends on where
it's going
that is when i consider myself in large
veg
that's when i'll kind of refocus my
feeding regimen to go more toward
uh developing shoots and branches more
vegetative growth instead of focusing so
much on the roots
we're still feeding microbes we're still
feeding things to feed the roots
encourage root growth but i'm more
focused on getting nitrogen into the
plant
get it vigorous get it big get it happy
i start getting it shaped
for the flowering phase so um
i don't know that there is an official
uh day
when veg starts i say that it's when
those real true leaves pop
out and you've got a [ __ ] plant that
looks like a plant that you're not
paranoid you don't have a little newborn
that you're
cuddling in a little blanket that's when
i think we have actually got
plants that are entering the vegetative
phase uh so when they've got those first
real
fan leaves is when i say so the best
part about running your own commercial
grow
is that sort of stuff is up to you or
your own personal grow
that stuff is up to you you get to make
your own schedules your own cycles
your own flows your own standard
operating procedures
these plants are very versatile very
flexible ah
they are adaptable they can grow your
way you know there's no one way to grow
it as long as we give it a veg cycle and
a flowering cycle and we dry it and cure
it properly
most of the time we're going to come out
with a usable product it's all about
those details in the middle that dictate
quality but
there's no hard and fast rule set by day
one of veg is
this day unless you're in a commercial
environment and you've written that
sop and then you get to decide that day
one officially is this day
i keep saying it i think it's when those
true leaves first start popping out now
you can start feeding it before that you
can feed it very lightly before that
they've got enough energy to get them
going probably 14 days if you're going
to go a little bit longer before you put
it into a bigger pot or something
definitely feed it
give it a little bit of nitrogen focus
on building solid roots
something like lightning start maybe a
little bit of recharge in there or the
equivalent
is always a good idea maybe some mammoth
p just to make it go shebang and get it
started
but i don't know that there is an
official a book
a rule a referee that tells us when
official day one of veg
is so uh you get to kind of decide that
on your own
you guys excuse me for the throat
clearing i'm gonna just take a drink
here let's fix this right quick
once again i'm sipping on that uh
nudesense pineapple
and uh what is that pineapple and
coconut juice and it is divine
oh i could just chug that whole cup and
just one good fat drink there
all right my friend squirrel master i
hope i answered your question
uh like i said there's no hard fast rule
basically when you get your first
true leaves that is when you have
entered the vegetative
stage then you get to decide how long
you want to veg i do
about 14 days in the clone or seedling
stage uh
two to three maybe four weeks in a small
pot and then
uh like five to maybe six weeks in a
larger pot i got about
a nine week vegetative stage a nine week
flowering stage it works out real well
but it's kind of up to you all right i
feel like i got off on a long ramble on
that one
so let's jump into another email that
will keep me a little bit
more focused this one came from our
friend uh they want their name said
it says trolling nobody knows who
trolling is what up trolling and it's
not trolling with an
eye and it's trolling t-r-o-l-a-n a
little bit different than troll in
different type of vibe going on there no
trolling but all trolling
anyway the message goes hey rj i love
the podcast and the community
you are creating thank you i appreciate
that uh shout out to the irie army and
thank you for being a big part of that
community
it says easily one of the best and most
inviting cannabis communities
i've seen in the last six years of using
cannabis
for my service connected disabilities
hey i owe you a big thank you for your
service
ah thank you we do appreciate that it
goes on to say you've helped me grow
much better than before and i cannot
thank you enough you've earned my
support and
then some thank you that means a lot to
me i'm glad to help you out in the
garden hearing that i am making people's
gardens better
uh that's what i'm here for so that
means a lot and just hearing that
you guys recognize that we were kind of
forming a community here uh that the
irie genetics that the grow from your
heart podcast all the stuff i do is a
big part of a community
we've got a nice little crew the irie
army uh the other people that hang out
you guys are awesome so thank you and
thank you for noticing that i'm trying
to kind of
cultivate a little bit of a community
here i understand that ah
i accidentally became some kind of a
community leader i do my best to embrace
that role
it goes on to say i especially liked
your latest podcast talking about
cannabis education
i had a follow-up question i'm currently
going to school to change careers into
software engineering and
programming oh man that's that stuff
gives me a headache so i'm glad you are
doing it
it says i'll graduate in three years and
i'm increasingly drawn to the
agriculture
technology side of cannabis like grow
software and control
what or where would you recommend to
start getting involved in the nerdy
side of cultivation i'm currently in
northern california
but definitely curious of all of my
options i love seeing the quality of
your show increase with all the love
you're getting and deserve take care
from our friend trollin
hey trolling first of all thanks again
for the great compliments and i'm proud
of you for going to school
for software engineering and programming
that sounds intimidating to me
uh you'll graduate in three years it's
awesome that you've got a plan my friend
now you want to know where we can get
you in in the cannabis industry
the cannabis industry like all
horticulture all cultivation industries
are rapidly evolving um
i know you want to maybe do things like
uh some sort of cultivation
stuff like tracking or something like
that i really like what pete is doing
shout out to my buddy pete from p
l grow also shout out to pl grow systems
check out their updated website
uh big up to my friends at plgrow um
he does a thing where he can take photos
of plants with an infrared camera
and identify plant issues before the
human eye can even see it
he is developing a database of photos
that can help us identify
plant issues by just taking a picture of
our plant it'll say oh you've basically
got this
there are a lot of great technology
options in
the cannabis realm however what i think
is really practical
and that i think we are really lacking
in a lot of existing
and upcoming markets are opportunities
for
testing testing has become widely
popular in the markets where it is
available
but it's not available to everybody yet
in the cannabis industry
whether it's commercial personal growing
whatever if it's the caregiver model if
it's the commercial grow there's not
enough testing available
people can get if you run a commercial
cultivation you can get your product
tested for terpenes
uh for potency for mold for yeast for
contaminants for heavy metals but in
colorado if you've got a personal grow
you cannot get your product tested for
anything
so one of the first things i would like
to see is more available of testing part
of that reason is logistics and
legalities
they kind of [ __ ] blocked us on testing
here because of legalities but in new
markets you can work that into
the new recreational and medical rules
when you make that that you can have
a testing facility available for the
home grower that is something i think we
need
potency testing thc cbd cbn
cbg thcv and whatever new cannabinoid is
popular this week and by the time you
listen to this podcast
we should be testing for all of that
stuff everybody should have access to
that
also i think we should have access to
terpene testing we should be able to
test our flowers and concentrates for
terpenes
we should also be able to test them like
i said a moment ago for contaminants
mold mildew pathogens problems
also for pesticides and heavy metals i'd
like to see that sort of stuff widely
available maybe you could develop
something for the home grower
that they can do it at home maybe we can
submit a sample and a thing at home and
drop it off to you
and it's already just ready all you
gotta do is shake it or something you
guys could do your job really quickly
maybe you can offer something like that
um also a testing
for presence of cannabinoid precursors
all right i had to take a little drink
there i apologize for that let me jump
back right where i was
another thing we could use is the
testing labs that can show us the
presence of precursors for cannabinoids
it is very useful as a breeder
to be able to take a sample of plant
tissue send it to a lab
and they can tell me that these samples
of plants are high in cannabinoid
precursors
and this batch of plants isn't really
testing high in uh cannabinoid
precursors
we can remove the load testers from the
batch and we can actually do breeding
based on the predicative testing
from the presence of cannabinoid
precursors and move forward with those
high testing plants and not waste our
time with the low
testing plants if our goal is to breed
for high thc
so that's another lab i would love to
see another thing i would love to see is
something like
gene verification i don't know uh if
there's a market for this other than my
desire but
i would like to be able to i have
created some strains
so maybe i could send you a couple of
samples of a rise
maybe a couple of samples of strawberry
starburst maybe a morning do sample
and then you could take those samples
and gene sequence them
and put them in a database and have
standard samples of
real tested genetics that way we have a
real database of real tested genetics
there was another company doing it
i've looked a lot at what they have
posted it seems like a lot of their
genetics their database is a little bit
convoluted
there was no way to stop anybody from
sending a fake sample in there
i don't know uh how reliable that
database has become some of it is
questionable to me
but to do something that is a breeder
based gene
verification database would be really
cool in my opinion
like only the people that are breeding
these strains or people who have been
vetted or something
people with a reputation people that you
know and can rely on people that have
been vetted that's what i'm trying to
say people have been auditioned and
gone through an application process can
actually send you in tissue sample and
get these plants into a database that is
something i would love to see then
in the future if somebody's got a clone
in like five years and they're like bro
i got the grateful dog
you'd be like i don't know if you really
do just send a sample of it to you
and they'll go oh man you really do have
the grateful dog or you're full of [ __ ]
that is not the grateful dog that's
actually just
this you could actually tell them what
it is if you've got a sample of that
i know that sounds crazy that could be
just a dream but there's something in
there
that could be viable for all growers
some sort of gene
verification would be really cool now we
just got to be sure
not to let that get corrupted because
that's kind of what seems like happened
last time they were allowing random
samples in there the samples were just
convoluted the database got convoluted
then also the company
seemed to use our data the data they
collected for
uh unscrupulous activity maybe
uh the the definition of it i'm trying
to stay out all that right now and not
get political on that [ __ ] but
we could use a new company that does
that with better interests that's kind
of what i'm thinking i want to say
um in agriculture technology there are
so many people and so many things doing
agricultural technology that i think the
testing labs
are what i desire the most um tracking
is done well
seed to sell points are covered quite
well pesticide application and stuff is
done quite well
i'm not sure uh honestly as a guy
who's been growing uh before all this
technology took over
until it gets to giant scale cultivation
i think we need to get back to our roots
a little bit
and stop paying so much attention to the
meters and the technology don't get me
wrong in a big cultivation
i love all of the data that i can get
that is great for
uh the lead grower for upper management
for the consultants but as grotechs and
home growers
i think most of those folks need to get
away from all of the machines and
devices and watch the plants
i've been growing i don't need as many
devices
because i can look at the plants have
you ever seen a guitar player get up on
stage
and if he doesn't need a guitar tuner
doesn't he just look like that much more
of a badass
the guy that needs a guitar tuner you're
like oh you can't tune by ear bro come
on how long you've been doing this
i feel like i can tune the plants by ear
i can just look at them and i can say oh
this
because i haven't been relying on all
amazing impressive technology i do use
the technology to my advantage don't get
me wrong i love the gear i love the toys
they are great i use them second i find
too many growers using the equipment the
technology the toys the meters the
gadgets first
and they're always on their phone
checking to see what's wrong with their
grow
when i go put your phone away bro let's
go in the grow room and look at the
plants and see what is wrong with those
plants i use the plants first
as my first guide my judgment my
indicator
they're going to tell me what's wrong
before the meter
like maybe one day your meter will beep
and something will go bro it's too hot
in here
that's cool but most of the time i can
look at the plants and they go it's too
hot in here
it's too cold in here also have you ever
thought about just reaching
out and touching the plants if you think
it might be cold in the grow room it's a
cold season right now
if you think maybe the plants are cold
touch them just reach out and put your
hand on them
just touch them just like your mama used
to do and be like oh you need a sweater
you could do that to the plants just
touch the plants see if their cheeks are
cold
put your hands right around them they're
yours you could touch them you could
squeeze them violate them all you want
anyway i do love all the technology i
love seeing you guys advance all the
technology and the toys and stuff in the
grow environment
but let's not forget that we've been
growing these plants
way way way before we had all this
technology
some of the most amazing cannabis i've
seen grown came from just a very basic
archaic almost basement grow with lights
and fans and an air conditioner
and the dude that grew it at the time
had no idea that there was a way to set
all this [ __ ] up with the internet and
use all these monitors so
um i do appreciate your desire to uh be
in the agricultural technology side of
cannabis
i don't think i gave you uh the details
you want because you are in
the software engineering and you want to
do software and control and i
recommended testing
but honestly that is what i see is
needed the most right now at this time
a lot of the other stuff is well covered
there are so many companies
making uh vpd monitors and co2 monitors
and notification systems
uh tracking systems weight systems data
entry and data logging systems a lot of
that stuff
is taken up but we do need more labs in
my
opinion all right trolling i do want to
thank you for the great question i wish
i had a better answer for you
i do want to thank you once again for
your service i also want to wish you the
best of luck in your education
i hope you reach all of your goals in
the next three years then i hope the
next five to ten years are [ __ ]
amazing
uh because of the amazing education
you've got i hope you have a wonderful
amazing career ahead of you
thank you for the great message
everybody else that sent me a message i
want to thank you also for the amazing
content
everybody else out there thank you for
listening thank you for watching
if you feel like this episode was
educational informative and or
entertaining
and you'd like to make a financial
contribution to the show all you have to
do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need will be
right there on the screen and of course
there is that link in the show notes
and or the video description to make it
nice and easy for all of
my friends also if you've got any
questions corrections comments or
concerns i would love to hear from you
the email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com don't be shy also
don't forget to check out the website
the website is iregenetics.com all
things roster jeff
all things grow from your heart all
things ire genetics are right there at
iregenetics.com
ladies and gentlemen boys and girls
pimps and hoes friends and foes smokers
growers clone cutters and pollen
chuckers
that is all i've got for you for this
episode you know i'll be back in just a
couple of days with fresh new content
i want to give a giant shout out to my
buddy lemur priest and until next time
take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you