yeah welcome back podcast world i'm your
host my friends call me rosta jeff
and this is episode 615 of the grow from
your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to answer a
few grow questions before we get there
let's do a few shout outs to a few
members of the 710 club
of course the 710 club are the folks who
support us on patreon
at the 7 and 10 cent a month level or
higher so with no further ado let's
start off with the big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out
to my friend godfather kush let's send a
big thank you shout out to og purple
thumb and matt hemingway
let's send a big thank you shout out to
dave's not here and triumph
nomi by my guacamole and terp burglar
let's send a special thank you shout out
to learning and burning let's send a
thank you shout out to smokey j
1360 and kojacks and let's wrap it up
with the big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out
to my friend stoned trout bomb
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who supports the show on
patreon
if you are not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so
all you have to do is visit
[Music]
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need to
support the show will be right there on
the screen
and of course i did include that link in
the show notes and in the video
description
to make it super easy for all of my
friends really you guys thank you
for all of that continued patreon
support i do
appreciate it where do we go from there
oh i wanted to do
something rare we don't do this on the
podcast a lot
i used to talk about what i do all the
time i used to talk about going to
comedy shows
i used to talk about going to concerts
uh guess what we don't get to do that
kind of [ __ ] anymore so
i've been doing some netflixing what did
i watch on netflix i recently watched
a documentary about the cecil hotel
uh to be really quick we'll just say
that that was a four-hour show
that could have been 45 minutes
so before you jump in too far the cecil
hotel
all of the answers are in the first 15
minutes of the show everything you
needed to know
was told to you in the beginning you
could put the whole damn story together
watch it if you're really interested but
ah man
four hours of my life i should have been
recording podcasts or doing something
way different that [ __ ] could have been
a 45 maybe an hour and 15 at the most
there was a lot of extra content that
did not need to be in there
long story could have been a really
short story
that's my review on the cecil hotel all
right where do we go from there
the new discord link in the last episode
i mentioned that there were some epa
some upgrades to the irie genetics ivory
army discord
we've gotten our own vanity discord
link that's right instead of saying it
out loud right here i'll just put it in
the show notes and
in the description you guys can go ahead
and just click on that that'll take you
right to the discord
join the irie army iregenetics grow from
your heart podcast
discord gang there's a lot of cool [ __ ]
going on over there
i don't honestly i don't participate
enough in the discord i've got a lot
going on you guys
uh i make a lot of other things happen
so big thanks to the people that do make
the discord happen and who are on the
discord but when i pop in there
holy [ __ ] there's a lot happening there
are uh chat rooms happening there are
video chats happening
there are conversations about growing
happening there are auctions
there are all kinds of great crazy
anything you can think of that may
happen in an online community
it's probably happening in the discord
so go check it out it's a great time a
great place to go meet
uh new members of the ire army it's a
good place for the irie army and the dgc
to kind of mesh together right there
so a big shout out to everybody over
there holding it down in
the discord also this is completely
random i just heard it through my
headphones a moment ago don't know if
you guys can hear it
uh there are some cats in my
neighborhood and i don't know if they
are making
babies or having babies but they're
right over there just a little bit i
haven't identified exactly where i think
it's out of my yard but the yard next to
me
behind me ish there are some cats over
there either making
kittens or having kittens or something
similar or maybe i should go check
further but i'm pretty sure it's cats
doing cat things over there
but if it comes through the headphones
there's nobody
there's nobody tied up here nothing
weird is going on i think those are cats
i've been hearing it
randomly for a little bit this evening i
really want i want to believe that those
are cats making that noise
i'm starting to wonder what it really is
now i shouldn't have brought that up
anyway those are cats if it comes
through the microphone you guys i
i'm gonna we're gonna that's my story
and i'm sticking to it it's cats i think
they're making
making more kittens over there that's
what it sounds like to me all right
so i did say at the start of the show i
was going to answer some grow questions
let's get right to that part so we don't
have to talk about cats making kittens
anymore
um let's get right to the grow question
part this one came
from my email inbox and it came from i'm
looking to see if they want their name
said they did not give me a name to use
so i'm not going to give them
their name said but shout out to you
you'll know who you are when i read your
message
it goes just a like at this it says hey
ross to jeff i just started listening to
your podcast
and i really like it thank you i
appreciate that i appreciate you for
listening thank you
it said i'm not sure if you've been
asked or answered this before but
what are your thoughts on curing with
humidity packs and he actually listed a
brand name he said boveda
there are several brands of humidity
packs available i'm not going to
uh endorse or bash or promote or
belittle
any uh particular brand this is my
overall opinion
on the humidity packs which are used to
preserve dry and cure
uh originally were for cigars now
they're used in the cannabis industry
quite a bit
but let's talk about how i feel about
boveda packs
i don't really find it necessary to use
a boveda pack
if you dried and cured your product
properly in the beginning
um that does take a little bit of
experience to get to that point so
maybe if you're using it as a little bit
of a training wheel for drying and
curing
that's acceptable i don't need a boveda
pack to dry and cure my product
i don't think it's necessary but it's
helpful if it's working for you do it
don't stop doing something just because
rasta jeff doesn't do it i don't think
it's necessary
i think and this is my opinion mike
seems to agree with me a few people have
argued
some people agree with me sometimes i
think if you cure with the boveda pack
in there it gives it
sort of a moist different flavor that
you don't want in the finished product
if you wait until the product is
properly dried and cured and you're
preserving that moisture level with the
boveda pack
then it works well and it tastes good so
i don't think it's necessary for
actually drawing and curing
the product i think it's better for
long-term storage and for preserving
the freshness of the project product
once you've got it like stored for a
while
maybe more long-term storage not drying
and curing is what i'm trying to say vin
also my opinion has widely varied and
swayed back and forth over time when it
comes to
the boveda and other brand humidity
packs i've said before that
i think it kind of leaves a weird flavor
it kind of
and i could that could be completely
full of [ __ ] maybe it was something else
in the grow doing that
but i feel like it was making the buds
taste different when we quit using the
boveda packs the herb tasted better
in my opinion now we do i do live in
colorado
where i experience what is known as the
colorado crunch
if i go buy if i buy an eighth or an
ounce of weed
from the dispensary it's going to be
crunchy because
the dispensary weed is stored in a jar
on the shelf to where everybody can see
it that comes in
the bud tender grabs it sets it out in
front of you you smell it or maybe not
now during covid but during most times
you'd smell it
and then they open it up they pop off
the lid they weigh out either an eighth
or they weigh out at a quarter or maybe
your ounce if that's what you're buying
maybe two ounces if you're going hard
then they put the lid back on it and
they put it back on the shelf maybe they
popped open three or four other jars and
showed you all of those at the same time
that's happening with every customer
that comes in there so that weed is
getting super dry
if they put that herb back in a big
container at the end of the night with
the boveda package
and sealed it up or maybe just put some
boveda packs in that jar
that may prevent that colorado
crispiness that may be a good use
for the boveda pack there so if you're
slow drying it and slow curing it get it
as close
as you can to perfect then add the
boveda pack if you mess it up and get it
too dry
then that's when i would say to to
reintroduce that boveda pack and
re-moisten the product at that time but
i think if you're doing it right you
don't really need the boveda pack
um if you've got enough product to where
you
think you may need to store it with the
pack i'm not gonna like i said earlier
if you like it do it
maybe get a small jar and try it with
the boveda pack in a small jar and try
it without
i think if you dry and cure it properly
and you get a big jar that you keep your
like personal stash in
put a couple of packs in there just to
keep that one
long-term fresh then however often it
takes you to smoke and ate the weed
take an eighth out of your big jar put
it in your smaller jar and make that one
the jar that you pop open and
open and close all the time so you got
your big storage jar you got your
smaller jar
that way your big jar stays fresh it's
not getting cracked open all the time
then you got your smaller one that does
get opened and closed all the time when
you're reaching for a nug
maybe even put a boveda pack in with
that eighth maybe a quarter depending on
how hard you smoke
but you asked mainly about curing uh
thoughts on curing with boveda humidity
packs
i would prefer dry and cure without it
use a dialed in room use
jars use a humidifier and a dehumidifier
use a heater and an air conditioner use
those things
for your drying and curing and then once
it's in the jar trimmed up
uh just getting that final touch that's
when you can add the bovedas
in my opinion um i don't want to bash
the product i don't want to bash the
company many people love them
i just think if it's done properly you
don't need them until it comes to that
long-term storage
that's when they do come in very handy
they prevent you from getting that
colorado crunch
so put your big jar put a couple of
boveda packs in the big jar
and then uh if you've got some bud that
you did get from the dispensary that
came and it showed up all crispy and
crunchy
throwing a couple of boveda packs in
there that will help re-moisten
and stabilize that product all right i
think i rambled on long enough about the
boveda packs
i do have some friends that have a
podcast they did do the boveda challenge
where they put
some dried and cured herbs into two
different jars one with the bovida one
without
and you could tell the difference the
one with it was a little moister
moisture is that a word it is now
because i said it right somebody put
that in the
in the dictionary moisture it was more
moist one bud was more moist more supple
it burned a little differently
the other had that colorado crunch
effect that i talked about you could
just hear it go
if you broke it up by the microphone it
burned really quickly
but i didn't get to taste that herb so i
can't testify to the flavor
visually audibly it did look and appear
and sound like better product but i
didn't get to consume it
so i can't testify much to that but
ah the quick summary drying and curing
don't need it
storage or re uh what is it remoistening
is the word we're going to use
uh that is when i would use the boveda
packs got awful rambling on that one
this could be a long show
the next question oh by the way that
question came from my email box my email
in back inbox my email address is holy
[ __ ] that was hard to say
my email address is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com
since i put so much effort into it
please use that email address
send me your grow questions this
question came
from the grow help tab on my website my
website is iriegenetics.com
on that website you will find a tab that
says grow help if you click on that grow
help tab you can ask grow questions
we ask you a few preliminary questions
just to kind of give me an idea of
what's going on in your grow
then at the bottom it says the problem
and that's where you are given the
opportunity to tell me about the problem
in your grow
then i will read that on the podcast and
we will diagnose or
recommend some solutions for your
problem
that's where this question came from
they want me to use the name
t.420 on instagram so this one came from
t.420
t.420 is growing cookies kush from
barney's farm
they're growing washing machine from
ripper seeds and one smoothie auto by 42
fast buds and it was a sample seed
a lot of these details are not necessary
because i know the question
let's skip some of that what are you
feeding it they're feeding it remo
nutrients i don't know if that's ramo or
remo nutrients but shout out ramos a
cool ass dude up there in canada
growing with the ramo nutrients using
five mils of micro
five mils of grow five mils of velo kelp
eight mils of magnifical that sounds
like a [ __ ] great name for a product
for the calmag product
uh five mils of nature's candy i can
imagine that that's like a sweetener
and five eight milliliters of microbial
mass
and it says it's the first time i'll
continue to use this once every
two weeks uh then it says a little more
about the grow which isn't necessary for
the question
it says i have a small question here
since i'm starting the microbial mass
should i follow the dosage indicated on
the bottle or should i reduce it to half
as i have with the rest of my nutrients
like you suggest in your videos
thank you so much for your time i really
am learning a lot from you
watching your videos reminds me of my
chef when i was an apprentice
ah there's a lot of stuff there in that
last [ __ ] sentence holy [ __ ]
uh you're learning a lot thank you i do
appreciate that it makes me
feel good it makes it worth my time
knowing that you are learning a lot
uh the time that i put into this the
energy the equipment the effort
is worth it because you're learning a
lot that means a lot uh reminds me
of when you were of your chef when you
were the apprentice
i like that uh you could be the
grasshopper i'll be mr miyagi however
you want to do it
as long as you're learning bro i will
keep teaching i'm glad you're following
along
now uh let's get past the wax on wax off
portion and let's talk about the
recommendation here
you are using a microbial product called
microbial mass
i did a little quick research uh it
looks fancy it looks a little bit
expensive it's got a lot of fancy
microbes in there it's packaged up very
well as long as it is not too expensive
i would probably use that product as
recommended
i do recommend most the time that you
use most
products at about half to three quarters
of the recommended strength so
if it says use a hundred i say start
with 50 see how it responds
then try 75 see how it responds you
rarely have to go all the way up to 100
of what they recommend
i like to have faith in the companies
which we choose to work with
but they're in the business of doing
business their business is you buying
more nutrients
if they can get you to splash on just a
few extra milliliters
a few times a week that's that much
sooner you got to buy
that many more bottles so if they can
get you to use it more quickly they
certainly will and they're not in your
grow they don't know what you're growing
how you're growing when you're growing
what you're doing
so those are recommendations i would
start with about half of that maybe your
plants are going to [ __ ] thrive a lot
of plants respond better
with a little bit of nutrients when you
start putting more on you start seeing
what the nutrients do not what the plant
does and i like to see what my plants do
then adapt my nutrients to that so in
most cases i would recommend starting
with about 50
of the recommended dosage on the bottle
then work your way up maybe to 75 maybe
80.
you're rarely going to get up to need a
100 of the recommended dosage on the
bottle i don't know if you guys hear the
weird noises happening in my
neighborhood but i'm sorry if i look
distracted momentarily
because i certainly certainly was all
right let's get back on track
uh you're probably going to need 50 to
75 percent of the recommended dosage on
the bottle
for the micro products however the other
products let me back up the other
products you do have the opportunity the
potential to burn
your plants you can cause problems you
can burn the leaf tips you can burn the
whole damn leaf
you can cause root issues you can cause
lockouts you can disrupt the soil and
the plant growth altogether
with a lot of those products those salty
products the shalated buffered nutrients
can do a lot of damage the micro
products i don't
really in my opinion feel like you can
overdose on microbe products
the thing to think about there is cost
effectiveness you said you were going to
use it every two weeks
um i think i'd like to see it every
maybe every once a week if you're going
to use a micro product i didn't research
how often to use it
but in my opinion it feels like once a
week is enough to keep those colonies
thriving just to get those microbes
whatever you've got going on
once a week gets them going if you're
using tap water if you're using filtered
water
some of your microbes are going to be
destroyed by environmental factors by
competition within the root zone
maybe just by chlorine in your water
maybe chloramine in your water
a lot of things are going to be
competing and destroying your microbes
so maybe if you use a little bit too
much all you're doing is supercharging
overpowering the other things and
keeping that microbe colony
super strong within your rhizosphere so
if it is cost effective and
it's not cutting into your budget if
you're still able to afford the rest of
your nutrients and eat like a king and
buy good concentrates i would say feed
that bad dog
that micro product as recommended if it
feels excessive
maybe reduce it you said you're going to
do it every two weeks
i again unless it says to do it every
two weeks i would almost do it every
once a week every other micro product i
can think of
they recommend doing it once per week so
i'd read the bottle see if they say once
a week or once every two weeks and
basically
if you're gonna use the rest of remo's
instructions the rest of his bottles
i would just go with what he recommends
at that recommended level because
uh i've seen ramos plants and i've seen
what he does and that dude has a
kick-ass garden eh so uh shout out to
remo and ramon nutrients if that's the
dude then i'm thinking that makes these
nutrients right it's gotta be
that's the dude's name it's gotta be
what you're using yeah shout out to ramo
um yeah so just use the recommended uh
part on that micro product i really
don't think you'll overdo it i don't
think you'll overdose it
and you'll just be compensating for
anything that may be destroying
any of the microbes that you've already
got going on if it's chlorine chloramine
or competition within the root zone and
if you've got a bunch of microbes in
there
that just prevents you from getting
other bad or other things which may be
bad
into that root zone big shout out to my
friend t.420
uh that's his instagram name he wants to
be called t.420
thank you for the great great question
bro i hope i was able to help you out
go ahead and use that product if it is
cost
effective one thing i should add and i'm
not trying to dis on anybody's nutrient
line but
if you do find that maybe you're using a
nutrient line and maybe the microbes
from that line are too expensive or
maybe the enzymes are too expensive or
maybe the calmag is too expensive
you don't have to always use
the full lineup of one company you don't
have to use
ramos everything everything everything
ramo if you find that there's a more
affordable more cost effective micro
product you can absolutely swap it out
for this microbial product if it
fits your budget your wallet your style
your grow better
um but with that being said be very
careful that you don't overlap anything
when you're reading the bottles see what
your npk values are your nitrogen
phosphorous potassium see how much if
there's calcium or magnesium in one
bottle maybe there's boron and copper
and zinc in one bottle
make sure you're not overlapping any
nutrients in two different bottles
because
this company probably put a few elements
in a couple of bottles and you can mix
them up and get the ideal mix but
this other company did similar but they
mixed bottles a little bit differently
so you do have the potential
to maybe overlap nitrogen or phosphorous
or potassium or calcium
it is possible so it's your
responsibility to read those bottles and
make sure
but as a as a grower as a breeder with a
lot of experience
i've talked about using veg bloom and
new millennium at the same time but i'm
also mixing
in what's that bloom booster that i can
never remember the name of the one with
the bat guano stuff on it
bud swell there we go i just have to
stop thinking about it the name comes to
my brain
i'm also mixing in bud swell i'm also
mixing in
uh silicium i also mix in other products
that are not new millennium or
uh veg bloom based so there are other
random products that do go into my grow
because they work well with my recipe
it's all about
uh if even if you give a professional
chef a written recipe
he's going to go ah you said to use this
i want to use this and make it mine
because he's the chef and i'm the
[ __ ] grower
and i know what results i'm looking for
so i'm able to kind of manipulate my
feeds custom tailor my feeds
dial in my feeds to give me exactly what
i need
for the outcome which i need uh that way
it like week three if i say oh man i'm
running a little bit low on this i can
grab something and i know what to mix in
to add that to make my plants go kapow
shabang i'm not limited by
what this lineup says to do maybe i only
need
one element and this all these bottles
have three elements in each bottle and i
just need one thing maybe i've got a
product that's got that one
[ __ ] thing and they're ready readily
available i don't have to add the
nitrogen and the other stuff in there
get that one in there with the other
bottle from another brand
just but be careful if you go doing that
stuff you guys but don't think that you
have to buy just because you bought
one brand of something doesn't mean you
have to stick with that entire lineup
it's much easier when you're a beginner
grower to do that but as you get better
maybe you can add some other things
i feel like i've said enough into that
let's keep
going with this podcast i think the cats
are done i haven't heard them in a few
minutes
hopefully i didn't just jinx myself the
next message came from my email no this
one came from patreon this one came from
coach steve
shout out to coach steve i hear from you
a lot uh thank you for supporting the
grow from your heart podcast and the dgc
this message goes just like this it says
hey ross to jeff i hope you've had a
great weekend i had a great weekend
thank you bro about to have another
great weekend not to to my own horn it
is about to be my
birthday weekend i think this episode
will come out on my birthday
so i'll be smoking dabs and eating cake
and having a good ass time
i promise you i had a good weekend it
says i just listened to episode 603
on the topic of light leaks and i don't
think i heard you mention
a dark period for vegetative plants if
you did i'm sorry i missed that
yes i did talk about light leaks in
depth on a previous episode
and i did not talk about vegetative
plants very much
vegetative plants get overlooked quite
often we're going to discuss that here
in just a moment
the message goes on to say i do see a
lot of growers treating the dark period
in veg with the same rules as flower can
you please mention that
can you please mention that during veg
you do not need
uninterrupted darkness uh then it says
great show as always
thanks from coach steve uh you are
you are right technically in uh in
you're right we don't need on an
uninterrupted darkness in the vegetative
stage
but do you like getting woken up when
you're sleeping bro either to the plants
uh they're doing there are processes
happening when they're sleeping so it's
best not to disrupt them
we can but it's best not to once they've
gone to sleep for their
uh if it's four to six maybe eight hours
it's best just to let them rest but it
is not
nearly as critical if you must interrupt
a light cycle in a grow
let it happen during the veg so if
you've got to set up a grow space
and you've got like two rooms and you
have to walk through one to get to the
other
always make the walk through room the
veg space because you can have that one
on you can turn it on if you need to get
through there the flower room you cannot
interrupt that's what we discussed in
the previous episode
but you're correct it is mostly
mostly important not to interrupt that
dark period during the veg stage
uh just because things are happening
that's when a lot of processes happen is
at night
so the plants are just chilling they're
doing a lot of processing and we don't
want to disrupt that you don't like
being woken up in the middle of the
night
so just let them process let them do
their things but it is not critical
you're not going to cause
hermaphroditism
they're not going to freak out on you it
won't be hypercritical
so um let's talk more about the veg
phase because i did like that
inspiration
uh you're right it's not as critical to
keep them in the dark phase
but the veg phage phase is often
overlooked and people weigh heavily only
focus like i did in that episode
heavily heavily they focus too much on
the flower phase
so let's talk briefly here about the
vegetative stage of growth and why
i feel veg is often overlooked and super
duper i don't think i've said super
duper since i was a kid
it's super duper important to have a
solid veg
strategy a solid veg space a solid veg
feeding regimen a good vegetative goal
um
a strategy that all of that is under the
word strategy is what i started with veg
is way important and people completely
forget about that
the vegetative stage is where we are
working on healthy roots
healthy roots is where we get healthy
fruits if you don't have healthy plants
on the bottom you can't get healthy
plants up top
so we're working on healthy roots we're
working on
general basic plant health so that when
we start packing on weight
these plants are ready when we start
putting them under 12 12 and things
start going haywire
and their hormonal systems they can
transfer nice and smoothly
if they are hit by a pest or something
in flour we want them super strong in
veg
so that they are ready for this so this
is the foundation of
everything do you want your plants to go
to flower
looking like me i'm tall and skinny i'm
six foot five and like 180 pounds
or do you want your plants going to
flower looking like brock lesnar he's
like six
two and like [ __ ] 280 bro he could b
pick me up snap me in half eat part of
me and store rest of me for
later so would you rather have your
plants go into flower
looking like this or looking like this
and there's still not much there when i
do that but you see what i'm trying to
do right
would you rather have them looking like
this pin or looking like my wrist which
still i know not much difference but
that is up to you and that all happens
in the vegetative
stage of your growth um
shaping topping popping twisting
bottoming lollipopping these are all
things that should start
in the vegetative growth if you're going
to put your plants in a trellis and net
them out
that should happen in the vegetative
growth stage
people are forgetting to do a lot of
things in veg
lack of work and veg creates [ __ ] plants
in flower
shit-shaped plants in flower struggle
buds in flower buds that are too tall
buds that are floppy
uh one bud that's way up here one bud
that's way over here
one bud that's way this tall so your
light's gotta be way up here
and you've got these little buds down
here that aren't getting a lot of light
but these couple of buds are sticking up
way close to the light and you're
freaking out
veg is where we can fix and prevent and
prepare for all of these problems
so shape them and veg pop them twist
them bend
them down get them the structure that
you want the strength and vigor that you
want
prepare them in the vegetative stage set
yourself up for success
before we go into flour also any mistake
you make in the veg phase
prolongs your flowering stage i like to
correct any problems before i go to
flower i don't like to go into flower
with problems because you can't spray
you can't do as many things to the
plants once you're into flower
so i need my issues of the room of the
grow
in my life i need all of the problems
resolved before we go into the flowering
phase
so if you've got an issue in veg you got
to correct that [ __ ]
quickly get your plants back on track
now not only are you
lacking growth and performance and vigor
from the plants
uh potential that is potential potency
harvest weight of what you're going to
get in the end
because you're [ __ ] up in the veg
phase you got to correct that you've got
to recover
now you're also behind you're probably
minimum
a week to two weeks behind from any
[ __ ] problem that happens in your
grow if you get spider mites
it's gonna take you a solid two weeks to
get rid of them another week to recover
another week to get back on track now
you're [ __ ] four weeks behind in your
grow
because you weren't taking good enough
care of the vegetative
stage that is where the preventative
pest management happens that's where all
the shaping and structuring happens
that's where route development happens
this is where all of the planning should
take
place because this is the foundation the
structure the infrastructure
for the future plants that we are
growing do you want to grow struggle
buds or do you want to grow
big fat donkey dicks do you want one big
bud
that's touching the light with a bunch
of [ __ ] at the bottom or do you want
a nice canopy an even row of buds that
fills the entire room with a nice
airflow
beautiful [ __ ] everything is clean
and organized
that's up to you but it starts it starts
at day one of the vet it starts from the
day you cut that clone it starts when
you start thinking about the room
uh let me segue in to that one
the room people don't spend enough money
attention time and details and effort on
their vegetative stage
in their vegetative room i'm sorry they
think they can just
hang up a light and they've got a veg
room in some cases that will work
do you have a fan in there are you
controlling the humidity are you
controlling the temperature in that room
do you have something some sort of duct
that pulls old air out and moves
out the humidity do you have something
that brings in fresh air do you need or
have a humidifier or dehumidifier
is your bedroom setting you up for
success you spent all
i know you spent a bunch of money you
spent like 90 of your money on the
flowering room didn't you
you got the best lights you got the best
soil
you got the best [ __ ] pots you got
the best timer you got that thing on the
wall that all the lights plug into it's
got the best programmable [ __ ] on it
you got your pl minder unit or your
pulse monitor you got your co2 setup
going on you got it all cranking in the
flower room right
but you didn't spin [ __ ] in the bedroom
so by the time you get to that flower
room those plants are wonky they're all
[ __ ]
un evenly shaped and [ __ ] look like
charlie brown's christmas tree because
people don't spend enough time effort
energy money
uh effort that's the bottom line effort
and strategy there's no strategery
happening in the bedroom so
uh you end up with weak light not the
right light
lights of the wrong spectrum lights that
are way too high or way too low from
your plants
uh i see bedrooms that are way too
over packed because they were poorly
planned there's not enough room for
mother plants for flowering or for
vegetative plants
for clones for [ __ ] that needs to be
transplanted they get way too packed in
there they start getting tall and
stretchy
starts getting too humid in there start
getting powdery mildew
start getting lazy because they're too
packed in start getting spider mites
the plants start going into flower and
pre-flowering because they're too packed
in
now your clones look like [ __ ] your next
round of veg plants look like [ __ ]
it all starts becoming a really quick
[ __ ] struggle and it just takes a
week of falling behind for all this [ __ ]
to happen
so prep your veg room have a really nice
bedroom
or i see people with their plants way
too far apart a lot of wasted space in
there
they're just wasting money because the
lights are running if you got like
if you set up your bedroom to have two
lights for when you have 24 big plants
and right now you got 24 cups
turn off that second light move those
[ __ ] plants under the one light
and quit wasting so much space you guys
come on there's so many things you can
do to set yourself up for success
i see plants way too far apart way too
close together
another thing that breaks my heart is
filthy
filthy grow rooms sometimes i'm guilty
of this
sometimes it takes me a day or two to
get my [ __ ] together and get everything
caught up and cleaned
but it doesn't stay filthy i see people
with just
grow rooms that were never even built to
be clean or just never even thought
about how sanitation could affect the
quality of their product
i'm not sure why i keep getting spider
mites and fungus gnats and i go to look
at your grow and it's like in a shed
with a door that doesn't seal and the
[ __ ] bark is peeling off the tree and
falling off the tree through the ceiling
into your grow space
like there's all kinds of weird [ __ ]
that i've seen in grows you guys clean
up just a little bit take some pride in
your grow
take some pride in your work and those
plants will show you they'll be like oh
daddy thank you or maybe even mommy
thank you for taking such good care of
us we're gonna make you so proud
you gotta go in there and take care of
that veg space so
the veg space is just as important if
not more important than your flowering
space
how long are your flowering lights on 12
hours a day right
plants are sleeping for 12 hours how
long are your lights on in veg
16 18 20 hours a day why wouldn't you
spend enough
effort money time energy on making that
a super fresh place for your plants to
be also
we need both rooms to be ideal don't
don't blow the whole budget the whole
wad
on making a ferrari of a flowering room
if you're gonna roll around
in a pinto of a veg space maybe get two
i'm trying to find cars that are right
in the middle get your two teslas now we
got a tesla
automated veg space tesla automated
flowering space
somebody's going to send me [ __ ] hate
mail youtube comments why i chose tesla
it's the one i chose i was driving in
denver and saw a lot of teslas recently
don't get on me we all got to say some
kind of words right you talk for a while
and go get some criticism
you guys this was a fun episode coach
steve thank you for the great episode
thank you or for the great question the
great email
thank you for inspiring a nice rant
about vegetative growth i do appreciate
it
ladies and gentlemen boys and girls
pimps and hoes friends
foes smokers growers clone cutters
pollen chuckers ah commercial
cultivators
home growers closet tokers and heavy
dabbers
i want to thank each and every one of
you for listening to the grow from your
heart podcast i've been having a lot of
fun doing these shows
a lot of fun putting out the content a
lot of fun being on other people's
podcasts i hung out on embracing
organics last night that was a really
good time
i do my show on monday my audience my
group my friends you guys have become my
friends during covid
you guys are [ __ ] great i really
enjoy hanging out with you i hope you
are getting as much from this
as i am because it is very fulfilling
the relationship has been going very
well so thank you guys
i appreciate it um if you feel like this
episode was educational informative
or entertaining and you'd like to
support the show financially
all you got to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need is right
there on the screen
um help us out sign up for patreon uh
there's more to that but oh there is a
link in the show notes in the video
description for all my friends
there's always something i forget when
it comes to the patreon ads but hey
i'm only goddamn human right let's keep
going if you've got any questions
corrections comments or concerns i would
love your information your feedback your
input
just send me a message my email address
is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com yeah it's hotmail i'm old
school
it's the only one that doesn't get
hacked and now don't try to hack me just
because i said that
also i would appreciate it appreciate it
that's the word i would appreciate it
and i encourage you to visit my website
at iregenetics.com
all things ire genetics all things grow
from your heart podcast all things rust
and jeff
are right there at iregenetics.com don't
forget there's a grow help tab
there is a uh vendor link where you can
get irie genetics beans
there's an irie store where you can get
fresh irie genetics hats and t-shirts
and hoodies
there is a question tab there is a tab
where you can just stay in contact
i try sometimes i fail about once a
month i try to send out
a newsletter via mailchimp sign up for
the mailchimp you'll get the newsletter
you'll get the coupon codes you'll get
all the fresh drops there will be a new
coupon code coming out that you guys do
want to find so check us out on the
website
iriegenetics.com you guys my voice is
getting dry my throat's burning out
i want to thank you again once again for
listening you know i'll be back in just
a couple of days with fresh new content
i want to give a big shout out to my
buddy sam
heads dgc and until next time take a fat
dab
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you