yeah welcome back
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rasta jeff
and this is episode 616 of the grow from
your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to read a few
emails before we get there
let's do a few shout outs to a few
members of the 710 club
of course the 710 club are the folks who
support us on patreon
at the 7 and 10 a month level or higher
so with no further ado let's start off
with the big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out
to my friend bob let's send a big thank
you shout out to jeffrey
let's send a big thank you shout out to
billy podunk let's send a big thank you
shout out to rosta green thumb and
blackbird 76.
let's send a big thank you shout out to
owen g crossman and grant m
dayron t and kenna organic
let's send a big thank you shout out to
kurt z and tree star meadow
and let's wrap it up with the big grow
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out
to my friend freakfish big thanks and
big shout out to everybody who supports
the show on patreon if you are not
already supporting the show and you
would like to learn how to do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need will be
right there on the screen and of course
i did include a link in the show notes
and in the video description to make it
super easy for all of
my friends once again you guys thank you
for all of that continued
patreon support sometimes it does blow
my mind to open up patreon
and see all the support the messages the
interactions the love
it does mean a lot to me so really thank
you i do appreciate it
all right also i owe you guys a big
thank you for all of the birthday love
that's right
on the last episode i mentioned that
show came out on my birthday
my inbox my youtube my social media
my life went haywire with birthday love
birthday messages
it felt amazing so thank you it does
mean a lot to me to get so many
uh very warm greetings very uh
well put deep thought out messages from
people
wishing me a happy birthday some people
sent some really great messages
uh some people just said happy birthday
some people sent a nice elaborate
message
thank you i do appreciate all of the
above also i got a lot of great gifts
from
from friends fans listeners from the
family from the irie army
thank you i do appreciate every single
one of those gifts
some of them are very thoughtful gifts
gifts like gloves and hats that [ __ ] is
thoughtful thank you guys i got
drumsticks
i got a lot of great things i don't want
to go talking about gifts that i was
given i got shoes
you guys i'm a shoe head i'm a drummer
and it's cold so
uh clothing to keep me warm was
beautiful drumsticks were amazing and
shoes are one of my favorite things
i got a shoe cleaning kit from somebody
you guys know who you are big thanks to
everybody who gave me some
amazing beautiful birthday gifts and
most of all that birthday love
didn't mean a lot thank you i feel like
i'm rambling let's move forward from
that
happy birthday if it's your birthday and
if your birthday is coming up this year
happy birthday to you because the
birthday love does feel good
uh discord you guys i've got an irie
genetics discord channel
i will put the link right here in the
video you can see it on the screen right
now
the link is also in the video
description so look for that
the irie genetics irie army grow from
your heart podcast
all things roster jeff discord channel
is a good time the discord is blowing up
the server has been getting a lot of
boosts
yesterday after my birthday celebration
on the monday night live feed
i hung out in the discord neighborhood
chat i will include a link to that
in the show notes here uh there is a
discord chat where i hang out on video
take dabs with the crew anybody is
welcome anybody is invited
if you can figure out how to make
discord work how to make that chat work
and how to get in there
that's the only test there is come in
agree to the rules the rules are that
the neighborhood is always right and you
won't be a dick
so come on in and hang out if you can
agree to those rules like i said before
if you can make
uh discord work and if you can get
through all the hoops that discord makes
you do to get to
our live chat you're more than welcome
you're more than invited i make no
promises as to
how frequently how often what kind of
schedule i'm going to adhere to being in
that live chat
when i've got some time to kill maybe
when i'm packing up seeds i like to just
put on some headphones turn on a
microphone and hang out with my friends
and take some dabs in there
during these quarantine times during
these lockdown times if you're listening
in the future right now we're still in
sort of a quarantine situation we're not
allowed to play with our friends as much
as we'd like
during these sort of times uh it's
really nice to have something like a
zoom chat like the discord chat
things like that to be interactive with
more uh fellow smokers growers stoners
like-minded friends
and it's also a beautiful way for me to
keep in touch with the ire army with the
crew the people that are growing my
strains
the people that support me i really like
hanging out with you guys and just
chilling out i'm taking dabs kicking
back you guys get to ask me questions
it's funny because sometimes people come
in they're a little bit i hate to say
the word star struck but they've been
following me for a while they've been
watching the show they come in and
they're like holy [ __ ] there he is
they don't know what to say they don't
know what to do i just welcome you
say what's up we take some dabs we hang
out uh i act like it's just no big deal
and eventually everyone's just hanging
out it's no big deal
i'm taking dabs with everybody cheers
and everybody talking about whatever's
on my mind you're talking about
whatever's on your mind
so it's fun once everybody comes in and
just settles down the star struck
feeling goes away
uh we all just hang out chill out it's a
spot for me to be interactive a spot for
you to be interactive i get some social
feed there you get some social
interaction there
so my point is uh the discord is blowing
up and the discord
hang in the neighborhood has become a
lot of fun so i invite you guys to come
hang out you're more than welcome you're
more than invited i would love to see
your smiling faces on camera you don't
have to cam up you can put up a little
icon a little logo on the screen if
you'd like to we'll just see a picture
of whatever you would like when you're
on the camera
but we'd love you to join the
conversation come hang out share the
vibe
uh there will be a link in the video
description
the show notes and also i will try to
type it right up here somewhere on the
screen
so that you can see that have an idea of
where to go
if you're new to discord be patient
there's a little bit to learn it's a
little bit overwhelming
once you figure it out it is a really
good time so that's enough rambling on
discord i invite you to join us on the
irie
genetics discord once again shout out to
all the
uh fine ladies and gentlemen who not
only participate in there but also run
that discord there are a lot of great
people who do a lot of great things to
make sure it works
i did not realize people were putting uh
so much
time and energy and effort and also
money into the irie genetics discord
that's basically
built for me it's i'm irie genetics it's
also but it's the community that's doing
it running it functioning it make it
happen
making it happen so thank you to the
[ __ ] irie army
the grow from your heart crew the rosta
jeff team
team irie genetics whatever you guys
want to call yourselves you know who you
are if you deserve some credit feel it
in your heart right now
feel this fist bump i'm giving you feel
the kiss i'm to give the mic
that was for you for being a good little
soldier thank you
i appreciate it big salute to everyone
in the discord the irie army for helping
me out
um then i want to say thanks to all of
it's weird calling you fans supporters
listeners viewers the army the crew the
gang that is learning from me
thank you guys for all of the love the
support
and most of all the trust you guys
you've got to have huge
trust in me to take my advice
to run your garden a lot of you are
relying on your garden for several
things maybe it's medicine
maybe it's how you're paying the bills
maybe it's a little bit of both maybe
it's your therapy
while you're gardening then it's your
therapy when you're trimming then it's
your financial survival when you flip it
then it's also your medicine when you
smoke it you use that flip to cover the
cost
you guys are trusting me with a lot and
i understand how much
uh trust you're putting in me basically
and i appreciate that you trust me
that much thank you that is [ __ ]
awesome that you guys
uh support me and you trust me that much
um
with your garden i'm basically writing
you instructions you're like what do i
do and i say do this and
most of the time you guys go and execute
my instructions and you're having great
success so thank you for the trust i
appreciate
that and thank you for the support not
only on the podcast not only in
everything that i try to do but my seed
company is thriving
my social media is thriving uh life is
good for
rosta jeff i read genetics the grow from
your heart podcast
without you guys it would not be a thing
you guys gals everybody out there
listening without you i would just be
some weirdo with the microphone and
hopes and dreams so thank you
i do appreciate it it does not go
unnoticed that
uh you guys have built a huge community
around the vibe the company
the idea that i created so thank you
that means a lot to me
to see it thriving to see it flourish
especially in these weird times
um not only are we in like a pandemic
situation
we're also a lot of people are
financially strapped people don't have a
lot of extra money because of this
uh finance this pandemic situation so
you choose to financially support me
that means a lot to me also there are
hundreds
if not thousands of shows to watch
support listen to spend your time money
energy on viewing clicking like
supporting encouraging loving and you
choose to do that to me
so that means a lot for me to me with me
however you want to put it
you financially support me i do make a
living from the podcast and through my
seed company and through my
consultations
so you support me you do help me make a
living ah that means a lot to me
you click like on all of my videos you
could be watching other videos
i've got 10 friends that make their own
videos that are probably watching my
show right now so thank you to everybody
that
chooses to watch me support me support
my company
support my patreon there are a lot of
podcasts out there with patreons and you
choose to support mine
you guys i appreciate i'm gushing uh
just feeling the vibe
i had a birthday feeling the love wanted
to return the love back to you guys
and make sure you guys know that i'm not
just sucking up rewards and not
feeling the appreciation for the love
respect and support that i'm getting
from you guys
i said it a minute ago without you i
wouldn't be successful
so thank each and every one of you no
matter how much you feel like you did or
did not your large or small contribution
thank you i appreciate that this
community is huge and it's happening
without me you guys are on discord
somebody is on discord in the discord
chat right now while i'm recording
people are in discord
answering grow from your heart questions
uh purple thumb is probably posting a
link how to sell ivory genetics
merchandise
uh dave's not here is running an auction
right now for me on discord while i'm
chilling right here
there's a lot of stuff happening
somebody is probably answering a grow
question on the discord
my web guy is updating web stuff just
randomly for me
uh you guys are amazing so thank you for
all of that the [ __ ] is happening
when i'm recording you guys are doing
things when i'm asleep
the discord is going the irie army is
still out there conquering getting [ __ ]
done
uh when i'm enjoying my weekend that
discord keeps running when i'm not even
there
so it's amazing thank you guys big shout
out to the ire army
uh i said it jokingly the other night
the irie army
we take more dabs before 9 a.m than most
people do all day
and we still kick ass we get [ __ ] done
uh we're kind to each other
we got awesome gardens we got good
families we're good people and we still
have time to hang out in that discord
chat at like four in the morning so
it's a huge community and i'm
overwhelmed if you can't tell i've been
gushing for
several minutes about this but i
appreciate it here's the morbid thought
that i had
excuse that throat clearing i did take
some gnarly dabs a minute ago
ah the morbid thought that i had was i
could pass away
now this moment as long as this episode
makes it out and you guys get my
gratitude
i could pass away right now and this
company this podcast
this idea that i created will still
thrive for
at least a decade to come until youtube
deletes my episodes
they'll stay up there uh we've got a
friend subcool who passed away like a
year ago
rest in peace and shout out to subcool i
still watch his videos
so with that i'm still keeping subby
alive you guys will continue to watch my
videos for a year i'm sure that
also i'm still growing sub cool seeds
so that tells me that when i'm gone
hopefully somebody out there is still
growing my seeds
for generations then maybe somebody will
breed with them just like i did for sub
sub's gone i took some of his stuff i
bred it to keep subby alive
the man may be gone but his work his
legend his idea his vibe will continue
as partly my uh
it's partly my job i felt to continue
that so somebody in the ivory army i
have a good feeling of
who a few of those people may be some of
them i don't even know i'm sure there
are people out there
kicking ass with my genetics doing work
for me that i don't even know yet
shout out thank you but there are a few
people i have in mind that i know if i
were to pass right now
some of those people would continue the
ire work my strains would be
crossed to other things and crossed with
themselves i know people would continue
the vibe
the website would be continued to
survive for quite a while it comes from
a bank account
until that bank account is drained the
website would exist
so if i passed away at this moment after
i put out this podcast we'll say just
after i hit post you guys get to hear
this
uh this company iriegenetics this
podcast the grow from your heart podcast
will survive
indefinitely uh possibly infinitely as
long as youtube goes on
this exists which is [ __ ] cool as
long as you guys are growing and
breeding and taking care of the clones
and seeds
the vibe the idea that i created now at
this point will last
almost indefinitely and that's [ __ ]
beautiful keep it going you guys
i don't plan on going anywhere but i'm
just saying keep it going
let's spread this forever i did this all
it's called the grow from your heart
podcast
the slogan behind irie genetics used to
be
grow from your heart and breed with love
uh we kind of separated the two entities
to have two different llc's here but
grow from your heart man that's always
what it's been about so
i feel like i'm rambling but uh just
keep growing from your heart you guys
and it'll keep going so i'm spreading
that love spreading that vibe is my
point
anyway i do have some topics for this
podcast it's not just going to be me
rambling for the whole show
well actually it is but we've got some
topics for me to ramble about let's jump
right into it this one came from my
email inbox
of course my email address is grow from
your heart at hotmail.com if you've got
any grow questions cannabis concerns
cannabis culture
cannabis community questions i'd love to
answer that stuff here on the show
here we go the first one says have you
done a show about which companies are
owned by hawthorne or plan on doing
that episode maybe some people are going
that's random why do we care about
what's owned by hawthorne
that's a really good question i'm not
going to do a specific episode on
companies which are owned by hawthorne
but this will set me up for a good rant
which goes a lot like this i'm not going
to bash or roast any certain brands or
companies
we know who we shouldn't support we know
most of us know who we should not be
supporting who the big devils are
in agriculture and commercial in the
world
uh in capitalism in just politics and
[ __ ] economics
we kind of know who we should be voting
who we should be avoiding
uh i'm kind of an older guy by now i'm
42 years old i've got a good idea of
where my money should go and
who's getting my money and who makes
what and who runs what at this point
so maybe some of you guys haven't put
too much thought about where the money
goes
so um here's the thing to think about
this guy is saying uh have why done a
show about hawthorne hawthorne is kind
of
a big company that owns a lot of things
they may not have the best values they
may not have the best uh
views on keeping the world safe and
healthy they may not be the best at
keeping humans safe and healthy they may
be focused more on the dollars
than the long-term effects of human
safety environmental safety and
environmental impact
so we're going to do a little talk about
avoiding those types of companies
and basically scotty real puts it best
scotty real says vote with your dollars
man
so we're going to talk about voting with
our dollars uh the word i wrote was
conscious spending
another thing i wrote on my flow chart
here was follow the money man
so when you're shopping for uh i'm gonna
focus this on grow supplies
nutrients soil soilless mix uh we'll go
as far as saying lights and equipment
anything in your grow but this could
apply to anything
in your life wherever you're spending
money time energy
is it worth it is it somewhere you want
to spend your hard-earned
money time energy money's expensive man
you work hard for it
you've got to do something you don't
want to do for a certain amount of time
probably unless you're blessed and have
it really lucky you're probably working
for somebody you don't like who doesn't
appreciate you that doesn't see how hard
you work that doesn't understand how
hard your struggle is
and it sucks so money's expensive
putting in your time and energy to get
money
that is expensive so follow the money
when you're spending it do you want to
spend that money
if you know that when you buy a product
you may have two options
does the company that you buy a product
from does company a use that money to
uh reforest the rain forest or some [ __ ]
and does the other company use that
money to shoot babies
uh on sundays who are you spending your
money with we already know we're gonna
save the rainforest not shoot babies on
sunday right
so that's an easy way to decide how to
spend your money do a little research on
where the money goes once you spend
it what are you going to do with it bro
are you going to support a presidential
candidate that we are not up for are you
going to support a presidential
candidate
that is on cannabis side because why are
you going to spend your money
with a company who is against the thing
that you're buying their product to do
so i don't want to be political but also
kind of it's not just political this is
a personal thing this is
uh this is a personal decision this is
some things a conscious decision we need
to start making
uh maybe some people aren't aware of
that does your contribution go to a good
cause or does your contribution go
to more research to create more products
that are not going to be desirable for
our planet our world
i'm trying not to bash too many specific
companies say too many names
we all know that monsanto is the devil
that scots is the devil
anybody that falls in that umbrella we
may not want to give them our money
if you've got the option to give your
money
to a mom and pop shop at bro and chick
owned shop in your neighborhood
maybe some uh lady that's been in the
grow community
opened up a new hydro store go shop
there avoid that big box shop
if you can i understand that some people
some places some locations
the only thing you've got is that big
chain store you have to go to lowe's you
may have to go to home depot you may
have to hit the walmart
but if there's a small shop that is
available it may be a dollar or two more
to shop there but
it's worth your time effort and energy
to support that family
when you buy something from bill's
garden supply store
bill gets to buy himself a truck and
drive around in that truck so that he
could take his kids to school
bill gets to buy his kids school clothes
you're not just going to walmart so that
walmart so that sam walton
i know he's gone but the walmart family
can buy more jets and ferraris and
corvettes and fly around and treat their
employees like [ __ ]
if you go over to bills bill is probably
the guy working there so bill's going to
treat you with kindness treat you with
respect
and appreciate your business and
appreciate you shopping there
just like i do when you choose to
support my brand my company
whether it's the grow from your heart
podcast or the ire genetic seeds
bill is going to appreciate that so
follow the money and also
uh if you don't shop at that small
mom-and-pop shop every time you need
something
when you do need something that only
they carry that place might not be there
if you go to walmart if you go to home
depot if you go to lowe's and you've got
a couple of questions hey bill
what's the best way to do this maybe you
get somebody at home depot or lowe's
that's slightly competent
competent that might be the word i tried
to say but if you go talk to bill at
bill's hardware
bill will have six or seven different
ideas on how to do it he'll find out
which is the best idea for you he'll
walk you up and down the aisles
build you a little shopping cart or the
[ __ ] that's gonna work best for you
shake your hand and wish you the best
and send you on your way
when you come back in two or three days
with pictures of the job on your phone
bill's gonna high-five you
you guys are gonna be friends you're
gonna be part of the community not just
walking into a big box
being another zombie with a credit card
leaving with a bunch of plastic
[ __ ] going home and hoping you've got
what you've got and giving our money to
the waltons and china so that was kind
of a weird long rant for a podcast about
cannabis
but let's follow the money when we're
shopping let's
follow the money conscious spending
conscious shopping conscious consuming
uh vote with your dollars man that's
basically what i'm trying to say
so when you're gonna buy a product if
you can
buy a locally sourced product if you can
i understand that not everything is made
everywhere
buy something local if it's not made
local buy it from a store that is local
and if not then think about where is the
money going
once i buy this hopefully it goes to a
local grow store
so that bill's gross store gets to pay
their bills they get to pay the light
bill they get to pay the rent then bill
gets to pay his mortgage and buy some
groceries
take care of the family that's always a
feel-good feeling right
then hopefully that money is going to a
company that is making a quality product
and not using a bunch of crappy uh
imported or
half-assed ingredients hopefully we're
trying to keep our money close to home
with people that we care about
instead of just watching it go blindly
just causes which we do not support
all right i feel like i've spent enough
time on that message uh
let's see do you want your name shouted
out i don't see your name on here at all
so i'm not going to give you
an uh shout out by name but you know who
you are thank you for the great message
and thank you
for sparking a great line of ranting on
this episode of the podcast
all right this next message came from
the grow help tab on my website that's
right if you go to the website
iriegenetics.com on the top bar there is
a grow help tab click on that
you will be able to ask a grow question
and ask for grow advice
we do ask a few preliminary questions
before we get there we ask your name
what strain you're growing if you're
growing indoors or outdoors you will see
the questionnaire if you do go to the
website and jump on that
grow help tab just click on that it'll
get you right to it then you can ask
your question
this question comes from our friend
newbie nuggs
they're growing granddaddy perp to
platinum cookies uh they're growing it
indoors they're in flower
let's see let's get right to the
question here because it says my
question
is on cutting clones for sexing so i've
talked about this in a previous episode
if you want to find out if you've got
male or female plants and you don't want
to wait till they get real
big you can cut a clone you can put that
clone in your rapid rooter under your
dome
put it under 1212 lighting and quite
quickly it will tell you if it's a male
or a female
then you'll know if the plant which that
clone came from was a boy or a girl and
you know if you need to continue working
with that plant or if you can get rid of
it
so that catches you up it says now
i am practicing saving for a dragon
punch and lemon sunrise for this march
good choices my friend those will grow
well in your garden it says i've never
ran
regular seeds as i have a five plant
limit over five
inches so i'm practicing and i took one
of my cuts
of the granddaddy purple candyland plant
and put it in
soil with mycorrhizae and dipped it in
cloning gel
so you got a clone so you've got a five
plant limit which uh that's very
restrictive and you want to grow some
regular seeds that's understandable
uh we gotta find out which are the males
and females so we don't grow the males
up too big and waste time
so you are doing a test run to find out
how to
sex your plants by doing quick clones uh
you took cuts
you took a cut of the gdp candyland
plant put it in soil with micros dipped
it in cloning gel
immediately put it into the flowering
tent and in a couple of days
you had pre flowers yes ah sounds like
you're doing it right so far
i let it go for another four days
steadily increasing flowering activity
i pulled it and obviously no roots yeah
it hasn't had time for roots at that
point but
it said i had no proper rooting
parameters or dome it was just a test oh
it wasn't even in a dome that's pretty
amazing
uh it's kind of amazing that it lived
this long uh
over four days in there without a dome
that's pretty killer good job man that's
uh that's good luck
it says is this a typical case on sexing
cuts does it usually happen this quickly
and flower without roots or was i lucky
this would help me in culling males
quickly
to see uh what meets our laws
here so it doesn't usually happen
that quickly i think you got kind of
lucky with the four days
but usually seven to ten days you'll be
able to tell if you've got males or
females within that time frame
what i think may have happened and i
think we've corresponded since this
what i think may have happened you may
have taken your cuts from the top of the
plant
and the tops are where there are more
hormones those plants are a little bit
more
or the tops are more ready to go into
flower all the hormones have moved up to
the top
so that the parts you cut we're like
hell yeah let's go into flour
when you took it away from the main part
of the plant it kind of went into panic
mode i was like i don't know what the
[ __ ]
to do man he took the roots away from me
you changed the light cycle
so it flowered super quickly it had a
couple of reasons
to go into flower really quickly so i
think that is why that happened
uh in my experience that is quicker than
it's ever happened than i have ever seen
so you got lucky there
and if it was a male that's a powerful
potent male that i would not breed with
i would skip him because he is too much
male for a breeding project that's a
good example of one to toss
to pass on to get to let go so i think
um
and then i think you did respond and say
that it was lower branches
so that plant was just big enough and it
was happy enough and it was ready to go
into flour
when you did that you just had a nice
happy healthy plant with a lot of
active hormones going on when you cut
that clone you didn't do any damage to
it when you potted it and you put that
mico
on the rooting gel on there you kept it
completely happy
and it just went into flour for you
because it was in the ideal conditions
to go into flour
uh you did something right man because
most of the time if you cut a clone and
do not put it in a dome
within a few days like that it will
wither up and it will fall over and die
so maybe you're on to something i hope
you took good notes i hope you remember
exactly what you did so you can do it
again and again and again because this
will be a very effective way
to learn how to cull those boys from
your garden i feel like there's a little
bit more to this podcast so let's ke or
this uh not the podcast to this uh
what is that this is a question that's
what this is um
let's keep reading so i can put my brain
back on some sort of a track here
uh it says oh that plant was probably in
panic mode because it got so it flipped
that's was the
the bottom line there then it says i
love the show and i want you to know i
will be joining patreon
soon ah thank you man no stress on
joining patreon
uh no rush on that it says i definitely
want to support everything you do
financially
i will be ordering two packs of lemon
sunrise and dragon punch this month and
then next month
i will join the army in full i know 10
bucks a month will not break me
but i live my life financially like i do
my grow very
disciplined um my friend it is weird
times right now
ah money is not guaranteed right now
income is not promised
tomorrow is not promised things can go
very strangely in these times
so uh you stay disciplined keep that
wallet tight keep the budget tight and
conserve those funds
i'm doing okay right now i had a good
couple of months so don't stress out
get those seeds get the garden going if
you need more help you let me know
and i'll look forward to the patreon
contributions but don't feel like you've
got to contribute to patreon that is not
required
you notice i'm still reading your
message still giving you a big salute
and a fist bump
uh nothing but love and respect for you
either way i understand you guys
a lot of people had to actually cancel
their patreon support in the past couple
of months because of
the pandy and don't feel bad about it i
want you
uh it's called grow from your heart i
want you to be happy i want you to have
what you need
i want you to feel love and feel safe
and secure and if
10 bucks is going to mess up your family
your life this month don't give it to me
i will be okay i'd rather you buy 10
more bucks worth of groceries maybe 10
more bucks worth of weed
uh maybe 10 more bucks for the kids
maybe who knows what it's for but if you
need it just use it man
i'm not going to feel bad i appreciate
you i love you i respect you either way
i've got a seed company that will keep
me going if the patreon doesn't do it
the seeds will do it if the seeds don't
do it patreon will do it and if those
don't fail some consulting will cover it
up
job will provide i will be okay so thank
you guys uh for the support but don't
ever feel like you've got to do it
especially my friend newbie nuggs get
the garden dialed in
live on that tight budget i do
understand it is coveted
times things can go weird at any moment
right now uh so there's more to this
it says there is a time empty pods and a
money envelope dedicated to you
just has to run its course so my friends
got some time
uh empty pot so that he could put the
seeds in and a money envelope so we
could start throwing some funding in so
we could help out the patreon
just has to run its course i understand
that bro time has got to run its course
hopefully after this pandy goes away
we'll get able to get back able to play
again get able to make some money again
live life like we used to do it he wraps
up with
thanks for taking the time to read this
hey my friend thank you for taking the
time
to type this and to send it if you ever
have any more questions you know how to
find me
of course this did come from the website
the grow help tab
at iregenetics.com
all right ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls pimps and hoes friends and foes
smokers growers clone cutters paul and
chuckers all you beautiful people out
there
i want to thank each and every one of
you for listening to episode 616 of the
grow from your heart podcast
it blows my mind every time i say the
episode numbers you guys
have you ever done anything 616 times
consistently
wow thank you guys for following me for
joining me for supporting me i truly
mean it every time i say that
my life is blessed i feel spoiled and i
couldn't be here without
each and every one of you every one of
you is a big piece
to the ivory army a big piece to the
grow from your heart puzzle
thank you i appreciate all of you if you
feel like this episode was educational
informative and or entertaining
if you'd like to make a financial
contribution to the show once again all
you have to do is visit
www.patreon forward slash grow from your
heart
all of the information you need is right
there on the screen once again big
thanks to everybody for supporting the
show
if you've got any questions corrections
comments or concerns
i'd love to hear from you the email
address is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com don't be shy send me an
email
make some new friends i apologize if i
have not answered your email right
right away or yet if you're still
waiting be patient one of my new years
my main new year's resolution was to be
better at answering emails
i'm trying there's one of me there are
thousands of you i'll answer the message
i'll get to it just be patient with me
also support the website
iriegenetics.com all things roster jeff
all things grow from your heart
all right iriegenetics.com go to
iregenetics.com sign up for the
newsletter there's a spot where you can
sign up for a newsletter
very soon i will be sending out a coupon
code for another thing
i'll be sending out some updates where
some seeds have been dropped where some
new merchandise is available
so stay posted stay updated that's what
i'm trying to say uh by going to
iriegenetics.com and of course don't
forget about the discord server
we're having a party on discord without
you
come join us that is all i've got for
you for this episode
uh thank you guys again for listening i
want to send a big rest in peace and a
big shout out to bunny whaler
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
you