[Music]
yeah welcome back podcast world i'm your
host my friends call me rosta jeff
and this is episode 619 of the grow from
your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to read a few
grow questions before we get there
let's do a few shout outs to a few
members of the 710 club
of course the 710 club or the folks who
support us on patreon
at the 7 and 10 cent a month level or
higher
so with no further ado let's start off
with the big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to my friend
frankie
let's send a special thank you shout out
to cincy 11 jr
let's send a big thank you shout out to
stash drop 269.
listen to thank you shout out to evil
grow and darren h
let's send a big thank you shout out to
shotgun yoda and mister
let's send a thank you shout out to kiwi
monsta and newby nuggs
let's send a big thank you shout out to
sticky randy's garden and kentucky fried
and let's wrap it up with the big grow
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out
to my friend jordan curl
thanks and big shout out to everybody
who continues to support the show on
patreon
if you are not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do that
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need to
support the show will be right there on
the screen
and you know i did include a link in the
show notes and the video description
to make it super easy for all of my
friends all right ladies and gentlemen
welcome to the show welcome to episode
619 i'm excited for this episode
let me start off by sending a big thank
you to everybody who has joined
the irie genetics ire army grow from
your heart
podcast discord server we recently
reached over 500 members on the discord
channel
thank you that means a lot to me big
thanks to the gang the crew that fired
up that discord
i am not there enough i hang out a
little bit in the discord
i've got a lot going on i need to be
breeding seeds packaging seeds doing
podcasts
but you guys are killing it on the
discord i am excited
i am elated i'm delighted there are a
bunch of words a bunch of big
hallmark sounding words that i want to
use to describe how i feel
about the way you guys are supporting
irie genetics the grow from your heart
podcast
all things ross to jeff it blows my mind
thank you
the community that is sprouted from this
show this company
is amazing it is overwhelming it's
tremendous it means a lot to me
and i can't stop thanking you enough so
thank you guys uh thank you to the
people who created it
the people who sustain it and the people
who just hang out in there and
participate
you all mean a lot to me big salute to
the entire irie army
all right what else do i want to talk
about before we get to the main part of
this email or as this episode here
the email part of this episode excuse
the new tongue i'm just getting used to
this new face
i'll learn how to talk with it pretty
soon here i've only had it for 42 years
now
just getting used to this english thing
um i am on another podcast on thursdays
occasionally i join the embracing
organics crew for their podcast we've
got a really nice panel
uh shout out to my buddy dirt man dan
and the entire embracing organics crew
but occasionally on thursdays i joined
the crew for an embracing organics
podcast the show is
on youtube it happens live on thursdays
it goes out uh we record approximately 7
10 p.m
mountain time on thursdays the show is
live at that time
i'll say the time again i go on at 7 10
p.m mountain time on thursday on youtube
simply search for embracing organics
you'll find the show i am not on every
single episode
but i hang out quite often i try to be
there every other episode
but scheduling life things are weird
sometimes they have another guest where
i feel like i could just let that guest
shine and i don't need to be there
what i'm getting at is on the embracing
organics
show that is coming up on thursday i am
recording today is the
uh 10th i believe the show will be on
the 11th by the time this comes out it
will already have happened
but i encourage you to go back and watch
it because if all things go correctly
we will be doing an edibles challenge on
that show and i will have eaten
a ridiculous amount of edibles and i
invite you to come hang out watch the
show
see what happened it hasn't happened yet
to be honest i'm talking to you in the
future
the show comes out in the future i'm
talking about another show that's
recorded in the future
but i'm pretty sure we're gonna have a
good time so i encourage you
to check out that show this will come
out monday so that show will have
already been out for a couple of days if
you have not watched
the embracing organics edibles challenge
i highly suggest you watch that it's got
to be a good time
i've got quite a bit of edibles that i'm
going to eat ah
i might [ __ ] my whole night up this
could be fun i invite you to come watch
all right now let's move into something
more serious i've got some emails
for this episode uh this email came from
the patreon inbox of course if you want
your questions answered patreon is the
quickest way to get them to the top of
the list
at patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart this one comes from our
friend tonto what's up tonto shout out
to my buddy up there in canada
hope you're doing well this one goes a
lot like this it says
hello rasta man i know you're busy uh
you know i'm thankful
all for all you do and i know that your
time is valuable
so let's get right to the question thank
you man that's uh that makes it really
easy
big salute for that one it says i
believe that i missed a nanner somewhere
in my recent crop
because my wife and i have found some
seeds while trimming
first of all big shout out to your wife
for helping you trim trimming sucks and
if you can find someone to do it with
you
that's a good person that's a good wife
she deserves a hug and a high five buy
her some good food and some fancy shoes
because she's helping you trim that's an
awesome wife shout out to the trim crew
goes on to say i don't believe the
plants had any pollen sacks as i have
shown my wife what to look for in the
garden
but not nanners i'm also not ruling this
out either
so our friend thinks that they have
found possibly could have found uh
nanners or missed nanners in their
garden because they did find seeds
uh what do i mean by nanners nanners are
what we call
male flowers that pop up in a female
plant so the plant has got
intersex traits or herbaphroditic
tendencies it's got a it's a female
plant they just showed
male sex parts in flower so a nano we
call it a banana because it just looks
like a little banana
that pops up out of your flowers
oftentimes they come in clusters
and it looks like a little bunch of
hanging bananas so we call those a
banana
what we were talking about is a male
flower
or a male flower popping up on a female
plant that is now showing us that it is
hermaphroditic and that one manner that
one male flower can produce pollen
which will then produce seeds in our
garden
so our buddy tonto found a few seeds
while trimming
he doesn't believe he had any pollen
sacks because he's shown his wife what
to look for but she doesn't know to look
for nanners
so that is very possible a lot of things
could have caused this one of the plants
could have just
stressed out and seeded itself there
could have been pollen from another
plant somewhere
one of the plants could have hermed
there are a lot of opportunities to make
this happen until you
actually look really closely and realize
what happened you'll never know
unless you find the nanner find the
pollen chucker find the light leak find
the issue
it's going to be a big question mark but
here's what we can do
it says my question is would these seeds
be considered good
or would they be untrustworthy i did a
quick google search but the results were
mainly forum based answers
which are always taken with the grain of
salt that is the way to take any forum
answers
social media answers forum answers [ __ ]
anything i say
should be taken with a grain of salt
always do your own research
always realize that those people are
doing things their way some people may
say oh you need to spray it with this
and do this but they have no idea what
you're doing and their suggestion may
[ __ ] you all
up so yes every piece of advice that you
read should be taken with a giant
chunk of salt it goes on to say i will
grow these out regardless
uh per out of pure curiosity and it is
my personal grow
i won't be giving these seeds or plant
to anyone out for obvious reasons that
is a man with good ethics
good morals that understands the risks
that are available in these seeds
it goes on to say on a personal note i
wanted to give a shout out
to parkland flower here in alberta
canada
even though i am unreliable due to my
injuries during my service
bro thank you for your service by the
way you are a service member and we got
to give you a big thank you for that
especially since you've been injured uh
providing your canadian service
it says um they are giving me the
opportunity to grow and learn at the
commercial level
which i think is such a kind thing to do
that is a beautiful blessing you are a
blessed lucky man
uh embrace that engage as much as you
can
ask a lot of questions but not too many
don't try to teach them how you grow
your growth try to learn how they grow
theirs
uh good job man congratulations and big
shout out to our friends at parkland
flower
in alberta canadia for giving my buddy
tonto
an opportunity i appreciate that um
and dude use all of the knowledge you've
gained here from the podcast in that
commercial grow and you will shine
now let's address the actual question
the issue at hand the reason this
message was sent
our buddy tanto has got some seeds that
randomly appeared in his garden
he doesn't know if there was a
hermaphrodite he doesn't know if there
was a light leak
we don't know what caused these seeds
these seeds will be known as
bag seed this is bag seed it's
questionable seeds we know what the
female plant was because we've got the
buds we can tell you that much of it
we do not know who the pollen donor was
we don't know who the baby daddy is
we got a mori povich situation here so
the question is
are these seeds worth the [ __ ] can i
trust them or are they problematic
i don't know just as much as you don't
know
i don't know what's in those seeds at
all they could be
uh feminized they could be intersex
they could be beautiful females they
could be amazing mutants they could be
the most amazing [ __ ] flowers you've
ever grown if you think about it
in my opinion to the best of my
knowledge all of the chem dog
lineage was a mistake those were seeds
that were found in buds read about chem
dog and the legend of the 13 seeds
you'll realize that a lot of the most
popular cannabis we were smoking
came from what was known as bag seed
seeds that were accidentally made
chem dog bought a bag of weed he found
seeds in there he grew the seeds
those seeds became the popular chem
lines we work with now chem 91 kim d
kim's sister all came from a bag of weed
they were all bag seed
those are strains that set the precedent
and expectation
for the future of cannabis they changed
the world the landscape of growing
breeding cannabis production consumption
now all people want to talk about is
chem and kush
because chem dog found those seeds in
that bag of weed so
you could have the next chem dog golden
goat was an accident golden goat
happened in a very similar manner to
what your seeds did
we all know how popular and in demand
golden goat is
i think girl scout cookies was an
accident gorilla glue number four
was an accident so there are a lot of
things that were
bred created this way there were
accidents
and they became stellar products so you
could have some
complete [ __ ] or you could have the
next
legend in that bag of seeds that you
have got there
you're doing it the right way don't give
them out don't let other people have
them because they could be problematic
also don't let other people have them
because they could be the [ __ ] gems
that make you famous
ah but you're doing it right grow them
yourself
keep a good eye on them while you're
growing know that you've got big
question marks on those seeds they were
free but they could be
hermaphrodites they could be intersex
they could be ticking time bombs
or they could be ticking awards i don't
really know
what else to other advice to give you
because uh until you grow them you do
not know that is the beauty of a bag
seed
so just like those forum members were
saying it could be anything and take all
of that advice with a grain of salt and
again take mine with a grain of salt
there's no way to tell what's in there
they could be amazing
they could be females they could be
males the way to do it is to grow it out
pay close attention to it through the
entire cycle now is when you really have
to start learning how to pay attention
to nanners
teach the wife what to look for in
intersex plants
look high look low anytime you stress
that plan out do anything weird do it
watch how it responds make sure you
don't get any hermaphroditism
any intersex traits you don't see any
manners it doesn't go completely weird
on you
also take a lot of pictures of it
because you might want to document this
because you may have
hot fire in there you may have the next
chem dog you may have the next girl
scout cookies golden goat gorilla glue
uh og tonto's kush going on in there and
we don't even know it yet
so grow those out and see what you've
got and
take clones when you grow them because
what if you're growing the most amazing
[ __ ] ever
and you don't have a clone on of it that
is going to be completely heartbreaking
so my buddy tonto my advice is grow them
see what you got get some clones and if
they're worth the [ __ ] grow them forever
then send me a clone if it's hot fire
all right the wraps it up with i hope
everything
coming up for you is irie much love from
our friend
tonto tonto thank you for the great
question i look forward to seeing
what you have created did you make fire
did you make some crazy mutants
let me know what you've got going on in
the garden i look forward to the update
also shout out to all my canadian
friends all right i do have another
question
this one also came from the patreon
let's see whose name they want me to use
they didn't sign it with the name so
we're going to skip that part
it goes a lot like this it says yo rasta
jeff i can't thank you enough for the
podcast uh you thank me
by sending these messages and you thank
me every month by contributing to
patreon
so thank you for that continued support
it is a very good exchange
it says i travel the state of oklahoma
fixing big yellow earth moving equipment
i think i used to be a courier that
delivered parts for your big yellow
earth-moving equipment had a bunch of
blades and [ __ ] in the truck all the
time used to stop there all the time
fun job dude it says i clock a lot of
miles on the road while listening to the
podcast which has helped my garden
tremendously
isn't that awesome that you can get an
education and kill time while you're in
the car
and then turn around and make your
garden look better that's [ __ ]
awesome i hope you're getting paid for
those hours too
that'd be super cool anyway it goes on
it says
um my question can you suggest a source
for genetics that are in close
representation
to key cannabis flavors so that say i
wanted to grow a good kush
or other key can so uh okay
i kind of stumbled on part of what he's
saying here but you guys are getting the
point
i wanted to grow a good kush or other
key cannabis flavors
much like you've done with the golden
goat strain so what this person
basically wants to do it says
i want to where is it i want to build i
want to smoke and build a palette much
like a sommelier
studies their palette for wine did i say
that word correctly because i just read
it off the page and i think i got it
right i didn't even study that one
until legalization you just got what the
guy had but now
with the passion for growing i'd like to
build my palette so that when the bud
tender says this is the gaseous gas or
the stinkiest cush
i can know if they're telling the truth
or just trying to make a sale
your golden goat is up next in my garden
much love and keep it ire this is a
great interesting question
especially for me since i talk a lot
about terps and flavors and aromas
and people tell me that i've got a
magical terp nose or that i smell terps
and flavors differently that i taste
things a little bit
more vividly than a lot of people we
recently discovered that i have got
something called synesthesia where i
smell and taste in colors
so my palate and my tasting and
flavoring thing is vivid and quite more
active than a lot of people
so i like this question talking about
how to develop your palate
and understand the flavors i thought
about
how to go about doing this and the only
way i can think of doing this is
try a lot of samples this is going to be
the fun part the way that the sommelier
gets good with wine is he tries a lot of
samples
with the sommelier he takes a little sip
swishes it around gets a taste
spits that [ __ ] out the fun part about
being the weed sommanier
is we're going to take a dab we're going
to smoke a bowl we're going to hold that
[ __ ] in and get the buzz and enjoy it
we don't have to spit it out every time
so the first thing that i would say is
smoke a lot of product you're gonna have
to uh
travel around to a lot of places and buy
a lot of product
whenever you're you say you travel
around a lot stop at a dispensary
everywhere you go
and get something if you can afford it i
don't know what your budget is i don't
know what you're trying to do but
get as much product as you can get just
grab an eighth or a gram here and there
and make sure they're well labeled maybe
when you go to the dispensary get
two different products that are vastly
different get a cushy thing
and a bubble gum flavored thing or like
a golden goat and an og kush you got
that tropical
and that funky so you can really tell
there's a difference this is going to
tell you
if the dispensary and that grow has a
difference in their product because a
lot of dispensaries all the product will
taste
very similar so now you've got a
guideline on how their product tastes if
it's all similar or if it's different
then you can smoke those two different
products and you can see
how does the og kush taste you can kind
of say i bought
jeff so g at this place it tastes gassy
cushy mothballs and swamp and then i
bought strawberry starburst at this
other place
and it tastes just like a strawberry
starburst to make notes then go to
another place
and buy another kind of kush and another
fruity thing and make notes on those
and try to just remember when i smoked
the strawberry one it tastes like
strawberry bubble gum when i smoke the
og kush it tastes like mothballs
just develop that palette smoke a lot of
samples smoke a lot of strains
but what you're gonna have to do is
verify that what you're smoking is
actually what
you think you're smoking some
dispensaries anything with the word og
or chem will sell so if i've got
strawberry something and it's not
selling
i'm gonna put the word strawberry kush
on it it will sell more quickly
and the dispensary will trick you and
now your research is kind of tainted
so you're gonna have to smoke a lot of
samples and develop develop that palette
just by smoking it that's the way that
foodies do it that's the way the
sommelier does it
just a lot of consumption a lot of
memory a lot of note taking
a lot of experience experience builds a
lot experience is
something you can't buy it's something
that you just have to do and that
develops a lot of uh
details a lot of knowledge the
experience will develop your knowledge
so try a lot of samples develop that
palette for various notes look for
things
uh try to be able to identify gas you
want to be able to smoke gas and fuel
identify that gas everybody wants gas
and fuel
then be able to identify earth look for
that like earthy
sort of earthy dirt coffee sort of a
smell be able to identify that in your
cannabis
then be able to identify the fruitier
flavors that come from cannabis you're
going to get your strawberries
your blueberries your oranges try to
identify that
then get good at finding the floral
notes that come from cannabis
so now you're kind of breaking it into
categories we're getting that earthy
stuff we're getting the gassy stuff
once you've got categories then you can
kind of say well this og kush falls in
the earthy gassy category the strawberry
starburst was in the berries
and floral maybe a little bit of
tropical category then you can start
kind of making
subcategories once you get the gas you
can go with
chemicals and diesel fuel or regular
feel or cleaners and [ __ ] like that
then once you get earth dialed in you'll
taste like dirt and mud
and swamp and mothballs and then you
break off into like
feet and funky [ __ ] like that then once
you get that fruity palette developed
you'll be able to tell the difference
between like oranges and blueberries and
strawberries
that's one that'll come natural to you
you're already tasting those things
all the time in your life everything is
flavored with berries and fruits
so those flavors and aromas should be
easy to discern and separate and
identify so you got your fruity palate
then that breaks down into like
berries tropicals and citrus then
you're also going to get that floral
thing where you're going to get stuff
like
lavender and lilacs and you're going to
get those hints of perfumey things
so basically start finding categories to
put flavors into
then find subcategories for those
flavors and smoke a lot of [ __ ]
and see which categories those fall into
you'll make your own
kind of bracketing system your own
judging system and you'll find out how
to categorize all this stuff in your
head how to compartmentalize all of your
notes in your head
but really just start smoking it with
purpose pay attention
um have a clean bowl a clean pipe or a
clean bong whichever your preferred
method is
clean your damn dab rig i see a lot of
bongs pipes and rigs that are filthy i'm
[ __ ] guilty my dab rig gets so dirty
sometimes
but clean that [ __ ] up and your product
will taste better ah you'll just get
more flavor out of it you'll get those
terps
so um just buy a lot of [ __ ] and smoke
it dude
i know that doesn't sound like a real
scientific approach but uh
experience will build your knowledge so
just find the things you want to smoke
and smoke them and then you'll start
seeing that
things that say kush kind of fall into
this cushy bracket there's
like a a dirty foot swampy
mothball gassy sort of a thing that
happens with kush and then you'll find
out that all the diesels
have this diesel sort of aroma you'll
find that hazes
have sort of a spicy sandalwood sort of
a peppery
uh maybe you'll get a lavender smell out
of some some hazes also but you'll start
finding
the commonalities in all of these things
then you'll start being able to smoke
something you'll take here you go
oh man i could taste the chem dog in
that and you'll get there you'll really
get there
then one day maybe once you're around it
a lot if you're in different grows
exposed to different nutrients and
products
you'll take your hit off the joint
you'll go damn you guys used way too
many worm castings in that
that's the kind of palette that you'll
be able to develop in the future i can
taste certain nutrients i can taste
products that were used in the grow
it's all about experience and you don't
know what [ __ ] smells like
excuse me you don't know what [ __ ]
smells like unless you've smelled some
[ __ ] so you got to get out in the world
and smell things
smell products when you're at the store
take a minute just smell the oranges
smell the bananas smell the watermelons
i know we all think we know what they
smell like but just smell stuff
just take a time take a minute and then
just enjoy things when you're walking
around the flowers
pick up a wildflower give it a smell
enjoy that simple stuff also when the
ladies see you taking a moment to just
stop and smell the flowers they see
something in you you're enjoying and
appreciating the world around you
enjoy that world appreciate it put your
phone away for a moment and smell some
stuff
add that to your your arsenal your
repertoire your
memory your uh your aromatic memory i
guess we're gonna call it your olfactory
memory
that way when you smell that in cannabis
you can go oh that smells like
lilacs or that smells like uh
honeysuckles
or that smells like dog poop just go
smell some stuff and then you have other
things to compare that to
and sorry i sniffled into the microphone
when i tried to do that scent thing for
you
i got that deviated septum and it's
rocking today anyway
get us back on track here the one thing
that's going to throw you off
is a mislabeled product that's one thing
that will definitely screw you all up if
you're testing a product that you think
is
orange kush and it's [ __ ] orange haze
and you mark it down in your mental
notes as orange cushy just [ __ ] up all
the results but
i think you're gonna be okay you're
smart enough you're human you can adjust
your notes and details and data entry
that way
uh i just wish that people wouldn't do
things like that to mess you
up then there are going to be things
like
if i grow if i had og kush and you had
og kush and five of our friends had og
kush
there will be variables in that grow
it's gonna taste smell
burn and affect you a little bit
differently based on my environment
that's a phenotypical expression if my
room's a little bit more humid
maybe i'll get stickier buds if your
room's a little dryer maybe you'll get
fluffier buds
if my room's warmer maybe i'll get
airier buds if your room is cooler maybe
you'll get more dense buds
all of these things will have a role on
the flavor
and effect of that finished product also
drying and curing
will have a huge difference and effect
and roll on the outcome of that product
if it's not dried and cured and
processed properly
well the same plant you can cut buds off
of one plant
and buds off the same plant dried one
one way and one the other way they could
taste completely differently
so things like that you'll learn how to
taste a proper drying cure
while you're learning to identify
different strains so that'll be fun for
you
i'm looking at my notes to make sure
i've covered everything the bottom line
here is
experience will develop knowledge test a
lot of samples
and ask a lot of questions and then my
last note was
eat stuff and experience smells you're
going to have to be around
non-cannabis things to expand your
uh your nose and your mouth palate your
flavor and your aroma palate
be around things that smell go to the
zoo go to the botanical garden
go to the store go to the farmer's
market go to the farm
be exposed to all types of different
smells and aromas
go to the restaurant smell the desserts
smell the entrees
just go smell a bunch of things and put
it's like learning words your vocabulary
gets better as you're exposed to
different words
your smells will get broader your
identifications will get better as
you're exposed
to more smells all right um
do i have your name no i don't think you
want me to say your name so i'm going to
skip that
um but dude thank you for the great
patreon message
and let me know how this goes if you've
got any more questions if i can steer
you
in a better direction to help you more
let me know because basically i just
told you to go smoke a bunch of weed and
smell a bunch of [ __ ]
but honestly i feel like that is the way
to uh develop
these skills yeah i wish you the best of
luck in your cannabis
somanie quest uh thank you for the great
message
i want to thank everybody for all the
continued patreon support and the
patreon messages
it is time for me to wrap up this
episode if you feel like this episode
was educational informative or
entertaining
and you would like to make a financial
contribution to the show once again all
you have to do is visit
slash grow www.patreon.com your heart
all of the information you need is right
there on the screen
serious you guys thank you for all that
patreon support it does mean the world
to me
also all that discord support is
impressive and blows my mind
if you've got any questions corrections
comments or concerns i would love to
hear from you the email address is grow
from your heart at hotmail.com
don't be shy send me a message i'd love
to get to you also if you send me an
email don't feel like i'm blowing you
off
i am recorded a couple of weeks of ahead
so if i don't answer your message
right away on the show sometimes i'm
just recorded ahead i've got shows
written
i'll write your question in the show and
it will come up just be patient with me
some people say hey i asked you a
question on sunday you didn't answer it
monday
give me a couple of mondays to get into
the rotation you never know how the
recording schedule
and the writing has happened just be
patient with me i will get to you
thank you also make sure you check out
my website iriegenetics.com
all things ire genetics all things grow
from your heart podcast all things ross
to jeff
are all there at iregenetics.com you can
find seed vendors
you can find out where to buy your sweet
irie genetics t-shirts and hats
uh the newsletter is there the grow help
tab is there
a link to patreon is there everything
you need is at iregenetics.com
before i go let me invite you to follow
me on
cannabuzz cannabis is a free cannabis
friendly social media application
it's available for your apple or android
mobile device
you cannot buy sell or trade cannabis on
cannabis
but we do invite you to post your
cannabis photography post your garden
pictures
post your dab videos post your duck face
weed smoking videos
post all that stuff up on cannabis we
would love to see you cannabis it is
free
download that for your phone create an
account log in
give me a follow i'm irie underscore
genetics on cannabis
i do a lot of fun [ __ ] on there i post a
lot of great pictures i answer a lot of
great questions
i do a few seat auctions come join the
community
on cannabaz catch the buzz follow me
there
i look forward to seeing you i think
that is all i've got for this episode
yep i'm looking at my notes i've done it
all you guys i want to thank you again
for listening to another episode you
know i'll be back in just a couple of
days with fresh new content
i want to give a giant shout out to my
swaziland bush grower friends
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you