yeah what's up cannabis Community it's
time for episode 62 of the grow from
your heart podcast your source for
Cannabis News education and conversation
if you're a new grower or a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a and
Dabber if you're on probation and you
can't smoke if you're a cannabis
activist or someone who's just curious
about the current state of cannabis this
my friends is the podcast for you I'm
your host roster Jeff thanks again for
joining me I want to send a huge thank
you shout out to the Mystic rootsman for
letting me use their music on the show
big huge thanks to cat and coot and the
entire Mystic Roots crew thanks for
letting me play the music the song
you're hearing right now is called the
constant struggle so sitting at the
table with me is our new guest Mr Paul
Rosales how you doing my friend good
should I say your whole name or is that
not a good thing no that's fine all
right I thought about right after I said
it and across the table from me is a
returning guest we got Clint Stewart
with us how you doing bro what's up
everybody hey everybody hey guys I'm
going to turn down that music so we can
talk a little bit how you guys doing
today doing good I'm so high my voice
got higher everybody's High except me a
well can we talk about why you're not
high you yeah yeah no no go for it uh
Paul happens to be on probation he was a
bad little boy I was got himself in
trouble we won't talk about what he did
cuz I don't even know I uh killed a man
just to watch him die nice I heard
there's a song somebody wrote about
wrote about Jim cash I'm not Jim cash is
that who else that was Jim Carrey Jim
Carrey wrote a song okay let's like it
so before we go down this road I want to
warn everybody listening these men are
Comedians and this could be uh a funny
episode you never know what's going to
come out of these boys' mouths if you've
listened to previous episodes with Clint
they've already got funny [ __ ] to say
because they see them already holding
back jokes if you've listened to any
previous episodes with Clint Clint is a
jokester this will be a very
entertaining episode I'll make sure of
it Clint will make sure of it
um since we're talking that you guys are
comedians let's just drop a plug right
away where can the kind folks ofo or
color see you this will come out um like
the second week of April so you're going
to have to plan your plugs in advance
well you can see us um every every
Thursday at the rainbow for the uh wild
cousins comedy open mic that's in PLO on
Santa Fe the Rainbow Bar April 7th uh we
have a show also at the rainbow uh for
$5 you can see Mary Mack who has uh been
on a bunch of stuff she's been on uh
Last Comic
Standing and um bunch of different
comedy festivals and apparently she did
a voice on uh aquatine Hunger Force so
uh who was she on aquatine do you know I
have no idea was she Carl yes yes I
think so I think she uh that time they
had Rush on there she played Getty Lee
nice
nice That's April 7th uh she's coming
with her husband who's uh been on
Letterman I'm spacing the name right now
but you should just come check it out
and come check us out every Thursday at
the rainbow yeah this will come out the
day before that I think so I think this
will come out the 6th I'm looking at my
phone right now trying to find the
calendar so the seventh you guys go
tomorrow night if you're listening to
this on the 6th go to the Rainbow Bar
it's in peblo um I have a friend who
thought that was in Colorado Springs
yeah they drove to Colorado Springs they
looked for the Rainbow Bar yep and they
realized that it's in PUO so they drove
back home and by the time they got there
I think they missed your show yeah well
that happens it's all right it's free
every week come down um it's it's a
really nice room too we get free pizza
and a free drink so that's so what
qualifies me as a comedian do I get up
and tell a joke yeah just get up there
and tell a joke get some pizza there we
go guys come do open mic night at the
rainbow and a free beer H yeah yeah and
a free beer you can have my free beer if
I go get one yeah cuz I don't need the
beer yeah awesome yeah same here
actually now you're drinking again
aren't you I don't
drink two men in the room that three men
in the room that don't drink alcohol
does not agree with me I do stupid [ __ ]
and so I don't do it I'm allergic to
alcohol I break out in handcuffs and fat
chicks yeah I just get I get really
angry and I say stuff that I don't mean
but I do that sober so I don't know if
that's how it just like multiplies when
you it gives it another level takes it
all out all right uh before we go too
far I should do the commercials because
we're going to get into this
conversation I can already tell uh huge
huge shout out to burn and Jesse and the
entire crew Ladon I'm not going to skip
you at H gr indoor growing supplies uh
make sure you visit hyro indoor growing
supplies they have two locations the
Denver store 6271 Beach Street stre or
the beautiful peblo location 618 East
4th Street check out high grow for
competitive pricing and a great
selection of indoor growing supplies
check it out guys when you go there make
sure you tell them that you listen to
The Grow from your heart podcast and
they will give you commercial pricing on
everything you purchase uh right now
they've got little clone pots on sale
for a penny like what are you going to
do for a penny dude go get some of those
I saw an ad today that they had uh hux
bulbs on sale for a ridiculous price I
think they were $69.99 for 1,000 watt
horux bulb go to High gr indoor growing
supplies get that [ __ ] tell them you
listen to the show support a local
business that's cool yeah yeah super
cool also the organic portions of the
episode are sponsored by the Rocky
Mountain worm company visit the Rocky
Mountain worm company in Colorado
Springs for fresh worm castings African
nightcrawlers red wigglers and all of
your organic soil amendments that was my
nickname in college was African
Nightcrawler nice I never went to
college I was going to say I was just
going to let that fly and I wanted to it
was that one time we were flying out of
college yeah that makes you the red
wiggler bro yeah I'm down sounds like a
wrestler name that sounds like uh my dog
on his back that's a red rocket oh
that's a little different that Wiggles
I'm skipping this okay guys
if this red rocket has been brought to
you by the Rocky Mountain worm company
guys if you want Rocky Mountain worm
company uh worm castings and you are not
here in Colorado check them out Rocky
Mountain worm company.com they'll ship
you worm castings they will ship you
dragonfly Earth medicine they will send
you Bashi you can order your grok Kashi
Bucket from there or your bokashi bucket
from there yeah these guys are nodding
their heads like yeah we we know what
all this organic soil [ __ ] means we sure
do not Bashi sounds like [ __ ] it kind
of grab my attention right I'm sure I'm
sure you uh I'm just going to let you
you you fresh out fresh out of the the
lock up we're going to let you have guys
make sure you support the Rocky Mountain
worm company love those guys they help
us out a lot if you want to sponsor the
show email me it's grow from yourheart
hotmail.com I'll get you all the
information that you need all right
that's enough ads that's enough all that
stuff we've just got fun and games ahead
of us now wo woohooo comedians tell me a
joke just kidding don't you hate that
[ __ ] do people do that to you your
comedian make me laugh it happens pretty
regularly it's silly cuz I still
consider myself an open micer comedian
comedian is something I aspire to be but
um I I I I don't like it oh you're a
comedian not really I mean I'm not
getting paid for this I'm still a steel
worker I I'll consider myself a comedian
or like consider the years I've been a
comedian as like as many times is like
claiming on my taxes and [ __ ] like that
nice okay that's fair enough respect
when when you actually start getting
like booked for gigs and stuff like that
like we're just local feature guys like
open you got a lot of heart dude and
that's what takes a lot of a lot of get
a lot of it is a lot of heart and that's
what you need a lot of guys are they
just don't have the heart they want to
go up there and repeat the same [ __ ]
every week and you can tell they're just
doing it to just do it you guys got the
heart you're putting work I do it
because it it's a way for me to get all
the negative [ __ ] I'm feeling about
myself out and if I can make people
laugh from it then it kind of validates
all the shitty things that I've ever
done well Paul that's kind of a
self-righteous way to look at it I'm
kind of about it it's very personal I'm
not doing it for anybody else the way
the way Paul does his comedy self
deprecatingly yeah so like it yeah it
might sound like oh this is he's doing
it for himself and it is but it's also
like I need to tell you this it's well
it's a healthy way to get [ __ ] out it's
way cheaper than a therapist and if
you're making me laugh we're both get
therapy out of it so that's pretty cool
and and if and and a lot of the guys
will you know we're all we're always
trying new stuff there's only a few guys
that you know kind of have fallen into a
trap of not doing new stuff fairly
regularly but um it's it's fun to see
like when a joke can fail too and you
can see what he wanted to do with it and
it's like damn dude like if you'd have
Twisted this that joke would have worked
it's neat seeing that stuff so you get
to see like the initial and like why
didn't that work and then you talk about
it and oh okay and you get to see it the
next time he does it and he's got a
little bit more confidence cuz he's done
it once like open mic comedy is so fun
to watch as an art form not just the
comedy that you're watching but the
comedy is like the reason you're putting
butts in seats yeah but for us to watch
guys evolve and get better and like um
perfect case in point was Dan Rainey
absolutely about Dany better he was he
was really not good when he started and
but he went from not good and he was
okay but he just now he's good and it
came fast it went a lot easier for him
to go from not good to like good I think
confidence had a lot to do with that his
his material I thought was always funny
it's just when he told it he was kind of
unsure about it and you can't really be
took a lot to get him started didn't it
just to get him up the first just to get
him on stage like he'd been coming to
comedy shows since like six months I
first started doing comedy and he was
just so scared to get up on stage and
tell a joke and then he finally did it
and for some people once you do it that
just opens up the floodgates you can't
stop doing it well I'll admit it uh as I
was a teenager I've watched comedy you
can tell from talking to me and I've
been into comedy as long as you guys
have I'm not but I've been in that club
and I would love to walk up on stage and
throw down one good set and I've got a
podcast I'm obviously okay was talking
in a group we do grow meetings where I
just run my mouth and talk about growing
dude I get I just thinking about going
up there to do a set no thank you I want
to [ __ ] my pants it it scares the [ __ ]
out of me that's the other part of it
like I know I can't I I can't say I
can't do it but I know that that's not
my wheelhouse yeah it's just weird for
me to even think about getting up there
but at the party or whatever I'll I'll
tell everybody a joke all day long
that's the other part of it when you get
up there and you really feel like you
have something to say and you want to
tell these people something and they
don't laugh at all it's so heartbreaking
yeah yeah but that's soul crushing but
that's that's the thing that I like
watching in other guys and in myself is
you watch these guys like I was trying
to get to with Dan is like he evolved
and you could see that Evolution every
step and it was neat and I think that um
you know there's guys that don't want to
come out to shows oh they tell the same
jokes or something like that but it's
like no like look at the new thing that
he did to the end I don't know like I
know that we're probably getting pretty
deep on like oh no it's like writing
it's like tailoring that that joke it's
I I understand what you're saying and it
does it's not something it's like making
a recipe perfect the first time you make
that recipe it was too spicy but you
knew what you're aiming for took out a
little spice added more garlic it's like
watching and I've seen you do it I've
watched your joke telling evolve not
just your jokes get better but your
approach to telling a joke you don't
have to get naked to have a punchline
anymore because your jokes have some
body to them keep your clothes on that
was a long time ago dud that was one of
the best bits I've ever seen hey thanks
buddy yeah that was amazing Jesus I'm
going to do that joke for everybody
right
now it it can't see it I get it cuz it's
a visual bit and
and that's how that's going to fail as a
joke in your I'm looking for Dan's
Twitter feed so that we can get Dan Dan
Champion there you go look for Dan
Champion just follow him randomly he'll
have no idea why he got a bmb's really
he's a really funny guy coming out of
Springs there's a few funny funny people
coming out of the Springs but I think
he's one of the funnier ones definitely
and he's really working on it and it's
neat to see that so it's it's definitely
uh it's it's like having a second job
when you're not getting paid for it
you're not getting paid for it yeah
you're not get but doesn't it I'm a
musician and I've gone and played free
shows and just that I know that feeling
of just locking in with the bass player
and getting the song right that that was
worth my setup time my couple hours on
stage yeah oh for sure to drive to
wherever and go do 15 minutes is is
really nice sometimes five yeah you'll
drive up to go do five you'll do 10 you
know you'll do 15 just because they're
they're like oh you drove from peblo
cool like do you have 15 minutes now
yeah probably I don't know I think I can
get about 15 with all of my material but
I don't use a lot of old stuff are you
exploiting your jail experience for
material I have okay I would definitely
have some material a jail material and a
recent breakup you should write a joke
about did not get raped and I'm offended
well I did get raped first of all and my
my comedy is very personal like I have
to be 100% honest with my writing and my
comedy cuz I feel like that's the only
way that I can really find my own voice
cuz I'm still looking for it I don't
really know what I'm exactly doing it I
just write from what see now I'm still
confused if you did or did not get raped
cuz you're a comedian and it's awkward
over here a little I didn't I didn't
quit winking after you say I didn't yeah
this is weird now surprisingly quit
touching my leg while you do it not a
lot of rape in pcj uh I did I did have a
friend who was in there who was
apparently someone's [ __ ] and that made
me feel a little weird just like just to
see that but guys we are going to talk
about weed in this show too it's not
just going to be Prison Sex the whole
talk nope there wasn't there wasn't any
sex or anything but he would give him
like foot rubs and clean his clothes and
like they would share commissary yeah it
was weird there was like these weird
[ __ ] these weird family roles that are
assigned to you when you're in jail for
like a considerable amount of time and I
was only in there for 16 days but I
still got assigned a certain role for a
thug like you I bet that 16 days is just
rough for for a [ __ ] like me that 16
days was the worst 16 days of my life #
man boobs by by uh day six he was the
adab of so you were you were about to
tell me which what your role was I want
I want to hear that my role was uh story
time I would I would tell stories at
night so people can go to sleep cuz they
couldn't sleep after a while without
hearing some kind of story and you
didn't get raped and when you talk
everyone falls asleep nobody liked you
in jail oh people loved me in jail I had
kosher trades that I would trade for
paper cuz I didn't have any money on my
on my uh my books or anything like that
so I found out uh like Nazis will
[ __ ] give me their you know teenage
daughters for some Jew peanut butter
they don't give a
[ __ ] all right and I got fresh fruit
that was cool yeah that's what I need if
I'm in jail that's definitely what I
want I only did 15 days and that was
almost 10 years ago so that was a long
time ago I don't have any jail stories
yeah either do I I'm proud of us let's
behave ourselves yeah no more jail no
more jail that's why I'm doing it right
not well now that cannabis is legal in
Colorado I I don't do anything that
would even like make me worth being in
trouble that was the only thing I ever
did was smoke too much weed and I just
dab out all day no one can worry yeah
all right yeah come to Colorado wussies
wussies or my my advice since Colorado's
getting full and it's getting expensive
to rent a house here uh make cannabis
legal where you are you can do that
there too you don't have to come oh you
can I mean it's cool if you're hot and
you wear yoga pants come here but like
if you're just come in here just to grow
some weed if you're easy if you're easy
and you don't mind a fat chubby guy on
top of you definitely come
here that's a sales pitch you cannot
argue with right there I like it fat
chubby I'll get on top of you I'll
smother you all night long I won't get
on top of you if you're really scared
you can get on top of me and it's like
it's like you know a fun air mattress
with a
penis it's like the little blowup nub on
the air exactly all right I want to read
a news article because Clint actually
told me that he had a question for me
and I'm going to my text message to try
to remember what that question was
because Jamaica yes yes um and I also
about using cannabis as a Sacrament we
talked a little bit about Jamaica uh
legalizing cannabis for medical use on a
past episode it was either the last one
or the one before um and they also have
made it it used to be if you recau with
any cannabis in Jamaica it would be a
7-Day uh sentence in a jamaic in jail
and it's nothing like the little luxury
condo that you just spent some time in
it would be uh the PUO County Jail no
but I've heard some good stories it's
the everyone in there trades stories of
like where to get arrested it's like you
got to go to Crowley County they have
carpet it's awesome but like apparently
Pablo County Jail is the worst facility
in the state wow well I would believe
that yeah well then the Jamaican jail is
it's still going to be worse yeah of
course but uh so and now in Jamaica if
you get caught with Canabis it's just a
fine you don't go to jail right away
it's like a $200 fine if you have less
than an ounce so now guys like us can go
and also they've made it to where if you
have a medical marijuana card in the
States you can go there and register
your medical marijuana card for a small
fee and get a pass to buy medical
marijuana while you were in Jamaica from
their stores yeah awesome I heard their
weed sucks though it's not going to now
because a lot of people from the United
States saw this coming that cannabis was
going to be legalized and I have friends
in the industry that have already flown
down there and set up shops and testing
labs and BC bubble man was down there
teaching everybody how to make good hash
so uh it's going on down there yeah so
that that's kind of kind of what I can
tell you about Jamaica without talking
too much about what we said on another
episode but then you asked me ironically
you said how about using uh cannabis as
a Sacrament and then today I look at the
Cannabis and there it's the news page I
check out the Cannabis their headline is
new in Indiana a cannabis Church gets
its chance yeah I think that's where I
got that idea for that question from Ni
was because Indiana passed that law that
allows people to discriminate against
gays like uh now like as a part of
religion is it okay to smoke weed there
and it has to be because they can't tell
you what to do by that law I didn't read
if you're going to uphold one you got to
uphold the other well I'll read the
whole article here uh the sub headline
says if someone is smoking in our church
God bless them Church founder Bill Levan
says this is a church to show a proper
way of life a loving way of life we are
all called
canarians I don't know how I feel about
the word canarians but we reok and drink
the punch really iard something cannabis
related to add to that we'll hear it
before we get into the article the uh a
lot of Jews smoke pot they smoke weed
and uh a lot of them especially now with
like the younger like more alternative
hidic groups that are coming up like in
New York like the nanox and everything
like that they uh they use it as a sort
of way to go back to their cultural
Roots the holy anointing oil had um a
cannaboss some in it which is cannabis
uhhuh and it had so much in it that it
would have psychoactive effects in it
and in other cases they think that when
the high priest would go into a tent to
speak to God they would use um things
like cannaboss some different other
herbs and stuff and incense and olive
oil and uh the THC oil and everything
and they would just basically HotBox
themselves as a way to speak to God and
oh uh Paul's Jewish by the way yeah very
there's a there's a book there's a book
about it called cannabis casum that if
anyone's interested they should
definitely check I will check that one
out for sure myself I will I will read
that yeah a lot of religions use
cannabis I think uh not just the
Rastafarians use cannabis uh if and
there's something even if you're not
from part of the world where cannabis
was there is something very similar
where you were and actually cannabis
seems to have made its way all the way
around the world so everybody is smoking
cannabis all of the religions the saus
have smoked it and the saus get
overlooked a lot but yeah I'm going to
read this article I totally agree with
what you're saying I'm going to read the
article all right I love it so the
article is by Sarah pulam Bailey from
The Washington Post and it says the
first church of cannabis Incorporated
has been approved by Indiana Secretary
of State after the state's religious
freedom legislation became law last week
the church's founder Bill levans said he
filed paperwork in a direct response to
Indiana Governor Mike Pence's signing
the religious freedom restoration act
into law last Thursday Secretary of
State Connie Lawson approved the church
as a religious Corporation with all the
stated intent to start a church based on
love and understanding with compassion
for all a can cannabis is listed as the
church's Sacrament in its Doctrine Levan
said and he will set up a church
hierarchy the church will plan to grow
hemp he said though they will not buy or
sell marijuana if someone is smoking in
our church God bless them Levan said
this is a church to show a proper way of
life a loving way of life we're called
canarians I wonder if they kind of
linked that word from the rosarians a
little bit unitarians maybe unitarians
any kind of Aryans huh huh big fan of
the arens yeah I'm sure I'm sure you are
I I've seen your swastika tattoo oh yeah
I have two it matches your Hitler
mustache very well one one on each ball
is that is that something we're doing
here in Colorado is there those sects up
like uh there's actually green Faith
Ministries which is a cannabis related
Church um here in poo or uh it's in
Denver I think they're in gy or G yeah I
think they're in gy there was a group in
Springs when uh my old band stem Beach
Soul Revival check them out on Facebook
book I think they're still doing stuff
they're doing stuff um we played a dab
party at uh hookah bar in in PUO yeah
and um there was a guy who was out there
handing out like sacramental joints and
stuff like that yeah I actually took
about an ounce of hash and dabbed
everybody out all night that night yeah
that I remember that that was a fun
night yeah that was the first time I
ever dabbed was it the last time it
wasn't the last time I dabbed a few
times on uh here but that was a long
time ago time I got him so high he had
to get up and
leave and then uh John Bueno turned as
wide as the walls yeah uh was it John
Bueno yeah I think John Bueno took a dab
and turned as wi as John Bueno would dab
no I think it was Luke CWI wasn't oh no
prevan it was prev there's been so many
people at this table that we've dabbed
out that have just yeah sorry dabs I
don't know how I feel about
dabs dabs dabs do Jeff Jabs look like
drugs oh it does I'm sure when you break
out a blowtorch and you start heating
that [ __ ] up I'm sure it does it looks
like drugs yeah guys when you're dabbing
someone just just remember that that
you're using a torch and it looks like
we're heating up some crack it seriously
does so like if people are discriminated
against you for doing dabs I am too
because because it looks like drugs you
guys are ruining weed it's too much it's
too much for me like I know like it's
supposedly cleaner right than smoking
the actual Lea yeah there's less crap
that you're smoking you're smoking the
more like pure form of it and all but
and butane it just [ __ ] me up so much
well don't they do like a different
method now yeah there's no butane yeah
the method you're probably talking about
is rosin where we're just using a a
pressing comb like a straightening iron
squeezing the juice out of the bud by
that way but with the BHO the butane
there's no butane left in our product
we're uh we're getting it clean we
figured out how to clean it out real
well that's good you are yeah I I smoke
cigarettes so I don't really care about
butane or anything like that I'm putting
horrible things into my body yummy and
uh that's a shout out to cigarettes I
don't know if you guys ever smoked those
before but give them a try they're fun
we had to talk about that on a previous
episode uh there were three guys in the
room I took like a half gr dab and
didn't choke and the other two guys are
cigarette smokers and they took little
tiny dabs and had to get up and leave so
they could go hwk lugies and die for a
minute so if you want to take fat dabs
if you want to do big hikes if you want
to go high in elevation if you want to
live long don't smoke cig if you want to
be a productive good human being don't
smoke cigarettes I'm not one of those
people though they're they're nasty also
if you don't want to get old smoke
cigarettes I don't really I don't really
care no I'm not I I don't want you to
get old either well yeah
old saggy
tits hey I'm losing I lost 38 PBS since
I went into jail [ __ ] congrat I'm losing
these I'm losing these man tits
everybody ladies less fat come on still
still all the funny half the fat still
fat but less this time which is really
like I wish all my ex-girlfriends would
come back cuz I think this is the like
the least amount I've weighed in my
whole life so I feel like Paul uh has a
few things he needs to get off his chest
he keeps going back to a specific top no
no no this that's three times this is
this is my this is my my entire spectrum
of ex-girlfriends I want to give them a
chance to come [ __ ] me again now that
I'm better looking so if any of you out
there ever hear this and you want to
come back I'm it's I'm more active I'm
more attractive so you know it's it's
really you know up to you and he's kind
of Thug now cuz he spent some time in
the SL a little Thug I met I have made a
lot of friends in there who want me to
do nefarious things for them I'm sure oh
yeah because they can't wait to get out
and get back into yeah exactly his
eyebrows say Thug
Life tatto he's got a 13 tattooed on the
inside of his lip looks good with your
teardrop tattoo I uh I heard a lot of
[ __ ] up stories from Mexican cartel
guys like this one kid that I was in
there with he's not a kid he's like 25
but uh he apparently [ __ ] two chickens
to death when he was like 13 in Mexico
all right I'm going to keep reading this
article from it says marijuana is
currently illegal in Indiana for both
medical and recreational use so the
church could test the application of the
the new law rfra prevents Indiana's
government sub from substantially
burgeoning a person's ex exercise of
religion if it can demonstrate that it
is at least the res at let me try that
again because I'm still [ __ ] up from
what Paul just said if it can
demonstrate that it is the least
restrictive means of furthering a
compelling governmental interest just
the best segue I've ever heard when when
we asked him why he did it he just said
uh cuz it's
Mexico so Mexico you have some explain
to
do did he behead the chickens when he
was done know if they ate him or what he
was like that egg came out of that hole
that egg is about that look what I could
do it seems like a waste of chicken he
was all hungry when he was done did he
eat it afterwards that's what we asked
but he said no that was gross that's
what's gross about that story
yeah is a interesting
character all right so L who spoke to
the post by phone said the church yeah
this is from Indiana this part Paul's
part is from Mexico uh Lan who spoke to
the post by phone said the church has
received $2,000 in donations and
received more than $7,000 or 7,000
Facebook fans in the 5 days that it has
existed he hopes to build the first
church or temple built of hemp creete a
building material similar to Concrete
that includes hemp that's cool going all
I've heard a lot about hemp creete and I
think it's amazing I that we need to
start using this more yeah Industrial
Hemp is a good idea especially since we
can now grow hemp in the United States
what are they doing just taking rocks
out creating putting hemp in instead of
concrete you know I don't know how they
make concrete so I don't want to sound
stupid and try to act like that's
exactly how they do it I don't know I
don't know either I'm sure they're using
some kind of canile as like the the
powdery agent yeah yeah I it's it's
apparently like extremely fire resistant
like so your houses won't burn down and
things and if it does it'll smell real
good smell really good I like I like how
we're two capable white men and we don't
know how to make concrete like we should
know you should know you're steel worker
I should know I'm a little mad about I
guess yeah like rosarian all right he
might not know how to make concrete that
guy that makes rebar probably that just
seems like a hobby of yours like I I'll
make concrete on the side just for fun
whipping up a batch of
[Laughter]
creete that's
fantastic waiting for Adam Cora to come
over so we can hang some drywalls oh
we're he's you know we're looking at
those joyes
and it is Adam Cora fix your [ __ ]
eyebrows bro oh God what do you think he
has tattooed under there oh man you just
grew him out so This Love
Line you know I like I like 1800 love
line I like I like that the thick
eyebrows is in with girls today cuz I
love thick eyebrows I hated the really
thin CH just pencil them in real good
that's not you know by the the the the
pr pretty nice with the girls I'm
looking at like the eyebrows is not what
I'm concent I know that's not what
you're concentrating on I like I like a
nice face but she doesn't have a
mustache Clint's excited yeah hey you
shaved your arms sweet I'm okay with a
mustache as long as it you know I can
grow a better one then it's
okay I'm gon to read some more of this
article so we are progressing I don't
don't ever stop I just want to get
through this one article through the
whole 45 minute show and I'll be happy
with life uh we're progressing to get a
building property to be our holy ground
he said we are going to set up
counseling for heroin service and we
have a huge epidemic in this country
we'll probably have Alcoholics Anonymous
too I'm not going to allow alcohol on
the premise Lan also wrote out the new
DD dozen Ten Commandments like a uh Ten
Commandments like list with suggestions
for Better Living sorry I'm laughing at
this article and you guys well I'm
trying to read uh the Bibles of other
religious religions are yester year
about the drinking out of goat skins
what about drinking out of goat skins
that doesn't relate to the people with
GPS in their hand and 7,000 Tunes in
that same hand he said the church is
very simple the first good book we're
going to ask partitioners to read and
understand is the Emperor wears no
clothes so it kind of feels to me like
this guy's copying that church on Weeds
remember that church on Weeds oh I
didn't watch weeds watch TV show yeah
weed I didn't watch it's a good TV show
remember that up until Nancy got shot
and then I I was like spoiler alert yeah
dude if you haven't [ __ ] watched that
by now I'm going to spoil the whole
the last episode of weeds definitely
made me tear up though that was a really
good season finale or series finale
remember I don't remember that part
that's really good all right more
article he says I'm very faith-driven
I'm very spiritual and I'm filled with
love he said I find that most religions
are misled into gross perversions of
what they are meant to be this path has
led me to lead a religion that people in
today's world can relate to we don't
have any guilt Doctrine built in we
don't have any sins built in once the
church is is established members will be
asked for individual donations of $4.20
a month he said said Indiana attorney
and political commentator Abdul Hakim
shabbaz wrote that Indiana legislators
may have put the state in a position to
acknowledge those who profess to smoke
pot as a religious Sacrament you see if
I would argue that under RFA as long as
you can show that Reaper is part of your
religious practices you got a pretty
good shot of getting off scott free he
wrote remember under rfra the state has
to articulate a compelling interest and
preventing you from smoking pot I argue
they can't the Church of cannabis is
just one test in many under indiia
Indiana's new law which has escalated a
national prominence in the past week
raising questions about the future of
religious freedom laws and gay rights so
I should recap a little bit the reason
that this is popping up is because in
Indiana uh they just tried to uh do some
rude [ __ ] to gay people citing the Bible
as their reasoning and then these people
said well if you're going to cite the
Bible for saying the Bible
says I don't even want to get into the
Bible some folks interpretation of of
the Bible says that homosexuality is
wrong I'm not going to say if I agree or
disagree I'm going to say that that's
what that one book says in what people
have read so since that is a thing we're
also saying that in that same book
they've said that all these herbs are
here for us to smoke we're playing by
these rules on the gay thing we're
playing by these rules on the pot thing
haha we win that's kind of what this
church is trying to do sick yeah so I
think that's kind of cool with two cues
sick gnarly bro smoke some weed in
church I want to see a letterman top 10
of his uh of like his uh dos and don'ts
like number one Thou shalt not spill the
bong water Thou shalt not okay I hate
when people use the Old Testament as
their sort of you know guide to hating
on gays and hating on anything because
that's where all the anti-gay stuff
comes from it doesn't come from the New
Testament yeah well it's all about the
cleanliness and and the reason why um a
lot of uh people think that the they
they put the the anti-gay thing in the
Old Testament was your living in a
desert you're living around people who
are all trying to kill you so every baby
counts at that point the Old Testament
is just a guide in how to survive in the
desert and some religions say that
you're not supposed to jerk off because
you don't want to waste sperm like that
could have been re uh carrying on our
religion and our race precious it's it's
continuing on our people so we can
continue to exist I'm a [ __ ] sinner
you're not going to get that chicken
pregnant and keep our religion going
we're not we're not living we're not
living in a desert around Pake P we're
not living in a desert around a bunch of
hosle barbarians who are trying to kill
us we kind of are in some ways yes I
guess we kind of are just in a little
bit different sense than back in the day
yeah well the world's grossly
overpopulated so you can you can have
sex with a with a guy if you want I yeah
I think you should you know do it yeah
if if you want to do that go for it I'm
not going to stop you it's not my
business I've never tried but I'm open
if if there's a handsome young guy who
wants to take me on a date and Paul
you've put yourself out here a lot on
this show you have yourself to the max
come to my comedy show my exgirlfriends
come [ __ ] me new girlfriends come [ __ ]
me and dudes I'm get anyone you know I'm
just getting weird with life now [ __ ] it
sounds good live a little right figured
it out live a little secret to life live
a little secret to
life all right yeah I don't know man if
if that's something that I don't I guess
I don't feel like it's uh like weed
sacramental to me but it's just kind of
like a hangout thing to do I don't even
do it for yeah yeah I would rather go
and hang out with somebody but are you a
religious or a spiritual person
otherwise no okay no do you think it's
kind of a way do you think it's kind of
a way for people to just smoke pot and
kind of abuse it in that sense
absolutely I think uh there are a lot of
people I do it I do it uh my first dab
is medical that first dab makes my
shoulders not hurt dude I knocked myself
clean the [ __ ] out a few days ago like
clean out and a the first dab makes that
not hurt uh second dab dab makes me good
and high third dab and I'm just dabbed
and having fun the fourth and fifth dab
that is just me abusing it because I've
got a lot of dabs and I like to see how
high we can get today yeah but in the
morning when I'm here by myself and I
need some thinking to do and I got to
clear my head and I got a lot of [ __ ] on
my mind and the world's going too fast
for me to get away from it all uh turn
off all the lights turn off the TV turn
off the phone turn off the computer get
as silent as I can roll up a big fat
spliff of Just Flowers just buds buds
that I grew uh my own personal hidden
way bud that nobody else has access to
nobody gets to see roll that up smoke a
big fatty middle finger size joint by
myself and close my eyes and just see
what I am really thinking because
sometimes my head's just going too fast
to even really hear what I'm thinking
and when I get nice and Blaze and just
close my eyes and just shut up for a
minute and get into that quiet space Oh
that's that's the truth it's not I
didn't really I'm not mad about some
Facebook [ __ ] Facebook doesn't matter
once you close your eyes and go into
that bubble whatever she said on
Facebook doesn't matter that guy talking
[ __ ] about your Instagram picture you
don't really care you're you're missing
your favorite TV show oh well you
realize like what's inside and it just
kind of it shows me more what I really
need to pay attention to and it kind of
calms me down a little bit see I felt
like I had the opposite thing for me
especially since I haven't been smoking
pot and smoking anything or doing
anything really for the past like 40
days and 50 days however many days it's
been is uh I was definitely abusing it I
I smoked
too much needlessly just to smoke it
just to see how high I could get like
you're saying and uh I'm gonna take a
dab right now it wouldn't it wouldn't
necessarily like clear my mind or help
me think straight or anything it would
kind of just make me think in worse ways
because I was always second guessing
myself and I was just overthinking
things and then my brain wouldn't shut
off because of it so now that i' I
haven't been smoking I felt like it's
greatly improved like my writing and
just my My overall sense of being that
was something I wanted to touch on uh
kind of Chang the vibe a little bit I
know Clint's kind of uh I'm going to
call you lightweight bro you smoke weed
like a little girl yeah but you're a
cheap date so I love it he's a big man
too yeah he's I bring my own weed so
that way it's not even like imposing on
anybody else like but he showed up with
I smoked your weed and it was tasty
that's some pretty tasty Bubba cush it
didn't taste bad it didn't make my mouth
burn and it got me ston it good weed
good uh he came over and took one rip
off of a pipe so when you write some
comedy do you like write it when you're
straight and then bellish it when you
get lit or how does smoking affect your
writing where does it come into play no
there's it's kind of like uh there's two
Clint in that aspect cuz there's Stone
Clint and then there's sober Clint and
uh and never the two shall meet but um
no they uh Stone Clint can write some
[ __ ] it's [ __ ] some of the [ __ ] that
comes out that I find in my phone when I
sober up is what the [ __ ] was I thinking
like this is so weird and and then I see
and I remember what I was trying to do
with it but there's no way I would have
ever written that sober okay and and I
you know I've I I write a lot and in
this last month I haven't written a
whole lot I just been taking some time
away from Comedy just just to clear my
head trying to get my medications
straight you know cuz I'm on a couple of
like anti-depressants cuz old happy
Clint wasn't super happy here recently
so we' got your back I'm doing group
therapy and then seeing a one-onone
are you yeah I've been seeing a
therapist too and it's that's like my
favorite time of the week like I go talk
with a dude for like an hour and he's
just like dude I got your back I don't
care what you say like and I don't do
anything that's terrible but I don't do
anything or I don't feel like I'm doing
good enough anyway what I was getting at
is like oh I I feel both ways I'll get
real introspective like you do Jeff and
like what what is the problem that I'm
feeling and then deal with it right in
that moment but I've also gotten the way
that Paul gets and where it's like all
right why is that making me feel this
way it's because of this it's because of
this I need to like quit doing
everything that I do wrong and only work
because I got a 13-year-old daughter and
I'm afraid she's not going to get to
College because she wants to be a
surgeon then I start dwelling on that
and that freaks me out yeah so but I get
like the super happy way too like you
know this joke that I wrote just and
maybe it's a little bit long but you go
and edit it when you're sober and it's
great and then you tell it when you're
so I only
I don't like getting up in front of
people stoned because I feel like that's
my time to to be on point yeah oh yeah
for sure when you're on the spotlight
you need to be on the spotlight yeah I
used to do a lot of mic time high and
now that I'm not high it's I've it's so
much better for me I feel and Doug
Benson bro I love you but I'm gonna say
this out loud I feel Doug Benson being
so high really squishes his comedy he
could be a better performer if he
weren't so high yeah like I could see it
it slows down I've seen him for I've I
personally have gotten Doug Benson so
high before a show that he's just
flubbed in complete bits and looked at
me and said rosta Jeff you got me way
too high like he told me on stage that I
got him too high yeah like that's you'd
never see a lot of other comedians you
see Bill Cosby doing that I'll tell you
that much
well I like the silence that you just
brought to the show dropped it I don't
know it's like picking on Bill Cosby is
like picking on Michael Jackson like
it's the people have chosen side and if
you [ __ ] decide which side you're on
publicly then the other side hates you
I'm just going to stay impartial I don't
care no either do I they're not going to
you got to do what you got to do man
they not going to hate me for hating a
rapist right hey if if if him sexually
abusing me gets me a TV spot I'm there
that's just me you a couple you don't
even need to eat the pills right yeah a
lot of people are going to hate me for
that
one hey April 7th what's up April 7th
come see comedy come see comedy yeah I'm
on there and uh but don't come for me
come for Mary Mack and her husband
they're really funny people yeah we'll
come for you too his name is Big his
name is big does he have a lot of words
a lot of letters in it big ma it's Tim
something they don't they don't share
the same last names probably for
entertainment
reasons I don't know buddy I don't I
don't know about all that change in your
name stuff yeah yeah go with your real
name I had a lot more to ask about that
but we got thrown off track and I have
no idea what the [ __ ] I was going to say
Sor I got excited we were talking about
when we were writing and stuff yeah and
uh yeah it's it's it's both ways though
like I can be stoned and right but it my
inspiration just comes from like the
weirdest [ __ ] just man like watching an
infomercial and it's like what the [ __ ]
why am I thinking about like this
different way to watch YouTube all of a
sudden yeah like it's it's and see
that's where that's that's kind of how I
started out with just like trying to
write comedy about funny situations or
just like little things that I think of
and I can't do that anymore now I have
to it's all written about my personal
experiences and about like my personal
feelings and stuff keeps it better I
think when you're telling like listen to
any artist that's written an album about
themselves that was real that first
album that most people come out with
it's their real life experience right
that second and third album It's Studio
pressure and they ran out of life
experience cuz now they're just being a
musician or that or they really took
something from that experience and they
made another one but a lot of times and
I'm not trying to say that Maus Yahoo's
first album live at stub BW his load but
you could tell he spent his whole life
writing that and then after that he's
like oh I have to make another album
[ __ ]
yeah well it's the same I feel that way
about comedy too like you'll see some
guys that like their first like their
first comedy special was like whoa
that's cool and and you knew that they
had worked like 12 years to get that
just that one hour 30 minutes 30 minutes
okay well even like there like uh the
first time I saw danne cook was um I
tried hard enough to bring him into this
yeah I mean he was funny back in the day
back when we were in in high school and
middle school he was the guy and and you
can't take that away from him for a
minute and and I know people say oh he
stole jokes from people but 90% dude I
don't know man you know he's yeah he
sold out Madison Square Garden so he
made comedy blow up we're still W in his
coattails because of him is why like
premium blend had him on there and I
don't remember a lot of sets other than
like him but you you'll see like he blew
up and now we're all riding that Co
tales and I don't remember what my point
was now so that's fun no but like his
first album that's what I mean is like
his first like 15 minutes was like oh
[ __ ] and now you you see him and he's
not as funny anymore he like going
through the motions I I watched his last
special it was hard to watch but I could
still go back and watch his first
special we're talking about comedy one
of the best uh comedy specials I've seen
in a long time is the bill bur special
that's in black and white [ __ ] you get
to watch that Paul I haven't I haven't
seen it watched that one uh um and you
guys I'm sorry you feel that way no
that's the name of the okay I was like
what since we're on this we're not even
talking about weed today guys we're
going to talk a little bit more about
comedy something we've been watching uh
yeah we're and I'm going to talk about
Rost and stuff for a second to on that
we've been watching this is not
happening with arri shaffir on YouTube
I've watched like all 50 something
episodes you guys check that out this is
not happen really funny yeah it's all of
it's on YouTube go go to The Comedy
Central YouTube channel there's a
playlist just go to number one and click
play and watch them
uh Joey Diaz's are the best Joey Diaz is
one of my favorite comedians ever uh Joe
Rogan does a couple of great ones on
there uh big J oakerson will make you
pee your pants laughing I thought Kyle
canan's was really funny a big Kyle
Canan fan uh who's the guy that gotten
the fight in a phone booth I don't
remember yeah well listen find that one
Clint's mother I think Clint's mom
Clint's mom's on the show she
won she won that she won the fight in
theone since we're talking about comedy
I brought up the event page so I can
give everybody the full uh Mary Mack has
been on Comedy centrals live at Gotham
NBC's Last Comic Standing Montreal's
Just for Laughs festival and the San
Francisco sketchfest and her husband Tim
harmston has been on Letterman oh wow so
we're going to have people that have
been on TV yeah they're actual people
who have done stuff before and that's uh
April 7th Tuesday uh the rainbow at 9:00
p.m. for $5 Pablo you're really missing
out if you don't go to this one yeah
come on down you guys I there's a good
chance I'll be there it's on Santa Fe uh
right near the Greenlight tab yeah right
up the street from the green light cool
just go check it out and have some
laughs get some drinks it's a really
cool bar come e Paul cuz we've really
described him in a weird way he's got a
Hitler mustache and a teardrop tattoo
from our description I have Thug Life
tattoo to my eyebrows and I'm just
desperate desperate for companionship
yeah he's thrown that out there I was
going to remind everybody of that
extremely Des wants attention he needs
some he needs a hug that's really what
he needs a mouth hug a mouth hug on my
penis no matter what you try to do with
these boys it always goes back to a dick
joke don't give a [ __ ] no we're we're
not comedians that's the thing we're
open micers yep it's all about the
mentality bro well I mean we treat it
serious but we're not getting paid for
this yeah even all that money that
Paul's bringing in like yeah $5 donation
that's not going to Paul Paul ain't
making [ __ ] on that show I'm not I'm not
getting paid at all for this show buying
pizza and beer for the comedians pretty
much we we actually get sponsored by
Paul's Pizza and in canoli in PUO which
if you haven't had Paul's Pizza you
should definitely go try it's on Norwood
where the Taco Casa is it's really good
they have like two topping to looked at
the clock I'm like large pizzas for like
$12 it's really really good guess how
fat he is if he knows the pizza specials
guys you get to guess his weight they're
my sponsor guess his weight on Twitter
so I know it cuz I tell people guess his
weight on Twitter and I'm a big fan of
pizza # 257 that's like what stops me
from committing suicide is like well
you're going to eat pizza again so just
just make it through tonight did you
watch did you listen to that uh Pete
Holmes do you watch listen to you made
it weird uh it's too long and I I can't
he had Henry Rollins on and he goes
Henry why do you want people to live
longer and his he goes two words more
pizza Henry Rollins is a smart guy I
hated Henry Rollins until I read his
book get in the van I have so much
respect for that guy after reading that
put in some work yeah created the DC
scene the he was part of the DC scene
and then you know created the LA scene
with SS records and Black Flag that's
crazy oh man you guys should just do a
punk rock podcast or some sort of I love
punk rock yeah well there you go we'll
do a whole episode not a not this show
but we're going to do another podcast
it's just called punk rock we'll do one
episode I'm down it'll go away yeah like
three minutes long we'll just yell like
a sweet oh it would just be a punk rock
song of a podcast a podcast my favorite
band is Black Flag and then you scream
something obnoxious too and then we'll
punch each other and drink a beer and
then that'll be the end of the show yeah
sounds like a good show sounds like a
Black Flag kind of show yep yep yep or's
punk rock Mike when you need him Steel
Toad sneakers steel that's a cool ass
band name I don't know if punk rock Mike
can still have the moniker punk rock mik
when he's more of a hobo I think he be
hobo Mike at this point vaned by the
river
mic we're going to put this show back on
track you know I wanted to relate my uh
my ganja meditation to your writing
session like when you're just being ston
and being goofy that's you're doing
you're kind of doing the same thing just
in a different way you're meditating and
connecting with yourself the same way I
am just I'm still very new at it just on
a different platform ah that doesn't I
don't think that I think I think that
there's still more self- exploration to
do that that I haven't uh been willing
to do yet cuz I'm afraid of it okay do
you know what I mean yeah you want to
smoke some DMT no no I like DMT nice I
would like to smoke some DMT Paul just
lit up he got a whole new demeanor his
his F life went up on his face they
don't they don't test for DMT so no I'm
just kidding mushrooms and DM probate
Crystal I'm just kidding I would never I
would never do that # lighter
sounds
just hey I have to abstain from alcohol
and marijuana they didn't say anything
about PCP or anything like that dyl
tryptamine or IAS was on that list now
we can't can uh yeah we can I was going
to say we can't promote or condone any
use of any uh illicit or psychedelic
drugs but uh yeah [ __ ] if you have
real DMT smoke DMT learn about yourself
get there that's that's all I'm going to
say about that we're not going to talk
too much about it on the show but yeah
wow do that go there I'm out go there do
it CL do that no I'm not going to force
anybody to do it but if you I'm still
lightweight if you're curious if you if
there's some [ __ ] inside yourself that
you want to know about and you want to
get inside your own head how shitty of a
human being you are or or figure out how
to stop being such a shitty human being
exactly figure out how to stop being
such a shitty human being take a good
blasted DMT and sit back on the couch
and close your eyes I uh debate the
debate lately has been opener eyes open
or closed eyes close your eyes dude get
the full experience definitely close
your eyes see the colors smell the
smells taste the tastes like oh yeah
it's like a whole Starburst
commercial yes DMT flavored Starburst
there's nothing like it all right uh
we've got almost an hour guys I'm not
going to edit this at all I'm going to
put this out just like it was I hope you
didn't say anything too stupid uhoh uhoh
uh you want to uh we did a few plugs
what's your Twitter handle Paul uh VHS
nerd I collect VHS tape so if any of you
guys out there want to get rid of your
mom's old VHS collection or if you have
an old VHS collection I'd definitely
love to go through it and take what you
don't want there you go guys you have a
PO Box we could ship those to no I'll
just come out and take them Paul will
come pick up he'll drive all the way to
Pennsylvania to come pick up your VHS
hit me up on Twitter check me out on
Instagram which is just VHS nerd to see
all the stuff that I got and you know
just drop me a line ladies is it hard to
find a VCR to play that [ __ ] on now not
really it's it's the the whole like VHS
thing is starting to get really popular
oh cuz all the hipsters I I don't even
necessarily think it's hipsters I just
think uh like a lot of new movies are
coming out like Maniac just got remade
not recently with uh the [ __ ] froto
baggin whatever the [ __ ] that guy's name
is samse gji
no uh the uh the [ __ ] his name Elijah
Wood Elijah Wood there you go I was I
could see him in [ __ ] Wilfred but I
just couldn't think of the name that was
a new movie that was like a like a a
remake that he did that was released on
VHS that's so there there's new uh VHS
releases there's also reissues of a lot
of old stuff uh company just got done
reissuing cannibal FOH and uh Cannibal
Holocaust which are some Italian you
know spaghetti splatter movies that are
really
good I was waiting for the word
spaghetti splatter to come up
spaget SP horor Italian horror is where
it's at there's really nothing better
than that in my opinion so if you have
any Italian horror movies on tape let me
know I'll take them let's get them to
Paul yeah don't you just have an
internet connection where you can like
watch stuff I don't have to it's not the
same I agree it's a lot of people like
vinyl and they will not use the I became
a nerd in a video store that was like my
favorite thing to do when my parents
would not want to deal with me and they
just like I'll just take him to the
video store so we can rent a movie and a
in a game and that's where I became a
nerd and like that's where I first saw
my first horror big box and really got
intrigued by the cover art by it and
that's really why when I go out and I
search through tons and tons of tapes at
thrift stores I see something that I've
never seen before but the cover Art's
really good but the movie is [ __ ]
terrible I love it because the cover
Art's so good and I just love shitty
movies what's the shittiest what's the
best shitty movie you've watched the
best shitty movie is definitely you're
the hunter from the future that is the
the shittiest [ __ ] movie I have ever
seen it starts out kind of like a
fantasy epic where they're fighting
dinosaurs and barbarians and there's a
point when he uses uh he uses a
pterodactyl as a hang glider to kick
someone in the face as you do and then
it just Segways into now he's the hunter
from the future so I should have seen
this coming it Segways into Androids and
spaceships and all kinds of [ __ ] it's
just the weirdest [ __ ] thing I've
ever seen holy [ __ ] it's amazing though
though so if you can check it out you
can uh actually watch it on YouTube for
like $3 is you're the hunter from the
future or if any girls want to come over
to my house or any dudes like we heard
or any dudes you know we'll get weird
it's fine uh come watch come watch some
tapes BR bring your own couch but it's
it's up there with that one and then
shopping mall
man I've seen shopping mall mall is
years and years ago like on HBO or
Cinema dude remember USA up all night I
think that's where I saw chopping mall
that makes where I saw it was clean
enough to be on USA yeah I was a little
I was a little guy my mom would watch
USA up all night with me probably where
we saw it that's the first time that I
saw Toxic Avenger oh yeah what's up toxy
I miss [ __ ] love the Toxic Avenger my
hero monster hero nice that's on Netflix
trauma yeah I have it on I have two
copies on VHS I have an unrated copy and
I have the edited R rated copy I was
just giving everybody an option to go
see it yeah if they want to go watch it
if you haven't seen the Toxic Avenger
and you love pot you should definitely
get really high and then watch the Toxic
Avenger you'll laugh your ass off there
you go all right Clint it's your turn
plugs where do we find you uh Instagram
and everywhere it's at tall Clint he
hasn't been doing much social media you
guys he's taking a break letting his
brain
I've been going crazy with social media
so check me out doing shows yeah and
also check out the wild cousins oh yeah
wild cousins yeah those guys should
probably keep an eye on that we have
t-shirts too Clint we do have T-shirts
you do yes they're cozy I wear one I've
got one they're nice thank you buddy it
came from you yeah thank you thank you
uh you can find me it's IR gentics on
Instagram uh if you want to find the
podcast it's gfyh podcast on Twitter of
course there's a Facebook I've got my
own Facebook and Twitter there's a lot
of social media going on in my world you
can find me just sear search search
search you'll find it all guys thanks
for listening I'll be back the Cannabis
Cup is coming up so I'm going to have to
do some pre-recording and [ __ ] to get
through that week but I'll do a lot of
good stuff for you I hope to see you
with the Cannabis Cup um after the
Cannabis Cup April 26th at H gr indoor
growing supplies there is a Growers
meeting at 6 o'clock be there I'm going
to speak Jesse's going to speak we're
kind of debating what we're going to
talk about we will finalize that and
start writing out our part here pretty
soon uh big thanks to these guys for
coming thanks thanks for having us oh
man I've wanted to get you on for a
little while it's fun it is definitely
fun having you guys on bring some normal
folks instead of a bunch of grown nerds
onto the show once in a while yeah Gro
nerds I check out the sponsors see what
the what the audience thinks in this one
was trying to learn something and you
guys made me laugh well you got to laugh
laughter is medicine I hope you smoked a
fat joint laughter asses off with these
guys make sure you check out the Rocky
Mountain worm company also high grow
indoor growing supplies don't forget
about Nature's green remedies
if you want to sponsor a really cool
podcast send me an email it's grow from
yourheart hotmail.com I'll get you all
that
information um let's see I think that's
all we got to say right don't forget the
show's available on iTunes Stitcher and
every episode's available on iry
genetics.com don't forget about that
donation button on the podcast page go
to the uh IR gentics colorado.com click
on the grow from your heart podcast tab
at the top right there's a donation
button donate some cash if you'd like to
I'm not begging I'm just letting you
know that it's there I'm never going to
charge you money for the show the show
will always be free everything will be
free free free free freedom but if you
want to make a contribution I would love
it um yeah I guess that's enough for the
day for today that was hard to say I'm
dabbed out I need another dab a big huge
shout out to my ninja Spence Spence
you're doing me a huge favor this week
dude I appreciate it more than you will
ever know thanks a lot I appreciate the
help and all of your guidance so until
next time take a fat dab give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]
oh