[Music]
all right here we go welcome back
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rosta jeff
joining me today on camera is my buddy
white mike welcome to the show bro
what's up man how you doing everybody
thanks for joining us mike thanks for
getting some time away from the families
are
setting up the cool backdrop there set
up the microphone it's good to have you
back on the show a lot of people have
been asking for you so they're going to
be excited to see you
glad to be back glad to have you this is
episode number
620 i'm going to try to remember to look
into the camera i've got mike on the
zoom here on this screen i've got the
camera up there i'm going to try to do
my best to look into the camera i
apologize if i forget
i'm trying to pay attention to my buddy
here trying to host a show trying to
look at a camera trying to read notes
and also on highest giraffe [ __ ] so i
got a lot of things going on but we will
make this happen thank you for joining
me ladies and gentlemen episode 620
white mike is here in this episode we're
going to talk about
a proposed potency limit on colorado
cannabis this is a hot topic
for myself and for mike uh we're going
to jump into that but first we got to do
what we normally do let's do some shout
outs
to a few of the great folks who support
us on patreon i'm going to start off
with the big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to my buddy
thomas mcginnis
let's send a big shout out to real raw
let's send a big thank you shout out to
billy podunk
who is also the discord champ if discord
was a game
uh billy podunk is winning big shout out
to that dude always on the discord
channel drop in
say hello there will be a link to the
discord in the show notes let's continue
with the shout out to bongstein bear i
love that name let's send a shout out to
ez057 big fist bump brother let's send a
thank you shout out to my buddy alabama
man
let's send a special thank you to glen
geroni and gramps memo let's send it
thank you to single t
and dank groves listen to thank you
shout out to noah n and let's wrap up
the grow from your heart podcast thank
you shout outs with a big thank you
shout out
to my buddy ryan waters big thanks and
big shout out to all my friends who
support my show on patreon
of course you can find us at patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart there
is a link in the show notes
i feel like it is uh a polite and
important now that i give mike an
opportunity
to do some patreon shout outs so mike it
is all yours buddy go ahead and spread
some love
thanks bro um i want to give a shout out
to the grow from the heart podcast for
always supporting me
uh og purple thumb thank you very much
learning and burning
chris farmer z thank you all so very
much for supporting me
and uh yeah we wouldn't be here without
you when we might be
but the show would not look this good
that's the truth i would still do it
even without him but we wouldn't have
the cool
gear and all that fanciness happened and
it'd still look all rickety uh special
shout out to our buddy og purple thumb
he supports uh irie genetics in many
many ways
uh all things roster jeff grow from your
heart irie genetics moji purple thumb
has got my back so it's good to see that
he's supporting you as well
thank you bro i do appreciate you
helping out my crew my buddies this is a
great community we've got here
mike didn't shout it out but make sure
you give mike a patreon click at
patreon.com forward slash
white mike super easy to remember um
i think that's all the business stuff
we've got here at the top of the show we
did the patreon shout outs i welcome to
mike
mike just in case people do want to
stalk you while they're listening to the
show is there anywhere they can find you
on the social media
you can find me on twitter at nemopunk15
and you can find me on
facebook at pueblo for sensible cannabis
laws there we go you guys give him a
follow follow my buddy
stalk him harass him give him some
feedback um
also all things that mike says are
opinions of mike don't send me the
emails
you gotta send me the hate mail i always
say that and then i never get it poor
jeff does
where should they send that hate mail or
the or the great emails where should
they send you the uh the updates and the
greetings mike
just hit me up on social media you can
direct message either those accounts
there you go direct message send him a
dm be nice to mike he volunteers
to do this for free he deals with two
kids and a wife all day this is his
getaway
please be nice to my friend um i don't
think we want to jump into too much more
else i think we could probably jump
right into the main topic
of today's show people are going to
notice that you've got a boo-boo on your
fingers if you've moved that hand
towards the camera
i actually took the boo-boo off to hide
the boo-boo oh okay
i'll put that back on now that you've
added it i didn't want to make it a
topic of the show
i was just yeah i uh i broke a finger
took it off yeah mike's got a booboo he
broke a finger it was a dog thing
we've addressed it and we've told him
why yep i tried to keep a dog from
getting hurt the dog didn't bite me or
nothing everybody's okay
shout out to rufus you're a good boy
shout out to mike for rescuing rufus
good work bro i would have done the same
thing i would have had a broken finger
too if i were in the situation i think
you did the right thing so
yeah i literally thought don't do it
you're gonna break your finger right
before i broke my fingers so
listeners if you ever think don't do
that you're going to break a finger
i advise you to not do that because
you're probably going to
know if you gave me the option though if
break a finger or somebody's dog get hit
by a car i'll sacrifice my finger for
almost for sure
just you know i'm just down so you did
the right thing i would have still reach
out and help the dog you guys help the
dog get your finger busted that's your
man
your finger will heal maybe the dog
would have gotten hurt worse i don't
know mike's a big dude he can deal with
that the [ __ ] pinkie will be okay
anyway it's just it's amusing and
annoying it's just
it gets to be amusing and annoying for
like six weeks yeah what i've noticed
about youtube is if there is a thing
somebody will address it and if we don't
they will and now we don't have to
answer the comments because we already
did
that's just how social media and the
internet work now mike i've been doing
this for way too long i guess is it
jaded or programmed or just aware which
one am i professional
experienced i like that okay um speaking
of professional and experience we do
have a podcast i do have notes we do
have some [ __ ] to talk about
um a topic with i've got
like four one two three if i got five
little uh bullet points here
actually tabs open wow mike's doing it
real all right
um let's keep this going before we ruin
the appearance um
they love it when we ramble they sure do
use they like it when we ramble when you
talk about the podcast that helps us
find the show
so um mike's taking a rip off that maybe
i can get this out now
mike has told me recently that there are
proposed
potency limits in colorado for
cannabis and concentrates and possibly
edibles i didn't ask that far
i also failed to ask if this was for
recreational or
for uh medical cannabis but i figured
that would be a great topic for the show
i didn't ask a lot of questions i wanted
to save it all here and be fresh
i didn't want to blow it all in the
hallway so uh let's talk about this mike
they are proposing making potency limits
on cannabis here in colorado my first
question of course
is this medical or recreational cannabis
that they're trying to mess with here
the proposed bill would affect both med
and rec
um so both right now
this is just in colorado but the people
behind it
are national okay or at least connected
to a network of national anti-cannabis
organizations
organization it's one national org
um and then each one of their members
runs and
their own little state group and it's
usually just
five or six annoying parents working
together in concert on social media but
um over the last nine years they've
slowly built a foothold of support
in state legislatures including
colorado's
so right now in colorado um
pardon if i wander from the mic i'm
reading
um as the language reads at the time of
this writing which was
february 17th of this year
uh we have a proposed bill that would
cap thc potency at 15
for both medical and recreational
marijuana products
presumably for edibles they're going to
leave that with the 100 milligram
recreational limit and what is it 300
package for med i think so
uh might be higher but anyway anyway
it's been so long since i've bought a
matt edible
um they'll probably leave the med limits
alone for
the potency limits for edibles alone for
now
but this would apply to flowers and
concentrates
okay um if that sounds insane to some of
y'all there's some reasons for that
yeah it should sound the
legislation excuse me tongue tied
the representative behind this bill and
i'm going to butcher her name and i
apologize for that it is not intentional
um i'm just bad at this is yadra
kavio um she's a
colorado representative from thornton
she's the sponsor of the bill
she's also a pediatrician and her
slant on this is that high potency
cannabis products are bad for teenagers
and so they shouldn't exist in the legal
market in colorado
that's their starting off point and over
the years they've slowly built a
foothold in the legislature where
this bill is instead of getting laughed
out of the door
is slowly working its way through the
process of becoming a bill
but the products aren't for teenagers so
that shouldn't even be a thing
it shouldn't be um but
if you're 18 you can shop medically
and they're it's
the think of the kids angle is just what
it's always been it's just
a ploy or a ruse yeah
the lawyer brain and me goes well yeah
you don't want the teenagers to have it
that's fine we don't sell it to
teenagers
you've got to be 21 to get it yeah
that's that's how we stop that
if you're in the dispensary shopping
legally under 18
you have two physicians monitoring your
care
um it's it's not willy-nilly
a parent has to do all the shopping like
it's
um it's very regulated in colorado more
regulated than anything else we have
here
but um the antipop groups
maybe four years ago realized that they
didn't have
a prayer uh of getting a repeal passed
through the vote there's no way that the
voters are going to vote
out marijuana once it's been voted it's
just not going to happen
oh there's so much money it's not going
anywhere with all the money it makes
yep um so
two years ago i think they tried to do
a ballot measure that would do the same
thing cap potency at 15
um their ballot measure
went nowhere because one of the
marijuana industry groups in denver
hired the two or three signature
gathering firms in colorado and just
said you're busy now
when they call don't answer the phone
here's your finder's fee
and that was the end of that the 15
uh 15 potency bill that was going to go
through the ballot
um system like legalization did that's
dirty politics that's planned dirty i i
hate to say how much i like that
approach
it is plain dirty but i like that our
side's plain dirty considering
these laws were playing dirty to begin
with like
there were never a bunch of doctors that
were like hey this is hurting people we
should make it harder to get
it was always politicians going you know
life would be easier if poor and brown
people couldn't vote
yeah so why don't we make the stuff that
they like to do when they're off hours
illegal and we can just arrest them
and make them felons and then we don't
ever have to count their votes again
um so when we did that two years ago
i thought that's funny like i would have
preferred a good good old-fashioned
shellacking
and i liked that they were completely
thwarted by having to be
grassroots like if they can't hire
people to do the signature gathering
that means they would have to have a
broad base of support willing to do it
themselves
and this happens all the time in
colorado it might be harder in other
places but
we have at least one active recall
effort going all the time
right where a group of people is trying
to oust a politician or change a law
and so signature gathering gathering's
pretty common here
this could have been done if they had
support and they didn't
um so now they're back and they found a
representative from
thornton to sponsor the bill they were
trying to keep it a secret in a draft
got left in a copier somewhere or
something and they got outed about
three months ago um since then there's
been some reporting on it
um the bill wants to do some other stuff
too like it's
uh it wants to create a medical
marijuana monitoring program
so patients purchases are tracked in a
statewide system
they can try to limit looping
they want better tracking of the patient
doctor relationship
so that they can make sure that the
doctor that signed your medical
marijuana card
is really monitoring your progress and
your health and all of that
they want data collection to track the
effects of high potency thc
products um it seeks to protect public
health
through potency limits and the
prohibition of dangerous products used
by underage youth
ah sorry i'm reading
yeah they just want to be all up in my
business i'm a [ __ ] adult i've
already got a medical marijuana card
from my doctor who approves
and there's no reason for anybody else
to step in that's one of my favorite
things about medical cannabis is that i
can dose
myself without i know i'm not going to
kill myself so i could dose myself
if it still hurts i could take more if
it doesn't hurt so much i don't have to
take as much
i don't need somebody involved that
doesn't know what the [ __ ] they're
talking about in my medicine
yeah it's not like a number of other
medicines
that we have in the house like it's a
little weird cannabis is the only
medicine in my house that's locked up
but there are a bunch of medicines in my
house
that will harm my kids if my kids eat
the whole container
and with the cannabis if that were to
happen it'd just be sleepy time for
quite a while right and you'd probably
face way more
legal problems if they ate your cannabis
than if they ate the bottle of bleach
yeah um it's really unfortunate
that the laws are still as screwed up as
they are especially around this but uh
it's basically nonsense there's so many
different facets of why this is
horseshit
like they say they picked the 15 number
because
that's where other countries have found
um
terror bad effects on cannabis products
and it's just a myth like we've had
hashish
since pre-history um
we know through modern testing
that um like hand rub hash
old school hash that's been around since
the 70s um
dry sieve hash that's been around since
the i mean i've i said the 60s and 70s
it's been around a hell of a lot longer
than that um
that's when it got popular again in the
u.s in popular culture
but uh these forms of hash are like 30
to 60
pure that's been true
the whole time if making cannabis
products more pure
led to more negative outcomes we would
have noticed a long [ __ ] time ago
um you and i would be displaying it
right
or uh during the clinical trials for
marinol or its knockoffs
we would have found something other than
what we see
like we've all been around people that
consumed too much cannabis and got a
little too high and it's like oh buddy
you need a snickers and like a chair yep
here's a gatorade and a burrito
you know that's your prescription to get
better from your weed overdose
take a little bit of a nap and you'll be
just fine yep
i mean maybe first timers who way overdo
it like still high at breakfast
but like a lot of that's just because
you're in a better mood and you see the
world better
yeah like any edibles to still be high
at breakfast [ __ ]
but uh like they're 15 number they're
picking as trash
they like to pretend that that's where
cannabis gets dangerous because that's
the number
britain randomly picked like 30 years
ago to differ
or to differentiate between um
can't regular cannabis and what they
call skunk
the netherlands followed suit similarly
there's a potency cap
um where in the dutch market cannabis
isn't legal it's just overly tolerated
overly is the wrong word but highly
tolerated
and so it's a certain thc percentage in
flower
the the dutch government officially
considers
cannabis worth caring about again and so
that's been
misconstrued by um
prohibitionists in the states is that's
when the
cannabis gets dangerous is when it's
over 15 or 16
so ridiculous it's absolutely ridiculous
so um if you're a medical patient don't
you need
potent medicine if you are and i'm just
asking not necessarily but yeah
there's a lot of good reasons to have
potent medicine would you rather me take
if i were sick and elderly
would you rather me take 17 inhalations
off of a shitty product
or two dabs that's two ins and outs of
breathing to get the medication i need
we're not going to consume less we're
going to consume
more if it's a lesser quality product
we're just going to consume more
right and if they're talking about uh
monitoring and limiting our purchasing
even further
we're gonna have to this is going to
drive me back to the black market is
what this will do
i know how much i every week i go i buy
my limit probably two times a week when
it comes to concentrates i know what day
my favorite dispensary gets a drop shout
out to you guys over there you know who
you are
uh i would say your name but i don't
want more people cleaning you out on the
concentration
that's why you're not getting shot
enough yeah yeah so i go over there and
i get my concentrates about twice a week
i get my limit
and by the time i'm ready to go back i'm
close to running out
so if they restrict my limit of
purchases that's gonna [ __ ] me up if
they restrict
the potency they would be cutting my
potency in
essentially a third uh no less than
what's
uh and that's not even the tip of why
this bill is bad like it'll be super
annoying for you and me
because we'll have to consume a much
higher volume of product
i'd be getting one-fifth of the potency
on this jar
if it were limited to 15 but it's not
just
like what's the other eighty-five
percent now
that's why i got this no that is what
led to
the vaping crisis last year the year
before last in 2019.
god 2020 still seems like five years in
my head
yeah um but in 2019 there was a big
vaping crisis coast to coast
and it took a while for us to really
shake out the data but once we did
we found that it's a leak or
its additives to thc in cartridges
and so it's shitty cartridges and shitty
additives
that were causing the problem and people
were
consuming those two things because they
wanted the thc
which doesn't harm anybody so
it's the additives that they now wanted
us to make up
85 percent of our extracts yeah
and how am i going to grow i can't grow
flowers that are 15
or lower i would not that's the real
reason they picked 15
is because it would gut the industry
um they know they can't vote us um away
and so they're hoping to to make a rule
that it's impossible to
meet we the whole industry would have to
re-breed
yeah if it's not like a paint color we
can't be like oh there's too much blue
in that
put a little more white in and tone it
down like no
it's you can't spray something on it to
bring the thc percentage down a little
bit
um you could do what they do at the
university of mississippi and put the
whole plant through a
blender and call that final product i
guess
um they brag about being able to provide
any
thc content you want yes
just they take their trash and clean it
up until it's just hash if you want them
to
um but in colorado
we've been breeding for thc
for god what
since what years yeah i was gonna say
since the [ __ ] 60s probably that's
because we didn't know about
the secondary cannabinoids we didn't
care we just wanted to get highs we
didn't have laptops one of the
one of the problems of prohibitions
aren't smoking the weed anyway i'm tired
of lab tests machines aren't smoking the
wheels
how's it do like we didn't know what we
had yeah i mean until
they really discovered thc and really
figured out a lot about it
it was just marijuana's fun and we're
not sure why yep
and then it was oh it's because of the
thc and we didn't get to even thinking
about the other stuff
until medical had already been in around
the country for a decade
but uh at this point to try to rebreed
an entire genetic line across the state
down to below 15 flour
it's impossible it would take two or
three years of trial and error
in cross breeding to cbd rich low thc
genetics and that's the point if they
make us take a two-year
non-profitable we have to completely
time
out we're done do you think the labs
will do us the same favor that they
probably do for some people
and just mark this as 12 instead of 32
probably not um i don't know the labs do
that everybody says those labs cheat
they paid the labs
dude i don't know who to pay uh i worked
with the labs i sent so much product to
the labs i
honestly look into this camera we've
never paid for a good lab test i've got
some of the highest lab tests in the
[ __ ] country
and we've never paid for a lab test
wouldn't know who the [ __ ] to pay if i
had to they bill us for our
time and [ __ ] but i don't know who to
pay for a higher number so that's not a
thing you guys could say on that [ __ ]
come on
it uh there were a couple of
labs that tried it right at the start
before we had rules because before we
had rules
people were asking for labs and so labs
started to crop up and it was about
then that the state was like wait they
have
what now what do you mean a lab like a
crack house
and it was like no like a testing lab
where a computer tells you what's in it
and that's when they really threw down
the first layer rules
but i think only one or two potency
scandals like that have actually
happened in the country it's it's just
it's almost an urban legend not quite
purely
people outside of the industry are the
ones that you hear saying they paid for
a higher test it's always those people
the people that aren't involved
so there you go guys myth busted you
it's highly unlikely that anybody is
paying for a lab test
i've seen stores [ __ ] customers for
sure
stores can do it yeah we're on a jar
nobody's going to change it
salesman can like there's not an oath
that you think
where you swear on the constitution of
like i will do whatever the [ __ ] i have
to do to get tips in my tip jar that is
the oath it's a bud tender
yeah the the owner only cares what my
numbers my sales numbers are and my
sales numbers are better if i tell you
what you want to hear as a customer
that's just what am i going to be
smoking mike what's going to be in my
dad's what else is going to be in here
am i going to be just they
they haven't thought this out at all
they're there's no talk about
practicality or functionality at all
because the people behind it
know and want it to kill the industry
and that everybody else is just hearing
the
we gotta protect the kids piece of it um
that's how it's built and packaged right
now and so far
there's been industry pushback but not
organized or focused
so this one might stick around for a
while i hope it doesn't
yeah this one it should get hammered
down
into nothing quickly and brutally
um because it's absolute backdoor
horseshit like yeah it's detrimental to
the industry
okay the caller put it up to a vote
be [ __ ] voted out like if they really
put it on the ballot and we got voted
out
like i'd have some serious soul
searching to do but
this isn't that this is them trying to
slip uh
oh well you know we're just trying to
help out the kids and then no no no
like no we already make it infinitely
harder
to get a weed than we do like a bunch of
bullets
or alcohol i was going to say a bottle
of whiskey i can drive down the street
and get enough whiskey to kill me
like i could literally no other product
is limited like this
yeah there's there's nothing out there
that
i mean because recreational cannabis is
recreational colorado it's supposed to
be legal just like booze
but i can go to the liquor store and buy
everything
i can pay for yeah same thing with the
gun store like i might have to wait a
while to pick up
some guns as opposed to others and i'm
not a big gun guy so i don't know the
ins and outs so like i could get the
pistols but not the rifles or whatever
the [ __ ]
but like i know that i could be like
give me all the bullets
and normally like right now there's a
limit of like one or two per customer
everywhere because there's a shortage
but normally they'd be like
cash or charge sir i'll have the boy get
the dolly
and we'll start loading your truck there
you go and
i mean same thing with farm tools or
whatever the [ __ ] you know
yeah yeah i could i could hurt my i
could hurt myself with anything to be
honest with you so
we've already got it limited to an ounce
per person per
per store if you want to amass a bunch i
guess you can go to store after store
after store and buy your ounce at each
store
every day but like the teenager can
already just go to the liquor store
flash a fake id just as easily as going
to 15 20 different dispensaries
and walk out like it's just so we've
already made it much harder to acquire a
shitload of cannabis
everybody's got a bigger burden
everybody's got just
window dressing the people that want
something find a way to
get it that's just how supply demand
desires wants that's
either legally or illegally we will get
what we want we're [ __ ] humans we
have desires we have wants and needs we
got money
there's a ways and means to get what we
want we'll [ __ ] make it happen
so we should call this the karen bill
because it sounds like just a bunch of
[ __ ] karen's trying to get all kearny
on our
[ __ ] product here the national group
to keep an eye on is called project sam
they've been pushing the
thc is more potent or the thc in our
marijuana products is
higher than ever before it's not
grandfather's weed
i've heard that um they've literally
been saying that since we were in high
school
it's when we were in school in the 80s
and 90s it was all marijuana's way
stronger than it was in our day
and they've literally said that every
year well it is radical russ
added up and it might have to be like
two thousand percent thc to be
if they were right each time it's a
little bit stronger
it's a little bit stronger every year
and that's partly i am pushing that we
are there's a lot of us out there shout
out to my breeder friends who are out
there trying to push the limits on that
thc
don't [ __ ] stop don't stop hiring
never stop more potency
also more terps get the terms
the only place they've been successful
with a constant
potency cap is in vermont
right now vermont has a potency cap of
60 for concentrates
apparently washington state is
considering similar legislation
um the anti-pot groups have figured out
that
don't do it isn't a winning message and
so they're
shifted to a couple of similar
toned down messages like just go with
decriminalization
somehow decrim is better denver was
decrim when i was a teenager it wasn't
[ __ ] better i promise you
right um i still take the same thing
with
uh cannabis is more potent potent now
than ever before
um there's a couple others uh
big alcohol and big tobacco are going to
take it over which i
chuckle like if either one of those com
industries got into marijuana they'd be
selling a much safer product to humanity
and like i don't like marlboro i gave
them way too much money for way too long
but if they started selling weed like
they're switching to a company or
a product that kills zero people a year
versus one that kills four hundred
thousand
like that's a net win for humanity but
they think it's a winning argument to be
like they might get into it too
let's bring them on i've never said that
yeah we uh
all the people like me have been busy
working for the last couple years
like we haven't been fighting the good
fight anymore and so the
the people on the other side are
starting to gain some traction again so
everybody needs to buck up and i think i
said it a bunch last time i was on but
find out who your elected
representatives are it's a one quick
internet search away and email them as
often as you can get it legal where you
are if it's not
if it's legal where you are the rules
can be better
this is a colorado issue here mike so
who do they contact here in colorado to
try to prevent this sort of all of your
elected reps um so just
if you're in colorado doesn't matter
where you are say who's my
state representative for whatever your
area is
aurora denver thornton pueblo springs
the names will come up send them an
email um
down here in pueblo you're looking at
leroy garcia
um danaya eskar i think
that sounds right since i checked um
i know bobert's our national rep
um she's not gonna be super helpful with
federal legalization but y'all can try
um no comment yeah we could do in like
another two hours on what's happening
nationally and federally because there
is
something like 850 marijuana bills
in states in congress right now so
there's a lot of movement everywhere
um there's uh
there's a dude from nebraska i don't
know if he was the attorney general or
the
the governor saying that if you legalize
marijuana it's killing your kids
and like he was serious when he said
that into a microphone
staring at a camera and he's getting
eaten alive on the internet for it
but uh there's a whole different faction
that's just eating it up and they're
like yeah he's right
it is and then they throw out nonsense
like traffic accidents or
schizophrenia i think a lot of our age
like our generation the older people
that were programmed with the reefer
madness with all the hysteria
unfortunately slash they're passing
they're
disappearing they're covets [ __ ]
wiping them out they're getting old
they're retiring they're
going away the younger generations are
all about let me do whatever the [ __ ] i
want generation dreadlocks
uh the generation what do they call them
the millennials a lot of us are
them us we're just like let us do what
we want so pretty soon a lot of the
silly
control stuff is going to go away i say
that that's the
hope but they've been saying that since
they're taking away words and feelings
now so we're not allowed to have certain
words and feelings so i don't know where
the future is going mike i really
thought i had a
plan and some hope for the future until
i fought deeper into it and
they took away words from us so i don't
know it's different now
did i just kill the whole show we can go
there but
no i don't think the listeners are going
to like my views on
this stuff um so if they do limit the
potency levels on flowers and
concentrates
the entire industry will have to
redesign their entire
sops their production facilities their
equipment
everything will be different um way
worse than that because you can't change
potency with an ssop
i mean i can't i can't throw less calmag
in the bucket
and have the potency go from 31 to 18.
um and with concentrates they just do
what they're doing now
and then add 85 [ __ ]
i don't know why anyone would want it's
that's the point it's designed to
destroy the industry
and it's not even
cloaked or veiled at all
that or other than the thinnest garnish
of
think of the children nonsense it's
really really really ugly and the fact
that this is gaining traction drives me
[ __ ] nuts
because the whole argument for it is
nonsense
um the potency thing
it's not more potent than it was before
we've always had concentrates
with butane extracts and stuff we've
purified it recreationally but that's
what marinol is right they already did
that
it's not new or special it's just
advertised more so that everybody knows
about it now
um it's that there's a logical fallacy i
forget the name of it but it's when you
see something for the first time
your brain goes oh reggae must be new
i've never heard it before and then
somebody that's
not clueless about reggae it was oh bro
right there's a whole section in the
music store how have you never seen this
and that's the same thing with hash when
you're like well yeah i know that wax
and shatter look scary and the dab rigs
look kind of scary but
do you know about black tar hash and the
hot knife hits cause
not any less scary and they're like oh
my god what was that
and you start explaining some of this
stuff and their jaw drops
and then there's there's inevitably one
old guy in the group that's giggling and
it's like you're the [ __ ] one that
went to parties
because everybody in the generation
above us knows about hot knife hits
or a little piece of hash on a pin in a
matchbook under a beer glass
with a straw like before dab rigs they
had a bunch of stupid ways of
just lose so many young listeners minds
like what's he [ __ ] talking about you
guys go
go think about old stories videos old
knife hits
i used to put the hash on a pin with
some heat under it somehow
um if i can put a cup over it so when
the hash burns you catch all the smoke
in a cup and lift it up and suck the
smoke out of the cup
we just have to do weird [ __ ] everybody
there
take two butter knives and set them on
the stove until the ends glow
and instead of blow torching a banger
you're just heating up two knives and
then you'd have a
glass or a plastic straw you'd mash a
piece of hash between the two
knives and freebase it because there's
no other way to say it
yeah hash pipes like weezer had that
song back in 2001
but only people who traveled
internationally or were really into
cannabis knew what the [ __ ] they were
talking about
yeah but it's not like it's not new it's
just redressed
is is modern hash and it's allowing
people to replay fear cards that they
haven't been able to play in 20 years
it drives me nuts yeah uh we were at any
point
into it we were at an event and back in
the day they would sell us
uh co2 concentrate oil like uh
it's dab oil you could dab it you could
smoke it uh
but it would come in a syringe not like
with a needle on it
but that's how they would measure it out
and suck frosting kind of
yeah it's it's an oral syringe is
actually what it is you can
yeah yes that you could feed a kitten or
something out of this little syringe
you just put in the kitten's mouth and
shove the medicine down the kitten's
throat instead of having to get it to
eat something or something like that
that's what i used it for
but the owner of this place saw the
syringe and he tried to make us all
leave like you guys have to get out of
here
i was like bro that that's weed in there
and he did not believe us i had to
sit down and educate him because he saw
what looked like a syringe
and completely there was no talking no
[ __ ]
it was just over and i had to every now
and then
the syringes you'll see are popular in
the dispensaries because you can refill
cartridges with them
yeah and so instead of throwing your
card out when it's
it goes empty for the first time because
the carts not toast
you can save a few bucks by refilling it
and every now and then
some anti-pop mom will get on facebook
and share a couple of cell phone photos
she's snapped inside a dispensary
or a screen grab off a dispensary menu
on the online
and it'll include a refill syringe and
then for the next
two three months as i watch this photo
gets bounced around the echo chamber
that is the anti-power world
um that
they get so fired up but oh my god
they're injecting thc now and
i heard it causes instant schizophrenia
and
they're injected 100 pure thc and it's
it's doing crazy
things to these teenagers yeah and it's
like
it's a plastic there's no needle
no needle no needle on there you guys
we're not shooting up thc those syringes
like a little thing of decorative
frosting like yeah a lot of times you've
done that
oil that's rso you scored out just a
little like a pea size or a piece of
rice onto your finger and eat it
and you just put in the syringe because
it's easier to push it out and dose it
that way
it's not we're not going to shoot it up
you guys honestly that same club um
i pulled out a bottle of water out of my
backpack to fill up my dab rig
and the guy said you can't bring
beverages in here i was like bro it's
water i can bring water in here is you
have to buy beverages here
i was like it's to fill up my pipe dude
and he almost made me throw my
bottle of water away and i was like
we're not coming back here don't worry
that's why we need
real cannabis spaces yes so bad
and man if your state isn't legal yet
you gotta be writing everyone in office
right now
saying here's a way for us to make
millions and millions of dollars
and all the information is online right
now you can put together a hell of an
argument in like an
hour um email me if you need more
information
send me a message on social media mike
write up
add a template that people can copy and
paste um
it's so easy it's so so easy just go put
it on your facebook just hit
what'd we hit 10 billion in tax revenue
it might have been 1 billion a billion
[ __ ] load we just hit another major
milestone um
why are all the roads still all [ __ ]
up look if we get a billion dollars
like a wreck so
the people ask that about the roads and
the schools all the time and it's just
because
roads cost more than you think roads
cost
um like colorado rakes in it
and what seems like an amazing amount of
marijuana tax revenue
and i'm not saying it's not helpful
the anti-pop people work very hard to
make this
this fact seem shocking but our pot
revenue is about one percent of our
state budget
um which i mean one percent doesn't
sound like a lot but the number's huge
like it's colorado spends a lot of money
every year so does your state
um but one percent is super helpful
we're one percent less [ __ ]
um everything's one percent better
financially in colorado because of our
cannabis industry and for the most part
that's business that's already happening
um everybody i know that smokes weed
smoked weed before it was legal to smoke
weed
and that includes the people that have
become legal since legalization they all
smoked illegal weed before
they were legal that's just how it goes
sounds like we might be going back to
smoking more illegal weed if they start
[ __ ] with my concentrates mike i'm
not gonna smoke 15
dabs i'll be pouring the entire ram into
my
[ __ ] into the banger just every time
yeah
or trying to figure out how that that'll
be the immediate
response by people like us is down at
the head shop there will be a new
product
where you use solution a and tab b
to turn your 85 crap hash
back into 90 good hash yep
that's just how it'll be well they fixed
the price
if i'm getting one-fifth of my thc
do i get one-fifth of the price do i get
four you gotta pay for that filler
no yep this is that
it's it's fully not functional and it's
it's how i know that there's no good
faith if there was good faith here
they would have at least a couple of
people who understand how the cannabis
industry works and how we got here that
would have talked them out of
ever attempting this bill and it's
if your goal is really to protect the
kids there's a million ways
that we can protect kids like it used to
be my profession it's my wife's
profession
i know a lot of people whose job could
be
briefly or lightly described as
protecting kids and they could all use
[ __ ] more money and more funding and
more
resources and more people but this isn't
it this is a kill the marijuana
bill yeah kill the marijuana industry
bill plain and simple
it's not karen's responsibility to make
sure my daughter
doesn't get high potency concentrates
it's my responsibility i'm the one that
bought it at the dispensary i've got the
money the adult id though i was gonna
say the medical marijuana card but
that's not even necessary
i've got all the credentials i bought it
it's in my house where my daughter is
it's my responsibility
to make sure she doesn't get it so it's
not karen's responsibility
so karen stay the [ __ ] out of it we got
this under control
when it's it's not even neck you feel
like the world is full of stuff
that potency matters like i've got three
different strengths of town on my
[ __ ] cabinet
i can take like eight of the little ones
but if i take eight of the big ones it's
gonna be my last [ __ ] headache
um same thing with the vodka if
i screw up and drink the vodka like it's
corona
really bad things are gonna happen in my
world that aren't at all
intended or suggested by the
manufacturer
just because potent hash exists doesn't
necessarily mean
mean it's a problem it just means
there's nuance here that
middle american never noticed you don't
see a bunch of shooters you see big ass
bottles of vodka at the store yep
all right mike we've been going for
approximately 40 something-ish minutes
here maybe a couple of edits i know we
talked for a minute sure we started
going
um i think we covered all the major
notes that i have made do you have any
magical mic
moments that you would like to recap
regroup re-ramble upon before we start
wrapping up this beautiful podcast
uh just uh keep writing your elected
officials and uh keep an eye on the
anti-pop crowd because they're granting
traction again and
you always got to be wary of stupid
people in large groups because
they can do an amazing amount of damage
if left unsupervised
if people have listened to this far
they're probably interested in the
social are in the activism side of
things
they want to know how to help us out and
be on team cannabis so mike remind them
once again how they can find you so that
you can help them be a part of team
legalization you can find me on twitter
at nemopunk15 you can find me on
facebook at
pueblo for sensible cannabis laws and
you can find me on patreon at
patreon.com
forward slash white mic no as smooth as
[ __ ] dude i was gonna make sure you got
that patreon in there good job buddy
you're getting good at this podcasting
thing
i may let you come back on the show
since you were so good at that
i'll try to be nice and i'll try not to
get his death threats
there are only a couple i handled them
it's okay um ladies and gentlemen if
you'd like to support me on social media
it's really easy my uh instagram
uh you can follow the grow from your
heart podcast on instagram i honestly
don't post enough there i do post a lot
on ire underscore genetics that's where
i post the most on instagram
i post more on cannabis let's talk about
cannabis briefly here cannabis is a
cannabis friendly social media
application you can't buy sell or trade
cannabis
but you can post all of your cannabis
content you can post pictures of your
plants your dried buds you could do your
dab videos there
uh you could do garden tours you could
post product reviews all of the things
that the other social media applications
will chastise you for
we encourage and invite you to post
those on cannabis
cannabis is a free app it's available on
your android or apple device you can
also log in on your computer
check it out cannabis download the app
create an account log in give me a
follow
check out all the cool [ __ ] that i post
up there i think you will enjoy canada
if you enjoy the show
you should enjoy cannibals so give me a
follow there also check out my website
all things roster jeff grow from your
heart irie genetics are on my website
iregenetics.com
make sure you sign up for the newsletter
there if you need a grow help there's a
grow help tab
there are seed vendors there there's a
merch spot you can get shirts stickers
hats all kinds of great
beanies not hats let me correct myself
they're more like a beanie not a build
hat
you get that sort of stuff there um what
else do i need to say oh my patreon
also if you feel like the episode was
educational informative entertaining
maybe you'd just like to throw me a buck
or two because you learned something or
you'd like to support the cause
i support that as well the patreon is
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart
all of the information is right there on
the screen and thank you
to everybody for the patreon support i
think the last part of my wrap up here
is my email address if you've got
questions corrections comments or
concerns
positive or negative feedback i'd like
to hear from you the email address is
grow from your heart
at hotmail.com don't be shy send me a
message also
disclaimer uh i've got a lot of messages
that's gonna take me a minute to get
back to you that's
one of my new year's resolutions was to
be better at answering emails
i i'm trying dude it's hard when there's
so many every time
you share your screen when we're
prepping and i see something like a
notification bar it gives me so much
[ __ ] anxiety bro
i think if i got the volume of traffic
you get i'd cry
your notifications shouldn't be triple
digits that's all i'm saying but they
are so i'm trying you guys there's one
of me there are thousands of you i love
respect
appreciate uh you never stop sending us
every one of you yeah but it does take
me a minute i stay up late at night i
get up early in the morning
i'm trying and i do appreciate it don't
stop but don't feel like i've skipped
you abandon you forgotten you
you could be next on the list you could
be way down the list uh just
have faith in me i'm doing my best to
get to all of the content that you guys
are requesting
i appreciate it i love it but it's just
i keep saying there's one of me while
mike is on the screen but you guys know
what i mean it's mostly just one of me
uh where do we go from there mike i got
way off on a tangent there
i think that's all i just wanted to
confirm that there's only one ross to
jeff
thank you bro because some people get
one ah there's only one white mic
thank god actually i listen to another
podcast they talk about their friend
white mike all the time and it's really
funny
there are so many people like we all
have
we even have subheadings that are the
same like there's just too many mics
that's so funny yeah that better not be
you out there to live in the good life
that other white mic i hear about he's
having too much fun and you're not
telling me about it
i wish i was out having fun now it's uh
locked down life here man it's one of my
kids has um
a covet on friendly health conditions
yes so we're on we're still on super
lock danielle
yeah mike has been a hobbit for a minute
now
but yeah shakes his head and looks into
the camera yes
yep all right i think that uh i think
that wraps us up here for this episode
of the podcast i just want to [ __ ]
hang out thanks for listening everybody
yeah this is take some dabs and we're
going to zoom it up together bro cause
we don't get to hang out it's [ __ ]
late at night here you got some time
it's quiet here
uh we're gonna have i'm about to eat
some gummy oh [ __ ]
on camera even um yeah i'm gonna talk
about that edibles challenge on the next
episode you guys i'm gonna recap the
embracing organics edibles challenge
it'll be a brief talk but we'll hit that
one up on the next i love it
it was a good time uh we're not gonna
blow it now save that one for the next
episode
teaser i'm going to tie in the next
episode i do plan on talking about
renewing my medical marijuana card
and um that edibles challenge
and then i think i've got a question
about patreon
and then a um a photo question i like
popping photos into the video question
is the stuff that i've got highlighted
for the next episode
i usually don't give hints about the
next episode so thank you for making it
this far on the show mike thank you for
being here bro
it is time to wrap it up i want to take
a big fat [ __ ] dab so
um you know i'll be back in a couple of
days with fresh new content i owe a big
shout out to my buddy buzzbro
and until next time take a fat dab oh
shout out to mike also for being here
until next time take a fat dab and give
your mom a hug for me
oh yeah good show bro thank you bro that
was a fun one nah i got a piss i'll be
back in a minute then we'll dab
go i'm gonna do the same
you