yeah welcome back podcast world
i'm your host my friends call me rasta
jeff and this is episode 620
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to answer a
couple of grow
questions before we get there let's do a
few shout outs to a few members of the
710 club
of course the 710 club are my friends
who support us on patreon
at the 7 and 10 cent a month level or
higher
so with no further ado let's start off
with the big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out
to my friend sweet james jones let's
send a thank you shout out to rico
relaxo
let's send a special thank you shout out
to my buddy mobius grows
let's send a big fist bump and a thank
you shout out to chris b and tartan mike
let's send a big thank you shout out to
grant m and black hippie let's send a
big thank you shout out to my friend
levity loveday
let's send a big thank you shout out to
thomas m and mister let's send a big
thank you shout out to green vet
and let's wrap it up with the big grow
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out
to my friend redbeard big thank you and
big shout out to everybody who continues
to support the show on patreon
if you are not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so
all you have to do is visit www dot
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need will be
right there on the screen
and of course i did include a link in
the show notes and in the video
description
to make everything nice and easy for all
of my friends
alright thanks for joining me everybody
thanks for those patreon contributions
i do owe you an apology if you watched
the latest youtube video
you may have noticed that that video was
super grainy and not top quality
i apologize for that i pride myself on
putting out a top
quality product that video was not top
quality
mike and i thanks uh to mike for joining
me mike and i recorded via zoom
everything looked beautiful on the
computer screen everything sounded great
when i went to process the video and do
the editing it wasn't great
i did not want to can it i didn't want
to throw that episode away i wanted to
make sure you guys got to hear what mike
and i had to say mainly what mike had to
say in that episode
wanted to make sure that got put out i
did my best to clean it up
edit that a little bit put that show out
but i know that was not up to rasta jeff
standards that was not grow from your
heart podcast standards
i apologize things will be better in the
future i'll do my best to not make that
happen
i think i found the solution i found a
way to
mitigate that problem you guys don't
care what the solution is i almost
rambled on about that but
i found a way to record three different
video options and three different audio
options
i'll do my best to piece those three
recordings together that's six different
recordings to make a top shelf podcast
out of
i've got a backup plan for next time i
apologize that i failed you
on the last episode if you listen to the
audio you probably loved it you didn't
notice that it was a zoom meeting that
looked like [ __ ] there were a couple of
moments where it did kind of get
staticky but
i'm rambling about an apology you guys i
apologize that episode was not up to par
not up to my standards i'll up my game
we'll get the stuff going properly in
the future
but thank you for putting up with that i
do appreciate it um i did talk about the
edibles episode if you watched that last
episode
i told you i was going to recap the
edibles episode of the embracing
organics podcast
let's talk about embracing organics for
a brief moment embracing organics is a
podcast or a youtube show that is
it happens live on youtube every
thursday
uh it happens at 7 p.m mountain time i'm
in the mountain time zone i don't know
where you are
i know my time zone i know what time it
is for me you're gonna have to translate
use google it'll help you out but
thursday at 7 pm mountain time for about
two hours
honestly it's about 7 10 7 15 because we
like to take a few dabs and hang out but
a little after seven until about a
little after nine we hang out on youtube
and we talk about growing organically we
talk about growing we talk about all
kinds of random chaotic stuff
uh on one episode of the embracing
organics show recently
we did eat a bunch of edibles i myself
ate a 250 milligram dose of edibles
and we hung out and we tried to have a
show uh that was a good show let's recap
that now by the way i didn't mention
that if you do miss the live show of
embracing organics
you can always catch the replay the show
stays up on youtube once it's over
we repost it up to youtube it does stay
you can watch it basically
forever so search right now embracing
organics give them a subscribe
let them know rasta jeff sent you anyway
let's talk about
the edibles challenge episode that i
participated in
on embracing organics with my friends we
all acquired the same edibles the same
amount of edibles
some of us ate all 250 right at the
start of the show some of us kind of
dosed ourselves
slowly throughout the show some people
didn't choose to eat all of the dosage
uh as i watched a few people just throw
it all into their mouths at the start of
the show
my plan was to eat 50 now 50 later see
how it goes maybe
50 more a couple people threw all 250 in
their mouths and i thought
i don't want to be late to the party so
i just ate all 250 right there at the
beginning
i took a couple of monstrous dabs after
i ate the 250 i was like i'm not super
high
then i took a dab that put me on another
planet
and from there i was uh it's i needed a
seat belt for my office chair cause i
felt like i was gonna float away i was
super high so i ate the 250 milligrams
of edibles
i survived the show i had a good time i
hung out in the after show
if you're part of the embracing organics
live crew chat
uh part of their patreon we hang out
with you after on patreon you're invited
to come hang out we give you a link you
can join the show
we'll let you hang out and join the
video and we chat i did a good
job hanging out with those folks after
uh but as soon as i signed out
i ate everything in the refrigerator i
ate everything in the cupboards and then
i slept on the couch until i had to wake
up and pee
then i went back to sleep and it was a
blurry blurry night the next morning i
woke up doing the damn did i eat
all of the food and yes i did i ate all
of the food
i drank all of the drinks uh consumed
everything in the house smoked all of
the concentrates also
the funny part was watching a few of my
friends try to manage themselves
one of our friends i'm i may not say
everybody's names i don't know that they
want to be called out i don't need to
embarrass ourselves our friends
uh one of our friends north of the
border had to check out early
he was twisted he was done he was
roasted he was cooked he was barbecued
it was over for him uh we've got a
jamaican friend shout out to my jamaican
friend rastafari
ah he looks like a statue he was just it
looks like weekend at bernie's at his
house he was laid out just a little
he was just one if he didn't have such
bad cottonmouth he would have been
drooling on himself i do believe
tanasi handled himself quite well dirt
man dan didn't seem to be very affected
uh watching keith try to handle i said i
wasn't gonna say their names but [ __ ] it
we're saying their names are gonna watch
the show
keith was gonna stop at a certain amount
of edibles he was already
plenty intoxicated you could see it on
his face his mouth wasn't moving
uh he would say words but his mouth
wasn't making the right shape for those
words
it's kind of funny to watch him but oh
he's kind of pale too
he said if he got so many likes on the
video that he would eat
more edibles and basically he said if he
got 150 he would eat the 150 and if we
got 200 likes on the video
he would eat 200. um i may be a smart
ass and maybe not the best friend on the
planet
sometimes i used my social media prowess
and i posted to facebook saying hey
we're on this live video and if you post
enough likes
my buddy will eat more edibles please
come give us more likes and guess what
my facebook friends came through shout
out to you guys for coming through
and keith ate way too many edibles that
night
i think we had a good time overall oh we
got to see who could handle the edibles
nobody honestly
was uh wrecked in a dangerous position i
said that our canadian friend checked
out early because he was twisted
it was okay he did the same thing i did
he way too much food and went to bed
uh he's still canadian he still talks
funny he's still killing it at life
i just took a few hours to get him out
of that weed coma so we all handled it
pretty well it was a good show
once again i encourage you to check out
the embracing organics edibles challenge
just search for embracing organics you
will find it ah it's a good time
where am i going from there i got my
medical marijuana card renewed
what that's right during covid times we
are still getting our medical marijuana
cards renewed it's hard to get
appointments it's hard to
to do a lot of things in person i got an
email from my
cannabis doctor that said hey it's time
to renew would you like to do it over
the phone and i said sure
and they said make an appointment on
this app so i clicked on a thing and it
said
here are your times and i picked a time
it said be ready 10 minutes ahead of
time to fill out a paper
i got a text message 10 minutes ahead of
time i filled out that paper i hit send
after i hit send i got a phone call it
was the weed doctor and said hey
uh why do you need medical marijuana and
i explained why and they said have you
had medical marijuana before and i said
this is like my 14th or 15th year of
renewing my card
they giggled and they said cool your
paperwork is pushed through give me your
credit card number
i paid them for my medical marijuana
card filled out a couple of papers on
the state
uh if the state didn't have a small
snafu with my paperwork
it would have taken a total of two hours
to get my medical marijuana card renewed
i didn't have to leave the house didn't
have to put on pants
like i said there was a small technical
mistake not a big deal something was
spelled wrong and so
i was just a technical the other people
the service i used
uh spelled my name wrong my name is
spelled wrong technically they spelled
it correctly but it's not the way
my full name is spelled if that made any
sense to you uh but other than the quick
snafu it would have taken me a total of
maybe two hours to get my weed card
renewed
which is remarkable back in the day uh
we would make appointments
and you would go to the weed doctor and
you would realize that
they just said sure come at 11 and they
told everybody they called to come
at 11 or whatever time they felt was
good they just said come in
there were no appointments we would
stand in line uh all day
sometimes you'd get there at nine in the
morning you'd get to see the dock at
five
and they would sign your paperwork that
day and send you on your way it used to
cost
uh somewhere between three and five
hundred dollars to see the doctor this
time it was 80 bucks
it used to cost 120 to register with the
state this time it was 25. 25
it's getting much cheaper the whole
appointment everything was 105
it took me less than two hours didn't
have to leave the house
technically didn't have to put on pants
i did wear pants just to make you feel
better
but that was quick that was easy so i'm
good for a solid year
i got my medical marijuana card
really comfortable it was a really
pain-free [ __ ] flawless process they
call you and ask you a few questions
uh then they ask you if you're crazy
basically do you have any mental
conditions they would start are you
suicidal do you want to hurt yourself or
anybody else
are you pregnant weird [ __ ] like that
and if they most of the time you know
how to answer the questions it's so much
easier over the phone
uh and then when i told her it was my
14th year or 15th year of renewing my
card
she just started typing she's like we
don't need to ask all these questions
we're just gonna go ahead and uh
i think you're ready to go and she
re-give me my card so i got the new weed
card
everything is good to go got my plant
count taken care of
i do not opt for the uh increased plant
counts because in colorado we're
limited to 12 plants anyway if i were
going to have a dispensary or something
grow my plants i may go for the extra
plants but i don't pay extra for the
extended plant count
it doesn't make any sense it's pointless
for me so i'm just got the regular plant
count
uh gonna crush it with that it's fine
for me it does what i need to do i got a
small grow space anyway
i've made those numbers work for the
past couple of years so didn't need to
increase
i was amazing how easy it would have
been just to pay for the extended plant
count
which is basically money uh allegedly
i'm not sure
anyway that was the weed card doctor the
next thing i want to talk about is
congratulations to my friends at
cannabaz that's right
i talk about cannabis all the time i'll
do it quickly right now cannabis is a
social media application it's a lot like
excuse me i'm just going to clear my
throat real hard we'll keep going
sorry i did take a bunch of fat dabs
before the show so i do have that
dab throat happening i'm sure you were
as tired of it as i was
anyway cannabis it's a social media
application you can't buy trade or sell
cannabis on there
but you can post all of your cannabis
photography dab videos garden shots all
the stuff that
the other social media applications will
take down and ban you for
bring that [ __ ] to cannabis cannabis we
want to see your weed picks don't bring
your booty pics
uh don't bring your boobie shots we
don't need that there i mean be
cute but don't overdo it you know that's
all that there's plenty of that on ig
we want the cannabis community
composter weed picks anyway on cannabiz
there was a
some controversy with the word cannabis
another company
was claiming that they had a copyright
on the word buzz
and cannabis couldn't use cannabis they
had to hire a lawyer
not to to my own horn i did my best to
help with the contributions for the
lawyer we got the lawyer covered
a few other people helped as well there
were auctions there were raffles and
things like that
that helped cover the cost of the lawyer
i can't say i did it i did my best to
help and also a lot of cannabis family
ivory army grow from your heart gang
we all helped out a lot you helped out a
lot so thank you but
had to get a lawyer had to fight a
copyright lawsuit
and congratulations to canada buzz
because they won
the [ __ ] lawsuit shout out to
my friends at cana buzz
they own the name cannabis nobody can
take it from them the trademark lawsuit
is over
uh they're keeping it good work you guys
i'm happy for you they don't have to
change the name of the app which would
have been a total pain in the ass
don't have to change branding so you
guys catch a buzz
join us over on i probably don't even
know that catch a buzz is something i
can say that's probably somebody else's
if not q go uh go copyright that [ __ ]
catch a buzz join the community
at cannabaz uh i'm on cannabis a lot
i've got nearly 60
000 cannabis followers thank you guys i
do a lot of [ __ ] on cannabis
post a lot do a lot of uh interaction
there join me i invite you cannabis it's
free
i am irie underscore genetics i wanted
to say congrats to my friends because
that has been an uphill battle and i'm
glad it's finally over for you
uh next i want to give a special shout
out to a friend of mine uh he's a
business partner but more importantly
he's a friend of mine more importantly
he is a good [ __ ] person
i want to give a shout out to my friend
james bean from seeds here now
this is not advertising this is not a
plug for seeds here now but do make sure
to check out seeds herenow.com and use
coupon code gfyh10
but the important part here is that we
acknowledge an
outstanding person an excellent member
of the cannabis community and my friend
james bean
i'm not kissing his ass or doing
anything like that i did an episode
talking about a person
who was leaving their partner behind
because their morals their ideas and
their grow room ethics changed
and our viewer our friend wanted some
advice and some guidance basically some
reassurance and some affirmation that
they were doing the right thing
i talked about that person and gave them
some guidance on the podcast
my friend my business partner james bean
sent me a message and said hey
that person is an awesome person and i
would like to give them a reward so
uh james bean that is admirable of you
that's uh you deserve a big high five a
salute a shout out
uh you've got my respect you already had
my respect but i want to make it known
to the community how good of a person
you are uh you run a solid business
uh you talk a solid game you're amazing
on podcasts but people may not know the
truth that deep down inside you're a
good
[ __ ] dude and i've got your back
because you've always got my back and
you've got the communities back
i wanted to take a moment shout out
james bean from seeds here now
also if you're the person that sent me
that message
uh check your email or send me another
email because uh
we would like to help you out for being
such a good person
shout out bro let's keep moving i wanted
to make sure to acknowledge my friend
james bean
dude i do appreciate you the community
does appreciate you
thank you now this is the part of the
show where we are going to read
the listener emails i've got cottonmouth
so bad you guys i took so many fat dabs
right before the show
i'm gonna take a sip of this kombucha
recompose myself and then we're gonna
read the
listener emails here let's take a drink
sip something with me hydrate you guys
hashtag sips tea
all right not editing that out i'm human
thank you for joining me now here is the
first email on this show
this one is titled shout out question it
came from
actually i just grabbed this from
youtube somebody said i joined
the patreon approximately two weeks ago
and i still have not gotten a shout
out my friend crazy hand replied this
was a youtube comment
crazy hand replied to the comment it
says i feel he does it randomly
uh i've never heard mine on a shout out
part and then he mentioned it
and then he did me a solid and gave me a
special shout out and then he said my
rng is always bad i can't remember what
rng stands for but
um uh so mainly the question here is
uh somebody said they signed up for
patreon approximately two weeks ago i
still haven't given them a shout out
there are a couple of reasons for that
it's nothing personal i think this
person actually did get their shout out
shortly after this
comment was posted let me explain why if
you contribute to patreon sometimes it
does take me a minute to give you a
shout out
i am recorded one solid week ahead i do
two
shows a week i try to record both of
them uh so if
the show that comes out tuesday was
recorded last tuesday basically or the
show that comes out thursday
was recorded the tuesday before so i'm
several days ahead
just in case something goes wrong i
don't want to have to get on the mic and
record a show thursday edit it post it
hope it comes out on youtube on time on
thursday
i'm ahead of myself so uh we gotta wait
for the episodes to come out in the
order which they come out
and with the covid times uh with [ __ ]
life the way that it is i try to be at
least one or two episodes ahead
so that if something does go wrong in my
life i've got one or two loaded up in
the can
is what we say uh i've got a couple
loaded up that i can launch
if something's wrong with me if
something's wrong with my gear if my
internet's down
i've got a backup plan so uh you send me
the
message on the first saying hey i'm a
patron i want the shout out
i write it down on the first maybe i'll
record on the third or fourth
uh then that won't come out till the
seventh maybe and then
maybe i recorded two episodes maybe
you're the second episode that month
that i record
you're not going to get your shout out
till the 10th maybe you're the third
you're looking at the 13th of the month
now
so it's just about the first of the
month i write down the shout outs and
then i record them through the month
and it may just take a minute i do get
to them
also i'm getting i don't want to
complain i'm getting an overwhelming
amount of shoutouts and amount uh
overwhelming amount of contributions and
response i
love it i can't keep up i used to do 10
shout outs at the top of every episode
if you pay attention now sometimes it's
12. sometimes i extend it to 13 if the
names are short and i can sneak it in
so it went from 10 shout outs every
episode to 12 or 13.
i may and i can't make you a promise
because my time is limited
i may have to step it up and do a third
episode just to get the patreon
shoutouts in every month which
if i can find another one more evening
to record i would love to give you a
third episode and if i can get the
content
if you guys can send me more questions
and [ __ ] i would love to get that third
episode out i would make the adjustments
but that may be
what has to happen so uh the main issue
is
that you're i get the patreon notice on
the first of the month and then i put
out
eight episodes every month you may get
your shout out on that eighth episode
and i just go down the list honestly uh
i just pick the 710 club and i just
start writing their names i actually
type them into the computer
and i just read them as they come up so
uh sometimes people get snuck in there
if there's a special circumstance
like if it's your birthday or if you
just contributed to patreon today and
you're brand new maybe i'll put you on
there
but for the most part uh they're random
they just i get the notifications on the
first
i try to get them all done by the end of
the month if not i continue them through
the next month
they used to be 10. excuse me used to be
10. now it's 12 or 13. i may have to do
that third episode i'm trying
to adjust my schedule for that third
episode you guys podcasting isn't as
easy as it looks i gotta
uh i gotta write the show it has to come
from somewhere i gotta i've talked about
this before we're not gonna ramble too
much
i got editing to do afterward then it
takes a long time for youtube to post it
as well so
uh be patient and if that's the same
with the questions if you've sent me
your questions on patreon on the first
and i haven't read it by the second
please be patient it may take me a few
weeks to get to you i'm recorded ahead
at least two episodes
and i've got questions lined up for at
least four or five episodes already
i'm written ahead recorded ahead please
be patient i do respect your questions
your time
i appreciate you i don't want you to
stop uh keep in mind
there are a lot of you and there's only
one of me this is a one-man podcast
there's nobody behind the scenes here
uh i am the writer editor director
producer
uh i do all of this stuff so please be
patient with me
but don't stop i like the pressure i do
no pressure no diamonds if you don't
keep me
going i get lazy idle hands are the
devil's playground so you guys please
keep me overloaded
it inspires me so don't stop can't stop
won't stop
i'm [ __ ] high and rambly but let's
keep it on track i've got another great
question
this one came from patreon it came from
jackie daytona
and it said no actually this one came
from youtube came from jackie daytona on
youtube and it said hey jeff
thanks again for the great info i had a
thought when you were explaining nanners
in a previous episode i talked about
nanners
uh hermaphroditic male flowers and
female plants
ah that's what i was calling nanners it
says people love
visuals i love visuals too but i think
you have something different in mind in
this question here
i think you mean visual aids it says and
sometimes a pop-up photo can show a good
example of what you're talking about
i've been putting in photos right about
here uh somewhere here in this region in
the video
i've been learning a lot more with my
editing equipment i've got a couple of
uh
other ideas that may happen here in the
future to give you some more uh visual
aids
but uh it says nanners herms male female
parts etc
people obviously can just google it
however it could really add a new
dynamic to your already great podcast
thank you for sharing your generous
knowledge
uh man jackie daytona thank you i do
appreciate that great comment that is a
good idea that is great feedback i love
constructive criticism
uh positive or negative feedback as long
as they're done politely
are both taken well uh this is a great
idea you're very very accurate and very
correct i should
have posted a picture of a plant with a
nano
right here that was a missed opportunity
good job on catching that
uh so now's a good time to catch up uh
never too late right now's a good time
better late than never is what i think
my brain is trying to say
so at this point i'm going to pop up a
couple of photos here on the screen and
we're going to talk once again about
nanners if you listen to the episode
about nanners
here is a great visual representation of
nanners what i'm going to show you
is a female cannabis plant that is late
into flower this is a very well
developed flower and you will see that
in the very center of this flower
there are two yellow things that just
don't look right popping out of the
center of the bud
i'm gonna put the picture right here on
the screen and right here in the center
i'll try to circle it or something i
need to learn the software so i can't
promise you what's going to happen but
i'll do something to indicate
right here this part that i'm showing is
what i'm calling the nano you'll see why
we call that the banana
that is a female plant it's got buds on
it it's got trichomes we can see the
female
pistols is what you may want to call
them we can see the female
clearly see that it's a female but we
see a couple of male parts in the middle
of that plant
those are nanners that is what we call
an intersex plant that is what we call a
hermaphrodite plant that is
hermaphroditic
sometimes those manners contain pollen
and that pollen can pollinate your room
now this plant is way too far beyond
pollination point for that to be an
issue but if you've got younger plants
in the room
that plant could receive the pollen so
that is what we call a nano
that could or could not contain pollen
sometimes they have pollen sometimes
they do not have pollen sometimes they
have pollen
that is non-viable so
that's what a nano looks like i'm going
to scroll through my ipad here and find
another picture and explain this one
once again
this one the thing that looks like a
tongue sticking out of the butt it looks
like a yellow tongue
that is a nano that is a male flower
sticking out of a female plant once
again
we have got a hermaphrodite an intersex
plant
so this plant the past two shots that i
showed you there would be a decision to
make
if there's no pollen coming out of those
nanners if you're running one crop on
one cycle that has no chance of getting
pollinated
you may keep that plant around a couple
of late nanners
in late flower may not be detrimental to
the grow
if it happens early that's when i get
rid of them for sure if it happens in
week one or week two it's gone week
three it's gone
week four five and six i'd probably get
rid of it week eight
i would consider keeping that bad dog
because the flowers are so far
into bloom they're so far into ripeness
the female parts which
would receive that pollen are so
recessed and dried up that that plant
won't receive pollen it will not
pollinate it will not make seeds
so this plant with this tongue looking
male pollen sac sticking out
if that is the fire if that's a really
good cannabis and it only makes one or
two of those on the entire plant
i may consider keeping that but that is
a clear picture
of a nano very good shot i'm going to
call this one a tongue we got a new word
for it looks like a tongue in my opinion
i'm going to scroll through my ipad and
see what my next photo is the next photo
which i'm going to show you
is a very clear shot of a cannabis plant
with male and female sex parts clearly
displayed
in one single bud set of this plant this
is a lower bud
we can see the female parts uh this
little hair that we see coming off here
uh a lot of people call it the hairs
those are a lot of people are gonna call
it pistols uh those are stigmas or
pistols i may have said stamens a moment
ago that's the wrong word i shouldn't
have said stamen i don't know
uh why i said stamen talking about the
female plants uh stigmas and pistols is
what those are called
uh the little hairy parts here this
other part that's opened up that looks
like a sea shell that opened or a flower
that bloomed
that is a male cannabis flower that part
that opened up the pollen was in there
that may have contained pollen that is
now all over the garden that part is
actually the stamen that part there is
the stamen
it popped open uh it may have shot
pollen all over the plants next to this
the female parts the pistols and the
stigmas may have been pollinated
so this is a plant with clear intersex
traits we can see a male flower a male
pollen sac which has been opened and we
can see
the female stigmas or pistols so that is
a very good shot to show you a male
and a female now i'm going to scroll
through my ipad and see what i've got
next
the next photo is another shot of a male
and a female flower on the same plant
they're early in the flower this is a
great way to show you
what a male flower is going to look like
so we've got a guy
who is holding a small part of a plant
to indicate what we're looking at
this part here that looks like a pod it
is seed shaped it's bean shaped
that is a male flower and that thing
is a day or two away from opening up and
pollinating the rest of the grow that
thing's big and beefy
it's swollen it's going to come out just
a little more and protrude then it will
point down
then it will open up and pollen will
come out of that pollen sac that is a
very clear
male pollen sac however further up the
plant the little bud that we see here
it's got those female parts those little
the things you guys like to call hairs
those stigmas and pistols that are
sticking off there that is a clear
female part
and then you can see uh i can see
swollen calyxes or swollen bracts which
i will assume
are seeded already or are developing
seeds or
will develop seeds so that is a very
clear shot
of a hermaphroditic plant a male female
intersex plant all right i think i've
made it clear what male
this part right here that is a male
plant that part
not a male plant that is a male part if
your plants show that it is probably a
male
if it's got these hairy parts up here
that's what we're looking for in a
female
i'll try to post a solid picture of a
male that's a boy
now i'll post a solid picture of a
female that's a female
and now you've seen what the intersex
plants look like now i've made it clear
what manners look like what males look
like what females look like what
intersex plants look like
that should help you out quite a bit one
thing
that you should not get paranoid about
are swollen brax or
swollen calyxes when you're looking at a
cannabis plant the parts that develop
are calyxes and brax they keep growing
sometimes those look like they're
swollen and they look like they are
male parts those are not male parts they
will be
at the bottom of the bud so you'll have
a little branch and at the bottom of the
butt it'll start to look like popcorn
it'll have little balls
those could be swollen bracts or
calyxes don't over judge don't get too
paranoid don't get too excited
and get too quick to cut down a plant
that is showing you female parts because
you
think it may be a male verify make sure
that it's a male
at the intersections at the nodes is
where you're most likely to see
the first signs of male sex if you're
seeing those balls and the buds that is
probably
a swollen calyx or a bract that is just
swollen because it's developing the way
it should
don't be paranoid ah don't let your mind
play tricks on you
and most importantly don't cut down a
female because you've mistaken it
for a male plant all right i think that
is all i've got
i want to thank everybody on social
media i posted hey guys i need n gals
i need a photo of hermaphroditic plants
and i especially need a shot with some
nanners in it
i want to thank all of my friends who
sent me pictures of plants with nanners
uh i did with hell withhold their names
to protect the innocent i don't want to
say
hey my buddy jim has hermaphroditic
plants in his garden
here you go i just felt it would be best
to keep those names
uh to myself keep those people protected
i may also show at the end of the video
i may just pop up a few more pictures of
intersex
plants because i did get a lot so i want
to thank all of my friends who sent me
all of the marvelous intersex plant
pictures i got so many
uh some of them made me sick to my
stomach some of them were exactly what i
was looking for
thank you i thought it was great that i
had to reach out and ask for pictures
of intersex plants being a breeder you'd
think i'd have that but guess what
i don't have that maybe i just didn't
take enough pictures we don't take pics
of our fuck-ups right you only take
pictures of the good stuff
all right you guys i'm gonna quit
rambling i got nice and high before this
episode so i want to thank you for
putting up with my rambles
i want to thank you for putting up with
the throat clearing uh once again i
apologize for that last
episode but i want to thank you for
listening to another successful episode
of the girl from your heart podcast
if you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
maybe you learned something maybe you
had a couple of chuckles maybe you just
like to throw me a dollar for my time
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need is right there on the screen
once again there is a link in the show
notes and the video description to make
it easy for all my friends
big thanks to everybody who supports the
show on patreon
if you've got any questions corrections
comments or concerns all you have to do
is send me an email
the email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com make sure you check
out my website
at iriegenetics.com all things grow from
your heart all things ire genetics
all things ross to jeff are right there
at iregenetics.com
that is all i've got for you ladies and
gentlemen i'll be back in a couple of
days with fresh new content
i want to give a giant shout out to my
friend cascadian groan
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
full season
you