all right here we go take 27 maybe it's
could be take 30. i've honestly lost
count of takes at this time
we're gonna get it right this time here
we go welcome to the show podcast world
i am your host my friends call me rasta
jeff this is episode 621 of the grow
from your heart podcast
this may be a short episode this is
definitely not your regularly
scheduled program uh this is a very
special episode dedicated to a very
special person
it is not the show i wanted to deliver
to you it is not the show i wanted to
record today
but this is the show that my friend
stoneyscholar deserves
i'm gonna try to keep it together i may
get emotional i may have to take a
couple of breaks there may be some weird
edits
but we're gonna get through this
together um a couple of nights ago
my friend stoney scholar a very integral
member of the ivory army
a very huge member of the cannabis
community a very important part of the
world
was hit and killed by a drunk driver uh
i've got a lot of mixed emotions about
that the first one is [ __ ] my friend is
dead i've got sadness and sorrow
then i've got a lot of mixed emotions
toward the person who killed my friend
it's not my spot to judge it's not my
spot to deal with that but
holy [ __ ] uh my friend is dead and it's
somebody else's fault so
uh that sucks that person i'm not gonna
cast any judgment or hate on that person
they've got to deal with the fact that
they took out my friend their
uh they got to deal with that for the
rest of their living life but man [ __ ]
you for killing my friend is how i
honestly feel
it hurts it sucks somebody's gone my
friend is gone somebody's husband is
gone
uh a bunch of pets daddy is gone and
that [ __ ]
sucks dude ah we're not gonna [ __ ] and
complain on the show that's what it
feels like i've started off doing
a lot of emotions going on let's turn
this into a special shout out
and a tribute to my friend stoney
scholar i discovered stony on the
embracing organics podcast shout out to
the whole eo crew
i hope you guys watch the eo podcast
that we talk about stony i'm sure we're
going to talk about them
the whole episode so check that one uh
but i met stoney discovered stony
scholar through the embracing organics
podcast he was eo crew
he was dgc that his dude grows crew he
was also irie army before he knew it he
just had to find us and discover us and
become part of the crew
he quickly became irie army uh he was a
good dude he was
uh he was a fellow grower uh he was irie
army he was dgc
he was a husband he was a pet dad he was
a good friend he was my [ __ ] friend
he was a cool
funny dude he was cantankerous and
ornery
and uh a little bit he liked to push it
and he was a little bit provocative
those are my favorite kind of [ __ ]
people he was cantankerous is one of the
words i like to use for him
uh that those are great people i always
had a good time talking to him i did
troll him a little bit
uh but that was the relationship that we
had we trolled each other we poked each
other i gave him a hard time he gave me
a hard time
it was to encourage each other when i'm
trolling you and poking you
it's a gentle way of showing you that
there is a better way i'm encouraging
you
we're just enlightening each other it's
how bros and guys do it i'll do it to
the ladies
too but we had kind of a trolly
relationship with each other
and it was fun i just hope he knows that
i had nothing but love
and respect and that our friendly
bickering was nothing but
two old guys friendly arguing bickering
is too old guys
so stoney i hope you always took me with
a grain of salt
i hope you always knew i was giving you
my [ __ ] with tongue-in-cheek
i had nothing but love still got nothing
but love and respect for stony scholar
uh i think i'm still in shock and pissed
off and angry that he's gone
uh but doing this podcast is helping me
and my boy deserves this
uh stoney was a generous [ __ ] dude
actually this pipe i've been smoking out
of on recent live shows and recent
episodes was a gift
to my buddy stoney so i told you how i
discovered him let me tell you how i
actually met
stony scholar in person the dude grows
concentration celebration i think it was
that event there are so many events
don't remember the name don't remember
which one it was it was the dude grows
event
at the uh v was the place used to be
called
cultivated synergy was that what it was
cultivated synergy up there in denver
really cool place the dude gross would
throw parties there events there
uh the stoney scholar came there and
actually hung out he came with
uh stabby he came with the whole eo crew
and met me hung out at my booth he
actually stored his backpack behind the
ivory genetics booth
the whole night because he had so much
[ __ ] with him because he was on the road
he brought me this pipe gave me this
pipe as a gift
if you wanted to smoke some of his
concentrates he'd hand you the jar say
take as big of a [ __ ] dab you want
if you wanted to smoke his flower he'd
say pick the bud you want to smoke
dude was super generous super kind we
had funny laughs
we had we were grouchy old men together
that laughed at grouchy old men [ __ ] and
i loved it it felt good it was fun
uh it feels good to honestly you guys
this is therapy for me
and i owe this to my friend stoney so
i'm gonna hit this ball
think about my buddy stoney then we'll
continue in a moment here i just wanted
to make sure
that we'd give him a shout out for being
a generous dude being a cantankerous
dude
always an honest dude he never to me he
never seemed dishonest he was too
cantankerous and honoring to tell a lie
he'd rather tell you the dirty truth
with his tongue in his cheek and look at
you sideways and be like actually you
look like a [ __ ] idiot in that shirt
you would never tell you look good in
something he didn't look good in that
was his style and i appreciate that in
people that's the kind of friends i like
to have around
i'm gonna hit a bowl take a very brief
moment it's a podcast i can't do a
[ __ ] hour of silence for my boy we're
gonna hit a bowl
have a brief moment think about your
friends think about the people that are
around you the people you don't see
often enough the people you see too
often
think about the folks you love the
people you're going to miss when they're
not around
i'm going to think about my buddy stoney
scholar if you knew stony think about
him while i hit this ball maybe hit a
bull with me if you didn't know him
send a vibe up to him or think about the
people that you miss or that you don't
want to miss
let's uh celebrate stony scholar with a
puff off of this bowl together
i'm gonna quit rambling moment of
silence and a rip from my buddy stoney
scholar let's do it together you guys
cheers stoney scholar
i'll never forget that stony scholar
showed up to the event with the [ __ ]
email and a rig ready to go
plugged it into my booth and just
started taking dabs at my booth i was
like this is like my workspace bro
we're gonna have to make some room and
he's like sure i'll just put it behind
your booth
and everybody ended up behind my booth
dabbing and having a good time
i was a great little home base it's a
really good time hanging out with stony
scholar
it's [ __ ] that i'm never going to
get to do that again i want to give him
compliments and praises he was a good
dude he's a good grower
we gave each other a lot of [ __ ] but it
was to drive each other
i come on here and i seem like i am the
cannabis guru i'm the one teaching i'm
the one
uh spreading the knowledge and sharing
things with everybody uh
stoney taught me a lot don't get it
twisted i learn a lot from
everybody stoney never failed to teach
me something he had new ideas
he was innovative he had completely
different thought processes we think in
a completely different way
which i enjoy and respect those are the
kind of friends i like to be surrounded
by i don't need a bunch of friends that
all love reggae and fish and all want to
grow weed and do all the same exact [ __ ]
or we end up doing the same exact [ __ ]
i love that he was different than me
that he was a good dude so
um i think if i just keep going i'm
rambling and this will get emotional
and all of that stuff so um there's
nothing left to do but take a big fat
dab and just give a big fist bump this
right here fist bump stoney scholar
that's for you bro
i wanted to come on here and make sure
to show you some love you deserved a
full episode
it's a short one you guys i'm in no
condition
uh to record a long podcast about
growing weed i'll be back in a couple of
days you know how i do it
thank you uh for joining me for this
episode thank you for paying tribute to
my buddy stoney scholar
thank you for supporting the podcast and
for being my friend i got a lot of
people
sending me shout outs saying hey i heard
we lost a friend yes we did
i am okay uh it hurts it sucks
like i said before i'm mad that my
friend is gone i'm mad that i don't get
to troll him talk [ __ ] to him get his
advice give him advice have that dude
around
uh i'm angry that somebody recklessly
and irresponsibly killed my friend
that's completely [ __ ] uh it is not
my place to judge or punish that person
so i'm going to do my best to forgive
them in my heart that will take some
time to be honest with you
uh i don't i don't know exactly how to
let go of the feeling of you killed my
friend so [ __ ] you
uh but that'll that will come i'm
getting older things are i'm learning a
lot
uh but i'm gonna deal with it the best i
can we've got a big crew
that does uh support each other but
we're gonna need some love and support
the entire embracing organics family
lost a huge team member
uh stoney was working on some projects
that lost a huge team member so
uh i'm okay i'm gonna be okay let's send
those love and hugs to the eo crew
shout out to my friends at eo i started
off on that podcast just being
a panel i was a guest they invited me to
be a guest and then they said hey dude
you are now a panel member you can hang
out anytime honestly now it's the eo
family
uh we check on each other uh we send
each other messages we're always saying
what's up making sure everybody's okay i
get funny messages from some of those
guys in the morning
uh stab you'll message me at [ __ ]
three in the morning dirt mandan hits me
up around five
everybody's in different time zones so
it's really fun uh dave and i talk a lot
more than you guys would imagine
so we've become the embracing organics
family and yes sometimes there are
riffs in the force and groups have
bickering and whatnot but hopefully
something like this will show
a lot of the younger kids that we got to
put the [ __ ] away
we got to be friends we got to love one
another we got to respect each other not
just in each group but in the community
and the world
overall uh that's a good way to wrap
this up you guys
love the people you could love love the
people that are around you
they may not be there forever i know
we're focused on the gardens we're
focused on business we're focused on
moving forward it's quarantine it's
covet time
who knows what we're focused on right
now let's not forget to focus on love
and friendship
take a minute to thank your friends for
being your friends take a minute to
enjoy your friends while they're your
friends the old ones the young ones and
these weird times anybody can go away at
any time
it could be a drunk driver it could be
covet it could be heart disease
it could be so many things in this world
that could take you out so let's
appreciate the people that are around
let's spend some time with those people
put down the iphones put down the ipads
spend some eye to eye contact with the
people that we love
i'm gonna heat up a dab nail i'm gonna
take a fat dab in honor of my buddy
stoney scholar
i think i'm just going to let the
credits roll by or something like that
while i take this dab maybe i'll play
some music or something
i don't want to make the video too long
and redundant and obnoxious
so once again i want to send a giant
shout out to my buddy stoney scholar
stay tuned he did leave behind a wife
who is now
she does not have a husband who uh i can
only imagine what it would be like to
lose your partner in life
part of the income is gone it's not just
the income it's the stability
the emotional support that person's been
there next to you every waking hour
that's going to be a huge adjustment i
am sure
that there will be some sort of
fundraising for mrs
stoney scholar we need to keep her on
her feet
emotionally uh physically financially we
need to make sure that there's
a rent paid uh some food in the
refrigerator and that she's got
the best smile that she could possibly
get while her husband is gone and she's
adjusting to this there may be funeral
costs
so as soon as i do know those details
i'll either post them in the show notes
video description or i will share them
on social media
but i'm going to ask you guys to help my
friend stoney and trust me i will make a
generous contribution to help out stony
scholar as well
we got to take care of the family take
care of the army all right you guys this
dab nail is quite hot there's no need
for me to continue
uh i want to thank you guys for
listening to this once again shout out
stony scholar
uh i'm gonna miss you miss talking [ __ ]
to you miss getting [ __ ] talked back to
me
uh fist bump big hug i'll see you one
day bro
until next time take a fat dab and give
your mom a hug for me
you