yeah welcome to the show podcast world
i'm your host my friends call me rosta
jeff and this is episode
623 of the grow from your heart podcast
this is the birthday celebration episode
before we get to celebrating too hard
let's do a few shout outs to a few
members of the 710 club
let's start off with the big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to the captain
and commander of the irie army let's
send a big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out to my buddy lemur
priest
let's follow that up with a big thank
you shout out to my buddy dave's not
here
let's send a big thank you shout out to
my friend og purple thumb
let's send a big thank you to aldi and
brian c let's follow that up with a big
thank you shout out to smoke one and
john bendit
let's send a big thank you shout out to
brett g and miss mel
let's send a big thank you to zo so jay
and eric ross
i want to send a big thank you shout out
to tommy and the kanekrat
let's send a big thank you shout out to
kurt z and then let's wrap it up with
the big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out
to my friend ez057 big thanks and big
shout out to everybody who continues to
support the show on patreon
if you are not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need will be
right there on the screen and of course
i did include a link
in the show notes or the video
description to make it nice and easy
for all of my friends to support the
show ladies and gentlemen i mentioned it
at the top of the show this is the
birthday
celebration this is seven years of
podcasting before we get to that
i want to say thank you thank you guys
for all of the feedback on a couple of
previous episodes
the last episode was not my favorite
show it was an episode dedicated to a
friend
who we lost to a drunk driver thank you
for all of the condolences all of the
love all of the support all of the
feedback
i did try to include a link to the
gofundme to the paypal account
to support my friend's wife in the show
notes however uh youtube is removing
those links
i couldn't put the link in the show
notes or the video description or in the
comments it keeps taking it out it keeps
flagging that
if i keep trying to put it in there they
will take down my video so i couldn't
put the description up there
if you would like a link on how to help
contribute to my friend help his wife
help out with funeral costs
send me a message we will get you a link
also stabby has been posting the link a
lot of my other friends have posted the
link on other social media platforms
i will post it on cannabis because they
will not take it down shout out to cana
buzz
but i wanted to make sure to say thank
you for all of the love
all of the support all of the hugs and
virtual kisses
it meant a lot to me i did receive that
and it did make me feel a lot better so
thank you guys for that
also thank you for all of the feedback
on the visual aids episode i did an
episode where i dropped in a lot of
fancy pictures and photos
tried to teach a lot tried to up my game
thank you for all of the feedback and
compliments on that episode i spent a
lot of time doing that
it took me a lot of time learning how to
do that learning video editing software
there comes a lot of points in time when
you just want to
smash your head straight into the
computer screen a few times i've avoided
all of that we've gotten
a lot of work done thank you guys for
all of the feedback it makes it worth it
taking all that time to learn it figure
it out produce it all of the feedback
all of the compliments that makes all of
that worth it
you guys told me that the show has
improved a lot that makes all of my
efforts worth it when you guys notice it
so thank you you guys i'm having fun
learning video editing software
it has been a really fun time and i've
got some great friends out there that
give me some great advice
tech tips so thank you guys for that um
also i want to thank you for the great
feedback recently i co-hosted the dude
grows show with my buddy the dude and
guru i feel that filled in for my good
friend scotty real
i got a lot of great uh compliments a
lot of great feedback on that podcast
thank you i had a really good time uh
the dude scottie guru i look forward to
hanging out
with her without any of you on there if
anybody needs a fill in if you need a
replacement
let me know i could pull almost any of
those jobs i think i can do guru's job i
can almost keep up with you guru
uh you do the uh the tech and the
knowledge all at the same time
so big shout out for that but i'm
rambling uh i was on the dude grows
podcast if you did not catch that
make sure you watch that it is available
on there uh all of their feeds it's on
their youtube feed it's on their
podcasting feed if it's apple podcast
spotify stitcher wherever you find the
dude gross show
make sure you check out the episode
co-hosted by
yours truly ross to jeff i had a really
good time on that podcast i had a lot of
fun
i was trying not to interrupt too much
because we know that our friend scotty
real does kind of butt in a little bit
with a lot of stuff to say i didn't want
to overrun the show because i'm not the
a regular member of that show i wanted
to be a good gracious guest
also had to fill my shoes had to pull my
own weight and be involved so
it's hard to find that borderline there
but i think we did a good job on the
show
thanks to everybody for the compliments
the comments the feedback if you haven't
seen it go watch it leave some comments
on the video
most importantly let them know that
rasta jeff sent you so you know to go
watch
that show uh what am i going to talk
about before we get to the birthday
celebration
i wrote down the words super stoney
tolerance swings holy [ __ ] i may have
talked about this in the past on the
show it may have
been a long time how about you right now
i'm going through a phase
where i can basically open up my jar of
concentrates and just look at it
and be stoned out of my [ __ ] dome i
go through phases where
uh the guy at the dispensary is like bro
you were here yesterday and i'm like i
know
i know trust me i know and then i go
through phases like today where i could
just look at the jar and be
[ __ ] wrecked all day long right now
i'm going through one of those phases
where i can take one dab and i get
so high and then i go through it'll
probably last a week maybe three days
four or five days maybe a week tops and
then next week i'll go buy concentrates
and i will smoke all of the concentrates
and not even get a nice buzz
so do you go through weird shifts and
swings in your tolerance
i definitely notice it is based on a lot
of it's based on my hydration i haven't
been hydrating properly i've been
a little extra uh physically busy been
working a little bit more physically
been in a grow a little bit more and
that's dehydrating me a little bit i'm
wondering if that's contributing to
the extra buzz i've been getting uh my
diet has changed a little honestly been
eating more food
and still getting extra high when i
smoke so i'm curious
send me some feedback wherever you
interact with me uh do you go through
phases where
sometimes you can smoke all of the
product and not get stoned at all
and then sometimes you go through phases
where you smoke a little bit of the
product and you're [ __ ] wrecked for
the day
do you go through phases ebbs and flows
like that with your tolerance
give me some feedback uh you can hit me
up on twitter it's at gfyhpodcast you
can find me on instagram
it is uh at ire underscore genetics or
of course there is an
instagram for the show i don't use it
very often it is the grow from your
heart podcast on instagram
of course there is cannabis i love
cannabis uh leave a comment in the
youtube video
just give me some feedback let me know
am i the only one that goes through
these weird ebbs and flows of tolerance
i didn't take a tolerance break or
anything i've been smoking
i did a tolerance break a while back but
i mean i'm back on the train we've been
smoking we've been puffing but man the
past couple of days
i could take a dab and it's like high
school high blow out the dab and i'm
like oh i'm
silly got to take a couple of seconds
got to get a couple of snacks in me
gotta recharge anyway if you can't tell
today's one of them days when i got
[ __ ] high as [ __ ] from just a couple
of dabs so
so totally super rambly now here's where
we are going to get
serious i'm going to shift gears here
really quickly and this isn't going to
last for very long we're going to get
out of this but this is required
uh as a responsible uh person with a
microphone with a platform as a [ __ ]
human this is something that i
feel i'm responsible to do i need to
take a moment we need to take a moment
to uh send some love some vibes some
hugs
some healing energy to all of the
victims
and the recent tragedies which have
swept our nation there have been some
terrible
uh domestic terrorism some shootings
whatever you want to label it
it's [ __ ] ridiculous uh it's a mental
health problem i don't know
if it's a gun problem a mental health
problem this is not the podcast for that
it's a mental health issue in my opinion
um i don't know
what to do about it what to say about it
other than uh
holy [ __ ] this sucks it's [ __ ] up
people are broken things are rough
um i want to take a minute to send some
love some of my heart some of my energy
some
jaw love to all of the victims of all of
the terrible shootings that have
happened recently
uh the victims of violence uh terrorism
uh we'll start with the victims here in
colorado let's send a big uh
big moment of silence here just a brief
second of silence for everybody in
boulder
who not only the people who lost their
lives the people who witnessed it the
people who were affected by it
this sort of thing leaves big ripples so
brief moment for everybody up there in
boulder who was affected by this one
quick moment of silence here it is
all right that was for all of our people
in boulder uh another
another mention for all of the people in
georgia there was another tragedy in
georgia you know you can't just
be specific and do this for the ones
that we are aware of for the ones that
hit home that were local
i want to do a moment of silence a
little [ __ ] jalla for
everybody who's been dealing with some
[ __ ] who's been a victim of some
[ __ ]
uh if your car got broken into if there
was terrorism if you're just feeling
sorrow
here's a little bit of jaw love a little
moment for you here's a big fist bump
for you but let's just take a second
put some energy out there together right
now you guys let's just put some love
into the air
some healing energy some rastafari
whatever you believe in
feel it put some love out there let's do
it together for just one second on the
count of three
one two three rastafari all right
that is for everybody out there feeling
some effects of some sort of tragedy if
it was a shooting in boulder
if it was a shooting in georgia if it
was something across the planet that i'm
not aware of if it's something inside of
you some turmoil
hopefully we can all do some energy work
together get us all through that
together all right
that got weird on this podcast uh where
do we go from there
um we gotta do our best you guys this is
a weird time uh we're gonna do our best
bring everybody together the place we go
from there is talking about celebrating
a podcast birthday
what oh my goodness you guys i can't
think of many other things i've been
doing for
seven years this is the seventh year of
the grow from your heart podcast
this episode will come out on march 25th
speaking of march 25th
happy birthday to one of my best friends
on the planet happy birthday
to rob the dude if you know rob the dude
send him some birthday love even if you
don't know rob the dude send him some
birthday love
uh robbie and i went to high school
together i moved to
colorado in the middle of high school
made good friends with robbie shortly
after that
um we ended up going to a bunch of fish
concerts and
uh fish related concerts and mo shows
lots of mo
uh we even did a little bit of string
cheese and a lot of widespread panic
concerts we've been to a lot of shows
together you guys
robbie and i have done a lot of miles in
the car together we've been to a lot of
states together
we've been on planes trains and
automobiles together we've been
around this whole [ __ ] country
together having a good time he was my
road dog for
uh more than half of my fish experiences
90 of my widespread panic experiences
have got robbie the dude right next to
me for those
so uh without that dude i wouldn't be uh
who
how what and where i am today he's
played a huge role in who and what and
how and where i am so
i need to send a big shout out to my
buddy rob the dude happy birthday bro
love you miss you
he's in massachusetts right now being a
masshole hope you're well brother uh i
hope you hear this you're not
technologically
advanced you're kind of living in the
stone ages the stone ages if you will
but i hope you hear this brother big
shout out love you bro hope you have a
good birthday you'll definitely get some
text messages and some harassing phone
calls from me
uh so shout out to my buddy robbie
anyway this comes out on march 25th
the podcast birthday is officially march
28th this will be
seven years of podcasting i said i
haven't done anything for seven years
i've done some [ __ ] for seven years guys
i've been a parent for nearly 18 years
i've had these dreadlocks for a [ __ ]
16 holy [ __ ] ah so i've been doing some
things but
seven years of podcasting some of you
are brand new at listening some of you
may this may be your first episode
listening
some of you may have listened since
episode 1 when the show was called
the igrow culture podcast let's ramble
about that for a moment
um oh by the way there's not going to be
any grow talk or anything like that in
this episode this is all just gonna be a
birthday celebration i'm gonna ramble
and regroup from the past couple of
episodes which have been stressful
we're gonna have a good time and then
after this one we're gonna jump deep
into the grow lessons again
um but back in the day the show was
called the igrow culture podcast i
started off with igrow culture as
episode one
it was a play on like ipad ipod i
everything it was a lowercase i and then
the word grow with a capital g
i grow like ipad uh you know what i'm
saying right all the apple stuff
so as i grow culture uh because it was
the i
grow i was growing some culture i was
growing cannabis culture
i was growing we were cultivating and it
was also a play on the word
agriculture is where i was going with
that agroculture
i was also a little bit of when you put
i and stuff it makes a little rastafari
i feel that's a whole nother avenue if
you understand the rastafari lingo then
you get that but
um about 30 or 40 episodes into the
igrow culture
podcast i received a cease and desist
letter from a company called
igrow culture that's right they were a
a college accredited company who made
courses for colleges for agricultural
studies
so they were teaching like ag schools
they were the ones making the books for
the agriculture schools
and they kindly said hey we see you've
got a new podcast or a few episodes in
we would appreciate it if you stop using
the word agroculture
and if you do continue to use that then
we will have to have our lawyers
step in and sue the [ __ ] out of you it's
not exactly what they said
i'm paraphrasing but that was when i
decided you know i don't really like the
word i grow culture anyway
i thought about it uh my company is the
growth or
my company is irie genetics premium
seeds
the slogan for ire genetics was grow
from your heart and breed with love
and i thought that growth from your
heart is what we do it's what i do it's
what i'd like to teach you to do
it's what the show is about i'm giving
you free grow lessons you're getting
free content
you're learning how to grow your product
for free i'm giving it to you from my
heart i would appreciate you to grow
from your heart so it felt natural
grow from your heart podcast so that
happened at episode 50 at episode 50
i rebranded everything i had a new logo
made i
redid i actually re-uh branded with a
new youtube channel because i couldn't
redo all the words and all the names
so i created a brand new youtube channel
i changed all the logos everywhere else
changed all the names
and we became the grow from your heart
podcast at episode 50.
ah my point was a lot of you may be
brand new a lot of you probably jumped
in right in the middle
many of you jumped in when i started
doing the video podcast around episode
500 is when i think that happened 5 20
ish maybe 3 something i don't even know
it's been so long
but many of you jumped in when the video
started on youtube so thank you for that
but many of you
have been here since the beginning and
it is crazy to think that you guys have
been listening to me for seven years
what blows my mind is when somebody says
hey dude i discovered your podcast
yesterday
and i've already listened to like 400
episodes or something of your show and
i'm like oh my goodness
these people have heard me from back in
the day i used to write out entire
podcasts like type them out on paper and
read it like a script
so today we will be doing episode 325 of
the grow from your heart podcast
brought to you by our friends at
seedsharenow.com make sure
and i would just read it like that and i
didn't i didn't flow i didn't feel good
and now i just turn on the mic and i've
got like five bullet points on the
screen and we just [ __ ] talk for 30
or 40 minutes and hopefully
don't have to edit too much [ __ ] out the
show has progressed i feel like i have
grown
so far as a podcaster i feel like i've
grown a lot as a cultivator
uh a commercial cultivator a home
cultivator
also i feel like i've grown so much as a
teacher i understand
so much better how to guide you to
success now
uh man i feel like we've come a long way
together so my main point of that ramble
was
uh some of you are new some of you been
here forever some of you been here right
in the middle
uh thank each and every one of you for
listening to me for supporting me for
encouraging me
uh for emailing me for commenting on my
videos
uh my audio posts uh thank you for
uh the compliments and noticing my
progression
i went from having a terrible audio
quality sound that was over compressed
and sound tinny
i focused way too much on just the wrong
stuff i didn't know i was new at
podcasting
then we improved the sound then we
improved the video now we're in 4k
uh most of the time it's in 4k i record
in 4k sometimes youtube doesn't
[ __ ] let me post it in 4k but that's
hey that's that's another story we're in
4k
now we got the joe rogan microphone
coming to you booming the set looks good
i feel like we've come a long way and
you guys have noticed it so the uh the
compliments
and the the compliments is what it is
encouragement that keeps me going so
thank you
um i'm really rambling i just wanted to
make sure to give thanks and praise for
you
guys uh to you guys for all of the
support because
i do put a lot of work into it i write
the shows i produce the shows i come and
ramble for
30 or 40 minutes i edit it down make it
look shiny put all kinds of video
touches to it then i put it out there
and just hope you guys accept it
uh but without an audience it would just
be
some weirdo talking into a microphone
with a bunch of toys this would just be
all me and this would just be [ __ ]
weird so thank you guys
i appreciate you i love you and i
respect you now let's get a little
deeper into all of these thanks
uh notes i want to send a big thanks to
mike
mike is an integral part of this podcast
he's not on enough episodes mike's a
busy man he's got a family
he's got children he's got his own life
i understand that but
mike thank you bro uh nothing but love
respect and appreciation for you it's
time to get you back on the podcast
again the audience loves you
i love you the show loves you big thanks
to mike uh he contributes a lot to the
show
maybe sometimes he won't be on the show
but he'll send me a message and say make
sure you talk about this or he'll say
when you talk about this make sure to
cover this point so mike is a big part
of the show behind the scenes
behind the camera in front of the camera
thank you bro i appreciate that
i want to thank mike i want to thank all
of the guests who have been on the show
everybody from day one uh kevin
mike spence maddie garden of whedon uh
joe buzzy jessie gross especially
uh sloppy's been on the show i'm gonna
miss somebody barefoot
uh organic as [ __ ] everybody that's been
on the show
thank you i appreciate it it's been
awesome uh
you guys make the show without you guys
coming on the show without you being a
part of the show the show wouldn't grow
shout out to uh double door dank uh
send some love to double door dank
actually you guys dumbledore's been uh
dealing with some health issues so let's
send him some jaw love as well
but thanks to all the people that have
been on the show i'm sure i missed
several guests there that i did not
mention because we've had quite a few
people on the show
but thank you guys uh all the people
that have gathered at the table in the
past in the present and in the future
uh even friends that have fallen off
we've had some falling outs we've had
some
some rifts and the force here if you
will still big shout out to all those
people that were on the show without you
guys the show wouldn't have existed
and people say hey why do you leave up
some of those episodes that person has
proved themselves to be a phony
or has proved themselves to be a fool
since they were on your show why do you
leave it up
i can't change history taking down a
podcast episode is not going to change
the fact that we were cool at that point
that we were friends at that point
that episode that knowledge that info is
still probably valid
and then we can see what that person has
evolved into some people have changed
some people wearing masks
some people have really evolved into
bigger and better people some people
have been abandoned and deleted and
blocked completely
so the reason i don't take down those
messages or those old episodes is
because it's a time capsule
uh the podcast happened those things
were said i'm kind of a historian here
doing this so that's why some of the
episodes if you ask why do you leave
that up
it's a time capsule can't change history
just by deleting an episode
can't change the future by deleting an
episode all right
so thanks to all of the guests past
present and future even if we don't kick
it anymore
even if i don't rep your brand or you
don't wrap my [ __ ] thank you
it was still worth having you on the
show uh also
thank you to all of the shows which have
had me as a guest
i've been on a lot of podcasts i think
the first show i appeared on may have
been
john doe radio with tim martin
what that's some old school [ __ ] tim i'd
love to see you get moving again you
talk about getting it fired up
maybe you've gotten it going i haven't
seen it on itunes i look for you
occasionally
if the john doe radio fired up again i
would give it a follow
uh but tim martin was one of the reasons
why i started the show
uh his show inspired me there were a lot
of shows that inspired me we don't need
to go too far into that
but i was talking a lot about cannabis
teaching my friends and then somebody
asked me the same question like three
times in a row and i thought i should
record this and do it that's why a
podcast started but
thanks to all the people that had me as
a guest i was on john doe radio that got
me started
i've been on the dude grows show i've
been on medical marijuana radio with our
friend
ls love down there in new mexico i've
been on
okay so here's one we should really make
sure to touch on
big shout out to the gang at embracing
organics
embracing organics invited me to be on
their video zoom podcast which goes live
on youtube
i was hesitant for a couple of reasons
at the time i wasn't doing video shows
i wasn't prepared or comfortable to go
on video also i wasn't doing live shows
at the time
so i was about to be on camera live that
was really nerve-wracking it was a
little uh
made me nervous to be honest with you
but we did it and after that there was
no turning back now i get on the
microphone and i talk and i ramble
and this is like where i live this is my
space right here i feel so good in the
podcasting zone
i don't know that i would have gotten
comfortable on the video i don't know
that i would have learned the live
zoom stuff without my buddy dirt man dan
and the embracing organics crew
so we all owe a special thank you to
dirt man dan
and embracing organics because i
wouldn't be doing this show the way i'm
doing it
uh without that encouragement without
that shift without that boost
it was good practice and it got me going
so thank you bro you guys really did
contribute to my show
to my success by showing me the way on
how to do it you guys made me really
confident
uh being on those shows uh showing me
how to do the zoom stuff
that made me really confident and
knowing that i've got such a cool
uh team of [ __ ] nerds and grow geeks
behind me
if i've got a computer question a zoom
question a [ __ ] youtube
question an equipment question i have
got three guys i can call
i'm like thousands of people's weed guys
so it's really relieving knowing that
i've got
tech guys camera guys uh camera gals
that i can message and call and be like
hey i'm trying to do this i can't figure
it out and i'll go dude
just mix a and b and press c and you're
like oh that was [ __ ] so easy thank
you
so you guys have made me confident uh
and you've helped me get to where i am
today so thank you guys
for that uh thanks to all my friends who
deal with all of my endless and
ridiculous
technical questions we do have good
relationships because i answer all of
your weed questions freely
but sometimes i feel like i'm annoying i
feel like i'm a pain in the ass when
i've got a thousand technical questions
when i'm shopping to buy equipment i ask
everybody too many questions google is
my friend but my friends with experience
are also very knowledgeable uh shout out
to my web guys
uh shout out to ben who keeps the
website updated shout out to tony
who built the original framework for the
original website shout out to my buddy
buzz bros
uh for all of the camera and photography
advice also shout out to reefer madness
for similar camera and photography and
computer help
um shout out to everybody who's been
giving me camera help lately
i asked dirtman dan for some advice
fumador gave me some advice
the whole gang in the neighborhood gave
me some good camera advice
uh there will be another camera here in
the future uh so thank you guys for all
of the guidance and help thank you guys
you do make my life easier you make the
show better with all of those little
details i couldn't do this by myself
i say it's a one-man show i say i do
this by myself but honestly the army
keeps me going you guys help out a lot
so big thanks to the entire
ire army the whole grow from your heart
podcast crew without you guys
i keep saying this without you i look
like a [ __ ] psychopath if there
wasn't
somebody watching this video listening
to this audio feed and clicking like and
interacting with me
if i just did this twice a week just for
fun i may need a doctor
may need different medication so thank
you guys you validate my
my vision uh you show me that my
guidance and that my advice and then my
efforts actually have results
you send me pictures of your garden you
send me thanks and you say dude i did
what you said
you rescued my grow so thank you thank
you for the trust
thank you for the respect thank you for
the support uh thank you for the honesty
you guys are completely honest with me
when a show sucks you guys tell me when
a show is great
you guys tell me thank you for that so
um i just want to say thank you you guys
it's been [ __ ]
seven years of podcasting so thank you
uh thanks for all the support thank you
for sticking with me
keep sticking with me um i need to send
a special thank you to all of the
patreon supporters
it was a struggle to get 200 patreon
supporters now we've been hovering
just above 200. we stay about 205 210
patreon supporters
thank you that is hard to do as a
solitary podcaster that is a challenge
thank you guys i truly truly appreciate
that stick around
i'm getting better at podcasting i'm
getting better at growing
i'm learning more about growing all the
time i'm reading more about plants about
the plant cycles i learn more about
commercial growing there's always more
stuff to learn i'm not
going to stop learning i love advancing
my knowledge so that i can keep sharing
it with you guys so stick with me
for another seven maybe 10 more years
let's just keep doing this [ __ ] there's
no
end in sight i don't see a reason to
stop so i'm learning more about growing
i'm learning more about the gear
i'm getting more comfortable with the
equipment i'm getting much better at
editing
there will be more cameras more
microphones in the future
uh covet is going away i don't know if
it's going away or whatever restrictions
are easing
there's a vaccine we're able to play
with our friends again pretty soon
there will be people here at the podcast
table there will be more options for the
show coming up there will be more visual
aids
stick around you guys i'm excited um i
feel like i
skipped a note oh no it's still down
there on the bottom cool
um i'm gonna have more guests more zoom
stuff coming up
i did notice that when i record on zoom
my video comes out super grainy i think
i've resolved that issue i talked about
that in a previous episode
i'm still learning you guys uh just like
you're learning the grow i'm learning
this stuff so be patient
stick with it um i don't want to make
any promises but i'm going to need to do
that third
episode maybe every other week or
something maybe do a bonus one or two
extra episodes every month because i
can't fit in all of the questions from
patreon and all the patreon shout outs
so if things keep going well if we stay
above 200 patrons
things go like they are i'm going to
have to do that third episode i owe it
to you
so thank you for that um i had a couple
of things in the way of my time i'm
getting better at time management
i had a health concern that turned out
to be a false alarm
so that is out of the way that's a
little bit of stress i don't have to
worry about
that helps me uh focus a little bit more
on the podcasting also i don't have to
go to the doctor
and figure out what the [ __ ] is going on
i'm gonna live you guys and there's
honestly nothing [ __ ] wrong with me
i'm an old man that was paranoid so that
was nice to [ __ ] find out
anyway i'll be able to get more
podcasting going i'll be bringing you
better content more focused grow lessons
deeper
more in-depth grow knowledge uh more
visual aids more visual learning
things are going to get better i promise
you i owe it to you
you deserve it for all of the support
which you have given me so thank you
guys
i do appreciate it happy birthday to the
podcast
happy birthday to you i don't know when
your birthday is but i'm sure that
sometime between now and the next
birthday episode i put out you've got a
birthday coming
so happy birthday get yourself something
nice buy yourself a really
really something [ __ ] i was gonna say
a really nice bag of weed a really nice
expensive grandma concentrates i don't
know what you want for your birthday
get what you need eat a good meal spin
it with somebody that you love
think about all the people that you love
here's a birthday high five a birthday
fist bump happy birthday to you thanks
for all the birthday love i can already
see the birthday comments rolling in on
youtube thank you guys i appreciate that
all right i think that is all i've got
for the birthday
episode we are coming out of covet i
mentioned that a moment ago
you guys i cannot wait to see you at
an event soon it's going to take me a
minute to get comfortable going to the
events
i want people to get out and go to
events in public and learn how to
[ __ ] act in public again
some of you guys haven't been out for a
while you may have forgotten some of the
common courtesies
uh let's get that [ __ ] back under
control then
i'll go back out into society and join
you guys be good to one another
uh be good to everybody out there be
good to yourself be good to the
community
uh just be good be good be good do good
feel good
it'll all come back to you um where do
we go from there that's it you guys
let's start wrapping it up if you feel
like this episode was educational
informative or entertaining
maybe you learned something maybe you
had a couple of chuckles maybe you just
want to throw me a dollar for my time
the way the the way that you can do that
is by joining me on patreon
you can do that at patreon patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart that
was harder to say than it looked
if you've got any questions corrections
comments or concerns i'd love to hear
from you my email address is grow
fromyourheart
at hotmail.com don't be shy send me some
messages send me some feedback
i would love to hear from you uh also
the
website i am [ __ ] lost and rambly
here at the end quit looking at the
notes and lost my flow we've got a
website
everything grow from your heart podcast
irie genetics all things ross to jeff
are at my website iriegenetics.com on
that website there is a spot where you
can sign up for a newsletter
about once a month every two weeks i
send out a newsletter keep you updated
what's going on with the company
let you know where their new seed drops
i'll let you know uh where there are
special merchandise deals let you know
things that may be coming up things you
might not want to miss
so sign up for the newsletter and irie
iriegenetics.com
all right that is all i've got for you
i'll be back in just a couple of days
we'll get the show back on the regular
schedule
i want to send a big birthday shout out
to my buddy white mike
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom
a hug for me
[Music]