[Music]
all right here we go welcome back
podcast world
i'm your host my friends call me rosta
jeff and this is episode 625
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to read a few
patreon questions
before we get there let's do a few shout
outs to a few members of the 710 club
of course the 710 club are those folks
who support us on patreon
at the 7 and 10 cent a month level or
higher
so let's kick it off with the big grow
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out to my buddy kes burton
let's send a thank you shout out to adhd
grower and don't tread on me420
let's send a big thank you shout out to
big sexy dank and the terp burglar
let's send a thank you shout out to
caribou heart genetics and josiah w
i want to send a big thank you shout out
to the baptista and girls grow too
let's send a big thank you shout out to
red eyed optimist and my buddy aldi
and then let's wrap it up with the big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out
to my buddy og purple thumb big thanks
and big shout out to everybody who
supports the show on patreon
if you are not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need will be
right there on the screen and i did
include that link in the show notes
and in the video description to make it
easy for all of my friends
maybe you're working maybe you're
driving maybe you got the kids maybe you
can't pull out the ipad or the iphone
and click on the link right now
it will be there when you're ready
patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
right in a recent episode i did talk
about
having what i was calling tolerance
swings
i was mentioning that sometimes i can
buy a gram of concentrates and let's be
real i never buy a gram of concentrates
i always buy several grams of
concentrates let's just be honest with
each other here
but when i buy concentrates sometimes i
get home and i smoke
a gram of concentrates and i'm like i
really wish i would have gotten a better
buzz
and it has nothing to do with the
concentrates because i'm buying the same
brand all the time
i prefer a certain brand i like a
certain little range of flavors which
they offer
so the concentrates are consistent then
there will be some days
when i can open up that same jar of
concentrate and take just
you know like a maybe a 0.25 maybe a 0.2
of a gram of a dab out of that thing
and just be completely obliterated my
eyes get heavy they get red time starts
traveling funny i can't remember what
the [ __ ] i was thinking about
so i have what i call drastic tolerance
swings
one day i can look at the jar of dabs
and get [ __ ] wrecked one day i can
smoke the whole jar of dabs all of the
dabs and not get a proper buzz
there are several things that i think
contribute to that a lot of them are
health-wise
i realized maybe i was catching a cold
when i was getting that super
low tolerance time period for a week
there
had a little bit of a sniffle that was
rude to do into the microphone but it
was a good example
i was getting a little bit of a sniffle
there i noticed i was taking a nap more
than usual
so i may have been fighting off a little
bit of a cold that may have been
affecting
my cannabis tolerance just getting extra
high because there were other things
happening in my body
uh also i've noticed my levels of
hydration have a lot to do
with how buzzed i get from cannabis if
i've been drinking
sugary and sweet drinks maybe i've had
some juice or something
uh maybe i've had i don't drink a lot of
sugary junky crap but
if i've had too much uh sugary foods or
snacks or something
juice with a lot of sugar in it a real
fruity kombucha
i got that high blood sugar i can't get
the proper buzz because i'm just
competing with the sugar
uh if i've eaten a big fat fatty meal
with a bunch of rice and a bunch of
noodles and stuff
sometimes the dabs make me more lazy
then they will give me a nice head buzz
so a lot of it has to do with diet with
my intake with my other things i'm
putting into my body what i'm reacting
with responding to
hydration is one of the major issues in
my dab ability
if i'm not properly hydrated i can't
take a big dab
because my lungs say bro what are you
doing
if i'm well hydrated if i've had several
glasses or bottles of water today
and i take a big fat dab my lungs go
yeah dude you're nice and hydrated you
can
use that dryness into your lungs and
it's not going to be a big deal so a lot
of it is
physical a lot of it is what i'm putting
into my body to go along with the dabs
to prepare for the dabs and recover from
the subsequent dabs
another thing that people chimed in with
the most common
response and reaction and comment was
company
have a lot to do with your dabs in your
response to consuming cannabis
when you're by yourself and you smoke or
you eat edibles you don't have anybody
to look over and go dude are you as
[ __ ] high as me
or dude did you even get anything off of
those edibles you don't have that
you don't have anybody to ask anybody to
laugh at or compare it to or to give you
hints it's just you trying to figure
life out
you may not even notice uh and this is
gonna segue into the next part here
you might not even notice how high you
are until you change your environment a
lot of people said
uh environment and setting have a lot to
do with your buzz
uh your and your environment will give
you a phenotypical expression on your
buzz that's just a grow room joke
but environment and setting have a lot
to do with it i've noticed if i dab
right here
or if i dab in the other office space
which you guys are familiar with if
you've seen my live videos or seen me on
other shows i've got another office
space in which i
uh frequently take dabs and hang out do
recordings in there
if i hang out in those spaces my
tolerance is unlimited because i don't
have to do anything except to deal with
my personal space i know where this
microphone is
i know where this table is this chair is
secure i'm safe
in my office space i've got a nice chill
super comfy office chair i've got all
the music i can imagine i got a nice
sound set up in there
i got the air pods in my ears there's a
couch in there nothing could go wrong
there's a change of clothes in there
are a bunch of sneakers it's a chill
place nothing could go wrong in my
little chill areas
so sometimes i'll take a bunch of dabs
and for the sake of telling a story that
a lot of people are going to listen to
i'll call my uber driver and they'll
come pick me up
as soon as i get in that uber i think to
myself holy [ __ ] i'm high as
[ __ ] but when i was chilling in the
office or chilling at the recording
studio space
i didn't even notice how buzzed i was i
was cool everything was going just fine
and then i walked outside and felt that
outside air hit my skin and i went
oh [ __ ] and the neighbor across the way
said what's up ross to jeff and i went
hey bro and realized
i'm talking in slow motion and hearing
in 3d and then you get in the uber and
the uber driver is like where you going
you're like i don't [ __ ] know dude i
typed that in a minute ago and already
forgot where are you taking me
like you don't realize until you change
your setting and your environment and
then you get somewhere
how many times have you thought you were
cool maybe you go somewhere and
allegedly hypothetically
you drive too and i'm just going to say
in high school back in the day where i'm
from we all went to the mall i like to
go hit the mall on saturdays and buy
some sneakers go see if there's any new
sneaker drops
uh so sometimes allegedly you drive to
the mall you get to the mall parking lot
you
roll a fat one up or maybe you burn it
on the way to the mall whatever you do
right you smoke on the way to the mall
and you think i'm legit
you get out of the car the cloud comes
out of the car you all giggle you
[ __ ] put in eye drops like nobody's
gonna notice that all six of you are
walking around smelling like a [ __ ]
dispensary in the mall giggling at
stupid [ __ ] looking stoned in there
you think you're getting away with it
but it's cool anyway you walk into the
mall and then you realize
oh my goodness there are people in here
and there are stores
and there are lights and i'm so high
that it's almost uncomfortable but it's
really fun because i like that sort of a
thing
i've noticed that when i change my
setting my environment my surroundings i
really get a different buzz
i've noticed that when we used to go to
city council meetings
i would get the most paranoid weird
anxiety ridden buzz
and it was cool because i could have
cannabis you weren't supposed to take it
in there
but i mean i could be around cannabis i
could be stoned i was a medical cannabis
patient there
talking about medical cannabis i was
definitely consuming
uh between work and the meetings so i
was going in and
uh they knew that i smelled like
cannabis and looked like cannabis and
for some reason that buzz was
just so [ __ ] nerve-wracking being in
there super high
i probably would not have enjoyed it as
much it probably would have been even
more nerve-wracking if i wasn't nice and
blazed
so then there are places that i go that
i feel just totally [ __ ] i don't even
notice that i'm blazed once i get to the
dispensary
i'm like what's up guys and gals because
my friends work at all the dispensaries
where i shop and i'm just hanging out
with my bros
hanging out with my friends i gotta show
my idea and give them money but we all
know each other we say what's up it's a
fist bump situation
so when i'm at the dispensary i don't
notice how buzzed i am get back in the
car to drive in the get in the uber
again to get back home and then i'm like
dude you're going too fast and he's like
i'm parked bro
like it's just all about setting
scenario
location that is a huge uh contributing
factor to
the buzz which i feel like a lot of us
receive uh who you're with imagine if
you're smoking with me
uh some people and not to sound that way
some people do meet me and smoke with me
and they act all starstruck and weird
that's really funny to me
but then smoking with me you've got
nothing to worry about like i'm not the
cops i'm not
babylon i'm not your mom i'm not your
lawyer i'm not your doctor
we're going to smoke dabs and we're
going to have a good ass time i don't
care what you do once we get stoned do
your thing we're gonna have fun
uh be weird eat snacks uh say strange
things stare off into space
i expect it from you i got you too damn
high then imagine smoking dabs with your
doctor
you're gonna get a really weird buzz
it's going to be kind of [ __ ] strange
if you got a cool lawyer you might get
to smoke some dabs with your lawyer but
it's all about who
and where what you're smoking uh
sometimes in the car you got that little
protective bubble as soon as you get out
of the car you're not in that bubble
life is weird out there it's lots of
environment
you think you're fine until you pull up
to the drive-through window and try to
order you guys be careful if you're
smoking in the car these are all just
hypothetical funny ideas that i may or
may not have experienced in my high
school days
um another thing that heavily in my
opinion contributes to
uh the buzz which i receive can from
consuming my cannabis
is not only the product the product is
definitely a huge factor i've said that
i've got my favorite brands
i've got a few brands i really select
and support uh none of them sponsor the
show they don't pay me to talk about
them i just like to buy the products
because they taste good they smoke well
they give me a good buzz
uh most of the time i buy green dot labs
uh the live batter
uh part of the time i buy the binsk
batter because it tastes good and it
gives me a nice buzz
there are a couple more that i'll buy
just in the periphery if those are ran
out or sold out or whatever
but that's what i prefer um those
products give me a nice buzz if i get
something and i like the batters
when i smoke the diamonds the buzz comes
on real fast real strong it's more of a
head sweat
[ __ ] bug-eyed sort of a thing
sometimes that's what i'm after
so that's a different sort of a buzz the
product is what i'm talking about
shatter gives me a completely different
buzz than the
diamonds the sauce or the batter smoking
flour
is a completely different buzz i like to
carry a pipe around
uh when i'm doing chores around the
house if i'm just cleaning up if i'm
cooking food
if i'm cleaning up from cooking food if
i'm chopping vegetables just got a pipe
sitting there and i just [ __ ] take a
rip off the pipe there's usually a pipe
within reach just
like a little security blanket just to
keep the little buzz going it doesn't
give me what i need from a dab but it'll
make the dab last a little longer so the
product
and then what i was going to get to next
is the device
my favorite rig i'm going to say that
sentence again because i feel like i
slurred that one all out
my favorite rig gives me a completely
different buzz
than my non-favorite rig my first place
rig hits way better than my second place
rig i love my second and third place
rigs i've got a lot of rigs
but my first place rig is first place
for a reason
uh something about the ritual of the way
it fits in my hand
the way the mouthpiece fits against my
mouth the way that the
carb cap reaches the way that the dabber
reaches
not it's far enough away from my eyes to
where i don't look cross-eyed trying to
get the dabber
into the banger uh and then when i go to
carb cabba cap it it's not too far away
from my face but it's not so big that
it's cumbersome
my rig is my favorite rig and it gives
me the most beautiful hits i know that
rig i know
how hard to pull i know how hard to draw
i know how long to draw i know how to
wiggle the carb cap
i know exactly how much water to put
into it i know
when i've bitten off more than i can
chew and i should stop pulling so hard
or pull a little bit harder with that
rig
that rig is my favorite and i talk about
it a lot i show it off a lot
i'll pop a picture in right now so that
you guys can see the rig i'm talking
about but that's the rig i love to hit
ah it feels really nice on my lungs
gives me a good dab
when i hit other rigs sometimes i don't
even feel like i got a nice hit got a
nice buzz because i'm like ah this rig
sucks or whatever the nail is too small
the mouthpiece is shaped
funny i don't like the little peepee
shaped mouthpiece if it's like a
a peepee shape if it's phallic shaped
and it's got the little hole in it
and i have to make a kissy shaped face
to hit it i feel like the size dabs i
take i get a lot of concentrate built up
on
the kissy face part of my lips and my
lips get all sticky and they get all red
and i look all weird
and then i walk around doing this for
the next 20 minutes with my lips i'm
just going
because i got that sticky [ __ ] on my
lips and act like a little kid don't
know what the [ __ ] to do with it
so i don't like the peepee shaped
tapered skinny uh skinny mouth rigs i
prefer a flared out trumpet mouthpiece
style rig
that i can just put over my mouth and
then i know that the smoke is getting in
there and i don't have to make that
uh duck face peepee suck face whatever
face you're talking about
so sometimes somebody's rigged i'll take
a dab of really quality concentrates and
i know it's a fat
dab and i'm like where'd all that smoke
go where's my dab dude what happened
and i don't know their nail i don't know
their carb cap i don't know their rig
and so the nail is too hot or too cold i
don't cap it properly i don't hit it at
the right time
and then also the rig just sucks it
doesn't bubble right there's too much
too little water in there
i don't feel like i got a good dab then
occasionally
i'm gonna i'm gonna give praise right
after i complain just because this does
happen too in reality in life
occasionally somebody will hand me a dab
and a rig and they'll be like you want
to hit my new rig and i'll be like that
looks all fancy
and i'll go in to take a hit and that
rig will uppercut me in the dick and it
will be one of the best dabs i've ever
had
so it's kind of unpredictable sometimes
with the rig it depends on the shape of
the rig the quality of the rig who made
the rig has a lot to do with it there
are some makers out there that really
focus on good
getting a good fat rip some people want
to
and this is all opinion based some
people
in my opinion like or want too many
bubbles and spinnies and functions and
twists and turns and
[ __ ] fancy ways for the water to go
and drains and spouts and twisties and i
said twisty too many times
but they want all these directions and
cool flows and recycles and end cycles
and out cycles and donuts and [ __ ]
that's cool but in my opinion every one
of those twists turns
ands out steals a little bit of my dab
it seals the airflow it steals the
the terps it steals the resin and it's
more to clean just not for me i like a
dab
that goes from the banger to the water
to where it cools off a little bit
doesn't splash me in my mouth and then
into my brain
so that it's just like dab and uppercut
oh i'm stoned that's what i want from it
so
um i got off on a huge ramble on there
but the rig the [ __ ]
setting the environment that rig has a
lot to do with it in my opinion is where
i was headed a lot of people like a
really ornate rig
i prefer a simple rig punch me in the
face get me going so
who you're hanging out with will have a
lot to do with it if you smoke with me
or if you smoke with your [ __ ] lawyer
or if you smoke with a judge
probably gonna cop a different buzz
environment
if you're smoking before you go into a
rock concert or
a dispensary totally chill you shouldn't
be paranoid at all if you smoke before
you go into court or walk into the bank
you're probably going to get the sweats
you're probably going to get the armpit
sweats and a little bit of anxiety it's
all about setting it's all about where
you're going
then also the rig and the product are
gonna have a lot to do with the buzz
then what you've eaten what you've
consumed your physical health your
mental health are going to have a lot to
do
with how that buzz comes on to you i
really really talked a lot longer than i
meant to about that part so
this is the part where i'm going to jump
into some patreon questions
i've gotten a lot of like short random
patreon questions that have just been
sitting around so i
kind of just compiled a few of them a
couple come from people that are uh they
send me a lot of questions
a couple of these are from brand new
people i'm just gonna go through a few
of these
and see if i can't knock out a couple
pages of these just like short random
questions
i think the first two came from the same
person so with
less rambling a little less talk a
little more action let's jump into the
first one
it says here is a question for you ross
to jeff sometimes i hear you talk about
rubbing
the stems of the male plant as you
describe the odors
in very vivid and graphic terms yes some
of my terms are very
graphic then it says are we to take from
this
that terpene profiles are male dominant
traits so let's talk about this question
when i do talk about selecting male
plants and also female plants
i like to rub the stem of the plant the
stock of the plant so you got
the [ __ ] base of the plant and i've
lolly popped that probably a few inches
and then the branches come up and
whatever
a lot of times i'll just grab that naked
stock of the plant just pinch it with my
fingers and rub it give it a little
a little rub and tug and then smell my
fingers
and i notice a lot in those aromas that
come off of there that's not what the
plant is going to smell like when it's
finished
that's not what the final product will
smell like but it tells me a little bit
of what the ingredients i'm working with
now smell like
and from experience from being a breeder
that's done this a lot
i know what the now flavor the now smell
will turn into later and what it
translates to
into the breeding project so i know
that in my opinion a male plant that
smells acrid
like vomit like bar trash can like that
fermented bar trash can if you've ever
had to take out the trash at the bar
if you've ever taken up the trash at the
bowling alley or somewhere that serves
booze and food
there's this acrid smell on the bottom
of the trash can that's just
it's fermented it's funky it's putrid
that smell in a male plant translates to
gassy uh funky burnt rubber
tennis ball cushy stinky aromas
when you breed with that plant so that's
why i talk about rubbing the male of the
plant
i give it a little rub and tug straight
up smell my fingers
and observe what i've smelled then try
to hit the fingers with rubbing alcohol
get all that smell off of there rub them
on your jeans or on your khakis real
hard
use your other hand smell another plant
then clean that hand again and then
hopefully by now the terps are gone from
both hands you go back and repeat the
process you could smell a few plants and
see what you're working with
one will [ __ ] stand out even if you
don't clean your fingers enough
one of them will make you go ooh
go with your heart go with your body go
with your uh your senses that's like
your your body knows when you need
something desire something wants
something when something's gonna work
for you
uh when you smell oranges you go that
smells good because there's vitamins in
there when you smell poop
your body goes i probably shouldn't eat
that because that's waste we've got pro
we're programmed to know what our body
wants so go with the one
uh that your nose tells you tells you to
go with i did a podcast
maybe six years ago that's called follow
your nose
because your nose always knows that's
what you can sam taught us and it's
still accurate
uh follow your nose because your nose is
one of your biggest receptors that can
tell your body what's good for you and
what's bad for you like i just said
oranges smell good for a reason poopoo
smells bad for a reason
now the question is are we to take from
this that terpenes are male
dominant traits no that is not what i
mean by that
um i just know what that male trait
delivers to the mix and i know that i've
had success
using uh that ingredient so
a lot of our when you're chefing you
need to use butter and cream or
two other things i can't think of right
now that would mix well but butter and
cream mix well every [ __ ] time right
uh or salt and cream i'm [ __ ] that
all up anyway you gotta salt the cream
right
so if you've got a plant that [ __ ] uh
you can always count on that male plant
that smells like puke to be your cream
it's always gonna work with most things
or it's always gonna be your
your butter you can butter up almost
everything it's always gonna work so
that's
it's just chefing in my opinion i've had
good that may have been a terrible
[ __ ] analogy i may have lost
everybody with that but you know me
um so i just think that it's like
cheffing and i know
that that's a good starter that's a good
base that's a good color palette to bust
out to start with it will mix well with
a lot of things
it will complement a lot of things uh
that muted puke
flavor uh is like kind of on the darker
grayer side if you think in colors
and if you mix it with the pinks and
blues which you get from like strawberry
blueberry
oranges which you'd get from orange
flavored terps it allows them to mingle
very well together then you get that
dark color with the lighter color and it
brings out the best of both worlds
that's a little view into my weird
thought process on
colors and flavors and chefing and
creating strains
i just know that that puke flavored
trait uh
evolves or translates into good things
in the future i know that
if you've got a male plant that smells
acrid and sour
that you get that weird uh swampy cushy
flavor in the end if it's got berries at
the start
it's going to have way too much berries
in the flavor in the end that's just
something i know from working with a lot
of male plants
so rub those males rub the females see
what they work see what they smell like
see what they turn
into once you work with them a few times
you'll get familiar with it you'll say
when it smells like berries at the start
when it's got this uh watermelon smell
or strawberry smell at the beginning it
turns into
grapefruits at the end or something
you'll notice that you'll start to learn
that
that's just all from growing the same
plants over and over
and over again all right thank you for
that great question my friend i'm going
to move on to the next question on my
cards here
it says ross to jeff thank you for
sharing sharing
your unique talent have you ever
included cow manure compost or mushroom
compost in your soil mixes
do you have an opinion one way or the
other and i just simply replied with no
because that is not my style
i buy cocoa i buy perlite and i mix
cocoa and perlite together and that's
generally my mix
for a commercial grow in my personal
grows i honestly rotate from
something like a roots organics or the
707 mix
sometimes i buy what's it called
fertilum in the red
bag then i put a lot of perlite in that
sometimes i buy what is the other one
fox farms ocean forest
i buy right now it's kind of hard to get
a lot of soil because things are limited
because of the situations we're in
so i get what is available and i believe
that since i'm feeding my plants with
such good nutrients
i mainly use new millennium bottled
nutrients with a couple of additives
uh there's some bud swell in there
there's uh
some green sensation in there there's a
little bit of veg bloom products in
there i use the shine
but i'm mainly using high quality inputs
so as long as i've got a good substrate
for my plants to hang out and the roots
to be in
as long as i'm feeding them while i'm
not super picky about my soil or my
medium
as long as it's kind of fluffy and it's
well aerated and it's a good quality and
it's clean
then that's what i'm using but i usually
don't use any sort of compost no manure
or anything like that i live in the city
my neighbors are close i don't have a
lot of space a lot of yard space a lot
of
room for like composting and [ __ ] like
that i just got a lot of storage and
[ __ ] like that taking up all my space so
that's not my style
so no never done that uh probably won't
do that
uh just not the way that i grow more of
a commercial grower with a different
mindset doing things a little bit of a
different way
the next weird question that i got was
is your real name jeff
uh yeah the name is jeff i am the lemon
jeffrey
i'm the jeff behind lemon jeffrey that's
why i was named lemon jeffrey that's me
bro
russ oh god i'm not even editing that
out rasta jeff
lemon jeff that's where all the jeff
stuff comes from
yes the name is jeff real name's jeffrey
if you want to get technical
um all right what about old bottles of
nutrients i have unopened
quartz of calmag and containers of great
white that are three
or more years old should i flush them
into my septic tank
there's a lot to unpack in that question
um a lot of your products should have an
expiration date printed on them if you
look
on the lid or on the bottom of the
bottle somewhere there should be an
expiration date
i don't know what those companies
recommend for storage
for long-term use if they're more than a
year old i generally get rid of them
um the quartz of calmag
i would open up and smell it see what it
smells like if it smells like calmag
should
if you've been using cow mag for a while
you know what it smells like it smells
like cow mag like a bottle of calamag
it's got a very distinct smell to it
when you get it on your fingers you
smell it all day
it's not terrible but it's got a very a
very noticeable aroma
smell them see if they're okay i would
consider using the calmag
maybe if it's past its expiration date
but if you can toss it and get another
one if it's affordable i would just do
that don't risk it
if it's chunky if it smells bad then
toss it immediately
check for an expiration date the great
white
um i don't know how hot or cold you've
had those stored i don't know how dry or
moist and which the environment in which
those were stored has been
but if it hasn't changed colors i think
it starts off like a whitish gray if it
hasn't turned purple or too
dark and it hasn't clumped up and gotten
chunky it's probably okay to use the
good thing is uh
if you use that product and it is
expired you're probably
not let me try to [ __ ] get my tongue
under control here
you're probably not going to cause any
harm
by using that product should it be
expired you've just got a bunch of dead
microbes
it'll just be a bunch of inert matter
that'll just be just
sand basically floating around in your
water when you mix it in
so i don't think there will be a problem
if you do attempt to use it however i
would look for
a an expiration date on both of those
maybe
i do not work for those companies i
would say maybe contact the vendors the
manufacturers and see
how long they recommend you keep them
around if they were in a cool
dry dark safe environment maybe they'll
last a little longer
if you had adverse conditions extremes
of one end or the other
they're probably toast and i would
consider getting rid of them if you can
afford it
toss them out get some fresh [ __ ] not
talking trash about your budget
i know everybody has [ __ ] tightened down
right now because of the pandemic
because of the
situation in which we are all facing so
i don't really have any solid advice for
you contact the vendors
or check out the products if the dried
products have become
purple or chunky and dried up and stuck
together
i would toss that if it's gummy i would
definitely toss
that if the other product is chunky as
well smells bad
if they smell bad don't use them get rid
of them uh contact the vendors
see what they say look for that
expiration date
here's another question i found to be
kind of funny this is not grow related
this is just random it says what did
walmart do to piss you off
i did not know that i had expressed
anywhere that i had
any sort of hatred or anger toward
walmart but i just thought this was
funny it was something i could just
address really quickly
i do try to answer all of the patreon
questions and this one came in so i'm
standing by my word and doing my best to
answer this
and it could be real quick if i'd quit
rambling about it uh what did walmart do
to piss me off
nothing like directly nothing like they
didn't stab me they didn't punch me
i just don't like the way that walmart
treats the community
i don't think that they're uh they're
not it's not cool man it's babylon man
they come to communities and they shut
down mom and pop stores
and then they build the big walmart
store and then every three blocks you
got a walmart neighborhood market and it
makes it hard for the small
mom and shop community stores stores yes
those two
to stay in business and survive and as a
small business myself i understand what
it's like we need to make
ends meet we need to pay our employees
and [ __ ] handle things
it's a struggle sometimes so seeing
walmart crush things
uh was kind of weird and then if you
want to get closer to home
my mom no longer works there so i could
talk about it my mom worked at walmart
and they didn't give a [ __ ] about her
i love my mom dearly she's the most
important person in my world in my life
and walmart treated my mom like [ __ ] so
uh
watching somebody or a company or an
entity treat somebody you love
more than anything that you wish you
could solve all their problems and
[ __ ] just pay their way for life
to see that company treat my mama like
[ __ ] that made me salty to be quite
honest with you
um she worked there for years it's you
guys don't care about what my mom did
for walmart
my mom probably doesn't want her
business broadcasted out but i feel like
walmart did her dirty
so and not just one time i just feel
like it was a continued
uh a continued [ __ ] you from walmart to
her and to the family just because the
way they treated her she was a kick-ass
employee
uh i got my work ethic from my mom and
if you guys know me you know i [ __ ]
work my ass off my mom will work circles
around me
uh she's old enough to be my mama
obviously and she will still [ __ ]
work circles around me
so i'm salty at walmart for treating my
mama like [ __ ]
anybody that treats your mama like [ __ ]
you're gonna have some hatred for i
don't know that it's hatred salty is the
word
uh if i can shop anywhere else i just go
there
there's no need for me to give my money
that i work for my mama works hard for
her money
there's no need to spend my money at a
company that doesn't give a [ __ ] about
the people
uh that does kind of sketchy shady
things i should i should be careful with
what i'm saying because
uh they may [ __ ] delete my sku tag
and i made [ __ ] disappear
i may be taking that inventory and never
[ __ ] return here if i keep talking so
i just didn't like the way they treated
my mom she doesn't work there anymore so
we can talk [ __ ] now they can't fire
they can't do a [ __ ] thing but
i just didn't like it so that's pretty
much why i'm salty on walmart they
didn't do anything directly they just
just a bunch of years of just [ __ ]
jabs just being
dicks like i don't know i just didn't
care for it that's not cool
there's probably better places to work
and if you work for walmart do your
thing
i understand it's a pandemic get your
[ __ ] paycheck but
oh man yeah i wouldn't do it i wouldn't
work there
and i'm privileged and blessed so i
understand things are different but
that's what walmart did to piss me off
uh it was mean to my mama and anybody
that's got a problem with my mama
got a problem with me
kind of [ __ ] joking mostly [ __ ]
serious so let's keep
moving forward this is a fun podcast i
like these short questions
this is a good thursday show i think
this comes out on thursday happy
thursday y'all
this one goes like this i'm never gonna
say y'all again either
uh hey bro big fan with a big question
is flash photography bad for the plants
could it go as far as making our plants
turn into hermaphrodites or
express intersex um
i do not think that flash photography is
bad for the plants
during the lights-on cycle don't disrupt
the nighttime cycle with flash
photography that will probably piss them
off
um you can think of it like this
what do you accept when you're sleeping
you want it
still dark and quiet right shut the [ __ ]
up turn off the lights and don't bother
me
that's what you want when you're
sleeping guess what that's what the
plants want also
they want to be in a cool temperature a
cool environment they just don't want to
be [ __ ] with they want it dark
they want it quiet and they want to be
left the [ __ ] alone if you go if i
walked into your bedroom
when you fell asleep two or three hours
after just walk in there and start going
hey could i get you to maybe
uh strike a pose [ __ ] and start taking
pictures with flash photography
you're gonna throw everything in reach
at me and i'm gonna have photos of it
it's gonna be really funny i'm gonna
post them and tag you
but [ __ ] shit's gonna come flying to
me from all directions
your glass of water you got by the
bedside that's coming the book you were
reading before bed
that's coming if i haven't ran yet
you're probably shooting at me by now
for taking flash photography
of you trying to sleep you're probably
in your undies probably don't look your
best probably all puffy faced and
[ __ ] confused
the plants feel the same way don't go
taking pictures of the ladies
in there don't take any pictures of
ladies and they're sleeping unless you
got their permission you guys
no ladies even none of the ladies all
you guys out there listen to me no
ladies want you taking their pictures
when they're asleep and that comes down
to the cannabis plants and all ladies in
our lives don't do it
skip that be a better person than that
that's partly a joke again
again completely [ __ ] serious when
they're awake
let them get dressed up let them pose
let them do their thing let them be
prepared and take all the flash
photography you want
i don't think flash photography will
harm the plants in the daylight cycle in
the night time cycle
yes you've got the potential to cause
huge catastrophic problems with flash
photography
in my opinion just because you're
walking in there you probably got a
light on when you go in there you got to
maneuver around the room you're taking
pictures you're looking at the camera
screen
probably using your phone for a
flashlight not even thinking about that
being a light
just take pictures when the lights are
on use your flash photography at that
point they will be cool i don't think
that'll make them hurt
i've been going for a long time i've got
one more question we're going to finish
this page of questions
then we'll wrap up this random questions
episode this one says
another soil question for you
hey ross to jeff i know you've worked at
a commercial grow in your youth that's
funny in my youth
in my youth i was a [ __ ] most of my
commercial growing has been as an adult
but thank you i appreciate that maybe
i'm still in my youth [ __ ] yeah
still in my youth anyway it says with
all of the craft breweries in colorado
have you ever heard of anyone making a
soil blend containing a percentage of
spent barley grains
from the brewery uh then they signed
their name i don't know if they want
their name said i did not ask i did not
verify clarify or confirm
or deny so i'm not going to say that but
let's answer the question
um i have never heard of that honestly
i'm sure it's happening somewhere i
don't think it's happening in a
commercial grow
because there's probably some stupid
rule
that bans uh the brewery
from giving out that spent stuff and
another stupid rule
that would ban the commercial grow from
accepting that spent stuff honestly
there's probably some
logistics that put a big piece of red
tape from allowing that to happen
that's just how both of those industries
work they're both highly overly
regulated
and there would just be i'd probably
have to pay a million dollars to buy it
and then probably they'd have to spend a
[ __ ] million dollars just to sell it
to me
only the government and uh the governing
agencies would make the two million
dollars
both of us would be [ __ ] out of money
um that's just how this [ __ ] works in
commercial uh cannabis and commercial
alcohol production so
i don't know anybody doing that that's
my assumption by the way once again bro
science bro news bro info
i don't know anybody doing it never
heard of it done is that a good idea
containing a percentage of barley grains
from the brewery
i don't know i never thought of that
never heard of that idea that's a new
one for me
but very creative and uh thank you for
the
uh the podcast content all right i think
that's as far as i'm gonna go with all
these random questions that i've printed
out here
this was a fun episode i had a good time
you guys thank you for letting me
regroup we had a couple of episodes that
were kind of off the rails there we had
a uh
a rest in peace episode once again shout
out and rest in peace to my buddy stoney
scholar
uh hope the whole family is recovering
well hope extended family and all the
podcast gang is recovering well
then we had a birthday episode where the
podcast had a birthday that one wasn't
very
uh informative now this one we've uh we
had another episode where i tried to do
some educating answer some questions
now we've got this episode here where i
just did 20 questions with ross to jeff
thank you jeez excuse me for that thank
you guys for giving me the opportunity
to get my [ __ ] back together
uh i'm back on the rails the show will
only continue to improve from here
thank you for hanging out i think it is
time to wrap up this episode my throat's
obviously done i'm over here
uh what are the words choking and
coughing i tried to say chalking which i
don't think is a real word
maybe it is now all right this was a fun
episode you guys thank you for hanging
out thank you for letting me ramble at
you for uh
over 30 minutes you got a long show out
of me thank you for hanging out on a
thursday
i'll be back in a couple of days with
fresh new content if you feel like this
episode was educational informative
entertaining
maybe you learned a couple of things
maybe i improved your garden maybe i
increased
your harvest weight maybe you'd like to
contribute to the show
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need to
support the show will be right there on
the screen
where else do we go from there email
address if you've got any questions
corrections comments or concerns
you know i would love to hear from you
again that email address is grow from
your heart
at hotmail.com don't be shy send me your
questions we'll get you answered here on
the podcast again
don't forget about the website at
iriegenetics.com
that is all i've got you guys my voice
is done i need a drink
i need a dab i need some good food in my
life then we're going to take some more
dabs
then we're going to take some more dabs
ladies and gentlemen be good to one
another
be good to yourself be good to the
garden i'll catch you in a couple of
days let's give a big
giant shout out to my friend black thumb
grower and until next time take a fat
dab
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you