[Music]
yeah welcome back podcast world
i'm your host my friends call me rasta
jeff and this is episode 628
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to talk about a
new strain that i'm releasing for 420
before we get there let's do a few shout
outs to a few members of
the 710 club of course the 710 club or
those folks who support us on patreon
at the 7 and 10 a month level or higher
so with no further ado let's start off
with the big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out
to my good friends mobius grows and
rosin man
let's follow that up with a big thank
you shout out to pack northwest den and
captain mojo
let's send a big thank you shout out to
froggle rock and kiwi monster
i want to send a big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out to
aaron and ez057
let's send a big thank you shout out to
zoso j and danky dave
let's follow that up with a big thank
you shout out to papa zee and john
bendit
then let's wrap it all up with the big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out and a fist bump
to my buddy brett g big thanks and big
shout out to everybody
who continues to support the show on
patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need will be
right there on the screen
and i did make a link in the show notes
and in the video description that takes
you right to patreon that's there for
all of my friends who could be working
driving
maybe you got the kids maybe you're
stuck in a cubicle maybe you just can't
pull out the phone and visit patreon
right now
that link will be there for you later
patreon.com forward slash
grow from your heart all right welcome
to the show everybody in this episode
we are going to focus on a new strain
which i'm going to release for 420
let's talk about a couple of other
things before we get to that strain
highlight
in a previous episode i did talk about
finding a male
plant out of a pack of feminized seeds i
talked about how rare that could be i
talked about the opportunities for that
i was enlightened by a great friend i
don't know if they want a shout out i
don't know if they want their business
out there but i'm just going to say
that i was educated about a very
great male plant that came from
feminized
seed stock somebody had seeds um
they had a plant that they loved they
couldn't get to that plant anymore it
was taken from them they had seed stock
they had feminized seeds
within that femme stock they did find a
male and they use that male
to make more seeds it makes regular
seeds but
those regular seeds do seem to put out a
higher ratio
of females so there has been a discovery
i've been educated i've been updated
there is a likelihood of a male popping
up in female stock and when it does
sometimes it has proven itself to be a
very
useful tool for a good breeder so that
was an update i wanted to share with you
also we talked about using spent barley
in a previous episode
a listener asked about using spent
barley from a grow
from a brewery to use that in a
commercial grow they said there's a
bunch of stuff left
over i got mixed reviews and mixed
emotions
in response to using the spent barley
some people said
you're going to get way too many bugs
they said they tried it they had too
many bugs it had too many sugars
other people said they'd do it and it
works beautifully so i got both sides of
that story
i believe both of those people because
who knows what the uh
the other factors were that could have
contributed to that but i did hear
positives
and negatives i wanted to make sure to
update you guys
and share that with you because i like
the feedback i like the info and the
people that replied
are great people in the industry that i
greatly respect and trust
wanted to share that info all right
another thing i want to talk about is
the discord channel
you guys the irie genetics grow from
your heart podcast
the rasta jeff discord channel has
exploded there are so many members users
viewers visitors the community
is huge it is out of control i'm going
to ask you guys one time
just play nicely be kind over there i'm
pretty sure everybody listening
watching participating now is totally
kind and totally cool
but as the leader of the irie army the
guy whose name is on that [ __ ]
discord
i just want to ask you one time just be
nice you guys are indirectly
representing me and it turns out you
were directly representing me in some
people's eyes
so just remember some of the [ __ ] you
say over there could be taken a skew
could be taken wrong
and it could accidentally represent the
ivory army
in a negative light so keep that in
light when you're uh keep that in mind
when you're
posting commenting scrolling and
trolling honestly you guys do your thing
being adult but keep in mind you are
uh on a public forum some people might
get salty let's just be nice also if you
got upset
i can't babysit everybody there's a lot
of people over there it's the internet
show me where the internet hurts you
today but let's play nice you guys
let's play nice let's be all inclusive i
don't condone promote
ah i'm not down with any [ __ ] that's
no racism no uh no uh none of that crap
we're not gonna segregate
segregate or discriminate anybody over
there everybody's there to have a good
time
let's just focus on that i've already
given it way too much attention
let's move forward to the main topic of
today's
podcast let's get ready to ramble um i
said at the top of the show we're going
to talk about a strain that i'm going to
release for 420
that strain is the blueberry cookies
crossed to jack the ripper
let me back up one step just in case
you're not aware i
am rosted jeff not only am i the host
and producer of the grow from your heart
podcast also
i breed seeds i am the sole proprietor
i am irie genetics premium seeds it's
just me i do everything from the
breeding the selecting
the packaging the social media stuff the
email stuff it is all just me with that
being said
uh if you're sending me emails and i'm
not responding right away it's cause
i've got about 14
000 unread emails i'm trying but
i read genetics premium seeds is all me
i make seeds i make regular and
feminized ganja seeds
for the legal market so they can produce
high quality medicine and recreational
cannabis for themselves and their
clientele
in a legal fashion so that's what i do i
have recently
uh recently we lost a breeder who taught
me
a lot and inspired me a lot that man was
known by subcool a lot of you
that are listening know who sub cool was
if you didn't know who subcool was
already
uh i invite you to just press pause on
my show google
sub cool google the weed nerd watch some
weed nerd shows fall in love with
subbies fall in love with sub that was
hard to say
i meant it but it was hard to say fall
in love with subby just like we all did
learn from sub
a lot of my teachings a lot of my
learning a lot of my education a lot of
my delivery and style
came from sub i like to say i learned a
lot of what to do
and also a lot of what not to do in the
cannabis industry from my friend sub
cool
dude wasn't perfect wasn't an angel but
he was a bad [ __ ] and he was my
friend he taught me a lot
so sub cool passed away rest in peace
subby i miss you i love you the whole
irie army misses you we all love you
i wish you were still here he's not so
in honor what i did i got a pack of
seeds that were bred by sub cool
and i found a male out of that package
of seeds i found a jack the ripper male
that was beautiful
he had a beautiful structure he was a
stud ah he was a ripper
he had a nice aroma a nice structure he
flowered well
ah he had the right shape to him it was
what i was looking for the male plant
had trichomes
i've posted so many photos of this male
jack the ripper plant the
whole project was posted on my instagram
on irie underscore genetics
anyway i found this jack the ripper mail
i crossed it to
my prized blueberry cookies female
i got that blueberry cookies female from
a commercial grow several years ago
and i've been crossing it to a lot of
things and it is an amazing plan it does
a lot of great breeding
i'm actually googling jack the ripper
right now because i didn't write down
the genetics
and uh it's got a lot of different
things in it when i get to that point
i'm going to want to be able to give you
the exact
details on that so i took the jack the
ripper mail this is the part where i
want to
read you the details of what jack the
ripper is and uh instead of finding the
mail
it brought up the serial killer of
course so i'm going to type in strain
instead of cross
because it's going to be a lot more info
anyway it's going to get us there it is
a cross
of i'm trying to just go quickly on this
show here
of course i want to know if i'm 21 or
older i used to go to subcool's website
and that link is now
uh it's a dead link now he's probably
not paying the bill since he's passed
away
uh jack the ripper or jto jtr is the
flagship hybrid from subcool the dank
and it was created to make his famous
jacks cleaner in seed form
uh it's known as the fastest lemon haze
available
i just want to know the genetics it is
space dude and jack jack the
and jack herrer but i wanted a better
breakdown of it
now i feel very unprofessional i'm
probably not even going to edit this
uh i used to go to sub site you guys
that side is gone now
jack the ripper seeds
now let's do strain details that's
better
it's probably going to take me like seed
finder or something but
i don't want to use leafy that's whack
all right you may have noticed a quick
edit there you may not have noticed
anything i don't know what you're
talking about let's talk about jack the
ripper the male that i chose
jack the ripper is a cross of jack's
cleaner and space queen space queen is
uh sub cools prized mail space dude was
the prized mail sort of like my king
solomon
how that is what i cross everything to
space dude
is what sub cool crossed everything to
so we've got a jax cleaner
to space queen or the space dude male
let's talk about jack's cleaner that was
pluton and lamb's bread
and purple haze and northern lights
cross to
jack hair so we've got the pluton i'm
not sure what pluton is that's an
unknown strain but we've got lamb's
bread in there
definitely a classic one of my favorites
a jamaican favorite
uh we got purple haze in there it
doesn't get any more classic than purple
haze
we got northern lights in there that is
an old school one then that is cross to
the jack hero we got a lot of great
lineage
in the jax cleaner that is crossed to
the space queen let's see if there's a
breakdown for the space queen that is
romulan
and cindy 99 so that is a lot of great
stuff going in there we got the romulan
also in the golden goat that is a short
squatty
uh faster flowering kind of a sativa
dominant plant that flowers quite
quickly
across to the cindy 99 uh big shout out
to our friends uh brothers grimm
big shout out to mr soul for the cindy99
ah
that's got um princess and p94 which is
jack herrer
to a mystery male so we've got jack hair
on two different ends of this
it was sort of subs kind of an idea to
make his version of
jack hair or a jack's cleaner seed
form so we've got jack the ripper the
reason i wanted to breed the
two jack the ripper is i really love
i've smoked a lot of jack the ripper it
represents subcool very well
um it's not using his space queen or his
space dude which
would have been too obvious to make a
jack a sub cool tribute cross
so i made a jack the ripper cross
because it's one of his flagship strains
i love the flavors and aromas that come
from that strain it's got these uh
the phenotypes that i found i found a
key lime pie phenotype that was just
delicious lots of lemon
lemon cleaner like lemon pledges
bathroom cleaner
and lemons lots of just crazy lemon
candy and cleaner flavors
so i like the jack the ripper for the
buzz the flavor the aromas
and the growth it's got a really sativa
like head ringing buzz but it doesn't
take a super long time to flower you
could get it done in 63 days
some strains that give you that potency
that buzz take closer to 70 72 days
so he'd come down a week early and he'd
still get wrecked from it which i really
like i like that panic attack
uh heart racing [ __ ] uh lose your
keys when they're in your hand
can't find your cell phone when it's
ringing in your pocket sort of stuff i
love that kind of herb
ah waiting for the stop light to turn
green or the stop sign to turn green
waiting for the stop sign to turn green
is one of my favorite kind of herbs if
you got that kind of weed that's the
best
the kind of weed you gotta turn down the
radio so that you can see the street
signs better
that's this kind of herb so that is jack
the ripper uh that is the male that i
selected from the sub cool side of this
cross now let's talk about the female we
got to talk about the female i chose to
breed with
the female in this cross was the
blueberry cookies that is blueberry
cross to tahoe og then cross to
the thin mint cookies that's one of my
favorite crosses i've made
the leonardo that is leonardo that is
what leonardo is
then from there we've got six other
outcrosses of leonardo
to make the tmnt line i reversed it to
make that full
feminized line it is also the blue
raspberry truffle
uh that is a rise across to the
uh the blueberry cookie sorry my brain
went totally numb for a minute there
the arise pollinating the blueberry
cookies makes the blue raspberry truffle
i was also thinking about the blue pill
is the blueberry cookies
to the reversed golden good so i've made
a lot of things
with this blueberry cookies it's one of
my favorites it kicks ass
now we've got the blueberry cookies
cross 2 jack the ripper
i don't think i've even said the name of
it yet which is i'm doing that on
purpose i'm trying to build a little bit
of suspense
to the best of my recom election i have
not said the name so we've talked about
the parents we've talked about the jack
the ripper
why i selected that jack the ripper to
first reason was to tribute
to tribute sub cool second reason was
flavor aroma structure flowering time
and potency
all of those things are amazing with
jack the ripper very good breeding
candidate
then i've got the blueberry cookies
why do i breed to that it is pungent it
is potent
it is vigorous you can beat the [ __ ] out
of that plant and it will recover you
could pee on it light it on fire and
kick it over
and leave and then tomorrow when you
come back that plant will be standing up
stronger than it ever was going
that was a good try i don't know what
you thought you were going to do to me
that plant is a boss it's a savage
it grows amazingly well in all
conditions it tastes good
it is potent as [ __ ] it harvests very
well and it breeds very very well
it's a very good breeder it brings a lot
to the table in breeding
but it also allows a lot to be added to
it in breeding
it's a good ingredient it's not just a
dominant flavor in the breeding it
lets things open up to it so that's the
blueberry cookies
uh the blueberry to tahoe to the cookies
we got the jack the ripper which has got
the lamb's bread the ak-47
the northern light sorry it makes aka
northern lights in my head all the time
there's a reason for that we'll talk
about in the future um
so we got a whole hodgepodge of genetics
going on in that one
um then do i want to tell you the name
of it or do i want to talk i
why i selected them that blueberry
cookies is a champ and i knew they would
breed well together
something about when i see two plants i
just go ooh you
it's like just hanging out with friends
hanging out with two people you know
and now i used to say hanging out with a
guy and you know a girl but
it's 20 21 you're hanging out with a
person and you go hey
you know bill you may really like steve
or you may really like emily i don't
know which [ __ ] one but
hypothetically you may like one of them
and you just know it
and you hook bill up with steve or emily
and they got a [ __ ] completely happy
future just because you could see it
in my analogy it's got to be bill and
emily because they're going to breed
sorry steve
but bill and emily are going to breed
and they make beautiful children and
then you go haha i got to
i got to predict that that happened so
my plants i could just see it sometimes
i know that if i pollinate that girl
with that male
the offspring is gonna be [ __ ]
stellar sometimes i just know that
so i took the jack the ripper male
i took the blueberry cookies female
don't worry i also pollinated a bunch of
other
females when i did this so there will be
other females released with other cool
names
um we'll talk about that in a future
episode i made jack the ripper f2s
that was a really fun project so i did
the pollination we made
the project i've talked about why i've
talked about the selections talked about
the parents
talked about blueberry cookies talked
about jtr now what does this cross
make this cross makes crazy pungent
crazy potent sativa dominant hybrids
that smell and taste are you ready for
these flavor descriptions these came
from my testers because i didn't make
these up
blueberry syrup blueberry fun dip
fake blue candy flavors
lemon berries weird sour
stuff and then i thought one smelled
like red bull
and somebody else told me they smelled
like purple flintstone
vitamins i think the red bull and
flintstone vitamins may be the same
aroma
somebody else said it was vitamins i
thought it was red bull we're getting
blueberry
blueberry syrup blueberry fun dip fake
blue candy flavors and then we got lemon
berries
weird sour stuff that's a really good
description because
it's weird sour stuff i say it's got a
wang to it you smell it you're like
that's just kind of wang it's got a wang
to it it's deliciously wangy
it's got a really nice flavor ah sour
stuff
red bull vitamins and then a lot of
people said
lemon cleaner smells like chemicals and
cleaner
so there are a lot of wonderful
marvelous aromas coming from this
some of them almost kind of burn your
eyes in a good good way
the concentrates didn't get to smoke a
lot they went really quickly
the concentrates were almost uh lemon
spicy it was almost so much lemons that
it like
hit your nose and cleaned your sinuses
you could almost feel it
i heated up the dab nail i could almost
feel it and it was like a
a saucy diamond-y consistency uh
when i would put it into the banger i
could almost taste it and feel the
effervescence hitting my lungs and nose
before the dab even felt like it
vaporized or volatized or whatever it
did in my banger before i saw
smoke or vapor in the the rig i could
feel those terps hitting me
it was like spicy lemony like ah
if you've ever cleaned cleaned anything
with orange cleaner it was like using
lemon
cleaner it was very terpy very
terpadelic with a little bit of a
spiciness to it
i'm [ __ ] rambling so this could be a
long fun episode i'm really having a
good time behind the mic today i've
needed to get behind mike for a minute
and let loose
let's talk about the buzz a lot of
people said the buzz
was very social some people said they
wish they would let it go longer because
they cut it too early and they got a
really
high racy head buzz i got the word
talkative and chatty from a lot of
people who tested this they were
so when you smoke this you turn into me
you just start [ __ ] talking just
talkative and chatty but sometimes you
know what the [ __ ] you're talking about
it'll just talk you into circles you'll
talk yourself into space
uh it's mind moving as something i wrote
um
something about those jack the ripper uh
jack harrow terps in there mixed with
the girl scout cookies terps in there
if something just moves your brain
sometimes it can give you a little bit
of panic some people reported it was too
much too heavy
they said when they cut it down too
early they were a little bit panicky a
little bit racy and a little bit
bug-eyed and they wish they'd let it go
a little bit longer
so it'll make you talkative it'll make
you social it'll make you chatty
it's mind-moving sometimes it'll give
you panic but it will give you a strong
moving head buzz it'll get you going
really good
so that is the consumption factors also
i noticed it make sure it makes my eyes
completely [ __ ] red i don't know if
it did that to anybody else
cannabis doesn't make my eyes red i
gotta smoke hard to get red eyes it's
got to be like the late night session
once i'm burned out and maxed out for
the day but ah this stuff
smoking on this strain that i haven't
named yet i'm trying to dodge the name
i'm gonna give you the name just to be
fun here pretty soon but
this stuff did make my eyes completely
super red so we got flavors we got
aromas
we got the buzz now let's talk about
some of the most important factors to a
lot of you this is growing this cannabis
how is this going to work for you
one thing i want to talk about is these
were some of the healthiest as
healthiest most healthy seeds
i have ever produced i've been making
seeds for a long time
sometimes some plants just make ugly
seeds
sometimes some plants make beautiful
seeds almost every seed that came out of
this run
was beautiful what was the difference
the new addition the new anomaly the new
change up
canon leds from black sail market big
shout out to my buddy keith it
black sail market erg those canon leds
made my seeds
beautiful bigger fatter robust it could
have been that male
but ah man those seeds were beautiful i
think it was the light i think it was
the light because every seed sometimes
you get some shitty seeds in the mix
the seeds on the bottom of the plant
don't look good you get some white dead
seeds but didn't get any of those
all of the seeds were [ __ ] awesome so
some of the biggest
baddest healthiest most beautiful seeds
i've ever bred they were done under leds
i got a lot of reports of really good
female to male ratios a lot of these
plants are popping up females so that is
really awesome for you guys out there
i can't make any guarantees but the
reports a lot of females
also a lot of very good germination
rates
90 to 100 german germination rates
from almost everybody i sent seeds to
the people that said they didn't get
good germs they said themselves
i [ __ ] something up so i'm gonna say
we got more than 90
germination which is uh that qualifies
in my book
uh these plants veg very vigorously they
don't veg like something that would be
crossed with a rise they don't have that
hyper vigor
but they veg quickly and they veg very
strongly these plants are strong
uh where are we going i lost my place in
my notes there we go
uh they make that classic christmas tree
kind of a menorah shape they grow
branchy bottom and they grow
the top goes real tall the other
branches try to catch up to that
we're going to talk more about how to
deal with that in a minute here um
in veg there's nothing super indicative
of which phenotype you've got
other than leaf size we'll talk more
specifically about phenotypes later in
the episode but
you're not going to be able to tell
which phenotype you've got early in veg
unless you've got huge maple leaf
size leaves um those are the platinum
cookies heavy phenotypes if you get the
super thin leaf
that's jack anything in the middle there
or it could be kind of lamb's bready
jack
lamb's bread leaning i'm not super
experienced with the lamb spread i can't
tell you enough details to know if
that's what i'm seeing
but uh most of them are going to lie
anywhere in between there you're going
to get big fat leaves or real skinny
leaves or anywhere in between because
this is a crazy hybrid with a lot of
different genetics
so you're going to see big mashups of
different things most of the plants
will make one big dominant top and a
nice bushy bottom i know bushy bottom is
going to get a lot of people's attention
we all like them big bottom girls it
does get that big fat bottom but it's
gonna grow one main top and it's gonna
keep growing that christmas tree menorah
sort of shape
i generally top it we're gonna talk more
about that
i call it making it makes a menorah or a
christmas tree with what i call the
leader one ambitious [ __ ] leader
you gotta knock that leader out in my
opinion most of the time
i suggest topping these plants i keep
saying it's gonna make that one liter
top
you got all the bottoms coming up cut
out that main top and then it creates a
nice
like a shrub like just a nice bush if
you put it in a big pot these plants
will spread out
really nicely so when you put these
plants into flower they will transition
into bloom
very quickly as something i've noticed
that could be because i'm growing under
leds and when i switch from
18 6 to 11 13 they trigger into flowers
super quickly but it is something i
observed these plants went more quickly
than other plants in the same room
they triggered quickly into flour they
transfer transition quickly into the
bloom phase
these plants love being tied down
they're weird girls they want to be
twisted popped and tortured and held
down
you can do that to these girls pop them
twist them
be careful but you can do that they like
to be tied down trellis down and netted
down
so you can do that uh into like week
three or four a flower
they get soft and vine like these plants
will grow
with like some plants are known to get
woody and hard
and they don't bend and pop and twist as
easily as these plants will these plants
get like
ah like a sappy wire structure like you
could bend them and wrap them around a
vine
they're very very twisty and viny they
pop
pop and twist them very carefully
because of that viney structure
sometimes you'll just blow up that whole
stem you'll go to twist it
it'll just rip off or you'll just
explode the whole thing but they're soft
they're very soft if you take care of
them and stay
nice and healthy they'll be soft and
supple and pliable and bright bright
green
tie them down twist them they will need
some supports because they're so twisty
so pliable
some of those longer branches especially
your bottom branches are gonna get
droopy and floppy give them some love
give them some support some plant viagra
if you will
now i keep saying that these plants will
stay soft and really light green and
very supple
and very pliable that is if we properly
feed them these plants will get a little
bit picky about the nutrients you can't
over feed them but
they like a lot of nitrogen and veg and
you gotta drop that [ __ ] out almost
immediately as you transition into flour
pay attention to these plants because
they're picky
with nutrients if you over feed them
when they go into flower
they don't make big buds they just make
little sparse buds and they make a lot
of branching and a lot of leaves
if your leaves are not doing the normal
leaf shape thing you expect if they're
starting to kind of mutate a little bit
they're getting too much nitrogen in my
experience that could be one very
quick indicator of too much nitrogen um
they'll take the feedings they'll take a
little bit of heat they're going to get
super frosty and they're going to make
what i call taco leaves
or what also is known as a resin rail
the leaves that come out of the
the main buds are going to get resin on
them very quickly when it gets warm in
the grow room or a little bit humid in
the grow room
they will canoe or taco on you
i don't think that is from the room
being too hot i think that is just a
trait
from the jack the ripper that is
something i saw the jack the ripper do
some of the phenotypes from jtr did that
some of the offspring are doing that
i don't think there's a problem in the
room i don't think you're [ __ ] up i
think that it just wants to taco up and
make room
for resin because the trichomes pop up
out of the top of that taco
i don't think it's your fault so if
you're not over feeding it
if your ph isn't [ __ ] up and if it's
not too hot or too humid or too dry in
the room
you're getting a little bit of like just
leaf tacoing a little bit of leaf
canoeing with trichomes on top
don't panic that is what this plant does
um another thing this plant does not
tolerate
cold if you get them cold they'll go
yellow they'll stop eating they'll get
pissed off at you another thing don't
over defoliate
i talk about leafing the plants that i
breed don't do that to this plant
the girl scout cookies doesn't like
being defoliated heavily
uh the jack herrera is not a fan of
super defoliation guess what
the blueberry cookies jack the ripper
cross does not like to be defoliated
heavily
moderate defoliation at best don't go
super hard
it likes the leaves this plant is
relying on those skinny leaves for
energy so don't piss it off and take too
many off
over defoliating getting it cold over
feeding it some of the things we think
would boost up some plants
ah those things are what piss off this
plant this is a little bit
more of a challenging plant you can't be
oh that new guy that tries to give it
more [ __ ] and do more to it to make it
speed up this is one of those plants
that less
will do better i think this plant it's
got a lot of hodgepodge genetics but i
think this would have been found more
like
in some tropical area where people
couldn't have gotten to it and it would
have just been [ __ ] up and abandoned
by people and then it would just been
out there in nature and it would have
gone
crazy tall and gotten out of control and
it didn't need a lot of attention it
didn't want you to defoliate it didn't
want you to give it too much care
just let it grow and give it supports
and i think it'll be okay
um also i think it doesn't like wind a
lot of the phenotypes i grew and
experienced
everybody by the fan got pissed off the
plants back behind the fan they were all
perfect they were cool
the jack the ripper crosses that were by
the fan they do not tolerate the wind
very well so
don't give them too much wind don't blow
too hard on them
and don't get them too cold the cold
pissed them off and made them slow down
something i can say these plants grow
really well
until you piss them off if you stay out
of their way keep them happy
give them a solid feed pay attention to
the feed high nitrogen in the beginning
taper off that nitrogen
start raising up your phosphorus and
potassium just do it just like you
should a basic plant they'll work very
well the minute you screw something up
with these plants once they go yellow
once they go angry you're [ __ ]
um they get yellow they'll start
crisping up
cold will do it too much moisture will
do it
too much nutrients will do it they're
really easy to grow once
once you get them going but once they're
angry it is over i think the haze
makes it go super fast and the og makes
it super finicky
you cross that it's super quick to be
super finicky
uh as soon as something goes wrong it
lets you know so if you're growing in
hydro keep an eye on it
if you're a soil or soilless mix person
uh you may have some time to rebound or
recover but
uh it's going to let you know when it's
got problems also stay on top of up
potting and root bound nests because
when this one gets root bound
she'll stop growing as soon as the roots
hit the outside of that pot it just goes
no i'm done i like to test things in
cups and get them started in cups
these little [ __ ] hit the edges of
the cups and just stopped they're like
nope
i thought they were mad i thought they
were [ __ ] angry they're just at the
edge i had to uphold them as soon as i
outpotted them
shabang they went crazy again so uh also
a couple of them tried to flower on me
once they got to root bound that is
something to think about
it likes all of the light some plants
some of the plants had to turn down the
canon leds move them right out from
underneath there because they don't like
all that light
put the jack the ripper crosses directly
under the light put the light on the
jack the ripper
crosses feed the light to these plants
it wants
all of the [ __ ] light did i mention
that these plants want light
they will take it it's got lamb's bread
in there it's got jack hair in there
it can take some [ __ ] light give it
all the light it doesn't like
wind i mentioned that if you put them
too close to the fan they get pissy
if it gets too dry in there they get
pissy if it gets too wet in there guess
what
they get pissy you got to keep it just
right in there
they're a little bit weird some of the
plants in the room i mentioned this
got fried by leds i put some new plants
in a room and with a new built room with
some brand new leds the tops of some of
them
roasted guess what the jack the rippers
didn't do they didn't roast
they just took it everything crossed to
the jack the ripper was fine
with being punished by too much light
they were unscathed is the word i put on
my notes
the next part to talk about they stretch
um these plants will stretch on you the
first few days of flower they're going
to take off
but but but but top them not in flour
before you flour them top them pop them
and twist them and that will slow down
the stretch give them a nice
feed give them a nice npk and they will
not take off too fast on you but they do
stretch they get tall on you i lost my
place on my notes
uh where are we oh
um feeding feeding the skinny leaf
phenotype oh i missed this part
they are super easy to clone when you
take that top off of that plant
clone it because they are super easy to
clone they love to clone you can
basically just set it down
it will make a clone feeding the skinny
leaf phenotype wants
less food and higher ph but
don't slow down the calcium i said less
food don't knock out the calcium
so i'll repeat that the skinnier leaved
phenotypes
want less food so if you've got a real
thin phenotype
thinly phenotype it wants less food and
a higher ph
but it also wants more calcium don't
slow down the calmag
on that thin leaf phenotype all of the
phenotypes seem to love calcium later in
life not when they're little they got
pissy
let me give them a lot of calmag a lot
of calcium later on in life they really
loved it
ah they seem to feed moderately don't
over feed give them that calmag
overfeeding nitrogen that's the note i
wanted to make sure to get you
makes them stretchy and leafy but they
don't make
buds so early in flower
taper off that nitrogen but pay
attention to what they're doing if
they're getting yellow keep that
nitrogen going but don't overdo it
they would rather be fed so if you're a
guy or a gal that feeds once every three
days and then gives it water and then
water and then
feed i said that kind of weird if you
feed and then once a week and then give
it water throughout the week maybe feed
twice a week maybe feed three times a
week
if you're growing in cocoa or hydro
definitely feed these [ __ ]
every time pay attention your ppms don't
go too high they would rather have
low feeding every day than a high
feeding uh one at a time so
uh feed them low and often they love
cocoa and otter auto water systems they
go crazy and aeroponics and cocoa they
clone
like [ __ ] crazy and aeroponics cloner
um they explode in an easy cloner these
plants i said it right here several
times they make
crazy crazy roots but once those roots
hit the walls
they stop growing let's talk about how i
would grow these plants i feel like i've
got a lot to say and i feel like i've
been going for a long time but that's
cool
ah let me take a drink and we'll
continue with this i'm gonna take a sip
this is how i would grow these plants
i would veg them in a cup or a six inch
net pot
until you see them stop growing that
means they're root bound
as soon as they're caught then put them
in a three or a five or a seven gallon
pot i would only transplant them one
time
because they grow so vigorously that
that's a waste of time
doing staggered or graduated pots go
from your cup
to your final big daddy final shoes
uh your graduation pot so i would
recommend
either nine no let me start here on this
note i would recommend
either five ah no that's not what i
meant to even write
i would recommend four seven gallon pots
or
six five gallon pots veg those
so let me say that again because i did
stumble through the start of that four
seven gallon pots per light this is in
like a five by five area
uh we're gonna base this on a five by
five ten or a one thousand watt light
or one of keith's canon leds i would say
four seven gallon pots so that's a
section about this big as the pot
you'll start spreading them out as they
grow four or seven gallons
or six five gallons that's just a little
bit smaller
and a couple more plants depending on
your plant count this could be uh
very very influential if you got a low
plant count do
more big [ __ ] plants that's the way
to do it if you got unlimited plants
just do a bunch of little plants and veg
for like a week and flip them
anyway i would do four seven gallon pots
or
six five gallon pots veg those until
they are about knee high
i'm a tall dude go to my knee
tall knee uh top those at that time then
spread it out
with either a tomato cage or a trellis
net or
sticks you can put sticks in there
angling out you can put them angling
in however you want to do it but spread
those tops out so light gets to that
whole plant
uh leaf it a little bit so the plant
penetrates so the light penetrates in
there
so then you've got either four sevens or
six fives veg to knee-high
top them spread them out let them
recover then flip them
or or here's another option i would do
nine three gallon pots on the same
footprint
just smaller plants we're gonna veg for
less time uh we're gonna veg for like
two three maybe four weeks at all
in those [ __ ] small pots then flip
them do not
top them in those small pots because
they're gonna get tall you just want
that big one glory bud in there
put a stick in there to hold up that
glory cola the rest will support itself
so either four sevens six
fives or nine threes is the way i would
do it if you do the threes don't top
them
the other ones definitely do top them um
one more thing to talk about these
plants are very bug resistant from what
i've noticed
what i've also noticed is jack herrer
crosses
and blueberry crosses are both bug
resistant we got both of those in here
so we're getting a lot of bug resistance
something i should mention
some of the people did report getting a
rash from trimming
these trees people that are allergic to
hazes
and blue dream are also allergic to this
plant i've done an episode
all about plant rashes and getting a
rash from trimming
guess what those same people got a rash
from trimming
this cross it's something in the
blueberry it's something in the haze
something in that is giving them a rash
and a histamine reaction so people are
getting hives
and an arm rash from trimming this
strain i just want to give you a
disclaimer
if the hazes or the blueberry if blue
dream
gave you a rash this one will from
trimming it those people can smoke it
once it's dried and cured but they
cannot trim it kind of weird
all right um i said i would talk about
phenotypes i feel like this is a long
podcast but you guys should love this
phenotypes
there obviously is a blueberry cookies
phenotype it is the blueberry cookies
cross
it has got the blue skittles flavors
it's got blue skittles blue raspberries
most of that wiggling a bling bling blue
flavor
comes from the blueberry cookies it is
the whiter leaf
phenotype that comes from the tahoe in
the blueberry cookies
there's also a jack hair phenotype that
one's got
haze maybe a little bit of peppermint
maybe some sandalwood and skunk
those are going to be the longer longest
finishing phenotypes
there may be a little bit of jack maybe
a little bit of lamb's bread in there
that spiciness that sandalwood maybe
a little bit of the the lamb's bread
coming through
but that's a lot of jack hair in that
phenotype there's a
jack the ripper phenotype which is
lemons and rotten fruit and i love it
then ladies and gentlemen here's the
official name of this strain
we've gotten this far into this podcast
and i haven't told you the name of this
strain
i'm so good at building suspense the
name of this cross is the blueberry
butcher
shout out to lovin in her eyes for
throwing that name in the hat
i love it blueberry butcher i tossed
around a lot of ideas that always came
back
to blueberry butcher so shout out uh to
loving in her eyes for a great name
you're gonna get a pack for show i hope
you grow it hope you breed with it
but the blueberry butcher was named by
loving in her eyes it's a great name
jack the ripper was a serial killer
blueberry cookies i wanted to maybe name
it serial killer that would have been
cool
that may get used for something else
don't steal it cereal not
s-e-r-i-l-i-a whatever else
we got lost there but cereal like the
breakfast serial killer right anyway
this is blueberry butcher beautiful name
let's talk about the phenotype which i
have named the blueberry butcher
it is the blueberry cookies structure
but
the jack the ripper rotten mango
lemon lime funk red bull smell
all right that's a lot of stuff to take
in the blueberry butcher
it is the blueberry cookies structure
it's tall it's got jagged leaves it just
looks like a classic
cannabis plant if you saw the silhouette
you'd go that's the weed they used to
put in pictures
like it is [ __ ] photogenic weed it's
the blueberry cookie structure very well
supported
very stout some of the others are a
little skinny a little wispy definitely
need support the blueberry cookies
dominant structure
will support itself very very sturdy
very stout
so it's got that stout structure which
you're looking for you want plants that
will hold themselves up
they could build great big buds on
themselves that's what we want takes
popping and twisting very well
then it's got that jack the ripper
rotten mango flavor to it almost
and when i say this flavor people
wrinkle up their noses and they cringe
but
it smells like a bar trash can a little
bit of fermented funk and vomit
along with a little bit of rotten mango
and dirty fruit a little bit of feet
going on a little bit of baby [ __ ] and
baby food
it sounds terrible right no if you're a
cannabis consumer a cannabis
uh connoisseur you're going damn i need
a [ __ ] bag of that
also it's got lemon lime funk and a
little bit of red bull
or chewable flintstones vitamins the
purple color to be more specific
the dinos i think they are so that is
the blueberry butcher
phenotype specifically that is the one
i'm after
a lot of times people want to talk about
phenotypes and like what phenotype is
this what is this called
uh find the one that you like i i'm
telling you which one i like but i want
you to grow this and find the phenotype
that blows your mind
who cares if that girl makes me happy
she's in your garden find the girl that
makes
find that blueberry butcher that makes
you happy find the jack the ripper
phenotype that you love
find the one that is for you but that is
the phenotype i really love the
blueberry butcher
it's got the structure of the blueberry
cookies it's got the potency
uh the blueberry cookies is kinda it'll
put you down it'll make you think weird
but then the jack the ripper comes in
and adds to that and it just [ __ ]
lifts your head up it pulls the rug out
from underneath you and you're like
where are my keys
and you're like they're in your hand bro
you're like oh all right where do we
park and you're like you're parked bro
and it's one of those kind of things
i really love it so there's another
phenotype that is not as common but does
pop up
this one is purple it's the purple
butcher
um it's not as potent in my opinion it
doesn't have that psychedelia to it
it's more sedative it'll lay you the
[ __ ] down it finishes
super early it's a shorter plant it's a
squattier bushier plant
it's really easy to find early on in the
cycle when you see those big fat leaves
and the plant that doesn't grow tall the
others will take off on you they'll get
almost a fishing pole thing if you don't
have enough light they'll get tall
if it's short squatty and makes up at
the nodes
where the nodes meet the branch it has
like a little extra
i don't even know what to call it not
webbing but a little extra callous
looking spot somebody will tell me what
that technical term is now that i've
mentioned that i don't know what that's
called
it looks like instead of the branches
just coming out they've got a little
extra suction making them a little more
sturdy
a lot of those phenotypes will end up
being the shortier squat phenotype that
makes purple buds
those purple buds ah they smell like uh
lavender and lemons and those have that
chewable vitamin and dirty feet
and elderberries is it elderberries that
may be
there's an aroma that i'm thinking of an
older vitamin from the health food store
yeah dude it's elderberries
yep it's elderberries and something else
purple from the health food store
and those chewable [ __ ] vitamins
that's what it smells like i can taste
it and smell it in my mouth right now
ah lavender lilacs elderberries um
elderberry tea with honey in it yep
and flintstones vitamins that's a purple
phenotype so
those are the phenotypes there's the
blueberry cookies phenotype that tastes
like blue skittles it's got the whiter
leaves
uh it's kind of got that tahoe going on
uh there's the jackhair phenotype it's
hazy sandalwood skunk
that's gonna be a long finisher the jack
the ripper phenotype will be kind of a
quick finisher
not as long as that jack hair finisher
that's lemons and rotten fruit
then we got the blueberry butcher that
is the blue cookie structure with that
mango
the wango tango lemon lime red bull and
vitamin sort of flavor then there's that
purple one
which in my opinion isn't the desirable
phenotype but it will pop up
if you got the clientele that's into
purple this one will pay the bills for
you there
um all of the phenotypes i recommend you
top them you'll see where to top them
if you're not good at topping plants
this plant will tell you top me here
it'll make a nice bottom and the one
will just shoot up right out of the top
and you'll go that's the [ __ ] thing
that needs to come out
follow it down until it looks like you
got a nice even canopy and take that
[ __ ] right out of there clone that top
because they make beautiful clothes this
plant clones
very very easily some of it uh some of
its assets and features
attributes will give you a headache that
cloning part simple as [ __ ] it'll clone
so easily for you um
expect around 70 days finishing time
some people told me they went 82 days
some people said they did 65 and really
wish they had gone longer
so let it go 70 72 days check those
trichomes it is
all about the trichomes as a breeder i'm
going to say
some people went 82 days so
there are 80 day phenotypes in these
packs of seeds you guys i'm not going to
[ __ ] you
the blueberry butcher can go up to 82
days but
it puts out giant harvest weights people
were
bragging about how much they pulled off
their test plants
so the test plants were banging out
produce production
usable weight profitable weight also it
is
highly potent ah i said potent my voice
cut out there sorry let me take another
drink
all right who knows where i'm gonna edit
most of these phenotypes will put out
great
harvest weights and most of them will be
ridiculously potent
all of the photos you saw all the plants
were just coated in trichomes maybe i'll
scroll a couple photos through right
here
but they were all coated in resin they
all smelled amazing
super potent big fat harvest uh super
great bag of peel
and a beautiful name so that is the
blueberry butcher
i owe a big shout out to everybody
who tested seeds for me on this round if
you were testing any of the jack the
ripper crosses there was
jack the ripper to blueberry cookies if
you tested that you can name it
blueberry butcher that is what you can
write on the package on the jar on the
plants on the clones
those are blueberry butcher the
blueberry cookies female
cross two the jack the ripper male is
officially
blueberry butcher you heard it here
first on this podcast
i will say that again on my monday night
instagram live hey if you don't watch
the monday night instagram live join me
this monday on instagram every monday
approximately 7 10 mountain time that's
colorado time at 7 10 p.m in the
mountain time zone
i don't know where you are you could be
specific time you could be pacific time
you could be east coast time you could
be somewhere else in the [ __ ] world
ah you could be in china for all i know
where it's 14 hours ahead of me
you could watch from there check me out
on instagram irie underscore genetics
check out all the great photos
that the testers posted but on the
monday show i'm going to talk about this
strain i'm sure people will have
questions once they hear this
so blueberry butcher uh the next
question is going to be where do i get
blueberry butcher the first place you
can find blueberry butcher
is seeds here now.com use coupon code
gfyh10 that'll save you 10
off your full order there will be more
irie genetics dropping on 420
i'm going to release the jack the ripper
f2s
there will be at least two phenotypes
that i've approved for release they're
packaged up they're ready to go
it'll be number two and number four i
will explain the differences
on my website check out my website
iriegenetics.com those will drop on 420
there'll be a lot of other great stuff
dropping i feel like i really
got on a ramble check out the monday
show i'll check out the strain there
also check out seeds herenow.com that's
where they'll be available
and shout out to the testers we're back
on track now seeds here now.com will be
the first place to get them
make sure you check out the website
iregenetics.com there will be
full strain descriptions on the jack the
ripper f2s
full strain description on the blueberry
butcher if i do decide to release
anything else for a 420
it will be posted up there also details
on the sale
the drop and releases will be included
in my mailchimp newsletter how do you
get that you go to my website
iriegenetics.com
halfway down there's a spot that says
join the newsletter
type in your email address click enter
there that will send
you to my mailchimp and every time i
type a new newsletter
you'll get the newsletter you'll get a
notification an update of what's going
on
with the irie genetics world it could be
a new drop it could be a new strain
could be a giveaway could be a contest
who knows what's coming up in the summer
with irie genetics well that was a
mouthful
uh you guys had a lot to say on this
show this is a good time
check out the blueberry butcher at
seedshearnow.com shout out to my testers
just in case i went over that too
quickly
uh you guys this was a fun episode i
want your feedback if you're growing if
you do grow this one
send me some feedback send me updates
this was tested by a solid
test crew but a lot more seeds are going
to go out a lot more people are going to
be growing this
so we're going to get a lot more
discoveries don't be shy send me your
photos send me your feedback send me
your updates my email address is
grow from your heart at hotmail.com i'd
love to get some feedback on the jack
the ripper crosses
and anything you've grown from mine if
you've got pictures photos questions
concerns updates feedback
any of that stuff i'm open to all of it
grow from your heart at hotmail.com
what else do we got let's do this part
if you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
maybe you learned something maybe i
improved your garden over time
maybe i made you giggle maybe i'm just
keeping you company during quarantine
and keeping your sanity
maybe you'd like to contribute to the
show financially i do appreciate that
i like to make it easy all you have to
do is visit www.patreon.com forward
slash grow from your heart
all of the information you need is right
there on the screen once again
big thank you big shout out big fist
bump big salute
to everybody who supports the show on
patreon i do truly
appreciate all of that support uh there
is the website iriegenetics.com or all
things ire genetics
all things grow from your heart all
things rosta jeff are right there
on the website iriegenetics.com
you guys thank you you guys gals
binaries uh non-gender specific
everybody out there kittens
doggies uh dolphins whatever you
identify as
even the furries thank you guys for
hanging out this was a fun episode
hope you guys had as much fun as i did
you know i'll be back in a couple of
days with fresh new content i do look
forward to all the feedback
all the returns all the photos i want to
give a giant shout out to my buddy
grimble the druid and until next time
take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you