[Music]
yeah welcome back podcast world i'm your
host my friends call me rasta jeff
and this is episode 628 of the grow from
your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to read a
couple of patreon messages
before we get there let's do a few shout
outs to a few members of the 710 club
of course the 710 club are those folks
who support us on patreon
at the 7.10 a month level or higher
so with no further ado let's start off
with the big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out
to my good friend glenn jeroni let's
send a thank you shout out to carl w and
the candocrat
let's send a big thank you to gaiuty
grows and tyler filth
let's send a thank you shout out to
xavier and zack c let's send a big thank
you to grow meds for life
let's send a big thank you shout out to
my friend maverick let's send a big
thank you shout out to hash
slinging dabber and then let's wrap it
up with the big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out
to my friend buzzards bay buds
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon
if you are not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so
all you have to do is visit
forward www.patreon.com grow from your
heart all of the information you need
will be right there on the screen and of
course i did include a link
in the show notes and in the video
description to make it nice and easy
for all of my friends i haven't been
talking about what i'm dabbing at the
start of the show
but i am extra fast today i feel like
i'm going super fast i feel like i'm
kind of rambling so i'm going to mention
that i'm dabbing something called dirty
business
from green dot labs it's a sour diesel
and og cush cross
i don't have the jar here next to me to
give you the full details but i do know
i'm all [ __ ] up from it and it's
delicious and i enjoy it so you're gonna
have to deal with me going a little bit
fast and a little bit rambly in this
episode
big shout out to our friends at green
dot labs all right let's do some updates
in a previous episode i did talk about
auto watering uh when i did the auto
watering system i kind of looked over
overlooked a couple of details i forgot
to mention uh
auto pots and hemp buckets and sips
systems these are very affordable and
very simple ways
to auto water our plants they're gravity
fed you don't need any timers any
buttons any magic
it is gravity fed like i said before so
if you want an easier system that i
completely [ __ ] overlooked did not
think about until my kind friends
reminded me
uh do a little research on autopots the
auto pot system is great
you fill up one reservoir run some some
lines to other pots
they work on a uh it's gonna be i can't
even think of the word right now it's
like a capillary system it knows how
moist the medium is
and if it needs more water it gives it
more water if it doesn't
it turns it off the hempy buckets kind
of work on a similar method
uh these are what are known as sips
systems sub
irrigation uh planning systems i think
that's what it is sub
sub subterraneal irrigation you guys
obviously this is not my field of
expertise but
i had to remind you about it had to tell
you about it if you're looking to build
your
auto watering system looking for an
affordable route an affordable
alternative
something very easy to do something
gravity fed something very reliable
look into the hippie buckets the auto
pots something in that realm
a sips system is what you're looking for
all right that was my update on that
what else did i want to talk about you
guys i've been scrolling social media
uh when i'm chilling out trying to relax
a little bit i scroll just like you and
i've been seeing a lot of great things
on social media
i've also been seeing a lot of [ __ ]
one thing that drives me crazy is i see
a lot of grow rooms a lot of grow tents
a lot of grow environments
that simply are wasting a ton of space
if you've got a five by five grow tent i
would like to see at least four by four
worth of herb in there we don't need
three by three we don't need
one plant and a five by five one plant
over here one plant over here
let's put those right under the center
of the light get them as much light as
we can possibly get them
spoil those two plants or even better
let's fill the room
you guys a lot of places growing
cannabis is illegal
and you're growing and you're setting up
a five by five you're paying for
electricity
you're going in you're paying for the
lights you're paying for the electricity
you're losing
you're using your time your manpower
also
you're committing a crime if you're
gonna commit a [ __ ] felony go in
fill that [ __ ] room don't commit a
felony for a little couple of nugs
commit a [ __ ] felony for a rewarding
[ __ ]
prize at the end you guys so what i'm
saying is i see a five by five tent with
like one plant over here and one plant
over here
this shit's a disorganized chaotic mess
have a strategy have a plan
fill your 5x5 if you've got a 5x5 canopy
a 5x5 tent
i'd like to see a 5x5 canopy in there my
tents
when i unzip the tent it just busts out
it looks like a 70s bush busting out of
a bikini
it's ridiculous when i open the tent
that's what i like to see from you so
think about how to fill that tent
maximize your space
let's not get a five by five tent and
put three plants in there and have one
super tall one super short one not even
under the [ __ ] light
think about what you're doing you're
using the lights you're using the space
you're using the electricity
the soil all of that costs money time
energy and like i said before you're
possibly committing a crime
if you're gonna commit a crime make it
[ __ ] worth it felonies are not free
that's what we used to say don't do your
own felonies
for free for yourself either all right i
just wanted to say
fill your space if i gave you a cooler
and i was like here's a box it's three
feet by three feet by three feet
you can put as much weed in there as you
want are you gonna put two feet by two
feet worth of weight or are you gonna
put
[ __ ] three by three by three worth of
weed in that [ __ ] you're gonna fill it
up right
if i said fill it up with cookies or
beer or weed whatever you want you're
gonna stack that [ __ ] up you're not
gonna just stack the middle of it put a
couple over here a couple over here
that is not efficient i'm a commercial
cannabis cultivator i'm all about
efficiency productivity
uh and then also i'm a drummer so i'm
used to packing the car
uh if there's a space put some [ __ ] in
that space dude all right that's enough
ranting about space and wasted space in
your grow tents i see it a lot on social
media
it drives me crazy organize your tent
what the hell are you guys doing get in
there and clean that [ __ ] up if you're
gonna commit a crime
[ __ ] commit a crime all right that is
enough of the rambling intro part of the
podcast i do have a couple of messages
here that are going to get me
rambling on a focused subject i told you
guys those dabs are that
dirty business i think that's what it's
called dirty business that [ __ ] got me
high as [ __ ]
i'm talkative i'm rambly but that is
good for a podcast
this one comes from patreon before we go
too far on patreon let's give a shout
out to my buddy
st skinny and mama skinny for supporting
us on patreon
also for being long time cannabis and
patreon and grow from your heart
irie army supporters they've been on the
team for a long time been showing love
for a long time big shout out
to saint skinny and mama skinny mama
saint
however you want it to go this is how
the first question from patreon goes
this one says rosta jeff get your lab
coat then it says what are the chances
that an
industrial hemp farm would potentially
pollinate and
outdoor cannabis grow would it even
pollinate yes it's the same plant
technically in colorado the only
difference between cannabis and hemp
is a [ __ ] lab test if you got more
than .03 thc
your cannabis if you got less than that
it's hemp so it is the same plant
uh that is how we make strains of
different cannabinoid ratios is by
breeding
high thc to high cbd or other varieties
we just breed those together
then you come out with different ratios
different numbers of thc and cbd that is
how it's done how the breeding has
happened
uh but what are the chances of
industrial hemp potentially
potentially potentially that's my new
word what are the chances of industrial
hype potentially
uh pollinationaling uh let's see it
right now potentially pollinating an
outdoor cannabis grow
would it even cross-pollinate yes it
absolutely would it is the same plant
it is very possible it's very likely
unfortunately it's kind of common
back in the day we had agricultural
rules that you couldn't set up a farm of
a certain type within a certain amount
of kilometers
of another farm of that same type when
the cannabis industry came in
we started building hemp farms and
cannabis farms somebody forgot about
that guideline and that rule and we've
begun building
cannabis farms and grows and hemp grows
and hemp farms
right on top of each other and it is
happening i know of several people who
have lost
cannabis crops and who have had hemp
crops contaminated due to stray pollen
something that did happen last year that
messed up an entire outdoor hemp crop
is somebody's outdoor hemp crop was
pollinated early by a cannabis crop
their intention was to make outdoor
feminized hemp seed
that [ __ ] got destroyed by somebody
else's crop before that they're in
litigation now finding out
if there's something if that farmer who
pollinated on accident owes
the farmer who got pollinated something
so that [ __ ] does happen it's very
common it's very likely
there are things that people do to try
to prevent that there are different
kinds of trees and plants we can set up
as a barrier that will stop the pollen
so it does happen it happens often it's
very possible
and like i said before that's how we get
different types of either hemp or
different types of cannabis if you
pollinate that hemp
let's say you got some cbd that's got
like 20 or some hemp with like 20
cbd and cannabis with 20 thc when those
cross
you're gonna get wildly wildly varying
different cannabinoid ratios so
that's what we do to cross things it is
absolutely possible
same plant to cross pollinate that stuff
so
it will happen it will continue to
happen until people uh
learn the distancing rules this is why i
stress so much at outdoor season this is
why i tell people how important it is
to find those male plants and get them
out of your garden yeah it's cool that
you're getting the seeds out of
your garden you're not going to
pollinate your garden but what about
everybody in your neighborhood
that is growing cannabis outdoors
everybody for miles has potential to be
pollinated
that pollen can go i'm gonna guess two
or three miles without being disrupted
if you get that wind
blowing that pollen just right it can go
two or three miles or you got some birds
or some bees just like the pollinators
are supposed to do
they move pollen around quite far so
they land on your cannabis plants
they get pollen in their feathers or in
their bug fuzz i don't know what that
shit's called on a bug
uh they get on their little bug legs the
bug flies around
it goes to another cannabis plant it
just took that pollen to your from
another crop over to your crop it
pollinated your [ __ ]
that's why it's really really important
that we pay attention to getting male
plants
out of the outdoor garden as soon as
possible you're not only going to
potentially
potentially there that word is again
you're not only
potentially going to [ __ ] up your grow
but you could mess up every grow
for miles uh the custom of dealing with
that
in some states that have been growing
outdoor for quite a while if you
pollinate my crop
i come get your crop and then i may come
get your crop next year and can't do
[ __ ] about it because you don't [ __ ]
up my crop and that's how things work on
the hill
that's just ah how it goes that's grower
justice out on the hill there hill
justice
[ __ ] on my crop we're taking yours i got
bills to pay
you're not taking that my crop all right
that's just how it goes i'm gonna move
forward from that that one came from oh
you don't want your name said you are uh
you know who you are big shout out thank
you for all of the support
i just wrote down your name to give you
a shout out in a future episode
so uh thank you for the support bro
you're around a lot and i do appreciate
you
all right i'm high and [ __ ] rambly so
we're gonna keep on moving
um where does the next question go this
next question also came from
uh the email inbox from a long time
listener they do not want their name
said they would rather be called
used to be cool you've been around for a
while my friend you've been cool the
whole time
ah your name i'm just gonna call you
cool as [ __ ] my friend is cool as [ __ ]
cool as [ __ ] k
uh here is the message from cool as [ __ ]
k it says if you read this on your show
do not use my real name trust me bro i
will not
reveal your identity it goes a lot like
this it says rasta jeff that is me
it says as you are one of the top
cannabis breeders in the world
i don't know about that i will accept
that title if you want to give it to me
never tried to get that title didn't
know that was a thing
um let's hear some feedback on that
anyway i thought you would be the person
to ask about this issue
some time ago i had wanted to obtain bog
seeds blue
kush that's bushy old growers blue kush
but they were sold out
as that strain quite often is sold out
because that was a badass strain
it says i periodically checked for a
restock but then as you know
bushy old grower from bog seeds passed
away suddenly
making the possibility of getting bog
seeds very slim yes once bogg died
the prices off all of his seeds
increased astronomically
hopefully some of those proceeds are
going to miss his bog because she is
still around and we do need to support
and take care of a
a lovely lady who does not have her
husband around the head of household the
[ __ ] bread winner
so hopefully some of those markups and
auctions are going to mrs bogg but yes
those seeds are now hard to find
it says i decided to make one last check
a few weeks ago and
seeds here now.com had a few packs in
stock so i got a pack
yes our friends at seeds herenow.com i'm
going to interrupt myself and do a quick
apology disclaimer for seeds herenow.com
they did
a spring cleaning of their website when
they did the spring cleaning they
discovered a couple of tech issues it's
none of my business to air their
business but
they had some tech issues they were
rebuilding the website it took them
longer than expected and anticipated
they're getting their [ __ ] together if
by the time this episode comes out they
should have their [ __ ] together
i want to apologize for them what they
were doing was updating their system to
give you as a customer the most
streamlined experience you could
possibly have
so for a couple of days they were down
but it was to improve service
for you as the customer that's what the
idea was uh while they were doing that
they did an inventory and they
discovered a lot of packs that
were in inventory that were not on the
website some things were on a vault some
things were on a stash
some things got discovered those have
been put on the inventory at seeds here
now
so if there's some [ __ ] you've been
looking for uh that you thought you
might have missed like our friend i used
to be cool here found some bog seeds
there was some thug pug stuff that went
up there's a lot of great [ __ ] so
if you've been trying to look at seeds
here now.com and you've been getting an
error message or something is wrong with
the website
be patient check again now if it's not
back now keep being patient i try
promise you you can trust me it will be
worth your time just coming back
checking it out give us another shot
give them another shot
everything they did was to improve the
service for
you on your shopping end on your
receiving end
make it better for you as the consumer
all right that's
the disclaimer for seeds here now i
covered two things check them out again
they did some website updates also
restocks on a lot of old gear that was
sold out now i'm gonna get myself back
here
into this message it says it made me
think about making
blue cush seeds to preserve it for my
future use isn't that amazing when
you've got some seeds and you love them
so much they're like i've got to
preserve this how do i do this again how
do i make more
that's what turns growers into breeders
that's where it all starts
so it says however i realized i'm
ignorant about making seeds he goes on
to say i don't mean that i don't know
that a male plant pollinates a female
plant but since i've got
limited space i'm going to need to
return my pollinated female to my flower
tent so
our friend has a basic understanding of
breeding he knows that a male and a
female makes seeds
he's got the basic idea he knows he's
going to make f2 seeds
the dilemma that our friend used to be
cool is running into here
is once they pollinate this plant it
will need to be returned
to the flowering room so that it can
continue to flower there's only one
flower room
he doesn't want to want to pollinate the
entire grow because he does need some
usable medicine
so um there are a couple things about
this but i'm going to continue with the
message
my questions are how long does it take
for pollen to impregnate a female
and if the pollen is immediately
accepted by the female can i then spray
that said female
with water to kill any remaining pollen
and safely place her back into the
end of the flowering tent also
if you think i would benefit from any
other information
uh to help advance my plan i would
appreciate the input we're gonna give
you some guidance and information here
in just a moment
uh it says i know you've been very busy
and swamped with questions uh
of course i love getting back to you bro
never feel stressed about that
i've had these seeds for several months
but because of unforeseen circumstances
my schedule was delayed everybody's
behind schedule my grow is off schedule
don't worry about that then it says uh
thank you for all you do for the
community bro you are very welcome thank
you for the
continued feedback and support then they
wrap it up with used to be cool
let's talk about your breeding questions
you've got
you've obviously got a male plant
somewhere that's producing pollen i want
to know where that male plant is
because if it's not in your main
flowering space you've got it somewhere
in a 1212 cycle producing pollen
what i would do in an ideal world is i
would put
that female plant i would get it into
flower i would move it in there with
that male plant
i would leave it in there for just a day
you know just put it in there knock it
uh let that male plant dust it real good
let that pollen
be accepted then i would just leave it
in that room
or i would put it in a veg room
ideally you would pollinate this plant
and give it two to three days maybe five
to seven days at the most
just to make sure that it's impregnated
well then
i would move that plant back into a veg
room
that plants already got pollen all of
the bud sites that are going to receive
pollen have been pollinated
the magic has been done we're no longer
looking to make flowers or buds now
we're focused on making seeds
if you move that plant back into a veg
room under 186
it will continue to produce those seeds
it's been impregnated
its whole goal now is to finish those
seeds those seeds will keep going
so if you have a veg room you can move
that plant
into the veg area or leave it in that
room
where you just pollinated where that
male plant is and put that light on
the veg cycle i don't know if you've got
that extra room so that's just my main
idea i would put it back into the
vegetative room
the plants in the veg room can't get
pollinated the seeds will
mature more quickly in a vegetative room
because they're getting more photons
more light energy
and again we're not focused on flowers
so the plant that you have pollinated
will continue to produce those seeds at
the same time it will
reveg so you're going to have that plant
will be seeded
filled with viable seeds and it will
begin to make clones
that you can cut off of there to make
another mother plant to again
preserve that original mother so i
if you have the room i would put it into
a vegetative space
let me read because there was something
that got my attention here
and i thought of an idea that i wanted
to read to tell you
um yeah i think you've got the right
idea i can't think of what the part that
left my head was but i would just put it
back into the vegetative
space or um pollinate it
leave it in that flower room for a
couple of days you can leave it in there
for
in the dark if you need to after it
receives the pollen it can sit in that
dark space
for like 24 48 hours in the dark it
won't make a difference it won't get too
angry
then take that plant out of there spray
that plant down with water because the
pollen at this point has been received
spray yourself down with water spray the
other girls down with water
then you can put it back in that room
but i'm not going to guarantee that you
have killed
all of the pollen there still could be
viable pollen on that plant
that could get into that room you may
make minimal seeds but if you do
what's wrong with that is this your
personal crop maybe you get
uh maybe you got like four other strains
in there maybe the uh bog strain the
blue kush
is loaded with seeds maybe the red kush
the purple kush and the i'm gonna just
guess raphael
in there maybe maybe those all get
dusted with a couple of flecks of pollen
now maybe you've got four or five seeds
of all of those also
across to the blue kush maybe that's
what you did on accident maybe that's
not a bad idea maybe that's not a bad
deal
maybe you do want all those seedless but
that's going to be the worst case
scenario
the thing that left my brain it just
came back as i paused so
i'm going to talk about that another
thing you could really do that i as a
breeder
who i run seeded crops most of the time
in my grow spaces but i also like to do
a non-seeded crop so we got
a test run of new stuff that way mike
and i have something to [ __ ] smoke on
that's not seeded up we could try new
stuff
i can write strain reports i can select
phenotypes and keepers and move forward
projects
but i stagger my grows to where
these are so far into flower that they
can't receive pollen and these are so
early into flower that they can't
receive pollen
but my target plant is right at the
right time so i've got one crop that's
going to get seeded and one crop that's
almost done
and then another crop that's about to go
in flowers so it's just all about timing
at that point
stagger them to where one is too far
ahead one is too early
that may help you out i know you've
probably got one room
you probably got a flowering room maybe
you got a veg room uh
but um i'm confused on what you've got
because you've got another space with a
male plant that's in flower
you've got to have another space with
that boy that's in flower because if the
boy is in with the girls all your girls
are going to get seated
so i'm assuming there's a boy space
somewhere get that boy go in
get him you could put the girl right in
there with that boy the whole time you
can let them share space
or you could put that girl in there when
the pollination time is perfect
but just sacrifice that space once
you've cut down the mail cleaned them up
you can leave that girl in there for a
little while
until you feel like that pollen has been
absorbed i'd say just a few days
uh two to three days at the most five to
seven days
it's pregnant like a few seconds after
you pollinate it but
um leave it in that other space and then
move it to the veg room
under 18 6 or then move it back to the
other flower room but
treat it with water maybe treat it with
water a couple of times you know let it
receive the pollen let it sleep for a
couple of days hit it with water
uh let the lights [ __ ] cycle hit it
with water again move it back into the
other room hit those [ __ ] in that
room with water
spray yourself down also because that
pollen's gonna get everywhere
i feel like i've given you the right
idea either put the plant
in the space where the male was after
you pollinate it put the plant in the
veg space after you pollinate it or very
carefully spray everything down
and put it back into that flower room
your other option is to stagger
your crops which i know is kind of a
pain in the ass we all want to make as
much as we can you want to fill that
room like i just said
but sometimes you got to make a little
space just for that one pollinated
pregnant girl
the pregnant girls are always special
you got to treat them special give them
their own space
do special things special arrangements
for them
all right my buddy used to be cool i
hope i uh thoroughly successfully and
efficiently answered your question
if you've got a follow up don't be shy
you know how to reach me my email
address is
grow from your heart at hotmail.com
alright ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls pimps and hoes friends and foes
smokers growers clone cutters pollen
chuckers skateboarders
fruit booters playing pilots at
helicopter
commandos i don't know what the [ __ ] i'm
even saying anymore you guys those dabs
were
highly effective and i had a good time
on this podcast i want to thank you
again for listening to another episode
of the grow from your heart podcast if
you feel like this episode
was educational informative entertaining
maybe i improved your garden maybe i
taught you something
maybe you had a couple of laughs maybe
you'd like to support the show
financially all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need is right
there on the screen of course there is a
link in the show notes
or the video description to make it nice
and easy all you got to do is click on
it that'll get you right where
you need to be also make sure you check
us out on youtube go to the youtube
channel
subscribe to the grow from your heart
podcast on youtube that's right click
subscribe that way every time i put out
a new episode you will get a
notification there's a little bell right
there on the screen click on that bell
that will tell you hey there's a brand
new episode you can give it a listen
never miss a show also click
like on the videos click like that helps
us out that puts me in the algorithm
more more people see the videos the more
people that see the videos
the more subscribers we get the more
subscribers the more people growing
better cannabis that means when you go
out in public you go to a concert
wherever you go
chances are that herb that somebody's
smoking next to you may be just a little
bit better because maybe
they're listening to the grow from your
heart podcast i've said it once before
and i'll say it again
if you've got any questions corrections
comments or concerns my email address is
grow from your heart at hotmail.com
you know i would love to hear from you
don't forget to check out my website
ireegenetics.com all things ire genetics
all things grow from your heart all
things rosta jeffer right there at
iregenetics.com
don't forget to sign up for the
newsletter uh there will be some new
coupon codes and things coming up for
april
don't miss the 420 show that's right the
next episode should be the 420 show i've
got some cool plans
for 420 and 421 stay tuned i'm excited
to present
those shows to you all right ladies and
gentlemen boys and girls
that is enough for this episode i hope
you had as much fun listening as i did
recording this episode
i'll be back in a couple of days with
the 420 episode i want to give a giant
shout out to my friend
ou812 and until next time take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
was