[Music]
yeah welcome back podcast world
i'm your host my friends call me rosta
jeff and this is episode 630
of the grow from your heart podcast this
is the special 420 celebration episode
happy 4
20. this episode comes out on april 19th
i hope you are ready to celebrate
on 4 20 with us for my 4 20 celebration
this year i invited a bunch of friends
to join me on a zoom
meeting i had about 25 friends show up
big shout out to everybody that joined
us
we talked about cannabis we talked about
the cannabis industry we talked a little
[ __ ] i edited some of it out
i left a little bit of it in i hope you
guys enjoy it i don't want to make a
really long intro because the show is
really really long
so with no further ado here is the 420
celebration episode
of the grow from your heart podcast
really quickly welcome to the 420 show
thanks everybody that showed up some
will come some will go more will show up
i'm going to quickly try to do intros uh
now i feel dirt man dan's pain getting
through intros on like 12 screens it's
gonna be a fun adventure here but
i see dirt man dan looking at me uh
durban dan really quickly can you tell
us
where you're located and how we can
stalk you on social media
all right so i'm dirt man dan i'm over
here on the east coast
um you can find me on social media at
dirtman van or
embracing organics uh on instagram right
all right all right yeah thank you for
joining me bro it's fun being on
embracing organics uh you inspired
this madness here so this is all your
fault uh let's follow that up
by introducing the first dreadlock that
showed up to the party uh it's welcome
my buddy steve also known as
potentponics uh where are you joining us
from steve and how can people stalk you
on social media
sure i'm joining you guys from oklahoma
this week i travel around quite a bit
and you can find me at either ap
mjclast.com or growingwithfish's podcast
on your favorite podcast app we have
that on all the
uh different separate platforms that are
out there
you know so whatever you use check it
out check them out i highly endorse the
potent ponix podcast also fully endorsed
that embracing organics podcast
another fellow podcaster on the panel
who's lighting up a fatty over there
a new friend of mine uh known as
sequence from the michigan
bros grow show that's a mouthful welcome
to the show brother you want to tell
everybody where you're joining us from
and how they can stop you tonight
yeah i'm joining from michigan and yeah
we didn't intend on the podcast getting
big enough that people would have to say
the name
major oversight on our part but yeah you
can find us at michigan bros grow show
on youtube
and uh my own instagram doesn't really
matter that much thank you for having me
jeff appreciate it very
much thanks for joining us bro thank you
for being here for the 420 show i'm
gonna keep moving down the line in
the direction i've got it i want to
welcome my buddy genetic memory farms
uh you might be quiet but welcome to the
show bro oh thanks jeff
thanks i appreciate you having us uh all
of us here from the neighborhood just
stopping in so
uh yeah i really appreciate you making a
platform for the community man thank you
very very much and appreciate you having
us
thank you bro where are you coming in
from tonight oh uh
i'm locking down the midwest i'm from
illinois so i'm one of the weirdos here
in the midwest kind of the third coast
so you know if anybody if i can be
helpful to anybody with food play i'm
i'm in a food
industry by you know trade so my kind of
thing is food science anybody's got any
questions hit me up on ig
genetic memory farms there we go thanks
for joining us brother
i'm going to keep moving to my right uh
a fellow podcaster who i see on
everybody's show i want to welcome my
buddy raptor to the
to the show raptor where are you joining
us from how do we stalk you bro
uh hey how's it going everyone thank you
so much for inviting me jeff
i am from southern california uh i've
been growing for
almost four years just about now and
yeah just
kind of delved into it and once i
started learning
got into more
[Music]
i wanted to major in it so that's where
i am now uh getting all into that right
in the middle
of all my schooling too uh just like
jeff mentioned uh i'm on uh
you can see me here and there on a
couple podcasts but yeah
uh mainly i'm helping out p uh operation
grow along with schwoo
and having a good time saturdays 1 pm
pacific standard time
uh yeah you could also find them youtube
operation girl we go live there
and we'll actually uh be doing a
collaborative effort
with the neighborhood i uh really
excited for that we're gonna have a 420
special probably you're all going to be
seeing that hopefully when this
record recording is available so yeah
you could find us at the neighborhood
grows at instagram and
at youtube awesome bro thank you for
joining us
oh and you can uh find me specifically
raptorgrow all one word
instagram perfect he's got the little
raptor is a logo
i want to ask about that but there's too
many people to talk to right now we'll
move on uh i think who i have next i got
cuz up next on the list cuz
thank you for joining me bro where are
you coming from and how can we stalk you
on the social media
cheers thanks for having me uh coming in
from the west coast of canada
might be one of the oh no we got a
couple other canadians on here today
yeah
um my name's because i love it yeah you
can find me on youtube and instagram
i'm also involved in the neighborhood
grows you'll find me there also with
youtube and instagram
and the grow 4 show which is a canadian
based uh trying to help
small uh canadian legal growers with
their four plants
uh you'll find me there as well thanks
for teaching people bro thank you
for sure i gotta keep these intros going
because more people are popping in as i
do intros we're never gonna get through
these
uh so i'm gonna move right over to my
buddy duckweed duck where are you coming
in from bro and how can we stalk you on
social media
uh cheers everyone i am uh i'm duckweed
i'm
coming all the way from [ __ ]
caribbean a little island called
trinidad and tobago we just kind of
decriminalized and in the whole process
of doing [ __ ]
just about a little over a year now um
so yeah looking forward to this cool
hangout with uh
all you crazy stunners um again thanks
jeff for putting this together and
inviting us all
you can find me at uh nuts and guts 868
on instagram
and uh other than that uh same like
raptor mentioned and a couple other guys
would mention
uh the neighborhood guru show um also
the operation go show
so yeah peace love and respect thank you
bro thanks for joining us all the way
from over there staying up late to hang
out
that's so good uh let's move on to one
of my
favorite partners in crime a guy that's
been on my podcast quite a few times a
familiar face to everybody
uh mike thanks for joining us bro you
want to tell everybody where you're
joining from
and maybe you might want to let them
know how to stock you on the social
media
uh joining from big bad pueblo colorado
um just like always
and uh if you want to stalk me on social
media check me out at twitter you can
find me at nemopunk15
or on facebook at pueblo for sensible
cannabis laws
excellent thanks for being quick bro uh
now let's
move over to somebody who i've been
doing a lot of fun stuff with the guy
that runs cannabis the guy responsible
for a big part of the cannabis community
i think we all know where to find him
but we'll give him a chance to introduce
himself to you want to tell us where
you're coming in from
and give us a little bit of info about
cannabis
hey everyone uh thanks so much jeff for
inviting me um
i really appreciate it and shout out to
white mike as a listener of the show
it's cool
in the same zoom as this uh the wonder
twins or whatever
you want to call them um but uh yeah
anyways i'm uh q grows you can find me
on instagram
as well as cannabis i co-founded
cannabis
with jrtoken who you may know from the
do gross crew and many other
uh things and uh yeah cannabis
is a cannabis social network and
cannabis community of over 115 000
people
many of them are on this zoom and
elsewhere so i just want to shout out to
you all and appreciate you all i hope
you all have a great 4 20.
thank you bro thank you i got to keep
going on these intros because i'm never
going to get caught up there are 20
people in here now i think i'm a quarter
of the way through here
uh so thanks for joining me queue sorry
to be so quick stabby now is your time
to shine brother would you like to tell
people
where you're coming in from and how you
can be stocked on the social media
uh usually i'm trying not to be found
but if you do want to hear me
rant and rave about like uh red worms or
just organic growing in general there's
a couple years worth of that on
the embracing organics channel and
recently i've been uh
you muted yourself i didn't do it that
was that was me fat finger sorry about
that but on
recently i've been uh honored to be a
guest on the michigan girls bro show
uh just works out a little bit better
for my schedule you know i got a family
life got a
full-time job and all that and uh
sometimes i'll pop up on can buzz with
updates
usually i keep it pretty low-key though
it's good to hear from you uh it's good
to know that you're over there on the
michigan bro
bros grow show uh plenty of podcasting
for everybody i'll have to go check it
out more often it is
everything you're involved if you're
looking for me get that a lot if you're
trying to find me
i'm on the uh irie army discord oh yes
everybody into the in the discord half
the people here i think are on that
discord so thank you for mentioning that
it's it we built a great community over
there and
huge shout out to graybeard he deserves
all the credit in the world he puts in
so much work over there
he's such a good dude super chill and
like daily there are just people in
there hanging chilling
talking grow talking all i mean we get
crazy in there sometimes it's pretty
cool
uh just out there conversations man like
with like-minded individuals it's it's
really good it's a good community
yeah i have to close the app at night
because i just go bleep because you guys
are just always yeah you got to modify
your notes
sometimes i like it yeah all right savvy
thank you bro we're going to move on
we'll talk more about discord tomato but
i got about 10 more people to get
through and then we're going to turn
this party into a smoke sesh
uh let's move up more toward canada and
introduce my buddy a fellow grower mr
schwabydubydu
thank you for joining us bro you want to
tell people how to stalk you and let us
know where you're coming from
i'm coming from ontario canada you can
stalk me on instagram at truevideo and
on
youtube the girlfriend show and
operation growth
awesome thank you brother you're doing a
great job on all those breeding projects
i love seeing your progress
keep the picks coming for sure
i know i'm excited then we get to grow
it i love that quick introduction there
uh who's next on my list i've got a good
friend a good supporter of the irie army
a member of the discord
a big contributor to the can of buzz my
buddy dave's not here is here and he's
even showing his face
welcome brother uh do you want to tell
people how to stalk you and also uh
let them know where you're coming in
from well i'm
coming in from uh new york fresh and
legal now uh congrats bro
that's a beautiful thing uh you can find
me on instagram dave underscores not
here spelled with a z like you see on
the screen
uh it's a pleasure to be here and you'll
see me on the neighborhood grow show and
there you go thanks for having me thank
you bro thanks for keeping it quick
perfect
uh then let's move over to another
member of the neighborhood another huge
contributing factor of the ire army a
guy that i call the ridge
if you join us on youtube and you see
somebody moderating people if you got
kicked out of the youtube chat
it was this guy that did it let's
welcome my buddy perk to the show
welcome perp you want to let us know
uh where you're coming from and how we
can stalk you on the social media
yeah uh first thank you um uh
i'm also coming from new york newly
legal uh
so that's a great thing and uh you can
find me on instagram
it's a purple thumb og and i am part of
the
neighborhood grows community and i
uh you'll be seeing more of me uh with
my other friends so
keep it going that's about it thank you
bro thanks for being brief we're gonna
talk here in just a minute i got i think
six more to go through so uh let's move
it right on through and go
to more of my canadian friends let's
pick up my buddy shipwreck for a minute
uh shippy you want to tell us how we can
find you on social media and let us know
what part of canadia you're coming in
from
yeah what's up everyone good to see all
the spam in one split one place
um i'm not too far away from schwub uh
southern ontario and you can find me on
instagram
uh shipwreck underscore 420 or on the
neighborhood groves
awesome bro thanks for joining us man
it's always a pleasure to hear your
sweet canadian voice
that's what i expected from a canadian
aw shucks all right we're going to
switch it up now now we're moving over
to i think
oklahoma uh we're going to go talk to
somebody who's been on the show before a
repeat offender
a good friend of mine a fellow grower of
what but never mind we're just gonna
introduce them jesse welcome to the show
bro you want to tell people how to find
you
and where you're located hey can can you
hear me
yes we can brother look good sound good
okay hey hey
yeah here in uh moore oklahoma what's up
uh
uh long time listener first time caller
looking good in the irony too yeah yeah
yeah
you like that i i'm here with my home
with carlos maxie weed
what's up mexican good just happy 420
cheers cheers from mexico mexico
hi everyone happy 420
[Applause]
bro uh jessie grows on instagram
um and that's pretty much how you find
me uh also maybe wet mount creations but
uh maybe you can find carlos here uh
mexiweed yeah basically on instagram
youtube facebook you can find me next to
it you will find this logo
excellent give them both a follow you
guys great growers good guys to follow
thank you for joining us i gotta keep
moving i think i got four more people to
get through and less more pop in we're
making some segments some headway here
i got a new friend here on the screen
somebody i've never met face to face but
a long time supporter of the highway
army
rocking the highway gear putting a smile
on my face looks like somebody that
honestly would have just been in my crew
i'm not one to judge a book by its cover
but me and this guy definitely would
have rode around in the band together
cause some [ __ ] trouble i want to
welcome i believe red eye jedi grows to
the show
uh brother you want to let us know where
you're coming in from and tell us how we
can stalk you on that social media
hello everybody it's great to be here
happy 4 20 um
you can find me on instagram at red eye
jedi girls
i pop into the neighborhood every once
in a while just hang out with everybody
um just happy to be here i'm happy to
hang out with
all you people and happy 420 everybody
what's going on 420 brother hell yeah
let's get baked you guys don't be afraid
to smoke on screen everybody should have
clouds in their room by now
this is the 420 show it will come out on
4 19 but you know this is the 420 show
so definitely put those clouds in the
air
uh quick quick note there when i was in
high school i wanted my band to be
called
red eye jedi that was really a dream of
mine nobody else agreed
i should have done it anyway let's keep
it moving i've got a good friend here
that i've met in the neighborhood he's
been a longtime supporter uh he goes by
a lot of names today we're going to call
him ganja grow up
ganja you want to let us know how we can
stock you on the socials and where
you're coming in from today
cheers happy 420 rasta jeff uh just a
grower in boston
uh you can find me around the
neighborhood uh and
most of all the canada uh you know all
the kind of content on youtube and
wherever just discord it's great stuff
thank you very much thank you for
joining us bro you go by a different
name
on all of the chats and youtube you're a
different name a lot of the other stuff
you're a different name
do you want to let them know that or do
you want to keep that secret so then
they know who they're actually talking
to
right yeah i know i kind of keep it a
little distant just because uh
i just want to know if you want them to
know who's trolling the [ __ ] out of them
or not
i usually keep it simple though don't i
i love it i love it
you're only here because i love you
that's it now i'm wondering if i know
who you are
oh you do you do all right let's dig out
of this hole real quick and move right
on over to
the captain and commander of the irie
army one of the honestly the longest
supporters
of ire genetics the grow from your heart
podcast not only a supporter this dude's
become my friend we email back and forth
we
talk he's a good dude he's an educator
he's my friend i've said his name before
uh welcome to the show my buddy lemur
priest thank you for joining us bro
hey thanks for having me it's cool to
see everyone here
happy 420. um happy 420 dude
yeah oh it's it's cool to see everyone
um yeah it's been
it's been a while um since
i found the podcast and hurry genetics
and
yeah i've been loving it smoking on
summer eyes actually for 420 yeah
beautiful i appreciate that you grow my
genetics so well stinky
and gross and it's it's like
gross in all the right ways yeah i love
it i love it
would you show off the tattoo if i asked
you or is that too much for the show
of course oh perk's got a tattoo too we
overlooked that i apologize for
uh yeah check out that tattoo you guys
that was the first ivory genetics tattoo
i ever saw
burp if you want to flash yours too go
for it but i'm not sure exactly where
yours is
this could be yeah all right
yeah it's on his instagram is where it
is give him a follow-up yeah
thanks for getting naked for us lemur
yeah anytime yeah there you go
put it up yeah
i did it myself so you know that's i
can't i couldn't do that
yeah i'm asking dudes to undress on my
show we gotta get the views somehow you
guys
listen man it looks like a fly right now
but when i get all riled up i swear
it's the irie army logo
number is i reached out fans.com
that's irie jeff at onlyfans.com
don't tell anybody about that it's it's
rasta dread the only fantasy
we got one more intro to do and then we
can turn turn loose this circus here
uh i made a new friend on the hood he's
been following me for a little while i'm
now following him too really cool dude
a fellow seed nerd uh maybe different
kinds of seeds sometimes but seed nerds
are seed nerds i know the feeling you
know the struggle
i want to welcome to the show my friend
the foraging gardener welcome foraging
thank you sarah glad to be here happy
420 everybody happy yeah
yes you are but i'm also a cannabis
connoisseur obviously
yes yes they're packing up seeds when at
the same time as me just trying to
order that's what they do in the
neighborhood every night so that's what
i'm doing in the background if i'm not
on camera i usually
i need vegetable seeds i'm going to hit
you up yeah you see it
it's different there we go all right
business has happened and i like it bro
where are you chiming in from and how
can my friends follow you here on social
media i'm in the midwest i'm still in
prohibition land
all right the midwest is a
decriminalized land
that's right where we got no vegetable
seeds though
what's that yeah what we got in the
vegetable seeds oh bellaseats.com
oh [ __ ] yeah there you go good move good
move duck thank you all right thank you
for joining us by the way everybody
thank you for uh being patient with
getting through 20 intros that's
amazingly impressive nobody talked over
anybody we all got through that
uh happy 420 welcome to the show um i
don't even know where to begin
uh i guess we can do this and we'll
start the conversation here
does anybody know what 420 actually came
from does everybody in this room
have any idea why we celebrate 420 what
this is all about are we just smoking
because we're smoking from the storyline
students thing yeah okay all right so i
know i i think i know a little bit about
it it was some college students in
california that would uh
smoke i believe it was at 4 20 after a
certain class right
i could be yeah i think they were
getting out of school got out of school
about four and they'd all meet it
at a place at a certain stature i
believe it was at 4 20.
yeah i heard it was like some college
kids in norcal [ __ ]
like grateful dead kids i'm pretty sure
some of them were deadheads yeah i'm
pretty sure a couple of them were
deadheads
i was a group they called themselves the
waldos is actually what the group was
called
and so most of the story is basically
yeah they would just meet every day at
this one spot and
smoke at 420 and that's where 420 came
from so we owe
this holiday this meeting this podcast
is all because of a bunch of dorks that
wanted to gather after school and smoke
some weed together
and they made a time 4 20 and it stuck
imagine starting a legend that big
or like a piece of folklore you know
that's a crazy thing that's like
inventing the words
yeah that will live on forever too every
stoner
imagine the first time they heard that
from someone else like oh hey man like
420 you know and then like
dude i swear i made that up yeah you
know
you did yeah are they saying our thing
bro are they doing our thing
yeah and then they saw stickers of it
and shirts and now there's
420 pipe cleaner and 420 stores and the
mile marker 420 sign gets stolen
everywhere we don't have a mile marker
420 in colorado
we have 419.99 because they'll steal the
420 every time
unfortunately we don't have that amount
of miles yeah
so we don't even get the 4.25
allegedly i would trade you something
for it mike you tried to say something
and your mic did not sound loud enough
buddy
i don't even remember what it was at
this point
thank you for joining us for the brief
moment it was great to meet you on
camera good to see you i look forward to
hanging out in the
bunch of stuff we're going to future so
happy 420 bro
happy 420 man we'll see you next time
brother raptor what's in the box i'm
taking a puff
yeah the waldos were high school kids
yeah san rafael high school i believe
was the rumored
location i knew san rafael was the the
place but i didn't know if it was a
college or high school
raptor go ahead and totally interrupted
you oh no worries i actually wanted to
hear that too but uh yeah i got some uh
strawberry starburst let's see
when was this harvest january 21st 2020
so
what a way to bring in that year and uh
actually
uh super delicious i love it just uh
like a strawberry candy like it's so
well i
i really enjoy it and i actually um i
don't personally
uh come bust i use a vaporizer i happen
to use a
underdog vapes this just lines up with
this
and my bong so yeah i'm able to enjoy
all the flavor like all the flavor it's
delicious i
i i've really been enjoying it through
the whole year and i've just had like a
nice little stash
like right there that's the way to do it
are you self-sufficient
can you keep yourself supplied oh yeah
like
uh i just said that was from january of
last year so yeah that's pretty
impressive
i'm doing i do not i do not have product
from january
i don't have a product from january of
this year
because i made a point to save it that
long-term
do you think it's better after a really
long cure and storage like that
no i just didn't want to smoke it all
okay
right right i agree he's got to be
conservative he doesn't have a very
large grow
that's true that's true that little
cubicle doesn't put out
too many pounds
san rafael high school in marin county
which is north of san francisco on the
other side of the golden gate bridge
that's a lot of details but that's where
420 came from
because they met by the wall yeah yeah i
read the wicked
high times well no i remember high times
doing a whole story about it
uh and reading this many times yeah i
read that too actually
really do you remember where you first
heard about 420 or was it in high time
or was it somebody in
high school yeah high school no doubt
uh
the actual the guy that introduced the
actual number 420 to me has actually
passed away now so shout out to my buddy
james richie he's no longer with us he
was an amazing artist
uh really obnoxious outspoken dude an
amazing bass player
but he was the first one that i ever
heard say 420 and i was like what the
[ __ ] 4 20.
and in the context it was said i knew
what it meant but i didn't know i didn't
know 420 yet
in mexico is the same 420 it's like the
same like a big high school basically
they're talking about the portrait thing
so he's like oh it's that small critics
like stoner thing
yeah that's really cool cultural crosses
borders i love it
420 worldwide i'm gonna puff to that one
cheers
damn i gotta bust up my pipe now you
even own flower jeff
because i have a bowl that matches that
and i broke it
uh shortly before he passed away i was
going to get in contact with him
because uh he had the guy make a
matching set and i was gonna have it
repaired
and now i don't even know how to contact
that dude oh man well if that person's
watching contact myself or stabby so we
could get that pipe repaired because
they could be watching you never know
i have one people get repaired by
someone else that's [ __ ] sweet
yeah somebody else can fix it yeah i'm i
mean i'm not going to throw it away ever
i'll find someone eventually but i was
just hoping to have the original artist
do it we're gonna have to get sequence
some new lungs over there for 4 20.
my whole body is sweating i was like
forget that
that's the second time i've done that
but i decided i was gonna say that was a
that was watching that that was huge
yeah i wouldn't push it 100 degrees
because i
figured it was really big it would cool
it off did not work
that's awesome impressive rip bro next
time i'll try to put you up on the big
screen if i remember before i see it
coming
yeah speaking of dab presses i recently
got a low temp setup and man
i love it i'm in love i may have to try
some more rosin because all my friends
are making raw
squishing all day and i'm just not a fan
of most of what i smoke when it comes to
rosin but
just have to figure uh figure out how to
do that correctly that looks good
you know i have a sequence i have not as
soon as dan tells us
what he's smoking we're going to talk
about that because that thing's
interesting pink lemonade ambrosia from
apothecary farms i recognize those
ladies
yes sir i'm not even gonna ask how
why when and where because i know where
you are my friend that's magical i'm
proud of you
all right let's focus oh look cuz that's
some crack over there
some good clear looking concentrates bro
thank you this is uh some durbin poison
live resin
nice very it's delicious
it's still magically delicious all right
let's talk about that little uh
little thermometer thing you've got over
there i've seen a lot of people with
that i'm gonna put you up here on the
main screen
what happened oh we got cuz up there we
go the turpa meter there we go
they're like a hundred bucks and it
tells the temperature
using a thermocoupler yeah mold it for
the camera
and it's really really probably the best
way
to tell the temperature for uh a banger
you can't use it for like a slurper but
phenomenal right
so basically heat up your banger stick
it right on in there and wait till it
gets the temperature that you're
comfortable with and then rip it
yeah it'll rise up until it like settles
and then once it starts dropping in temp
you know
yeah yeah that's cool at a steady temp
so i try to dab anywhere between four
and five hundred usually
all right this is to read uh
are you getting 70 degrees off of an ir
thermometer and it stays at the same
temperature the whole dab
yeah an email is really nice and you you
can use this to calibrate your email as
well
oh that's pretty sweet we did that at my
buddy's house so we could put it on the
email and adjusted the email accordingly
it's a great idea
yeah that's awesome i like an email but
uh for some reason i
it just doesn't it's not hot enough to
i've got to heat up my bang or any way
to clean it or something it just doesn't
it's not efficient for me i love having
it around it'd be good right now
if i had a center i would hit the email
so i didn't have to have the torch going
but for the most part i prefer just
torching it up and
doing it that way but that's a beautiful
setup you got cuz the mothership
yeah it's another cord on the table for
a podcaster that's a whole nother thing
that's true i see arguments i've owned
an email as well
many rigs perished to the uh the old
email cord
i've seen it pull a joint right off
before yeah i've seen last killers for
sure
but to each their own that's why they
make a lot of different toys and that's
why potheads buy them because we love
toys and it's a lot of good clean fun
um since nobody asked i'm dabbing on
picasso
uh live batter from green dot it's got
me talkative it's got me a little heavy
eyed and droopy eyed
i'm digging this guitar took one fat dab
out of this container it's working
pretty good for me
working pretty good so this is the 420
episode we've been talking about what
you guys are smoking on
uh this is the pre-420 episode we're in
a weird uh
i don't even want to say the word a
weird pandemic situation still it's kind
of ending people are getting medicines
and [ __ ]
but what are we doing for 420s anybody
got any fun plans or anything we going
out we stand in having a party
lockdown yeah exactly yeah i thought
i would have gone to the beach but like
we just got
17 new cases yesterday and then 85 today
so we're back into like a kind of semi
lockdown
uh no beaches no nothing no gathering
more than five
that kind of [ __ ] so [ __ ] i guess
we'll
be around be online
the neighborhood yeah there's a there's
a public neighborhood hangout on discord
so you guys if you're asking about the
neighborhood
ask anybody here in one of these chats
through a message and we'll tell you how
to get there don't worry
so there's some stuff going on here in
oklahoma for 420.
uh there's like a uh like the jackhair
cup or something like that
um and there's like some local events
like like us personally we we have a
like a
kind of family barbecue plan to grow
with all the employees
and like their significant others so
that's what we'll be doing on the actual
420 so
if if anybody else is in oklahoma in
southern oklahoma i'll be
uh on sunday uh with afroman and um
i forget what the other guy is playing
with kid lennon i think is the other guy
um uh we've got a big cannabis fest
going on on sunday down in durant at
bubba's
brew house and uh we'll be there with a
whole bunch of stuff if you hit me up oh
oh hey hey steve um i think i have
tickets to the
uh oh no i think it's like 421 it's um
uh rome and uh wb from the dirty heads
and down there at the bubba's brewhouse
and direct yeah i'll see you there then
i have to go to durant soon guys we'll
meet up in durant one time because i
have to go there soon i got a thing
going on there
hey tickets for that show so i've got
extras
forever for everyone that doesn't know
about the [ __ ] duran oklahoma which is
in the middle of nowhere actually kind
of
the texas oklahoma border has the
largest currently the largest cannabis
friendly venue in all of the united
states as far as i'm aware they can have
over 2 000 people in that venue
and we're going to be friends with the
owners so it's a really cool venue and
if you're looking for a
place to host the cannabis event it's a
the largest place you can legally do
that type of event united states right
now damn i didn't know i guess i know
where we're building the commune
hey hey there's also a big casino there
so like if you guys want to lose like a
bunch of money
you know i mean to an airport
like oklahoma city i think it's two
hours north and i think dallas is like
an hour
south so like pick your airport i i
would suggest dallas first of all
you gotta fly somewhere and get a rental
car but it sounds yeah it was cheaper
yeah yeah oklahoma city airport sucks a
dick it's not a real airport
guys hate to interrupt the show but uh
we got another
member joining us jumping in from uh
i'll let him tell us where he's coming
in from
my good friend bob on the job has jumped
in it looks like his internet's a little
bit choppy so if he cuts out i do
apologize
he is coming from an island but rasta
bob welcome to the show uh we have been
asking people to tell us where they're
coming in from
and their social media handle if you
want to share that with us so the mic is
all yours if you want to talk for a
moment bob
oh he's hitting the chalice and he's
muted oh yeah bob what's up dude
we'll give him a minute you got to get
up
yeah a jamaican moment yeah he might be
you will let him talk whenever he pops
in island that's a little unstable
sometimes i think
yeah he's here we know he's here he'll
give us a rasta salute greetings
need some starlink down there
there he is rastafari
looks like somebody's telling tyler
schwubby goodbye i might have to get out
of here get out of here brother
yeah i gotta get water guys go get water
have a good night
thank you for joining us shout out to
canadians
all right i'm gonna take a dab i'm gonna
heat up this dab nail my torch is
overwhelming through these earbuds so
i'm gonna have to start some kind of
conversation so you guys could talk
while i smoke it yeah because i got a
an idea that i had actually just like
yesterday it's all yours buddy i'm
muting my mic let's hear it
so uh i was thinking about starting a
little you know i'm everyone's doing
podcast right but i thought
what if uh we use the discord for a
source for content
and we've got a channel on there already
called the hotbox we could just do like
the hotbox live
and it would just be a disc you know it
it's a i think it's a
limit of four people in that chat room
so you just do like a
pow wow chat go live and uh just
broadcast it to the internet
i mean we talk about all sorts of stuff
on uh the discord from
i was ranting out and raving about uh
molten salt thorium reactors the other
day
but we talk about growing and we help
people identify past
problems and all sorts of cool stuff on
there it's a real cool community
sounds fun if i'm going to do more live
stuff i'm going to do
something that goes up on youtube and
patreon is my next idea because i owe my
patrons something
and i can't figure out what to give them
i don't want to give them merch
i know it does it i i don't like the
name of it but it's like a new
type of patreon and there's a lot i'm
gonna take it down
like this okay just a new
there's a lot of new stuff coming up
like that with like the brave browser
and uh earning crypto from like people
just viewing your
your post and stuff like that
technology's kind of i need to clone
myself if i want to do that
that's why i feel like i need to do
something just for patreon because uh
the patreons contribute and they don't
really get anything extra they get a
shout out they get a high five
i don't want to be uh committed to
giving them merchandise every month
because that's more merch i have to
come up with and print ship and deliver
so i feel like if i just did like a live
show or something for the patrons that'd
be really cool
yeah so something that's the plan it's
usually the way to go with that kind of
stuff
did you guys get sweaty from that dad
too or was it just me it was just you
oh god 800 dab sweats
and finally recovered from mine oh
i'm glad you guys are here to carry the
show for a moment
it was way easier with 20 people isn't
it so much fun mike usually it's you and
i trying to figure out how to fill 30
minutes
yeah when you're like i'm gonna hit this
phil every time my brain goes
blank you can count on stabby to talk
who knows what he's going to say but you
can always count on him
yeah you never know what's going on in
my mouth i'm i'm a gorilla full of
snakes
all right i'm going to try to find an
image of that to put on the screen
flying through with snake smoking uh
bongs of uh some leonardo actually by
himself it's delicious blueberries
it's all blueberry some funky
notes in there it's so good so good
those are all the right words what's the
plan behind you in your picture bro
uh that is
i think that's um it's a plant called
rascals
cool it's like another
all right but pretty plant it's a pretty
color pretty nice actually yeah
it's got that perpetuity yeah
i pulled out some of the uh i said i was
keeping some of mine around from january
i pulled out some of the raphael
that i grew uh back over the winter and
uh
can you pull some out of the jar
absolutely that might help it focus a
lot
but yeah so i kept a small jar of this
around because like i love the flavor so
much and
you know like stabby said earlier i
don't have a huge grow so like
when i pull something down i like to try
and keep at least one small jar of it
just kind of stashed away for like
special occasions
and today i feel like you know it's a
pretty special occasion
but the rafael
oh there you go yeah um
i've gotten so many compliments off of
people that have smoked it
they said you know it's everything from
like strawberry candy to like
blueberry shisha and you know just the
the flavor profile on it it's very
complex
nobody can really 100 percent nail down
what it is
yeah she's she's absolutely frosty and
it's i've had her probably for like
close to three years now
that i've kept her around and it was
not even gonna lie it was like a one pop
wonder like i still have
most of the seeds left from the the
femme pack that i bought
you know it was just a one-seed wonder
so there could be something even
better in there that i don't even know
about yet
you've already got a champion i love
that you say there's a flavor a thing in
there that you can't describe because i
always say it's got something
like a funk or a wang or just uh
nose curling goodness there is this
something that
everybody just they just can't nail it
down what it is but
it they're like one person says it's
grape
one person says it's cough syrup one
person says it's strawberry candy one
person says it's
blueberry like it it changes flavor
profiles as
different people like get to yeah yeah
i was in a sliver shop
yeah randomly right i was at a sneaker
shop and somebody opened a red bull
and i thought oh that's the blueberry
cookies i've never smelled anything that
had that same
that made me that familiar and it's got
a little bit of a red bull sort of all
the blueberry cookies crosses
have that like how red bull is almost
gross from far away but as you get
closer it turns into berries
it had like an energy drink to it and it
definitely made me think about blueberry
cookies it was
just similar to that jeff that had that
i was listening to the most recent
podcast and you used that term wang
yeah i was listening to it in the truck
with carlos he's like
learning spanish oh my wife spoiled um
but uh uh uh he he asked me what what
does
wang mean like like what does wayne
taste like and i wanted to avoid like
like what the heck yeah
it doesn't taste like salty it's at the
tip of your tongue
all of the websites because it can't say
wang now no no no
like some kind wait
maybe tang is the word i gotta read you
all the websites in the description
like a weird tagginess yeah
yeah a tangy
the old panda somebody got the giggles
is that burn that was burnt shout out to
burn i hope she can hear this i was uh
you know i got to test the uh the
blueberry butcher
and i was trying to like pinpoint the
berry smells that i was getting off of
it
and it kept changing throughout the grow
right like early on i swear i was
getting like some
some uh like sour cherry smells or
something like that but i think
uh it was like an elderberry or
something and that's not a
a note that i'm really terribly familiar
with you know what i mean
but there's definitely something uh
different about it not like a fermented
because i've had plants before
they had like that fermented berries or
almost like a wine
uh terpene to it when when it was
finished curing
uh but this was like a like a fresh
berry smell
to it and then i had a recent on a
recent show i said
elderberries too oh nice a squatty fino
huh yeah
the squatty was uh like a
lemon lime citrus soda
did it have a hint of urinal cakes uh
i'd have to check it
to see how i mean it's it's all dry now
and you know what urinal cakes taste
like
i worked out ten years i cleaned the
pizza a lot
so are the different colors different
are they the same
most of them smell like uh like
spearmint bubbles spearmint gum or
something you know
that gummy stuff it's another lemon
smell
yeah i had a i had a lot of berry phenos
in the ones that i had but i also had a
lot of those
uh world uh phylotaxi or whatever
whatever it's called
the uh the triple nodes or the triple
bridges yeah each nodes
uh which number was that two or four
that does that one of those does that
more than the other
i think it's number two that does that
i don't know well i kept the mail of it
and you uh you donated to my breeding
project so
man already breeding with my unreleased
gear i love it
the game hey hey i messaged you guys
you might be too high to remember but i
got your blessing ahead of time dave
just held up some nuggets what are you
showing off there dave
this is that blueberry butcher you're
talking about yeah
there we go um i'll take a quarter
you really killed that girl dave yeah
that was let me put you up on that like
however i do let me pin you here see if
i can make it happen there we go
i hope he came up on your guys screen he
came up on mine
it's kind of phallic like bro how come
everything you're involved in is a
little dick-like
what do you want me to tell you man he
really puts his passion into it
it shows you really definitely put your
heart into it speaking of fact anybody
else
anybody else got any herbs to show off
i've got some uh
a little bit of it's dry and crunchy now
because i've had it for a minute but i
keep going back for this because they're
killing it
this is double dose i bred this and it
was grown
by oh man i know the grower it's a
commercial grow mike knows the name of
them too they're the one the grow that
has the dj in their grow all the time
indico indico colorado double dose
and they sell it at a dispensary near me
for a reasonable price but they don't
let you buy more than a quarter at a
time so i got to go in there a couple
times a week and get a quarter but
that's the double dose
dried flour i'm digging it's pretty good
it's got a nice flavor to it
it's a little too dry by now i think
they've had the same batch for a while
but it's good herb i like it
nice nice i haven't got some packs of
that i need to pop them
i have some orange juice i've got some
i've got too much [ __ ] in the garden
right now
i've got i got the blueberry butcher
clones and uh
i've got a blue raspberry truffle i got
a bunch of iron genetics [ __ ] in there
perf's got some nice looking herb
speaking of
clones i was just
uh one of my local buddies just gifted
me a morning dew clone
not bad score i mean here you go that's
a good gift
that's a good buddy yeah yeah really
like dude look at this thing like
how how can you complain when something
like that shows up oh zappy girl
really healthy that's a happy little
girl dude yeah and that's a good
phenotype i recognize that
i can recognize that leaf structure
there are
it's uh three leaves per node if that if
that helps any
all right that's uh that one's really
easy to trim too yeah
yeah it's the that's the 1091 leaf yeah
so i'm excited to
to play with this one she's gonna be fun
and it's nice too like because it's
already been hunted out like he grew a
couple of them i know it's a girl i know
it's gonna be pretty decent
so now i just get to stick it in my soil
and see how it does
there you go learn that girl see how
much nitrogen phosphorus potassium
led light she likes and growing under
the leds is a whole new curve for me i'm
a very experienced grower
and i have put some plants through the
damn ringer learning these leds
looks like raptor and cuz got some weed
to show
their nuggets i was just showing uh the
strawberry starbursts
quarantine
yeah yeah yeah i
didn't even hear you guys say to get the
point in quarantine
yeah i had a question for you guys
yes two weeks one question
so um we're going into the outdoor
season here soon
so um what do you think uh jeff and and
everyone else
what are the best strains uh for my
regenetics to grow outdoor
if you want to grow some and that's a
great question uh strains that would be
you know really resistant to bud mold
or bud rot uh maybe somehow don't
attract moths because moss
get out of my stuff last year you just
gave me a really
uh so the strain i was going to say to
answer your question uh before i do it i
want to welcome our friend double door
dank to the room double door dank just
popped in it looks like he's frozen for
the time being but he's here
so i want to acknowledge him and show
some love
we know you're here but your mind keeps
cutting out too so love much love enough
respect you guys chime in whenever you
can
uh but for outdoor for ivory genetics i
would definitely recommend the morning
do in almost all locations
uh the morning do i say it's funny
because it smells like mothballs and you
just said what's gonna
get the moths away uh maybe that's got
something to do with why the bugs don't
get to but it doesn't get mold it
doesn't get mildew
ah it grows really well outdoor so that
morning due is killer for the outdoor
uh environment if you've got a longer
flowering season the sun kiss will do
really well for you
our buddy double door's got a sunkissed
phenotype in california
that finishes in like 55-60 days that
just crushes it fills up the greenhouse
ah they're paying the [ __ ] bills off
that sunkist he threw up a thumbs up in
the chat
i don't know if you guys can see that
but thumbs up in response to that
that sunkist is killing it out there in
california i get pictures and reports of
people from that so
uh the morning dude the sun kiss and
then probably the orange gas on if you
have a longer longer flowering season
like okay in the caribbean like
yeah yeah you guys would kill with the
orange gas that would kill it out there
if you ran any of your stuff out here
and like what do you mean a lot of the
stuff off yours
as well oh yeah what's up jeff what's up
steve what's up man
it's good to see you bro [ __ ] hell
man
long time no see i haven't seen steve
since [ __ ] namo expo or the dab
concentrate event
where he was at we were all getting
[ __ ] you know dab down
that was a fun time probably the
was the last time we all got to hang out
together man yeah
that was a lot of fun man [ __ ] steve
is down there [ __ ] you know shout out
his uh
grown fishes podcast i've been listening
quite a bit to that
i gotta say man i'm really impressed
with all that the information you know i
passed that on to
many people uh i'm pretty
pretty excited man i've been promoting
you got your podcast like a [ __ ]
dude
there's a lot of people who wanna
use natural uh you know fish microbials
to
to power the farm so i'm pretty excited
man
that's awesome i turned off your camera
because it was i turned off your camera
because your wi-fi was killing you but
you sound much better now
you you've got a face for radio anyway
brother
i want to double down real quick
hopefully steven
you guys can hear me right now yeah we
can only bro i want to double down on
what he said about watching steve's
content because even if
you're not gonna grow with fishes you
will definitely learn something watching
steve's content
i mean i've i've even adopted the whole
dual root zone thing now like i've got
my pots and trays full of hydroton
the dude knows a lot he's very well
educated never uh never
misjudged dread i love it when i walk in
with the dreads and people think i'm not
gonna know [ __ ] and then i reschool them
on their entire [ __ ] grow
it's the funnest thing to do so you can
learn a lot from my brother steve
i appreciate it guys sorry about the dog
there for a second but yeah i appreciate
it that's family too bro the dog is
family
dog's on the show now the dog's famous
but steve's probably gotten
uh steve's probably got some of the
highest level of actual education
you know how do you deal with the
moisture the amount of [ __ ] moisture
that you deal with the uh the humidities
that keep that going that you know
you're constantly running
fluid through you know how do you guys
deal with that you know on an aquaponics
level
yeah i've molded up a house with just a
fish tank so that's a pretty good
question
uh ross de bob said anything to the
platinum tangy uh the orange gas
or sunkist is great outdoors rasta bob
also made a good point he said piranha
is another one that could take it great
outdoors
uh that's absolutely absolutely true
prana finishes early
uh it's got blueberry and flow and a
rise in it so it's potent it's vigorous
uh but it's very limited in quantity on
seeds i'm not sure where you'll be able
to find it i've got a couple of packs
left so good luck finding the prana
but that one kills it outdoors
definitely crushes
yeah so with the uh with the humidity it
generally makes it pretty easy to
maintain vpd in a place like colorado
where it's so dry
but definitely can be an issue um at
night time mainly so we do
you know definitely have to make sure we
have dehumidifiers or a good airflow at
nighttime but that's
fixing plus just proper pruning and
making sure you have you know cultivars
that are adapted to it and finally some
phenos
in your cultivars that you're looking
for that are a little bit you know more
more human tolerant
you know trying to stick to more
equatorial strains similarly growing in
even in oklahoma is similar to right you
have higher humidity
or texas or anywhere on the gulf coast
you could have higher humidity
uh and you know or jamaica you guys are
down in jamaica and trinity um
uh you guys are very similar to growth
in terms of humidity
we'll see like i'm in santa cruz man i'm
right on the coast literally we
get a lot of ocean winds and a lot of uh
you know a lot of that fog coming off
the ocean and nights and stuff and we
get you know tremendous amounts of
humidity spikes at night and so there's
a lot of people here trying to do the
aquaponics thing at the same time
uh you know any advice for people you
know growing greenhouse that are trying
to do this
uh you know you know symbiotic in a kind
of higher humidity
environment other than you know i i know
dehumidification is probably key to
everything but you know uh you know just
some simple advice to some of the people
in the higher
humidity environments so the other big
thing i would say is going to be
ultra critical and high humidity
environments is relying heavily on
geothermal
over wet walls because geothermal will
operate just fine in high humidity
environments
whereas wet walls are horribly
inefficient in human humid environments
so
you know if you have cooler ground or
even even better if you have a cool
aquifer
and you can pull like in jamaica for
example underground it's still 70 72
degrees right it's
not that much cooler because it's the
tropics but if you find an aquifer that
aquifer is much cooler
so if you can pull water up from
underground and circulate that through
either a heat exchanger attached to a
wet wall
to basically chill that wet wall or to
have it attached directly to the slab or
through a heat exchanger in your grill
beds
um for yourself you can actually you
know do it that way to cool everything
down
and be very efficient even in a very
human place like the caribbean
hell yeah dude well one of the things
that i ran into major league
oh [ __ ] my bad i'm sorry man i didn't
mean to overtalk you yeah but like
you're good i'm gonna interrupt both of
you guys though i'm gonna interrupt
everybody so we can welcome mr bagsy to
the show what up mr bagsy hey mr baxter
cheers back to you what up my brother
how's it going back
hey jeff yeah what's up
what's up everybody i actually made my
video it says it's inactive
oh yeah it turns you off what chops up
your uh active video again i got a good
wi-fi now
there you go should be ready to go there
we go there we go oh there he is there's
that sexy face coming from cali bro ah
you know what i mean santa cruz we're in
the dodger right now
um so you're coming in from santa cruz
how can we follow you on social media
man just give people your social media
real quick i didn't let people plug
their social media when they come in
yeah friendly fire farms uh friendly
fire farms is uh what i've got going on
right now i've got
outdoor greenhouse and indoor running
right now i've got three different
sections
and we're running each uh pretty
successfully uh
out here as well as i've got people in
north uh california
i want to say colorado that's so funny i
lived in colorado for so long i can't
stop saying it
but uh i got people up in north
california above sacramento also rings
a lot of jeff's stuff and as well as a
lot of some of my stuff so i'm pretty
proud right now
uh one of the biggest things uh steve
man uh i'll tell you what there's been
more questions about aquaponics down
here than you can imagine
and i've had to answer so much [ __ ] and
i just keep saying grow with fishes
you need to check out the podcast
because like if you really want to know
how to do this this is
how you're going to do it because
symbiotic aquaponics is not something
you just walk into it's a
it's definitely a process that i think
people need to understand the amount of
bacteria you need to build up the amount
of
you know like uh to properly aquaponics
i've been growing for like 12 years 20
years 40 years i don't even know and
aquaponics is like
a completely different thing to me i
don't know the first step about
aquaponics like i would be if you're
like send me up an aquaponics girl
i'd go well here's steve's card that's
how i would set up the aquaponics screen
i'm going to cut you off so we can talk
to mr bagsy real quick we're going to
talk to backstreet
what's up mr bag he looks sexy as [ __ ]
he's got a fresh haircut he's back from
colorado he's got that giant long in his
lap
he's also muted so we can't hear a damn
thing he's saying
he doesn't yeah i keep muting i don't
want to make you i don't want to make
noise yeah what's up what's going on you
can make noise it's a podcast bro uh
when people have been coming in i've
been uh been being polite and letting us
letting ben tell us where they're coming
from and how we can find them on social
media so we get you some social media
followers yeah man i'm from missouri i
live in missouri right now i'm okay you
can sound more enthusiastic about it
i'm from no i'm kind of dude i kind of
had something to drink yeah i'm probably
a little slower
i'm a caregiver out here um yeah i'm in
missouri yeah hanging out
we hang out in the neighborhood all the
time i know you come through uh we have
the new uh
youtube channel the uh neighborhood
grows that we're starting up yeah
let's plug that real quick everybody's
been mentioning it i guess now is a good
time since we got
in my opinion you're the [ __ ] like
the leader of the hood you're the mr
rogers bro we gotta get you a silly
sweater
stinky fingers no we just hang around
yeah dude yeah it's about us
in the neighborhood association yeah i
mean everyone everyone who comes through
yeah that's the part of the neighborhood
we all just kind of hang out and talk
and
help each other that's you know what
it's really yeah i learned it from you
it became i mean you know when i started
yeah
but like when i showed you i basically
got all that from you jeff
i mean your whole growing mentality and
everything is easy for me to catch on to
um you know i watch the michigan bros
and everybody it's really how i found
all you guys and it's really you know
how everyone comes together it's really
cool um everyone who comes through the
hood
you know i [ __ ] love everybody and
everyone i watch i love you guys too
even though i don't know you but
uh yeah i mean that's kind of what we're
about we just kind of hang around and
talk
about everything and then we have good
topics to talk about so we want to you
know go live so
that's kind of what we're doing i can't
wait for you so tell us about the going
live part tell us about this live 420
show that the hood's doing yeah we're
going to be here
yeah we're just yeah we're all just
going to hang out on the 420 show
but we're going to start out as a show
we're going to do like beginner grows
helping people you know at starting out
beginner grows and whatnot and then go
from there you know
up to what raptor knows i mean raptor
knows a ton of
knowledge gmf everybody that comes into
the hood has so much good knowledge so
if we can just keep all that going
that's kind of what what we're trying to
do you know
go live yeah having more shows and more
people feed off of ideas is what all
this is about so
um that's that's that's what i'm you
know i don't know everything i'm a newer
grower i'm a salt grower i'm you know i
i do uh
i love growing i want to learn more and
it's cool being around all you guys
so that's that's really uh yeah it's
possible you learn quickly
you learn very quickly and your video
skills are red like you're definitely
skilled with uh video audio this
production is off the chain thank you
yeah that'll be fine i'm pretty excited
you're not even ready for what's about
to happen now you guys i just allowed
somebody into this chat that's going to
break the whole chat
oh [ __ ]
the podcast tonight for 4 20 in pearl
well thank you so much
did you see your bong you said your
mom's name is pearl
uh where are you coming in from tonight
and how do we find you on social media
miss painted lady
i am coming in from actually a meeting i
just got out of a meeting and
um everybody can find me on instagram at
painted lady gardens and cannabis at
painted
lady 13 i believe i'm over there so
michigan girls grow show michigan bros
grow show sunday and monday nights
are there 12 other painted ladies no
13 is just my number so i like it i like
it 13 pearls in that necklace
well [ __ ] don't make me a hoe
[Laughter]
we're going to talk about growing weed
again real soon here this is getting
not a question for steve actually i've
seen the
large-scale aquaponics setups that he's
done firsthand
what's the smallest you could possibly
do could you do like a goldfish tank for
dan's setup like so we the smallest i've
actually grown anything on aquaponics
about two and a half gallon tank i grew
forehead the lettuce but as far as
cannabis the smallest we were able to
get a cannabis plant to grow
with uh uh what would normally be
considered an appropriate amount of fish
and an aquarium was about 40 gallons um
just in terms of
it it takes so much biomass of fish to
create enough biomass of
fish manure yeah i think if you're using
enough fertilizer 20 gallon guppy tank
uh that was just packed to the brim you
could probably make it work but you know
i'm not going to tell people to do that
yeah that'd be kind of unethical uh
treatment of the guppies even though
they are guppies
but like i was just curious because like
how could uh your average home grower or
hobbyist grower
adopt an aquaponic system so you could
just take like
fill in their garage full of fish sure
so you could just take an over the flow
overflow aquarium filter box
you get for a saltwater aquarium or
drill your tank if you're really into
glass
um but most people just buy an overflow
tank run that down to your sub tank
and then run a return pump to either up
to your fish tank and then
you either run a second pump for your
flood and drain table or
run that on a bell siphon or loop siphon
so you don't you know everything can run
continuously but yeah it's super simple
you know i mean it's not a
lot of work if you already have a grow
tank grow tray and something it's
literally like a trip to the
saltwater fish store and you can have
that up and running in about half an
hour
nice it's always thought it was way more
than that
oh yeah that's awesome man yeah i didn't
know if you had to develop like quite a
bit of culture before
they started actually being efficient
and you know
how much you know bacteria you have to
develop before that starts becoming you
know a relevant
uh feeding you know you know this fish
the same way that you would cycle or
make sure you're a good living soil bed
same thing you do with the aquarium or
an aquaponics system populating those
microbes the same way we would when we
inoculate our gardens in the springtime
in our soil beds very similar
okay oh yeah that's awesome man it's
good to know
good question i like dondre grover's
comments in the chat all right guys i
think we got interrupted when we were
talking about what everybody's gonna do
for 420 we know that duck's on lockdown
after that i think we totally got off
the rails and [ __ ] abandon that whole
topic and started talking about
aquaponics and
[ __ ] who knows what else i don't
remember because i've been smoking as
much as you guys
that's that's why i invited you i knew i
would need content i didn't know i would
need all the content off the rails
um oh look look who's joining us let me
allow somebody into the room here before
we ask this one
but everybody think about what you're
going to do for 420 because after i do
this intro here we're going to talk
about that
he's connecting he is here he's live in
the chat he's wearing some death metal
shirt today what you got going on what's
up black sail
let's welcome to the room my buddy black
sail market what's up keith here in the
show bro
brother yo happy 420
look at this [ __ ] crowd happy four
times that's a barrel of monkeys i'm so
glad everyone made it
fashionable
smoking down where are you coming from
people
how can people find you on social media
keith uh
black sale market on cannabis which is a
[ __ ] phenomenal app
every grower should be on there uh black
sale market on instagram
keith at blacksailmarket.com or just
blacksalemarket.com hit me up with your
led questions
we're gonna do a full episode with keith
pretty soon this uh zoo meeting here is
kind of a practice run to get good at
doing zoom meetings with other people so
i think i got the hang of it i was able
to manage 22 people i think i can do a
one-on-one show now with keith
we'll get a lot of you guys on shows one
on one now keith thank you for joining
us bro don't let anybody pick on you for
being late
uh i said come one come all come
whenever you can so i'm glad people made
it
now i'm gonna ask the question that's
been pending uh the only person i know
what they're doing for 420 is duck
because he said
[ __ ] lockdown because the beaches are
close i hope he gets duck i hope you get
somebody on that couch by the way just
just drop that in there real quick
yeah yeah we have some books pieces
tomorrow busy day
beautiful what is anybody else doing
keith just popped in do you have any
plans for 420 are you stuck in the house
because of the the pandy
uh you know i'll probably end up going
over to nazis and getting stoned
it's pretty much what i do for fun you
know so you're going to take a dab
and then take a nap on the dog bed huh
yeah man pretty much that's a party it's
actually a great time for you
that was it how many dads will you take
throughout the day like three maybe four
yeah i take a lot of dabs throughout the
day but i take like tiny little baby
dabs dude like
one pedro dab is like a [ __ ] week's
worth all at once
and so i get very pale and then i pass
out
i hear half quarter dabs are all the
rage in canada
[Laughter]
damn straight there is all around
oh you're crazy eh all right miss
painted lady i know you're out there
on that the other coast uh do you have
any plans for the 420 are you trapped
indoors because of the pandy
what [ __ ] coast do you think i'm on
i'm in michigan
dude when i said where are you earlier
you said you came from
so i thought you were just dodging your
location and leaving that a secret so i
was just going to go with
he's going to run michigan by the
michigan bros grove show
so no i'm in michigan i just don't even
know where in michigan i am
okay you know but i don't know nothing
yeah and kid rock came from michigan
that's all i know
oh man he picked the worst one
one more time and i'm gonna mute your
mic you're like dale remind me
yeah no we're gonna hang out with the
michigan bros
oh yeah we just had an event at
sequences uh housewarming not too long
ago
so when was that sequence couple weeks
ago i guess yeah where are you going
to do another event um because basically
our
pandemic bubble has been our group we've
done a bunch of events with just our
group of people and we
smoke and stuff and uh it's went well um
so we'll probably do something for 420
we haven't played anything yet though
that's normal
we don't ever have so it's only five
days why start planning now
yeah yeah exactly though
we do have a what was that loser an
event bigfoot lodge where we're gonna do
um what is it sequence yeah we're gonna
be i do
we're gonna be vending and stuff at an
event in uh northern michigan
and then camping overnight in july two
different days in july
very fun events are happening are going
to come
back soon sometime i'm so excited for
events i miss events and concerts and
just going up to denver to dab on
tonight's couch would be a good time
right now
i will say they had a comedy event at
the dyspo the other day which was pretty
cool they had like five comics they
called in from other states
and it was just nice to see like live
events again like you know what i mean
it was outdoor but
it was still nice to see like dyspo's
putting on like barbecues and
you know having these [ __ ] fun events
again you know it kind of reminded me of
before the whole
covet thing it was really nice like
people were in truck beds just watching
this it was great it was
a lot of fun i'm hoping i'm ready we're
gonna open up a little bit
i'm so ready for events i don't know how
long it'll be before i go to big big
events
but like small medium events i'm ready
to do it but it's going to take a while
for people to remember how to act
so i'm not ready to go to big big stuff
yet but medium stuff i'm in
there maybe a medium-sized event coming
up in may that i'll start advertising
here really soon i just gotta
just send that final agreement i gotta
write the check and then i'll start
advertising
there's a thing in denver though you
guys coming up in may be prepared
mike said i was gonna say i think the
last time we all hung out together was
actually at
frosty mcnuggets house not not tenazis
that's how damn dog yeah yeah no i knew
that was uh i'm just saying it would be
nice just to go sit on tanasi's couch
with the dogs and tanasi and keith would
be a [ __ ] party at this point in time
the most company i've had in the past
few months has been mike like no offense
to mike but we've seen each other dude
i'd like like a couple other people
would be cool
like you know yeah i definitely remember
that everybody got uh got the coveted
frosty mcnuggets
house i do remember we all shared it
that night
everybody's not in their head like yeah
we all went home and got sick
oops you guys got sick i didn't get that
dick donut though
do you guys remember the dick donut was
a legendary i don't know what the [ __ ]
that was amazing anybody that wasn't
there is lost now
hey cascadian grown just went live on
instagram if anybody wants to tell them
that the party's over here
the event you guys described sounds like
one of the ones that we would have done
here so it's nice to know that those
sorts of
communities still exist all over the
place
it's a thing we try to foster a lot over
here in michigan
now you can't stop the cannabis
community there there definitely uh are
a lot of restrictions in loopholes right
now but you can't stop us
we're a bunch of underground we like the
growers and breeders have always been a
bunch of underground rebels that was
just something legal so
we're still we've still got a rebel
mindset we got a rule breaker mindset we
were always that kid in school that
[ __ ] was late and stoned and didn't
give a [ __ ] i don't feel tardy like that
was always us
still is i don't know what you're
talking about dumbledore's showing off
his swords
yeah we do weapons training down here
this is actually a
[ __ ] this is actually a dojo for a
karate school at the bottom of the place
i live at
and they do weapons training karate
school down here and it's [ __ ]
insane if you've never seen guys fight
with [ __ ] full on staffs
and you know swords like that's just
insane
like straight sweep the leg all of these
here these are the practice swords and
then we have
more behind me and they have arm weights
and [ __ ] they wear while they do the
sword fight it's insane bro we have a
full
outdoor section whereas the pad where
they fight it's nuts man if you've never
watched guys [ __ ] do weapons training
for kung fu it's [ __ ] awesome
you didn't just show that video and
you're like bro my new house we got all
this i'd go i think that's too high
i think matt ate mushrooms and got
creative and told us a story but then
you just panned
a really great commercial bro if [ __ ]
goes down can i come there
yeah the zombie apocalypse we're going
to get all the zombie weapons
you're too high i was hoping he was
going to pick something up
got a kick-ass bell over there
gone that [ __ ]
is actually [ __ ] really sharp this is
one of the staffs
it's like three and a half feet long
what
this is one
so when you see these behind me holy
[ __ ] those are six feet tall
yeah it looks like a neginto it's like
all the weapons from that uh
chateau fight scene in the matrix where
they like oh yeah
you guys remember the the wristbands
from uh [ __ ] uh the
kung fu uh what is it called a [ __ ]
that like almost funny movie where
they'd have their wristbands to block
all the [ __ ] in the middle
of the bands that's not ours
these are the ones that don't kill you
when you get here yeah so we do this do
they smoke when they train
do they smoke when they're practicing
and [ __ ] or do they go in there just
wide-eyed and bushy-tailed
oh no they smoke oh they never made each
other
here bro like i you guys you have a
stitches kit like does anybody there
know
how to apply a tourniquet in stitches
um we don't know is it the answer
when somebody starts doing the answer
put some dirt on it super glue and duct
tape
oh you're raising my sword with that
because when he brought it out on the
show the other night i was thinking the
dirt man dan
oh painted ladies holding a beautiful
plant holy [ __ ]
hey lady what are you holding right now
it's the jack the ripper f2
number two or number four no f2 never
mind
[Music]
[ __ ] with jeff i love jeff yeah that's
awesome yeah it's like a dildo she's
like dangling it
going it's a gorgeous
look at this thing it's so fluffy
that looks like an auto plant the way it
flowered it almost looks
like an auto plant yeah it's just in a
cup so that thing vegged real short
that's pretty awesome i love it that's
exactly how i describe it it grows that
bottom bush and then it just takes off
it makes that leader top
hell yeah that's [ __ ] cool i've got a
couple other and three gallons right now
that are they've got about the same
christmas tree structure that are doing
really well so
i'm stoked to see how those turn out the
biggest size pot you're using
what's that sorry what's the biggest
what's the biggest size pot you're using
right now is 10 gals
tango let's do 10 gallon door that gets
crazy
how long are you going to let those
flower uh
those aren't in 10 gal those are only in
three gales right now they're really in
veg but
um but they they're gonna let those cups
flower
the solo cup yeah this only has a couple
more weeks
nice yeah this is with the cannabis
challenge
i'm not going to win but i thought she
was cute it was my first time ever
attitude is that
i'm not going to win why [ __ ] enter
you got to be like i'm going to win i'm
going to crush this contest [ __ ]
everybody else i'm a champ
no start spinning the prizes
that's a second place attitude you gotta
have a first place attitude
uh well there's my first place attitude
beautiful that's why you're one of my
favorite [ __ ]
girls i mean i have eyes i've seen some
of the other cops and they're doing
great so i just didn't really push her
that hard so
that's gonna be the thumbnail of this
episode this painted lady with her
finger up at me like that's what i'm
gonna try to put up on youtube
bro you know what i think that ladies
[ __ ] no she's throwing down
right now she's i need somebody to keep
me in line
oh there we go check it out somebody
went and gave him the message
thank you guys for whoever did that i'm
going to assume it was raptor with all
that responsibility
he's coming in we'll introduce him here
as soon as we go get the camera going
maybe here's cascadia
cheers and cascadian girl popping in
there he is what's up brother good to
see you cascadian
hey guys glad to be here
glad somebody passed you goodbye
a bunch of great people in here tonight
where are you coming from cascadian
i am in the cascades man
[Music]
grown i grew up in the cascades boy that
makes more sense than anything i've ever
heard tonight
um what's your instagram handle so
people can follow you if they want to
stalk you while you're on here
if they're looking for me man you catch
me at cascading ground dude keep it
pretty simple beautiful
give him a follow he's doing some cool
stuff do you have any photos of the
thing you're working on can we talk
about your project you're a separator
so that one you'll find at cascadian
hort
h-o-r-t that is the horticulture company
that i started i separated that out from
the rest of everything else i got going
on so
yeah we can talk about it man it's
that's pretty cool i'm really excited
about it
there's a car that's a cascadian horde
instagram right
yeah that's the instagram handle at
cascadian horse um
working on a seed cleaner on an electric
seat cleaner
i'm assuming that's what you're alluding
to yes sir yes sir
yeah i'm pretty excited about it it's uh
handmade these hands so uh
it's been a good time it's been a
learning experience i've had to make a
prototype or two and alter the
the designs a little bit i'm happy with
where where it is now i just have to put
the final design together and i'll have
prototype videos up and running
um the model itself is very well proven
it's actually open source so the only
thing i'm really selling
is not the model it's not a secret it's
just my labor in parts
that's that's the only reason for a
market is my labor in parts
so uh it's very time tested design it's
really
it's really cool they use it a lot in um
bird breeding
because they can't yeah they can't waste
the food so they have to recover their
costs from the seeds that the birds eat
they have to clean that out of the seeds
that they just spill
so it's made for all size seeds because
they
they don't use one in particular seed
it's always a mix
so it works for all kinds of seeds and
should be pretty cool i just got to dial
it in a little bit
it's a good product i've seen it and i
know where the idea came from and i know
the idea is solid so i hope you have
great success with that bro
uh when they're ready i'm definitely
going to be looking at one i've got a
seat cleaner now but you know i can
always put them side by side and clean
twice as many seeds
appreciate it man thanks for letting me
have a moment to talk about it oh yeah
man gotta support the community here
gotta support the community you guys if
you're a if you're just a regular grower
not just a regular girl i'm not trying
to downplay a grower
if you're a grower that's got a trim
your version of trimming which you guys
call trim gel which i find disrespectful
to anybody that's been in real jail
where you're listening to sublime eating
cheetos quit saying trim jail
but you guys that are in trim jail uh
the breeders version
is cleaning seeds and packing seeds uh
that is our version we gotta get on
32 hours of netflix and just be prepared
and have 12 bottles of water and just go
to cleaning and packing seeds that's our
version so that machine he's making
is definitely useful helpful for
somebody in our position
so yeah good work bro i need one uh
anybody else here do any breeding or is
it just me i'm looking around to see who
we're playing with
yeah yeah i'm looking for some ladies
any single ladies yeah you're always
gonna put some stains on that couch bro
as soon
i've been called a breeder before but it
was in a different context it felt like
yeah yeah does your pull out game is
weak i heard burp say that uh that he's
doing some pollen dusting what are you
doing over there
yeah i'd dusted a little pollen on a
pretty much everything in my flower
right now
um today i've dusted some
well i'm not gonna spill the beans right
now but i put it on to a bunch of uh
ivory stuff so and i'm collecting some
uh what is it uh
blue raspberry truffle pollen as well
so beautiful was the baby daddy and this
breeding run
ire genetics or another breeder i was
another breeder
okay cool but that's cool because all my
shit's like if you keep breeding with
mine you bottleneck yourself so that's
really cool right yeah yeah
yeah no i'm reaching far out far out
so i like that the further out the
better i promise you i will
i trust your selections i've seen what
you do anybody else out there breeding
or just just our man perv
wow silence in the breeding i know chuck
and paul
doing some i'm sorry yeah
go ahead one of you guys go ahead i was
just saying i wanted to breed later like
i have
sts and uh i have pollen that i've
collected and i made one cross
that i'm testing now but i'm no breeder
or anything like that
yeah you're doing you're breeding you're
making that's breeding
otherwise you know yeah you're learning
it um
like i'm doing some open pollination
right now i have some really awesome
seeds i got in zimbabwe up in the hills
uh some really cool sativas doing some
open pollination with that to try and
batch them out so we can give a bunch of
them out
do something cool you said cool sativas
how how long are those flowering
uh that's the million dollar question
all right
i'm really curious about some zimbabwe
sativa i guess 12 weeks dog 12 weeks i'm
going to say 16. i'm going to
be 16. yeah 12 is pretty weak
yeah yeah very ambitious guys
i picked these uh earth or i guess
they'd be late in the summer early in
the fall their time so
they actually would be equivalent to us
would kind of be like early september
finishers
but we'll see i also have no idea when
they were planted they i just happened
to
be in the right place at the right time
and uh and get a you know a nice tour of
a farm where i was going through and
they were mature seeds so
obviously uh you know paper planes found
a way to follow
yeah i love it i love it big respect for
all the work you do moving genetics
around that's the only way that i need
to say that but big respect for it
i appreciate that as a seed breeder and
somebody trying to move seeds around i
know your struggle brother definitely
all right cass i saw you raise your hand
and say that you're breeding some seeds
so cascadian i'll give you a chance to
talk about your breeding project if you
want to go for it now oh dude
i got a whole ball of wax i'm just
getting ready to crack into
i'm going back i'm going back in time
not really i'm going to land race
heirloom genetics and getting out of
what i call the box which is
camps diesels ogs all that's coming
yeah i'm going back to to uh some land
races and mixing
particular land races with my
environment in mind so
i'm really focused on the
pakistani and afghanis
hindu kush and mixing that with
himalayan
genetics nepalese manapuri burma
the really wet stuff so that i can get
the yield
and the hash from the hindus but the
mold resistance and the structure from
the himalayas and really nice you can
know those from my area so
many people so many people overlook the
resistance part they just want instagram
ability
so i'm glad you're talking about
resistance early on in your breeding
instead of i'm going to find a phenotype
that sells wheat on instagram
that's what it's all about now nah man i
want to breed for the future
for the day with that the plant is set
free and you can put it outside and
we need to develop regional cultivars
and and regional
like genetic families it doesn't just
need to be a single cultivar it needs to
be interrelated families that are
regional
uh like appalachian style where they
thrive in that environment
and they might thrive in other
environments but they're cultivated for
that environment so that the day that
the cuffs come off we
we can just literally take our seeds and
go outside and just
throw them and they go we don't i've got
mountain kush you've got your
cascadian kush black sail's got his
denver kush
duck's got his caribbean kush we all
just throw our acclimated perfect seeds
out there yeah
i can't wait for that that's what i'm
breeding i'm reading for that world i'm
i'm always looking
10 steps ahead so i'm bringing for that
world not the world we live in right now
because this is a [ __ ]
go back to the future you need that
delorean it's where we're headed
now we just named all of our subsequent
crosses yeah we got the 88 miles per
hour we got the dock we got the marty
mcfly your c-line just named itself bro
good job dave straight names are
they already hungry from his lineup
looks like rastabob is showing us some
plants and i'm not even paying attention
because i'm over here trying to pay
attention to all this other stuff
oh and then he cut out is that the
chamber
oh [ __ ] bob where are you man looking
pretty sativa there
i was gonna say man some skinny
skinny leaves yeah yeah that's going to
be a long flower long finisher there but
i bet the buzz is incredible
i like that stuff that gives me like the
shakes and the sweats and a panic
attack it looks like gmf has got to go
gmf thank you for hanging out brother
i will see you in the hood next time oh
thank you again jeff have a great night
any time brother
i hope you baked up something good bud
oh trying uh i will say if anyone's
interested in 420 i'll be making some
infused kombucha
and some infused loaded no alcohol beer
so i'll let you all know how those turn
out
i'm interested thanks again jeff
any time brother jealous
yeah it looks like ship was right uh bob
wrote in the chat here that that's a
land race running
uh chamba he's going to cross it with
some jamaican jamaican landers
that's what we said he says
that was rad i can't believe nobody else
has any 420 plans i'm trying to weasel
420 plans out of you guys so i can find
something to do and nobody's got any
plans
on my couch we got the
420 neighborhood uh sesh going on 4 p.m
pacific standard time
7 p.m eastern standard time so yeah that
way we could make the west coast 420 and
uh
east coast seven it's awesome awesome so
just type in
without pandemic uh on youtube it's
at the neighborhood grows instagram and
that neighborhood grows youtube
same thing we were able to snack both of
those and
yeah it's gonna be fun we're just gonna
be hanging out introducing ourselves
talking about what we're gonna be uh
covering over the next foreseeable
future
yeah it'll be a lot of fun we'll also be
discussing
uh recently a lot of states came online
for cannabis so we'll also be getting
into that a little more hopefully we'll
be
we'll be able to talk to people who are
actually living in those areas so
uh yeah it'll definitely be an
interesting conversation so
hope to ha have uh anyone here is
welcome to join us as well
it's just going to be us hanging out
again and then uh we will be doing it on
mondays
4 p.m pacific standard time and 7 p.m
awesome i look forward to learning from
you man you definitely have a lot of
stuff to teach so i'll definitely
support your show any time
um oh yeah you've taught me a lot about
uh fungus and agar and
uh tissue culture and all kinds of great
things so just a little bit of time i've
been asking you questions you felt
you overflow my head where i'm like okay
stop raptor that's enough my brain's
gonna dump out
any of this [ __ ] it's uh it's a lot of
fun for me uh
that's why i've actually always been
interested in horticulture
like unknowingly i was brought up with
uh in my grandma's garden
and she's man uh an insane grower she
uh the the fruit that i would pick off
those trees are just always so awesome
so it's delicious it's just like oh the
leave it alone method you know
neglect those are the real growers for
all the old school people
yeah yeah uh learned a lot from her and
uh
learned a lot from just uh going to
school and
basically focusing on those things that
i was interested in
yeah and i actually got a great start
from canada's organum
i was looking more into biochemistry
when i actually started growing so when
i started growing i
did get introduced to cannabis organim
through embracing organics and just
started following him uh
cannabis organim at youtube great source
of knowledge uh i really hope to see him
come back online someday
but with all the amount of i learned so
much from you
oh you shut him down or did he disappear
voluntarily
okay yeah yeah uh always a bunch of
knowledge uh coming out of there
i wish uh him much love just like stabby
was saying
there's so much knowledge you can learn
from him he's the one that actually got
me
uh into my ecology so i got to
i got to hang out with him uh he took me
on my first foray mushroom foray that's
just
mushroom hunting no fancy work
promotional hunting and
it was awesome i got into that whole
world and into horticulture and so much
so that i
actually switched majors into
horticulture so
yeah uh it's he was such a big
inspiration
uh man uh i'm definitely gonna hit him
up
uh have his number he was really he's
always been really busy
it you know and you just hit up friends
and it's it's in the middle of like some
uh
a lot of stuff that they're going
through so yeah it's about time i hit
him up again and at very least like
once everything calms down i am going up
to the pnw i actually plan to go up
there
at very least twice twice a year to
collect
mushroom tissue samples and spores
to add to my own collection and just for
my own little uh side projects i've been
looking into
like uh dna marking for
local uh
a lot of species in my area but
specifically mushrooms
so yeah uh going to be starting up that
working with operation grow on some
other stuff
that will be connected to those stuff
yeah
i gave him an uh an invite but it's a
little uh late for him it's
right in the middle of his nap time yeah
but he's uh he's a great source of
knowledge uh i'm happy to be connected
to his group as well
they uh we do a lot we actually uh
got to interview binocular university
and he talked a little bit about
yeah and uh he got to uh tell us about
polyamorous chain reaction uh testing so
that's just pcr testing
and that's the whole uh how we're able
to get
no male and female before even flower
happens
right yeah like that are important also
that goes into
uh getting dna markers so that's what
i'm going to be looking into so
we'll be we'll be working on stuff like
that in the very near future
it's just a matter of uh saving up and
doing
uh a little bit of organization who's
doing what uh how are we gonna
accomplish this
what sources are we gonna use so yeah
it's it's gonna be a lot of fun
and hopefully we can also share all the
knowledge on the neighborhood grows
we actually uh just like mr bagsy was
saying
gonna be starting off with introductory
grows and just starting off
from step one you know where
where are you in your grow especially
yeah yeah just like you guys are
starting with the goal if you don't
start with that goal and a plan it all
turns to [ __ ] so you're absolutely doing
it right
and you guys in the future you younger
guys you guys make me feel like i missed
a bunch of stuff
uh now i know how my parents feel when i
talk about the internet like you guys
talk about some growing stuff and i'm
like where was i when that happened
you guys are younger than me going to
school doing all this new technology
stuff i love what you guys are bringing
to cannabis that is so impressive to me
i love staying to the roots i keep it
simple stupid i got
an air conditioner a light and a
dehumidifier you know i try not to put
too many moving parts in there because
that's when it gets complicated and [ __ ]
goes wrong but you guys that have all
this science you guys blow my mind i
love it
it's so amazing to see you see davis
right now is actually offering grants to
local growers right here uh
to do electro electrolytical stimulus to
plants
uh basically electrical stimulus to
plants uh to see how they affect the
growth
and uh there's literally grants for
right now in the different uh electrical
stimulus of plants and how it affects
and
uh stimulates uh different functions
yeah it's really cool man they're doing
a lot of stuff
and you get funded for it and they'll
literally pay for everything it's pretty
[ __ ] cool
room now or is that just a basic ass
kitchen
that's uh that's just basically out of a
college uh i've worked with a lot of
growers in the area and uh right now
i'm trying to control you is that a real
normal kitchen you're in or is that some
mystical apothecary behind you
oh no this is a it's a japanese kitchen
japanese thing asian theme right now
like my whole place is literally the the
pot i have you
set against right now is all just asian
themed
um kitchen uh and living
everything i do here is like asian
themed is pretty cool we have a giant
koi garden
[ __ ] it's peace garden we have giants
sand
[ __ ] lot that you can do the rake
stuff for peace guarding
stuff the rakes did this guy really
say that the pot that i have you guys
resting against right now like
we're really in a japanese kitchen if
you have us resting against that pot
right now
yeah his knives are little katanas yeah
no and you know it's uh it's kind of
funny because we literally have a watch
tumor garden
a lot of uh different versions of uh
different breeds of cactuses going on
right now
we even have some traditional stuff um
you know
some maybe some masculine based stuff
allegedly but um we have a lot of
different uh
kind of uh little gardens going on right
now along the property and they're
they're a lot of fun
we take care of them we have a
greenhouse we have an outdoor section
and then we have also you know a few
private gardens along the property as
well so
you know we do are all of those japanese
themed as well
oh they are there there's a koi garden
there's a full [ __ ] pond there's the
full japanese
themed center courtyard
the most important part you have to take
your shoes off to go in there
[ __ ] no man i mean i should but like i
don't know because like you know
i'm american so i feel like it doesn't
apply to me
are you worried about forest fires with
those paper walls uh
you know i mean uh honestly we have
we've cut several fire roads we've got
about 40 acres
up here and we've got about six fire
roads cut out all the brush has been
cleared around our property as well as
we put in a
large water reservoirs that the fire
department can directly tap into so our
house is kind of on the more safer zone
is there like a conch shell or maybe
like a ram horn that you blow that
summons all of the ninjas
or do they just show up at a certain
time for class every day well they show
up they show up every two days they show
up every [ __ ] two days and they do
classes and it's [ __ ] awesome and new
weapons
training is [ __ ] amazing like you can
come down here at any time if you guys
ever want to do it live when they're
doing weapons training i'll definitely
give you guys a stoner view of some
people just to get it back on track of
cannabis i want to know what did ninjas
do for 420
they kicked all kickstarter's asses when
they come back
to [ __ ] off our edibles that's what they
do we bring them edibles and they come
down here and
they fight for four hours straight after
we give them cookies
they're the stars of death yeah
no it's a it's a lot of fun uh most the
people on the property here
are you know um they're medicated so a
lot of
it happens you know under medication uh
so on a scale of
one to need a nap how medicated are you
right now
uh i am not as medicated as jeff because
jeffy's smoking like a goddamn freight
train
and i've seen your [ __ ] half gram
dabs you take so
you know my my my smoking a bowl or two
here and there is like
very small to you and your your dad
[ __ ] you're damaged man
all right matt what are you doing for
420 brother just curious since we've got
you highlighted here what are you doing
for 420 um
actually got i've got actually a bunch
of buddies coming up we're having a big
harvest
actually i planned everything to be
dried right at the time of 420 literally
a few days before
my entire room is going to be dried and
ready to be cured ready to [ __ ] smoke
so i invited a bunch of friends up
we got a little plot on this property
that's right up along the beach coast
and literally it's this flat spot you
can see all the way to monterey to santa
cruz beach line
and we're all camping out and we're all
doing a big [ __ ] we might be
allegedly doing mushrooms
and a bunch of other [ __ ] but my whole
harvest is coming down and we're gonna
have
fish blasting in honor of my buddy jeff
here
uh and so we're gonna you know it's
gonna be a good time so 420 up it you
know santa cruz if you're in the area
let me know i'll [ __ ] put you up on
the camping list and we'll get you guys
all up on there
i thought you did a trick i'm all trim i
was gonna say to those ninjas trim
weave real quickly they bust out their
ninja swords and just get the weed
trimmed up
and they've all got a mask on already so
everybody's safe
oh yeah dude be so much fun
one of them chops it the other one flips
it over and then they just do this a few
times and it's trimmed
yeah it's all [ __ ] done [ __ ] yeah
dude
matt i'm glad you made it bro it's been
a long time since we've got to hang out
so this was [ __ ] fun to get you in
here from socal
mid cow not even socal mid okay yeah
right on the coast
man right between monterey and san jose
and santa cruz man right in the middle
right near the beach
the ocean growing you know what i mean
no i don't know what that means
we get too much goddamn humidity that's
what it means so don't
feel bad that's what it means ocean
grown means you get too much goddamn
[ __ ] fog off the bed i was gifted
i'm not going to go too deep into this
but i was gifted some california spider
mites
bro those mendomites are the most
voracious
[ __ ] mites that i have ever dealt
with
uh shout out to the mendomites they
didn't come from behind exactly from
your neck of the woods
but no i know exactly who gave them to
you yeah don't go down that don't go
down there
i don't want to have to edit you but i'm
not going to explain the name
but those might work crazy yeah
those cali mites were the worst never
had mice like that they're probably
you know what killed them you know we
got rid of them colorado cold
that's what did it like just get it
super cold from the colorado cold and
they were like i don't know what to do
with this
and like they stopped like yeah i ruined
that [ __ ] fest for sure
that's why that's why it's so important
you hit them during veg that's why i
tell
everybody you know if you get cuts from
people you don't know or you don't
[ __ ]
have if you aren't sure about their [ __ ]
[ __ ] quarantine them shit's off
all of the protocol but those those
bites were
they were just like yeah you thought we
were gone and they just all ran out at
one time and they'll give me the finger
and like
[ __ ] you i'm flipping you off so hard
right now and then they just ran away
and i tried to hit them with pesticides
they just laughed at me dude they were
vegeta did you dip the clones in soft
oil x it seems to be about the only
thing that works
for getting ready for me
i don't have that because it just feels
like it's more uh
more harsh than i'm ready for but i'll
try it it's probably like a canola some
sort of a white oil with a wetting agent
or something in there i may do that
but a dip is a good idea yeah i dip
all my clones if it's coming in from off
property it gets dipped
i don't care if i have to to to take a
rooted clone and reroute it
it's not worth the bio security of me
you know risking the facility
yeah it did slow me down quite a bit to
be honest with you it definitely uh that
and another thing that i adjusted
another learning curve got me it's
really cramping your style i'm sure
yeah just be sure to tell people that
didn't come from my goddamn garden
you know what i'm saying they're ninja
mites bro it's already obvious where
they came from they're ninja mites
and we all know ninja
[Laughter]
that i'll never use again trust me i
didn't know what i was doing remember
when we were knew when you'd go to the
grocery store and you'd be like i have
mice they'd go here go spray this all
over your crop
and then you'd get like a wig blister on
your arm and you're like i wonder what
that's from
like it could have been the pesticides
but i hit these plants with this product
one time we're not going to talk about
what it was because [ __ ] me for doing it
i know better now i shame on me forever
using that i didn't know better
[ __ ] the guy at the groce store is what
we got to do but i use this product and
i came in the next day
and the spider mites were dead but they
were repelling from the plants they
looked like they were like
what do we do i'm out of here and they
just threw a [ __ ] web and rappelled
from the leaves like cliffhanger and
they just died swinging there
just a bunch of mites swinging in the
[ __ ] fan dead as [ __ ]
that was it was a neat thing to see but
oh my god i'll never use that product
again
i should not have done that i didn't
know any better i apologize but i'm
honest
but watching those bugs they're just
swinging
what was that organic certified there
was an organic certified
mite spray that everyone was using in
colorado for a while there and like
everyone wanted to trash their grows
like what was that
one
these guys lied and said that their
product was organic but there was other
stuff hidden
in the product that they weren't
claiming so people were failing
pesticide tests
uh i went on a podcast episode and i
talked about it and i said hey
if this is your company you've got an
open invite to be on my show whenever
you like so you can come explain this
and they never did
like i'm sure they heard it because
somebody had to plant the country
remember that's funny no i don't
remember i try to stay
i'm so busy doing a podcast i don't
worry about [ __ ] gossipy stuff i
don't have time bro
oh i know half of colorado dunks in the
eagle 21 so that's why i mentioned that
one
that was the number one yeah eagle 20 is
banned in every commercial
[ __ ] facility now that's just gone
yeah uh it burns off into cyanide gas or
something so
yeah can't have that around and if you
need that you went too hard on something
anyway buy a dehumidifier
yeah no i'm with you man i just watched
facilities do man it's not i can know i
don't get donated at all it's just one
of those things where it's like
[ __ ] man now they've got technology uh
they come in and they swab the walls
and they can tell you what pesticides
have been used for like the past two or
three years
and if they detect an illegal pesticide
in there from years ago
years ago uh if anybody gets that one
that's funny um
years ago they get your pesticides from
years ago they'll shut you down and
kill the crop that you've got and it's
all lost you got to kill everything and
start fresh
so yeah you gotta be careful with what
they sprayed in there the previous
owners could have sprayed something and
i bought that facility and now
they come in and they test it and
they're like no we found a midi culprit
in the wall and you're like ah [ __ ]
like document when you found that so
that we can kill everything before that
start fresh
i found some super uh differences being
in colorado and
uh california as far as like the
dispensary goes experience
uh you hear they don't give you three
stickers they don't check your id
three times it almost feels illegal the
way they do here you [ __ ] walk into a
dispensary they just take your [ __ ]
money and hand you weed they don't give
a [ __ ] they don't give you just
they're like they're like you wanna
risting you're like nah i don't give a
[ __ ]
it's not like call right they don't
sticker that [ __ ] up there's not three
[ __ ]
there's no plastic [ __ ] they just hand
you a [ __ ] bag of weed and they're
just like here you go man 40 bucks
you're like wow this is great
it's weird though because coming from
colorado literally they'll check your id
three [ __ ] times
literally you know at each [ __ ] stop
of it and make sure you're the same
person you were 10 seconds ago
and like stick your [ __ ] and i i almost
respect that more because it is so
thorough in colorado like it was so
thorough there
and then i got here and it was just like
basically it was like how which bag you
want bro
and i'm just like [ __ ] hell i guess
that one [ __ ] hey just
do you want a receipt no i'm good
straight you can go on now
was like what the [ __ ] that was like
they shut up and take my money kind of
thing yeah they're just like you just
[ __ ] hand us money we'll hand you
weed dude
you just get the [ __ ] out of here now
and it's weird because coming from
colorado
where they try to like oh they're going
to give you four stickers to tell you
that this will cause cancer if you're
pregnant please do not smoke this
or if you're you know this may cause all
this [ __ ] and they'll sticker it three
or four times before you can leave the
place and then they'll staple your bag
with a receipt on the outside
and they'll hand it to you and you walk
out the door after you've been an id
three times
here you you hand them id at the door
and they're just like oh you're 21 cool
sweet go in how much do you want
the first situation the first situation
to describe is when it becomes drugs
they literally felt way more black
market than i've ever felt my life
i walked in i felt like i was talking to
straight stoner sitting on his couch
[ __ ] smoking weed with me dude he was
just like here you go [ __ ] 40 bucks
dog i was like straight up
sweet i'm gonna go home now beat me at
street fighter i'll give you a half a
gram extra
hell yeah if i can beat you at [ __ ]
mario kart how much i get off
ten percent what's up dude let's do this
about buying weed sitting on some dude's
[ __ ] couch watching him [ __ ]
finish around a [ __ ] final fantasy 7
before i can get an eighth from him like
bro just press pause and give me a bag
of weed
we'd play madden for the bag
[ __ ]
i'll bet you the bag i'll bet you the
bag i'll beat you i'm mad and if i lose
i'll pay you double
oh [ __ ] do you remember blitz i bliss
was my [ __ ]
does anybody play blitz back in the day
football that was the football game of
choice right there because you got super
powers you could like [ __ ] blow
through people and [ __ ] that [ __ ]
yeah that was for people who couldn't
play madden that's
i was right p and counter strike and
used to work at a cyber cafe
i played real pro games sorry
dad sweats
oh what's up
i don't know what anybody said you all
sounded like charlie brown's teacher all
at once
right ganja i was just saying something
stupid
i wanted something it just sounds like
that anyway i score on galaga
you just told everybody how old you are
too oh [ __ ]
cheers poop the only way out have a good
one bro
don't feel bad thanks for being here
shout out to new york thank you happy
420 everyone
yeah happy shout out to new york much
longer
the mighty wrench earlier earlier you
were asking about what people do for 420
420 is kind of uh six months roughly
away from thanksgiving
does anybody else get together with
their friends and kind of have like a
thanks
stone or thanksgiving it's something
that i kind of started after we used to
do a 420 party back in
philadelphia and we were always super
hungry afterwards so one year i just got
the idea hey i'm going to cook a turkey
and we kind of turned into this huge
potluck that we had each year does
anybody else kind of do a friend's
gathering kind of thing like that
no but now that i'm doing this camping
trip i may start doing that [ __ ] hell
that sounds good can i get stone to eat
a bunch of [ __ ] rice it's going to be
miserable
i kind of went the other way i kind of
um that's why i didn't share so i
usually reserve that day for myself
um it's one of
two or maybe three days out of the year
that i'd take and i just
it's mine um i'm pretty greedy with it
that's
so i kind of went the other way i i take
my flowers and i do what i want to do
it's usually me and my dog and we go
getting lost in the woods or we go find
a lake or we go
it's just usually for me because the
rest of my life is so everybody
everybody everybody that's
i take that day for me so i kind of went
the other way i can totally see why you
would go do friends living
friendsgiving and stuff that's beautiful
but i went the other way personally
no that's that's really great that's
beautiful cascadian
it's so beautiful
i'm hoping that uh in the forest
yeah john 4 20.
[ __ ] bag of mushrooms in his hand
people's just biggest [ __ ] big old
smile on his face that's the way to do
it man
i had a lot of fun in the woods on my
trip so
you enjoy you deserve it you work hard a
long time always good for you
i'm trying to get rasta bob on the show
when his connection's a little better
it'll just be bob and i
and we're going to talk a little bit
more about another 420 aspect that a lot
of us aren't even
uh probably aware of only a couple of
people in this room probably even
understand what i'm hinting at so
it'll be a cool lesson for a lot of
people when we get bob on uh with that
uh high grade jamaican internet
connection it'll be just tim and i so we
can edit stuff out a little easier
but we'll get you going bob big respect
thank you for uh being able
available and able to do that for me
whenever you're ready ross whenever
you're ready
that's how good the uh ganja is over
there this smoke
you know really interferes with all that
connection it's uh
yeah that chalice
i saw something online i saw something
online that made me feel weird inside
when i read it
somebody had a plant outside and it was
going to go into flower
and they said how do i stop this from
going into flower we recommended
put a little led light over it right
that way it doesn't go into flower
they asked they seriously asked
will the wind outside blow the light
away from the flower
keith is cracking up you've seen this
too as a white guy you shared it with us
the guy drew a
[ __ ] picture with like the light
beams coming down
the wind like coming through and hitting
them
if you want better efficiency in your
growth for your lights just put a fan up
top and just blow the light around
i always wondered i was wondering doing
this the whole time don't you guys
understand that
that light is photons i mean come on i
don't know
i know i want two of whatever
why the guys would have the fans blowing
on their plants like that because you
always see the plants like shaking in
the wind i'm like
that's not healthy right but if you
gotta blow all the light
onto the plant then that man it's just
mind-blowing dude i can't believe it i
just
started talking when you started talking
i assumed they meant like blowing the
light
itself away like the unit not the light
that's
being that's what i was like oh i guess
i guess if it's a lightweight the wind
because what if it's hanging
like i was like
is that what for the sake of humanity i
wish that's what they were asking but
this person truly thought that the
lumens or the whatevers the jewels
the photons were going to get blown away
is this person from hey i'm not going
which part of
wherever i'm not even going to say a
place but yeah we need to protect this
person they
they're a jewel to society we we very
rarely come from
this right it could be a great museum
yeah so you guys when you put your
lights outside put up a windscreen to
prevent
the [ __ ] lumens from being stolen by
by the way
so you know the whole like single photon
slit
experiment where you get like different
scatter patterns
i always wondered if you took like a
grid pattern that was like really
microscopic and put it as like a
a filter on your light if you could get
a bigger scatter pattern with the
photons
anyways just on like a total nerd thing
i wish i understood enough that to
understand any of that the double slit
experiment yeah
like a micro light diffuser that's
that's the concept of a light diffuser
um in a in like a commercial setting
they have the lights warehouse oh yeah
i'm just talking about between the light
and the actual thing anyways
it's totally just like stupid proof of
concept like a magnifying glass will
burn
it'll help make the light more intense
to burn my leaves why can't we put a
special shape of lids on there to give
us i see where you're going bro
something the same idea just a bunch of
little magnifying glasses that are just
enough to make it better but not enough
to burn
any lens that you put on top of the led
actually is a decrease in efficiency
whether you use a 90 degree lens or any
other sort of lenses that you see that
aftermarket
a lot of companies use but they all uh
they equal inefficiency in the
transmission of
ppfd to the canopy so yeah you
the best way is to have nothing between
the led
and your plants well yeah like it has to
bounce
to get through there turn down the damn
leds because my plants didn't like 100
i was amazed they wanted like uh closer
to 50 to introduce them they had to
adjust for a while my plants were kind
of mad at me
i got a phantom led right now i had to
run it at 60 percent because
anything over that i started yellow
leaves and started getting to curl their
tips up and i was like ah
you [ __ ] [ __ ] and even if you
pulled them off what you thought with an
hbs would work
at about 60 it would work very well but
any more than 60
it was just [ __ ] curling up leaves
and making them not happy
i don't know i had yellow on me they
were it was just like hey that's too
much light i'm gonna go yellow fast
but i've learned and that's and i i'm
[ __ ] excited about learning i was
like oh they're going yellow what do i
do
like i always know what to do in the
grove and i walked in i was like oh this
is
kind of exciting to see if i can fix
them and bring them out of this crap
yeah i haven't had to do that in a while
since i worked at this one commercial
girl where
i felt like a couple of guys were just
purposely trying to throw wrenches in
the works every day
to walk in and find out what they did
yeah i kind of wonder like what you guys
do with hid lights that
you can't just like raise and dim um
because
like if you are giving a plant
you know 18 hours of light in veg and
then you cut it down
you know 33 to 12 hours for flower um
you know that's 33 less light every day
so like to give them the same intensity
and veg and flower
like is definitely not optimal
well generally you'd run a much lower
wattage or you wouldn't run
hids in bed anyway you would probably
switch to hids once you hit flower
for the most part you know 315's uh cmh
are
kind of the popular veggies like right
now but running hids in general like you
would not want to just run
like straight up hids and then try to go
into flower from there
but the 12 12 photo period that's how
plants work and they're naturally going
to want to work on that photo period of
12 12. so when you reduce that light
it's just changing how they permit uh
the hormones that are in the plant to
switch into flowers it's not a matter of
reducing how much light is getting and
photosynthesis it needs that to switch
into that photo period
but i would i would say when you veg
with hid
it's really easy to use the lux meter
and use numbers and
yeah and vegetable and but it is getting
less light but in for you
it's it's a lot higher of a
light intensity than it is in veg
so um
okay i had a learning curve where it was
like
clearly getting too much light but you
know i was like oh it's pretty high up
okay i have i had them on
full blast because it's just kind of
what we do
yeah put it
yes it was just like okay no
yeah i had the same learning curve and
um
it's getting less light time
it's getting more than delivered
i'm gonna kill your camera brother
because you're kind of cutting out but
we'll keep your audio going we're gonna
stop your video for you
i got you yeah yeah you sound much
better now
yeah much better um you're saying
sweet but so
it gets less light in
flower
it also gets about double a little more
than double the intensity
um i would go from about 20 lux
to 60
60 depending on the cultivar um
so it is getting more light energy in
flower
um even with the radius
oh he's cutting out a lot i'm gonna
interrupt him a lot um i've noticed that
i can definitely reduce the amount of
hours i run my lights with the leds
compared to when i was running the hps's
i used to run 20 on and five off because
i keep mother plants for breeding
and i like to keep them growing but
definitely not going into flower
and i want to producing a lot of clones
for me i was able to put the veg room
down to 18-6
and i don't see any plants trying to
flower early
and i noticed they start drooping later
in the day which tells me they've gotten
enough light they're tired they're
sleepy they're ready to take a nap
so yeah i'm definitely running less
light hours and i've got
the leds i thought that they went that
that knob went 100 to zero percent but
it's like
uh it's different so i even turned them
down further than i thought i had them
i've got them less than 50
right now and i've gone maybe too close
together but my clients are loving it
now that i kind of figured it out
uh i get the less hours less intensity
it feels like if you're giving them the
right light they don't need nearly as
much of it
and they're just they're beasting out
and i think environment plays a lot in
that
light uh you know there's guys who run
11 13 i think even durham and dan before
did an
uh uh episode of embracing organics
where they were talking about doing 11
is versus the 12 12 just to reduce you
know the overall monthly light bill but
you can still achieve
some of the same goals maybe with a
higher tdg ratio uh
giving them more dark to light um but
just also reducing you know one hour a
day
uh and light cycle so there's definitely
room to play with these photo period
plants and i think if
uh you know i don't know if you're if
you're worried about like some of the
uh differences between the switching and
transition you know that's part of why
like there is that transition period
where they say you know like
uh you know going from flower to you
know going from veg to flower you
probably gotta you know a couple days
before they start
start to really take that photo period
you know before they start to show that
they're starting those signs you'll even
notice that they
they have that veg cycle down even if
you're running in eighteen six they'll
still assume that for the first three to
five days
even in your flowers like when you first
switch them it's just how photoperiod
work
and uh reducing them to that isn't going
to affect them so much
if you're still maintaining the same
kind of intensity or if you run into hid
from t5s
that's just how we've always ran
one thing i've noticed for sure is that
the batch of seeds i made under led
lights have the best germination rate of
any seeds i've ever made
that's that's something i can for sure
say these seeds are
like all these packs are sealed right
dump it up dump them out and show you to
look at vacuum sealed these packs so
i can't show you sorry and if you get
them you're mad that they're sealed
don't complain they're sealed you know
they're tamper free
i've had a couple people be like bro i
tried for an hour to get that open
it's not my fault you need a helmet and
velcro shoes it's just a [ __ ] heat
seal you can get it open
come on
with those things i really
i'd love to hear steve's view on you
know light cycles and stuff because you
know he bases a lot of his stuff
especially greenhouse work and stuff
like that based on the season cycles and
life cycles of the region
so i'd definitely like to hear you know
maybe how he bases a lot more
when he starts seasons and you know
based on his area of you know
where he thinks uh you know different
parts of the year are better for certain
areas i would love to hear kind of some
of the light seasons that he's
experienced
if i'm going to transition something
outdoors i try to get within an hour of
what it's going to
transition into generally they won't
pout too much within about an hour hour
and a half
difference when you get past that they
really start pouting
and you might have a bit of a slow down
period where it kind of was curious if
it wants to go to flower and it'll go
back to veg
most of the time or you know just hang a
couple of
obnoxious uh you know like you go to the
walmart
or lowe's or any of these other box
stores after christmas
they always have those like regular leds
and then the obnoxiously bright white
ones right
those obnoxiously bright white ones are
great for just throwing over your plants
for two hours
just to give them that extra day you
know on your outdoor there's
i mean they're still useful for
something and you can get them on
clearance
you know after christmas and oftentimes
this time of year they're discounted
because
they're not they're not moving so that's
definitely something else that
you know i like to do now i i will say
too on the other direction that i've
seen quite a bit of different cultivars
particularly in the cbd cultivars
throw um male flowers if they're kept
under 24 hours of
of daylight even in veg well they'd be
beautiful beautiful looking female
flowers
but in in each node there's one to four
little tiny flowers that are you know
occasionally throwing pollen
now if i drop those same same exact
plants down to 186
they stopped doing that now the only
difference that i've changed on those in
that particular grow was the lights
nothing else changed no nutrients no
temperature no that was the only thing
and it was the jamaican lion lions and
the
the ac dc lines were the two that that
were showing that particular expression
and
i just attributed it to being you know
something to do with cbd because cbd in
particular is
fairly pigeonholed genetic
well pretty much too there's only a few
places in the world where there's 24
hour light you know you have the reuter
wallace in russia and you have alaska
there are
places where it does the 24-hour
situation why i imagine a lot of the
photoperiod
plants are not prepared honestly for
yeah that kind of
anyway so it makes sense that that would
be the case
i think plants are just like humans if
you keep us awake for 24 hours
for a long period of time we go crazy
plants do that too they have hormones
that
have to be produced at nighttime and if
they don't have a sleep cycle
it chemically has a hard time producing
certain compounds
and i'm sure it would negatively impact
the immune system of the plant as well i
mean that would probably be the first
thing to suffer
when you're thinking about putting them
outside and trying to match the uh
the daylight hours of outside sorry my
brain could think work daylight hours uh
when you're trying to match those
daylight hours are you thinking about
the uh the far red light that the sun's
putting off as it goes down are you
compensating for any of that
i've never worried about that the only
time i've ever tried to worry about that
is if i was trying to make them go to
sleep faster
um the phytochrome uh you know when you
with the far red triggers that
phytochrome and the leaves and
and it helps put the plants to sleep and
i've seen quite a bit of data that shows
that
you know it does make a pretty
significant difference you can even eke
out you know extra half hour an hour
with your lights on
um if you're really trying to push
numbers and still have that same sleep
period as far as
you know that hormone build up to
actually make the plants fully you know
have that full sleep cycle
so definitely uh definitely something
that you can play with a little bit but
i haven't done anything on the outdoor
i'll be honest with you on all the the
bigger stuff that i've done the last
three years
including africa we had a greenhouse
facility that was basically the nursery
that cranked out all the production
plants
and we did a couple of testers in there
and stuff like that maybe had a you know
two or three flowering rooms and then
everything else was just mass produced
for the fields right so once we figured
out that which cultivars were going to
give us really good production
we were cloning that out and again the
consistency of production that you get
from clones still beats the living
daylights out of seed you know
um uh you know you need you need to have
that if you're really going to have now
i do think that you know in another few
years they'll get the genetics
stabilized but
um certainly not with autos but
definitely with and
you know less or so with photos they're
just not stable enough to have mass seed
batches that are that
you know over ten thousand or fifty or a
hundred thousand seeds
that are you know that predictable of a
key mars the kingdom of our
stability it just doesn't exist and who
knows if we'll ever be able to achieve
that i mean just look at apple trees
they've never achieved that genetically
ever to be able to have i mean if you
take an apple
uh an apple tree every single seed of
that apple tree is a different pheno
that's why johnny appleseed was able to
have so many different strains named
after him and contributed him is because
he planted more phenos than anyone else
did that's awesome
how much knowledge you bring brother we
have a better chance of doing it with
cannabis than we do with appleseed
though
oh yeah wait way better chance for sure
yeah i don't mean to say we can't i'm
just saying that yeah much shorter
we're quite a few years off i hate to
interrupt you gentlemen but uh we had
another lady join the group we gotta
take a moment to welcome the lady uh
cass popped in i'm gonna give her a
minute to tell us where she's from
because that has been the custom
cass where are you joining us from
tonight cheers from texas
i kind of felt that coming
coming um i'm not sure if you want
people stalking you on social media but
i usually give people
a chance to tell us their social media
uh tell them how they can find you or
your business online if you want to or
you could tell me to not do that if you
want
i will say steve uh one thing that i
heard from a botanist is kind of scary
she got interrupted and went silent
sorry cass
they talked right over your in your
intro follow cassie guys if you know how
to follow cass follow her
go ahead bro what are you saying i would
say one thing that i've heard from a
botanist
is that uh they would like to unicrop
cannabis in the same way that they have
done tomatoes and potatoes in our
uh and our in our grocery stores to
where it's very much
the same crop that they produce mass
massively on tissue culture levels where
it's
you know one you know specific thing and
i've heard botanists talk about you know
trying to stabilize out cannabis into
the way
to where they can do that as well which
i don't think they'll be able to do
because cannabis lovers also love
variety
but uh it is one of the things that if
they were to go to federal that they've
talked about a lot of botanists are very
big on the unit cropping idea
of you know monetizing and just trying
to make one crop that you can reproduce
non-stop that's just you know
commercially viable and it's going to be
ahead of no way
we'll get tired of that so quickly i go
to the dispensary and i never buy the
same thing two times in a row unless
it's something i've read and they got it
but every time i go i get different
concentrates yeah but how many times do
you ask for a different tomato at the
grocery store dog
how many times do you ask us that's
that's a different
different ballgame but i got roma's i
got cherries i got uh those purple
hearts but yeah
i think uh there's always and if that
does happen you're always going to be
growing [ __ ] something you bred and
i'm going to be growing something i
bread and uh hopefully steve's growing
something he bred and hopefully painted
ladies growing something high bread
yeah i've just i've heard rumors from
several botanists and several people on
the multi-million dollar kind of
commercial facilities who are trying to
sew
hardcore mono crops so they can just get
these consistent [ __ ]
that's just all the same and it's just
kind of horrifying to think because we
all love so much variety as cannabis
consumers
the gentleman that brought you quote
unquote outrageous new strains was
summarily fired two weeks ago
do their credit just because they want
to mono crop something doesn't mean
it's going to suck and it doesn't mean
they want monocrop
enough varieties to fill a walmart um
i'm not uh i'm not for that game i'm
just playing devil's advocate
uh if they've got they've got the
resources to
line breed one into
homogeny they can do that again
so if they can offer you one that they
can grow by the acre
watch out because in five years they'll
offer you 10. well well that's what they
do right now in idaho with the potato
crops that literally my family has
several potato farms
up there and right now lays and [ __ ]
pringles have their own potato that they
tissue culture and every time they
produce the same potato
they only have the same potato they mono
crop for those companies because they're
specifically bred
to be what that company wants it's a
certain shape that works well in their
machines it's a certain shape that cuts
to the right point
uh you know certain ones want elongated
potatoes potatoes certain ones
rounded potatoes depending on the
company they'll monitor crop it out and
tissue culture
to the end of existence so we're going
to cut up tomatoes or potatoes i said
tomatoes damn what's wrong with my brain
injury
i did that the other day talking about
the
he was potatoes up to say something just
know there's no rapper
talking about [ __ ] idahos and russets
like nobody's got no rappers
so as soon as a rapper starts rapping
about potatoes then it'll change but
everybody wants different weed like
everybody's gonna always want different
we i'm a breeder and i know that
the mono crop ideal work a little bit in
a big old commercial those guys this
facility
mono crop at the [ __ ] out but uh nobody
buys one pack of the
one pack of seeds from it they always
get two packs and they always get like
multiple different kinds so
i don't see too many of the the home
growers and the basement buccaneers
doing that
like no not necessarily without the
product
not the not the home growers but when
you got somebody that wants to launch
now you got to open your mind a little
bit look into the future a little bit
but when you've got somebody that wants
to
launch an international product and they
need to reproducible
cannabinoids they need a stabilized line
that can grow the same
year to year to year to keep their
product as consistent as you expect your
cognac to be um
[Music]
it's a it's a different ball game you'll
always have the people that are making
the
you'll always have the the exotic mics
of the world but you're gonna have
come on come on some of us have to grow
mids okay some of us have
guys
and if we grow it we're going to go
allah
all right
right now people only know two red
cigarettes
are green cigarettes it's only two type
they have mental or
some red type so once you have it a lot
in demand it will be offered in the
future
greatest thing about the ganjapay it
will always get bigger and bigger
and bigger so the craft market will grow
and
you know our commute market will you
know get there eventually so everybody
will have a nice piece of the pipe to
eat
do you guys get strain lock and you guys
get tired of smoking the same thing like
if i gave you
i was like you could have 100 pounds of
herb would you want like 100 pounds of
mike's favorite strain is the grateful
dog are you still taking a hundred
pounds of grateful dog are you gonna
switch up and want some
strawberry or muted bro you want some
strawberry coffee in 10 10 10
10.
and and then we got guys like
out there keeping stuff you know uh
keeping things natural you know we we
got a lot of interbred stuff here in the
in the states i'm proud of roster bob
keeping everything kind of
firey and [ __ ] traditional you know
that that that sound gruner
didn't call me an inbreeder you just
call me an inbreeder
i mean you know i'm you keep it
traditional too you know i mean you
supply some stuff you know for some
incredible people too my guy but you
know i am proud of rastabob for staying
with your dish
man i gotta i gotta troll you man you
came in hot tonight i gotta troll you
back you came in hot you're gonna get
trolled
don't make don't make me rush g jeff
don't make me roast you right now
come on come on come down with the new
table bro you haven't been to the new
table we gotta get you soaked
in oh man uh yeah i had a bad medical
visit today so i'm trying to stress too
hard on that right now yeah i wasn't
gonna go there
but uh if you need anything bro
everybody in this chat's got your back
so
i like trolling on you but definitely
nothing but love for you come sit at the
table take some dabs for sure
you know i love you guys
i don't want 100 pounds of the same weed
i want a lot of different weed because i
feel like i get
i don't know i feel like after a certain
amount of time i they just don't it just
doesn't do it for me anymore and then i
have switched up and they go back to and
we have to be grateful
we have to be grateful that we are at
this point we can be picky
usually it was high grade
you can get a red stripe or a green
stripe or a gold stripe one
you always know what you're getting when
you run out in between all right
there's a couple things i've had in my
lifetime
just a couple where i could smoke 100
pounds of that
and not complain and not ask for
anything different
maybe two or three but that's it what is
it you're gonna have to tell me at least
yeah yeah we all want to know one of
them at least
i think that's like that there's there's
nothing did you like
the pre-98 bubba set me back man that
was a life changer all right
um and if you ever if you ever get a
real
sour a real sour not some [ __ ] that
somebody called
sour but real sour that [ __ ] will blow
you right off your feet
shipwreck um white mike
all right let me help the panel a bit
let me help the panel a little bit oh
connection what about that
that we always go to we might not want
to admit it
but you know just we find ourselves just
going back to it every now and then we
just want to grow it again if we get a
cut we're going to run it again
we just always have to have it you know
so
you know it kind of grows on you some of
them grows on you be
you know blue raspberry truffle wink
wink
i can't get rid of the lemon g i mean
the terps are just too good
that makes me smile i'm with cascadian
with that
bubble man i just can't get away from it
it's so good
the pre-98 bubba and the hollywood pure
code
oh yeah dude we have a similar a similar
flavor palette the sweetness the
funkiness
let me let me get one out the jar real
quick
i think mine would have to be i got some
really amazing seeds from dragonfly
earth medicine the g13 hash plant
i can smoke that every day the whole day
all day
and it just puts me in a really good
head space where i get a ton of stuff
done
and focus really well and just makes me
happy nice how about you sequence you've
been quiet what do you like to smoke
uh i got this crescendo behind my head i
could smoke a lot of that but max nice
gmo probably some chicken with that gmo
mike's got some crescendo concentrates
that company makes a great crescendo
batter
really nice gmo is a really potent
strain so it's one like if you were
going to put a lot of it in front of
yourself that's one that you would pick
because it almost always tests it like
30 plus percent
and you know if you're gonna have a
shitload of a strain and you're gonna
get a tolerance
to it you might as well get one that'll
get you there yeah
if you guys ever come across the uh star
dog cory
cut uh thank me later you won't be
disappointed
that is that the one that smells kind of
like strawberries and watermelons and
kind of
real good for a commercial girl i don't
i didn't get that from me
okay i think that's allegedly the cut
that i made star struck with
allegedly but i have no proof of that
look at his face three it's three uh
this one is first i mean the cut the cut
is about
maybe a year and a half but this is
maybe
like three months right in my perfect
smoking zone right yeah
all right i hate to admit it but i will
admit it i just keep getting
why you know after i always have a zip
for a quarter
just yeah right now or a half quarter
what does it smell like the bomb what is
what does bubba smell like
all right this one is sweet
but it's not that artificial sweet it's
like
sugary but very mild sugar
not like i would say like mapley but not
super sweet
if you understand it's not the sweet
part of maple it's more like that
honeysuckle
i don't know it's kind of earthy and you
know
earthy and sweet you know it's sweet
earth but it's not like
super sugary loud candy you understand
it's
kind of mellow earthy mellow sweet
like a subtle it's the same vibrate than
it gives the same vibration it gives you
know your smoke it is kind of very
smooth
the first one is oh wow it's very nice
and by the second
our third bull bubba hug you up give you
one of them big bug or hog you know
hug your flight bubble but it's nice
they're very pleasurable you know
and you can go to it consistently i
really have to say
anybody else got to go to oh mr bagsy
made it back hey
anybody else got to go too straight that
you could just smoke 50 pounds of and
never get tired of it
we beat that question really smoke
anything i don't know yeah there we go
somebody's grateful someone who's
grateful cass you've been super quiet is
there anything you could smoke
a hundred pounds of and not get burned
out
i don't think so you're a diamond dabber
aren't you more into diamonds and [ __ ]
well which part do not get burnt out i
don't
like you can't just smoke any amount of
anything or
variety is the spice of oh lord
sauces and spices yeah that that hundred
pound girl might take bigger dabs than
everybody in this room
i'm sure of it me and keith kind of
hanging the dab that same
dab what do you call it you know the box
micro dabs
micro dab
all day shout out to the half quarter
gang you might be able to smoke me under
the table with
with concentrates but i can make a
[ __ ] magic trick out of your weed
wow i can smoke your weed out your
flowers but
i can't hang on the concentrates we've
all got our thing
edibles make me goofy if i eat too many
so and i
don't like smoking some garlic earlier
and i can't tell the garlic would have
really did good we tried it out here and
i can't tell you the grass is on the
blend so
this is one of our garlic productions
i don't remember that drink horlicks
like
um oh or ovaltine or
we'll have one they call it horlicks so
they call garlic you know kind of garlic
but a little bit sweeter but it
still has that garlic smell you know but
and it's strong the effect there
i don't know gmo are not familiar with
the names but that garlic
turps are whatever really really is
doing yeah
it under peanut butter made a nice
influence on that oh yeah you know it
was all garlic
it was our candy and dessert and you
know wedding cake and this kind of
sugary dish and donuts and ice cream and
the garlic and the peanut butter just
kind of you know really diversified
the portfolio sounds pretty good when
you come back
feels like other drugs it goes through
your body in a different way it feels so
nice
it's like a hug it's like a big garlic
hug
but i'm gonna i'm gonna um push up
somebody real quick just make sure you
plant better than painted lady
i'm gonna have to head out of here
before i turn into a pumpkin guys
cheers we'll see you next time
thanks for being here anytime you want
to uh chill and do a podcast or whatever
just hit me up
i like that i definitely do i'll text
you later today to say thanks for this
awesome thank you congrats on the new
baby yeah yeah
i'm sure you can hear them in the
background go enjoy everyone
reading projects running steve
uh all right guys we've been going for a
long time we've gone for like two hours
and 40 minutes
uh this is gonna be a long ass youtube
video i might edit some of this i might
not i haven't made any of those
decisions yet
um i'm gonna start right now and say uh
thank you guys this was a good time
thanks for giving me two and a half
hours of everybody's evening that was
awesome
does anybody have any fun [ __ ] they'd
like to say that they got skipped on
left out of before we started wrapping
up this two hour and 45 minute show
i just you i appreciate it i'm gonna say
if you're out there and you don't have a
community kind of like we have here on
this go create one start a local grow
club
i we didn't have one down here in
southern oklahoma we just got together
with a local
hookah lounge and we're like hey can we
host the thing there and they're like
yeah we can't have anybody here
right now because of covid so sure so
now they let us every every second
tuesday of every month
we can kind of take over the hookah
lounge and we bring traffic to there and
and it's kind of on a neutral territory
so dispensaries can all come there and
no one's feeling weird about it and
share knowledge share your knowledge you
know if you're the person that knows the
most in your area
teach the other people around you you
know go be the person out there that's
what 420 is all about is sharing with
the
knowledge and seeds and everything else
that we have and then the fruits of our
labor so go out there and create
communities wherever you are and you'll
be surprised how quickly you know all
kinds of cool things happen
i love that steve there's a there's a
steve in every state every community you
guys somebody just has to step up and be
that guy
uh why mike is not in the chat right now
i don't see him but why mike would say
do your political part if you're the guy
that does the the lobbying the politics
part
do that part fill that role uh everybody
in here does a role in the cannabis
community i make the seeds keith makes
the lights
everybody does a part in here so find
your role find your niche in that
community and step up you're absolutely
right steve thank you i appreciate you
for saying that
that's awesome dude build the community
join ours also you can be a part of ours
there's
uh i do my own show my own style steve's
show is his show a different style
but both shows are [ __ ] awesome in
their own right embracing organics is a
great show
all the shows out there watch them all
find the one that works for you i mean
you may hate my show and love steve's or
you may love mine and steve's and hate
the other ones out there find the ones
that are the best for you
we aren't mad at you if you don't watch
our show we don't even know honestly so
yeah join our community create your own
spread the vibe uh team cannabis that's
what it's all about we want to make all
this
legal for everybody everywhere so nobody
has to go to jail for cannabis nobody
has to
[ __ ] worry about getting medicine
nobody has to worry about recreating and
us grow enthusiasts can just grow our
[ __ ] asses off to keep all those
people happy
so great message steve anybody else got
anything else out there because i talk a
lot
i just wanted a quick thank everybody is
in here man steve it's been a pleasure
to [ __ ] talk to you
again [ __ ] since the indo-expo ladies
always great to hear from you
everybody in here thank you guys for
being in here man it's always a pleasure
to talk to all you guys and you know uh
jeff especially man you're an old friend
of mine and i can't wait
thanks for hanging out man [ __ ] this
has been an awesome
experience it's been fun bro thank you
for joining us uh we'll have to see you
soon man mike and i look forward to
seeing you you're gonna come out here
we're gonna go out there and harass the
[ __ ] out of you sometime soon
santa cruz bro in the summer time gotta
take somebody out there and go go visit
um all right anybody else got any final
words any uh jerry's moments what do
they call it at the end when jerry did
that [ __ ]
jerry's moments jerry's thoughts trey's
final thoughts who's got that for us
today
well just uh thank you so much for
having all the cross-platform love
uh i was trying to count all the shows
that were being repped because of you
like
here uh yours uh potentponics
uh the neighborhood uh shout out to
operation bro we've had an
uh cousin troopy show uh
duckweed what was uh remind me again
what's the show grow
bro grow for show please check them out
uh check us out neighborhood
and uh gosh that's michigan bros grow
show
exactly yeah so yeah racing organics is
wrapped down here we've got a lot of
people covered
awesome thank you bro you're in for it
you're always
yeah somebody and yeah until i try to
avoid it yeah yeah that's why i'm like
listing everything off like
you go to edit and you're like oh [ __ ] i
forgot someone real important they're
going to hate you yeah
some people like matched up like yeah
exactly yeah
and exactly the cannabis community i
really appreciate all the cross-platform
love
that's what it should be about like
we're all just trying to learn we're all
just trying to
do better for ourselves and the people
that we care about and our community
just like ponix was saying uh do what
you can
locally do what you can through the
internet even with
whatever position you are in your job
you can you can make a difference
absolutely that's a great way to
reference family yes don't be a dick and
show love that's probably the best way
to wrap it up good good note there dave
uh good good reminder it's amazing that
that came from you anyway
uh thank you guys thanks everybody for
joining me this was awesome to have such
a
loyal group of friends i honestly didn't
know how many people would show up so
this was amazing big shout out to
everybody on every screen i'm looking at
big love much respect for all of you
guys i look forward to getting all of
you on a show individually
uh talking a little bit more about your
specified topic i know everybody here is
a special niche
uh big shout out to everybody watching
i'm gonna sign off with my friends here
say goodbye and then i'll be back to do
like an official wrap up for the podcast
all right all right all right i think
that was a glorious train wreck i'm not
sure what i expected when i invited 100
people to join me on a zoo meeting
i'm not sure that if i expected 25 of
them to show up but i am grateful that
they did
i think i had a good time i think i
handled it well that was the first time
i've ever hosted a zoo meeting
with approximately 25 people so i had a
good time i learned a lot i will be
doing
things kind of like that in the future
maybe not with that many that is kind of
a
circus with that many people but i will
be doing more things with more zoom
guests now that i've had some practice
and gotten better at it
i want to send a big thank you to each
and every person who stopped into that
zoo meeting
if you were there for 30 seconds or two
and a half or four hours
thank you i do appreciate all of the
love the support the participation
without each and every member of the ire
army it would not be what it is you all
feel your own role your own position
your own spot i need every one of you
we all appreciate you thank you big
salute to everybody who popped in
also thanks to everybody who has watched
this far this has been an extremely long
podcast
with very little grow knowledge and a
lot of just rambles and hanging out
i hope you had a good time i hope you
got to celebrate 420 with us
i think that is all we've got i hope you
guys noticed how many people were
rocking
the irie genetics merchandise on that
show that means a lot to me
to check out a show and everybody's
wearing my gear thank you guys
that was super cool if you feel like
this episode was educational informative
entertaining
maybe you had a good time maybe you just
like to throw me a couple of bucks for
my work
all you have to do is visit my patreon
at patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need is right
there on the screen of course i'll put a
link in the show notes
and the video description to make it
super easy for all of my friends
also check out my website
iriegenetics.com
all things rosta jeff all things grow
from your heart all things
ire genetics are right there of course
at iregenetics.com
then if you've got any questions
corrections comments or concerns maybe
some updates maybe some constructive
criticism maybe some kind of feedback
you can send me an email my email
address is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com you know i do look
forward
to hearing from all of my friends i
think that is all i've got for this
extremely long episode enjoy your 420
i'll be back in a couple of days with
fresh new content i think you're gonna
like the next episode
i want to give a giant shout out to
everybody who participated in the 420
episode
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
foreign