yeah welcome back podcast world
i'm your host my friends call me rosta
jeff and this is episode
631 of the grow from your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to feature my
friend rasta bob from jamaica
before we get there let's do a few shout
outs to a few members of the 710 club
of course the 710 club or those folks
who support us on patreon
at the 7 and 10 cent a month level or
higher so with no further ado let's
start off with the big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out
to my friend groove2112 let's send a big
thank you shout out to nicholas a
let's send a thank you shout out to 10
pitcher let's send a thank you shout out
to only one kenobi
let's send a big girl from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to my
friends susan burns and aaron weeks
let's send a thank you shout out to
smokey mcpot let's hit a big thank you
shout out to d
ober and big bad john let's send a big
thank you shout out to audrey k
and big head todd and then let's wrap it
up with the big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out
to my friend chandler big thanks and big
shout out to everybody who continues to
support the show on patreon
if you are not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need is right
there on the screen and you know i did
include a link in the show notes and the
video description
to make it super easy for all of my
friends who want to support the show
for real big up thank you for all of the
continued support
i don't want to ramble on too much at
the start of this show because this is a
great episode in my opinion
i do want to say thank you for watching
the 420 episode
the previous episode was the 420 episode
i had about 25
30 friends popped through through the
zoo meeting i think there were 22 people
on screen at one time a few people came
a few people went
big thanks big shout out to everybody
who came through big thanks and big
shout out to everybody who watched that
show it was kind of a beautiful glorious
train wreck
i don't know that i will invite so many
people on camera ever again
but it was a wonderful experience and i
did enjoy it but like i said i don't
know if we'll do that again we will have
shows with other guests but certainly
not
25 other guests
[Music]
all right that part is out of the way i
thanked you for the 420 show
now this is the 4 21 show
uh there is a special significance for
420 and 421 in the rastafari culture
i got some good friends to teach us
about it big shout out to my friends
who came from kingston jamaica to teach
us about
420 and 421 in rastafari culture
a couple of things i should mention
before we roll that clip
uh there are a lot of sounds of jamaica
in the background they are not recording
in a recording studio
they are recording in a banana field in
kingston jamaica
so you will hear birds you will hear
dogs you may hear a car
you may hear some jamaican reggae music
in the background
uh it is the natural sound of jamaica i
enjoy it i appreciated it
bob and i were having some scheduling
conflicts i was actually out of town for
the 4 20 weekend and a couple of days
before that
uh bob was trying to record with me then
also bob's got that beautiful
jamaican internet so his internet wasn't
really super strong at some times in a
zoo meeting kind of
goes wonky a little bit so bob was kind
enough to set up a camera
grab a rastafari elder big thanks and
big respect to the rastafari elder who
appeared on camera for us to teach us
a lot about rastafari and 420 and the
correlation
but bob grabbed the camera they pressed
record and they recorded a segment to
teach us
about the importance of 420 and 421 to
jamaica and rosters and rastafari across
jamaica
um this will raise some questions you
guys will have a lot of questions if
you're not familiar with rasta culture
some of these things may be brand new
words brand new terms brand new phrases
to you
if you've got any questions i look
forward to your emails your questions my
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
cannot wait to hear the questions that
this show brings up
you guys i feel like i'm rambling i said
i wasn't going to do that
so with no further ado let's bring in
the segment with rasta bob and his
friend
from jamaica
let's say the record game
all right so the importance of 420 to
rastafari it's trying to show the
international community that
you know just thinking about the visit
of his majesty
on the 21st and the year that it
happened
i think it was a 63. six 66
right so thinking back in jamaica's
history but then ganja was super
illegal criminalized you know where
rasta was being beaten and you know
you know eventually it was very hard
time where people would take on the
grandchild but that day i knew it's
particular it was almost like it was
free
that day you know i hear people talking
about thousands of charlie santos and
jaspreef and
urban police not knowing what to do they
actually gave a free-for-all they didn't
even was
concerned about ganja
and that day 420 in the preparation
you know intensity for his visit of his
imperial majesty the following day the
21st
so i'll just kind of open if you could
just you know come on
give thanks um i think that
what we now know as 420.
didn't exist until perhaps a decade or a
little less than a decade
after 1966 which is when his majesty
came to jamaica
now the important visit of his majesty
started
from the 18th of april in trinidad
which was his first stop but by the 21st
of april he was on his way to jamaica
now jamaica had declared a public
holiday
for the 21st of april 1966
to meet the arrival of his majesty
what that meant is that rastafari who
was still very much
the outcast in jamaica started to
mobilize themselves on the 20th
so the 20th became a major mobilization
day for rastafari and
if you remember that at those in those
days rastafari couldn't take a bus
and didn't have certain kind of access
so the accounts of various bedrooms that
they started to walk
from all over the island into the
gullies through the hope valley
in an effort to get out by the airport
and in so doing
they were also sure that a part of the
celebration was ganja
so part of the account of his majesty
is people actually came out with her
branches
palm leaves ganja big star
yeah as as parts of the celebration of
this
ancient um king who would now touch down
on the jamaican land what it meant is
that
rastafari who whole ganja as
a part of the connection to divine
wanted to incense create a
a herb atmosphere to receive the
solomonic king because you know
as far as we are concerned uh ganja is a
part of that solomonic legacy
a part of our lore is that it is the
herb that emerges from the tomb of
solomon
after he passes so in receiving this
king
and in keeping with our fire element
because fire is an element that is very
much central
to rastafari experience and in lieu of
building a fire key and holding an ayah
the ritual of ganja becomes the
embodiment of that fire principle
so what is said is that brethren
stormed the tarmac blazing
chalice and issuing smoke or incense
of her ganja and the official
protocol could do nothing but just
silently observe they couldn't
choose to arrest our in any way abuse
rastafari which still was very much
standard because
if you remember three years before his
majesty arrived in jamaica
we had a major rastafari repression in
the cardinals incident in 1963
so a part of our conversation is that
his majesty actually come
three years later to check on ironi
particularly
well i don't know i don't i don't want
yesterday from there so that's why 63
was sticking out
in my brain so the coral gardens
incident was really just in summary for
all the viewers and listeners
was just where the state itself for my
overstanding
the government issued a decree that you
know a terrible attraction
yeah kill them kill them on site beat
them kill them and
it wasn't even the police and the
soldiers that were given that that are
character i heard that even the
excellence of society yeah the public
but i get your point um the real thing
is that
herb became a major part of how
rastafarian mobilized
the day before his majesty arrives right
so in our mind
the the real beginning of 420
is our overnight vision in
receiving his majesty now i know 420
also has a time
issue as a culture operating around a
certain time of the day
for this herb sacrament and i i wouldn't
necessarily claim that rastafari needed
that kind of
retreat that the 420 space that emerges
in the 70s among
mummies and you know a range of people
who are trying to have this
break for us herb is not a break
it is a part of our
consistent communing you know um
in in some instances people talk about
micro dosing well
it is our micro dosing throughout the
day
if we are allowed to uh because it
doesn't impair
it in fact we develop the kind of
training where herb becomes a necessary
sort of nutrient to fuel and keep our
work moving
and we come out of that space where
herb infused work becomes
clearly a demonstration of our
spirituality and our philosophy
in fact some people think that they
can't work unless the heavens have been
set
um correctly in this herb space so our
herb approach is not necessarily
driven by an oar even though we do have
that kind of approach
where people would have a morning cup as
a way of setting themselves
for the day and then you know they might
want one
midday um certainly after work
and that is usually now i suppose more
in keeping with that idea of 420
that after work unwinding usually
um in a congregation that's when well i
think i think it does more the school
has that again after school you know 420
that was really the old high school that
was when you know school is otalica
early
so 4 20 well you know link up some night
school
yeah so it's not
you know targeted for a specific time
frame but maybe an aluminum cycle right
around it's more you know interwoven
within that tradition so just the world
far 420 i know the celebrations going
out so i just wanted to give a like
you know heights in terms of what that
day
420 represented for rastafarian the
different
celebratory preparation kind of aspect
that it would mean so 420 begin with us
in in principle just based on the
importance of the arrival of his majesty
it is a major anniversary of our
mobilization and within our community
that's when our navy begins it actually
begins
on the night of the 20th in honor of
receiving his majesty's arrival
on the 21st so the the 20th of april
which is how we would speak
it is an important mobilization day for
and what that would mean is ones would
be coming in with their sacrament
as a part of this communion that is
sheared freely
you know pawns of her barrels and
bills of her coming in to the various
points that i and i would move
to congregate usually for a nabbing
celebration
all right we'll give thanks yeah we
appreciate the time
[Music]
all right podcast world i don't have a
lot left to say after that beautiful
segment from our friends from jamaica
i do want to make sure to take a moment
and give thanks to our friends for
taking time out of their day to film
that video for us uh we got to see
the jamaican sunshine we got to see the
banana trees in the background that was
beautiful
i appreciate that so thank you also
thank you for sharing the wisdom and
knowledge with
us uh you shared a lot of knowledge
about uh the island of jamaica the
significance of 420 and 421 the
significance of
uh those dates for uh the island the
significance of those dates for rasta
and the significance of that day and
those dates
for ganja and i love the correlation of
all of that so give thanks big respect
for teaching us so much about
ganja and rasta and 420 in such a short
time that was beautiful
give thanks big respect i appreciate you
everybody else out there thank you for
watching
thank you for hanging out with my
friends from jamaica i'm sure you
enjoyed it as much as i did
if you've got any questions corrections
comments or concerns i would love to
hear from you my email address is grow
from your heart
hotmail.com don't be shy send me that
feedback send me those questions
i would love to hear from you also make
sure you check out my website
iriegenetics.com everything rasta jeff
everything grow from your heart
everything i read genetics of course is
right there
iriegenetics.com that is all i've got
for you for this episode
once again thank you for watching thank
you for listening i want to send a giant
birthday shout out to my friend rastabob
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
oh