[Music]
yeah welcome back podcast world i'm your
host my friends call me rasta jeff
and this is episode 633 of the grow from
your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to read a
couple of patreon messages before we get
there
let's do a few shout outs to a few
members of the 710 club
of course the 710 club are those folks
who support us on patreon
at the 7 and 10 a month level or higher
so with no further ado
let's kick it off the big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out
to my friend paparoni let's send a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out
to nick a and tristar meadow let's send
a big fist bump to andy davies and billy
podunk let's send a big roster salutes
my friends easy057 and zoso j
let's send a big thank you shout out to
bongstein baron alabama man
let's send a big high five to my friends
glenn geroni and guido
seven let's send a big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out to
sacred tree organic farms
and learning and burning let's send a
big thank you shout out to my friend
gaiuty grows
and then let's wrap it all up with the
big grow from your heart podcast thank
you shout out
to my friend jackie daytona big thanks
and big shout
out to everybody who continues to
support the show on patreon
if you are not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need will be
right there on the screen and of course
i did include a link in the show notes
and the video description to make it
nice and easy for all of my friends
maybe you can't pull out your phone and
hit that link right now maybe you're
driving
maybe you're taking a dab maybe you're
doing both maybe you're at work
maybe you're chasing the kids around
maybe you're hanging out with the lady
and got this in one earbud acting like
you're paying attention
i don't know what you're doing but don't
get yourself in trouble the link will be
there when you've got time
it's patreon.com forward slash grow
from your heart i want to start off by
thanking
everybody for the tremendous response to
the release of the blueberry butcher
strain
you guys blew my mind it sold out in two
different websites i had to restock them
two different times and then it sold out
again
that went super quickly there will be a
restock i've got a few more packs of
those to put together and get them out i
did not expect to sell as many packs as
i did that quickly
thank you thank you i do appreciate it
if you missed the blueberry butcher
episode i highly recommend you go back
and check that out
when there are more seeds available
there will be more seeds very soon
uh that is something i'm going to have
to make a lot of once again
uh pay attention there's a few more to
get out so there will be a restock but
grab those while you can if you don't
get them on the restock they will be
made again
once again you guys i'm high and rambly
but thank you for the support
on the blueberry butcher release on 420
big shot out to seeds herenow.com
also shytownseeds.com for just killing
it on seed on 420.
all right where do we go from there main
topics of the show
you know i like to answer questions from
patreon uh the patreon supporters
their questions get moved to the top of
the list i've been slacking on patreon
questions
uh we had a lot of holiday stuff to get
through and then i got distracted by 4
20. i am back in the swing of patreon
questions
so let's jump right into this first one
this is a great question for a cannabis
breeder
it goes a lot like this this one came
from my friend all mixed up shout out to
all mixed up bro you do great work
i love looking at your photos on
cannabis on instagram on social media
you have a really good eye for where to
take the shot your plants look good so
you've got good subjects you got good
framing
kind of looks like you might have
learned from me to be honest but i'm not
gonna give myself credit for that but it
looks like shots i would have [ __ ]
taken dude so good damn
job also uh very good tester work when i
send you tester seeds you do a damn good
job with those also so shout out to my
friend all mixed up
uh i'm gonna get into the message
because it goes a lot like this ross to
jeff i've got a question
bro i have got answers but it says
before i ask my questions
i just want to say thank you for all
that you do bro bro thank you
uh it is a symbiosis it's a team effort
i may be the team captain but without a
captain of the team
without a team the captain is just a
[ __ ] egomaniac so i'm glad that i've
got a bunch of people
uh that listen and learn and appreciate
and respect me and the feeling is mutual
i
i appreciate i learn and i respect you
guys just as much i get a lot of
feedback from you that teaches me
as much as i feel like i teach you so
the feeling is mutual thank you guys
uh not just my friend all mixed up with
the whole army thank you i learned from
everybody
a good teacher once taught me that you
can learn something from
everybody as a musician i learned i can
learn something from
everybody i've heard uh brand new
musicians that have no idea what they're
doing
pull off the coolest licks on a guitar
play the freshest fills on the drums
because they're the most creative they
don't know the rules they just did some
[ __ ] i learned something from that
little kid in the
guitar center [ __ ] drum room who just
did this thing and i was blown away
put it into my repertoire as a
professional drummer so i learned from
everybody i can learn something from
anybody on the planet some
everybody's got something to teach me so
i learned from you guys as much as you
learned from me
i need to learn to stay focused because
i'm rambly as as [ __ ] today anyway
um thank you bro for recognizing my hard
work and my dedication to this industry
this
community this craft this lifestyle bro
i'm [ __ ] in it to win it at this
point
i've got uh there's this is what i'm
doing so
anyway it says bro my question goes like
this
i have a white widow plant which i've
been growing for 20 plus years
i bet that's a badass plant dude uh old
school white widow was fire
and then if you've chosen to keep it
around for 20 years it has got
to be the heat that has got to be a gem
it says
i keep a mother plant and veg for around
six months to a year before taking
a couple healthy clones then sending her
into flour
ah that's what a lot of us do i keep a
mother plant around for about six months
and then i chop the mother plant do a
bunch of clones i flower out
the some of the clones and i keep one of
the really good ones but not the best of
course the best goes to the flower room
i keep one of the like the top three as
my new mother plant so i can just keep
refreshing that genetic
every three six usually about six months
sometimes nine months to a year
depending on how the plant grows
if it's the mac you only need to do it
once a year if it's a rise you got to do
it three times a year just depends on
the
speed of the plant so our friend has a
white widow plant they keep a mother
plant
they cut some clones send it to flower
and then
they keep the mother plant around now
the question is would it be possible and
actually type
is it be possible and i like that is it
be possible to make seeds of her
to keep her around instead of always
keeping a mom plant around
taking up space so our friend does not
want to keep the mother plant around and
they want to make some seeds of this
plant
so the mother plant is not always taking
up space the first thing i would
recommend is just little tiny bonsai
mother plant
cut a clone as soon as it gets too big
cut a clone of that as soon as it gets
too big cut a clone of that just always
have a little tiny one
a little tiny tiny mother plant would be
an option but that's not what you asked
you asked about seeds
yes it would be very possible very
viable to make seeds of this plant
i would just make s-ones self-seeds
we'll talk more in detail about that in
a minute i wanna wrap up the letter
and then i'll get myself on a good rant
talking about making seeds of this plant
um would you recommend going this route
by making seeds of this pheno
or just keep doing it the way i have
been doing it bro your way works
uh you don't have to keep a mother plant
you can have a large veg plant going
and as soon as you put it into flower
cut a clone of it and then let that one
keep growing as the next veg plant
you never have a mother plant per se but
you've always got a healthy plant and
veg that you can get a clone from
and then maybe wait seven to ten days
before you flip it to make sure you're
gonna get a clone
and then maybe take too many clones just
i don't know your clone skill but you
don't have to keep another plant you can
have a veg plant
that is a clone donor as well and then
flour and then
keep doing that you have one that is a
veg plant that goes into flower one's a
veg plant it goes into flower
you can do that but that's a really easy
process
you want to think about making seeds
that's the part where i'm going to focus
because i'm known as being a seed
breeder
i think the keeping a veg plant and not
having a mother plant i think you can
understand how to move that into the
process just take the mother plant
you've got
consider that a veg plan when it's time
to get clones take three
five ten clones from it flower it i
think that's what you're doing so
uh you figured out that process let's
talk about making seeds because that is
where
my area of expertise does lie he does
wrap it up with thanks ross to jeff
hey thank you all mixed up i appreciate
the feedback the input and the great
question here
here is my answer if you want to make uh
preservation
seeds of this uh strain so that you've
got it forever this is what i would do
and this would work for uh maybe you
just don't want to keep this strain
around maybe you've got it maybe you
want to go on vacation and simply just
not grow for a minute but you want to
come back and have a reliable stock of
something to work with
ah maybe you just want to move and you
can't move the plants with you or
however you want to preserve this
forever in seed form this is how i would
do it
um i would reverse the plant to keep it
pure
and use that plant as the pollen donor
and the female plant the pollen receiver
that way we're not adulterating it
for this to happen you've got to make
feminized s1
self seeds so you're going to cut one
clone
and that will be selected as your pollen
donor it's a female right now but we're
going to make it give you pollen don't
worry
then i would cut two or three other
clones those will be the pollen
receivers that you're
that are going to make use seeds uh
they'll receive the pollen the seeds
will come from them
so you've got your pollen giver it they
all look the same right now they're all
clones of that white widow plant they
all look the same but
we're going to take one and we're going
to treat it with silver thiosulfate
i've done a full episode on silver
thiosulfate i've done a full episode on
making feminized seeds
with those two episodes together you
should be able to
get at least a good head start a good
blueprint on how to make fem seeds you
may need to
hit me up for details questions maybe
search the internet for some fine detail
some fine tuning
but i think with what i gave you you
should be able to make uh you should be
able to find and make the silver
thiosulfate then you should be
able to execute the process of reversing
the plant
pollinating the pollen receiver plants
and creating seeds out of that
i know who you are uh i know you listen
well
and i know you can do this i know you've
got the knowledge already from listening
to the show to do this
so i would reverse it that way you keep
it pure that way when you come back to
these seeds
it is unadulterated it is just your
white widow plant
any other way of crossing this plant to
make seeds would adulterate it
if you took another male plant and
pollinated that female
you're making a new f1 cross it's going
to be
something white widow to arise white
widow 2 strawberry starburst white widow
to
whatever other male plant you used so
when you grow it it's not going to be
your white widow it's going to be
adulterated excuse the kombucha burps
anyway i would reverse it that way
you're keeping it pure it is still white
widow you're going to find
a little bit of phenotypical variation
but within five or six seeds maybe 10
seeds
you'll definitely find that phenotype
that looks just like the one you started
with that you reversed
so uh cut two or more clones uh you're
going to need one as a paul and donor
one is a paul and receiver i would in my
scenario
i would do two or three as the pollen
giver and like six as the receiver
because i would reverse the other three
at different spray
intervals and ratios to learn that plant
and then i don't know how well the
others are going to receive pollen i
would make sure
that i got enough plants to receive
pollen i'm just extra careful when it
comes to reversing and pollinating
that's also my career so i got to rely
on that
so cut two or more clones reverse one
like i said before you've got the
knowledge
in your head already from listening to
my show how to make silver thiosulfate
how and when to apply it to the plant
how to [ __ ] make that plant create
pollen sacks and put that pollen
on the girls you know how to do that if
you don't message me i'll get you
through it
so reverse one plant pollinate one or
more and then wait
all you gotta do is wait uh then harvest
the seeds then
store those seeds they should be nice
and hard and tiger striped or at least
dark brown when you pull them out
let them dry really hard then store them
with all of your other seeds well
labeled and guess what
you've now got reserve stock of your
white widow and they're feminized also
so you're not going to find boys in
there
so that's going to help you out but
you're not able to breed with that
unless you do more reversals or find a
different male it can't be a male
for breeding i'm going to press pause
take a drink and catch my breath and
we'll wrap this question up and move
forward
all right i am back i'm well hydrated
i'm well medicated i'm ready to ramble
on i think i pretty much answered this
question about preservation
uh cut a few clones reverse one uh
pollinate
make seeds harvest the seeds dry them
and store them and then when it comes
time
to grow this again you have got it
the hardest part about this project in
my opinion
and many people are probably going to
agree with me is cutting down
the plant you've kept for 20 years
making fem seeds out of it that's just a
process that's a standard operating
procedure
cutting down a plant that you've been
attached to for 20 years is going to
feel strange inside
if it wasn't before now that i've
mentioned it it is certainly going to
make you feel
some type of way that's the part that's
going to be the real challenge here
there's no sop
for detachment for cutting down a plant
you've been in love with for 20 years
i recently let go of my flow plant there
was nothing wrong with flow i had flow
for
12 years 13 years i honestly just got
bored with it
i bred to it i grew it i smoke it i bred
it to everything
and it was a great plant but it just
wasn't i don't know it was like a seven
out of a ten and i like elevens
so it had to go but that plant was
around
through my evolution as a grower as a
breeder
as like uh a basement buccaneer to a
commercial grower that flow was around
that float paid
a lot of bills that flow paid a lot of
favors that flow
paved a lot of ways i would wake up and
smell that plant and it would make me
nauseous because i had been around it
grew it smelled it smoked it sold it for
so long
that it had to go so maybe you're done
with this white widow but obviously
you're not
done done it's like a girl you want to
break up with but you still keep her
number in your phone you're like i ain't
done yet
making these femme seeds out of her
anyway i'm rambling but the hardest part
is going to be getting rid of this plant
dude you can make all the seeds you want
cut all the clones you want good luck
when it's time to cut it down you're
getting it shaky
it's going to be fun make a video make a
video when you do it
bro thank you for the great message that
was a really good question i hope i
answered it thoroughly
i know i keep saying that you've got the
information to do the reversal because i
know you're a smart person
if you need help if you need guidance
you know i know who you are you know who
i am you know all you have to do is ask
me
for help say all right i'm ready to do
the reversal what do i do you know i'll
guide you through it if you need help
alright big shout out to my buddy all
mixed up
i need to keep moving because i'm awful
rambly on this podcast
this message came from patreon
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart
it is from our friend sticky randy and
it goes a lot
like this it says hey ross to jeff
here's a good question for you what kind
of notes
should i take while doing a breeding
phenohunt
for males and female plants um that's a
really good question
and honestly it's kind of up to you i
mean that's a very vague shitty answer
but what are you
interested in what do you care about the
main things i look for
are germination ratios i'm not sure if
you're asking me like
uh you're doing a breeding pheno hunt
for males and females
so are you looking for males to use in
the breeding
like i'm not sure what exactly you're
asking but for notes for taking
i always take like notes on germination
rates how many
sprouts throw 100 seeds in a paper towel
and see how many of them pop write that
down
that's my germination ratio it's a
really easy number to get uh it's a real
easy number to math up it's a really
good number to have
so that's where i start germination
ratios then ah how many of those
made it out of the dirt how many of them
were males and females how many looked
like [ __ ] how many were vigorous
all of my plants are labeled with a
number and or a letter
uh if something stands out any sort of
anomaly
gets written down anything you notice
gets written down that's how i do it
i don't know what you're interested in
as a breeder i want to see growth
structure
at certain times how it responds to
certain things i do to it
um if i fed it recharged did it over
get to absorb too much nitrogen because
sometimes if you feed it
too much recharge it'll make it cycle
too quickly
uh when i gave it calmag did the leaves
get real serrated or did it start to get
pale on me because i overfed
it um i write down notes like that
things that i notice
i write down every feed everything i mix
up
so if i've got a 25 gallon i will say a
20 gallon reservoir it's easier to do
math
uh if i do a 20 gallon reservoir i write
down that i put
uh 60 mils of this product in there 120
mils of this product in there
10 mils of this product in there and i
write down as i pour it in i just it's a
google document honestly in my phone
so i just open it up and i type 60 i
pour in 60 then go to the next product
type in equinox 120 pour in the 120 of
equinox
74 grams of shine and that's just a
[ __ ] wild exaggeration i'm just
making up numbers now but
put a bunch of shine in there stir it up
then guess what i do next
i measure the ph i measure the ec guess
what i do then i write those down in a
google document
i've got google documents for the ph the
ec the feed
and the runoff uh in and out for the
past [ __ ] six years of my grow
so if i come up with any issues scroll
through i've got a good guideline of
what might have happened so those are
notes i take
you're asking about breeding ah
internodal structure how far apart are
the nodes
do you have like a criteria in your head
that you say
these branches are squatty these
branches are sturdy
these branches are stretchy these
branches are twisty
ah this plant has a christmas tree
structure this plant has a fern-like
stretch
like do you have something even if it's
just a guideline or a
bracket system in your own head do you
have something like that to compare the
plants to
in your own head so whatever you find
important is what's important for your
grow notes what are you looking for
obviously structure appearance leaf size
leaf shape
germination rates growth rates ah
aroma rub the stems give it a smell rub
the leaves give it a smell
are the leaves perking up or the leaves
drooping are there
10 plants in the room and one of them is
doing something different
write that down whatever that one plant
is doing write it down
also stand near that plant and look
around
is the air conditioner blowing on that
plant is the heater blowing on that
plant is the humidifier
extra humidifying that plant is it right
under one of the lights is it right
far away from one of the lights that's
the [ __ ] i write down because
the scientific method requires all of
the data we can get
if you say um i've got 10 plants and
this one over here is growing real tall
that must be the best plant
what if the light's right there and we
don't know that and we pick that plant
and we take that plant to our facility
and fill the entire facility with that
one plant
and it doesn't perform the way it did in
that one situation because it was
right next to the [ __ ] light or it
was right by the heater and it loved
that heat
and we don't know that that one plant
got the heater so there's no scientific
method to that unless you write down
every detail that you can see ah also
details we cannot see humidity
temperature vpd
uh anything you can think of write all
of that [ __ ] down
in a commercial environment one of the
things i like the guys to do guys and
gals now there are lots of lovely
excellent ladies working in the
commercial facilities
when you walk in and out of a commercial
grow room i have you write down the vpd
the temperature and humidity on a little
chart just it gives us
accountability also makes you look that
way you walk in the room you check the
meters
sometimes you get complacent and a
growth sometimes the staff is busy
thinking about
task a and they get color blind or they
get the blinders on what's it called
tunnel vision is the word i'm looking
for
and they can't focus so they just walk
right in there and
they don't realize that the room is
super humid because they're
going in there just to find that pair of
scissors at the end of that hallway at
the end of that [ __ ] grow table
and they don't realize it's super humid
so when they walk in there every time
they gotta look at the monitor write
down the vpd the temperature and the
humidity and initial it
and that way i know the last time mitt
mark came in here mark is a made-up name
don't yell at mark for [ __ ] up
the last time mark came in here he
looked at the vpd and it was cool that
was two hours ago
i'm in here it's [ __ ] up something
happened in the last hour and a half we
got to figure out
go look at the cameras go look at the
charts look at the plants figure out
what went wrong in the room
is the dehumidifier broken is the air
conditioner stuck on is
one of the blowers in the room stuck
somewhere that's when we started
investigating so
every little detail make notes that way
you can find the problems
every it's like a murder investigation
the more [ __ ] you know
the easier it is to solve the crime and
a lot of times when you find a problem
in the grow
it's like a big ol who done it do we
have spider mites is it too cold in here
is it too hot in here how's the vpd
all of that shit's gonna go through your
mind the minute you see an issue in the
grow
you're gonna go what did i feed it last
time did you spray it anything
and if i'm a consultant and i come to
your grow to help you out
those are the questions i'm gonna ask
did you spray anything
what was the last thing you sprayed how
many days ago
and then what was the product you
sprayed before that because let's see if
those two products
are having a reaction on your leaf
surface that could be [ __ ] everything
up
we may solve the problem just by looking
at paperwork we may not have to leave
the office
maybe you could have saved yourself half
of the consulting fee by doing it over
zoom
and not making me drive all the way to
your grow because the minute i put on my
dunks
i start charging you extra money if i'm
driving to the facility
it costs you double what it costs for
cost for me to do a consultation on zoom
that's just a business way of doing
things so you could save yourself
half the money by having double the
paperwork keep [ __ ] notes
so i'm going to ask you what did you
spray these plants what did you spray
them
before that how many milliliters of
whatever
[ __ ] you sprayed on there was in there
who applied it can we talk to them
did you soak the plants did you just
spray them till they're running off did
you spray them with a mist
did you spray them from the underside or
did you spray them from the top
when you sprayed them did you turn the
lights off or turn the lights on i've
got questions
hopefully you've got notes for those
answers then i'm going to ask you what
did you feed these plants last
i want to know what you fed them every
nutrient what was the ph what was the
ppm or ec
do you have a runoff chart that i can
look at to see what looked like for the
past
three weeks until the week when [ __ ]
went wrong those are the questions i'm
going to want to ask
then i'm going to ask you what was the
vpd
vpd can cause and solve so many problems
temperature and humidity
just like you bro if i put you outside
for two weeks and made you just deal
with [ __ ]
you'd be stressed out you'd go through
some problems you need a good vpd we can
fix your whole life with the vpd
issue so i'm gonna ask you all those
things have those notes
those are the notes i recommend having
for breeding uh you said phenol hunt for
breeding
um structure shape aroma leaf size
color uh trichome density trichome
size and shape some plants have
long skinny tall trichomes some have
shorter
thicker fatter trichomes though in my
opinion you get a different buzz from
those
are you breeding are you growing to make
concentrates if you're going to make
concentrates you want the taller
skinnier trichomes
they come apart from the buds better if
you're going to manhandle your buds
maybe you want those shorter thicker
trichomes
concentrate makers are going to have
feedback and opinions on that
cannot wait to hear it my email address
is grow from your heart at hotmail.com
so the notes that you would take
honestly i got way far rambling into the
weeds on that but
the notes are all about what are
important to you what matters
to you when it comes to your breeding
you're growing what do you want to know
what are you going to want to pay
attention to what are you going to want
to document i am excessive
ah i got some ocd in the grow room
that's why i'm here
i'm on a different i'm doing things on a
different level because i've got a
different passion my brain is on that
path
it's just what i do it's what i think
about so do you want to be ocd about it
do you want to take copious notes
ridiculous notes
do you want to take just enough notes or
you can not even take notes that is up
to you
if you've got a memory see that's the
thing i like to smoke right before i
work it's just i put on
music uh put on my favorite song put on
my favorite podcast i got joey diaz
cussing me on my left ear
just [ __ ] cruising take a couple dabs
and go in there and i got joey what's up
[ __ ] we're gonna grow some [ __ ]
weed today and i'm like hell yeah we are
so take a couple dabs and go in and get
all these marvelous ideas and [ __ ]
and i think i'm gonna do this and do
this and then i'm gonna feed the plants
this
if i don't take [ __ ] notes i don't
remember any of the marvelous ideas i
don't know what i did to the plants
so i take a lot of notes because i like
to smoke debs
and i'm listening to uncle joey or some
fish and i just i don't remember a
goddamn thing cause i'm nice and high in
there and i'm in the zone
so that's why i take a lot of notes you
should take notes on what is important
to you
uh sticky randy i rambled on about that
question so you definitely got a good
answer
if you've got any more questions if i
can dial that in for you a little bit
better send me some feedback because i
do want to make sure i answer your
questions thoroughly
i went overboard on that one bro thank
you for the great question thank you for
the patreon contribution
how far are we into this show we are at
the point where i start saying ladies
and gentlemen boys and girls
pimps hoes friends foes crips and bloods
smokers growers clone cutters pollen
chuckers
break dancers and new wave kids fruit
booters and skateboarders i want to
thank each and every one of you for
watching this episode of the grow from
your heart podcast
got super baked and had a good time with
you thank you for hanging out hope you
had as much fun as i did
if you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
maybe you had a couple of laughs maybe
you just want to throw me a couple of
bucks because i put a lot of work into
the show
all you have to do is visit my patreon
campaign at www.patreon.com forward
slash grow from your heart
all of the information you need to
support the show is right there on the
screen
once again there's a link in the show
notes there's a link in the youtube
video
click on that that'll get you right
there be safe if you got your hands full
if you've got any questions corrections
comments or concerns my email address is
grow from your heart at hotmail.com
don't be shy you know i'd love to hear
from you also visit the website for all
things irie genetics
all things ire genetics wait i said that
twice all things ire genetics all things
grow from your heart and all things
rosta jeff that's what i meant to say
what i wanted to say after that if you
visit the website
you will find the web store for irie
genetics merch like this cool
irie army t-shirt there are a bunch of
t-shirts on there there's some stickers
there's some more stuff there for you to
check out
go visit the website also there's a list
of vendors there if you're looking for
irie genetics beans irie genetics gear
there's a list of about seven vendors on
there go check out the vendors
somebody has got what you are looking
for don't miss it
iriegenetics.com also there is a
newsletter
sign up spot go in there type in your
email address i'll send you a newsletter
about once a month i try not to overload
you
sometimes i honestly forget i'll send
you a newsletter approximately once a
month with updates on what's going on
with iriegenetics with the podcast with
some seed drops maybe some special
events
there is a special event coming up i'm
waiting for an email
with an address and some times and some
info for some links and [ __ ] like that
so we can get you tickets
but until i've got that i've just got to
tease you about it may 22nd somewhere in
denver there will be a seed
selling purchasing exchanging event
don't know the proper wording for that
but if you need seeds
come to denver may 22nd we'll get you
laced up with this event i will be there
a lot of other great seed vendors will
be there
we'll get you taken care of uh but if
you check out my website join the
newsletter
you will get updated info on that you
will not miss a thing iriegenetics.com
that was the point of all that nonsense
ladies and gentlemen boys and girls this
was a fun episode to record i had a good
time
cut loose on the microphone this is my
zen spot right here nobody can mess with
me when i'm
behind these lights and in front of this
camera so thank you for joining me in my
sweet spot
i'll be back in a couple of days with
fresh new content i want to give a giant
shout out to my good friend john bendit
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
[Applause]
[Music]
you