[Music]
yeah welcome back podcast world
i'm your host my friends call me rasta
jeff and this is episode 635
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to focus on
patreon
messages before we get there let's do a
few shout outs to a few members of the
710 club
of course the 710 club are the friends
who support us on patreon
at the 7 and 10 cent a month level or
higher so with no further ado let's kick
it off with the big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out
to my friend urban farmer let's send a
big thank you shout out to paul
forrester and ivan munoz
let's send a big thank you shout out to
roll this nug and justin clauser
let's send a big thank you to jordan
perks and stone trout bomb
i want to send a big thank you shout out
to dayron t and grant mulkey
i want to send a special thank you shout
out to blackbird 76 and cano organic
let's follow it up with a shout out to
nicholas a and then let's wrap it all up
with the big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out
to my friend dz from detroit big thanks
and big shout out to everybody
who continues to support the show on
patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do that
all you've got to do is visit www
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need is right
there on the screen
and there is a link in the show notes
and the video description
to make it super easy for all of my
friends click on that link that will get
you right to patreon
take you right to my page all the info
you need is right there
on the screen all right i don't have a
lot of stuff to ramble about here at the
start of the show i do have one
important thing to remind you about
don't forget about the groovy gravy
secret stash
seed exchange event happening in denver
may 22nd at an
undisclosed secret location that's right
you will be given the
exact address and location when the time
is appropriate we're trying to keep that
on the down low until the right time
anyway make sure you follow the link in
the video description there's a link
in the video the show description that
will get you right to the place to get
tickets when you get there to get
tickets
use coupon code rosta jeff and that will
save you 20
on ticket pricing the vip tickets are
all sold out at this time a couple of
people have messaged me
and they said bro i want to get in on
the event i want to get vip tickets
i am just a vendor i don't run the event
i'm not part of the event staff
i signed up i paid to be a vendor i'm
basically a guest just like you
so if you want to participate in the
event if you want to buy a ticket you've
got to go through the proper channels
contact groovy gravy you can find them
on social media
look for my posts you can find them if
the tickets are sold out the tickets are
sold out i can't help you
the vip tickets are gone i can't get you
vip tickets
by the time this airs the regular
tickets will be very
very low so get yourself a ticket now
come join us in denver
hang out can't wait to meet you get you
some sweet seeds give you some fresh
deals
i look forward to seeing you may 22nd at
the groovy gravy
secret stash seed exchange event at an
undisclosed location
in denver colorado all right that is
enough news that's enough updates
it's enough bill paying enough
advertising let's get into the main
portion of this podcast i do have an
email right here in front of me
and it comes from a person named brett e
and it goes
just a like this it says hey ross to
jeff i just signed up for patreon
and i saw your post about the shout outs
and that's great but you can use
my ig moniker instead of my real name
that would be great
my ig moniker is no till illuminati so
big shout out to our friend no-till
illuminati
i mentioned in a previous episode that
when you sign up on patreon
i will give you a shout out under the
name you signed up under on patreon it's
the name i've got it's what i read on
the screen
it's easiest for me however i've
realized that some people don't want me
to say that name that they've got
another name they'd rather get a shout
out through
if you've got that name you want me to
say send it to me i'll do my best to
find that message i'll flag it i'll
print it out
i'll try to remember i'll try to
correlate that name that i see on the
screen to the name that you've sent me
honestly it takes a couple tries i've
got the add i got the brain thing
also my highest giraffe [ __ ] half the
time so i will do my best to correlate
the appropriate name to the appropriate
shout out
this person right here had the right
approach uh big shout out to our friend
no till illuminati that is their
instagram handle give them a follow
at no-till illuminati on the instagram
and once again shout out to them and
thank you for the support bro
i want to keep moving the next message
says this one actually came from my
website if you visit my website
iriegenetics.com
there is a grow help tab on that website
you can click on grow help
you can send me a message it does ask
you a couple of questions before you get
there
but this person basically said what
would you what cultivar would you
recommend
for concentrates that's a very good
question
uh let me back up i am a podcaster of
course you know me as the girl from your
heart podcast i'm also
the sole proprietor soul breeder i'm the
guy from ire genetics premium seed so i
also make a lot of seeds that's what
this question comes from
just because not everybody knows that
all the stuff that i do
so they're asking about some of the
strains that i breed from ire genetics
what cultivar would you recommend for
concentrates that is a very good
question
i really like talking about my
concentrates about my strains about my
cultivars about my breeding
so this will get me going i really like
this one i've got a lot of answers for
this question it kind of depends on
what kind of concentrates you want to
make do you want to make bubble hash do
you want to make bho
are you squishing stuff how are you
doing it that's going to kind of make a
difference here
what i've noticed is the strawberry
starburst
always makes super tasty delicious high
potency
concentrates no matter how you run it
how you press it squish it wash it
extract it blast it process it whatever
you want to call it
strawberry starburst will make amazing
concentrates
i am not a big fan of rosin i don't like
to smoke rosin most of the time
and i'm not a hater this is my honest
opinion i love a lot
of things rosin is not for me it tastes
like burnt popcorn
and popsicle sticks and that's not the
terp for me
so a lot of people love rosin a lot of
people love bho
a lot of people love different types of
stuff um
if you were making uh so i was where was
i i
remember what i was saying now i'm not a
big fan of rosin i got myself back on
track
uh my friend pedro made some rosin from
some strawberry starburst
and that rosin was some of the most
delicious and potent concentrate
i have ever inhaled and exhaled on the
inhale it tastes like sweet candy like
almost those uh
those watermelon candies or strawberry
candies that grandma used to have in a
candy dish on the table that got dusty
and [ __ ] but they still tasted good
i tasted like that on the inhale then on
the exhale it was like sweet bubble gum
and kush and it just stayed on my tongue
and i was high as [ __ ] my eyes got heavy
my lungs felt heavy from it
so that was a pedro dab of strawberry
starburst rosin
i bred the strawberry starburst our
buddy kelvin medina
actually grew the flowers and then pedro
from pedro's grow room
did the extraction and it was delicious
so the strawberry starburst is one of
the best for any kind of concentrates in
my opinion
then i also feel the same way about the
blue raspberry truffle
the blue raspberry truffle makes amazing
bho concentrates if you're making
anything using a solvent extract or a
solvent extraction
that blue raspberry truffle will dump
resin and it tastes so
crazy the concentrates and the terps are
just ridiculous it's like
ah blue raspberry candy blue raspberry
suckers
tropical skittles sour flavors uh
there's just tart flavors in there
there's cherry there's blueberry there's
all kinds of funky [ __ ] in there
uh it's got some just razzy stuff going
on it's really delicious so
then there's another one i talk about
all the time when it comes to
concentrates
one of my favorites for concentrates is
the cream
the cream makes really great bubble hash
the cream makes really good press hash
if you make bubble and then press it it
is tremendous it comes out white
and beach sandy there's something about
i'm not a concentrate maker i've said
this before
i enjoy concentrates i have i
experimented and attempted to make
concentrates i'm better at [ __ ] up a
concentrate
than i am at making them i'm much better
at smoking a concentrate than i am at
making them
so i let the concentrate makers do that
i focus on breeding podcasting growing
other things i feel like i've got my
niche but i don't know a lot
about the science of extracting but i
know there are different
size and shape trichomes on plants
and i thought that i know that the
strawberry starburst and blue raspberry
truffle
make tall trichomes with a big fat head
that is something i've seen
something i've seen under a microscope
something people have noticed and shown
to me
the opposite of that happens with the
cream those are short
and bulky almost like stocky fat boy
kind of
bowling pin shaped trichomes so they're
shorter and closer to the plant and
they're wider
and more bulbous on the top and they
have a fatter head for some reason that
seems to make a better bubble hash
product
i don't know again i'm not the
concentrate maker i don't know
your end of the job but i can tell the
two trichome size differences shape
differences
the two strains i mentioned at the first
have the longer skinny or taller
trichomes
and the short have shorter fatter
trichomes and they make completely
different kinds of concentrates
so you'll get like a oily texture out of
some and a sandy texture out of others
i think that the cream makes like a
beach sand like a
kind of a gritty baby powder sort of a
texture when it comes to making
concentrates and it's so beautiful
ah so my top three that i would
recommend would be the blue raspberry
truffle the strawberry starburst and
the cream with that being said the
blueberry
butcher that i just put out i said
blueberry putcher the blueberry butcher
that i just put out
also dumps and makes all kinds of
amazing concentrates
i breed for that high thc stuff because
i like to get
so high that i almost can't function
like i try to i try to give myself a
panic attack
if i don't well if i walk into the mall
and i'm okay
i didn't get high enough i gotta walk
into the mall and be like [ __ ] i can't
be here
that's the way my dab should make me
feel so i breed for that
high intensity panic attack [ __ ] head
buzz head ringing
[ __ ] crazy high that you got your
eyes dart around the room and your heart
beats out of your chest i love that
but i'm also breeding for intense flavor
i love good tasting weed weed should
taste good concentrates should taste
even better
so i'm breeding basically for perfect
concentrate plants
like i love to smoke concentrates i grow
my plants and they're extracted
immediately in fact today i got to smoke
some
uh concentrate made from a plant that i
bred that a friend grew who'd rather
remain anonymous but bro you know who
you are and those concentrates
were [ __ ] delicious thank you bro so
uh yeah i
grow my stuff with concentrate
production in mind i breed with
concentrate production in mind
because that's what i prefer i like to
smoke flour but
dabbing is where it's at for me i'm a
busy guy also been smoking for
[ __ ] 25 years at least now so my
tolerance is off the charts
i got to smoke a pound of weed to get a
nice buzz i could take six dabs and be
[ __ ] wrecked if i do it right so
i really like dabbing i got myself way
far off track here what would i
recommend for concentrates again the
cream
strawberry starburst blue raspberry
truffle and if you can get your hands on
it
that blueberry butcher is a great one
you can find the blueberry butcher at
seeds herenow.com
make sure that you use coupon code
gfyh10 that'll save you 10
on your full order sneaky commercial
right in there
all right i'm going to move on this one
does come from patreon hey thank you for
the question about the cultivar also
that's a great question and when you do
get seeds i want to know how it runs for
you
and i want to know how the concentrates
come out let me know what strain you
choose
let me know how you extracted it let me
know if you were satisfied with my
recommendations
and then i'll get you my address you can
fill me up with some concentrates all
right
let's keep moving this one does come
from patreon it says what up ross did
jeff
i've been listening to your podcast for
over two years since i started my grow
journey
i wanted to say thank you for the
motivation and the knowledge you gave me
to continue to give countless
oh that you gave me and you continue to
give countless new growers that's a
great way to start a message
um you've been listening for two years
which thank you for following along for
so long i'm glad i didn't annoy you and
run you off
thanks for the motivation bro thank you
for the motivation this is a two-way
street
i put out content you listen to it you
say thank you and motivate me
i know your garden's getting better it
is a two-way street so thank you
for the motivation this is a good
relationship um
and knowledge i've said it before i've
got this knowledge in my head
i was blessed by what created me you
guys know i believe in rastafari so
john gave me this knowledge and if i
didn't share it i would be disrespectful
to myself to ja
and to you like i was given a gift i've
got this gift of gab i've got this gift
of learning of teaching
this obvious gift of a green thumb and i
enjoy cannabis with a passion
if i didn't put this back out something
would go wrong i would spontaneously
combust
jaw would say you're being selfish with
your gifts and strike me down in some
way
thunder lightning brimstone all that
good stuff so i just try to
share the gift i was given it's uh it's
in me and it would be selfish not to put
it back out there and it feels good it's
very
rewarding i get to teach you how to grow
and then you say thank you and then you
guys send me money on patreon
like it's [ __ ] tremendous i love it
it's a really good relationship it's a
really good
i'm grateful for it it feels good it
doesn't feel dirty i've had jobs i've
done things where i've walked away and
like yeah i got paid but i kind of feel
like a piece of [ __ ] inside for that
i don't feel like a piece of [ __ ] when i
do this this feels good this feels right
i know this is where i'm supposed to be
so big up big thanks for noticing
rastafari let's get myself back on track
uh oh and then i can uh countless new
growers i love knowing that i'm helping
countless new growers
every [ __ ] couple of months we get a
new state legalized and that's a full
state population of new potential
growers and i'm down to help every one
of them and i love it
so now it says um where were we
you're genuinely genuinely helping
people and i fully support that
if it wouldn't be too much it would be
cool if you could shout out my youtube
channel
rasta green thumb as i basically make
videos off of your teachings
started last year due to the pandemic my
new life mission is to get this valuable
knowledge
to as many people as i can and
particularly the minority community
who's been oppressed heavily from
[ __ ] cannabis laws
i respect that uh being a white
rastafarian i've got a lot of friends of
different colors
from different places just being an
american person being a roster man has
nothing to do with that i guess
i love people from all different colors
cultures i love
accents i love [ __ ] vibes from
everywhere ah man if we didn't have
people from other places
this country would be boring as [ __ ] if
it was just all one color people or one
type of people
this show would suck so i appreciate
what you're doing for uh
uh minorities and trying to help people
out and get to them uh
uh who've been oppressed heavily from
[ __ ] cannabis laws i agree with that
uh and so thank you for doing what you
can for that and you said you're kind of
just spreading my teachings
uh give me some shout outs bro let them
know where you learned it and then
everything is cool as long as you
uh acknowledge your source give your
teacher some credit you can share my
knowledge all you would like
let them know to listen to my show as
well as yours i'll give you a shout out
you give me a shout out you've been
following for a long time
shout out to my buddy ross to green
thumb check them out on the youtube
channel
it does follow up with i've got an
actual question
it says when it comes to breeding if you
were to breed with the strains you've
already made which ones do you think
would make something amazing
if combined such as raphael and orange
gasm
making a strawberry orange kind of terp
and then it says i plan to breed seeds
in the future and i want to use your
high standards of testing them
as well as picking good parents also
would you be opposed to me
making s-ones of some of your strains
and giving them to people
in my personal discord that need help
getting seeds
i want to touch on the making s ones of
my stuff before we talk about
your breeding and then i'll remember to
dust this microphone off
before i record another show things
dirty and embarrassing i'm sorry um
it is cool with me if you make s ones to
give to your friends in need
that i can't like afford seeds acquire
seeds and get seeds
when you become uh when it becomes a bad
idea is when you're stepping on my toes
stealing customers
uh just kind of [ __ ] with me so if
you're gonna make these seeds
and give them to people who are in need
that is respectable
uh you've got my permission and my
respect for that
don't cross the line and sell those
seeds and make s-ones of something that
i am putting out and then try to
piggyback off of that [ __ ] and make a
dollar off
of it that's a dick move it sounds like
what you're trying to do is totally cool
you're trying to help people i want you
to help people
if my strains become s ones and help
people that is improving
people's quality of life making people's
lives better uh
letting you help people you do that but
don't be a dick move and put them on the
market and sell them as
uh lemon jeffrey s ones or something
that's just being a dick move and
uh it's not gonna work for you anyway
but still in the community and the seed
breeding realm
that's that's where the borderline is if
you're gonna give them away i'm cool
with that give them away
but don't go making money off of my
creations which i know that sounds weird
because you're like bro you just make
seeds off of other people's strains yes
i do some work with it but
i've done my own research i've developed
my strains i've found parents i made
them you're just making photocopies
there's already somebody out there doing
that don't be that guy all right i know
you're not gonna do that i just had to
make that disclaimer i love you bro
no worries on that um so if you're gonna
make s-ones and give them away to people
in need that is cool don't make s-ones
and then profit off of my work that
you're just piggybacking on
that's a [ __ ] move i know you're not
going to do that because you say
take care brother may job provide you
with many more blessings and bless up
that shows me your respectful roster man
you're not going to do that to me now
let's talk about
the main part of your question here when
it comes to breeding if i were to breed
with strains i've already made
which strains do you think would make
some amaze something amazing
and then you ask about raphael and
orangegasm making orange strawberry kind
of terps
that sounds great but honestly it sounds
like it's so many sweet and tropical
things they're gonna cancel each other
out and it's gonna be weird and there's
already a lot of stuff already like that
honestly that's already been done uh
that's tangy
that's all the tangy crosses uh that's
tangibanji that's
uh strawberry banana tangy that's
already been done
um the tangy so let's talk about that we
could go back in time here
so you've got to be careful not to
bottleneck yourself when you were
breeding and if
i know the family history the family
trees of these tray of these two strains
raphael is a blueberry cookies two
strawberry fields
strawberry fields comes from crockett um
orange gasm
is golden goat to platinum tangy
platinum tangy is platinum cookies
to tangy tangy is back over here in
crockett's camp
i would have to carefully research the
strawberry fields
and the tangy and see if they have
similar parents because if so
they've already been it's already been
done that cross is kind of do you see
what i'm saying like they already
if crockett owns both those parents he's
probably already done that cross there's
no need for me to do it
also if i'm gonna breed so if i use that
strawberry there's the strawberry uh
fields in there
and the tangi in there they probably
already have a parent in there i don't
want to breed with something that's got
a similar parent
that's not going to do me any good
that's going backwards
so just with a little bit of quick
thinking about my family tree
raphael to orange gasm would just
basically be remaking some crockett [ __ ]
and i need to stay further away from
that to be original
i don't want to rewrite stairway to
heaven [ __ ] zeppelin already did that
so i need to use the same chords and
play it differently or [ __ ] not play
those chords at all
like i just don't want to recreate
something that crockett did or something
so close to crockett's camp and i know
you probably didn't even realize
that there was strawberry fields in
there that's from crockett and there's
tangy in there that's from crockett
and now we're just playing with two of
crockett's things all over again and
as a respectable breeder that's crockett
stuff he should if anyone's gonna cross
those two it should be crockett i don't
need to go backwards
so that is why uh i wouldn't cross those
and you gotta be careful about
bottlenecking yourself if there's a
similar parent which i'm sure there is i
didn't research that
but i'm sure there's a similar parent
between the tangie and the strawberry
fields probably a tangy something
probably that orange calio is probably
in there somewhere on both of them
uh so i would want to do that because
then i'm just breeding back to that same
parent that calio
that is common in those two is going to
come out again
it's just not something that would
interest me so um
then that's something as a breeder i
have to be careful about everything is
pollinated by king solomon
so if i want to breed strawberry
starburst to anything it can't be blue
it could be but it's not a good idea i'm
going backwards again i'm kind of
inbreeding cousin [ __ ]
uh that's never a good idea so i would
do strawberry star
strawberry strawberry starburst i'm
trying to keep my brain straight here
strawberry starburst 2 blue raspberry
truffle
would have two arise parents in there
we're going to get a lot of arise traits
strawberry starburst to sunkist we got
arize traits in there
so i've got to be careful not to breed
that back to anything that's been done
to arise
so then i would look to my blueberry
cookies line
or my grateful dog line and breed it to
something else that i have bread
all right here's a good example of some
strains i've crossed together that have
been strains i've created that i've
crossed together
the grateful dog is an inbred feminized
project i'm not going to talk too much
about the history of that you guys know
about that already
i've got the grateful dog that is my
plant femme seed female only
i've got the keeper the prize the winner
of that then i also made the arise which
is golden goat cross to daybreaker
then i took the golden goat and
daybreaker found a male out of that
that's king solomon
i pollinated that grateful dog and that
makes my morning do
so that is uh my child my child and my
grandchildren basically
crossing their making stuff so that's
when i'm able to cross stuff is when i
open it up and do
things that aren't all king solomon or
all the jack the ripper mail or all the
grateful dog mail
now you want to know uh uh what would be
something amazing something else you
think i would
be something else you think i could make
that would be amazing the jack the
ripper crosses i just made
are amazing i do plan on finding some
males in that line
to go back to some of my females so
there will be some
jack the ripper crosses to our rise
crosses check the ripper crosses to
blueberry cookies crosses
some of those things will go back um
some of the feminized only stuff to more
feminized only stuff will be fun also
so when it comes to breeding if i were
to breed with the strains i've already
made which ones do i think would make
something amazing
ah grateful dog to arise that made
morning dew
um what else could we talk about lemons
uh lemon jeffrey
to the arise made lemon sunrise i made
both of those those are pretty awesome
there are a couple other things that
i've made that i haven't even released
that are pretty awesome that i'm not
even going to talk about the king's king
kim grape stomper oh g
crosses bred to some other stuff we're
pretty rad but
the reason i can't breed everything to
everything i want to go back to that is
because i will bottleneck myself all
work everything will all be
jack the ripper across to a rise crossed
to the same [ __ ] so
that's why you see me looking for new
males occasionally that's why every
year or two years i bust out a new
feminize project because i just need a
different
male plant to open up my breeding i'm
limited by plant counts i'm very very
limited by the amount of plants which i
can have here in the state of colorado
and in the position which i've put
myself in in the community on youtube
everywhere my face if you open if you
think about cannabis you probably
a lot of times my name is associated
with that so they whoever they are
babylon knows who i am so i've got to
follow the rules be really careful
i don't have an extra leaf if i'm
allowed 600 leaves i got 599 leaves you
know what i'm saying i'm following the
rules so
very limited by the amount of plants
which i can have now because all these
regulations and how
[ __ ] known i've made myself that's my
fault but that was my choice as well i
guess
uh but i'm well known so i got to be
careful i'm kind of like [ __ ] poster
boy now so i got to be
very careful on my plant count so i've
got the legal amount of plants so
i can't i don't want to get rid of
something because if i get rid of it
then i can't make more seeds of that i
can't breed it and the things i've got
i've fallen in love with
so to find another male i just reverse a
female it seems like a great way to open
up my opportunities
then all of my female plants also can
work as fema and male plants and
it just gives me that many more options
to play with
all right i know i kind of danced around
the question about what else would make
amazing stuff
anything with a different mail across to
anything with a different mail from my
line would be cool i think
i would all work very well because my
selections have been very
very good the true kush cross to have
the truth across to everything that's
true kush to arise
the truth would make some really super
stinky indica dominant stuff that i
wanted to do
uh that chemdaily chem cross is going to
be great but uh
yeah i'm kind of rambling about that
because i wanted to dance around that i
do approve if you want to make those s1
seeds and pass them out to your friends
i have no problem with that don't make
money off of them um
and then just think about what you're
doing when it comes to breeding make
sure you don't bottleneck yourself
make sure you don't inbreed too much
unless that's what you mean to do
that's when you start pulling out those
traits from the
plants that you have a lot of the mix
and it's like chefing if you put two
ingredients and two ingredients that are
the same on both sides when you mix
those two bowls together
those two ingredients are gonna dominate
the mix you're not gonna be able to wash
those out of the flavor at all
all right there are more questions for
this show i don't want to ramble on for
too long i got too stoned and rambled a
lot in this episode there are a couple
of edit points i need to make sure to
catch
um let's see where do we go this one
came from our friend cincy 11 shout out
to cincy 11 on patreon
uh it goes like this it says pollination
back to 18 6. my head grower
and i pushed out on flipping the cross
10 back to 18 6. we both said we
uh wouldn't this cause problems after i
brought it up if it doesn't cause
problems why
and how many days after pollination is
cool to do it all right so what they're
talking about
is when i pollinate plants when i'm
breeding when my plants are only
intended for
seed after pollination i wait a couple
of days maybe three five maybe seven
days depending
on how the plants react then i will turn
my lights back to an 18-6
cycle and you're going to say why would
you do that because i'm not growing buds
i'm growing seeds i don't care what the
buds look like i'm not worried about
trichomes buds flowers
i am 100 focused on making quality seed
for the consumer which is you
so i turn my light timer back to 18 6.
why
because light is the main source of
energy for our plant that's the main
nutrient that our plant wants
also the main nutrient the main source
of energy to make those seeds
get big fat beefy healthy and harden up
faster
quicker and earlier than ever before so
i'm giving them more light
they're using so they're getting uh six
hours more they're getting half a day
more light
every day than they would if they were
on flower so that cuts down my flowering
time by a couple of weeks because
they're getting the light they need for
growth
during the day hours that they're on my
flowers turn to [ __ ]
my flowers look like a [ __ ] mess my
flowers start to re-veg
they start throwing out shoots and
making weird shaped leaves they do all
kinds of crazy funky [ __ ] but you know
what
i don't care i'm not growing for buds
not growing for buds at all
i throw the buds away i cut the plants
down i let them dry to a crisp
i put on rubber gloves and i go like
this i'll do it over the mic so the
audio listeners can hear i go like this
with the buds between my hands and they
crumble up into dust and all the seeds
fall out
i run that whole pile of stuff the dust
the sticks and everything through a seed
sorter and it pulls the seeds out for me
the leftover [ __ ] that's not seeds is
all trash
it all goes in a compost bin i don't do
anything with that it's been so beat up
it's been so finger banged and destroyed
through the extraction process of
getting the seeds out
it is absolutely useless to me we've
made edibles out of it we've made
concentrates out of it it's not worth it
it's green it's funky it tastes terrible
it's just been abused
so all that is trash so it will [ __ ] up
your plants your plants will look like
[ __ ] they'll go back into veg
they'll start shooting out shoots
they're gonna make all kind of crazy
mutated leaves and weird shapes but i
don't care i'm not growing for buds at
this point
what i'm talking about is purely a
seeded crop i'm only looking for seeds
once you cut those down and pull the
seeds out show me what the buds look
like
show me tell me what the buds look like
when you have those seeds in your hand
no one's ever going to know that those
plants look like [ __ ] aliens they
look
sad they look like they're in [ __ ]
some hostage situation
but the seeds are amazing because they
got more light they were able to
photosynthesize faster
they came down maybe three weeks sooner
than the plants that i did not put on
the 18 6 cycle
so don't puss out don't be afraid
it does cause problems it makes the
plants go [ __ ] completely bonkers
but aren't you growing for seeds and not
buds gotta focus on the goal here uh
worry about the outcome
not the process getting to the outcome
think about what's going on
i want to read the question in my head
one more time make sure i covered all
this stuff here
uh head grower pussed out uh said it
would cause problems yeah what kind of
problems bro ah no problems dude it's
just gonna make your seeds better and if
you're growing for a flower don't do
this
if you're grown for flower wait until
the last 10 to 14 days to flip it back
then that is cool
but if you're growing with seeds do it
about three five maybe seven to ten days
after pollination
so shortly after pollination it is safe
to turn those lights back to eighteen
six uh once you're uh once you see the
they're all curled up and they look like
they're pollinated you can see the
little seeds forming in there put it
back on eighteen
six uh there's no problem with that
they're going to eat more
they're going to grow more they're going
to finish sooner the seeds will be
bigger harder and fatter
this last crop of jack the ripper seeds
that i made was finished under 18
6 under leds and they're the biggest
fattest seeds i've ever bred with
the highest germination rate i've ever
accomplished so
don't puss out have confidence in
yourself have faith in what i'm teaching
you
and if it goes wrong send me a bunch of
[ __ ] hate mail tell me i'm an idiot
blast me all over the internet
i'm not wrong all right um i think that
is all i've got for this episode you
guys we've gone for quite a long time
i'm quite rambly
also my throat's getting dry and my add
is kicking in so i think it is time to
wrap up this episode i want to thank
everybody for hanging out for a fun
episode of the grow from your heart
podcast
i look forward to hanging god damn let
me clear my throat and try that again
like a professional
all right here we go i look forward to
hanging out with you guys in a couple of
days you know i'll be back with fresh
new content
if you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
and you'd like to make a financial
contribution to the show all you've got
to do is visit www.patreon.com forward
slash grow from your heart all of the
information you need
is right there on the screen then of
course if you've got any questions
corrections comments or concerns i would
love to hear from you the email address
is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com don't be shy reach out
send me those questions send me those
corrections send me your comments send
me your concerns
send me your positive feedback or send
me some ugly ass criticism
i'm cool i'm tough i'll take it don't
worry also make sure you visit the
website iriegenetics.com
everything irie genetics everything grow
from your heart all stuff for rasta jeff
related
is right there at iregenetics.com
all right everybody i'll be back in a
couple of days with fresh new content i
want to give a giant shout out to my
buddy north north terps
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you