yeah here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rosta jeff
and this is episode 636 of the grow from
your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to focus
mainly on patreon questions
before we get there let's do a few shout
outs to a few members of the 710 club
of course the 710 club are those folks
who support us on patreon
at the seven dollar and ten cent a month
level or higher so with no further ado
let's kick it off with the big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to my friend brohan 78 let's send a big
thank you shout out to 13 spark
let's send a special thank you shout out
to my buddy thomas mcginnis
let's send a big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to our buddy
mobius groves
let's send a special fist bump to canner
reaper let's send a big grow from your
heart podcast thank you to the red eyed
optimist
let's send a special thank you shout out
to grow man stan and rivan waters
let's send a big thank you to frugal
rock and stash drop
let's send a big fist bump to the big
sexy dank and black hippie
and then let's wrap it all up with the
big grow from your heart podcast thank
you shout out
to a longtime supporter and a big friend
let's send a special thank you shout out
to the bafsta big thanks and big shout
out
to everybody who continues to support
the show on patreon
if you are not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so
all you've got to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need will be
right there on the screen and of course
i did include a link in the show notes
and the video description
to make it nice and easy for all of my
friends maybe you're in the garden maybe
you're driving maybe you're at work
who knows what you're doing maybe you
can't reach into your pocket pull out
your phone right now
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart the link is in the notes
whenever you are ready and seriously
thank you
for all of the continued patreon support
i'm going to talk a little bit about
patreon in a moment
first let's talk about the seed exchange
event that's right the
secret stash brought to you by groovy
gravy is coming up may 22nd at a secret
location in denver that's right
when you get your tickets and the event
gets closer to happening you will get
the exact location
don't worry it's a great venue it's a
great spot parking will be available you
will be safe
it's a good covid friendly venue we're
going to do
things correctly here the groovy gravy
secret stash seed exchange event
happening may 22nd in denver
if you are interested find the link in
the show notes and the video description
there's a link with
instructions how to get tickets uh all
the details you need
will be in that link follow that link
also use coupon code
rasta jeff and you will save 20 off your
ticket pricing
once again all of the vip tickets are
sold out uh booths are sold out to the
best
of my knowledge i cannot do anything to
get you vip tickets or a booth
uh the best i can do for you is give you
this link you can get tickets there
the other good thing i can offer you is
coupon code rosta jeff all one word
rosta jeff that will save you 20 off if
you're looking for any other
uh details or information you of course
will have to contact
the groovy gravy group and they will get
you figured out get you situated
again i am a participant in this event
i'm not throwing the event
i am a paid vendor so i can't give you
any hookups any deals
can't pull any strings for you a lot of
people have asked that's why i'm saying
this
uh i can get you that coupon code rosta
jeff saves you 20
that's the best i could do i look
forward to seeing all my friends in
denver on the 22nd can't wait to see you
there
also you guys i was on the neighborhood
hang my friends have started a podcast
it's kind of a podcast it's a video show
maybe it's a vodcast if you will
they've got a show on youtube called the
neighborhood grows
grow show it is a great show it's mainly
hosted by my buddy raptor there are a
lot of great
uh faces on there we got og purple
thumbs on there we got dave on there
uh duck foots on there of course lori is
on there tent hangs out on there there
are a lot of great people i'm gonna
forget somebody
there's a lot of great uh friends and uh
family that hang out and congregate in
the neighborhood they've got
a great podcast happening i was a guest
on monday if you did not catch the live
show on monday
i highly because i do almost everything
quite highly i recommend
you find the neighborhood grow show not
only check out the episode i was on
because i had a good time
i was very comfortable i was very
relaxed i felt like i was just
hanging out with my bros uh just doing a
show it wasn't even really an interview
but they interviewed me quite well
i recommend you find the episode i was
on also subscribe
to their channel watch all the other uh
previous and subsequent
episodes give them some geez i'm gonna
catch my breath give them some support
that was harder to say than it looked
support the gang support the crew those
are friends of mine i got nothing but
love and respect for them we got to
spread this cannabis love around
uh pass the love just like you do with
joints so support my friends
on the neighborhood grows
the next order of business we need to
talk about here is
i am a [ __ ] talker when it comes to
smoking rosin boy i am not a big fan of
rosin
75 of the time your rosin tastes like a
popsicle stick or burnt popcorn
and i cannot stand the [ __ ] flavor of
a popsicle stick on my tongue if you put
a tongue depressor on my tongue
popsicle stick on my tongue i can feel
it in my bones in my body right now this
weird
ah they call it the chills it's an
uncomfortable [ __ ] feeling
i got i don't know if you call it
chicken skins or goosebumps whatever the
[ __ ] you call it wherever you are
my skin's crawling doing weird [ __ ] i
don't like a tongue depressor i don't
like that
unfinished wood texture in my mouth it's
disgusting
a lot of times that's what rosin tastes
like to me burnt popcorn and the tongue
depressor
and it makes my tongue and my face make
this terrible shape i go oh
and you can tell by looking that it
looks like i just took a bite of poop
uh it's not pleasant anyway i did take a
dab of some rosin
the past couple of days that was made by
a friend that was uh a gift that we
can't talk too much about
how it landed here and who got it to me
however
they know who they are i talked about
another product in a previous episode my
friend wondered if this was him
this time bro i am talking about your
rosin the [ __ ] was good it was tasty
i got a nice buzz from it it was heavy
on the lungs and the flavor changed
so many times there were two jars one
honestly is not my favorite but it's
smokable the other one i went back for
more so i do approve i do enjoy the
rosin
uh you guys are getting better the rosin
makers are getting better at making
rosin is what i've noticed
you're learning the temperatures the
times the techniques it's all being
dialed in
and it's getting better that being said
i'm still a batter fan
there's nothing uh nothing better than
some good green dot batter they do not
pay me to say that actually
i just go buy all my products at the
dispensary just like you do green dot
doesn't email me message me we have no
relationship
good product all right uh the reason i'm
stoned is rambly is because
of the um i can't think of the name of
the strain that i smoked but it was some
rosin
and it was delicious it'll come to me i
think it was some i don't want to say
the wrong one
i know what it was my brain will not
allow me to say it by the end of this
episode maybe i'll remember or i'll
press pause
go find it then tell you the real name
it's one word it's one word
i know the name of it just won't come to
my head because i'm
[ __ ] plenty stoned all right where
are we going from there it is springtime
this is where i could use
your help i do a lot of podcasting i'm
putting out a lot here
i'd like some feedback some replies some
information
this i guess is what we're going to call
the call to action in this episode
it is springtime i was out today driving
around running some errands you'll
notice i'm not wearing a hoodie no long
sleeve shirt in this episode
rocking a t-shirt and jeans and sneakers
it is finally
freaking nice outside it is the
springtime spring is upon us
ah people are looking lovely out there
the sunshine's got people in a good mood
also they're driving like a [ __ ] but
that's beside the point
what i'm getting at is i want to make
some spring and summer
irie genetics and grow from your heart
merchandise however that is not my niche
i'm not the best at that i'm better at
podcasting i am better
at being in the grow making seeds those
are the things i should focus on so i'm
going to ask you for help some more out
there
is a clothing designer somebody with
some cool artwork somebody that says
it is my turn to step up and help ross
to jeff what i'm looking for is
some spring apparel designs things i can
have printed in mass that aren't super
expensive and i can put them on my etsy
store and get them out to the people
so they can rock some new designs for
the spring i do have the green
and the orange shirts those are going to
look good for spring and summer that
purple shirt will look good i'll
replenish those
but we need some new designs maybe brand
new merch new ideas
i've expired expended exhausted that's
the word i've exhausted my brain on
merged ideas
i'm more focused on growing breeding and
podcasting so i'd like your help
uh what do you want with the irie
genetics branding on it what would you
rock
with the podcast logo on it where do we
go next honestly that is not my uh
my avenue my route my wheelhouse i'm
better at this stuff so i'm gonna focus
here
and i'm asking for your help what
merchandise is next
what do you think i could put out i like
to put out merchandise that works well
uh i sell seeds so what would go well
with
the seeds i put out shirts are cool uh
hats are cool stuff like that is great
stickers and things are awesome but what
are some other products maybe
that you could see branded that you
think would be beneficial to you
and me as well and we could work
together and get them in your hands all
right
i feel like i made my my piece clear
there you know what i'm looking for i
need some merchandise help also if you
draw
stuff if you make logos make designs and
you want to make like a certain color
t-shirt tank top something we need
merchandise for the ladies i don't have
any
ladies specific merchandise and the
ladies look great out there in the
summer so we got to get them looking
good
whatever's on your mind that you think
of if you draw if you create send me an
idea
trust me if you create something for me
you will be
heavily compensated ask dave dave does
me favors dave gets well taken care of
i'm generous i'm friendly anything i'm
going to profit from
i promise you will profit from as well
if you do work for me
i turn the money around it goes back
you'll get seeds you'll get gifts you'll
get merchandise you'll get whatever you
ask for
i'll make it fair to you so thank you um
that was a long ramble on just a little
basic request for some help with
merchandise but
um [ __ ] you know me we take dabs we get
rambling
all right we're going to jump into these
patreon messages i think i've covered
all of the important part at the start
here
um yeah we've got a message that came
from patreon this one comes from our
friend
uh sacred tree organic farms and it says
what's up rosta jeff i've been keeping
up to date on each show and i appreciate
the hard work but i haven't heard from
you in a minute
i totally understand you're a busy guy i
really just wanted to make sure
you're getting my contribution and that
you got my messages about my business
name being shouted out so i can address
two things here right now
uh which are great things to talk about
um yes i did get your message about
giving you the shout out for the correct
name let's recap that
in a previous episode i did mention that
i give you shout outs based on the names
i've got on patreon i don't know what
name
uh you signed up under i don't know what
your real name is i don't know your
instagram name i don't know your surname
i've got your name from patreon i said
instagram a moment ago maybe
i've got your patreon name here on a
paper that's what i give you a shout out
to because that's the info i have
got if you'd like me to shout out a
different name you've got to message me
i will print out the paper that says hey
shout me out at this i'll try to
correlate
uh the two names on the paper and
remember to start using
your requested shout out so our friend
at sacred
sacred tree organic farms yes brother ah
i did receive your request to be shouted
out as sacred tree organic farms let's
take a big moment
give a big salute a grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to our
friends at sacred
tree organic farms for their continued
support through patreon
now here's something else i want to
address while i've got this topic open
i'm going to make sure i covered this
getting your support you got your shout
out big love big respect thank you for
that then it says
uh take care brother bro you take care
as well and thank you for the support
thank you for the uh
opening so that i can open up this box
and talk about this topic
now the part i want to talk about is um
there's one of me
and there are over 250 patrons at this
time
i'm grateful for each and every one of
you
but it is hard to give each and every
one of you
undivided attention so if you've sent me
an email if you've sent me a request
a message i don't hate you i'm not mad
at you i love you
with all of my heart from the bottom of
my long dreadlocks
i love and appreciate each and every one
of you
but my inboxes have just become
ridiculous and unmanageable
i'm trying i'm doing my best you guys i
get so many messages patreon becomes a
priority of course because you do send
funding with that
i feel like if you send money i should
pay attention to you first you paid for
me to look at the messages
i do what i don't want is people to
think that they're giving me
uh financial support and i'm ignoring
you i am getting a lot of support a lot
of messages
and there are 250 patrons uh 30
000 instagram followers uh 60 something
thousand cannabis followers
plus the 14 000 unanswered emails in my
inbox
and the thing about emails that i've
discovered i will sit here at this table
and put on music just loud enough not to
distract me just to get me focused i'll
take a couple of dabs to get me in the
zone
i'll get some snacks in my hand so i'm
just shoving snacks into my mouth and
answering emails
hours will go by i will have answered a
couple of hundred emails and then guess
what happens
those people all reply so it's like
every
100 emails i send 50 more reply i only
catch up halfway
i'm not complaining i love it it is a
sign of success it is a sign of
longevity
but i don't want you guys to feel like
you're being ignored or
neglected or whatever i love you guys
please don't stop with the message
but be patient with me realize it's just
me dude
ah that's why it's quality i could
people say hire an intern so i hire
somebody to help you
i don't believe or trust that anybody
will have the
passion enthusiasm the care the eye for
detail for
the seed company the emails the podcast
it's all got to be me
that's why it's successful maybe that's
an ego thing
but i know it's working now the only
thing that's slacking is i'm not getting
enough done but
as a business owner if you can't catch
up with the work that's a good thing
that means you've got a business
that's working it's flowing when i take
a break and go i'm bored all my work's
done that's when i
[ __ ] up that's when there's a problem
so please don't ever feel like i'm
ignoring you disrespecting you blowing
you off
i am up late i start my day by answering
messages i finish my day by answering
messages my girlfriend's like hey do you
ever stop working and i'm like i wish
like i'm totally paying attention to you
but also i've got to answer these
patreon messages so
uh shout out to her for being awesome
and putting up with the 24 hour work but
also you guys i'm trying
and i think i've made my point i'm just
stoned and rambly i love you guys i'm
not ignoring you it's just me i'm gonna
take a drink
all right i did cover that topic quite
well we beat the [ __ ] out of that dead
horse let's move on to
another topic that is more grow focused
something we could talk about and learn
something here
uh this one came from our friend cynthia
11 on patreon big shout out to my buddy
cynthia levin
sends me a lot of great messages um we
did talk about
some other stuff and i replied why i
don't do it and he replied with good
point
haters suck uh that was part of a
private conversation but you're very
correct brother
haters do suck shout out to all my
haters out there
if you're watching this out of hatred
out of spite i love you i hope you're
doing well i hope you uh gain success
and i hope you have a wonderful life
hug a hater send them on their way now
this message goes
i do have a few ideas for episodes
i like that this one says i've got a two
by four a two foot by four foot not a
two inch by four inch but a two foot by
four foot
dry and cured tent so they've taken a
grow tent and they've modified it and
set it up to be
their drying space they're drying their
chopped down flowers in this tint
it says i have now found that if you use
a 2x4 tint
with exhaust you can exhaust with a duct
fan into a four inch carbon filter for
like five to ten days
the plants are hanging down during this
period then you can take them off the
strings use plastic bins and leave them
in there just uh then take them off the
strings leave them just enough of a stem
to trim with then let them sit in the
same environment
with the plastic bins on the ground for
five to ten more days
then trim it and jar it burp we burp for
three weeks daily leaving in the tent
this method has worked well and is
simple and easy
uh that's a great idea that is a great
way to use a grotin
a lot of us are growing in the grow tent
and don't have a place to dry and cure
that tent that you grew in would be
perfect just modify it a little bit
don't turn on the light because we don't
need the light
just like our friend said use an exhaust
so that you're sucking out all that
stale air
use a carbon filter so you're not
spreading that intense aroma around
because once you harvest the smell is
[ __ ] intense once you start rustling
those trichomes around moving the plants
around it really gets stinky
so you got your grow tint you got your
carbon filter you got your blower in
there you're sucking out the stale air
you're bringing in fresh air
a little bit of air movement is good not
ridiculous air movement in there you
don't want it blowing on those plants
but yeah you've got the right idea
they're hanging upside down which is
ideal uh take them off the string use
clean plastic bins and leave just enough
of a stem to trim with that
sounds ideal to me basically similar to
what we would do in a commercial
environment i'll talk on that in a
second
let them sit in the same environment in
the plastic bins on the ground yes
something the only thing you're not
doing that i do in a commercial
environment
is i put a humidifier and a dehumidifier
in that room
i don't use a tent i have a room uh with
locks and cameras and [ __ ] but
i put those device i put a humidifier
and dehumidifier in the same room
and set them both at 50 percent and let
them [ __ ] fight
that way it is always 50 humidity in
that room
if you can control the uh temperature
that would be ideal as well i understand
this is in your home
uh but it sounds like you're doing the
right thing um leave them for
so you've got them hanging for five to
ten days on the ground for five to ten
more days that's gonna be
14 20ish days that's right about the
right time period
then trim it and jar it then burp three
weeks daily
leaving in the tent um at this point you
could take them out of the tent if you
wanted to
put them on a shelf or whatever but if
you want to leave them in the tent
that's cool
uh this method has worked well and is
simple and easy yes that's a great idea
because
a lot of people don't have drank your
space they did not plan for that they
did not prep for that they don't know
where they're going to do it so that
tent
is a great space why not just utilize
that space you've already paid rent
already bought the gear it may slow you
down two weeks on your next crop
but if you're not looking for production
if you're just running this small crop
that is a beautiful idea since the
eleven thank you for the great idea
um if you got any more questions brother
i do look forward
to hearing from you guys use that space
you've got guys and gals
use the space you've got the only thing
i would do differently uh i would add
that humidifier and dehumidifier but uh
you might be in just the right area to
where you don't need to do that i've got
an area in my basement that is perfect
for drying and curing plants i don't
have to add or subtract anything the
plants just [ __ ] love it so
sometimes we get lucky alright i do have
another question this one
says if not bad genetics what causes
hermaphrodites or intersex traits that
is a very
very good question most of the time if
we see intersex traits in a plant we
immediately blame genetics it's either
genetics or grower right those are the
two things it could have been
but there's something we often overlook
and my buddy james bean calls it
the jurassic park effect and i
completely agree with that
um the bottom line is life finds
a way ah cannabis is an annual plant
that is designed to live for one season
it's supposed to veg flower produce
seeds
die the seeds grow next year annual plan
one season one year
we have developed plants that don't
produce pollen
and don't produce any seeds because they
are cincimillia plants we take them
we've taken the males out of the
equation
there's no seeds in the female plants
these plants know there's no seeds they
know they're not getting pollen a female
plant's whole
goal in life is to get pollinated that's
all she wants it's her sole purpose
is to get pollinated and make seeds so
that we can
can continue this uh generation or this
bran this uh seed line however whatever
label you want to put on it this brand
of seeds
can continue for generations and
generations
the male plant's whole idea is to drop
loads of pollen
on those female plants to continue his
bloodline that's why the male plant gets
taller
the pollen falls down the female plants
are lower they receive the pollen they
make seeds
the season ends they either get frozen
they fall to the ground and die the wind
drops them down the birds eat them [ __ ]
out the seeds somewhere else
seeds are scattered randomly chaotically
just like pollen
so that's not happening in our grow
rooms
it's just simply not happening we don't
have birds we don't have bees
uh we don't have a lot of things
happening in there these plants know the
female plants are like
[ __ ] horny i've been in this room for
this many weeks i've been in flour
around week three i really should have
got jizz done and got filled up with
seeds but that didn't happen
i'm like nine weeks into flour my
trichomes are ripe my leaves are weird
the season changed in here he's got it
nice and cold he changed the [ __ ]
light cycle i don't know what to do i'm
gonna die
and i didn't get pollinated so i'm not
gonna get to make babies
watch this and so that plant just goes
boink and it makes a [ __ ] seed
because
life finds a way just like jurassic park
bro they only had female plants but or
they only had female dinosaurs but
somehow one of them female dinosaurs
some immaculate conceptions some
some biblical [ __ ] happen and there are
more dinosaurs cannabis plants work just
like that they will
create their own seeds they will create
their own pollen
uh there are ways to make this happen
also um what causes herms
so stress will do it uh bad genetics
will do it
over feeding underfeeding terrible
environment will do it
but letting it go way too long will also
do it if you let if that plant should
have been
chopped down at week 8 and you let it go
to week 10 or 11 it will hermaphrodite
on you
a lot of things can contribute to
intersex traits and hermaphroditism
it should have been washed out in the
breeding it should have been selected
better
that should have been uh before we gave
you seeds or spread them out we should
have realized there's a trait in there
that needs to be bred out or
the seeds need to be tossed but
any plant has the opportunity to uh show
an intersex trait
it has got the will to survive life will
find a way
and shout out to my buddy james bean for
coining that jurassic park term
i don't know if he made that up but that
is who i heard it from life
will find a way just like jurassic park
so
um if not bad genetics what are some
causes of hermaphrodites the will to
survive bro is the main
cause for hermaphrodites it's not just
bad genetics sometimes grower error
you have to keep in mind that a lot of
the chem dog stuff a lot of the og stuff
is prone to being hermaphroditic to
showing intersex traits it's up to us to
not give it the opportunity we know that
certain things in the room will trigger
that
over feeding it under feeding it too
much cold drastic temperature swings
[ __ ] like that stress at all will cause
a chem 91
or a real old-school og kush plant to
just go herm on you over watering it
over watering an og kush plant can cause
it to turn into an intersex plant it
already was intersex
it'll cause it to show the intersex
trait so
a lot of things can trigger that you can
grow a plant several several times
and just one new thing can really piss
it off and make it display
that intersex trait for you all right
i've got one more
great message this is a good one it's
kind of a long message i'm going to cut
to the chase once i start reading it
i don't know if they want their name
said because i do
you'll understand why it says i hope you
uh this finds you well
i've had issues maintaining a constant
temperature and keeping humidity up in
my tents
i will set the stage for you to better
help you wrap your head around this
problem i like that approach
i will end with the steps i plan on
taking to look forward
uh look i will end with the steps i plan
on taking and
i look forward to hearing from your
expertise
so this is a great way to set up an
email it says i have two tents in a room
uh that is as sealed as can be while
maintaining an inconspicuous outside
view that's
[ __ ] understandable in my veg tin i
have two leds and then we talk a little
bit about the grow
then we come to the main problem of the
grow the room itself has
temperature fluctuations um we can't get
the room
much lower than 83 degrees i've taken
more of a macgyver approach for this
problem and i would like to avoid
bringing in ac units expensive
regulators and so on but
if that's what it has to be then so be
it it says so far my steps have been
placing buckets of water with an air
pump and stone in the tents
that's not going to make it cool you
need cool says i moved my flower tent to
the coldest part of the room away from
the basic
radiator to have to maintain minimum
heat which it obviously didn't work
then it says i'm a brand new grower and
i've listened to your collection of grow
tips four times
and i would like to have a nice setup
before i start my new seeds any
criticism
is appreciated and keep it up um
so i had a lot to say about this message
and then
i just cut right to the chase i was like
bro you can do all kinds of magic you
can hope and pray
you can move [ __ ] around the answer is
buy an air conditioner why are you
dodging an air conditioner
you can make this job as hard as you
want you can make this grow as
challenging as you want on yourself or
you already said it i could buy an air
conditioner you've already brought
buckets into the room and put bubblers
and [ __ ] in there
you're moving things around you're
trying to do macgyver tricks
why not go to the store and buy the air
conditioner and install the ac
so i said uh um buy the air conditioner
bro
and then he said an update i buckled and
got a regular ac
unit and i said uh sorry for the slow
reply but you have made the correct move
sometimes in a grow environment you have
just got to bite the bullet and get the
correct gear you can try
to macgyver stuff you can duct tape
stuff you can rig stuff up however you
want
but every bud you grow every half-assed
larvae fluffy nugget that you produce
is going to show that your grow room was
not what it could have been
you know your flaw you know your weakest
link
why are you gonna let that weak link
that [ __ ] in the armor
the [ __ ] the weak part be the weak
part you know it
that's fix that you did you did you
stepped up and i'm just saying anybody
out there who's thinking like this
ah it is springtime it's about to go
into summertime
it's not the time to be cheap now is the
time to get the dehumidifier you need
the air conditioner you need
get that room dialed in properly you're
growing medicine you're growing a
product
you want high quality when i worked at
guitar center i used this to explain
things to customers you could buy a
cheap-ass guitar if you want
but it's going to hurt the kids fingers
it's going to sound like [ __ ] it's never
going to be fun to play
you're never going to sound like
metallica on that shit-ass guitar
or you could step it up and not buy the
lowest level
you could buy a guitar center it goes
good better best you could buy
better you could buy the medium range
guitar where it doesn't kill your
fingers every time you play
and it's got potential to have good tone
it's not going to fall apart
it's not going to come out of tune every
time you hit the [ __ ] strings
get the better don't get the the shitty
one the good one get the better one so
that you actually enjoy growing
your your goal here is to produce a
product but also
growing can be very therapeutic for me
being in the grow room
i don't answer the phone if i'm in the
grow room and anybody calls
it maybe if the daughter calls because
my daughter might need something i'll
answer for
anybody else uh the girlfriend the
company
the banker the accountant i don't answer
for them that's
i'm in the garden dude that is my zen
space that is my moment
that is my area you can't [ __ ] with me
and if i just cheap-assed it and used a
shitty half-assed piece of gear in there
i wouldn't have any pride in it
and it wouldn't feel zen when i was in
there so put a lot of pride into it and
also understand that
this is a budget issue for a lot of
people but don't cheap out
you're buying other things i bet you
like maybe just don't buy
that playstation game or that xbox game
did i [ __ ] say that that's like me
saying don't buy that one pair of
sneakers
so that you can buy that air conditioner
but you know what i'm buying the
sneakers now
because i bought all the air
conditioners already and they're running
and the rooms are working
so i know things are where they need to
be and in turn the business is working
so since i put the money in
there's money coming out i can buy the
sneakers now you got to put the money in
to get the product out you want my point
is if you're going to do this [ __ ]
have pride in it have 100 pride
if you go in there and you just half-ass
it and the product comes out and you're
half-assed
when you smoke it it'll be a half-assed
product you'll have half-assed pride in
it
anything that you grow and you smoke and
you consume that you put pride into
you're gonna feel a better buzz more
pride when you consume it
so put pride in there we've talked about
this on a previous episode
a lot of you are growing allegedly maybe
potentially possibly
in an illegal place if you're gonna do
it [ __ ] do it
like don't go in there and just half ass
it have pride in it
felonies aren't free don't commit that
crime to [ __ ] just be doing it
commit that [ __ ] felony to win like
if you're gonna go in [ __ ] go
in dude all right i feel like i rambled
for a long time i've got another message
here but i think we should save this one
because i've been going for a long time
and the throat is nice and dry
um ladies and gentlemen boys and girls
pimps hoes friends
foes smokers growers clone cutters paul
and chuckers
i want to thank you again for listening
to another episode of the grow from your
heart podcast
um if you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
maybe you'd like to make a financial
contribution to the show maybe you'd
like to
show some support like my friend crazy
hands does big shout out to crazy hands
for supporting the show
also big shout out to my friends stony
like baloney and kurt z
for being huge supporters of the show
without guys like ez057
and aldridge this show wouldn't be what
it is i'm trying to sneak in more
patreon shout outs because they are
overloaded i've got a lot of them that
i'm due
i need to do more episodes put more
shout outs in the episodes but
gotta sneak them in there where it is
smooth if you feel like the episode was
educational or formative entertaining
you'd like to support us
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information is right there uh
once again big thanks to
everybody who supports the show if
you've got any questions corrections
comments or concerns i would love to
hear from
you my email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com again that's where
you can send
questions corrections comments concerns
or also your merchandise ideas i don't
know if i gave you the email address
before
that is the spot to send those
submissions trust me you'll get paid
once again if you uh what else do we got
for you the website that's where we're
going
uh make sure you check out the website
all things ire genetics all things grow
from your heart
are featured on my website
iregenetics.com
check it out um i think that's all i've
got for you i'll be back in a couple of
days with fresh new content this was a
sloppy ass ending but it was natural and
sometimes
that's how it goes thank you guys for
listening i look forward to joining you
in just a few days
i want to give a giant shout out to my
buddy og purple thumb
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
[Laughter]
you