[Music]
yeah welcome back podcast world
i'm your host my friends call me rasta
jeff and this is episode
637 of the grow from your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to answer a
couple of grow questions before we get
to that part you know i like to do shout
outs to our friends who support us on
patreon
so let's kick it off with the big grow
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out
to my friend lefty's farm let's send a
big thank you shout out to captain mojo
i want to send a big thank you shout out
to north north terps and a big thank you
shout out to miss north terps
listen to big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to caribou
heart tv
i want to send a big fist bump to girls
grow too let's send a big high five to
don't tread on me 420
let's send a big special thank you shout
out to josiah w
i want to send a big thank you shout out
to adhd grower
let's send a big fist bump to a long
time supporter let's send a special
thank you shout out to pack northwest
dan
let's send a big thank you shout out to
kes burton for all of the support he
does with the veterans
listen to big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to jt
grows i want to send a big fist bump to
zach's and scout in
and then let's wrap up these shout outs
with a big thank you shout out
to my friend paparoni big thanks and big
shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon
if you are not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so
all you've got to do is visit
www.patreon.com
from your heart of course all of the
information you need is right there on
the screen
uh there is a link in the show notes and
the video description so if you've got
your hands full maybe you're driving or
whatever you're doing
follow that link that will get you right
to the patreon page at patreon.com
forward slash
grow from your heart speaking of patreon
i'm going to jump right into this first
message it says hey i got the
subscription for my boyfriend as a gift
he goes by zecifer so in previous
episodes i've talked about making sure
to do
the appropriate shout out for the
appropriate name this person signed up
for patreon
i think i gave the girlfriend or the
other half of their relationship a shout
out
they sent me a message and said hey
please shout out zee safer because i
bought this subscription from my
boyfriend as a gift
so shout out to zeecifer you got a great
partner there getting you a
patreon subscription also thank you
zeesafer because i got a great gift out
of that as well
uh good work thank you uh both for the
support
all right once again you guys if i'm
doing shout outs and i'm not saying the
appropriate name
please politely kindly gently send me a
message and say hey you're calling me
zecifer or not calling me zecifer and
that's what i need to be called
let me know i'll get it straightened out
also am doing my best to catch up on
patreon messages i realize i am behind
i'm a one-man army uh no i'm not a
one-man army i'm a one person you guys
are a huge army
i'm a one-man show with a big army uh i
can't respond to everybody right away
but i'm doing my best i promise
i'm catching up uh the thing about
emails i've said this before you reply
to them and you get
more back people reply again ah thank
you guys for all the support it means a
lot to me
uh shout out to zeus and the gang now i
do want to move into some of the chatter
part of the show here that's what i
labeled this
it is called chatter uh this portion of
the show will be brought to you by my
friend ez057 shout out to ez057 for the
continued support
we do not have corporate sponsors here
on this show we've got friends and
family that support us and
i will give them shout outs when i feel
it's appropriate feels way better than
talking about a [ __ ] ass product i
probably wouldn't use and trying to pawn
off on you guys for money
not going to do that we're going to
shout out our friends in need love big
up big up to ez057
now the first chatter in today's episode
is a very
common thing i see on social media i
need to stay off social media honestly
because it's going to give me a [ __ ]
aneurysm but
something i want to talk about when we
talk about day one of flower
day one of flower is day one when you
turn that that timer to 12 12
that's day one of flower that is when
you started flowering so
i saw somebody say that the first two
weeks don't count the first week doesn't
count
you don't start counting until you see
hairs or something
nah bro you're the farmer you're the
grower it is
your control day one is when you flipped
that timer that is when you did it so
that is always going to be day one
and people are gonna say why do you get
to decide that that's day one because
i make the seed packages bro i printed
the labels on the seed pack and i
i decided that on my seeds that's day
one and all my other breeder friends we
talked about it and
we had a little meeting and a powwow and
a group and we all realized and decided
that we needed to say day one is the day
we turn the lights to 1212. a lot of you
some of you many of you a few of you i
don't know the ratio
some of the [ __ ] out there are going
to be turning the lights off completely
for 48 24 hours
then going into flower um i think day
one is when you put that 12 1212 on the
first time
and when it comes on 12 hours on 12
hours off that is now day one
people are gonna say what about day zero
and all kinds of weird [ __ ]
just quit overthinking it day one is the
first time you put the plants on a
12-hour day
that's day one a lot of people also talk
about
doing weird transitions i just mentioned
12 uh 24 hours off 48 hours off
there's not really a downside to that
that's free it doesn't cost you anything
you're not getting any light energy and
the plants will transition more quickly
but it's also not completely
necessary also i don't agree with like
uh tapering down light cycles they say
but that happens outdoors yeah we're not
growing outdoors at all
uh you don't want in my opinion i do not
want to
uh just slowly decrease the amount of
time
that the lights are on in my room they
go from uh either 20 on and
four off or 18 on and six off straight
to
12 12. boom straight into flower that is
day one that the day i change that timer
uh maybe it's tomorrow that they're
gonna wake up and do 12 on and 12 off
that is when i will count day one it's
generally a monday for me i like to flip
on monday it's just easier to keep track
of [ __ ]
flip on monday feed on monday do all the
big work on monday
catch up on the rest of the stuff
throughout the week all right so day one
is the day
that you flip those plants into flower
don't let anybody tell you any
differently
we're gonna set a standard here we're
all going to agree day one is the day
day one of flower is the day you flip
that timer to
12 12. uh we'll touch on veg
you could do veg however you want i do
sealing or clone stage and then i do
small veg and then i do large veg
you can break up the veg cycle however
you want that works best for you that is
your uh
your factory your grow your farm you get
to decide how you want on that so
uh you can label that however you want
my clones are clones you know what i'm
saying they're clones as soon as they
come from the cloner they are small
veg they're in either a four inch square
pot or a six inch net pot sometimes
they're in a beer cup
that is my small veg once it goes into a
one gallon pot
that could be medium veg depending on
what i'm doing then it'll go into three
gallon or a five gallon maybe a seven
now i'm in full veg so
you get to decide when you enter that
veg stage
small large veg that is kind of up to
you it doesn't matter because it's your
garden it's just an arbitrary label that
you're giving it
it we're not checking on you the one
that really matters is flour day one of
flower is when you flip
all right i want to move down the list
here another thing when i'm on the
internet and social media another thing
that makes me want to have a small
aneurysm
ah is people saying that they can tell
the sex of a seed by the shape of
that seed ah that's [ __ ]
quit believing that quit perpetuating
that quit spreading that
uh just stop it stop it
just [ __ ] stop stop with that you
can't tell the sex of a seed
by the shape of the seed you can't do
that i make feminized seeds i make
regular seeds
i can roll them on the table together
you can tell no difference between the
regular and femme seeds you can hold
them
one of each side by side with the
magnifying glass you're not going to see
any difference you've got to grow them
maybe you could do some science and cut
them open and do some dna checking and
you could tell which seed is male and
female
maybe at that point i don't even know if
you can do it then but you definitely
cannot tell by looking
people say that if it's got like a
volcano on the one end or a dimple on
one end or
[ __ ] no dude stop no you got to grow
them gotta grow them out so quit with
that [ __ ] that is not real
anybody that says that immediately
discredits themselves for anything else
they're going to tell me about cannabis
in the future
all right so uh what i wanted to get to
my next note is uh the internet is full
of backseat drivers and armchair
quarterbacks take all of that internet
advice you guys with a huge grain of
salt
and to be quite honest with you even my
advice
i don't know your grow the advice i give
uh works in i grow in either soilless
mix or cocoa
cocoa pots indoors under leds
or gavita lights the advice i give my
knowledge works for what i am doing
i try to keep it general so it works
across the board
but sometimes what i'm doing is kind of
specific and i try to be
specific about that and let you know if
you took some of my ideas
and you took the ideas that i give you
for an indoor grow and you did that in a
greenhouse it may not work if you did my
soil ideas in a hydro setup
it just may not work so when you see
people on the internet saying you've got
to do this
maybe they're growing in a completely
and different environment completely
different method completely different
plan than you so
don't be afraid to do things your way
there's no wrong way to grow cannabis
the wrong way is when the plants die or
you get raided that is the wrong way
you get mildew you get bugs you learn
from that you recover you move on
there's no real
wrong way if you get a harvest that
you're happy with
you did it right so don't let people on
the internet tell you you're doing it
wrong especially
people that aren't experienced or even
me if you want to do it your way you
could tell me to go [ __ ] myself and do
it your way and have fun
that's one of the most important parts
is have fun in the grow
a lot of us have made i've been guilty
of this i worked in commercial
cultivation
for so long that i let growing become
stressful
there were deadlines there were goals
there were numbers i was forgetting
about the most important part about
when somebody smokes this herb they're
going to feel better that's the most
important part and i was forgetting
about that
so have fun in there but while you're
having fun in there learn
don't forget to experiment learn
something broaden your horizons
just repeating the same cycle over and
over and over that's cool
until you get good at it but once you've
got your [ __ ] training wheels are
there take off those training wheels and
let's do some tricks bro let's do some
wheelies and [ __ ]
so get in there and have fun don't let
people slow you down don't people let
people sway you
experiment learn take a bunch of notes
so that when you do something positive
or negative to the plants
you've got notes i talk about that all
the time grow
as a grower those plants are going to
teach you things about yourself
the business will teach you things about
yourself you'll learn how to absorb
knowledge how you do learn and do not
learn then you'll go back and you'll
grow the plants and the plants will
teach you more things and then when you
smoke them you learn even more things
these plants are incredible to us they
can be greatly therapeutic if you take
care of them
so the internet doesn't always know does
not always know
your goals your obstacles your situation
your setup when you go looking for
advice on the internet
be very leery and be very careful look
to
trusted books there are plenty of books
on the internet for free
you don't have to go to facebook and go
to a group and be like what is this
there's a book out there that has that
answer that was written by a
professional
cannabis grower and an author that knows
what they're talking about
you're going to see a lot of wacky ass
answers on social media
be very careful advice is situational
i see a lot of times people say
something like uh you need to do this
and i'll just comment with why does this
grower need to do that
and they'll say i do it and i'll say
so i eat [ __ ] vegan food and drink
kombucha does that mean that all growers
need to do that like i'm good at growing
does that mean that since i
drink kombucha and eat [ __ ] vegan
that everybody else out there has to do
it to be good at growing no
it does not uh if i said i eat vegan and
drink kombucha and it makes me a better
grower because of this
then maybe i've got some ground some
ground to stand on
but if you're just saying because i do
it that's [ __ ] monkey sea monkey do
and there's no real scientific [ __ ]
support behind that
my favorite is when somebody's like well
my cousin did at one time and it worked
like man was your cousin growing hydro
was your cousin growing [ __ ]
soil was your cousin growing indoors or
outdoors we don't know we got one idea
your cousin said pour [ __ ]
biscuits and gravy on it on sunday and
it would go kapow right but
man we don't know what kind of biscuits
we don't know what kind of gravy and so
we got people [ __ ] up their gardens
putting biscuits and gravy out there on
sunday
and it's just messing [ __ ] up because
one guy's uncle did it one time and it
worked so
advice is very situational what works
for uh your buddies biscuits and gravy
grow
may not work for my soil grow may not
work for your hydro grow
may not work for somebody's vertical
grow so pay very close attention
then learn the plants you've got to
learn the plants that's the only way to
do this pay attention to the plants
you've got to
experiment you got to get in there and
[ __ ] up i've [ __ ] up recently i've
talked about i
had to kill a few plants because i just
wasn't happy with the way they were
going but i did an experiment
i learned i know what not to do next
time trust me i know what not to do that
is what i learned the most
what not to do next time um i've done a
full episode about mistakes i'm kind of
off on a ramble here but i enjoy it
um i've done a full episode about my
mistakes i don't post my failures to
social media you only see my victories
but the failures are what have made me a
better grower
i don't learn anything if i'm successful
every time if i don't get a bug
if i don't get a nutrient deficiency if
i don't run into an equipment failure
what do i learn my ego gets ahead of me
and i start thinking i can do anything
in the garden i start dancing in there
and
popping bottles of kombucha and throwing
quinoa flakes in the air like it's a
[ __ ] party that's just a hippie joke
guys don't take me too seriously
but then i do [ __ ] like i go ahead and
replace [ __ ] lights in the middle of
winter and then three days later it's a
negative 17. i don't have hps lights in
this grow room to keep the grow warm
anymore
and all my plants look like [ __ ] and
nearly die what i make mistakes like
that
because i just wasn't thinking i'd been
winning too much i hadn't taken an l in
a long time guess what i [ __ ] lost
that time
learned my big lesson from that l
anyway you guys don't be afraid to fail
a couple times but also set yourself up
for success don't let the internet ruin
your grow
if i say you should do something
research it think about it i'm not the
only grower that knows what i'm talking
about there are a lot of other people
you can cross-reference what i said with
them
guru has different approaches to how i
grow scotty has different approaches
or different approaches than how i grow
scotty grows differently than i grow
uh who else out there has a aquaponics
steve potent ponics steve grows
completely differently than i grow
but we're both having great success
we've both got podcasts that could teach
you don't be afraid to cross-reference
our knowledge you guys don't be
don't be scared to double check me
especially if you're growing a little
bit differently than what i'm used to
and what i'm teaching
uh straight up i do soilless mix or
cocoa in about a three gallon pot
uh if it's a commercial grow i'm using
gavitas if it's a personal girl i'm
using leds
if you're doing something differently my
advice is going to be a little bit
different you know
all right i think i made my point there
don't let the internet sway you you guys
have a goal have a plan [ __ ] do it i
see a lot of people say
can i do this and i just answer yes a
lot of the times because
yes and then i see people just trying to
[ __ ] crush their dreams
don't let the dream crushers crush your
dreams dude you can do it yes you can
uh can i do this most likely with
cannabis yes you can
if you can't i'm gonna tell you no
that'll kill your plants or no you can't
do it i'll give you a reason why though
i'm not just gonna [ __ ] all over your
hopes and dreams and say no you can't do
that and you're [ __ ] and [ __ ]
don't forget your helmet
no i'm gonna tell you why you can't do
that help you learn help you set
yourself up for success
help you have a good grow and let you
know why the idea is simply not going to
work before you spend time energy money
effort
and a broken heart on this crazy
experiment somebody's probably already
done
all right i'm way into this episode
where are we
i got to see when i started uh that much
time minus that much time means i got
plenty more time that's what that means
um i got a message where did this one
come from this looks like it came from
the website
yes on the irie genetics website at
iriegenetics.com there's a grow help tab
if you click on that grow help tab
we do ask you a few preliminary
questions we basically ask what strain
you're growing where you're growing it
uh if you're in veg flower what kind of
medium you're using
just a few details to help me answer
your question it makes it easier for me
when i've got some details
so that is where this question came from
got a lot of information
it gets down to the point it says i love
your show so much i listen to you on the
drive to work
you make mondays awesome that's great to
hear bro thank you don't forget about
thursdays
since i'm having problems making this
post so my message is shorter now but
could you please talk about
enzymes ah first off bruh i'm sorry if
the website was giving you [ __ ]
i hope you were able to post your
questions to the website maybe i should
check on that because
i haven't gotten a question in a minute
on there somebody sent me questions on
the website go to the grow help tab hit
me up make sure i'm getting those
um i've got a question could you please
talk about enzymes yes i will talk about
enzymes for you i wrote notes
somewhere here they are they're on this
page ooh i got scared thought i lost my
enzyme notes
um can you talk about enzymes and talk
about if i can use them
every watering as well as microbes i
just try to beef up non-feed days
or should i use them every time um
my first reaction to this was microbes
and enzymes every feeding
and i just saw dollar signs coming out
it's like that's [ __ ] expensive dude
um no you don't need to do that every
time that's going to get spendy
and that's quite excessive um those are
two expensive products enzymes and
microbes are
like the the turbo charge of your grow
and those are those are expensive so i
wouldn't use those
every time no i would use them
once a week and i would use them
separately in alternate feeding so if
you feed
uh you're probably gonna feed you're
gonna feed at least two or three times a
week right you got two or three separate
waterings per week no matter how big
your pots are
so let's say monday you know i like to
feed on monday give these bad [ __ ]
their main mix and some enzymes or their
main mix and some microbes one or the
other
then the next feeding give them their
main mix and the other one whichever one
you didn't give them
give it the main mix then that extra
nutrient the
enzymes are microbes sorry i'm thinking
about the next feeding the next feeding
may just be water
i may just give it plain water if you're
in uh soilless mix if you're in cocoa
feed it
if you're in hydro feed it but the next
time just water and then two feeds then
water maybe would be what i would do
but let's talk a little bit about these
products these uh
things that you're asking about um
enzymes
enzymes basically get in your they've
got to be fed in you can't follow your
feed them enzymes get down into the root
zone
and start breaking up any dead uh
anything that's dead funky decaying
dying matter that's not
going to be useful to the plant to the
rhizosphere it gets in there and just
eats all the dead [ __ ] that's what the
enzymes will do
kind of works as a cleaner uh cleans and
breaks down dead [ __ ] in your root zone
dying roots the root tips that are dying
off
if a root grew thought there's going to
be water here and you quit watering
enough to get to water
to that zone when you pour those enzymes
in there they're going to eat that dead
[ __ ] that died in there next time
to help clean it up keep it healthy keep
it moving kind of like a little uh
they're the
the recyclers they're just in there the
bottom feeders just cleaning [ __ ] up in
there
so that's enzymes um i do not have
the appropriate microscope nor the
appropriate education to tell you
if those enzymes are going to damage
your microbes
so i feel it would be wise beneficial to
feed them separately
i've seen studies that argue that the
enzymes could
disrupt the microbes if the microbes
could disrupt the enzymes
i've also seen studies that claim they
work together so
find the article that you agree with and
follow that one i guess but i would feed
them separately
so that is enzymes enzymes get in there
and clean [ __ ] up and break it down
that's why you hear uh enzymatic action
that's they're just breaking [ __ ] up
i think i like the little scrubbing
bubbles they're just in there scrubbing
and just chewing and just eating just
breaking [ __ ] down
uh then now let's talk about microbes
we've got a couple of different kinds of
microbes that come in mind
when we were talking about growing
cannabis uh we got mycorrhizal fungi and
beneficial bacteria
these things have a lot of different
functions when it comes to plants
these are the things that basically work
between the earth
and the plant they're the communicator
between your plant's root zone
and the der these things pick up a lot
of signals
they tell the plant a lot of things they
deliver a lot of things they provide
a lot of different functions there are
so many different types of microbes and
fungi
that they all have different jobs but
also can perform
each other's jobs i'm going to be honest
with you i am not the microbe
expert uh my friends scotty and guru uh
are [ __ ] overloaded with microbe
knowledge
ask them about microbes you will get a
long long episode
they're passionate about microbes but
the microbes basically help
buffer your soil or soilless mix they
help deliver the nutrients to the plants
they help the plants decide which
nutrients they want to be delivered
ah they uh what else do they do i wrote
something else oh they also help convert
nutrients into usable food
sometimes when we're pouring certain
things into the the rhizosphere there
into the nutrients into the root zone
some of those things aren't readily
available for the plants
those little microbes go oh i get this
little thing here and i got to do this
to it whomp
and it does a little magic trick and the
plant goes oh i can eat that now thank
you bro
so it's like just a little a little
buffer a little in between between the
root zone the earth
so to speak and the root of the plant
the microbes are the part that talk to
that
they're basically uh so if the the
nutrients are the i'm trying to pick
which end of this relationship i want to
be it's a drive-through window
you got the restaurant you got the
person coming up to the drive-through
the microbes are the pimply-faced kid
passing the burger
through the window or if you're going to
starbucks it's the beautiful barista
passing the the coffee over the window
that's the microbe for you they
they provide that relationship they take
the money they say hey we gotta give
this person this
uh stomachache [ __ ] toothache caramel
caffeine expendi and then they take the
money and i'm just making up starbucks
drinks couldn't think of one off the top
of my head
but they do the exchange for you
basically they take the money and then
they give you the drink and they send
you on your way so that's what microbes
are doing
and once again you guys i am not the
scientist i don't have a microscope or a
phd
i do have grow experience that's where i
think i am valuable i've got a lot of
experience i understand these plants on
a
not like a science level it's a
different level i just get them and i
can teach you that way
anyway i'm trying to defend myself here
um
but i'm just kind of talking a little
bit about microbes and enzymes
with the level of understanding that
i've got trying to let you understand
so um i would not use those products
they're expensive dude micro products
and enzymatic products can be very
expensive so
don't use them every watering that's
going to get expensive also i don't
think it's a there's no it's not
necessary there's no need for that
but do feed them on separate days uh
most of the microbe products you can
follow the instructions
with the dosage rate you're not going to
overdo it you can't overdo it with
microbes
the only thing you're doing is wasting
money when it gets to be too expensive
enzymes i don't know if you could over
feed maybe they could cause damage i've
never gotten that far with an enzymatic
product product before
but i hope i answered your question this
one did come from our buddy pt brad
pt brad thank you for the great question
i hope we rescued your strawberry
shortcake and
banana diesel if you've got any more
questions i do look forward to you uh
sending me more updates
uh ladies and gentlemen boys and girls i
do uh once again send me those questions
on the grow help tab because i haven't
gotten a message
there in a moment this message reminded
me that i don't think that's popping up
you guys might want to test me and send
that there
let me know what it does um i think
that's all i've got for you for this
episode i've been going for quite some
time now
i don't have enough time to open up
another email so i want to thank you
guys for listening to episode 637 of the
grow from your heart podcast
i had fun recording this show i hope you
had as much fun as i did big shout out
to my buddy billy podunk for hanging out
um let's see if you've got any questions
corrections comments or concerns you
know i'd love to hear from you
my email address is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com don't be shy reach out
send me a message also um i'm trying to
read something else here on the screen i
skipped a part that was important but
we'll talk about that
in another show if you feel like the
episode was educational informative or
entertaining and you'd like to support
the show financially
all you've got to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need is right
there of course there is a link in the
show notes
and the video description that makes it
nice and easy for all of my friends who
are busy
right now also don't forget about the
website where i keep talking about that
grow help
tab iriegenetics.com all things ire
genetics are right there
click that grow help tab send me your
grow questions also there is a
newsletter tab that says stay up to date
click on that newsletter tab
type in your email address you will get
a mailchimp message from me
approximately once a month i haven't
sent one out this month yet
the only thing i've got to tell you
about and advertise is that seed sales
event and it is nearly sold out
so make sure you join us for that but
join up on the mailchimp and you will
get a newsletter
i try to mail you once a month i will
not spam you too much i try not to
overload you but i want to keep you in
the loop and keep you updated
so check out the website click on that
stay updated tab
type in your email address you will get
a message approximately once a month
i'll do my best not to spam you
i think that is all i have got for you i
want to thank you guys again for
listening
i want to give a giant shout out to my
friend raptor grow and until next time
take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you