[Music]
yeah welcome back podcast world
i'm your host my friends call me rasta
jeff and this is episode 638
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to focus on
patreon questions
before we get there let's do a few shout
outs to a few members of the 710 club
of course the 710 club or those folks
who support us on patreon
at the 7 and 10 cent a month level or
higher so with no further ado let's
start off with the big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out
to my friend dom c let's send a big
thank you shout out to 716 grows
let's send a big thank you shout out to
paul f and new old guy
listen to thank you shout out to ivan m
and roll this nug
let's send a big thank you shout out to
jethro earl 710 and tartan mike
let's send a big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to my friend
tree star meadow
let's send a big thank you shout out to
zoso j and danky dave
a longtime supporter alabama man
and then let's wrap it all up with the
big grow from your heart podcast thank
you shout out
to my good friend glenn jeroni big
thanks and big shout out to everybody
who continues to support the show on
patreon if you
are not already supporting the show and
you would like to learn how to do so
all you've got to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need will be
right there on the screen of course i
did include that link in the show notes
and the video description to make it
super easy for all of my friends
i do want to thank everybody who sent me
an update sent me a message
uh gave me a heads up that there is a
problem with the podcast on apple
podcast stitcher radio spotify
uh all those services have been having a
technical issue with my podcast i
apologize
it is partially my fault it is partly
bluehost's fault uh bluehost did
an update something in that update
messed up my website you guys don't care
about the details
however i do know that the website
either has been or is messed up i don't
know if it's fixed by the time this
episode comes out at recording time
it is like halfway fixed it seemed like
it worked but it was still kind of funky
something was weird
anyway i cannot fix uh upload correct
adjust episodes on that service right
now
hopefully by the time this comes out
we'll have some progress but thank you
for the heads up
i do apologize that the episodes are not
or were not available on the service in
which you rely
if that ever happens again please do not
be shy to notify me to give me a heads
up that hey
your podcast is broken something's going
on i do like that sometimes that's how i
find i find out that there is an episode
so
let me know the episodes that have
disappeared or will not play will be
posted soon everything will be back to
normal
if you're hearing this that's probably
fixed in the future
if you are not able to find the episodes
on spotify apple podcast
uh stitcher radio any of those services
simply check out youtube so far youtube
has been reliable knock on wood
uh youtube is keeping us up they haven't
taken any videos down i'm going to talk
any further about that
if we disappear on the audio services
please do check out youtube maybe you've
checked that out by now
but maybe you're just missing shows i
don't know
and if you hear this in the future
because you've been missing episodes i
apologize that you missed a few episodes
but
please do catch up the episodes will be
back in the feed
as soon as we get things correct and it
just takes time you guys i got a
wonderful web friend a web guy working
on it big shout out to my web guy i
don't know if he wants his name said out
loud or anything but thank you bro
uh you're doing a great job i appreciate
it he interrupted his vacation to work
on my website so
that's the awesome kind of dude he is
thank you bro and you guys be patient
we'll get it going
what else do i want to talk about the
secret stash seed
exchange on may 22nd that's right i've
been talking about groovy gravy presents
the secret stash seed exchange in denver
colorado on may 22nd
i've been saying that most of the slots
are sold out however they did add
another time slot the way that this
event is working people are being given
a certain amount of time
to move through the building you'll get
to see all of the vendors who get to see
all of the exhibits
and then your time slot will be up and a
new group of people will move into the
building
this is to adhere to coveted
restrictions to keep everybody safe
basically just to be able to
be allowed to have a building or an
event in a building these are the types
of restrictions we need to follow
the point is they have added a full
another
time slot so if you're trying to get
tickets and the time you wanted wasn't
available or if something wasn't working
now is the time to check back at the
website the website is
in the link in the show notes it's in
the video description if you send me a
message i'll make sure to get you a link
also use coupon code rosta jeff that
will save you 20
off your general admission ticket i'm
going to say this again because i'm
still getting messages about it maybe
because the podcast is broken and some
people can't listen to it but
i cannot help you with booth space it is
too late for that
uh the place is full i cannot help you
with vip tickets
those are long sold out also i can't
help you with any access to the event or
tickets to the event or any vip hookups
other than that coupon code rasta jeff
all right i do apologize for the
clearing of the throat i've been smoking
a little bit of rosin it seems to go
heavier
in the lungs and throat uh but good in
stone so
shout out to my buddy purp got me nice
and heavily medicated
all right where do we go from there i
think i talked about all the important
stuff
another thing i wanted to talk about on
facebook i've been seeing people talking
on facebook social media
i scroll too much that's what i do and
i'm trying to relax a little bit
possibly pooping
but let's talk about what i saw on
social media people ask
uh often what nutrients should i be
using for an
outdoor grow i'm going to address this
in another question here soon but
the thing you should be using in an
outdoor grow something i would recommend
is i wouldn't go with the bottled
nutrients
i would go with amended soil and put
that plant right in the amended soil
and then feed it water and teas and top
dress it don't focus on bottled
nutrients outdoors
that's going to be a fiasco in my
opinion i think it would be more
beneficial
to focus on building a soil having a
starter soil
then amend that as times go time goes on
top dress
feed it tease then mainly you just got
to keep it wet and things will be
okay so when it comes to the best
nutrients for
an organic outdoor grow i would just
build that amended soil
and rock with some super soil or
something like that again i'm not the
organics expert
there are plenty of people out there
doing that
plenty of people out there who can give
you great organics advice refer to those
folks again that is not my area of
expertise
i do not want to mess you up all right
i've talked about all the stuff i
wanted to cover at the top of the show i
covered the news i covered the social
media stuff i saw
let's jump into the main topics of this
podcast which is of course the patreon
messages
this portion of portion what is the word
i'm looking for uh
this segment let's just say segment
because the other word i tried to say
did not work
this segment of the podcast is brought
to you by my friend the canon crap big
shout out to my buddy the canon crat
we don't use corporate sponsors here at
the grow from your heart podcast we let
our friends be
the sponsors shout out to the candy crap
for all the continued
support not just grow from your heart
podcast but also the irie
genetics support the ivory army wouldn't
be what it is without my friend the
kinetocrat big salute brother
all right now this first message came
from my friend lemur priest once again
big shout out to lemur priest
captain and commander of the irie army
he got stoned and
started reading stuff on seed packs
we're gonna kind of cut his message
short because
uh he wrote like multiple pages here um
i think he had a couple too many dabs
maybe but we're going to kind of
uh paraphrase what my buddy lemur said
we're going to make a good message out
of this it says i got
an idea about reading the listed
lineages of cultivars on seed packs and
websites that's a really good idea
we're going to get to the the topic of
this here of what he's actually talking
about it says hey ross to jeff
i'm humbled by your uh by the community
built around the podcast and your seed
company big thanks to you
i've been able to meet so many amazing
growers from all over the world
not everyone knows that there was a time
that sharing knowledge tips or helping
someone
else in their cannabis grow in any way
was a big no-no between being illegal at
the time
and mostly being used as a way for
someone to make or save money and the
investment of learning how to grow
relatively on your own there were lots
of incentives not to share tips yes
all of that makes sense back in the day
why would i teach you how to grow
because i'm the weed grower i'm going to
make all the money why would i give you
part of the pie part of the game
you could buy it from me and then resell
it if you want but i'm not going to
teach other people how to grow i agree
that used to be the mindset
that's why it took me a long time to
cave in and get into commercial
cultivation i didn't want to go teach
other people my tricks for an hourly
wage that didn't feel right
so yes i was illegal other people
couldn't know other people were going to
cut in on your market so we couldn't
share
tips and no yes we are in a state a
realm a time
an area a community where we could just
share the knowledge and i feel it's kind
of my duty to share the knowledge that
i've learned i talk a lot i've got the
gift of gab
obviously i just cannot shut up i can't
stop talking and i love cannabis i'm
passionate about cannabis
and i want you guys to be as good of a
grower as me i want you to enjoy
cannabis as much as i do so i feel like
it's my
my duty to come out here and share this
anyway it says
i remember getting lots of strange
skeptical looks from grower friends when
i would offer advice and tips
they would tell me it's weird i would
help them improve their plants because
uh they would have better herb and make
more money but honestly i was only
thinking about helping plants be happier
that's what it's all about bro make the
plants happier
the person that grows it is happier the
person that smokes it is happier grow
from your heart breed with love that's
what it's all about
uh he does talk a lot here our friend is
a teacher he says i love teaching
i found a place anyway we're going to
kind of skip a lot i could ask for
advice there's a lot he goes
on it says the peanut butter breath
batter has me ranting and sentimental
yes it does brother
i had to cut out several paragraphs of
what you were saying but i got nothing
but love for you bro there is a good
question in here um as i'm looking over
my seed collection reading the different
parents i noticed how some can be a
little confusing yes
if you're not immersed in the cannabis
world things can be confusing irie
genetics does a wonderful job of either
using cultivars with names or naming
them if you created them however some
breeders are not so helpful with that
yes
uh when i cross stuff i try to represent
the parent names in the cross in some
way shape or form or i try to
put the cross on the package really
clearly so that you know what i'm
working with
says sometimes a new cultivar isn't
something that is released and only used
for breeding purposes when that happens
this is when many of the parentheses are
used could you walk us through
some of the things we could see and what
they mean for the way they were bred all
right
now this there's a lot of talking going
on here but i understand what you're
asking
let me get to answering your question uh
he does break down some examples he says
for example picho g from ethos is peach
crescendo to millions of peaches
to quattro kush f3 how the three
cultivars are across make peacho g
and how is it different then and then
you list another thing um
this is this is a good question so let
me kind of back up because there is a
lot to talk about here
also shout out to lemur for the great
message this is going to get me talking
a lot
so the question is when we see multiple
strains listed
on a seed package how do we know which
was the male which crosses were which
used in that cross so a lot of times
basically you're going to see
strain a x strain b
in basic horticultural practices the
standard is to use
ladies first female plant x male plant
that's going to mean that the male plant
was the pollen donor and the plant
listed
first at the second plant was the pollen
donor the plant listed first was the
pollen
receiver so it's ladies first uh so
we're gonna say
uh golden goat to daybreaker you got a
golden goat female
a daybreaker male that daybreaker pollen
pollen donor
pollinated the female i'm stepping all
over my words but we're gonna get there
together just follow along
the daybreaker male pollinated the
golden goat female
to make a rise seeds so when you buy a
rye
seeds it says arise then in parentheses
underneath it
golden goat crossed daybreaker that's
real easy to understand that that is
golden goat and daybreaker and then you
know that golden goat
is this like sweet uh candy flavored gum
flavored
tropical sativa kind of thing with a
nice head buzz that makes you [ __ ]
weird high
and then you know that the daybreaker
maybe you know about daybreaker if not
i'll tell you about it daybreaker
is chem d and joseph og and it's real
stinky it smells funky
uh it's got like uh burnt tennis balls
burnt rubber
uh gassy skunky foot terps just funky
weird [ __ ] maybe some swamp ass in there
it's a short squatty plant so i know
both of those plants by
name now if i really wanted to i could
research both of those golden goat and
daybreaker and i could go further and
find the parents of each one and then
even further to find their parents
and i could learn about the family tree
the genetics the history the genealogy
the breakdown
the recipe if you will uh for each plant
so it's real easy when you've got
plant a and plant b grow plants a boy
plant right that's real simple for you
because you got two ingredients to work
with
what we're starting to see like our
friend lemur
mentioned here and pointed out to us and
highlighted is that sometimes we see
what do we got
crescendo to millions of peaches to
quattro kush
f3 how do we know which plant is the
male pollen donor in there because we
got three different things
one of those had to be a pollen donor
one of them had to be a female
then one of those plants had to
pollinate something else because you
can't put three plants into one mix like
that
so without a parenthesis in the what i
would call the appropriate or proper
place i don't know which plant was the
male i could do research
but as a seed seller and a seed breeder
why do i want to give somebody an
assignment or homework
when i could just tell you the answer on
my seed pack i could say oh that's
the quattro kush was the male or the
[ __ ] millions of peaches was the male
i'm going to assume because of the way
it's listed but you know what happens
when i assume i'm going to make an ass
out of everybody involved here
i would say the quattro cush f3 was the
pollen donor
and then probably crescendo to millions
of peaches was one cross
and they pollinated that with the
quattro kush now here's a way that they
would have made that more clear
and it would have been obvious and
apparent which the male plant was
a set of parentheses just around two
strain names would indicate
this is one plant so i don't know the
actual breakdown but hypothetically
we've got peach crescendo
uh to millions of peaches to quattro
cush f3 and that's written on two
different papers that's why i'm looking
back and forth
if i wanted to make it clear which was
the male and we're going to just assume
for this project for
for words and uh what we're talking
about right now
that the quattro cush was the male i
would simply put
peach crescendo to millions of peaches
in a parentheses and that would say this
is one plant
and since that one plant is listed first
uh
then the quattro kush listed after that
i would assume the quattro cushes the
male
what this would tell me is it is peach
crescendo
pollinated by millions of peaches that
would go in one parentheses that made
seeds those seeds were grown we found a
keeper
there that is peach crescendo to
millions of peaches in parentheses that
became one plant
i would just give that a name to make
that easier you know what i mean that
would be [ __ ]
so much easier give it a name and then
you don't have to have two different
names x something
i digress ah so in parentheses peach
crescendo to millions of peaches i know
that's a female peach crescendo
pollinated by a male millions of peaches
it made seeds then in this case since
those two are in the parentheses then
there's an
x and there's quattro kush f3 that would
indicate to me
that the quattro kush f3 pollinated
that plant that was in the parentheses
there that is going to be our female
it turns into algebra it looks like a
math problem but it all makes sense once
you start to understand it
it makes clear clear sense i'll try to
put some stuff on the screen
it depends on what i can do with final
cut pro i didn't think that through when
i said it
but i know i'll be able to put some
examples up on the screen because final
cut pro is awesome and i'm getting good
at it so
um an example of a male to female would
just be male plant
or no sorry i [ __ ] that up a fan an
example of a male to female plant would
be listed as female
x male girl plant times male plant makes
baby plant that's that easy right now
what if we take
what if i did not name a rise what if a
rise just didn't get a name
it would be golden goat x daybreaker
in parentheses that's what that plant
would be called because it doesn't have
a name it's a cross
golden goat's a daybreaker now what if
we cross that
to strawberry fields to make the
strawberry starburst it would be golden
goat
x daybreaker and parentheses x
strawberry fields
that would make the uh strawberry
starburst there i'm not sure what i said
cause i'm trying to think all this all
at once but that would make the
strawberry starburst there
so it's all about that parentheses i'm
gonna read more into lemur's
message and make sure i keep myself on
track here he says how is that different
from
okay how is the uh peach og from ethos
how is that different than
uh stromulin from romulan genetics which
is in parentheses
forum cut girl scout cookies x purple
panty dropper
in parentheses cross to romulan so it's
forum
cut girl scout cookies x purple panty
dropper and those two are in parentheses
and then that is listed x romulan which
is a very clear description right there
that tells me that in this first set of
parentheses we've got forum cut girl
scout cookies
crossed to the purple panty dropper if
they listed that correctly if they
followed industry standard
that is a forum cut girl scout cookies
female uh which is clone only so that
would make sense that that's a female
clone only is a whole another [ __ ]
can of worms to open up
we got this forum cut cookies pollinated
by a purple panty dropper that made one
plant
that was grown they found a keeper out
of that plant
in this scenario it was female because
it is listed first
that was pollinated by a male romulan
plant so we've got parentheses starting
parentheses right
forum cut girl scout cookies x purple
panty dropper closing parentheses that's
all in the set of parentheses there
x romulan so you're going to get i'm
going to call it
a purple uh cookie dropper right because
it's
[ __ ] purple panty dropper and girl
scout cookies just name that something
and we can make this a lot easier
purple cookie dropper to romulan and
that's going to be [ __ ]
the klingon or some show we're just
going to call it klingon you see it
happened that quickly we made a strain
we named it we got rid of all the
[ __ ] parentheses
so much easier that way uh the next
example that lemur throws at me
is how about uh how how girl scout
cookie the purple panty dropper wasn't
a named strain that was released and
used in the breeding project not to be
confused
uh yeah you're that's exactly what i was
talking about that plant wasn't named so
it doesn't have a name which makes
everything confusing
here he asked about another one if
you're feeling adventurous there is
snake eyes from motor rebel genetics uh
big shout out to
motor rebel because i wanted to use
snake eyes that's a really great [ __ ]
name i got storm shadow snake eyes would
have been a great accompanying name
good work bro i'm glad you beat me to it
i'm not mad at all it's a [ __ ] good
name i'm proud that i wanted to use a
name and somebody else had already used
it i mean it's a good one anyway
that one is all in parentheses and it
says
gg4 to kosher cush to heroin number one
all in parentheses right there so i
don't know
but i don't know the mail of that one
i'm going to assume it's the gorilla
glue number four to kosher kush was
pollinated by the heroin
number one but again i'm just assuming i
don't know what that breeder did there's
a missing parentheses there that doesn't
do anything
it [ __ ] it all up for me to tell you
the truth and then that was
x to lemon g to lemon thai which is
going to be
a lemon g female which is clone only
pollinated by the lemon thyme male
so uh without the correct parentheses
order there that's just a jumbled
[ __ ] of a mess and i really don't
know
uh what was used i know that it's a gg4
to kosher kush to hairy
female pollinated by a lemon oh g lemon
thyme male but
that gg4 kosher kush harawana cross
couldn't tell you where the mail was
because of the way it is listed i want
to assume
that the heroina was the male because
it's last in that list but
i can't promise anything because this
breeder didn't give me enough
information
um on top of the parentheses you're
going to see brackets occasionally
so we may have parent bracket
parentheses
parentheses and then brackets and then
they're getting creative on how they do
it
when you see it it will be apparent i'll
try to put some of that stuff up on the
screen also just so you can see what i'm
talking about but that's how
instead of using two sets of parentheses
because what if i took we're going to go
even further
the gg4 to kosher kush to hero wanna
cross to the lemon g to lemon tie what
if i crossed that
to the uh forum cut
gsc to purple panty dropper to romulan
now we've got so many things with
parentheses around it
uh i would just put the brackets around
all of that to indicate it's just one
[ __ ] thing or put it on
either side to show you that it's one
big thing this to this to this is
actually just it'll make sense once you
see it on the screen but sometimes
you're going to see brackets in there
that's going to confuse people that is
the next thing people are going to see
so he wraps it up with i think it's a
set of parentheses
i think i think of it as each set of
parentheses as a plan
and inside is what makes it up there are
countless other examples it might be
easier
uh yes your any more examples we're
going to confuse people more but i think
that is the thing
uh that needs to be said inside of each
parentheses
is each plant and you can tell which
plant was broken down
inside of that parentheses and then it's
crossed to the thing that it's got x's
too
i think you guys understand what i'm
trying to say more words on that are
just going to make it
more foggy all right lemur i hope i
answered your question
i hope everybody else out there learned
something from that i hope i didn't just
confuse you more
um without seeing it on a screen without
writing it
this is kind of hard to teach it's like
algebra you gotta [ __ ] follow along
with the visual aids and all that stuff
all at the same time
all right i'm gonna take a quick drink
of some coconut water and then we're
gonna continue with the show
don't think i'm gonna press pause i
don't think i'm gonna edit anything i'm
just gonna make you endure this drink
with me
hydrate yourselves and we will continue
with the show
all right all right all right thanks for
giving me an opportunity to wet my
whistle
let's keep going here this next one is a
nutrient
and feeding question i said a moment ago
we were going to talk about
outdoor feeding and feeding organically
this person is growing indoors
but my advice will still apply let me
start with the message it says
greetings and salutations greetings my
friend thank you for joining me
and thank you for the great message it
says it's been a while since my last
question i hope this finds you in the
entire army
ire army safely and doing wonderfully in
the desire of wanting to become
a seed tester for you down the road i've
been happily and diligently working
toward dialing in my grow room here are
some parameters and then we do go over
quite a few parameters which i will
touch on
uh as i answer the actual question we
don't need to read all of the parameters
uh a lot of the question will lead us
back up there to talk about that so
it says first off i'm trying to be as
organic of a grower as possible that's
admirable i do appreciate and respect
that
it says can you see any flaws or
possible deficiencies
in my soil and liquid selections and can
you make any
suggestions so we've got a good soil we
got nature's living soil we got bud
swell we got recharge
and we've got happy frog i am not
absolutely certain of any of the organic
uh certifications of any of those
products i definitely don't know about
recharge i don't know about happy frog
i think bud swell is organic but i can't
promise you that any of those are are
actually organic products uh look for an
omri listing on the package that's my
advice there
then bud swell i do think that's organic
that's just bottled uh
uh [ __ ] bat guano to the best of my
knowledge
we got elementally green big buds i
don't know what that product is i did
not research that one
then we list two products that concern
me right away terpinator
i don't think i'm going to assume and
we've talked about assuming once in this
episode maybe twice
i'm going to assume that terpinator is
not an organic product it could be
i could be completely [ __ ] wrong but
from what i remember what i see on that
bottle when i'm looking at it through
memory
that's not organic so you might want to
read about that then you've got calmag
as your next liquid uh which cow mag
there are a lot of brands out there a
lot of different products available
some may be organic but it's going to be
hard to find a straight pure liquid
organic calmag solution i think i've
never looked for a purely organic calmag
that could be a challenge so it depends
on the brand make sure you're checking
that omri listing
for organics on your calmag so
the terminator the calmag those are the
things that i would question
everything else you mentioned in here
seems to make sense for your grow
the only thing you're not the only goal
you're not reaching is that a complete
organic desire i don't know that you're
getting that with your list
now i said this on the other uh talk
about the outdoor grow that i saw on
social media
people are asking about what to grow
with outdoors so they can stay
completely organic which bottled
nutrients should they buy what products
should they use
i'm going to repeat what i said about
that uh if you're going to grow
completely organically and you don't
want to do salts and synthetic nutrients
why not just go with the full-on organic
amended soil the way that nature would
have done it go no-till go super soil
go something like that get all of the
things that would go into the dirt
and get a big tarp and put it on the
garage floor
mix up a couple of bags of uh whatever
soil is available right now damn it soil
and dirt are hard to get right now you
guys i've been to the grow store
a couple of grow stores to get products
and soil is low but
get the soilless mix the soil that you
can get and then mix in all of the
proper
amendments nutrients there are a lot of
different ways to mix up a super soil
i make this disclaimer often i do not
claim to be an organic grower i
am not a super soil expert i can tell
you the basics
but there are plenty of websites there
are plenty of things on the internet
that will get you
building a great super soil they don't
pay me to say if they don't sponsor me
uh but buildasoil.com will be a great
start
for building an organic soil and amended
soil so what i would do
i'd skip all the bottles i would skip
all this [ __ ] and i would mix up an
amended super soil
some sort of build a soil some sort of
ready-mixed soil that you could put
those plants in
then all you've got to feed them is
maybe a top dress between
phases maybe like at the end of veg give
them a top dress right at the start of
flower
top dress right as they start to bloom a
specific top dress as they're going
uh if they're getting bigger give them a
specific bloom booster top dress
i'm not the [ __ ] organic guy so i
don't know what to even tell you to top
dress or tea
teas would be a good idea feed them some
teas but if you want to go completely
organically and grow
organics and not have the bottles and
all that stuff and be sure that
everything you're using is organic i
would buy
amendments and mix up a good pre-amended
super soil
it's going to save you it's going to
take time in the beginning you're going
to spend a day mixing it up but
then you don't have to mix up nutrients
every time you water and that's why
to the outdoor growers who are looking
to do something organic outdoors and
want to know what nutrients to use
you're going to be watering every single
day outdoors do you want to spend the
time to mix up
you might water 20 gallons out there do
you want to spend time mixing up 20
gallons of water
worth of nutrients every single day or
do you want to spend one or two days in
the garage mixing up a big fat batch of
super soil
put your plants in that and then just
water the whole cycle because all you've
got to do is keep them wet because
inside that soil is everything that they
need um
some of you organic growers insist that
the herb tastes better gets you higher
so if it's doing that it may be worth
the pre-mix i don't know the difference
honestly i think it all gets me plenty
stone nowadays you guys are all growing
such good weed
but my advice would be to ditch 90
of these products if you've already got
them use them dude don't let me [ __ ] up
your plans your ideas but if you want to
stay as organic as possible
i would abandon ship on all these liquid
products and i would buy powders
boxes of stuff organic stuff when you go
to the grow store when you go to the
gardening store you'll see
all the boxes that you need all the dry
amendments they're all in one area
ah maybe you'll go to build a soil maybe
you'll go to your local grow shop i
recommend you go to like the local
farm area the local farming store if you
can if they're not going to bust you for
growing weed because sometimes
those people know what we're doing and
they may not like the way you look uh so
be careful where you're going but shop
locally if you can is what i'm getting
at give mom and pop the money try not to
give
the big boxes your money try not to give
amazon your money if possible
trust me i order plenty of [ __ ] i shop
where i have to especially during a
pandemic
give me what i need however the [ __ ] i
can get it but
i would get away from the bottle and
stuff if if you really want to be
and you said i'm trying to be as organic
of a grower as
possible bro i would really recommend uh
no-till growing for you i would
recommend
super soil i would recommend some type
of living soil growing for you that's
not
how i do it that's not what i do but
you're saying as organic as possible and
that is how you get as organic as
possible
no-till with a worm bin and [ __ ] a
compost pile
it's really rewarding um i eat a lot of
vegetables and a lot of ends of
vegetables end up in a bokashi bucket
and stuff and to know that i'm making
fertilizer
with my leftover food scraps that's just
rewarding so if you turn that into
cannabis products you're gonna love that
that's a good way to stay as organic as
possible
there are more questions to this one it
says what are some considerations to
have when deciding to grow
a mother plant uh that's a really easy
question it's like falling in love
um if you're in love with that plant
keep it and grow it as a mother plant
i always recommend every time you grow a
cannabis plant take a clone
like before you put a plant into flower
get a clone because what you're growing
could be the most amazing medicine
you've ever grown it could work in your
grow better than everything you've ever
grown it could work for your medicine
could work for your wallet maybe you're
a commercial grower growing for profit
maybe this one plant
works better than everything for you
take a freaking clone of
everything you ever grow then if you
find out that it's the hottest fire
you've got a mother plant that is how
you decide to keep a mother plant if you
fell in love with that
um something that sounds very crass but
this is the absolute [ __ ] truth it's
a lot like the dating pool
uh if you got one option you're gonna
keep that one you're gonna fall in love
you'll be completely [ __ ] happy but
if you got a bunch to choose from
the one that stands out to you will be
the mother plant you want to keep
something will tell you
uh it's just like falling in love with a
person the way i fall in love with
plants is very similar
i see plants plants plants plants oh
look at that plant that's just
the way it happens to me just like it
does with people it's like people people
people damn look at her
like i'm just attracted to specific
things and the plants do it just like
people do
i get similar signals in my body that
say
that plant right there bro that is the
one you want to pick uh
sometimes i'm wrong most of the time i'm
right being a breeder being a
seed selector being a commercial
cultivator i get to see a lot of plants
and i get to make a lot of selections
and i'm getting
pretty damn good at it i think so
considerations to have when deciding
to grow a mother plant is it a good
plant did that plant work well for you
did it meet all of your goals
people ask me what do i pick for a
phenotype what do you want dude
pick the [ __ ] that you want in your
garden did it smell the way you want did
it taste the way you wanted it give you
the buzz you want
did it flower in a timely manner did it
work well for your grow did all the
other plants in the room get powdery
mildew except that one
did all the other plants get hit by
mites except that one did all the other
plants term out except that one
were all the other plants like sevens
but this one's a nine that nine is your
keeper mother plant bro
so as long as it's a good plant as long
as it makes you happy and you want to
grow it again and keep it around
that is a characteristic i look for in a
mother plant you're basically just
preserving genetics to grow it over and
over again
do you love it does it work is it
successful
keep it from other plant then it says
lastly as a grower
how different how difficult is it to
create an autoflower strain
i know autos are not necessarily your
bag but i'm asking about what process
would entail in
general to create autoflower seeds
that's a good question
i am not an autoflower maker so
everything i say right now is kind of
partially coming out of my ass just a
little bit but i know enough about
breeding and i know enough about seeds
that i can cover this i feel like
um to make an autoflower you need an
autoflower you need at least one
autoflower so
ah get a pack of autoflower seeds would
be the way to do that now because
autoflowers you can't clone them they're
gonna flower
that clone is the same age as the
original plant which it came from
they're both gonna flower at the same
time to the best of my understanding
so uh you're gonna have to get a pack of
autoflower seeds i recommend
uh feminized autoflowers if you can get
them i think most of the people making
them are doing fems right now so
get you an autoflower feminized seed
pack then
uh grow them then um
to create an autoflower strain so you
need autoflower to [ __ ] have
autoflower
you need that trait to start with you
can't make uh
orange stuff without some orange so
you're gonna need an autoflower plant in
the mix
ah so get an autoflower plant and then
get a regular plant
and then you need to select most of us
are gonna get
uh feminized autoflowers so you're going
to have to get pollen from
a regular male plant and then pollinate
your autoflowers
those autoflowers are going to make
seeds ah
that is your f1 that's a real f1 you've
got a brand new cross a [ __ ]
autoflower to a photo period
you've just made a really unstable
sloppy [ __ ] crazy
uh really high-end variation f1
find two of those that autoflower you
gotta find a male and a female then
autoflower at this point
the only way you're going to know is to
grow them and they're going to
autoflower
so once you've found the male and female
that meet the criteria you want they've
got the shape and structure
aroma the traits you desire the leaf
shape and whatnot for your goal
they're autoflowering you see them start
to autoflower breed that male to that
female
now you've got f2 um they're not going
to carry that autoflower trait
until we get to about f5 f6
maybe f7 so you're going to have to keep
doing this process
grow the seeds out find a male and a
female to begin to autoflower on you
put them in a room let them pollinate
each other get the seeds out
find grow those seeds and veg find
plants that meet the criteria you're
looking for
plant shape plant structure stem rub
smell
let them start flowering when they get
into flower let that male pollinate that
female
we're probably at what now f2 f3 keep
going until we get to f6 by then
by then they should start coming out
more uniform
more uniform each time another way you
can do it is by reversing that
autoflower but that is a whole another
ball game
we're going to reverse the autoflower
plant it'll make pollen you put that
pollen on another plant
hopefully a female that is autoflowering
that's going to increase your chances of
getting more autoflower
more quickly again i am not an
autoflower breeder
i don't know exactly how many filial
generations it would take to
solidify that autoflower trait i think
by selfing a couple of things you could
probably lock it in
maybe back crossing or something but i
think by going forward in filial
generation and just finding
autoflower trade autoflower trade
autoflower trade that's going to lock it
in
that's probably the best way to do it
all the other trades have to be
secondary at that point that in my
opinion
is why a lot of people find that
autoflowers are inferior
our first trait that we're searching for
most of the time is potency and quality
right we're going for potency
terps then after that we think about uh
problems like is it resistant to bugs
resistant to mildew does it handle the
room well
but most of the time we go for potency
and terps in autoflowers the main thing
the main trait we're looking for is
autoflower
so everything else is secondary in my
opinion take that with a grain of salt
you guys because
like i said i'm not the autoflower guy
all of what i just said
came out my ass all right i tried to
talk the best i could about that
i'm not an expert i feel like i'm
knowledgeable i understand plants i
understand breeding enough to have
advice on that but again
take that with a big stinky grain of
salt all right i feel like i've been
going on for
quite some time this is a long podcast
with uh very little information i do
apologize for that i feel like i talked
a long time and did not teach you enough
thank you again for listening ladies and
gentlemen boys and girls pimps hoes
friends foes smokers growers
clone cutters pawn chuckers
skateboarders fruit booters uh
wind surfers and paris sailors i love
all you folks out there
all the cannabis community thank you
guys for hanging out um if you feel like
this episode was educational informative
and or entertaining uh maybe you'd like
to support the show financially all
you've got to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need is right
there on the screen once again big shout
out to my friend single t
frankie and noah n for the continued
patreon support
don't know what i would do without you
gang gang buzz buzz
shout out to the irie army also if
you've got any questions corrections
comments or concerns i would love to
hear from you
my email address is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com
don't be shy send me your questions send
me your corrections
send me comments concerns uh words of
wisdom
constructive criticism anything you've
got to say don't worry about my ego
don't worry about my feelings i'm ready
let me hear it send that [ __ ]
i gotta check the spam folder now all
right what else do we have the website
uh make sure you check out the website
all things ire genetics all things grow
from your heart
are all on my website at iregenetics.com
check that out make sure you click on
the newsletter tab
you can click on the newsletter tab sign
up for the newsletter you will stay
updated you'll get a
mailchimp newsletter approximately once
a month if you're wondering where the
main newsletter went
i did not send one i didn't have much to
talk about
anything you wanted to talk about i
wanted to tell you about you heard about
here on the show
so uh thank you for the support check
out the website iregenetics.com
also while you're there what else was i
going to tell you about there is the
newsletter the grow help tab that's what
i wanted to talk about there's a grow
help tab if you've got grow questions
click on the grow help tab uh you'll be
asked a few preliminary questions then
from there you'll be free to ask a grow
question i will answer your question on
the air uh please be patient i've got a
lot of questions lined up in front of me
got a big stack of patreon questions and
grow help questions i will get through
them because they do create
great content that is all i've got for
you i've been rambling for a long time
throat's getting dry the add is kicking
in
i want to thank you once again for
hanging out i'll be back in a couple of
days with fresh fresh new content
i want to give a giant shout out to my
friend chiefly420
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you