[Music]
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me ross to jeff
and this is episode 639 of the grow from
your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to focus on
emails before we get to those emails
let's do a few shout outs to a few
members of the 710 club
of course the 710 club are the folks who
support us on patreon
at the 7 and 10 cent a month level or
higher so with no further ado let's
start off with the big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out to my
friend
mister let's send a big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out to a
longtime supporter gramps memo
let's send it thank you to dank groves
and coach steve let's send a big thank
you shout out to stony like bologna
and godfather kush let's send a big grow
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out to mr mean
green eight and seven one six vibes
let's send a big fist bump to blackhawks
fan and just a smokin
i wanna send a big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to my friend
gaiuty grows
then let's wrap it all up with the big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out
to my friend jethro710
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon
if you are not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need will be
right there on the screen and of course
i did include a link
in the show notes and the video
description to make it nice and easy
for all of my friends all right i don't
have a lot of stuff to ramble about at
the start of the show let's jump right
into the email portion of the show
this one came to us from a person named
sam and it says you can use my name that
makes things a lot easier for me
i know i can just say this came from sam
and it says
i'm a relatively new grower thanks to
your podcast
it says i am a disabled veteran with
ptsd and a few years ago
i began discovering that cannabis is an
amazing medicine
and is much healthier of an alternative
to alcohol
uh first of all sam thank you for your
service i do appreciate what you've done
for the country
uh you've got some ptsd i know what
that's like it's probably different ptsd
but it still sucks
so bro thank you for your service and
thank you for the support on the podcast
and i'm glad you're growing now
it goes on to say also i'm glad you're
using cannabis instead of alcohol
i too am a uh i'm an alcoholic i haven't
had alcohol in a long time i'm not
tempted by alcohol i don't desire crave
or need alcohol but
there was a time in my life when alcohol
was a serious crutch
and i was not the best person i could be
i was kind of an [ __ ] to people
around me i was very irresponsible
wasn't responsible with my uh my words
my actions my health
my physical or mental well-being were
not important to me i've come a long way
since then and life is much better
without that poison in me
i understand the struggle it was uh
wasn't the easiest thing to quit i had
to get rid of friends and lifestyle
changes and [ __ ]
this is not the quit drinking alcohol
podcast i want to sympathize with you
and say that i know
how that feels and i'm really grateful
you've joined us on team cannabis and
we've gotten away from team alcohol
shout out to team cannabis
all right it keeps going uh i live in a
cannabis
unfriendly state so i can't afford to
continue purchasing
free market cannabis after researching
for almost a year and finally getting my
courage
i planted my first seeds allegedly in
the winter of 2018. bro congratulations
i'm glad you've stepped up and taken
responsibility for your own medicine
needs
it says i've used your podcast
extensively to do my research and i've
learned a great deal from it
thank you that means a lot to me it says
thank you so much for putting
it out there it's going it's uh it's a
given uh receive it's a full exchange is
what i'm saying here it's a give and
take
and i appreciate it since i still listen
regularly
regularly and i have some and i have
since made grow friends in my state
through your podcast
and the discord server big shout out to
all of my friends on the discord server
for helping out new friends old friends
making new friends connecting the
community
that is a cool place over there check
out the discord server there is a link
in the video description i'm going to
keep going
it says cannabis as a medicine is a very
well-known topic but i also wanted to
mention the therapeutic aspects
of the cannabis growing process i
completely agree with this i want to
keep reading but
i already want to say i fully agree with
that it says my garden has become
a haven for me that i use to manage my
stress and anxiety
it gives me something to research and
learn about when i'm feeling lost in the
world
and it helps me to know that i'm part of
a whole community of other home growers
out there
that many of them are veterans as well
and i have come as
i have come to learn yes i love that
whole statement
uh the garden should be your haven your
safe space
your moment of zen um
i was deeply immersed in the commercial
cannabis industry
since covid happened i have basically
backed out of all
of my commercial cannabis uh contracts
i'm not working with any facilities
right now
i don't go to any big places and you
know what i've never been more in love
with growing cannabis
my personal garden has not looked this
good in a long time
i was focused on a cannabis business i
was focused on production
schedules numbers weights potency
reports i was forgetting the thing that
i preach all the time
grow from your heart i was still doing
that but that was like seventh or eighth
on the list
it should be number one our friend sam
here is growing from his heart
because this plant this grow room is his
zen
it's his new playground it's the place
to go it's the library
it is the place where he could just go
and be himself i feel like when i go in
my garden
i put ear buds in and whatever i'm
listening to that's what i got in my
ears
i turn off the phone i got the phone on
case the daughter but i don't look
like if my daughter calls i'll answer
her she's about the only one i'm going
to answer in the garden
kids are important everybody else they
can wait i'm in the grow that is my
moment
of zen that is my time those plants need
my attention
that garden is relying on me and it's
just it feels so good it's my quiet
space
it smells good uh it's beautiful in
there if it's a snowy day outside it's
[ __ ] nice in the garden if it's a hot
day outside
beautiful in the garden it's always
about 78
79 degrees in there it's always just the
right humidity in there just depending
on what phase we're in
depending on which room i'm in but it's
never too extreme in the garden it's
beautiful in there
and i've got my earbuds in i either got
joey diaz yelling at me or chris
distefano telling me a dirty joke or
fish blaring in my ear
sometimes it's just dead silent in there
and it is beautiful
nobody can mess with me nobody can give
me any problems and then
the other thing i talk about and think
about is don't think about bills
don't think about problems if you've
been arguing with somebody if you
[ __ ] had a fight in traffic if your
neighbor's been being a dick if there's
something on your mind
don't carry that into the grow room with
you because you're going to put that on
the plants and they're going to be
stressed out too
so when i go in there i make it a point
to just close the door behind me and all
the [ __ ] out there
all the stuff out here in reality in
babylon gets left out here
everything in my grow is good vibes jot
love we don't think about that stuff
i'm not growing from my wallet i'm not
growing from my ego
i'm not growing for instagram i'll share
it with instagram
i'll put some money in my wallet after i
grow but that wasn't the intention the
intention is to
see this beautiful plant this amazing
product go from
point zero to point harvested dried
cured
and then either i get to consume it or
one of my friends gets to consume it or
a medical cannabis
consumer gets to consume it which is all
of us we're all medical cannabis
patients
one of us gets to consume that and we're
going to feel better
most of the time i feel good but when i
smoke i feel even
better and then when i don't feel good
and i smoke then i can feel
good and then even better so this plan
is very therapeutic it should be
uh it shouldn't be thought of as a
commodity as a product it should be
working
all the way from the beginning to the
end it should be building you up and
making you feel good don't let it get
stressful that's part of why i walked
away from the
large-scale commercial industry i could
go back i could do that but
i'm at a point where it was getting more
stressful than it was feeling rewarding
and just having my personal grow my
personal business
it's really there's more passion in it i
enjoy it i'm back to growing from my
heart
every plant i touch is growing with full
love because i could touch every plant
now
i can address every plant i don't have
to tell somebody go water those i'll
water these we'll hope they all get
watered by the end of the day
there's no stress i'm back to growing
pure with love from my heart
it's all about the love and enjoyment
now which i think will make all the
products better as well
so i want to get back into this um don't
think about your money don't think about
your wallet
don't think about how chicks are gonna
like you because you got weed don't
think about the drum set or the guitar
or the sneakers or the car you're gonna
buy
the video games you're gonna buy when
you sell that product don't think about
that stuff think about
it's like a meditation you start off
with the seed that doesn't have
it's got life in this little ball and
you brought it all the way to fruition
you get to harvest it and smoke it
that's weeks and weeks of nurturing and
meditation and growing you get to spend
with that plant
then while you're doing that you're also
meeting this whole group of people that
we've talked about the cannabis
community
you think well i wonder if my plants are
doing okay so you go to the internet
just compare your plants to others or to
get advice
and then you find this guy rasta jeff
and then you realize he's approachable i
can make friends with him and then you
realize
he's got a whole group of people that
hang out with them and made him a
discord server and you can chat with
everybody in there and so then not only
do you have these plants that are
uh zen meditative therapeutic and then
rewarding but then you make friends in a
community that
are also therapeutic rewarding having
friends is very rewarding we're social
creatures at least i am i can't shut the
[ __ ] up and i love having friends
so it does build a great thing being in
the garden the cannabis plant the
cannabis community is amazing you guys
already knew that i'm rambling
but this message meant a lot to me we
kind of get far from the point here
uh sometimes we forget our roots forget
our goals i wanted to go back and remind
myself and you guys that um we're
growing medicine
to nourish ourselves our bodies our
minds our spirits however you're taking
it i get all three from it
my body feels better when i smoke my
mind feels better and of course i use it
at rastafari i use it for meditation use
it for enjoyment
mind body spirit everything is feeling
better from consuming cannabis
we've got to remember to grow from our
hearts and not let
this plant be a commodity be a profit be
a product
i understand we have commercial
facilities and it is but go back to your
roots fall in love with this plant again
like i have i never lost my love but i
mean
now that i've given up the commercial
thing i've got more time to really love
these plants again i'm not thinking
about
time clocks and employees and schedules
and [ __ ] deliveries and manifests and
[ __ ] metric numbers and i don't mean
like the metric system i mean metric the
marijuana enforcement tracking and
regulation
something that we use here in colorado
and many other states it's one of the
worst
damn programs ever designed and it makes
people want to punch themselves in the
face repeatedly over and over all day
and i don't have to mess with that
because i'm not in the commercial
environment
more time to love the plants sam you got
me rambling bro thank you
there is more to this message excuse me
for that kombucha burp i hope the
microphone didn't pick it up not even
going to edit because i'm human
it goes on it says there are times when
my mental state is in the dumps
and the only thing i look forward to is
trimming or watering or making edibles
uh yeah that is a lot of why i quit
consuming alcohol i was trying to grow
and also drinking and i would go out and
get
shitty drunk and you forget that night
that you got [ __ ] to do in the morning
right and you get shitty drunk and you
wake up and you go throw up and you
think
i'm gonna poop some blood and go back to
sleep but then you realize [ __ ] i got a
garden to go take care of and you gotta
go play in the grow room hungover
no thank you bro i would much rather
grow cannabis sober
not hungover no let's get in there i
mean i said sober but trust me there are
dabs and blunts and joints and bone rips
all those things are happening that's
all acceptable but i'm not getting drunk
anymore
i can't be in a grow room drunk be under
grow lights hungover
no effing thank you so yeah that
contributed a lot to me being a
non-alcohol consumer
and you're right having those beautiful
plants in there to wake up to it's like
having pets
that aren't going to [ __ ] on the floor
and run away it really is
my plants have never [ __ ] on the floor
uh i've had plenty of dog [ __ ] right on
the floor
so yes when the mental state is in the
dumps sometimes knowing that those
plants relying on me
really does help me out and i seem like
an upbeat positive happy-go-lucky dude
i've got a traumatic brain injury that
sometimes
uh there are some dark dumpy days for me
and you're right being in the garden for
a couple of hours
i'll go in there thinking i [ __ ] hate
the world i don't want to talk to
anybody and then i'll come out being
like i'm going to call some friends and
hang out because life is good
the garden is very therapeutic spending
time with all that living stuff in there
it is very therapeutic but don't don't
forget to get some real nature sometimes
as well
um there's more to this i didn't realize
when i started growing that it would be
a tool for me in so many ways it is
such a tool in so many ways the thing
you didn't mention that i think you'll
discover
next uh and your growing adventure is
that now that you're taking good care of
these plants and feeding the plants
carefully the next thing
that will fall in line is you'll start
taking better care of yourself
physically health-wise what you consume
what you eat
you'll start thinking about the products
you eat better but not only
the things you eat but where they came
from how they were made how they were
sourced
you'll start it'll just be you'll get
more aware you're going to get woke
because you're growing weed
and it's going to help you out it's
going to be good for you you're already
getting a
mental boost from this which is giving
you a spiritual boost from this the next
thing you're going to get
is a physical learning lesson you're
going to realize why do i spend
so much time measuring precise
millimeters
milliliters for products to feed my
plants but when it comes time for my
dinner i slap [ __ ] butter
and [ __ ] cheese a bunch of [ __ ] in a
pan and eat it like i'm [ __ ] gonna
live through anything
you'll start thinking well maybe if i
give myself the appropriate [ __ ] maybe
i'll thrive like my plants do and it'll
all click in you one day and you'll go
huh that's why i felt like [ __ ]
because i was just eating [ __ ] all
the wrong [ __ ] so that's the next thing
you're gonna realize i think
when it comes to your cannabis adventure
i know this is a really
off topic kind of a message but you guys
i really feel this is the way it goes
you start learning about cannabis
you get that connection and then you say
i'm feeding my plants i should feed
myself i see it happen
especially in commercial growers because
they're in the grow all day bust and ass
they got to work harder
they got to eat more and they see it
they just see the thing also i'm in
there talking about how i eat well and
maybe that inspires them but
that's your next move dude uh it's been
great for your mental health
um my therapist and i have even
discovered that oftentimes when i'm
lacking
and caring for my mental health i'm
lacking and taking care of my grow
area as well isn't that how it's a
reflection
the way you do something is the way you
do everything and when that
mental state starts going [ __ ]
haywire the garden starts showing it
it really reflects the whole life starts
looking like it's unraveled and then you
go
ah everything's out of control i got to
get my [ __ ] together you go clean up the
garden start cleaning up your life and
then guess what you start having better
conversations your mind is more open
you're more free
i start actually wanting to go places
because your brain feels good you want
to be around people
it will spark that for you i agree
completely
so my grow area has become sort of a
metaphor
in my life that i can use for measuring
as a measuring stick for taking care of
myself yes my friend if that garden
starts getting out of control
you gotta reach out to a friend and say
hey why am i doing this or maybe just
reach inside of yourself and say what am
i lacking what am i [ __ ] up on why am
i hating the world why am i hiding why
am i being a recluse again
get it going maybe call a friend maybe
not i don't know maybe do your thing
maybe sometimes calling a friend isn't
the best thing to do when you're in the
dumps maybe just drag them down too but
you know how to get yourself out of it
go in that grow
take care of business and feel the pride
of the grow then smoke a fat one
he wraps it up with all of that to say
learning how to grow from your podcast
has been a life-changing experience for
me
and i can't thank you enough sam this
message was life-changing to me i get
messages like this frequently i get a
lot of messages but they never
stop warming my heart they never stop
filling me with pride
they never stop making me feel good
about what i do
um knowing that i'm helping you out with
your ptsd knowing that
we not just me you my guidance my advice
has led you to help yourself
with your ptsd and get your mental
health on track so thank you bro
this sort of stuff is like grow
nutrients for me you just gave me a
bloom booster you just gave me some
recharge
keep me going for a few more episodes
thank you bro i appreciate that
and again if you're ever in the dumps
bro and you need somebody to talk to i'm
a busy guy
i've got a lot of [ __ ] going on but if
you ever messaged and said i'm having a
[ __ ] dark day and need a friend
i'll bring you some [ __ ] sunshine bro
never fear don't be shy
and that goes to just about everybody
out there if you tell me i'm having a
dark day and shit's weird
we'll hang out for a minute don't worry
all right i've got a lot more messages
in front of me
been going for a long time i want to
make sure to cover as much as i can in
this episode
this is a great one this one comes from
my friend zachary you what up zachary
thank you for the great message this one
goes i've got a great question for you
do you grow your competitor's seeds for
either quality control standards
calling [ __ ] or just plain fun
that's a great question
the short answer is yeah bro i love to
grow my competitors seeds but the thing
is
i'm not going to call them competitors
let's call them
colleagues my friends my breeding bros
i don't find them to be competition we
all have businesses we all want to sell
seeds we all want to
[ __ ] make sales and do business but
that's not what it's all about
if a client or a customer came to me and
they said
hey i want this strain they list off a
few details
and that strain is not in my menu which
it probably is because i have a vast
menu with a lot of things and i know it
pretty well but if you say i want
something
and i don't have it i'll recommend
something from another breeder because
that is my job as a responsible grower
as a responsible community leader just
as a [ __ ] polite person
um and people have seen me do it and
they've been like bro that person would
have bought seeds from you and i could
be like yeah they would have bought
seeds but
they would not have gotten what they
wanted they would have wasted their
money and at harvest time they would
have been like man [ __ ] that guy he sold
me the wrong [ __ ]
instead they went and got the seeds they
wanted from one of my friends who's not
a competitor they're a colleague we're
all in the same gang
we're all in team cannabis they went got
the seeds they wanted from somebody they
grew them
and now they made two friends they said
damn these seeds are [ __ ] cool
and i'm glad that guy rosta jeff
recommended me though he could have
taken my hundred bucks and [ __ ] me and
just gave me something but instead
he said go over there and visit duke
diamond or go visit ethos or miss jill
because they've got what you're asking
for and he doesn't
i find that to be the way to operate
they're not my competitors they are my
friends we message each other on social
media
we talk we see each other at all of the
events we travel
we're all doing the same thing we live
and learn with each other
there are weird rivalries and some
people don't talk to each other and
i'd rather just not be friends with some
people but i don't got no bickering no
hate or no
nothing like that i don't talk [ __ ]
about anybody i don't have hatred for
any other breeder out there
if they don't like me that's cool that's
on them i'm down to be cool all the beef
is over in my opinion i'm [ __ ] too
old for that dumpster it's not high
school is what i think i'm getting at
uh i'm done with all the breeders they
got nothing but love and respect coming
from me
so uh i do grow out their stuff because
we're all what like that's where seeds
come from if i keep growing all of my
stuff i'm just going to be growing my
stuff
so i've got to introduce other things
into the garden or i bottleneck my
breeding so
where else is other stuff going to come
from other breeders so yeah i do breed
and grow and test run other breeders
stuff
sometimes i'm amazed sometimes i'm
[ __ ] amazed
sometimes i'm amazed i'm like i paid
money for this [ __ ] and other people are
paying money for this [ __ ] and there's
not a [ __ ]
whole threat of hate speech on the
[ __ ] internet about this person after
paying good money for these seeds
i don't go and bash anybody i don't talk
that [ __ ] that's not my place
if i were to say that [ __ ] anything i
say if i were to say that
seed company and i don't want to make up
numbers because there's probably a seed
company called that right now
if [ __ ] macbook seed company sold me
seeds and they sucked
it wouldn't do me any good to go online
and say macbook seed company sold me
herms
that just looks like i'm trying to big
up my company so there's no need to bash
it
uh i just don't talk about it when i do
get a keeper when i do get a champion
i'm not afraid to share that with you
recently i grew the
jack the ripper seeds i got some jack
the ripper seeds i shot it to sub cool
shout out to all of the
team tga team green avengers i shout out
to the people keeping the name alive
um but i grew some subcool stuff because
subcool
was one of my heroes like uh it's weird
as a 40 year old guy to talk about your
heroes but without sub cool and tga
genetics i wouldn't be irie genetics
roster jeff would just be
some random [ __ ] basement grower who
knows i'd be a musician probably you
would have never heard of me
i'd be a struggling ass musician or a
fake comedian i'd be a stand-up comic
that's what i would do
but without sub cool and tga i wouldn't
be here
so when subcool passed away rest in
peace subby big respect nothing but love
but when sub passed away
it was my duty to make some crosses in
honor of subcool so i bought the uh
i didn't buy i was given honestly i was
gifted some jack the ripper seeds from a
member of tga shout out to the person
who gave those to me
uh they don't need any controversy so i
won't say their name we don't need to
start all the emails but
i got some tga seeds from a friend i
grew them i found my keepers and i bred
to them so
that's a prime example of growing uh
people would consider tga a competitor
but that was a friend a colleague a
partner
um a teammate we're all on team cannabis
we're all
on legalization we're all in the green
team um
we want it we all want the same for the
customer the client the community
we want you guys to get a successful
seed grow a successful plant have a
happy harvest a successful outcome
so i don't find it um and i know you're
asking if i grow out competitor seeds
and i'm focusing more on the word
competitors
uh mr soul said at one time like we're
all musicians
and we're all in different bands and
maybe uh you like reggae maybe you like
country music maybe you like [ __ ] pop
hits from the 80s maybe you're into
[ __ ] norwegian death metal there's a
breeder out there that offers
something for you that you're into and
every breeder
just develops their own following they
get their own click their own niche
their own certain type of people and
it's all about the vibe that they
present so
um yeah i do love to grow other seeds
from other breeders
um not for calling [ __ ] or qc
standards just
because i like to grow cannabis i want
to see like what they've got to offer i
see
a breeder say hey i've got this coming
out and i'm like oh i've been watching
you and i know those two parents i'm
kind of curious what that's going to do
i'll buy a pack and run it just for fun
just to see what it does
sometimes i'll buy a pack and give it to
a friend and let them run it just to see
what it does because i'm that kind of
guy
i'm very curious i'm passionately
curious especially when it comes to
cannabis but also
i don't have a bunch of room so if i've
got a friend with some open space
you know who you are bro shout out for
running seedlings for me and finding us
some keepers
i just throw seedlings to other people
and they run [ __ ] for me to find us
stuff and then i go visit and check out
what they've got
and i help them pick keepers and
sometimes we disagree which means i get
one keeper they get the other cut a
clone
i take one home they get another we both
got what we wanted but we got two
different plants i got more breeding
stock they got growing stock
i'm rambling on that part but yeah bro i
love growing
other seed breeders stuff that's how i
find stuff for breeding
i'm growing the chem daily chem right
now which is chem d to i-95
from uh [ __ ] geez uh that one's from
jj from top dog right yeah
geez i almost forgot who that [ __ ] was
from i apologize for that i got so many
seeds i [ __ ] get lost
but i'm growing that one right now it
came from seed and it is fire that's a
breeder that's a keeper it's been bred
to
so that's where that came from just
about everything i've got came from a
seed eventually all plants came from a
seed
so the platinum tangy that i grow that
was a seed from garden of weeden
they somebody else found that but i mean
that came from garden of weed and the
strawberry starburst star the strawberry
fields i used to make strawberry
starburst
was a seed that started off as a
crockett seed i acquired the clone at a
commercial grow
but in the long run they are all seeds
so they all started from a seed
i'm rambling like a [ __ ] on that
answer now the answer is
yes bro i do grow other people's seeds i
love doing it
i like to compare i like to start my
seeds and their seeds at the same time
compare germ rates compare growth rates
just see what's going on
there are a lot of reasons to do it but
mainly because it's fun and that's how i
get some new [ __ ] to breed with
all right this is going to be a quick
thursday episode this next email i've
got is going to take way too long for
this show so i'm going to start wrapping
it up here
i want to thank you guys for listening
to episode 639 of the grow from your
heart podcast
i've got some cool stuff planned coming
up in a couple of episodes i don't want
to make any
i don't want my big mouth to write any
checks my skinny ass can't cash
cash you know what i'm saying but i got
some good [ __ ]
planned for you i hope i can pull it off
i'm excited to get it going
so i'm going to wrap this one up quickly
i can start working on that next episode
get some ideas
some notes going i may have to move a
camera i may have to use a different
microphone i've got some fun ideas you
guys are going to enjoy
i've already said too much
um if you feel like this episode was
educational informative and or
entertaining
maybe you'd like to support the show
financially all you've got to do is
visit www.patreon.com forward slash grow
from your heart
all of the information you need to
support the show is right there on the
screen
i want to give a big thanks to my buddy
dave's not here for all of the continued
patreon support also if you feel like oh
wait
where else was i going questions
corrections comments or concerns that's
what i wanted to say
if you've got questions corrections
comments or concerns i would love to
hear from you
my email address is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com don't be shy
send me some messages i love all of the
support also don't forget about the
website
iriegenetics.com all things ire genetics
all things grow from your heart
everything ross to jeff has posted
at iregenetics.com i really fell apart
at the end of this episode you guys
thanks for uh hanging out i'll be back
in a couple of days with fresh new
content
i want to thank everybody for listening
to another episode i owe a big giant
shout out to my friend girlsgrow2
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you