[Music]
yeah welcome back podcast world
i'm your host my friends call me rasta
jeff and this is episode 642
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to recap an event
i recently attended
then i want to talk a little bit about
storing our seeds before we get there
let's do a few shout outs to a few of
the kind folks who support the show on
patreon
let's start off with the big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to my friend nicholas a let's send a big
thank you shout out to canna reaper and
frugal rock
let's send a thank you shout out to
crazy hand grows and rivan waters
let's send a big fist bump to thomas
mcginnis and lefty's farm
i want to send a thank you shout out to
the big sexy dank and the bafsta
let's send a thank you shout out to pack
northwest den and stash drop
and then let's wrap up the shout outs
with a big thank you shout out to my
friend
the new old guy big thanks and big shout
out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon
if you are not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need is right
there on the screen and of course there
is a link in the show notes and the
video description
to make it super easy for all of my
friends
once again really thank you for all of
the continued patreon
support also thank you everybody for the
uh feedback from the last two episodes
the last two episodes were very
uh very video intensive i pulled some
plants out of the garden
i put gloves on and went hands-on with
the plants uh cut some plants up in one
episode we did some popping and twisting
and another episode
i cut some clones showed you guys how to
get those clones all the way
to uh and their cubs and their starting
homes uh thank you for all of the
feedback
i got a lot of feedback those are two of
my most watched videos already
uh most commented on videos most praised
videos
thank you i do appreciate that if you
were listening to this show on an audio
service
uh i do highly recommend that you go
check out the past two episodes on the
youtube channel please go subscribe
to the youtube channel even if you're
not gonna watch just go subscribe search
for the grow from your heart podcast
click subscribe
do me some favors give me some
subscriptions i do appreciate that
where do we go from there ah thank you
guys i do appreciate that
uh all the comments all the feedback
that is wonderful let's move right into
talking about oh i want to mention one
thing
a lot of the audio podcast services have
been messed up
um long story short my website got
messed up you don't care about the
details
uh a service provider changed a thing it
messed up all of my things things got
weird
my web guy is working diligently to
solve the problems
we don't know that there is a problem
until somebody tells us i didn't know
that the show wasn't on stitcher google
podcast spotify
uh it wasn't showing up in a lot of
places we were working to correct that
uh it should be corrected by the time
this episode comes out the thing is
every time we correct one thing we find
that something else is
messed up so we're playing the fix the
internet game i do apologize if you've
missed episodes i did not mean to
abandon you i didn't ditch you
i am struggling just like you just like
you want to listen to the shows i want
them to be available
trust me uh sponsors pay for it patreon
uh relies on the shows coming out
i do want the shows to come out on time
if the show is not on the service which
you are used to
i recommend checking youtube youtube
seems to be fairly reliable most of the
time
i put the shows up it is uh 12 o'clock
sunday night into monday morning and
then again 12 o'clock wednesday into
thursday morning
i do premieres on youtube i actually
hang out and watch the video with you
guys hang out in the chat
talk [ __ ] in the chat room uh join us
for that so if you're missing something
please do find us on youtube however i'm
just realizing that if you're not
finding the show
you're not even gonna get the message
it's like calling somebody who left
their phone at your house hey bro your
phone's at my house
the phone is just ringing on my table
all right let's move forward into
something
useful in this podcast i recently
attended a great event
i attended the groovy gravy secret stash
seed exchange event in denver colorado
that was a beautiful event we had a
great time
i was a low-key event it was kind of
low-key i would guess there were
somewhere between three and 500 people
at the whole event
uh which was not bad that was great for
um
i was kind of calling it a practice run
like getting back into the environment
re-entry
i haven't been to an event to a concert
to a comedy show
uh any big sort of gathering since uh
march 12th or 13th i was at the last
comedy show that was at the comedy works
downtown in denver uh the last show was
bobby lee they haven't had a big show
in that building since then they have
now by the time you hear this uh some
socially distant shows but
uh there haven't been any big shows
events uh anything like that for me to
go to
so it was exciting to get out this was
just a small event
most of the time i take two or three
people to a big event to help me out
this time it was mike and myself big
shout out to mike for helping me
kind of a small event but that was
perfect that's what i'm getting at i
needed a small event for re-entry to
learn how to deal with people again
how to be at an event environment it's
been so long that i kind of forgot
uh once we got there we totally fell
right into the rhythm though it was just
just like old times the drive up was
super smooth
uh it's about a three hour drive from
where mike and i were
uh to actually get to the event pretty
uneventful drive
we had a good talk on the way up there
mike and i just have really good
conversation probably should have
recorded that you guys would have
appreciated that
uh drive up was smooth parking and
loading were super smooth there was a
dedicated parking spot for
us uh not a spot but a parking lot the
lot was
plenty of spots for us we can get in
there and get a good clean parking space
i actually
uh dropped a mic off right in front of
the event with all of our merchandise
drove over parked
walked back not a big deal short walk to
get right to the event
getting in was cool setting up was cool
the flow of the event was super smooth
um um so let's talk about how the event
happened we got set up
and then about 20 minutes before the
doors were going to open we were told
hey the vips are going to be allowed to
enter in just a few minutes if you need
to do anything now's your chance
so mike got a drink and a snack i've
used the men's room we just got
ourselves organized and then the vips
were allowed in
vips were allowed i think to hang out
all day if you bought a vip ticket for
this event you were included all day
however after the vips there were time
slots
um the time slots went from noon to one
and then you were allowed to come in the
building with your wristband or with
your ticket you were allowed entry from
noon to one
to shop at the booths then when your
time slot was almost up they would run
around and there were a couple of guys
just politely saying hey there's about
10 minutes left in your time slot
please wrap up your shopping and then
head outside when you're done once you
got done you could go outside
and there were other booths outside i
honestly didn't make it out there there
were food trucks
um there were a lot of people on a dj
out there i heard i
honestly didn't make it there was a
massage booth out there that people were
coming back in and
saying man that massage was [ __ ]
great so shout out to the massage lady
um but so you would come in you'd get an
hour to shop and they would politely
uh remind you that your time is up and
you'd be escorted out to that back area
which was outside
once you were outside you could hang out
and socialize and hang out and uh i
don't know if there was consumption
happening out there i almost said you
could consume
don't want to snitch on anybody if that
was not allowed allegedly maybe people
were smoking out there so you were
allowed
one hour to shop which was kind of cool
there were about 10 booths um
i'm gonna say 10 to 12-ish boots i
didn't do a real
solid head count obviously they're about
10 or 12 booths most of those booths
were breeders
right in my uh little section where my
booth was set up
it was oni seeds in the corner and then
myself
and then another group that was a seed
seller
of they were a retailer so they had a
lot of other breeders they had a lot of
they had kalax seed company they had
some of my seeds
uh they just had seeds from a bunch of
other vendors or other breeders over
there and they were a reseller vending
other seeds which is cool nothing wrong
with that
there was also right across from me
looking straight at their booth all day
was uh top dog so big shout out to jj
and top dog also shout out to oni
shout out to my booth neighbors to the
right i cannot remember their name i had
it written down on paper didn't bring
that paper with me
um also down the row was
capulator capulator seeds and i think
it's rocky mountain high that he rolls
with that crew was down the way
there were a few other great booths also
uh tiki
uh ti i can't see i wrote it down i left
that paper in another room
tiki something tiki madness tinky maniac
something like that
uh they seemed cool good people they had
a lot of traffic at their booth
i think crop kings new invention by the
way let's mention that
crop king has changed their name you
guys if you uh uh if you know about the
if you know about crop king beware
they've also changed their name to
rocket seeds rocket seeds is also crop
king seeds i do not
work with them i do not support them i
do not endorse them if they are claiming
to have my seeds
that is fraudulent be careful where
you're buying your seeds from that's all
i need to say about that but
crop king is also now rocket seeds so
buyer beware
um i think they were there they had a
booth i didn't realize who that was
until later on
uh when i realized they changed their
names but it was kind of cool it was a
cool setup event so people got to come
in
they got an hour to shop and then they
got moved out uh to the outside area
it wasn't rude they knew that they got
an hour so there was from noon to one
got to shop
and then from 1 to 130 it was basically
just vips in the building and the vips
have already been to my booth a couple
of times they've shopped they've chatted
they've gotten their fist bumps so when
that 30-minute break between
uh groups between waves that would give
us time to just regroup i could take a
drink of water reorganize my booth
check my phone use the restroom if i
needed to go get a bagel if i wanted one
because they had bagels there for us
go get a coffee if we wanted one just
whatever you need you can get like a
good 20 or 30 minute break and that's
kind of cool
because when i go to an event i am the
mickey mouse of my brand i know that i'm
my face is on the package
people don't come there no offense mike
nobody came there to talk to mike some
people do but
90 of the people that come to my booth
want to talk to me and that's
understandable
so i don't get to leave the booth very
often but when you got a minute break
there in the middle you know that i can
just go use the restroom and no one's
going to come up to the booth and be
disappointed
that they didn't get to meet roster jeff
because they really do try to meet
everybody
try to shake everybody's hands if you
want a selfie a high five a picture
if you want me to autograph some [ __ ]
i'll do it because i understand without
uh the people that support me i wouldn't
be supported
so i'm grateful and thankful and i like
to uh
oblige and be cordial to the people who
have supported me uh i'm
successful because of those people but
they're successful with their grows
because of what we're giving each other
so it works out
um i really like that flow it's a great
time it was really good i keep rambling
about this event because i was excited
it was good just to be at an event
uh standing at my booth is just a good
feeling got the
irie genetics flag behind me i got the
banner at the table that says the
website it has my face on it we got
shirts hung up
people are coming up and telling us uh
how good of a job we do with the seeds
and how good of a job we do with the
podcast
somebody told me that they've been
growing for several years uh like maybe
eight or ten years i think they said and
then they discovered
the podcast two years ago and they said
that their crop has never been better
they're putting out a better product
better weights they're way more
successful
and they're having more fun and spending
less time doing it
i told them i said honestly bro that
statement
means more to me than all of the sales
i've made today because i
we sold some seeds we i'm not gonna lie
we sold some seeds at that event we did
okay
but the compliments from the community
the people letting me know
that this podcast is making your garden
more fruitful more successful and also
saving you time in there
but making it more enjoyable uh knowing
that you're enjoying the garden and
being successful because i sit here for
a couple hours a day and put together a
podcast
that makes it all worth it that fills me
up inside uh
it's like recharge for my soul uh it's
like big plant nutrients it's like a big
hps light for my soul it just lights me
up and grows me up you guys i do
appreciate it
so ah thank you to everybody who
gave me compliments on the podcast and
then lots of compliments on the seeds
people like bro i've had
better luck germinating your seeds than
any other brand i've had more vigorous
plants more potent plants more
uh heavy harvest than any other brand ah
that stuff means a lot to me thank you
guys so shout out to everybody
who came up and gave me feedback then
also some people were like had
a negative experience or you said
something on the show i didn't like
thank you ah that stuff matters to me
and i get to make corrections and
adjustments because of that so thank you
for that criticism and feedback as well
uh big thanks to everybody who came out
to the
uh groovy gravy secret stash seed event
that was a great time
uh i had a ton of fun i want to give
uh everybody that gave me a gift or a
present thank you you guys know who you
are
i didn't bring them all to the table
because i got a lot of great gifts thank
you guys shout out to jj for the pack of
seeds he gave me i'm looking at that at
another table i didn't bring that over
here
uh but i want to say a shout out to
wolfie wolf bro you threw up an amazing
event you looked stressed as [ __ ] when i
got there
by the end of the event you looked like
a man who would accomplished something
i saw the look on your face of like man
we did this and you did it bro it was
successful
uh shout out to microbelife hydro for
letting us
have an event in their warehouse that
was super cool as well
uh then big shout out to mike um i was
talking a moment ago how cool it was to
be at my booth
and just standing at the booth and
people coming up uh
being at the booth and standing there
doing business and then looking over
and my [ __ ] best friend that's been
hanging out and been my
right-hand man for since [ __ ] 2008
just looking over and seeing him nodding
his head in success
he's like we did it buddy i was like we
[ __ ] did it buddy uh just
being there with my bro uh that meant a
lot to me i don't know if he knows how
much that meant to me he was my first
choice when i needed booth help
uh he nailed it he was up early he was
on time he pulled his weight
and then some and he was [ __ ] a good
road dog too it was a long drive home
you guys that drive home was [ __ ]
exhausting
uh might have been a little rainstorm on
the way home but mike kept me awake mike
kept me [ __ ] talking
uh we had a good dinner so shout out to
my boy mike uh mike come on the show bro
i know you got the kiddos
things are chaotic in mike's world we're
not going to talk too much about his
private life but
uh he's doing some construction at home
some unexpected construction so he's
busy his back is being put to the test
but mike i appreciate you bro big shout
out for all the help at the event
uh bros for life bro fist bump um then
big shout out to uh my friend neil
my friend neil gave me some lemon
jeffrey
live rosin and he also gave me some
great compliments on the podcast
a lot of times i bash rosin i'm really
not a huge fan of most
rosin and most of you guys are gonna say
well you're not smoking the right rosin
or they're not doing it right i know i
know
and most you guys say that you give me
rosin it tastes like [ __ ] also
i think a lot of the times it tastes
like a popsicle stick or burnt popcorn
let's recap and head back to my buddy
neil he gave me this lemon jeffrey live
rosin
apparently i liked it because look at
the jar it is empty it is
zero it is finito fin the end throw it
away
i kept it because it still smells
amazing and this was my reminder to talk
about it on the show
this lemon jeffrey live rosin was
tremendous it didn't have the negative
flavors the negative things i usually
experience when i'm smoking rosin
this was delicious i uh if i had paid
money i didn't this was a gift if i had
paid money for this
i would go back and buy more that's how
much i enjoyed that so neil if you're
listening
bro ah had a great time talking to you i
feel like we made friends you don't do
social media which blows my [ __ ] mind
um send me a message bro because you're
getting a big shout out on the show
your concentrate was amazing lemon
jeffrey is quite possibly one of my top
three favorite flavors it's named after
me
i am the jeffrey in lemon jeffrey ah
that's one of my favorites bro you did a
really good job i would
i probably i'd buy that i got lost in
sidetracked and what i was saying
talking about how good that concentrate
was but
i mean it bro good [ __ ] good dude also
hope we hang out it doesn't have social
media though so that's weird
then i was given another gift um by
proxy big shout out to my friend jeremy
uh for the uh delicious uh strawberry
starburst number six and number five
and then also big shout out to justin
for being the facilitator of that
product
uh jeremy couldn't make it to the event
he was kind enough to send three jars of
concentrate with our friend to make sure
they made it to
the booth um same story here i generally
don't dab
rosin but this number six
the jar is empty dude it is empty
oh it smells ah it's got some tangy it's
got a little clementine to it
but then it's got like a strawberry like
a fake
strawberry candy strawberry incense sort
of thing going on to it
and this one did not last long you could
tell that jar is empty
it's got scrape marks in it i was trying
to get the final dabs
out of that one there was number six
there was number five and i think there
was also number three
number three is gone non-existent and
then i think there might be
just a little bit of the sap left in
number five so shout out to jeremy
dude this stuff was delicious uh good
job i would dab that
all day long super terpy super delicious
it didn't leave any weirdness on my nail
ah didn't make me cough didn't make me
choke one thing i noticed about smoking
rosin though i smoke uh bho i smoke
diamonds and sauce and primarily batters
um the rosins are heavy on my lungs i
don't need as big of a dab i still take
as big of a dab
but it feels like there's weight on my
chest for a minute after i smoke it i
kind of enjoy it
also it kind of [ __ ] freaks me out
getting older i don't know if i like
that weight on my chest feeling i don't
need a [ __ ] heart attack or a stroke
at this age
anyway uh big thanks and big shout out
to everybody for all the great gifts
also
uh big shout out to ez057 i got to meet
ez057
take a picture get a fist bump uh i said
hey bro you've been a supporter for a
long time i want to give you some free
seeds what do you want and he said
i've got everything and i said bro you
can't have everything on the list and
he's like i got it all bro
so i was able to give my friend a shirt
or a hoodie uh but he had all the seeds
so big shout out to ez057 that was
[ __ ] cool
also big shout out to my friend jake
jake you're a cool dude you came to the
booth several times
uh jake would come and shop and then do
a lap and then realize i've still got a
few more bucks i need to buy something
else
then he hit the atm he came back a few
times he left with
bags and bags of irie gear we made sure
to load him up jake's a cool [ __ ] guy
irie army
uh through and through i'm glad i met
you bro really cool guy i look forward
to chatting with you
i look forward to taking some dabs um
wolf mike neal jeremy
justin easy jake uh everybody else we
met
i look forward to taking dads with you
in the future uh also of course jj
from top dog it was great to finally
shake your hand and tell you thanks for
the inspiration
he gave me a pack of seeds you guys i'm
not going to talk about that but that
may end up being a breeding project
in the future also i want to send a big
shout out to dj nika t
i haven't seen nicotine in a long time
uh we used to be at all the same events
when there were cannabis events we would
be there
um dj nicoti is uh the i think he's the
owner and founder of essential extracts
at least he was
at one point that's how i knew him he
was dj nicoti also that guy from
essential extracts
he used to be the other guy with dreads
he's cut his dreads off now i'm not
following the trend
don't do it uh but dj nicoti showed up
and dj nicotine
set the vibe for the day it was
beautiful
uh mike was like i hope we don't have to
listen to sublime all day
and i get it uh mike's not really a
reggae fan mike's not a sublime kind of
fan
and when the dj started playing reggae
mike kind of looked at me like oh it's
gonna be reggae all day but a few songs
in
he blended reggae with some other stuff
with some good reggae with some other
stuff
mike's not a reggae fan and he actually
enjoyed the musical vibes it felt like
they were playing a playlist for me
so big shout out to dj nicoti cush and
coconut water you guys it was really
exciting to be at events again
um i'm just rambling about an event
because i wanted to recap it and talk
about it because i haven't gone out and
done something like that in such a long
time
that it was amazing it also made me
realize
i need to update my booth uh the booth
looked good uh but it could be better
some of the guys have more professional
booths
i saw a couple of things that inspired
me some ideas that i'm definitely going
to
uh i'm going to steal your ideas that's
how we do it right you see business that
works and you copy things that work and
you ditch ideas that don't work
that's what we're doing here i saw great
a couple of ways just to improve the
booth flow
improve uh the efficiency of the booth
and lessen the environmental impact i
want to do less paper at the booth i
know that's
uh some hippy [ __ ] but uh there will be
less paper less takeaway stuff it'll all
be digital
the world's digital now we don't need
paper all right so
thanks to everybody who came out to the
event i had a great time thanks for wolf
thanks to wolf for throwing the event
thanks to microblife hydro for hosting
us
uh and then big thanks to everybody who
was a partner in crime
at the event we had a great time and
thanks to everybody who came up to the
booth
i met a lot of people it's good to see
everybody big shout out to katie ann
peterson and your new uh
and your partner in crime there it's
good to see you all right that's a lot
of people
to give shout outs felt like the the bet
awards or something here
somebody did say that i do too many
shout outs at the start of the show for
patreon
um those folks actually pay a patreon
tier
where i promise to give them a shout out
on the show so if i didn't shout them
out i would be a dick
and i do it in the first minute of the
show if you don't want to hear the
commercial and the shout outs
hit that skip button when you don't hear
music anymore the shout outs are
probably over
it's usually the way it works the music
and the shout outs last about the same
time
and also the podcast is free you're
welcome um where are we going to go from
there
um once again i wrote down thanks for
being patient while we fix and refix and
refix all of the podcast servers if
you've missed episodes i apologize
uh it's driving me crazy as well but
we're working on it shout out to my web
guy i think he listens to the show
if you hear this bro big thanks
everybody appreciates you
uh not just me the people listening they
all appreciate you
now i do want to move on to the main
topic of this podcast i've been talking
for quite a while this is gonna be a
long show
um this portion of the show is brought
to you by my friend kes burton shout out
to my buddy kes burton this topic is
going to be
seed storage uh we sold a bunch of seeds
at the seed event
i get a lot of messages about how to
store seeds i felt like this would be a
great appropriate episode
to segue the seed event into seed
storage perhaps you went to an event
this weekend perhaps you've been
shopping online
perhaps you're headed to the events that
are coming up and you've got a bunch of
seeds
what do i do with my seeds as a seed
breeder as a seed seller
my number one recommendation for what
you do with your seeds is to
guess what grow them i didn't make seeds
for you to put them in a [ __ ] vault i
don't want those seeds in a [ __ ] desk
drawer
i don't want those seeds in your safe i
would prefer not to see them
in your [ __ ] junk drawer or your
underwear drawer or wherever you keep
them
in your fridge i want you to put them in
the dirt
depending on your location and your
legalities iregenetics is not
responsible for
violation of uh growing laws or rules or
regulations but
if you're in a safe legal place i really
want you to get them wet and put them in
the [ __ ] dirt
i don't want you to store them however i
do appreciate love and respect and
admire
that people are buying my seed packages
and keeping them like baseball cards
they treat them like a pokemon card i
gotta get them all and as a seller of
seeds
i have no complaints if you're gonna put
those in a drawer i guess i'm gonna be
excited about that but let's talk about
a way
to safely and effectively long-term
store these seeds seeds are not cheap
seeds do not last forever i like to
pride myself in being one of the more
affordable seed breeders also
i saw some prices this weekend i've seen
some prices online
and you guys are welcome i'm staying
very affordable i don't
need to take all of your money i just
need to get paid for my work i don't
need
we're not trying to get rich we're just
trying to live over here make sure
everybody's fed
uh maybe some some sneakers we'll be all
right anyway i'm rambling
but uh you've got expensive seeds you
want to keep them alive you want to keep
them safe you want to keep them stored
what is the best way
to store these seeds for long term most
of the seeds that you buy are going to
be
in a package they should be in some sort
of a sealed package already
i'm looking across the table jj sells
his seeds in that like mylar package it
seems to be vacuum sealed or at least
heat sealed
i'm looking at uh loving in her eyes has
quite an extravagant package but on the
inside those are sealed
inside of a little vial my seeds come in
a disc with the foam padding
on the inside the disc to keep the seeds
from rattling around
those are inside of a baggie with the
folded card insert that baggie is heat
sealed
so most of the seeds are going to be
sealed in a good package already
the first thing i would suggest is maybe
putting your seeds if you've got a lot
of packs you're trying to seal get one
box and put them all in one box that
does
seal um i've got for my
small personal stash that i know i'm
gonna i think i'm gonna run
i've got a it's a grateful dead lunch
box it's one of those metal lunch boxes
it doesn't seal super tight but it seals
enough for me
and all those seeds are already sealed
so i'm comfortable with that for my
personal little storage stash my uh
my nostalgic seed vault if you will i
would recommend something
that is airtight they make those little
uh all the head shops used to have them
in the late 90s early 2000s we were in
high school it's what we kept all our
[ __ ] in
just a little airtight stash box it's
just got a rubber grommet around it it's
a metal box
it's probably got led zeppelin or insane
clown posse or something [ __ ] printed
on it maybe you got tupac on yours i
don't know
but uh what we need to do is make an
irie genetics seed stash box just like
that if you know how to do that if you
were the person that does that please
contact me
ah we will hook you the [ __ ] up because
everybody out there is going to want to
buy an irie genetic seed stash box
let's get back on track we need a stash
box something that could be airtight not
super airtight isn't critical i like the
airtight so we're going to put the seeds
in the airtight box as the first step
then where do we put that
i see a lot of people putting their
seeds in the refrigerator
let me talk a little bit about that
because i'm going to say put your seeds
in a cool dry dark place and people are
going to say that's the refrigerator or
the crisper drawer
that is cool also i don't like the
freezer that's going to fall into this
category
think about if you put uh anything in
the crisper drawer anything in the
fridge
it makes condensation it gets cold in
there right it creates moisture inside
that package
then you take that out now that moisture
has to go somewhere that condensation
is inside of that package you've got
moisture moving around
inside of your package possibly inside
of your seed package what
germinates your seeds is moisture so you
can create a condensation issue by
putting your seeds in the fridge and
taking them out or putting them in the
freezer and taking them out too
frequently if you do choose to store
your seeds in the refrigerator or in the
freezer
put them in there and leave them there
for a while
if you're the kind of person that likes
to pull out your seeds and marvel at
your collection or show off your seeds
to your friends
i don't recommend putting them in that
deep of a cold
in that case i recommend just a cool
dry dark environment perhaps you live in
colorado and you've got a basement maybe
you've got a back
dark corner of that basement where you
can put a safe
put those seeds in that safe that will
stay cool
in the basement in colorado it stays
about
75 degrees ish it may get a little bit
colder in the winter it may get a little
bit hotter in the summer
but if you got the normal house
environment happening it's going to stay
about 75 down there in the basement
because you got the heater upstairs
running the house to keep it warm or you
got the cooler keeping it cool
it's gonna kind of adjust the downstairs
the house stays insulated
pretty good temperature down there find
that back secure corner nobody knows how
to find
put your safe with your seeds back there
that's nice and secure cool
dry dark safe environment also a safe
environment something that nobody could
get to
because you don't want people stealing
your expensive freaking seeds
um heat in my opinion is one of the best
ways to destroy
and degrade the lifespan of a seed so
keep those seeds cool the cooler the
better
to a point you don't want to get them so
cold that they rupture and explode
that's another thing to talk about super
dry seeds
i try to dry my seeds really really dry
before i send them to anybody something
we did discover
is that if you don't dry the seeds
enough um i was having
an issue that seeds going to one
direction i was getting complaints on it
seeds i sent to another direction i
didn't get any complaints about
and i was like how come everybody on the
east coast is having germination issues
with this new batch of seeds
everybody on the west coast their seeds
are just fine i thought about it it's
the middle of winter
the seeds going that way are [ __ ]
freezing the seeds going that way are
just fine
uh then i thought there's freezing and
erupting they're probably erupting
in cargo they're probably on a plane
they're getting too cold and they're
bursting
in the plane in the cargo so i've
started drying the seeds a little bit
more
i just put them with uh what is it
called it's not a boveda
it's a silicate pack that just sucks up
all the moisture
i've got the number written down at the
point i want to get it below once i'm
below that point
i know they won't rupture in the mail i
know they won't rupture in cargo they
won't rupture if they get too cold
makes the seeds a little bit safer this
is how much thought we're putting into
keeping the seeds safe and fresh to get
them to
the grower we want you to have success
if you don't have success with my seeds
you can email me
and over time eventually you will get a
replacement pack if you've got a good
reason if you didn't [ __ ] them up being
completely stupid
i'd rather have good customer service
and eat a pack than you hate me and
spread
[ __ ] [ __ ] on the internet about me
because i do care about you so
dry seeds is the main idea keep them
nice and dry store them in a cool dry
dark place don't freeze them
heat will ruin them i don't prefer them
in the freezer extremes of either way
i don't think are good if you've got to
go extreme one way cold is the best if
you think about it they probably fell
out of the plant they landed
they stayed in the snow the snow melted
it became water that water germinated
the seed it grew up so i think the cold
is preservation
that's not as bad as heat all right so
to recap i really recommend a cool dry
dark place uh if you insist on putting
them in the refrigerator i do recommend
you put them in that crisper drawer try
to keep them dry
put them in an airtight container if
you're going to put them in there
once again i don't recommend the freezer
if you're going to take them out and put
them back
if you're the kind of person that wants
to show them off just a cool dry dark
place
uh like a corner in the basement a shelf
in the basement something like that
something no one's gonna get to
uh none of your pets are going to find
them and eat them something else i want
to talk about
is when you're restoring these seeds
make sure that they are
labeled they have a name on them are
they in the original breeder packaging
did you write the name on a baggie and
every time you touch it you're rubbing
that name off with your thumb
and in a few years you won't even know
what those seeds are think about how
well labeled
and sealed those seeds are also write
down the date of when you put those in
there so you know how long you've had
those seeds around
then also are they regular or feminized
seeds i would write that down on the
packaging
as well i try to include as many details
as i can
in a package of seeds i like to be a
little bit excessive i claim to be a
sort of a cannabis historian or
something like that i'm documenting
cannabis
i talk a lot about cannabis i argue a
lot about cannabis i want to be correct
so i try to make a lot of details
uh in the future this cannabis stuff is
going to be talked about the revolution
of cannabis
uh how cannabis became legal in some
areas and we had medical cannabis and
the growing and the breeding and all
this culture will be talked about this
will be
uh we're pioneers if you're in this
right now you are a pioneer
and i was here from a lot of the
beginning of this stuff and so it's kind
of my responsibility with
the way my brain works the way i talk to
people with this show platform it's kind
of my responsibility
to make sure that history and cannabis
lore and all of that stuff stays
accurate i just had a
a lacewing a baby lace wing crawl on my
arm so my
ipm is working because it jumped from
this plant onto my arm a little baby
lace wing freaked me out i felt it
um yeah beneficial insects are the way
to go
um yeah if you've ever seen a little
baby lacing it looks like a little
crocodile looks like a little tiny
dinosaur one of the ugliest little bugs
ever and then it turns into a lacewing
i got totally distracted by feeling that
bug climb up my arm but i think i have
made
my point for most of this episode
because i really do not remember where i
was so i think that is a good point
uh just to start wrapping up the podcast
you guys i want to thank everybody for
listening
if you've got any questions corrections
comments or concerns i would love to
hear from you the email address is grow
from your heart at hotmail.com
of course don't forget to check out the
website at iregenetics.com
everything ire genetics everything grow
from your heart is right there on the
website
again if you feel like the podcast was
educational informative or entertaining
and you'd like to make a financial
contribution to the show
all you've got to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need is right
there on the screen and there is a link
in the show notes
and the video description to make it
super easy to get to
the patreon page that is all i've got
for you for this episode i want to thank
you again for listening
i'll be back in a couple of days with
fresh new content i want to give a giant
shout out to my friend captain mojo
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
you