[Music]
yeah welcome back podcast world i'm your
host my friends call me rasta jeff and
this
is episode 644 of the grow from your
heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to answer a
couple of emails and a couple of patreon
questions
before we get there let's do a few shout
outs to a few of those fine folks who
support us on patreon
let's start off with the big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to my friend saxon snowden let's send a
thank you shout out to
jt gross and levity loveday let's send a
big thank you shout out to alabama man
and glenn jeroni
let's send a big thank you shout out to
gramps memo and single t
i want to send a thank you shout out to
triom up and dang gross let's send a big
thank you shout out to guido and
mister and then let's wrap it all up
with the big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out
to my friend thecanacrat big thanks and
big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon
if you are not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need is right
there on the screen and of course
i did include a link in the show notes
and the video description
to make it nice and easy for all of my
friends you know the slogan if you're
driving if you're working if you're
trimming
don't take off your gloves don't crash
the car don't get in trouble at work
to support me on patreon the link will
be right there when you're ready
patreon.com forward slash grow
from your heart by the way if you're
listening to this at the grow if you're
working
make sure the rest of the crew is
listening to introduce the gang
to the grow from your heart podcast make
everybody a better grower
get everybody on the same team share the
show with your friends all right
so i've been asked a couple of questions
lately that we're gonna start the show
off here
um i get a lot of questions saying hey
where can i find either
your seeds your clones your flowers or
some sort of irie genetics products and
dispensaries
uh maybe i should give you a little
recap maybe not everybody knows
not only am i the host of the grow from
your heart podcast i am also the
uh owner founder sole proprietor uh the
head [ __ ] in charge of ire
genetics premium seeds
so i do run ire genetics premium seeds a
lot of people see my instagram posts my
social media posts
they want my flowers they want clones
and they want my seeds
so they ask where do i get that stuff in
colorado
uh unfortunately uh once i sell the
seeds i don't know where they go so i
don't know what dispensary
is growing my seeds my strains my clones
i don't know
i don't monitor the seeds i don't track
the clones i don't know where that stuff
goes
i don't know exactly what dispensary
will have what products
in stock on the shelf at any time i do
know there are several
uh commercial recreational and medical
dispensaries throughout colorado that do
have
my clones my plants in their grows but i
can't promise you when it will be on the
shelf they've got to grow it
they've got to harvest it dry it cure it
manifest it transfer it over the store
it's got to be on the shelf it's got to
be there when you get there
i really have no way of knowing what
happened that's just
it's their product once they've got the
seeds it is theirs once you guys have
purchased the seeds
uh you can ask me questions about how to
grow it and whatnot but those are your
seeds
you can do whatever you want with them
and yes you do have my blessing to breed
with the seeds that you get from me
please do breed with them
in exchange give me credit when you list
the genetics on your pack at least put
the proper strain name
and then maybe send me a 10 pack of
something if you bread something cool
but i'm not sure where to get flowers or
clones of my genetics and dispensaries
in colorado
also you cannot get my seeds in anywhere
in colorado just because of the way that
colorado law is set up
there are some boundaries there i do
recommend the online vendors for seeds
check out my website iriegenetics.com
uh that will give you a link to
approximately seven vendors on there we
will be adding more
uh shortly i'm just updating checking
emails getting all that stuff caught up
seeing what i can handle honestly
i don't wanna promise too many vendors
things that i cannot send to them so the
seeds are available on the internet
you've got to go to ireadgenetics.com
maybe seeds herenow.com
maybe dankseed.store there are a lot of
different options my website has a big
list
they will all have different stuff in
stock they'll be doing different deals
different pricing that is all up to them
they run their business how they would
like but their websites are all linked
up to my website
so the seeds you can get them on the
website clones and flowers i do not know
where to tell you to get clones or
flowers or finish product
i will not ship you anything i will not
mail you anything i will not meet you
anywhere for anything
you've got to use the apps that are
available to shop the dispensaries there
are a couple apps you can use
i'm not sure what you like the best use
the one you're using type in a strain
name look for a dispensary where you are
or where you're going or in that area
and see if it is available
i know that randomly i don't endorse any
specific dispensary i just happen to
know
that occasionally randomly a place
called trench town
has a couple of irie genetic strains
call before you drive
uh they may not even tell you anything
on the phone you may have to check out
the website or something
they don't know that you're 21 so when
you call the dispensary and you say
do you have this product and they say we
can't tell you over the phone that's
because you've got to be 21 to shop in
the dispensary and they don't want to
tell you anything if you're not 21
they're trying to protect themselves
so don't think they're being a dick
don't think they're being mean to you uh
we're trying to keep our licenses it
costs a million bucks for that license
we're not going to give it away
by giving dumb information over the
phone so don't feel like they're uh
being disrespectful they're trying to
cover their own ass you may have to
check a website you may have to go there
so trench town in denver uh sometimes
carries my products not my products
my strains they have acquired either
seeds or clones i had nothing to do with
it after that they've grown it they have
done
their stuff with it uh so that may be on
the shelf they may have lemon jeffrey
at trench town in denver uh once again
check before you drive if you can
kind love sometimes has lemon jeffrey it
may be the same cut they may be sharing
the same cut
between trench town and kind love also
a long time ago three rivers in pueblo
had a rise
i don't know if they've still got that
it may have been removed it may have
still be that i don't know honestly but
at one point in time it was there so
check
the website check the apps all those
services before you go
uh there are other spots in colorado
that may have my stuff but really i
don't know where to tell you to look
uh wherever you are if you're in
michigan i know my stuff is available
there if you're in new mexico
uh check out organtica they've got a lot
of my products if you are
in new mexico check out everest everest
grew
the [ __ ] out of some arise they won best
sativa in the chronicle magazine
uh the bud bowl or something like that
so the sativa
uh first place was a rise grown by
everest so check them out that light is
bugging my left eye to make my eye
twitch i may edit that part out i may
not
so if you're in new mexico check out
everest they've got the arise quite
often
i know that a lot of places across the
country have got my product so
just do the research you can check the
websites check the apps again
don't rely on my advice because i'm
telling you straight up i can't promise
you anything i don't know
uh once it's like once i've sold the
seed i don't know where that seed goes
you can grow it you can
do whatever you want with it and then
you can take thousands of clones from
one plant so i don't know where all of
those clones end up i have no idea
all right now to follow up on that a
little bit seeds here now.com should
have a restock very soon by the time
this episode drops
there should be a restock at seeds here
now.com
they were running very very low on ire
genetics products i apologize that we
let them get that low
uh they were doing a website update they
were doing some inventory updates
we were kind of in a holding position uh
no more holding we have got them a
restock by the time this episode comes
out everything should be on the website
honestly a lot of the stuff will be
resold out and we will be restocking it
again
we're going to do our best to keep the
stock updated and
in stock some things are honestly sold
out i have to make things ah
yeah but we're going to do our best to
keep things updated i apologize for the
low stock on seeds here now make sure
you do use coupon code gfyh10 while
checking out its seeds here now that'll
save you uh 10
that may save you the cost of shipping
if you're buying multiple packs
they may buy you another pack of seeds
so check out seeds herenow.com they
should have a restock
all right now let's move forward to the
main topics of today's podcast
this section of the show is brought to
you by my friend billy podunk big shout
out to my buddy billy podunk for always
supporting the podcast
thank you bro it's always good to see
you in the discord i've got a couple of
great messages here i printed some stuff
out
the first one came from our friend they
want their name said
we're going to say their name this one
came from newbie nuggs big up to newbie
nugs
got a couple of things in this message
that says hey ross to jeff first of all
thank you for the amazing work
you do not only in your breeding but
also in the knowledge you
share thank you i appreciate that i
always say that those compliments are
like recharge
it's like nutrients for my soul so thank
you i appreciate it then it says i have
a question
um also says i've included a picture but
we don't know we don't need the picture
here because i can explain this
uh he explains the grow it says i'm
running autoflowers for this setup i got
a
five uh he does talk about the grow he
says uh so i filled this run with some
bag of peel
red and purples now that i've been
talking forever let's get into the
question and all the environmentals that
you care about i did skip some stuff
there
but it says this is an autoflower named
red poison it's from sweet seeds
all right it says i know this breeder
has many strains bred for the sole
purpose of being red or purple that's
really cool we've got a breeder
breeding for the purpose of making a
color if you're breeding
have a purpose if they're starting out
looking for color that's a great goal a
great purpose
great bag appeal that will make you
stand out uh if you set three bags of
herb on the table and yours is [ __ ]
bright red or bright purple someone's
gonna grab that they're gonna want to
buy that [ __ ]
it gets attention so you're hitting the
bag of peel
on nailing that one right on the or
hitting that nail on the head
then it says these are almost five weeks
old
and as i popped into the tent to make an
update for youtube i see that two of
these babies are pre-flowering
and i mean they're just hitting
pre-flowers the pistols are barely
poking out
and the color is wild and it's got
exclamation points why the word color is
wild
now here's the question it says my
question is do you know what causes this
or the reason
that plants make colors and how it
spreads into the veins of the leaves
i've had many purplish strains but uh
this one looks like it is bleeding into
the leaves
fast is it a chlorophyll type of
chemical
and then it says it could be genetic and
then he lists his environment which
uh we don't need to go too much further
because you've already
answered the question yourself it is uh
basically
uh similar to chlorophyll but this is
known as an anthocyan i had to print
that word out because i've been saying
it wrong
i've just been calling it anthos because
i wasn't sure how to say the last part
because
i've never had to say it out loud before
honestly until today but
what you're seeing is anthocyanin it is
basically the purple version of
chlorophyll it's the
chlorophyll is what makes the leaves
green anthocyanin is what is making
that purple reddish color a lot of other
uh
things have that pigment is what we're
gonna call it uh carrots were actually
purple when they first started that's
what gives beets that color i think
from what i've read uh they've got
anthocyanin
uh it's blue violet or a red flavonoid
pigment found in plants this is the
definition of that so that's what you're
seeing
um and it's easy not easy it's
uh i guess it's easy to breed for that
because it's visually
uh identifiable when you're breeding
when you're growing plants that is a
very easy
visual indicator to identify like
potency pest resistance
uh hermaphroditism those are all traits
you've gotta wait and find out for
hermaphroditism you will see that
but you gotta wait that orange purple
different colors that's a very
visual thing you can definitely breed
for that you can select for that find
those very early
know if you're hitting your goal find
breeding plants that is very cool so
that's a really cool goal um he's
hitting the goal if you're getting
plants with that many colors
so that is a successful breeding project
in my opinion
all right newbie nugs what you've got
going on there is anthocyanin
uh they're hitting their goal they bred
for that red and purple color it's
popping up
that is exactly what you're seeing uh
thank you for the great question bro
thank you for the patreon support if
you've got any more questions i do look
forward to hearing from you
all right this one actually came from
youtube i don't generally answer
questions from the youtube comments
i happen to notice this one uh it's not
that i'm ignoring the youtube comments
there are just a lot of them
and as a content uh creator
we are taught not to read a lot of the
comments because uh the comments are
[ __ ] where all the savagery happens
the comments are where the savagery
happens that sentence wasn't as hard to
say as it looked
um people aren't kind in the comments
people don't give a [ __ ] in the comments
so we don't read a lot of them because
we just don't want to
just why even delve into the negativity
but i saw this one pop up
i actually got the email and it says
just like this it's from our friend
big mike from canada and it says great
show as usual and it says question
what are your smoke test processes once
you have created a new strain
how long into curing it do you wait uh
do you have smoke testers
do you test the flowers only or to the
concentrates also
do you wait for lab results i would
appreciate it if you could elaborate
during a show for these important steps
to choose for your keepers many thanks
in advance
keep up the great work you can mention
my name i'm big mike from
canada big mike from canada these are
great questions
uh let's just get right to it what are
your smoke test processes once you've
created a new strain
uh basically chop it down dry it and
cure it and smoke it my favorite ways
i roll a fat joint of it pack a bowl of
it pack a bong load of it
then i'm gonna smoke it um how long
into curing do you wait uh generally
i dry it i cure it for maybe a week
maybe two i am not one of those guys
that does the ridiculously long cure i
don't find it necessary to go a long
time
the chemical process i'm looking for
happened in about two weeks that's all i
need out of that then i start smoking it
sometimes i don't wait that long um
do you have smoke testers yeah everybody
around here loves to be a smoke tester
all i have to do is say hey i got some
new herb
and the couches will be full uh people
will invite me over
i get really popular when they know that
it is almost time to do some testing
uh some phenotype selections yeah i've
got a crew um
shout out to the crew they know who they
are uh by the way doug i miss you bro we
need to get you back on the smoke
testing team
if you still watch the show gotta get
you smoking again
um smoke testers yeah shout out to all
the test crew they know who they are
mike is one of the number one testers
um it's always up to me though i am i'm
the [ __ ] head [ __ ] in charge
if i decide that number six is the best
and other people said that number three
was the best guess what number six is
the winner
because i'm the one that [ __ ] i've
got the goal i know the plan so
i also know that that plant's going to
get bred to in the future and i've got
other ulterior motives
anyway uh test crew yes there's a test
crew
um what's the next part do you test the
flowers only or the concentrates
it depends on uh the timing if there's
somebody around that can make
concentrates for me sometimes getting
somebody to make some diamonds for me to
make some sauce or batter
is time consuming and it does uh they do
charge me for that
sometimes it's not cost effective
sometimes there's not enough product to
make it worth it
sometimes i just grew a bunch of tiny
tiny plants and we're just going to
smoke the flowers and see because that's
really what matters if the
flowers are no good most of the
customers are going to smoke it
as a flower when they buy seeds from me
most of them are only going to smoke
as a flower only a small percentage of
them will continue to make concentrates
out of it
um i know most of what i make is going
to make amazing concentrates
just because the potency and the terps
that i've chosen for my breeding palette
always
make great concentrates so if it's
available if it's an option i do have
concentrates made
do you wait for lab results that's a
good question a lot of people are hyped
up on lab results and i've started to
care less and less about lab results
um i've never had a high pressure liquid
chromatography machine
buy seeds from me i've never had a
[ __ ] lab device
smoke weed with me and say that it was
really good or really bad i don't smoke
weed with machines
i don't grow weed for test results i
grow weed for [ __ ]
human results human consumers that's who
is going to smoke it humans are going to
grow it
humans are going to smoke it i i
appreciate what the lab says
but i'd rather hear what you've got to
say i'd rather hear what mike's got to
say i'd rather hear what doug's got to
say
i'd rather hear what everybody in the
smoke circle's got to say about it
compared to what a [ __ ] machine has
to say about it the machines are awesome
the testing is cool
but what difference does it make if i
smoke it
mike smokes it kevin smokes it [ __ ]
matt smokes it
uh everybody smokes it and we all say
that sample number three is the winner
but the lab tests show that sample
number six has higher numbers
who cares what the lab test said we all
enjoyed number three better
we're the humans that are going to be
consuming it i've never smoked a joint
with a machine
pretty sure i have i'm pretty sure i
[ __ ] blew weed into a machine at the
bowling alley when it wouldn't [ __ ]
work right one time and it worked it
fixed that son of a [ __ ] but
anyway um i don't worry too much about
lab results in lab tests i do love
seeing a high number
it definitely it works for marketing i
think the numbers are more for marketing
we put the numbers on there people want
to buy the seeds when they see a higher
number at the dispensary
people just straight up say what's your
concentrate with the highest thc
so those numbers are good for marketing
good for advertising for me
it doesn't make a difference i want um i
want more terps if the number is
super high in thc then where do the
terps go we need just lower the thc and
put some terps in there for me and i'll
be okay
um there is more for this i would
appreciate it if you could elaborate on
this during a show i think i elaborated
bro on these important steps for
choosing keepers
um choosing keepers it's a lot of it is
the smoke report but a lot of it is how
does it grow
uh did it give me any problems any
stress during the grow
do i think that it's got traits that
it's going to pass on
in the offspring if i breed to it that
are going to give you problems as a
consumer i want to make sure that you've
got seeds that will be successful
a lot of my decision making in selection
is for
you um you may not be
the people purchasing the seeds may not
be as experienced of a grower as myself
you may not have
thousands of hours thousands of crops
under your belt you may not be a
commercial grower with
resources and space and [ __ ] money
for products
this may be the only pack of seeds you
can buy this may be the first pack of
seeds you bought this may be your first
and last run at growing wheat if you're
not successful
so i do my best to select plants that i
know
are going to make seeds that give you a
good opportunity to grow that's my main
goal
as a seed producer i do breed stuff that
you never get
ah because it's kind of bread for me
that's my secret stash i kind of know
that
if i put like uh some chem 91 and some
old og
kush [ __ ] together there's an
opportunity for intersex traits there
there's an opportunity for pain in the
ass plants
that stuff won't go anywhere that stays
for me but the stuff that i'm breeding
for
you that i know is going to be
commercially viable that i know i want
to release to the masses
i make sure that it's going to be
successful for the
very beginner grower and then i know
that the commercial grower the pro
grower that my crew my friends are going
to kill it they're going to hit the
numbers
they're going to hit bonuses everyone's
going to eat fat we're going to get good
concentrates
so that's what i put out as my
commercial seed
line i know you're going to have success
um so that's a part of
my selection for keepers then does it
work well in my grow because i'm the one
growing it i got to keep it in my grow
does it show me any problems um
does it breed well with other things
it's got to be able to breed well with
multiple different crosses maybe can i
reverse
it that also helps me select a keeper as
a breeder i think my criteria for
selecting keepers may be a little bit
different than some people
a lot of people are just looking for
smoke a lot of people are looking for
something that smokes well
smells good looks good in the bag and
bottom line is does it pay the bills
so that's we're growing for different
things our bottom line is a different
thing so my selection may be a little
bit different
but as the breeder creating a product
for you i understand your main goal so
i think that helps a lot me
understanding your goal providing a
product for you to hit your goal
helps out a lot so um giant mike that
was a big mike that was a great question
bro thank you
thanks for listening up there in canada
i do appreciate that i'm making sure i
answered all of your questions here hit
all the points
the process bro roll it up and smoke it
uh roll a fat joint because i want to
taste the flavor i want to taste the
flavor down at the end
smoke it in a bowl because generally if
i'm smoking
weed around the house it's in a bowl
because i like to pack a bowl and i just
set it in my lap and
i [ __ ] hit it now and put it in my
lap and walk around with it and
if i don't have nothing to do for a
couple of seconds let's hit a bowl and
then just
carry it around so i like to have weed
and a pipe like that
if i don't have a lot of time i'm
getting kind of older now i hate to
admit it but hitting a bong kind of
hurts sometimes but
i like to take a big fat bong rip get a
lot of flavor get a lot of experience
from
that flower in a big fat bong rip and
then of course make some concentrates
out of it
um how long do i cure it my products
doesn't my products don't get cured for
very long my personal stuff i don't
believe in over curing i don't think
it's necessary
the testers are the crew i feel like i
answered all of the points
so big mike thank you bro i do
appreciate it keep listening and if
you've got more questions
please do send them my way and if
everybody out there if you're not
already subscribed to the youtube
channel please do
click like and subscribe on the youtube
channel that is where this message came
from
leave some comments on the youtube
channel because that does make uh the
show move up in the algorithm
i do appreciate that sort of stuff right
i'm digging for the next message here
um we're gonna do this one this is gonna
be a longer podcast than i had
anticipated you're welcome you deserve
it
uh this one came from our friend jethro
earl 710 what up jethro thank you for
the great message
this one says hey ross to jeff feel free
to use my screen name
if you read this on the show already
done that part it says
i've been listening to your podcast for
a few years now and i have to say it's
helped me get through some long
work days bro i know the feeling thank
you
um i listen to podcast two when i'm
working and it does make a long day go
quite quickly says i give it five stars
thank you please uh go rate it and
review it wherever you're listening
it says i was so excited to see you post
my pictures of orange gasm if i'm
posting your pictures they must have
been beautiful
since i've been wanting to ask you to do
a show on photography for a while
now maybe some simple gear to get
started what do you use
also some tips to make better social
media posts i've put in my tester
application
and right after you did that podcast is
there anything i could do differently to
improve my chances to be selected
i'm just finishing up a run of orgasm i
now have strawberry starburst and veg
blueberry butcher and sonic boom coming
from seeds here now
uh then he gives us an email and then
his cannabis
he's jethro earl 710 on cannabis you
guys give him a follow make sure you
check out cannabaz
then he signs it keep up the good work
from your friend and then sign it with
his real name which we're gonna leave
out of the show
hey bro thank you this is a great
message um i'm going to talk briefly
about cannabis photography before i do
that i have got to tell you honestly
straight up 100
i do not consider myself a photographer
i have got
absolutely zero photography training
i don't know what the numbers mean i
don't know what that stuff
means on the camera basically the way
i've learned it
i got a camera started turning the knobs
turn one knob this way
take a bunch of pictures and start
turning the knob the other way and as it
goes this way i paid attention to the
changes in my photos
then i picked a different setting and
set it all the way at one end started
taking pictures take a couple and switch
the settings this way as i go and pay
attention to the differences
then learn how those two settings kind
of work with each other
that's how i learned photography i know
that's not the way to do it
but that is kind of how i learned stuff
i've been learning
under the gun i got a camera and i
thought i want to take pictures and i
started shooting pictures
they went online immediately my photos
got better i just kept doing it as i was
learning i never stopped to like
take a class or learn anything then i
ended up doing a podcast ended up doing
a video podcast i'm learning the video
production the same exact way
i produce the shows i edit them and then
as i'm producing and editing them
i learn mistakes i made corrections i
can make improvements i can make as i go
that is how i learned photography video
production podcasting
so i learned cannabis growing i did a
lot of reading and research on cannabis
growing so i was
ah completely passionate about it but
photography just came
kind of naturally to me i don't know
what i'm doing
i don't know how to take pictures of
anything but cannabis plants and
sneakers that is what i can take
pictures of
uh if you sign me up to be the
photographer at your wedding or at a
birthday party you're gonna be [ __ ]
mad cause i don't know what i'm doing
like i honestly i just have a good eye
for the shot i know what i want
i've looked at magazines long enough to
see what works well
uh but honestly i don't know what i'm
doing technically there's no schooling
behind it it's all just
hey that's a good image let's catch that
so that is my disclaimer
i am not a photographer i play with a
camera so one of the first things you
said
um let's see one of the first things you
want to know about some simple tips with
gear to get started
honest bro most of my photos are done
with an
iphone 8 plus that is honest i've got
this
eight plus and i love it for photography
it works very it's simple
uh i also have a canon
um oh it's a nikon d3200 sorry my brain
farted right there i have a nikon
d3200 that is kind of an older camera
i've got two lenses for it one is
close up and one is further away i use
the further away lens and zoom in
really close and i get beautiful shots
it's a nikon d3200
not a super expensive camera kind of an
older camera that's what i learned with
that is how i learned how to take photos
of cannabis
a lot of the stuff you see from
commercial grows that i post is with the
nikon d3200
uh now it's a very affordable camera
because it's kind of old
um i do not use the auto settings i've
learned a couple of settings on there
once you get
your aperture setting right and your iso
setting right you'll learn exactly how
to shoot in a grow room
um so what i'm getting at now i've
upgraded i've actually got the uh the
sony a6400
which uh takes beautiful pictures but i
prefer it for the video camera it
doesn't move a lot right now that i've
got it set up in the video spot
it's beautiful but that's what i'm using
now you don't see a lot of photos from
that
um most of it comes from the nikon
because it's uh that's actually kept
near the grow space
so what i was going to get out with that
the most important part about your
photography equipment in my opinion
is understand the tool you have got if
you're using an iphone
if you're using an android phone if
you're using a canon camera a nikon
camera a sony camera
learn that device but i don't think you
uh need a device that is above your
skill level
i've got the sony uh which is this one
the a6400
the a73 would take a much better photo a
much better video
but it's got so many buttons and so many
settings that i think
it would just stumble me it would trip
me up and confuse me
more than it would help me to be
productive i've got the highest
camera that i think i could understand
to be productive in a couple of years
once i understand all these settings and
tools and tricks i will upgrade
to that a7 3 by then there will be
something better out it'll be the
a [ __ ] 22 5 or some [ __ ] and we'll
get that one but
you see what i'm saying uh just get the
best
tool that you can understand i am not a
professional guitar player so i don't
have
[ __ ] les paul guitars and amplifiers
everywhere i'm a half-assed guitar
player so i've got a yamaha acoustic on
a standard that's dusty
get the best that you can handle don't
get something out of your league that's
going to intimidate you
cameras can be confusing if you don't
know what you're doing i honestly don't
know what any of those buttons and
settings mean i had to learn all of that
stuff on the fly
um i learned all of it on youtube
honestly so
know know the gear that you've got learn
the gear that you've got the best it's
not about having the best
gear it's about mastering the gear that
you do have
um then where are we gonna go
there's a big learning curve when you do
get a new camera
you're gonna think oh i'm gonna point
this camera at the [ __ ] plants and
take a picture
there's so many settings to play with
like i talked about before
that you're gonna have to figure out how
to shoot in your environment
a big tip and you can't do this
everywhere if i did this in some
commercial environments the uh
lead grower the owner would come and
throw a [ __ ] fit turn off the grow
lights
in my personal grow space i unplug the
grow lights when i'm taking pictures now
it's dark in there
and i turn on a fluorescent light and we
just got normal white lighting in the
room the 4800 or the 48k
4800 kelvin that's what i'm looking for
uh that color looks really good for
photography and for lighting that's what
i got going on right here those are at
4800k is what i believe the lighting in
front of me is the one behind me
different spectrum don't judge me by
that one i just did that for ambience
behind me these two in front
4800k is where they are set i think
that's a beautiful color for photography
uh so just use a fluorescent light turn
off the grow lights use a fluorescent
light in there
um the more lighting the better
um let's talk about the shot um
it doesn't matter how good your gear is
if you can't frame a shot if you don't
can't get your subject right you're not
going to take a good photo
think look at what you're shooting think
about the subject
get the subject in the shot and then
don't have a bunch of extra stuff in the
shot if you can clean up the background
i know where
a lot of us are taking pictures in the
garden we're in the grow so we can't
just move everything out of the
background if you can move that plant
in front of a background like this
curtain behind me or a cool color
or a contrasting color something that's
not green if you can put it in front of
black or purple or
blue or something like that to make the
greens and the reds pop out
that's always a good idea don't put it
right against the background put it
about a foot off of the background and
lots of lighting but think about what's
behind
that picture do you want to see like a
bunch of crates and five gallon buckets
and maybe the toilet or something like
that you don't want to see all that dumb
[ __ ] in the background we want to see a
beautiful
pleasing picture everything in the
picture should catch my eye and make me
go
oh that's a nice shot we don't need to
see your ph pen that's all crusty
and the floor that's dirty and [ __ ] like
that give us a pleasant shot
what's the goal of your shot what are
you trying to show me what do you want
me to see
as the photographer it's your
responsibility to show me
what you wanted me to see all i've got
is this picture you're not going to be
there to say
look at those trichomes if you want me
to look at those trichomes
get those trichomes in the shot that's
all you got to do the one picture is
your opportunity to tell me the story so
frame it the way you want it
get it framed up in there like the shot
you're looking at right now there's not
a bunch of junk in the background not a
bunch of junk in the sides
if you do take a picture and there's a
bunch of [ __ ] on the sides of your
picture don't be afraid to crop it you
could trim out the sides of your
pictures
like over here off camera there's some
recording equipment you can't even see
you think this room looks super clean
and organized no there's a mess right
there you can't even see it
but we just crop it out make it look
super good and super professional
nobody has to know about that stuff
unless you tell them
so make the shot pleasing frame it have
a good angle have a good background
think about good colors
uh colors that contrast your plant
colors that complement your plant
uh what are you trying to highlight i've
talked about this a little bit are you
trying to highlight the trichomes the
colors the leaf shape
uh the density of the buzz are you
trying to show me the whole plant
get what you want in that shot step back
step forward move around
don't be afraid to move around in the
ground sometimes i'll be in there
hanging off of a step ladder with one
foot on the stepladder and one foot
against the wall leaning up against the
door
[ __ ] precariously trying to get these
shots
get the shots you need get in there take
that shot
then when it's time when it's possible
move that plant somewhere better so you
can put it in front of a good background
put it
about a foot off of the background put
some good lighting on it
then start getting photos there um
lighting lighting lighting lighting is
amazing
the more lighting the better in my
opinion you can't add light to a photo
once you take it you can adjust the
exposure a little bit
but you can't add lighting to a photo
you can take lighting out later
so the more lighting is [ __ ] the
better in my opinion that's what i'm
getting at
lighting lighting lighting light it from
all angles if you can light it from the
bottom up from the back forward from the
front back
the more lighting the better that takes
out your shadows that takes out all the
weirdness
it makes it easier to edit then later on
when you learn photo stacking
uh you've just got so many more options
we're not even going to talk about photo
stacking now that's a whole nother ball
game
shout out to the people who try to teach
me that i just simply don't have the
patience for it
i get it but that's a lot of time you
photographers are crazy
um lighting lighting lighting uh light
that [ __ ] up
uh the 4800 kelvin lighting is beautiful
put a light in front of it
uh maybe take a couple of pictures with
your flash and see what it does take a
couple of pictures without the flash and
see what it does you're gonna notice a
huge difference
if the lighting is not right the flash
is going to give you shadows
see where that shadow lies adjust your
lighting there i've got
two lights in front of me and a light
behind me for this recording
uh the light behind me separates me from
my background i think it gives me a
little bit of depth when you put the
plants
uh to the background and a light between
them it'll provide depth it'll cut out a
bunch of shadows
that'll work really well that's a big
photography secret put a light behind
you
um so the beauty the beauty about
photography now
we've come a long way we're digital
we've got memory cards
back in the day every photo costed you
money costed money is that the
appropriate has cost it a word i don't
know
back in the day every photo was an
expense because
film wasn't free every photo went on to
a piece of film and it had to be
developed in a dark room somebody had to
go develop that film
that got expensive that got time
consuming now it's all digital
now just [ __ ] spray and pray and take
a bunch of shots
take get the angle you want set your
camera up where you want it get your
subject where you want it for this
we're just gonna say that my hand right
here is my subject and my microphone is
my camera get it set up
take a couple of shots chop chop chop
you got the shot you want right now
change the settings
just change one or two settings a couple
of directions take a couple more shots
chop chop chop
change the setting a couple more times
take a couple more then when you're
going through later on and looking at
your photos that one that shines for you
if you've got a good camera the settings
will pop up on the camera and show you
what settings you use to take that photo
now is your chance to grab a pen and
write down those settings and duplicate
those settings the next time you go into
the grow room
just go in there and change that setting
again or
put your camera on auto and go into the
room and take a couple of shots and then
once it's on auto it's going to adjust
itself for you find the setting you want
and then kind of mimic that and play
with it from there later
i like to use the macro mode on the
camera it's the one with a little tiny
flower on it that gets me nice and close
gets me some good close shots
if i'm backing up i generally use that
portrait mode
you'll learn your camera one of the
funnest parts about cameras
and photography is there are no rules uh
the only rules are like don't take
pictures of the wrong person at the
wrong time and don't get yourself in
trouble you [ __ ] creep
but the main part about photography
there's no rules take pictures and have
a good time you're not hurting anything
it doesn't cost you a lot once you've
got the gear
the memory card is in there snap snap
snap take a bunch of shots delete the
ones you don't like repeat the process
get better get more comfortable
eventually you get to where you can just
walk in
you can set up your camera and go oh
look there's the shot that we need and
you take two shots
you move over and you go and you go
thank you guys that was ten thousand
dollars
they pay you ten g's and you go back to
your studio and you edit a couple things
for a couple of seconds and you send
them their
[ __ ] pristine photos it only took you
two shots because you knew exactly what
you were looking for
you developed that photographer's eye
you just look at a shot and you go oh
that looks good right there the way that
plant shines right there the way that
leaf goes that direction in that
direction
you'll learn get this part of the plant
in there and kind of crop this part out
because it makes me want to see more get
just the top of the bud in there and
leave a little top for visual
like you'll start seeing it then you'll
learn the camera setting you'll say oh
there's this much light in here
i want to get this much depth in here i
should use this lens let's go shebang
and you'll take two shots
like a [ __ ] sniper sniper gets one
shot i want two angles
uh we're hitting two targets here so
shot move over shot again
go home make your money so uh i am not a
professional photographer i told you
what i do that's what you asked for
i can't teach you what a professional
photographer does i do not claim to be a
professional photog
ah that is not what i do i'm a guy with
a camera who's passionate about cannabis
who wanted to share those photos with my
friends
and just learned how to take pictures
because of that so i'm gonna make sure
answer the questions
what do you use iphone nikon and a canon
some tips
tips for better social media posts uh
that's a little tiny square what are you
trying to show me in that little tiny
square
if you look at most of my photos i am a
seed
maker who is trying to highlight my seed
brand i'm showing you
ah the colors the textures the trichome
level of the plants that are coming from
my seeds i try to have a good clear
background without a bunch of [ __ ] in
the background
uh good clear solid post that shows you
exactly what you're looking at
then i try to use somewhere between
three and five hashtags if you use the
same hashtag too many times
they'll start blocking that hashtag
they'll shadow ban it it won't get seen
so rotate your hashtags pick three or
five and stick with them
also before you use those hashtags
search them see if they have been shadow
banned or blocked because they're
blocking a lot of
the cannabis community popular hashtags
on social media now
so make sure they aren't blocked also
i've noticed that my stories get viewed
more than my posts so maybe post in your
stories post a post on instagram then
share it to your story
stories and posts with the location
definitely get more views that's
something that i've noticed
um where are we with that tips for more
social media
i think that's what i've got for you for
the best social media post put in my
tester application is there anything i
could do
to improve my chances right now i'm
taking a break from selecting testers
because i've got uh
i'm in over my head i got a lot going on
and i don't want to commit to sending
out a bunch of test seeds to people
right now i've got enough out there i'm
getting reports
i've got enough going on but uh i've got
you written down i know who you are now
you are now on my radar
radar when it comes time to selecting
testers your name does look familiar
that does help you out a lot and i also
now i know that you're on patreon
that does help out a lot as well uh
jethro earl thank you bro you gave me a
good question to ramble on
i hope i answered some questions
honestly i think honesty is the best
policy
i am not a trained educated skilled
photographer
uh i am just i'm an idiot with a lot of
experience to be quite honest with you
uh i just did it until i figured it out
i failed a few times but
the best part about failing with
photography is all you got to do is
delete a couple photos nothing went
wrong
just wasted some space on a memory card
a couple of flashes on the flash is all
so um yeah get experience to get there
and take pictures and then watch the
settings that work for you
modify repeat adjust and adapt and most
importantly dude have fun with it
have fun we've all been programmed and
brainwashed
to make all of our posts look exactly
the same for social media when we scroll
through social media
it all looks basically the same there's
a little we've all got the same
filters there's like a little we're all
we've all fallen into an algorithm
accidentally to make our photos
pleasing and appealing for social media
get away from that have fun take
pictures of what you love
snap the images that you see that's what
that's the beauty of the camera you've
got the camera you get to capture
what you see so get it the best you can
uh it's like playing an instrument
when i first got drums i didn't know how
to say what i was thinking on the drums
i would think booker took attack
doom
on top of it and i can think it and play
it now eventually
you'll get the same way with your camera
you'll say oh i see that shot i want to
get lighting here i want to get these
colors i want this texture
hit these buttons turn this knob zoom in
chip chop you got it you're ready to go
so bro thank you for the great question
it is time for me to wrap up this long
episode of the grow from your heart
podcast i want to thank you for hanging
out i had fun recording this episode
uh this wrap-up portion of the show is
brought to you by my friend adhd grower
big shout out to my buddy adhd grower we
don't have corporate sponsors here at
the grow from your heart podcast
we've got friends and family that
support us and i want to make sure to
give them some shout outs
if you feel like this episode was
educational informative and or
entertaining
maybe you like to just throw me a couple
of bucks because i taught you something
or made you laugh a couple of times
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need is right
there on the screen and again there is a
link
in the show notes and the video
description to make it nice and easy
for all of my friends if you have got
any questions corrections comments or
concerns
i would love to hear from you the email
address for the podcast is grow from
your heart
at hotmail.com once again we do have a
website
iregenetics.com all things ire genetics
all things grow from your heart all
things rosta jeff are listed right there
at iregenetics.com please do check it
out
that is all i've got for you for this
episode i want to thank you once again
for listening to a long episode of the
grow from your heart podcast
i want to give a big shout out to my
buddy north north terps and until next
time take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you