[Music]
yeah welcome to the show podcast world
i'm your host my friends call me rasta
jeff and this
is episode 645 of the grow from your
heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to focus on
grow questions before we get to those
grow questions
let's do a few shout outs to a few of
the kind folks who support the show on
patreon
let's start it off with the big grow
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out
to frankie let's send a big thank you
shout out to just a smoking and mr mean
green i want to send a big thank you
shout out to 716 vibes and blackhawks
fan
let's send a big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to noah n
and godfather kush i want to send a big
fist bump and a shout out to my buddy og
purple thumb
let's send a big thank you shout out to
a longtime supporter and a good friend
jesse grows
let's send a big thank you shout out to
levity loveday and then let's wrap this
part of the show up with the big grow
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out
to my friend learnin and burnin
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who supports the show on
patreon
if you are not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need is right
there on the screen and of course there
is a link in the show notes
and the video description to make it
nice and easy for
all of my friends ladies and gentlemen
boys and girls welcome to the show it
was a beautiful day today i hope it was
beautiful
wherever you are wherever you were
hanging out today whatever you were
doing i hope you had a wonderful day
i want to talk about this weather this
weather had people out and about people
are getting ready
for their outdoor grow i went to the
groce store today and the grow store
was super busy there were a lot of
people in there
uh some people wearing masks some people
not wearing masks
uh i said masks weird uh anyway
some people seem to have decided that
the pandemic is over some are still
participating
i'm not going down that avenue in this
uh conversation just notice that people
are
crowding the stores places are getting
busy at the grow store one thing i did
notice
[ __ ] is out of stock they did not have a
lot of the products i went for
um they didn't have the the first choice
products i went for i've always got a
backup plan they did not have the
soilless mix i prefer to buy they did
not have the base nutrients i wanted to
buy they didn't have a pesticide i was
looking for
they were out of rapid rooters it was
slim pickens at the grow store today it
was like all the b and c
rate products were on the shelf and all
the a-rate [ __ ] has been bought it has
been taken
uh they were waiting for trucks they did
not know when [ __ ] was coming i went to
another store
same story over there i really think all
the [ __ ] was on the same truck going to
all of the gross stores
they're waiting the [ __ ] is just not
coming so um you guys have a backup plan
is what i'm getting at if you were out
there shopping for grow supplies if you
were stubborn about what you use in the
grow
this is not gonna be the season for you
whether you're growing indoors or
outdoors you're going to need to be
flexible
because this covets situation the
pandemic the quarantine
all the weird shutdowns and [ __ ] have
made supplies
scarce they're more expensive they're
harder to get and it's going to take you
a little longer to get the things you're
sourcing if you can even find
your favorite products you may need to
find a backup plan uh get a
the second product that thing you've
been wondering if it works now may be
the time
for you to find out if that [ __ ] works
which could work out sometimes that's
how you find out that that other product
is better or
did something you didn't know it did
maybe you'll find some cool
[ __ ] but have a backup plan you guys if
you've got an outdoor grow coming up
go get your [ __ ] now don't wait because
[ __ ] is selling out
literally the guanos were selling out
[ __ ] was flying off the shelves
uh the fish [ __ ] was gone all of the uh
the mammoth pee all that [ __ ] it's all
gone off the shelves right now you guys
at least in my location so get on it get
yourself
some supplies while i was at the groce
store
i was asked a question i did take a
little bit of a note here on my phone
i'm not texting anybody i'm not hanging
out
on any chat i'm actually reading a
message on the phone i did take some
notes
at the grow store i got asked can you
explain why
transplanting a plant is a good idea
this person wanted to they were
wondering
uh the word that i want to use is
graduating the pots they wanted to just
go from
a paper towel when they germinate their
seed into their big seven gallon finish
or pot
and they were asking me why i recommend
up potting from
a small container to a medium-sized
maybe bigger then into that seven
uh i would do it a couple of different
ways depending on the time space
environment the requirements for the
room there are a lot of different
challenges and things we would face here
but they were asking uh how and why uh
we would go about doing different pot
sizes
why do we do that why wouldn't i just
put my seedling this little tiny
seedling into a seven gallon pot
filled with soilless mix or cocoa or
whatever we've chosen to use why can't i
just go into the straight pot
you can but think about all of the water
it's going to take to water that big pot
you don't need to use that much water
you could put that seedling and time
inside of a little teeny tiny pot and
you only have to water that little
section which gives you less opportunity
for
over watering you're gonna have less
space
to disrupt you're not gonna have to pour
a gallon of water in there you can just
pour a little bit of water in there and
that seedling will get the water that it
needs also
that's that much less cocoa that you
have to use right now if you don't need
that much cocoa
you don't have to buy that much cocoa so
you don't have to
put a little seedling in a big pot then
you're not going to risk over
watering it that's one of the main
issues over watering in that big pot
will be easy
because how much water what how much of
that big pot do i need to water you're
going to try to just water that little
space right there but then the roots are
going to grow and you're always going to
be chasing it
i start off honestly you've seen me do
my clones in a beer cup
i start off in a beer cup or a four or
six inch net pot is what i will start a
seedling in
i'll let it grow in there until it
becomes nearly root bound i want it
just pressing up against the walls there
i want the roots to say hey it is time
for some new shoes before they get new
shoes
so another reason i like that is a
faster wet and dry time i don't like my
plants staying wet for too long i like
them
uh not like dry but i don't want them
soggy the whole time i want there to be
availability for oxygen in that root
space when they dry out a little bit
there's room for air when there's too
much water in there
the water takes all the space where the
oxygen would be and the plants don't get
as much air i think
oxygen to the root space really
encourages root growth happy plants they
eat more they feed better
they perform better so a smaller pot
gives me a little bit
of a faster wet and dry cycle and in a
smaller pot that's good because i just
want those
roots to grow i want the plants to grow
so i can get them into their bigger pots
sooner so we've got these little plants
put them in a little cup put them in a
little pot
um water them less often also if you're
watering less space
you're wasting less nutrients you don't
have to mix up as much food
you're not going to water a 7 gallon pot
worth of space and only get the middle
you could have mixed up a little bit and
just watered that one small cup
so i think starting off small i would
start with a cup
excuse me i'd start with a cup and then
work my way into maybe a one gallon or a
three gallon and then that three gallon
would either go into a five or a seven
so i do a cup or a one or a cup into a
one and then that one
or the cup into the three gallon or into
the five gallon or the three gallon into
a seven i kind of just work my way up
i don't like to go uh too big too fast i
like him to grow in there and get a
little bit root bound i was saying i
want them
kind of pushing the edge i want them
like if they were a size 13
shoe i want them in a 12 and a half like
i want to be like hey bro can i get my
13s and then we'll upgrade them right
when they're ready
and then when i take them out of the pot
i kind of uh from the bottom i put my
fingers
into the bottom of the root zone and
just spread it out a little bit
so that it looks like you just blew the
bottom of that plant right up and people
like well you just [ __ ] up your roots
yes i did
and when i pot it into the next pot that
[ __ ] up root section is going to be
the most explosive root section in that
whole pot that part's going to go oh he
gave us a little opening
because right now the roots are kind of
tight they're wrapped around inside that
cup
i reached in there and pulled them apart
a little bit and gave them a little
space and that space is where the roots
are going to go
let's grow and they're going to take off
they're going to explode so i let them
get a little bit
tight in their early pot they want new
shoes they're begging for new kicks
before i put them in there
as soon as they get their new kicks they
take off running remember when you gave
a new little kid new shoes
or when you gave a little kid new shoes
he thought he could run faster the
plants are going to do the same
damn thing so you have less chance for
over watering
um they dry down more quickly you get to
water them more frequently if you get a
quicker dry and wet time more feeding
more watering time i like that
commercial grower i like that i let them
get tight that way when you up pot them
they do go a little bit more quickly
they take off
then here's another great thing in my
grow space
uh in a commercial environment or in
most places where uh we aren't super
limited by numbers
uh space is valuable and if i've got
a little tiny plant that is six inches
tall in
a seven gallon pot which i'm going to
guess is about 18 inches in diameter
i am wasting a lot of space
i can put those plants into smaller pots
and i can push them together
much closer which does a couple of
things i bought a lot more space which
means i've got room for a lot more
plants
uh keep in mind those are gonna get up
potted into bigger pots later and you'll
have to put them into the flower room
and they will take up more space but if
you're dividing rooms and they're going
multiple places you need more room for
more pots
smaller pots while you can is not a bad
idea
then if you're taking up less floor
space
with plants that means we can probably
turn off a couple of lights
if those plants are able to be moved
over to one side of the room and they
all fit
underneath two or three lights instead
of running all six or eight lights in
that room
you can save yourself that much
electricity the lights are on for
at least 18 hours a day in this
environment because we got small veg
plants we want them on eighteen six or
more
running one or two lights at that rate
is going to cost a little bit of money i
don't care if you're a commercial
environment
a home grow that will add up quite
quickly because along with that light
every light that's running you've got
a little bit of air conditioning going
you probably got a fan going
there's a dehumidifier every light adds
more equipment don't just think that
you're paying for that light when the
light runs
because there's a fan going with that
light there's something that goes along
with it to keep it cool
keep it comfortable the light creates
heat we got to move the heat then we
move the heat we create humidity you got
to get rid of the humidity
so many things happen because of that
light so don't just consider the cost of
the light
it's you're saving a lot of other things
when you turn off that light
so uh move those those big seven gallon
pots they're like 18 inches around i
think i'm i'm guessing i'm a drummer i
guess they're about 18 inches i'm
looking at 18 inch floor tom next to me
uh probably about 16 18 inches around
a three gallon pot i think is about 12
inches around when you look at that in a
grow room you can fit
uh three to four three gallon pots in
the space
of two seven gallon pots if you do it
right so save you a lot of room move
them closer together if you're doing one
gallon pots and get a bunch in there
don't cram the plants in so tight that
they're pushing on each other give them
space but i'm saying
don't waste a bunch of space in your
grow environment that's why
i would start with smaller pots uh start
off in a cup
or a one gallon pot or a net pot and
then as soon as it starts to get tight
in there and that plant's getting a
little bit bigger
that's when i put it into my next pot
now it has gone officially
in my labeling system from small veg to
its
vegetative stage now it's actually in
veg it's vegging it's not small veg it's
veg and then the next stage is like
we're about to flower these [ __ ]
that's when they get lollipopped and
cleaned up and start getting really
worked but
um yeah transplant them that way you can
save yourself space
save nutrients save water save soil you
can save lighting by pushing the plants
closer together by saving lighting
you're saving electricity by saving
electricity you were saving
a lot of money um i think i covered that
one that was a pretty good ramble on for
what was meant to be just a really quick
topic there so yeah graduated pot size i
do encourage you
to work your way up from a smaller pot
to a bigger pot to your final
destination pot which you do choose to
flower in
you don't want the plants to get root
bound if they do get root bound some
plants may panic on you they may start
to flower they'll stop
feeding they'll look really pissed off
it'll be confusing like why are these
plants doing this weird [ __ ] they're
root bound
they want to go into a bigger pot when
you up pot every time i up pot
i like to sprinkle a little bit of
microbe product either around the roots
of the plant that i'm potting or into
the hole in which it is getting potted
so i pull that pot that plant out of the
pot
the container i can see my white roots
on the outside of that dirt
just holding all that dirt together i'll
get a root product or a
mico product and just dust the outside
of it just sprinkle it
i'll turn that pot with my hand just
spin it and i'll just use a little cup
and just sprinkle some of the microbes
on there
and then i pot it on there there are
already microbes on that root zone
telling those roots hey bro go crazy
life is gonna be good in here
as soon as you put some water on it all
that [ __ ] activates it goes crazy
those plants go shabang kapow
all right i think i talked long enough
about that part let me read an email
that i've got here in front of me or
this podcast is going to get out of
control
long um big shout out to all my friends
at the grow store it's a good time
hanging out at the grow store i
apologize for
if i seemed rude because i was in a
hurry today i was simply
in a [ __ ] hurry today i was trying to
get a lot done and they didn't have what
i needed so that meant i had to go to
more
stores i was trying to be rude i had
[ __ ] to do
all right this one is not the one i'm
looking for is this the message i need
here we go this is the message i need
right here
excuse me for clearing the throat this
one says hey ross to jeff before my
question
i just wanted to shout you out and thank
you for all you do for the grow
community
i love the show because other podcasts
don't stay informational
and they can be hard to consume and
they're time consuming
and it's hard learning this process i
love the straightforward info and down
to business approach so
thank you ah that's a great compliment
that i try to i try
to stay on subject i try to stay on
point i do got the add and i also try to
have fun
but i also try to include you and make
you feel like you're hanging out i can
almost pass you the joint you know what
i'm saying if i had a joint right here i
could almost
i want you to feel like you're right
there you can almost smell the smoke i
want you hanging out with me so i'm glad
you feel like you're uh
learning from me and i'm glad you feel
like i stay on point
and uh yeah uh i stay informational
i used to talk about the comedy shows i
used to go to and [ __ ] sometimes i talk
about what i do but i try to talk about
just growing and not
not talk too much about myself on the
show now but i do want you to feel like
you're hanging out because we are we are
friends
uh let me get to the point here it says
my question and thank you for the
compliments dude it says my question
i'm running a 9x7 tent with two 1000
watt
mar mars hydro ts lights uh carbon
filter we got some details in here i'm
growing at three five and seven gallon
pots normally only running
three to five pots at a time i only use
fox farm ocean forest
and i always grow 100 organically i'm
using down to earth dry fertilizers
and bat guano i also add fish [ __ ] every
feed as well
so we got the down to earth dry ferts uh
bone meal
uh bat guano and fish [ __ ] every feed
uh each of my first five grows has
taught me new things and how to solve
different problems
the grow might have that is that's a
great thing to notice that every grow
you've solved a problem and gotten a
little bit better
none of your grows are going to be
problem free every grove is going to
have some sort of obstacle or hurdle an
issue to deal with
it's learning to deal with those
obstacles and eliminate them and not go
into panic mode i've seen growers i've
done it myself
you see an issue and you go oh [ __ ]
there's a problem all the alarms go off
in your head you [ __ ] pull the rip
cord you got to do all this dumb [ __ ] to
solve the problem
when really all you needed to do was go
take a dab or go smoke a [ __ ] joint
and really think clearly about how to
fix it needle went oh you know that's a
dumb problem i can solve this overnight
you don't get panic mode so quickly
because you realize that these plants
are fixable problems are solvable
so as long as you're learning something
with every grow you're making great
progress
let me find my spot here there we are my
spot on this message says
but i seem to be lacking in the nutrient
knowledge and the dry and cure stage
because before harvest the plants smell
amazing
and have a nice dense consistency but
after dry and cured the buds are airy
and light and have no
density there are a few things that can
be causing that i wrote that down
could be a lot of stuff adding up to
cause that
it goes on to say i have yet to have my
product smell or taste even close to
what it's like before i chop them down i
have a couple ideas why that's happening
as well
i've listened to your dry and cure
episode and other reliable sources but i
uh seem to not be able to translate that
knowledge i soak up into physically and
visually understanding this process
i have a hygrometer in the dry and cure
area but unfortunately i'm not
able to keep that area 100 dark that
dark isn't 100 crucial
but i do keep the humidity under 50
percent let's try to get that to about
50 or 60 percent
and make your product take just a little
bit longer to dry may help you out
uh what could be the main reason for my
airy buds and loss of aroma
thanks again ross to jeff for all the
information and time you have given
you give every day to home growers
learning
one love from and then i'm not sure if
they want their name said we're just
going to call him kyle today big shout
out to kyle thank you for the great
message bro
i do have some answers here i think i
can help you out a little bit
let me start with the disclaimer because
i like to do this uh organic growing
is not my specialty i straight up am a
bottled
nutrient grower i grow with new
millennium bottled nutrients sometimes i
add some products from veg bloom
or hydroponic research is the company
but most of what i'm growing
is non-organic i'm a salt-based grower
i find it easier in a commercial
environment to train a crew
to write a standard operating procedure
to have repeatable results results
by using bottled nutrients i love the
organics i love the idea i love the
passion
i love the sustainability but the way i
know how to grow
the goal for my commercial facilities
that i'm hired to help with
the goal that the owners have i think
that a
bottled nutrient system is the way to go
for my style it's repeatable it's
sustainable
i know how to do it the organics i don't
understand how to make it
repeatable and sustainable i don't
trainable for a crew i need to write
down instructions that can be done
by anybody when i'm gone
i think organics uh there are a lot of
variables that we would have to
have some hands-on experience and some
eyes to think about a little bit too
much
with the bottled nutrients i say 20 of
this 50 of this 20 of that and every
time we feed it it is the same
thing with organics you can get some
variables in there ah this is
my thought process on the whole thing so
i'm not an organic grower
that part is not my area of expertise so
when it comes to your nutrient knowledge
lacking i as well am lacking nutrients
knowledge in this department because i
don't do the organic stuff i understand
the nutrients i understand the elements
i understand the way the plants feed
but i'm doing it a little bit
differently than you are so i may not
have all of the answers when it comes to
the nutrient part
but um also i'm not sure if that is
enough
light in this room i'm not sure of the
spread of that light it could be enough
light but what i'm learning about leds
is they don't spread a lot we need more
spread on these leds i'm not complaining
i'm just saying that's what i'm learning
so
i'm wondering if you've got like one
section with a lot of light and the rest
of the room isn't getting a lot of light
because that'll help
uh more light spread around more proper
light would help with intensity
would help with bud density is what i'm
getting at so
one thing i would recommend to start
with and i don't know that this is doing
it i am uh
i'm guessing and assuming based on the
information i've got i'm trying to give
useful information
are you trellising are you using a net
to hold down the main tops if you've got
one top that's sticking up
that light is hitting this one we've
talked about this before that bud's
getting really hot but the rest of the
plants down here aren't getting the
intense light that they could
trellis this one down then the light
will hit all of the buds and all of the
buds will have a chance to be more dense
you won't have
tops that are real nice real tight kind
of good and then bottoms that are
shittier you'll have
a bunch of decent buds at the top maybe
they'll tighten up for you if you do
that that's just one idea
um i was looking at your nutrients a
little bit maybe a kelp
product in there would help you out i
don't know when you're feeding what
but i know that kelp products do help
with stank and density in my opinion in
my
experience a kelp product would help you
out there are plenty
of organic kelp products which you can
mix into your soil to begin with
or you can find a liquid kelp product
which you can feed in later
or you can find a kelp product that you
can foliar feed
uh you're trying to go organic so you're
going to have to do your research on
those products but that is a good start
for those ideas uh airy buds
is that that's probably grow
and cure related but we're gonna say it
starts in the grow there are a lot of
things that can be giving you
airy buds have you tried multiple
genetics the genetics have a lot to do
with that
if you're growing something that's from
a tropical environment that's meant to
be real airy because it gets humid there
and they need some airflow in those buds
that bud naturally just is not going to
be real dense if you're growing some og
kush
some chem dog and it's not getting dense
that is a room
or a feed issue there's a problem there
so let's check the genetics that's
something i would check on then
light is there enough light in that room
honestly i'm not familiar with the mars
hydro light
i don't know if that's enough uh
lighting i don't know if that's enough
wattage and i don't know the spread on
that light in that size of a room
i honestly don't know but that's
something we can check on something we
could investigate
that's one of the things on the list i
would eliminate to see if that is the
problem
is there enough light and like i
mentioned you have that one bud right in
the light is that bud good are you
trellising it down to get the light
everywhere
are you defoliating to get that light
further down into the canopy and get
some light penetration that may help you
out as well
something that does make uh fluffy buds
that will make the buds
actually fluff out and become airy and
be not as dense as they could
is environmental factors like too much
heat
think about in the summer um when it
gets too hot
you don't want even in the summer you
don't want your own hands resting on
your legs
your hands get all sweaty where your
hands are resting on your legs the
plants are just like that
they're gonna go hey calyx stacking on
top of me i don't want you up there and
they're just gonna start spreading and
getting fluffy
uh when it gets too hot they're just
trying to spread their legs so they're
not getting hot between their legs
the plants are doing the same thing like
bro it's too hot i'm trying to spread
out a little bit
those plants are doing the same thing
it's too hot it's too humid it's too
sticky the plants feel funky
instead of being dense they're getting
fluffy also they know if they get too
dense all that moisture will build up
inside of those buds
and if it's too humid in there all that
moisture will create a problem you'll
get boitritis or powdery mildew inside
of your buds
so um heat moisture things like that
could be causing you problems also a
drastic diurnal swing if you're getting
uh too hot at night or too cold in the
day or opposite or
more than eight to 12 degrees change
from day to night temperature
that can play a role in your fluffy buds
another thing the feeding if you're not
feeding properly if they're not getting
the food that they need
and they're not getting the nutrients
just imagine if you didn't eat proper
food you wouldn't build up the way you
needed to either
i'm a skinny dude i eat a pretty good
vegetarian diet
i look like a stick figure brock lesnar
is my height
but about three times my width in
density he eats a totally different diet
than me
he eats a high performance [ __ ] high
protein
rip your head off [ __ ] down your throat
kind of diet your plants may be needing
that brock lesnar diet
you may be giving them the rasta jeff
pasta and carbohydrate diet so
maybe it's diet i read what you're
giving them but i don't know exactly
how much of that and i don't know
exactly what's in all of those products
so you may need to add a couple of
things to boost that up a kelp product
maybe a bloom booster i don't know
exactly i made the disclaimer dude i
don't know exactly what you're doing
with these
organic nutrients i don't know what i'm
doing with your organic nutrients
so it could be a feed issue um i wrote
down trellis make sure you get more a
more consistent canopy
i've talked about that that even canopy
will help you out that way the light
will get to all of the buds
you won't have some dense some fluffy we
call the fluffy buds larf that stuff on
the bottom
that's larfey crap i usually pinch that
off it doesn't even make it to the
flower area
nobody wants to trim that that's junk uh
pinch that [ __ ] off if the light's not
getting down there get that off
let's try to move some of the energy to
the actual
bud part of the plants this should make
the buds tighter
more dense um so
that is what i think could be happening
during the grow
that is making the aroma and the density
lack in these plants
the second part is probably in the
dry and cure process something is
happening during the harvest time
light degrades terpenes heat degrades
terpenes
are these plants getting too warm are
you able to give them
a period of dark and cool for
12 to 24 hours before you harvest them
that may
that'll give you so the overnight while
the plants are sleeping in the dark and
the cool they will produce they
produce that word came out really weird
i hope i get some comments on that they
will
produce a bunch of terpenes right
they'll produce terps all night long
while they're sleeping
in that cool dark environment when you
start turning on lights and heat
those terps start getting uh they start
volatizing they start getting uh
degrading they start getting destroyed
so if you can get it cool and dark in
there for a while build up as many terps
as possible
give yourself a head start keep it cool
the whole time you're drying and
trimming it
try not to handle it too much uh try not
to touch it too much during the trim
process and the defoliation process
um you might be drying too quickly maybe
let's slow down the drying process a
little bit just a little tiny bit
you said you're keeping it about 50
humidity let's go about 60 and slow that
drying cure time
down just a little bit i know that
sounds crazy you want to smoke your
product but
you want to smoke a better product is
that dry and cure room cold enough if
it's colder the buds will get
tighter as they dry up if it's not cold
enough they're not gonna do that
um is it too dry in there is it too hot
in the dry and cure room that's gonna
[ __ ] up your product
is there wind in there the wind could be
blowing
your buds just drying drying them right
off it's just blowing the terps right
out
think about when you ride a motorcycle
or if you go out on the boat or if you
hang out in the wind all day
your lips are all chapped [ __ ] your
skin feels all dry
these plants if they're in the wind
hanging and drying in the wind or if
there's too much airflow in the dry room
they're doing the same thing all your
terps all your moisture it just got
sucked right out of the room
it's all in the room that's why your
herb smells like hay so i really think
that slowing down the drying and curing
process could help you out just go a
little bit slower
and if you're not getting um like a
an ammonia um an acrid pissy kind of
aroma
you're not trapping too much moisture in
there and you're not sealing it up too
early so i don't think that you're not
ruining it you're not giving you're not
getting the opportunity to ruin it i
think it may just be drying
too quickly for you uh so i would check
all the things we talked about in the
grow
is there proper lighting are you taking
care of the genetics the trellising the
heat the feed
humidity is the lights air water soil
the laws that's
laws l-a-w-s you guys have you thought
about that if i taught you that
i think i learned it from subcool i want
to give somebody credit because i think
it's uh
it's polite and important for a teacher
to give credit where you learn [ __ ] i
didn't learn everything i didn't make it
all up i think i learned
laws lights air water and soil i think i
learned that from subcool
are you following all of the laws if all
the laws are in line
then let's check out the dry and cure
tech we may need to just slow it down a
little bit
increase the humidity lower the
temperature may help you out just get it
slowed down just a little bit my last
note on this subject
is where are you drying and curing this
product are you doing it in the basement
are you doing it
under the grow lights where is this
happening if you dry and cure your
product
in a funky scented basement your product
will get
funky basement terps to it if you're
drying it in the bathroom it's going to
pick up bathroom terps
so that may be something that's going on
so for tighter more
dense more aroma i'm really thinking
it's going to be a slower drying cure
at a lower temperature that's going to
help you out
um maybe send me some pictures of the
plants right before you cut them
send me some pictures of your harvest
process let me know how you're
harvesting drying and curing
and maybe i can give you some more
advice more guidance maybe we can give
the listeners a little bit of a
follow-up
all right kyle i hope i answered your
question i hope i gave you some useful
info
again i'm not an expert in the organics
so i wasn't exactly sure where to start
but i feel like we got you
a little bit a little bit of info to get
you moving some stuff to check on
some adjustments to make i do look
forward to the update
uh ladies and gentlemen boys and girls
pimps and hoes friends foes smokers
growers clone cutters pollen chuckers
thank you for listening to this episode
if anybody out there has any grow
questions i would love to answer those
questions on the show for you the email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
also i've got a website my website is
iriegenetics.com
on that website there is a tab that says
grow help
if you click on that grow help tab
you'll be taken to a little
questionnaire
we ask you nine or ten questions they're
very basic question what kind of lights
are you using
what strain are you growing are you
growing indoors or outdoors
just the basic [ __ ] that will help me
answer your questions that way i get
some details about your grow
i can build a can paint an image of your
grow in my head that way when it comes
time to answer the question
all the details i need are right there
so if you hit that grow help tab
answer a few questions at the bottom it
says explain your problem simply tell me
what the [ __ ] is wrong with your plants
and i will read it i'll do my best to
answer your question thoroughly
here on the podcast i do appreciate all
of the listener interaction
uh this lets me know that i'm helping
somebody i know that we at least helped
kyle today
and if we're helping kyle there's
probably somebody else out there with
the same question the same problem
just a numbers game if one person asks
there's probably a lot of people out
there that i can help with the same
question so i do appreciate
the listener generated content thank you
and thank you for listening
if you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
maybe you'd just like to throw me a
couple of bucks because i made you
giggle or taught you a couple of things
all you have to do is visit
forward www.patreon.com grow from your
heart all of the information you need to
support the podcast is right there on
the screen
once again big thank you and big up to
everybody who has continued to support
the podcast
i think that is all i've got for you for
this episode i think i'm just running
out of camera time as well
so it is a good time to wrap up this
podcast thanks for listening
i'll be back in just a couple of days i
want to give a big shout out to my buddy
dave's not here and until next time take
a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]