yeah welcome to the show podcast world
i'm your host my friends call me rasta
jeff
and this is episode 604
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to read a couple
of patreon questions
before we get to that part of the show
let's do a few shout outs to a few of
the kind folks who support the show on
patreon
let's start off with the big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to my friend ryan waters i want to send
a big thank you shout out to thomas
mcginnis and frugal rock
let's send a thank you shout out to the
big sexy dank and adhd grower
i want to send a big thank you shout out
to stash drop 269 and caribou heart tv
let's send a big thank you to pac
northwest den and girls grow too
and then let's wrap it all up with the
big grow from your heart podcast thank
you shout out
to our friend tartan mike big thanks and
big shout out to everybody
who continues to support the show on
patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need is right
there on the screen and of course there
is a link in the show notes and the
video description
to make it nice and easy for all of my
friends welcome to the show everybody
let's start off with a couple of
uh internet questions i have received
from youtube
and from a couple of emails real quick
here people have been asking
why i don't smoke on the show that is a
very good question
it's a cannabis based show i talk about
smoking a lot
a lot of times i tell you what i just
smoked but why don't i smoke on the show
that's a very good
question first of all i smoked plenty
right before the show i take a couple of
fat dabs i set up these lights i set up
the camera
then i take a couple more dabs and make
sure everything's all rocking and
rolling
do a quick little mic check then i start
recording once i get my voice recovered
so i get plenty dabbed out before i
start the show there's no need to stop
talking
and take a couple of dabs and that gets
me to my second reason uh there's no
reason to stop
talking and take dabs i'm plenty lit i'm
here to
teach you guys and give you a quality
podcast if i stop and take a dab or
smoke a bowl in the middle
uh that would probably uh take away from
the quality of the show it would
definitely
derail my focus so i just try to stay
focused and keep smoking you notice when
i do have a guest when mike is on or
somebody else is here
when they're talking i do puff a little
bit but my intention for that is to keep
my uh
my hands busy i got atd and i don't know
what to do with my hands
so i'm just keeping my hands moving when
other people are here on the show also
it helps me to stay calm and not
interrupt
so much if i'm smoking a lot of times my
add tells me to chime in and say
something that's unnecessary
but i found that if i let a guest talk
they'll tell me what i want to know i
don't really need to interrupt so
i smoke while they're talking that's
when i do smoke
the main reason i don't smoke though
honestly is because youtube
sometimes will flag a video with
consumption i am more likely
to get my videos taken down my videos
flagged something disrupted by youtube
because of consumption in the video so
i'm doing my best
to keep these videos up on youtube keep
the channel clean
that is my main reason honestly for not
mass consumption here on the channel
you never know we may have a multiple
person show here in the future where we
just bust out and smoke a lot but for
the most part
i don't smoke because uh dabbing and
smoking gives me the
that in my throat and nobody wants that
[ __ ] in a podcast also i'm here to teach
you
i'm here to stay focused i mean here to
just keep talking you don't want to
watch me maybe you do want to watch me
smoke but that'll be my next point
i'm trying to give you a quality podcast
without getting the channel deleted is
my main reason why i don't smoke on the
show
the next point if you do want to hang
out and watch me smoke
join me on instagram live that's right
monday
at 7 10 p.m mountain time i'm here in
the colorado time zone i don't know what
time zone
you are in you will have to adjust but
monday
afternoon monday evening i guess it is
at 7 pm
mountain time around 7 10 p.m i jump on
sometime between 7 and 7 15. it's
usually about 7
10 i jump on instagram live my instagram
is ire
underscore genetics i r i e underscore
then you can spell genetics iriegenetics
on instagram if you give me a follow
there
every monday approximately 7 10 p.m i
hop on instagram live
i try to say hi to everybody that comes
into the live feed every name i see pop
in i try to say hello i try to greet you
people come in my door i try to say
what's up to you personally sometimes
instagram doesn't show me that you
popped in sometimes it'll say
uh let's see ryan waters and seven other
people have popped in and i can't say hi
to seven other because i don't know who
you are
so i just give you a shout out when you
come in but uh on that instagram live
show
i will smoke plenty of dabs i will read
all of the comments
i will answer a bunch of questions and i
will smoke a bunch of dabs we listen to
music we hang out we talk [ __ ]
and it is a good smoke session and a
hangout session is nowhere
nowhere near as formal as this podcast
it's all freestyle it is all
on the fly the questions are all just
shot to me randomly i try to answer them
all
so my point here if you want to hang out
and smoke with me if you want to watch
me smoke take fat dabs get too stoned i
get silly you guys i
i really get chilled out on that show i
smoke until i have to stop and go get
food
so uh monday nights on instagram give me
a follow on the instagram
i re underscore genetics leads me to one
more segway
ire the word is ire a lot of people call
it eerie genetics that's cool if you
want to call it irri it is a
little creepy but the word is irie irie
is a jamaican word
uh it means to just feel the best you
could feel to mean it means to feel
blessed and just good just feeling irie
you know when you're sitting uh for me
it's like uh on a hill
just a nice hillside with a little
breeze coming toward me a nice grassy
hill you know when you sit in the grass
the grass is just naturally cool
no matter how hot it is outside that
grass just feels good and cool on your
body you put your feet
your bare feet in that grass rub your
toes in the grass your butt's on the
grass
i got clothes on guys don't worry you
got clothes on but my butt's on the
grass i got my palms
touching that grass it's nice and cool
and i'm just sitting there i got a
little bit of breeze blowing my
dreadlocks out of my face
uh the sun is just right so you're just
kind of like damn it's bright but you're
not squinting and dying from it
and you're just maybe overlooking some
water maybe you got your dog next to you
maybe you got your
your partner with you maybe your best
friend maybe your lover maybe your
boyfriend girlfriend
maybe it's a unicorn it's [ __ ] 20 21
you could have whatever you want next to
you that makes you feel the happiest you
feel
that feeling right there when you're
just chilling maybe you got a white claw
in your hand because it's 20 21 i'm
drinking a kombucha you do what you want
but
that is feeling irie just when you feel
good
when the reggae music is playing at the
concert and you're just bobbing your
head and everybody's bobbing their head
and the smoke's in the air
and the sun is setting behind the stage
and the reggae stars are dancing
and the lights are popping up off the
stage and you're just like yeah
that feeling that is irie that's what
irie means
irie i'm sure you've heard it in reggae
music you've heard it in jamaican music
if you've gone to a reggae show the
reggae singer has said the word irie
because they are feeling irie they're
making you feel irie
so i've said it enough times it's not
eerie the word is irie
i read genetics cause i'm inspired by a
lot of rastafari jamaican culture you'll
also find a lot of grateful dead
references in my strained names anyway
i wanted to say i read genetics find me
on instagram
uh that was a long ramble about the word
irie but we gotta gotta teach the people
now another question i get often asked
is
why is the podcast age restricted
because i'm trying to keep the channel
uh i talk about cannabis i say the f
word i drop a lot of [ __ ] profane
language on here
i tried to edit myself back in the day
but i found that uh i say [ __ ] and
there's no reason to cut that out that's
just something that i say so it's gonna
be in the podcast therefore we must make
it um it's got to be
what's the word age restricted also i'm
talking about cannabis
uh people who are under the age of 18
probably
uh i don't know maybe they shouldn't be
learning about cannabis right away it's
not it's somebody's
it's their parents responsibility until
they're 18 to teach them about cannabis
the day after that i'll teach you
everything you want to know but
um until then it's your parents
responsibility to teach you that's the
technical legal [ __ ] right
so that's why it's age restricted on
youtube i want to keep the channel
i don't need little kids seeing the
channel and leaving comments and telling
their mom hey i want to take dabs and be
like rosta jeff
that would be [ __ ] weird so we keep
it age restricted for the adults all
you've got to do
is change on your google account change
your age to over 18.
you better be 18 if you do that wink
wink but all you've got to do is go put
in your birthday and change it and it
will let you
sign in somebody told me that youtube
wanted their credit card bro you're
doing something wrong
youtube does not want your credit card
you're probably not even seeing this
because you couldn't get that far
but uh youtube is age restricted because
i want to keep my channel you guys if it
were not age restricted little kids saw
this
might get me in trouble not in trouble
just get the channel taken down and i
want you
to be able to watch the show we tried to
post the videos other places and
it doesn't get any views and it just
sucks for loading it takes too long so
we're just going to do it on the youtube
we got to keep the channel all right
i've been rambling for quite some time
we have not gotten to the main
cannabis portion of this podcast i've
got some great questions from me
this question came from the patreon
channel this question comes from our
friend
they want their name said they said it
right in the email so we're just gonna
start by reading it
it says actually i think i have two
similar
yeah we got two emails with the same
question that's why we're gonna do this
the first one comes from it says what's
up roster jeff we got papa z here
you are welcome to use my name on the
air that's what i needed
it says thank you for everything you do
for all of us who strive to be better
growers and just plain better in life
bro thank you i'm glad i'm making you a
better grower
and i'm glad it is making you be a
better person in life big respect i
appreciate
that it says i won't ramble on as usual
thank you because i've done enough of
that it says here is my question
i just popped a pack of strawberry
starburst and i want to know in your
opinion
is it better to take a cutting as soon
as i am able from each seedling and then
plant that cutting after it roots
and flip that and find the males very
reasonable uh method
or should i just flip the seedling and
then switch it back to veg
after finding the male show their
finding them show their sex
and thanks for the videos they are
freaking epic so i did post some videos
on topping and cloning and people have
made a lot of comments on those
you're very welcome and thanks for
watching the videos uh my answer
the show oh he wraps it up with much
love and jaw guide from papa zee
my short answer is yes i'm going to read
another question that is very similar to
this
and then i think we are going to give
you some answers let me read this next
question and we'll delve deeper into
the answer to this this one says i have
a question being a michigan resident we
are now limited to 12 plants for
recreational growing
i like to maximize these uh gorilla
cookie seeds
i hope you guys didn't just hear my
stomach rumble i apologize if that came
through wow somebody feed the hippie
um where are we i've got these gorilla
cookie seeds i was given from a friend
in order to audition these plants before
going outside very wise move thank you
you've listened to my podcast previously
i hate it when people put plants outside
that they have not auditioned if you
don't know if that plant's a male or a
female please don't put it outside don't
pollinate all the other outdoor grows
this person has the right idea uh before
putting it outside i was thinking i
would start them inside my tent and veg
for eight weeks you're gonna have good
sized plants
flip it to flower and weed out the males
since i'm not breeding or looking to
[ __ ] up someone else's grove very good
forethought thank you
big respect for that i'm glad you're
thinking ahead and then revenge the
females to go outdoors is this going to
stress the girls too much or no
um then at the bottom of your question
bro i wrote the word
perfect um that's that's the best way to
do it
audition them before you put them
outside flip them into flower
wait to see what the males are then
re-veg the females
and put the females outside that is a
very beautiful
strategy this is very similar to the
question we were asked previously
previously so let's delve into this this
is kind of the same answer the same
question here
for both of these the main question is
i'm trying to determine
how to sex my plants they want to find
the quickest ways
of sexing their plants to determine if
they've got males or females
so that way we don't waste time putting
uh this guy's gonna put their plants
outdoors he's gonna veg for eight weeks
and then put them outside
that's a big plant if you put those
giant plants outside they're going to be
huge and when they start to turn
uh they show their sex on you that could
pollinate the whole [ __ ] neighborhood
so we don't want to put that male
outside
our other friend is going to be growing
in a tent and wants to make the best out
of their seeds
and they don't want to waste space very
reasonable reasonable expectations here
uh what i would recommend for my friend
who's going to go outdoors and
uh would also work for papa z i would
take a clone from those plants you're
going to veg for eight weeks
we could probably top around week three
and get a good clone
like the top it's gonna bush out and
it's gonna make a top i've showed you
this part on video before
take that top and make a clone out of
the top if you have another space
this is what i would do take the clone
out of the top of each of your plants
label your plants plant a plant b
plant c uh however many you have you
have 10 of them do numbers you have 12
do numbers it's going to be easier
do numbers 1 through 12 then take a
clone and label your clones
appropriately clone one clone two so
they match up with the planet came from
i hope that makes sense
uh then put those clones under 1212
lighting
the clones will begin to root and while
they are rooting they will show you if
they're male or female in about 10
12 maybe 14 days so then you don't have
to veg
giant plants you don't have to veg them
out for five extra weeks
should they be boys you can get rid of
them even sooner
than flipping the plants putting them
into veg and then finding out so the
sooner you can flip them
uh into flour or cut a clone would be
better don't let them get too big
then do it do it early you can do it
when they're tiny you can do it
as soon as you have a plant you know
what i mean by when it goes from a
seedling to looking like a plant once
you think it's an actual plant
then put that [ __ ] into flower they're
only going to be a foot tall
10 inches tall and they're going to be
14 inches tall by the time you find out
they're in the flour then put it back
into veg and then up pot it
and it will re-veg more quickly so
that'll save you time
uh save you some space if you've got
that second space
you can do the clones if not flour out
that original mom plant
and find out what you've got that way
you don't grow it so big i hate wasting
time space
energy i could have put different plants
in there and had a whole new project
underway
had i known that that one big pot was
wasting all my space that's the way i
think about it real estate's expensive
in a grow environment
now we're gonna lean back over here to
papa zee's question it's similar it's a
very similar thing my question
is uh is it better to take a cutting as
soon as i'm able
uh and then plant the cutting is it
roots and then flip that to find the
males or flip the seedlings
so about three weeks into veg take a
clone if you've got the opportunity
let's see
take cutting so take cuttings about
three weeks into veg take a cutting now
you've got this big mom plant
and you've got the cuttings you can at
that point put that cutting
into a flour immediately and it will
show you which ones are the males and
females
now you can toss the males immediately
if you want to and you can keep the
females
now you've already got backup clones of
those plants so you've got a mother
plant for the future
so if one of these plants turns out to
be stellar and you want to keep it
forever or
maybe you just don't have more plants to
grow maybe you want to keep something
around to grow in the future so you
don't have to keep popping seeds and
sexing stuff you can find one that's
reliable
uh then you've got a clone for it it's
already there in the clone dome
so that is one thing that is very
advantageous so if you've got a clone of
each of those plants and you put them
into flower
they will show you sex about the same
time frame that it would take
if you put the original plant into
flower and then let it show you sex it's
going to take about the same amount of
time
10 12 maybe 14 days they're both going
into flower
if you do it with the main plant then
you've got to re-veg it if you do it
with the clones there's no reveg
happening so
if you've got the option in this case i
would probably take the clones
and flower those out find the males pull
the males
and that way you don't have the main
mommy or the main plant
that you started with is not in flower
you don't have to revert it
it's going to take you a week or two to
get it back into the vegetative stage
then you've got to re-veg it then it's
going to regrow again
you could skip that two-week stress
period right there just by flowering out
that clone
then you've got a flowered clone that
will work as a mother you can re-veg
that clone and that will work as a
mother if you choose to keep it as a
mother
or just let that plant grow because you
already know that it's a female because
you've gotten a clone off of it
take more clones again if you choose to
keep it and then let that be your mother
plant for the future take clones later
on in the future
uh wouldn't be a bad idea i think that
makes sense of what i'm talking about
to be honest with you all of your
methods would work all of your ideas
would work it's just what is best for
you
you can cut clones then you can either
flip the clone you can either flip the
mom
or you can flip and return the mom
sometimes we just put the mom
into the flowering room and let them go
and then you just pull them out and
chop them down and throw them away at
that point if you find out that it's a
male or a female
or you keep the females is what i'm
saying you let the females keep going if
it's a boy you just chop it down
and then you just got that big plant in
there you're just running the risk an
experienced grower can spot the boys
pretty quickly we'll just go pull them
out
if you got a female and you didn't get
clones at that point you could pull it
out put it back in veg but
take a clone and flip it flip the mom
and let it go or
flip the mom until it shows you and then
re-veg it are the options both of you
guys have a great strategy
it's just all about deciding what works
best for you i think papa z
and i think both you guys are option
around week three take a clone and put
that tray of clones into flowery
immediately and in 14 days you'll know
what you've got
if you have the extra space to do so um
my friend that's going outdoors
i would recommend that you flower those
plants a little bit earlier than you
anticipated that way they got time to
re-veg and you don't waste so much time
and space with the plant that you don't
need
you don't have to water it feed it take
care of it waste space with it
if it is indeed a male plant all right
that was a long time for two emails i
hope i answered
a lot of questions for you guys there
let's see should i jump into this next
one
yes we've got plenty of time to jump
into this next email this next one comes
from my friend zachary
and it came from patreon at patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart
and it goes just like this it says sir
it doesn't slur like that i promise you
it says sir i just thought of another
question i've been using co2 mushroom
bags
for shits and giggles and i can honestly
say that i have no idea if it helped or
not
um if you can't quantify results in some
sort
of way it was not cost effective you
just donated money to that company is
basically what you did there
um did you use a meter or something
we're going to keep going
i have measured have i measured the co2
in the room
no but i keep close attention to my
ladies and i visit these hoes
every day they have a pretty steady
pattern about them my question
is do you use co2 supplementation and
what are the factors
that would make it worth it from a tent
grower to a building sized operation the
factors in mind
here are obvious temperature humidity
but also a room being sealed enough
air circulation etc uh there's a lot to
touch on already he does say side note
i've been growing three breeder seeds
including yours and from what i'm seeing
so far yours are killing it in my tent
conditions
and those extra seeds you gave me went
to some growers in need
thanks again that's a great way to wrap
up that message because it says that my
seeds are outperforming other breeders
and also shows that i gave you extra
seeds that's really cool thank you for
sharing that with us
uh let's focus on this question here
talking about
co2 in a room uh a sealed room is a big
factor where is that co2 going how are
you exhausting your tent
most of the time we put a blower at the
top of the tent or a carbon filter
somewhere near the top it's exhausting
the air out of the top blowing it out of
the tent
does that ducting go out of a window out
of the
domicile out of the building or does it
blow the air back into
the office space bedroom living room
basement attic wherever you might have
this grow tent
is that air being blown back into there
if it's going out the window your co2 is
now out the window it's part of the
atmosphere
uh you just co2 up the neighborhood with
the mushroom bag you honestly probably
didn't do [ __ ] but
uh you blew the co2 right out the window
if you had the ducting going out the
window if you're
blowing that air back into the room it
had the opportunity
to get sucked in through the passive
vents on the bottom or maybe you've got
an
active intake near the bottom of that
tent but possibly
some of it a portion of it got sucked
back in through the bottom and then
cycled back up through your tent again
also it mixed into the rest of the
atmosphere in the room
how big is that room how much airflow is
in that room
uh is there a door open is there a
window open is that door open to the
rest of the house
is that tent in a 9 000 square foot
warehouse by itself
is it in a 5x7 bedroom that is stifled
these are going to be huge factors that
depend that make that come into play
to decide it's all about airflow cubic
feet uh amount of [ __ ] co2 you've
introduced into the room where did it go
so it's all about the cycling and
recycling and the amount of sealed
environment you've got in there if
you're just blowing it out the window
you're literally just blowing it out the
window if it's sealed in there and
there's nowhere for it to go
it's circling back in there but also
that tells me that your room is probably
too hot and probably kind of humid also
unless you've got the appropriate
equipment in there to combat
that um let's see i like to aim for
fairly high ppms in a so in my personal
grows
i do not run co2 it's extra work it's a
couple of extra strip trips to the
growth store
i feel like my plants are the plants i'm
working with are high performance plants
people always tell me my plants
veg faster they flower with much more
vigor a little bit of co2 may make my
plants go too fast and mess up my whole
schedule
most of my stuff is in a small space my
personal stuff is in a very small space
i don't feel the need to augment the co2
there
also most of what i'm breeding for is
for seeds i don't need big fat buds i'd
get bigger plants with faster growth i'm
not worried on that big accelerated bud
growth
i want healthy seeds so that's mainly
what i focus on
in a commercial grow environment i co2
up those rooms
heavily somewhere between a thousand and
fourteen hundred ppms just depending on
what part of the flowering cycle we are
in uh in veg i stay around a thousand
and the flowering times will crank it up
to about 1400 ppms
it gets quite expensive to augment co2
in a large environment
if if if i notice that we can't keep it
up if we need uh more
co2 being dumped into the room then it's
cost effective i'll simply just keep the
ppms closer to a thousand if we can keep
it in the room if it's a smaller room
better sealed better airflow that's when
i'll crank it up
kind of in the later weeks of flower not
the final weeks but the later weeks of
flower i'll really crank up that co2
um so the factors are it's all about
sealed
can you how are you providing the co2 is
it coming from a burner if it's coming
from a burner
you were just limited by the performance
of that burner can you and the heat that
it puts off as well can you turn that
[ __ ] up
enough to saturate the room at the
desired level uh with the amount of
sealed
uh ceiling that you've done in that room
if you're using tanks
uh that gets expensive you've got to
refill the tanks
can you saturate the room with co2 at
the level you desire
and maintain those tanks can you get to
the store as often as you need to
can you carry in those tanks as often as
you need to without your neighbors
seeing you
uh co2 tanks being carried into the
house looks super
[ __ ] sketchy people don't realize you
may use co2 for a cannabis grow they
think you're doing something way
different
the kids in the neighborhood are going
to think you've got helium and they're
going to want [ __ ] helium balloons
so if you got that co2 tank uh you're
gonna have to move that
into the house a couple of times a week
or a couple of times a month or
something think about that do you want
to move that
also that gets expensive if your room is
not sealed properly
ah you're just ducting that [ __ ] right
out the window you just drove
picked it up snuck it into the house
paid for it
hooked it up and then vented it right
out the damn window so unless you're
sealing the room that is not cost
effective what are the other methods
of creating co2 we got the tanks we got
the burner oh we got these mushroom bags
i really don't know if those are
effective let's talk about that unless
you're getting out a meter you said you
do not use a meter
unless you're getting out a meter
there's no real way
to measure the amount of co2 in the room
i've got a lot of meters in the
commercial environment
that tell me what the the co2 is
throughout the room i've got it set up
to where if the co2 is too high here
too low here it'll actually turn on in
this region and not in this region
fans will kick on and move co2 it's a
pretty advanced room in some of these
places
uh you've got to have the meters we also
have these big meters that if it gets
dangerously high
the [ __ ] alarms go off and it tells
us to leave the building it's pretty
cool
i had that happen once almost [ __ ] my
pants scared the [ __ ] out of me
uh but we do have a lot of co2
monitoring in the commercial
environments you need a monitor if
you're going to pay
for the juice you got to monitor the
juice you got to get the equipment that
goes with it or you don't even know if
you're doing anything
you need some sort of quantifiable data
also quantifiable
results if you put that in there and you
didn't get any results out of it it was
not cost effective which means it didn't
do
it wasn't cost effective i wouldn't do
it again unless you got more out of
spending more money
don't do it again unless the quality is
better i need we're not looking i don't
think quality is going to be better
because of co2 you're just looking for
bigger fatter plants bigger fatter buds
so uh you need a meter uh i would
optimize
the room the tent is in a room in your
situation i would optimize
the room in which the tent is in because
that room is working as a lung room
you've got your main environment in the
tent and then outside that air gets to
mix around again
and kind of stabilize itself to the uh
room temperature which was gonna be
whatever ambient environment is if it's
a hot day it's going to be hot if it's
cool it's going to be cool
but it's getting to mix in there again
and kind of stabilize itself before it
gets sucked back into the room if you
can keep that room
closed and keep the co2 augmented in
that room as well
that will help you out a lot of people
uh adjust the
temperature and humidity of the room in
which the tent is in i wouldn't put my
air conditioner in the tent i would put
it in the bedroom
which the tent is in put my humidifier
and dehumidifier in that room
adjust that temperature and then blow
that perfect air into the tint and then
suck out the bad air out of the top of
the tent
so i'd be uh augmenting the co2 in that
big room as well i know that sounds
silly but
from a commercial growers standpoint
from a very experienced grower's
standpoint that's the way to do it now
what you're gonna have to do at that
point
is make sure that room is sealed are you
evacuating air out of that room somehow
are people opening the door or coming in
and out of that room if it's an active
house in the
or an active room in the house this may
not be the best way to do it you may
just want to rock it without co2 or just
be the guy that puts a little tank right
outside there
and runs the lines into right into the
tent and then just drops that co2 right
in there
it could get wasteful but it's going
right to the plants that way that works
too
um just try not to waste it it is
expensive is it cost effective i would
get meters
i would take a lot of notes we need
quantifiable data run two or three
harvests
of the same strain of the same plants
for the same amount of time with the
same feed
if you want it to be scientific you have
to do it scientifically
i know i said scientifically um if you
can't seal that room up
the way i said before put the tanks
right outside of the tent
run your lines right inside the tent and
run that perforated drip line right
above the plants
like six or eight inches above the
canopy make a loop all the way around
that tent maybe do a cross across the
middle if you can run the lines that way
so that co2 is dropping right into the
canopy of those plants and then your
extraction fan will suck it up
it's heavier than oxygen so it's going
to fall when that extraction fan comes
on it'll pull it back up
hopefully it sucks into the room and
then that extraction fan is pulling
passive air into the bottom hopefully
like i said before
it brings it right back into that tent
once it recycles with the air outside
um you're gonna need meters that's my
main advice bro find a meter
and see what the meter says you're
probably going to start off around 350
to 420 ppms of co2
in your room that's naturally what the
environment seems to be lately
see what you can do by augmenting it
with these cheap bags see if you want to
invest in more expensive equipment
pumping up the co2
if you get it high and you get a good
pattern and figure out what each strain
likes
it will increase your bulk it will make
the plants beef up bulk up fatten up
you will notice faster growth because of
that co2 if you can get it dialed in
um i wrote high ppm show results but
is it cost effective that is uh the main
thing to think about cost-effective
if it's not cost-effective cut it out
the only way to find out is to seal up
that room
let that [ __ ] rip and see what it does
for your plants all right uh
zachary thank you for the great patreon
question i want to thank everybody who
sent me messages today for the continued
patreon support i do see your names on a
lot of my things my instagram i see you
pop up
i see you on my patreon all the time i
see you in the discord i appreciate the
community interaction
big shout out to the irie army the grow
from your heart podcast crew
gang gang i do appreciate each and every
one of you thank you guys for the big
big support all right i do feel like
i've answered a couple of questions for
this episode i feel like i went for
about 30-ish minutes i tried to give you
a 30-minute episode
the numbers show me that uh people stop
listening dead-on stop listening at 36
minutes people start checking out about
18 minutes so i think 30 minutes is a
good show for you
big shout out to everybody out there
with attention
deficit problems i love you guys i'm in
your gang don't worry
um that's all i've got for this episode
if you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
maybe you learned a couple of things
maybe i improved your garden maybe you
just like to throw me a couple of bucks
because i'm educational or entertaining
i think i said that already anyway the
patreon is patreon.com forward slash
grow from your heart don't be shy
all the info you need is right there on
the screen at patreon.com forward slash
grow from your heart if you have any
questions corrections comments or
concerns
i would love to hear from you my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com don't be shy
send me that feedback let me know what
you're thinking about the show
i do appreciate it i get a lot of emails
i get a lot of interaction
if i haven't answered you don't feel
like i'm ignoring you uh there are
7 000 people subscribed to this podcast
thank you for the 7 000 subscribers by
the way
and there's only one of me so i get a
lot of messages i get a lot of emails i
get a lot of comments
i do try to reply to all of them but
it's just me and my little fingers can
only go
so fast so be patient with me i'm not
ignoring you i don't hate you
i love each and every one of you like my
own adopted pets i will get to your
messages i do promise
my new year's resolution was to be
better at answering emails
i don't know i don't know if i hit that
goal or not we're only halfway through
the year here so i got a lot of
a lot of catching up to do i feel like
we can fix this we can redeem that
um you guys i'm just rambling at this
point thank you for hanging out uh i'll
be back in a couple of days with fresh
new content i'm gonna give a giant shout
out to my friend blackbird76
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]