[Music]
yeah welcome back podcast world i'm your
host my friends call me rasta jeff
and this is episode 652
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to address the
second half of the question from billy
podunk in the last episode
but before we get there let's do a few
shout outs to a few of the kind of folks
who support the show
on patreon let's start off with the big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out
to my friend brian c let's send a big
thank you shout out to the captain and
commander of the irie army i want to
send a big thank you shout out to my
buddy lemur priest also
happy late birthday bro let's send a big
thank you shout out to my buddy smoke
what
i want to send a big thank you shout out
to a longtime supporter and a good
friend let's send a big thank you to my
buddy john bendit
i want to send a big thank you shout out
and a big hug to my friend miss mel
let's send a big thank you shout out to
zo so j bro keep the great photography
coming
i want to send a big thank you shout out
to my friend kurt zee let's send a big
fist bump to the kinecrat
i want to send a big thank you shout out
to brad and ez057
and then let's wrap it up with the big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out
to my buddy roz and man big thanks and
big shout out to everybody
who continues to support the show on
patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need will be
right there on the screen and of course
there is a link in the show notes
and in the video description to make it
nice and easy
for all of my friends
welcome to the show everybody if you are
watching on the video
service that's probably youtube if
you're watching on a video format
you may have noticed by now if things
went well i am probably recording
uh showing this episode in a
multi-camera format
uh big thanks to the patreon crew for
making that possible
the multi-camera the multi-angle format
has been fun to learn
a couple of headaches in that one but i
make it fun i will learn it i will just
keep making this show better and better
thank you for all of the compliments the
words of encouragement the words of
advice the tips and tricks on working
the new gear
i do appreciate it so thank you thank
you thank you so much
uh for the patreon contributions uh the
words of encouragement
the tips the tricks the advice the high
fives the boosts all of that stuff does
mean the world to me
i really appreciate it do not stop you
guys the email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com
twitter is at gfyh podcast and of course
there's the patreon
at patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
keep the love coming it does keep the
vibe high over here in the girl from
your heart studio
all right i don't want to ramble too
much i think i got rambling in the last
episode so i'm going to try to keep this
one kind of tight but every time i say
that
it's like i jinx myself every time i say
let's keep it quick and tight and do a
quick episode that is when i go off the
rails
i do want to keep it kind of quick kind
of tight in this one because i want to
make sure to get this camera
and this camera synced up and edited
properly into a proper multi-cam show
we'll see what we do you guys will know
how it went when the show comes out if
i'm just staring one direction
something went awry and i got some work
to do we'll figure out you guys i'm
having nothing but fun
learning all of this gear nothing but
fun it's a good time i love all this
tech toys we live in the future and it's
[ __ ] amazing
all right so i did say i was going to
jump into the second half of the
questions
from our friend uh billy podunk from the
last episode
in the last episode billy did ask why a
golden goat bat cross and i took a
little bit of time to explain
why a golden goat back cross i got a lot
of great feedback on that one
um then we asked why the story of golden
goat
i talked a little bit about the story of
golden goat then the next question is
can you tell the story of
daybreaker and that does segue into can
you talk about the story of arise
because of course arise
is golden goat and daybreaker so let's
talk a little bit about daybreaker
daybreaker
uh is another strain that once again i
acquired from
another source the golden goat was a
gift from my friend pineapple express
shout out to that dude if you're around
hope you're well brother uh
the daybreaker was a gift from our
friends at gage green
genetics gage green genetics is another
seed company they're doing a lot of
things
um they actually inspired so i was given
the daybreaker
they inspired a lot of my naming schemes
they had
a lot of strain names with one
word inspirational or motivational type
words or words that they were using for
a little while
they had a strain name called devotion
and i just felt like
when i used their strain that i should
put their name
into the works into the name of the
cross to kind of honor the name of the
plant which is why
a rise uh daybreaker to golden go got a
one word
inspirational motivational uplifting
type feeling word of a name and a rise
was the best you can do so um
let's let's get back on track here
daybreaker the story of daybreaker where
did the daybreaker came from it came
from
uh gage green genetics very uh
innovative folks in the cannabis
business
uh gauge green genetics not the other
gauge there's a lot of other fake gauges
out there
uh they are gauge green genetics has
been around for a long time that's the
og gage
uh so daybreaker daybreaker is a chem
d female we got the chem dog d female
pollinated by a
joseph og male i do not know the entire
story of the joseph og mail that was not
my og mail plant
to the best of my knowledge that was an
og mail gifted to
the gauge green genetics group or the
gage green group
there's mainly a couple of guys mike and
key play
that are mainly gauge green genetics and
i'm just speaking to the best of my
knowledge i could be wrong about
anything with gage green that's not my
company just people that i've worked
with
uh people in the industry so uh gauge
green is mainly
mic and key play and they run gage green
i got off topic of where i was going
there
anyway i acquired the uh so they got the
joseph og that's where i was they got
the joseph og mail
to the best of my knowledge joseph og
came from their friend
joseph who unfortunately passed away uh
is the story that i was told
all of that is cannabis legend and story
i don't have any verification of that
that's the best of what i know i like to
tell you the story behind a strain in a
plant
so there was joseph who gave the joseph
og to our friends at the gage green
group
gage green group then used the joseph og
to pollinate a chem d the chem d
of course uh sought out or uh searched
out chem dog strain from
uh chem dog and the legend of the 13
beans if you have not done the research
on chem dog and the legend of the 13
beans
i definitely recommend that story it's
all over the internet somewhere that
stuff you should know if you're
interested in cannabis
so our folks at gage green group took
the
joseph og that's probably an og they
call it og that's an og kush then they
pollinated that
to the chem d that made daybreaker seeds
uh daybreaker was a great cross why did
i love the daybreaker
why did i personally love the daybreaker
i had a couple of female phenotypes and
of course i had a male which i used for
breeding which we'll talk about in a
little bit
the female phenotypes had a
uh gassy um like a
fresh rubber burnt tennis ball kind of a
smell if you open up a can of tennis
balls there's a very distinct
smell that kind of comes out distinct
right it's got stink in it
uh this smell comes out and it just
smells really it's a pungent
uh rubbery dry but pungent smell it's
almost got a gassiness sort of a thing
to it
sometimes when i buy new stickers uh if
i get
bulk stickers from a sticker printer
sometimes they have a skunky
chemically sort of a smell to it and
that's kind of what a lot of these uh
daybreaker phenotypes were smelling like
it was gassy it was funky i describe it
as cushy and diesely which makes sense
because there's kush
and chem in there it's got those flavors
but if you don't know what kush and kim
smell like then you've got to make those
up as well
so it's like chemicals and burnt plastic
and tennis balls and all kinds of
wonderful
terrible smells come from their swampy
foot aromas dirty
armpit aromas body odors a lot of that
sort of stuff the leaves on these plants
were gigantic
the leaves that were coming from the
daybreaker seeds the plants were
gigantic you could serve [ __ ] dinner
on the sides of these leaves they were
dinner plates
which leads into later on why i chose to
use this plant for breeding
i would make beautiful purple colors but
it did have like a
a stretchy sort of a structure just that
og kush
sort of a thing that og kush does it
doesn't menora out like some of your uh
more
uh sought after just stretchy kind of
shaped plants the sought after shape is
what i was trying to say my brain is
really ahead of me today
i know what i'm trying to say my [ __ ]
mouth can't keep up it makes more of a
lanky stretchy sort of a thing
but it's worth it because the quality of
the buds that it puts out are so
pungent and so delicious it's got like
burnt rubber and mothballs and chocolate
and all that chemically stuff going on
but then they're just little dense golf
balls that are so hard and so coated in
resin
that when you put them in a bag like two
little nugs there's an eighth and people
are like that's not eighth row and they
put it on the scale in a ways four and
they're like holy [ __ ]
like i just it was just such good herb
and for the era when i found it and
discovered it that's when the kush and
the
rock buds and the tight dense [ __ ]
that's when that was super popular so
the daybreaker was great for that og
stank funk stuff
so that is the daybreaker let's talk a
little bit about daybreaker was the
first question the story of the
daybreaker
i don't know the inspiration behind
breeding that i don't know that that
wasn't my work
i acquired a package of seeds i was a
tester for the gage green group for a
really long time
uh they sent me the starlet cush i used
the starlet kush
i was a tester of that one and i
actually took photos of that and sent
those to gage and they put that they
didn't put them on there they submitted
them to skunk magazine
and uh humble brag my photos of gauge
green groups starlet kush was on the
cover
and the centerfold of skunk magazine so
most of the time when you're looking up
starlet cush
from gage green group most of those
photos you see will be my photos with
the red background
uh with the blue background those are my
photos uh
big up big thanks for the checking out
my photos but
i was a tester for gage um i tested a
lot of stuff for gage a lot
of winners some things that i wouldn't
have told him to put out and he listened
he took good advice they took good
advice
uh they took my my word um they used
what i had to say as an input
um they didn't just discredit me so
after testing for them for a long time
they just started sending me stuff
randomly and then i got to pack a
daybreaker and thought i'm going to grow
the [ __ ] out of these because i liked
the description
i grew it and found a couple of great
females that stuck around for a little
bit i grew them i worked with them i
smoked them i played with them
i shared clones of those but i found a
male that
was just amazing most of what i'm known
for breeding
is very sativa heavy it's got that panic
attack it's got the longer skinny leaves
it grows tall and skinny
and i was kind of breeding myself into a
box with a lot of that stuff i was
just reading the same thing the lemon
jeffrey the golden goat crosses
a lot of golden goat crosses so it's all
coming out kind of kind of go in the
same direction
and i wanted to try something new also i
had in mind of making
a couple of back crosses and other
things so i saw this
daybreaker male with these big wide fan
leaves and these purple colors
and it didn't want to drink the
daybreaker just doesn't want water you
can
not feed that [ __ ] for twice as long as
all the other plants not water her and
she will be
just fine uh when you do water her the
leaves stay droopy because the leaves
were so big
that when you water her the leaves would
just stay there and she looked angry
when you'd water her that plant wanted
it really really dry and that's a good
trait because that buys me time that
means the offspring later
possibly won't need as much water i can
water and then actually go for
a couple of days without having to water
those plants i can go take a break go on
vacation maybe go see fish maybe go do
some stuff
so ah i saw this daybreaker plant i saw
this male plant and this male plant that
was coming out when i would rub the stem
it smelled disgusting it had the most
pungent
disgusting aromas coming out of it and i
thought this is a breeder plant i need
to breed with this it was making purple
colors i was making trichomes add a
beautiful shape a beautiful structure
it was just as a breeder i knew this
dude right here needs to do
some [ __ ] pollen chucking in this
room so i put him in a room
with several females a lot of the stuff
never got put out the daybreaker crosses
uh there were probably when i make a
cross i don't just put one female in the
room that's not
like that that's cool you're gonna make
a new cross but why not put seven or
eight females in there whatever your
legal limit whatever your space limit is
something like that
put a lot in there make a lot of seeds
if you're gonna do it do it
so i had a lot of females in the room at
the time there was
um a girl scout cookies plant in the in
the room that one got called coffee cake
the girl scout cookies to daybreaker
um there was there were a lot in there i
can't even remember all of them right
now
um floata daybreaker there's a bunch of
good [ __ ] in there there was a lot of
good [ __ ] in there i still have a lot of
it also
um now my inbox is gonna blow up but uh
coffee cake you guys
anyway so i thought i'm going to put the
golden goat in there because
golden goat my selections on breeding um
are very important in my opinion
selection is
key it was very important that i chose
good breeding plants i put golden goat
in there
because golden goat was so completely
different from this daybreaker plant why
would i want to make
daybreaker to daybreaker why would i
want to put
chocolate mothballs gas and funk to more
chocolate moth balls gas and funk that's
going to come out the same thing
or or the breeding is going to be so
weird that those two
all those powerful traits the gas
mothballs funk chocolate
tennis balls all those terps are going
to meet in the middle and they're going
to cancel each other out and it's going
to come out smelling like raspberries or
something
like weird [ __ ] like that happens in
breeding what i would rather do
is take this chocolate funk and mix it
into other things like
the strawberry starburst you get
strawberry chocolate funk the girl's got
cookies it was kind of similar there but
you know you got to cross everything to
the [ __ ] cookies
uh the platinum tangy because then you
get the orange to the chocolate funk
that's kind of my idea when i'm breeding
to the lemon skunk there is actually
daybreaker to lemon skunk those seeds
really do exist
but things like that so that i can make
new [ __ ] i don't want to just
replicate and duplicate all the terps
that are already happening there's
enough
uh dessert and gas and [ __ ] kush
kind of smells like there's already cake
and [ __ ] twinkies and terps
that's already happening everywhere so i
want to make some new [ __ ] i try to
open up my breeding not bottle my
bottleneck myself into one direction so
selecting this golden goat to the
daybreaker i knew there was going to be
some amazing [ __ ] coming out of that the
golden goat we've talked about her
high potency everything i breed to the
golden goat comes out
highly potent uh golden goat to itself
golden goat as a male golden goat as a
female
anything i breed with the golden goat it
comes out magical so
uh i took the daybreaker male
uh beautiful structure stank ass aroma
making purple colors purple trichomes
the leaves were purple
big giant leaves the leaves would turn
black and start crinkling up toward the
end of the flowering phase
i took this male and i put them in a
room with all these other girls and in
that room was the golden goat so we did
some pollen chucking
now we have got a golden goat female
pollinated by that daybreaker male
that made a rise what a rise one of my
flagship strains one of my most popular
strains
arise tested at i don't even want to
save the numbers without pulling it up
somewhere because nobody ever believes
me it was 35.84
thca it was grown by our friends at
organica in albuquerque new mexico i
think
miles was in charge of that girl either
way i know miles touched it and it was
all his fault that it was really good
shout out to my buddy miles big up to
tim shout out to the entire
organica crew shout out to everybody out
there in albuquerque hope you're doing
well big up to new mexico
cannabis legalization what good job you
guys
um where the hell was i arise arise uh
daybreaker and golden goat cross right
um our rise was golden goat and
daybreaker i knew that it was going to
be a champion i grew a bunch of seeds
out of that
out immediately and very early on they
were just taking off they was going
most of the other seeds um i buy seeds
from other breeders i pop a lot of other
seeds i've bred a lot of other seeds
other seeds in that room were just not
doing what a ryze was doing a rise was
a rising to the occasion she was [ __ ]
taken off he was taken off there were
boys and girls in there
they were all exploding with growth and
i was like think i'm on to something
here
and i watched a few of the other crosses
in the room and they were growing they
were doing their thing but that arise
just kept going and going
every phenotype i grew of that was a
winner
i couldn't find one from that batch of a
rise that
i didn't want to keep uh those the first
batch was labeled
a b c d e uh all the way up to g
i think uh a and e were kept around for
a very very long time
f was around for quite a while i've
crossed i've made f2s of a and e
and f on possibly a couple others that i
don't talk about as much
uh then from another batch i discovered
um
number four and number eight and these
are females these were all female
arise crosses a rise f1s that i was
keeping around
um i've made f2s with the the same male
uh the solomon male the male that's been
dubbed solomon
but i kept him around um i made f twos
of the number eight the number four the
number
seven e a f possibly g that sounds like
a [ __ ] guitar chord right there e a f
g sounds like a [ __ ] guitar structure
chord structure
uh but i made f twos of a lot of those
uh there were so many good
phenotypes around that i just couldn't
there were subtle differences but like
so many similarities some were kind of
more golden goats some were kind of more
og kush
and if you smoke og kush or kemdog you
get [ __ ] high as [ __ ] from those if
you smoke golden goat you get high as
[ __ ]
so either buzz was completely desirable
sometimes i'm sit on
would end up sitting on the couch
sometimes i'd end up [ __ ] saying i'm
gonna go sit down and watch tv and i'd
end up in the kitchen cooking food and
cleaning the basement all the same
[ __ ] time
so it was like it was just tremendous
herb every phenotype had something to
offer
the smells were like sweet kush how can
you go wrong with sweetness and kush so
that was a rise uh then we'll talk about
the
arise male who was known as king solomon
i found a boy
in that batch of seeds i actually fino
hunted a boy
out of that batch of seeds i went
through several seeds looking for the
perfect male because i knew
i just knew there was a male in that
batch of seeds that was going to pass on
the magic that i saw
in that original cross when i first grew
that first batch of f1 or rye seeds i
saw them
like they didn't come out of the soil
they [ __ ] kicked the soil out of the
way
and they came out screaming like we're
[ __ ] here and we're gonna grow and
you cannot
stop us and i was like holy [ __ ] these
plants are onto something
i thought they were all boys because
usually male plants grow with that kind
of vigor but these
female and male plants were all just
taken off so i wanted to make that vigor
continue
so i found a few of my favorite female
plants of course that's how i do it like
i said before if i'm gonna pollinate
something i'm gonna pollinate a whole
bunch of [ __ ] somethings
so i found my daybreaker mail and i put
a bunch of ladies in the room
and i just started pollinating things
and here we are today i've got probably
i want to say that king solomon um is
probably responsible
for nearly a hundred crosses probably
uh 50 of them have been released
probably maybe close to that i don't
know but
that day breaker pollinated the golden
goat made
a rise a rise was i selected a male
he has been called solomon if you read
about king solomon uh
ladies were his weakness he could have
had anything he wanted he wanted a lot
of ladies
i thought my male plant should be named
solomon because he's got a lot of kids
everywhere just like solomon did
um that's some rasta [ __ ] right there
for you a peek into into my little rasta
brain
anyway that is the story you guys of
daybreaker daybreaker is not really my
story to tell
that's another breeder's story i gave
you my uh my
experience with it i know that it came
from the gage green group uh
came from mike and key play i got the
seeds because i used to be a tester
i did not test the daybreaker i would
not have bred with it had i tested it it
was already out it was given as a gift
free reign on breeding with that one i
don't think you should breed with the
tester
that's uh just another thing so i got
that one i grew it i
[ __ ] saw great potential in it
there's just something about
i'm like a cannabis matchmaker when i
see two plants i'm just like dude these
two plants it's like
uh [ __ ] those people with matchmaking
services or date makers or hooker up
friends you ever have friends that are
trying to hook up to your friends like
yo bill and susan should date
and then they do and they hit it off
you're like how the [ __ ] did you know
that i just know that i'm that kind of
guy i know that [ __ ] i know that
if plant a and plant b do the the
horizontal mambo i know that their kids
are going to be beautiful also
i'm at an advan at an advantage i'm kind
of cheating at this point i know that my
male plant
solomon is [ __ ] magic anything that
all saul touches
he's gonna turn into magic he's just got
the magic [ __ ] he's got the midas
touch bro
uh he pollinates female plants and the
offspring is just [ __ ]
awesome also uh i've got access to
some of the most elite female plants on
the planet i've got access to a lot of
stuff i've got friends that will acquire
or
get me things however i ask i can get
whatever i want you guys
and people return me clones of things if
i breed something and they grow it and
they find something stellar a lot of
times people offer to return me a clone
i've been taking more people up on those
offers so that i could do some more
uh reversals and some different projects
but so i've got female clones female
plants that
have been tried true tested they've been
through the wringer
i also have a lot of experience in the
commercial uh
cultivation uh what is it industry here
in colorado so i've been to a lot of
commercial growers and i went to a lot
of them
for extended periods of time i would go
to this one place for
maybe a four to eight maybe a 12 16 week
contract
uh maybe a two harvest full complete
harvest contract and i get to see their
plants for two full harvests
once or twice a week um by then you
learn
that plant sucks that plant's awesome
that one right there talks to me that
plant right there says something
can i get a clone of that and then
somehow we managed to get me a clone
i get it in my [ __ ] personal grow we
get rid of all the problems that
came with that clone because it came
from that dispensary grow
clean it up breed to it and voila we've
got another magic ingredient to make
more magic
my plants have been vetted and tested i
am kind of cheating but i know that i've
got successful breeding plants because
of that
so that is the story of a rise she tests
super high there's a full podcast about
arise
but i do enjoy kind of revisiting
because it's been years since i did that
podcast that episode definitely wasn't a
video podcast
ah a ryze eats very heavy her rise gets
pretty tall
she takes well to defoliation she can
handle high temperatures
uh right now it's probably kind of hard
to get a rise there are not a lot of
seeds left especially after this episode
airs they will sell out everywhere if
it's not already sold out
uh seeds here also check out
iriegenetics.com for a list of vendors
and opportunities where you can find a
rise not just a rise but all of the
strains that i'm putting out
i was going to wrap up the podcast but
since i'm teasing out teasing strains
that i'm putting out
coming soon you guys if you've listened
to this far into this ramble cast of an
episode
coming very soon two new strains from
ire genetics if you've been watching
social media you may have seen me test
these a couple of times
a few people out there are testing them
i'm waiting for some photos from other
great testers
these will be released i want to say
fall maybe winter
of this year if not early next year i do
need to make more
uh they're in the process it just takes
time and it's it's honestly just me i
gotta package it all up gotta get it
going but they're coming
so let's talk about two new strains
coming from iregenetics i'm proud to
announce i'm gonna use camera two for
this one
ladies and gentlemen i'm proud to
announce the names of a couple of
strains that i've been teasing and
hinting at you
uh for quite a while there's a cross it
is uh which one do we do first i've got
notes here
the first one i have taken a biscotti
female that's right i've got the
biscotti biscotti is an amazing plant
super dense bud
uh pastry flavors it's called biscotti
for a reason shout out to my buddy
double door dank for throwing me that
clone
the biscotti has been pollinated by the
arise
so it is biscotti to arise i use that
king solomon a rise cut
he's reliable these plants put off
confusing aromas it's like skunky
pastries it's like chemical
it's like chemical pastry electrical
fire and a pastry and
crayons or something it's really crazy
smells um
that one is called saka souffle
and if you get saka souffle more power
to you if you don't get saku souffle
that's just
you'll be okay the strain will still
grow for you now the other strain that i
want to announce the name of
uh i was gifted a clone of the kem de la
chem that is chem d
uh it is chem d cross to the i-95 that
comes from
jj from top dog genetics you guys know
how much i appreciate jj great breeding
great plants
uh great parent plant so the breeding is
always going to be solid with that guy
and he's not going to put out anything
that isn't [ __ ] stellar
i've taken the chem de la chem and of
course i pollinated that one as well
with the king solomon cut of my arise
the male
the popular king solomon the popular
arise uh that one is called
the machine so we've got saka souffle
and the machine
coming soon once again saka souffle
is biscotti to arise the machine is kem
de la chem
to arise uh both are wonderful strains
they pass my testing requirements
uh great plants good vigor good potency
good terps
uh they qualify to be in my garden they
qualify to be in
your garden big shout out to all the
test growers who helped me out to get
these strains out to market
uh wonderful test growers wonderful grow
reports great photos
ah thank you i truly appreciate it and
don't be offended if you have not been
selected as a test grower yet there's
always new [ __ ] coming
uh pandemic years slowed down a lot of
stuff you guys maybe next year you'll
get an opportunity to be a tester
keep those tester applications coming
there is a full podcast about being an
iriegenetics tester don't be shy
keep those coming i do still have them
on file i do not delete them i do not
throw them away
there's a folder in my macbook called
tester applications
it's in there when i need testers i
start at the top and just start reading
i got a few set to one side
you're gonna be next i got a big pile to
go through i do not
have a reject pile you go to the bottom
maybe one day i'll email you and go hey
you grow any more plants you do any
better you make any changes
what's new in your grow maybe you'll get
the opportunity to be a tester at that
point
but don't be discouraged if you haven't
been selected as a test grower for ire
genetics yet
the future is wide open all right ladies
and gentlemen boys girls pimps hoes
friends foes smokers growers clone
cutters paul and chuckers all you
beautiful cannabis enthusiasts out there
i want to thank you again for listening
to another episode of the grow from your
heart podcast if you have any questions
corrections comments or concerns
you know you can send me an email the
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com please don't be
shy don't worry about my little ego it
will be okay let me know how you feel
about the show
also if you want to help the show out if
you learned a couple of things if you
feel like the show is educational
informative entertaining maybe i rescued
your garden maybe i told you some cool
stories
uh maybe you just want to throw me a tip
just because you thought i was cool or
something the
patreon is patreon.com forward slash
grow from your heart
don't be shy help us out also make sure
to click like and click subscribe that
[ __ ] is free
you're just sitting there with your
phone in your hand anyway click on some
[ __ ] for me
thank you i do appreciate you also check
out my website iriegenetics.com lots of
cool [ __ ] going on on there
i talk about that enough don't need to
ramble about the website again
that is all i've got for you for this
episode the next episode will feature my
buddy white mike we're going to talk
about a
recent rule change here in the colorado
medical marijuana uh
rule scene what is it called atmosphere
environment
the canna space whatever i was doing so
good until now i fell apart here at the
end you guys it is time to go take some
dabs thank you for hanging out
i want to give a giant shout out to my
buddy black thumb grower and until next
time take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
you