all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rasta jeff and this
is episode 653 of the grow from your
heart podcast in this episode
mike is joining me to talk about a new
rule change here in colorado
welcome to the show mike thanks man
and uh good to be back everybody yeah
i'm glad to have you back bro pandemic
had things weird i don't want to talk
too much about the p word
uh but uh yeah let's have a good show
good good glad you're here glad you're
safe glad you're healthy uh dude i'm
glad you are surviving the flood and the
rain
holy [ __ ] i don't want to sound like an
old guy talking too much about the
weather
but dude it is raining in town right now
if if our connections look shitty on
this zoom video you guys we apologize
it is um i've never said the word deluge
but i think it may be
uh deluge outside today that may be the
official word
yeah there's been uh a lot of rainfall
in the last couple hours so
yeah the grow rooms the grows are using
all of the gear today we have the air
conditioner the dehumidifier the fan
everything but the heater today who
knows maybe by the end of the night
we'll kick on that heater for a couple
of degrees we're using all of the
equipment in the grow room today shout
out to the grow room gear
the dehumidifier is working for its
[ __ ] money today work
yes yeah that's the dehumidifiers the
most important piece of the room
yeah today it is working you went up the
list yeah
we that's the mvp today is that
dehumidifier uh mike i feel like it is a
good chance to give you the opportunity
to
uh let us know how people can stalk you
on social media and also maybe
uh how they can find you on what's that
facebook page you got that's another one
i'm thinking about
you can find me at twitter at nemopunk15
and you can find me on facebook at
pueblo for sensible cannabis laws
there you go give my buddy a follow
stalk them a little bit
uh also uh how about your patreon bro
you want to give a shout out to a few
the patreon folks uh patreon you can
find me on patreon if you'd like to
support me in the show
at patreon.com forward slash white mike
um big shout outs to tree star meadow
farmer z
learning and burning og purple thumb and
the grow from your heart podcast
really appreciate the support y'all
thank you glad to help you out uh
glad to be back on the show i actually
need to up my uh need
my contribution to you i feel like my
tier has gone up so i need to send a
little bit more your way
i just feels like that yeah [ __ ] rolls
downhill is what they say right
yeah [ __ ] rain pretty much everything go
downhill yeah we're
dude all right uh let's not focus too
much on the weather i feel like such an
old man type that's random like cats and
dogs it's raining cats and dogs out
there
but it is [ __ ] tremendous someone in
my life always says is the only thing
that goes uphill is money
and that's what i was trying not to say
well we're just getting older by the
minute
back to the rain big shout out to
everybody that supports mike on patreon
uh his list is growing something i
noticed is i've got a list here of
people i wanted to give a shout out to
and you just hit half of them so double
shout out to all the people you
mentioned
i think all of those people are also
part of my patreon campaign so thank you
guys
i also want to send it thank you yeah
they crush it good people and i'm trying
to get this hair off my microphone here
just so that doesn't show up for too
long
you saw it it was there i fixed it you
guys uh professional show we got big
shout out to my friend danky dave brett
c
know me by my guacamole samurai gardens
uh big respect to my buddy tonto
farmer z chicago dabber grimball the
druid uh tree star meadow og purple
thumb
the basta uh my list is longer i'm gonna
cut it short i was trying to cover a lot
of people today big shout out to all of
those folks right there for supporting
me on patreon my patreon is of course
patreon.com forward slash
grow from your heart there's a link in
the show notes video description i will
try
to remember maybe when i'm listening and
editing hey ross to jeff this is your
note
put a link to mike's patreon in the
video description there you go that was
for me you guys
uh also it kind of programmed you to go
support mike on patreon thanks you guys
for the patreon support
check this out this is one of the rare
opportunities i'll be able to do this
i'm going to zoom
video using my macbook for the camera so
look patreon
i've got two cameras thank you you guys
ah multicam stuff is coming editing
multicam is
is going to be fun but there you go
multiple cameras affiliated this week
folks
yes multi-cam is coming thank you
patreon for making that happen that's
patreon's uh that's your fault you guys
thank you
multicam i'm excited about it on
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart also uh you notice i'm rocking the
girl from your heart podcast official
t-shirt
uh hit the irie genetics website
iriegenetics.com there's an irie
genetics store
hit that you can grab the shirts there's
a link there if you go to the website
and sign up to the newsletter
there is a newsletter spot you'll find
it it's easy put in your email address
hit send it'll sign you up for my
newsletter once a month i will send you
a coupon code
for the etsy store perhaps a coupon code
for a new vendor
um just special deals and stuff i try
not to spam you too hard with the
newsletter i try to go once a month
maybe every two weeks if there's
something worth talking about but you'll
get a coupon code save a couple of bucks
that's always really helpful i feel like
i'm advertising too much and rambling
here at the start of the show
there is a point to this podcast i did
mention that we do have a serious topic
yes there are a lot of rules changing
they changed some rules here in colorado
before i hit that part
um i did have a couple of more uh bullet
points there are a lot of new legal
states coming online mike mentioned that
in kind of the
the pre-ramble pre-ramble such a good
word like a preamble but it's the
pre-ramble i just made that up
in our pre-ramble uh we talked about new
states coming online uh virginia
i think mike said shout out to the goo
to guru if virginia is now legal big up
to guru
um as soon as you said it it didn't
sound right on my ear so i'm going to
check it again
mike's google and i think you might be
correct it's one of those places but new
mexico is definitely legal now
uh new mexico had some controversy
because
uh they had a basically i don't remember
the letters of it they have a new mexico
medical marijuana program and
a couple of my friends just got their
medical marijuana cards renewed and they
paid big money to get certain plant
counts and do all this stuff and now
they're
allowed to grow so much product legally
because the state of colorado or new
mexico
made these rules today those rules
changed on the first and now all that
money that my friend paid
for his card to be valid for the next 18
months is no longer valid and he's
trying to
find some recourse with the state of new
mexico and new mexico is kind of telling
him to go [ __ ] himself so that's going
to be interesting but
what i'm getting at in the long rambles
here is
just because your location may have gone
legal
doesn't mean that you can walk out in
the streets with your bong
and do bong rips for prosperity so
many rules yeah there are so many rules
and it's your
your responsibility unfortunately to
know them before
you go partake or participate don't
don't be wait to told
be told the rules uh know them before
you break them so
some of them are not intuitive yeah yeah
but
just because it's legal where you are
doesn't mean that you can go
taking bong rips in the streets you can
smoke joints in the car
find out the rules and regulations where
you are sometimes
if uh if the thing was voted on today
and it passed
today people think we can dab in the
streets today number you got to wait for
it to actually go
into place it's gonna take a little time
yeah it's not just like hey we could dab
now it's like nope no
nope we gotta pat with the rule pass now
we gotta make there's a buffer time that
you gotta wait for
so i love the excitement i love the
enthusiasm i love all of that stuff
but be careful don't think uh don't
uh don't think that just because it's
legal
you can overdo yourself and then end up
in trouble
like when i'm going somewhere else i
went to another state just recently i
went to another place to go visit and
have a good time before i went there
i googled the rules around cannabis
because i knew the people i was going
with
what's a there was going to be cannabis
in my group i knew that somehow someway
when i got there there would be cannabis
products involved and i knew we would be
consuming cannabis i googled
possession laws possession limits what
happens if i get caught with
concentrates
what happens if i get caught with
concentrate gear like what if i have a
rig and a torch and a carb cap
and dabs in the car like what are my
opportunities here
you can buy stuff in a store in colorado
that will get you
years in prison in nearby st
oh mike um you guys i'm gonna talk over
mike for a moment mike's connection cut
out so i'm just gonna talk for a moment
and let him catch up
mike can't hear me he's giving me the
ear signals um but you guys i'm just
gonna ramble till mike's connection
catches up i'm pretty sure he
understands what's going on by now
uh the point is we could buy stuff here
in colorado and if i drive
to uh kansas there we go mike is back
yeah mike you made a very good point
brother i could buy some stuff here
at a dispensary uh 30 miles from the
kansas border
and drive that 30 miles and as soon as i
hit that [ __ ] border
boom i'm [ __ ] and there are so many
state troopers waiting at the utah
border uh the kansas border what's the
one north wyoming
new mexico doesn't have any [ __ ] cops
so they're not sitting there waiting for
you you got to get a little bit more
south but no honestly you guys there are
some cops in new mexico friendly
medical marijuana state now they're
recreational brothers
today they are recreational yeah and
they just weren't wrecked
um but texas is the big one
yeah i always think of yeah because the
grandma hatch in colorado is just a
[ __ ] good time
a grandma hash in texas is hard drugs
that your ass is going to prison for
the [ __ ] up part about texas well i
mean the one the one of the many
texas i love you i pick on texas a lot i
love you guys i love you guys nothing
but love for texas
shout out to empire dave uh one of the
[ __ ] up things about texas
so this is my green dot labs concentrate
container this was a jar of fatso number
two
i just scooped the last dab out of here
for me
in this jar you could see there's uh for
the people just listening
there are remnants like if i were
uh residue if i were a youngster
and i were [ __ ] scrounging up for
concentrates i could get two or three of
these jars and scrape that out of there
i could get a dab i could definitely
make a dab out of that
uh in years past when things weren't the
way they should be i've been known to
[ __ ] pull a couple jars out like i
know there's a dab [ __ ] in all of
these and scrape them together that's
happened
i guess that's the old school this is
the new school version of scraping your
[ __ ] pipe let me scrape all my jars
in texas this would be
uh i would be charged with the weight of
this jar
and its lid which this is a glass jar
with a big
dense plastic lid this is at least an
ounce
i would be charged with an ounce of
concentration because of this container
same legal classification as
meth and heroin i'm going to drop it on
the table and you can hear how damn
heavy it is
you really need to get the rules people
that's the the tangent we're on is it is
incredibly important to know the rules
where you're playing
yes and in texas they charge you for
your container weight so if you got some
[ __ ] in texas carrying parchment paper
that way it's lighter uh but just don't
[ __ ] around in texas is my legal as your
lawyer i highly advise you don't [ __ ]
around in texas behave yourself
um all right so know the rules where you
are
it doesn't mean you can dab in the
streets that's that was my point here i
don't want people getting in trouble
people are like hey i can grow a bunch
of weed now
maybe like be careful the one that
[ __ ] everybody here was
you can't grow weed in your backyard yes
like it feels like you should be able to
but you definitely can't i want to uh
kind of segue we're gonna get to the
topic here but
uh i saw somebody post a picture the
other day of their outdoor grow
and there were like 24 plants in their
outdoor colorado grow
hey guys be careful your limit is six
maybe 12 if you've got medical uh
credentials uh no you don't have
credentials or medical recommendations
two two adults in a house you can
legally grow 12.
yeah so 12. if there's just one adult if
it's a single adult property and only
one person's getting mail there the
the and you don't have a medical card to
limit
six but do not up to 12 with you and a
wife is
what did they get so do not post a photo
of
13 plants that's my advice post a
picture of 11 plants
like don't even yeah yep yeah that's
sami
my friends out there federally like
triple think about posting period
because the powers that be still like to
[ __ ] with
us any way they can because it can't yes
yeah depending on your location
definitely a double treatment here in
colorado it can [ __ ] with your
child custody cases it can [ __ ] with
your job
it can [ __ ] with your livelihood banking
ways your banking
um i mean there's sort of no end to the
list of ways
we have come up with to screw with
people
in an attempt to get them to not smoke
wheat
and during legalization even here in
colorado where we really started
legalization there's just no
no attempt yet to go back and go we
shouldn't [ __ ] with people's schools
school funding options because they got
caught with pot or
we shouldn't kick them out of federal
housing because they're smoking pot or
you know test positive we shouldn't
take them off transplant lists or
threaten to take their children away
like all those things still happen even
here
yeah so not to be debbie down around the
show but
well that's kind of what you're playing
so you can play safe we know that's your
role mike we know that's what you
what we brought you every party needs a
pooper yeah this is colorado you can
uh grow uh consume uh you can open up a
[ __ ] storefront you can advertise on
the radio but there's nowhere really
illegal to go smoke so
you gotta go home i totally checked
virginia did go legal
nice shout out to virginia the headline
said it was squirrely and you should
read the article to understand it
so do that i didn't um
i think it's funny that they said
squirrely in an article that's
i was awesome oh well [ __ ] i was hoping
the reporter said the word squirrely
reporter mike with the word squirrely on
the scene all right we've rambled for a
long [ __ ] time we've promised the
people a podcast here
uh there may be an editor seven to
happen into this
uh mike there are some new rules
happening in colorado that
are going to affect myself and possibly
you you don't shop as heavily as i do
but this may affect
me and you in the future uh affect
myself
the the people who wrote the bill that
we're talking about
hope it affects everybody um
that's their goal uh so the bill we're
talking about if you'd like to read
along
at home listeners you can look it up
it's colorado um so you can google this
by just typing
the capital letters co for colorado and
then
hb for house bill and
1317 is the serial number so
co hb 13
17.
it's designed as a bill to add
restrictions and regulations to
colorado's medical marijuana program and
marijuana concentrates
um the anti-cannabis powers the bee
around the country and here in colorado
have learned that um
the only two talking points they have
that anyone still gives a [ __ ] about are
marijuana is way stronger now than it
was in the 60s and you should be afraid
of that
and teenagers getting a hold of cannabis
is especially bad now because it's super
strong like we told you about a minute
ago
[Music]
long time listeners of this show will
know that i have
rambled at length repeatedly about what
nonsense both of those talking points
are
and i'm happy to do so again in a future
show
so anyway house bill 1317 with those two
talking points in mind
made its way through the colorado
legislature and was signed into law
about a week ago by governor poulos uh
most of the stuff i'm going to be
talking about takes place immediately
or whenever they can figure out how to
do it
because some of it's not immediately
possible in colorado
so under the new law they're changing
medical marijuana rules especially for
people under the age of 21. so right now
before this bill in colorado
you can be a medical marijuana patient
at any age
um if you're 21 or over you just go to
one doctor often a doctor that
specializes in medical marijuana
you talked to that doctor in a doctor's
appointment they fill out your paperwork
you send your paperwork into the state
you get a thing back on your phone now
it's very easy
um and that's all it takes to get your
medical marijuana card
i believe that's 18 and over yeah 18 and
up i'm sorry
um and there's a different group under
where you needed two doctors to sign off
on your card
and most medical marijuana doctors
didn't want
anything to do with you so there was
this middle group of people who were 18
to 21 who were too young to shop in
rec stores but old enough to shop in
medical stores
who would get medical marijuana cards
and the bill supposes a large number of
those people
were then retail selling cannabis they
purchased with their medical card
and cannabis concentrates to their high
school friends
and so they've come up with new rules
requiring anyone under 21 to go
see two marijuana doctors
or not two marijuana doctors two doctors
to sign their marijuana paperwork
um they've implemented a couple of other
rules that the physicians will have to
meet
um like reviewing previous doctor's
records
um recommending
dosage and potency limits especially for
patients under 21.
uh my video is frozen your video is
frozen you know you
sound perfect you just now froze as long
as you guys
as long as you still getting my
audiobook i was blowing out my dab you
just came right back dude i was blowing
up my dab and i looked and i was like is
he frozen or am i that high
um that works i needed to take a breath
anyway so
you're doing great it's a lot harder for
um under 18 year olds to purchase
cannabis concentrates one of the other
things that freaked them out
was recreational patients can only buy
eight grams of concentrates a day
medical patients could buy 40. um i was
surprised to learn that the number is
40. i was pretty sure it was
um like 50 something because 28 plus 28
and that's where the limit comes from
you know i've been at a shop that sells
me 56.
yeah all of the articles that i've read
recently have
specified the old limit was 40.
huh i was getting 56 at one spot shout
out to that place
that should have been the limit the way
i understand the way the law is written
it's just literally 15 news articles in
a row said the old limit was 40. i think
the bill language even says the old
limit was 40. wow
but it's pretty clear by one of the
other provisions in this bill that
people that understand colorado's
marijuana laws
and work kind of inside them were not
involved really
this is a bill written by anti-cannabis
people and
people they've managed to scare
um so they're requiring under 21 year
olds to go to two doctors
they've made it a really hard to be a
cannabis
uh doctor only um they're trying to push
so that anyone with a medical marijuana
card
is getting that from their primary care
physician
or if they're under 18 a primary care
physician and
a recommended specialist that already
has access to their whole medical
history
wow there's again this i really need to
stress this listeners this bill is not
meant
to do good or to make better or to
improve it is meant to hamper hinder
and destroy um explicitly
the people behind this are gleeful on
facebook over the death blow they've
served colorado's medical marijuana
program
this bill started out as a potency cap
at 15
um we'll get to that in a second
so if you're under 21 you've got to go
see two doctors
they made it way harder to be a medical
marijuana doctor in colorado
they're probably going to get incredibly
scarce as well
and we're slowly going to start seeing
other physicians who don't specialize in
cannabis being forced
to learn and catch up with the rest of
us
and then fill the gap that's created
when the medical marijuana doctors
start disappearing it changes the
purchase limits for
medical marijuana period down to eight
grams of concentrates per day
if you're under 21 so you're um
between 18 and 21 because if your
parents are shopping for you if you're
under 18 and you can't go into the
building
i believe those people could still get
full 8 grams of concentrates but if
you're between
the ages of 18 and 21 you'll be limited
to just
two per day so if you're an 18 year old
with stomach cancer
who's using concentrates as medicine
your life just got real [ __ ] shitty
um there's no other way to say it you
can't like imagine if you had to fill
your prescription
medicine in a day or two or three or
four days
yeah yeah if you had to go to the
pharmacy six times a month to get your
medicine
and have stomach cancer at the same time
like
it's super unfunctional and that's the
point they want to make it hard and
unfunctional um
so those are the main changes to medical
marijuana they also want to
one of the big ones that i almost just
forgot bad mike
um they're gonna set up a statewide
medical marijuana tracking
they want system yeah a function to our
tracking system metric
that tracks cannabis product from
a seed stage or clone stage through
moving out into the consumer world so
like you they track it to the dispensary
and then as the dispensary sells it
there's just a form that says they sold
that pound of weed
you know three and a half grams at a
time all day long until it was gone
they want it set up so that it marks
that
jeff bought three grams on monday and
three more grams on wednesday and i came
in on tuesday and bought four grams and
then seven grams on sunday
they want it all specific to the patient
so that
the state registry will kick out an
error at a retail level if an 18 to 21
year old
tries to store hop and buy more than
2 grams per day
they also want it set up so that the
doctor's recommendation of
you should have um
[Music]
x amount of cannabis per dose x amount
of doses per day
so like when you your other stuff it's
in milligrams so 50 milligrams in the
morning
by mouth with food or whatever or three
times a day with
just water they want the same thing with
marijuana or cannabis medicine
and they also want a potency attachment
too because one of the theories they've
built into the bill is that the higher
the potency number
the more problematic it becomes um
consumption consequence wise they're
the people behind this bill have an
operating theory
that cannabis concentrates cause
schizophrenia
so like these aren't sane people a lot
of them are
very tragic figures um i can get into
that too
but i kind of want to stay focused on
the bill before i get too slowly off
yeah and 280d off into the corner
um so that's the medical marijuana stuff
um the tracking program
super unfeasible right now
the last time i worked with metricmetric
was not capable of doing that it was
barely capable of doing what we're
asking it to do
asking it to track retail enough so
that the state database knows how many
grams of medical marijuana everybody
bought last week is going to be really
complicated
there's another state that actually does
that they used to they don't anymore
they just
changed that system to the fro i think
so uh but they used to go by units and
you were allowed so many units per month
and the state would know how many units
you have and it would be in your
computer
and as you shop just like you would say
mike's got 100 units and you'd buy
whatever and then it would take it out
of your units
yeah like a concentrate would be two
units and a flower a gram would be a
unit or whatever
i don't know how they broke it down but
um the folks behind this bill
really hoped this would kill medical and
i think that's a big reason
they don't have any sort of tracking
system for reg
or for recreational it's just it's just
specifically targeted on the med program
um they're making it harder on doctors
they're making it harder on dispensaries
they're making it harder on med grows
the whole point is to squeeze the
medical industry until it just shutters
and colorado just has a recreational
industry because
people needing cannabis medicine is
bulletproof
politically it's got support
in the 70s and 80s yeah the
anyone who spent any time working in or
around
marijuana knows its healing potential um
sanjay gupta is an incredible example of
staunch prohibitionist who worked
against us spending time
near us and having his eyes opened
wide to the point where he was a major
advocate for
years with those camp weed specials on
cnn
if you don't know what i'm talking about
please google sanjay gupta weed specials
is four or five hours of wonderful
television
if you're unfamiliar with medical
marijuana those will get you all cut up
um so some other parts of this bill
uh limiting medical purchasing down from
from 40 grams a day to eight is pretty
brutal
for a lot of med patients
um it also sets money aside to study
um cannabis potency because
you can't just give people concentrates
and see what happens to them
that'd be wildly unethical according to
modern psychology and modern medical
studies
and the dea and nida won't allow it
so the odds that this money
is used for actual research is zero or
maybe one percent
so they'll probably pull articles
and just compile their findings from
other articles where they tried to look
at this
nobody's really done the research um
which is funny because the original
marijuana research where they discovered
the thc and cbd molecule was done with
ashish
and the researcher has a lovely story
about going to the police station and
picking up confiscated kilos and then
riding on a public bus back to the lab
with them
so hashish and concentrates have been
part of marijuana research
since the first day we started
researching it mike what if we try to
transport some
uh medical concentrates on the bus now
like hey
mike i'm just going to laugh really hard
putting it on the contractions portion
of a manifest
that'd be so funny walk the bus stop bus
one one seven
ride to stop 74. you guys that work
metric i want to know if this works for
you i saw somebody uh in the directions
it said planned route it said uh
quickest possible route or most logical
route or something like that
and they just typed that as their whole
travel guide so that was my go-to for
like the last year i did manifest
really did it work for you i never had
anybody complain
no you're not in jail so that works my
favorite thing i submitted my med badge
and there's the thing that when you
submit it
it says hey just because you're
submitting your badge doesn't mean
you're relinquished of any crimes you
may have committed while you had this
badge yeah it doesn't that [ __ ] is
so funny yeah this isn't like you didn't
just hit safe by [ __ ] tapping out of
the game
you could still be [ __ ] that was that
was a great clause they made sure i
signed that little stipulation i was
like yeah
i just need this because other stuff not
worried um
all right mike so they're going to limit
our concentrate uh purchases
i want to ask do you think uh that this
is just going to send
people to the black market the free
market sorry the what is it
there are so many words um i still say
black
black market i get that the cannabis
market is such a weird space and the
history of it is super interesting
and so it's very different than other
illicit markets
in the late 90s and the time when we
were really involved it was
small home grows and friends and
associates and that's a reason that
there weren't a lot of bodies
you know like we just stopped being
friends when
somebody [ __ ] up or we just didn't
like that guy or maybe somebody got beat
up you know
like there weren't major shootouts over
turf and [ __ ]
um but uh
it never fully went away it just stopped
having a point here in colorado like
it's just so easy to hit the dispensary
i don't have to call anybody
i don't have to arrange anything um the
odds that
what we grew up in has a major
resurgency or resurgence here is pretty
slim
i think what's likely to happen is it's
going to squeeze medical to death
and so there's going to be a slow
turnover of
all of the places that have med and
wreck are slowly going to convert their
med to
more wreck and the places that just have
med
are gonna be desperate as [ __ ] to
convert to wreck
because med still i'm
99 sure requires patient
sign ups for plant counts
um my medical program function knowledge
is a little rusty because
i'm not even a med card holder for the
first time in like
15 years right now because i've been so
damn busy [ __ ] i haven't even been on
the show
right um so i've even let my med card
lapse but i'm 99
sure medical dispensaries here still
need patience to sign up with them
so that they can have a plant limit
and grow it in their grow and when med
medical marijuana doctors vanish
they're going to be way hard up for
patients
starting in a few months because patient
numbers drop off every month
you know so like this bill was designed
to kill medical and it's probably gonna
do it
it's frustrating i was really surprised
with how little the industry pushed back
on this
as soon as they got the potency cap
pushed to a potency study they sat out
the rest of the fight which sucks
i didn't hear too much about it stuff i
hear a lot about a lot of these things
and this one was kind of quiet
i feel like this one's coming out the
time
um the couple of times i brought it up
because there was a packaging
requirement that was tied to this where
they were gonna have
yeah all cannabis concentrates had to be
sold
in one tenth of a gram containers
which would mean you could still go buy
your 8 grams but instead of 8 jars you
would have to buy
80 jars or they would have to figure out
a way to divvy up
well it's inside the jar into 10 set
easily identifiable segments
um that got cut out thank god through an
amendment
um but instead they inserted like three
million dollars in funding
for uh an educational campaign to talk
to youth about extracted thc
um another million a year to keep that
program going through 2024
um another two million dollars for
one of the local universities to
research
cannabis potency and the effects of
potent cannabis products on humans
another 1.7 million dollars to create a
reporting system for coroners
to report all
um violent deaths so anything but died
of old age they want
a tox screen run and those results
reported to a statewide database
because the people behind this bill are
a hundred percent sure
that if you smoke cannabis you commit
suicide later
especially if you're dabbing um they
write books about it they go to
conferences where they tell each other
about it
i mean it's i smoked a gram
of concentrates while we've been sitting
here on zoom we've been on zoom for much
longer than we've been recording this
podcast i've consumed a gram
this jar is empty i showed the jar i
kind of want to go something i've never
done on a podcast on my show i've done
it
as a guest i want to get up and go to my
concentrate location and acquire another
jar
and uh i have no desire to hurt myself
or other people bro
it's [ __ ] shenanigans it's [ __ ]
is what that is it's [ __ ] stupid
so between the ages of
12 and 30. all of the crazy happens
and like that's when you leave the house
for the first time
that's when you discover who you are as
a person that's where you go on
[ __ ] i can't believe we lived through
that kind of [ __ ] bro type adventures
um that's the and then the vans started
rolling type
that's the age group yeah yeah and if
you look at all of the metrics
like that age group dies young
the most like in that window it's not 40
year olds it's not 10 year olds it's
like 16 to 30.
um that's also when mental illness
appears
that's also when um
other disorders like anxiety bipolar
opposition defiant those can really come
to a head in the late teens early
twenties
and the other thing that happens then is
you start
experimenting with narcotics and and
alcohol tobacco pot those are the big
three
sex drugs and rock and roll man yep it's
just not the same if you don't do all
three
um
but gotta go fast for a large part the
people behind this bill
and the people that make up the
anti-cannabis movement are people who
had loved ones who died young
and were using cannabis to some extent
before they died some of these people
were clearly experiencing mental illness
one of the things that you learn when
you study depression and mental illness
and psychology
is that when people are in a state of
mental anguish
or anxiety depression
you self-medicate with anything you need
your hands on
yeah and anyone who's known someone with
mental illness or depression
especially when that was emerging in
them
they self-medicate wildly because you
think
i'm not depressed i'm tired so you drink
a lot of you start abusing caffeine
the caffeine starts taking its toll so
you start smoking pot or drinking at
night to take the edge off so you can
unwind
and that tends to make mental illness
worse and so there's
definitely a cycle that can start when
a young person starts suffering and
starts
self-medicating and then eventually
commits suicide
and if you look at it objectively from
the outside you can see that
oh it's not an a leads to b leads to c
thing
it's it was all depression and
all of the steps you're seeing aren't
steps
they're not dominoes they're symptoms
that all come from the middle thing
yeah and when you're up close
all you see is the loss and
when we were kids these people would
yeah
you seek to place blame and when we were
kids these people
ended up to some extent going from
middle school to middle school to tell
you not to smoke crack
um or whatever it was of the day don't
don't drink my kid died in a drunk
driving accident
don't do coke my kid died coked out in a
car accident
don't do heroin my my favorite son who
was a wrestler and a star
athlete died of heroin like now they
have
online anti-pop groups that they can get
whatever from
these groups have been throwing
everything they can
at the wall trying to see what sticks
and the only two things that get any
traction with anybody anymore
are the potency argument and the think
about the kids argument
save the children and
i mean i was really disgusted to see
that this gained traction
i was horrified when it got all the
sponsors i got
i was horrified with how quickly it
moved through
the colorado house and senate um
jared polis is incredibly pro-cannabis
had a big signing event where the people
behind this bill went to the governor's
mansion and hung out around him
at the signing table while he signed it
and then got to take home the ceremonial
pens and [ __ ]
and some of that's just the pomp and
circumstance that goes with
bill signing ceremonial depends that's
just
like a lot of times they just
five of them get signed and you read
about it in the news
the next day these five bills got signed
into law here's what they do
there's no ceremony there's no
ceremonial pens there's just
the process being fulfilled legally
and so the fact that there was a signing
ceremony in ceremonial pens was
disturbing in its own right because
that pop and circumstance isn't
necessarily
standard even though it is common and to
see a pro-cannabis
governor sign an anti-cannabis
bill that's only thinly veiled as a
regulation build was pretty ugly did we
just lose video again i saw you glitch
and then wave
you're bad good audio yep audio is
beautiful so you're back
yeah the audio stays good yeah i'm
recording on a backup source as well so
i'm thinking trying to do this right
um yeah i always thought that dude was
on our team and then when i read what he
had done i was like wait what but
yeah he did a couple other things that
confused me too so i'm not i don't even
want to talk too much about politics
like
i don't know enough but i feel like i
learned
certain people because they they
represent us okay i'm scrolling through
the article on the westward here just to
make sure i'm hitting all the points i
need to and the the paragraph right here
is the recreational marijuana industry
has stayed largely neutral or silent on
the bill
um the medical marijuana community which
means
actual community members or they would
have said industry um
voiced the loudest resistance um over a
hundred medical marijuana doctors
sent an opposition letter to the
governor asking him to veto
um i don't think the governor's veto
would have done anything
because it looks like they really did
have the votes to force it through
regardless
that's rough um
[Music]
this sets up a couple of studies that
because of the limitations in this
policy and law
the the study can only conclude that
concentrates are scary
and we don't know enough and i think
that's going to be enough for them to
try to push concentrates out of the
wreck market
in two years
yeah the people behind these bills their
goal is to [ __ ]
and to destroy and they know that they
can't
like if they just ran a straight up
let's repeal amendment 64 and go back to
prohibition
that they would get laughed out of the
[ __ ] state like maybe not even left
maybe rudd not on a rail
like um but
they found ways where they can get in
on the side conversation and they can
bleed us dry
and one of them was let's keep adding
taxes yeah
until there was no money left to pay the
people
and they got real close to doing it that
way
and got stuck yeah there's so many taxes
yep they came up with the let's do the
potency bill
and two or three years ago we were able
to just we hired
all of the petition circulating
companies
and we made sure they were otherwise
occupied and the
the anti-pop people were just straight
up about the fact that they didn't have
a broad enough coalition to support to
get the signatures anyway without a
hired company
and then this year they
found a way to get the legislators to
push it forward through them so they
didn't need
any signatures yeah they got a couple of
sponsors to take their
their language and tweak it a little bit
and throw it forward
and the original bill would have killed
the concentrate industry completely
yeah completely yeah things you were
telling me about the industry down for
a couple of years some of the things you
said the past few months had me worried
i was like clutching my dab rig going
hey wait but i mean what are they gonna
do with my dabs
yep and it's we're in one of those weird
fluxes
i mean historically society makes a
bunch of progress
and things get newer and better and more
interesting
and then a period of conflict happens
like an 18-month pandemic to shut
everything down
and then things go conservative for a
while
sometimes it's a minute sometimes it's
10 years
and it usually the pendulum swings the
other way for a bit
um you can go back and pull some like
[ __ ] level lyrics from the 1930s
because the 20s and 30s had a big sexual
revolution
that was so far repressed they had to
[ __ ] reinvent that [ __ ] in the 60s
um mike's over here making wap
references
a couple months late but i'm still
impressed life's different
um it's just
this feels like something we're gonna
backslide on and i
really need the community to give a [ __ ]
about us because it's not a good thing
um
the powers that be are pissed that they
can't take away our voting rights
because we like cannabis they're pissed
that they can't take away our property
because we like cannabis
they're really pissed that we've made an
industry
out of buying selling growing and
consuming cannabis and if they can find
a way
to put the genie back in the bottle and
go back to kicking doors in because you
might have a quarter ounce of weed in
the table
they're gonna and we can't let them
and this is them trying the best they
know how right now to backslide
if you get online and look for like
project sam
or smart approaches to marijuana talking
about this bill in colorado
their language is explicit colorado's
experiment with legalization has failed
full stop proof of that is this
regulation bill where we're finally
going to hold
those evil marijuana people accountable
and we
finally fought and hard-won regulations
and they act like we don't have any
rules
they act like it's people growing in
their basements and selling it on street
corners to toddlers
it's insane and they get away with it
because
people like me have two kids now and we
don't make it to all the meetings
anymore
right and i'm over here running a
podcast and not doing my job i guess
so mike how do we to start wrapping up
because we've been going for uh long
enough uh how do we
make sure that [ __ ] doesn't happen like
this uh to us in the future here in
colorado but in places where they are
working on legalization and building
their foundation
uh how did we miss this and how do we
make sure stuff like this doesn't keep
happening and what can we do i want to
get some final moments from
some some mike's minutes if you will i
think this happened because the industry
grew complacent
um part of our legal industry is chase
people like me out because we're
annoying
um we remind the boss that federal law
says brakes are a [ __ ] thing
we we call the boss when it's 105
degrees in the building in our property
oh you tell me hey buddy you're driving
too fast with all the
dab rig and you're in the cup holder
you're that guy that's why that's why we
call him white mike you guys that's his
[ __ ] job
i like the boss don't like it when you
tell him you won't
skirt the law for the same amount of
money they just don't like it
they don't like it when you call them on
the [ __ ] and that's what advocates
do is we see something that's wrong and
it pisses us off and we stand up and
speak about it
and it's it takes a lot of work it takes
a lot of dedication it takes an endless
amount of study and reading um
i mean just knowing this bill was a
thing you have to at least
check the news regularly or you wouldn't
even heard about it
yeah i wouldn't have known without you
it
uh when i asked when
the packaging requirement for hash still
said concentrates had to be served in
tenth of a gram containers
when that was still direct language in
the bill i asked around every time i was
in a shop
y'all hear about the the regulation bill
to come no what do you mean
oh it's it's really [ __ ] up you should
learn about it one of the things is
they're gonna
require packaging oh they wouldn't do
that that doesn't make any sense
that would hurt us they wouldn't do that
that was the take
everywhere and getting people to
understand
that the world don't like us
matter of fact most of them grew up
sitting in circle
talking about how much they ought to
hate us to shun us to chase us out of
the room
like there's still companies that are
big mad that we all smoke weed now and
if they want us to pass a drug test
they're gonna have to pay us a lot
because we'll take a look more shitty
job because we get to smoke weed there
not at the job but i mean you were
allowed afterwards afterwards yeah like
yeah
tell you what to do at home as soon as
the boss starts talking to you about
what to do in your off hours it's time
to find a new boss
yep that's the truth or create a job of
your own
and they don't like that they've lost
that bit of control
and a lot of industries have their hands
tied because
in the full prohibition days we used to
pay people
to think up ways to try to convince me
and jeff not to smoke weed
and so they were like you can't ever
hold a license
operating heavy equipment or driving a
truck
or um using a forklift
or working in like the meatpacking
industry
like they get all those [ __ ] people
have to get drug tested constantly
the fast food employees and they they
got
insurance companies to give the
companies big discounts if they would
just drug test their employees
and so one by one all of these
industries got a little thumb
on their necks saying we've got a drug
test yep
and places like colorado the company's
forced to choose between
eating that insurance discount or drug
testing their people and not having a
workforce
like it's just people got to stay
vigilant and stay on top of this stuff
and we really need to start electing
better people
holy [ __ ] um predictably the sponsors of
this bill
one of the main sponsors is a
pediatrician
a pediatrician and she's talking about
18 year olds cannabis habits she's a
pediatrician
yeah what do you think her take on this
is do you think her patients are honest
with her
do you think 18 year olds are honest
with their dog that [ __ ] wasn't
right doctors like you smell like
cigarettes and i can see them on the
floor over there where they fell out of
your pants you sure you don't smoke yeah
i don't smoke dog
like i certainly don't smoke weed doc
yep you'll tell my mom i can't have her
now
yeah like it's just ridiculous and then
they fear-monger this [ __ ] in and it's
really gonna [ __ ] with the industry
the that potency study it's set up in
this bill
so that a commission is formed to do the
study
and then whatever recommendations they
make
the med and
the department of revenue have to figure
out how to make them a rule
and so if they come back saying our
research shows that anything above 15
thc is considered a hard drug which if
they just google
where does the netherlands not to stop
caring about cannabis
it's i think it's 15 thc oh wow and
all of a sudden we've got that rule here
where anything above 15
is a no go like it's that could happen
in other states i think uh
there's one state on the east coast that
has a potency cap already i think it's
for concentrates how do you what what do
you so what if you make a concentrate
that's over 60
what do you do you got to throw some
other [ __ ] in there that's
the with what though yeah right i don't
even want to know
what that's gross all right like i said
i was going to give you a mike's moment
and i gave you like an hour and a half
20 minutes
yeah i knew that's what i was going to
get out of you we were going to try to
wrap this up half an hour folks thanks
thanks for listening to the rambles
folks we appreciate it thank you for
being on the show but also bro you were
saying how much dedication reading time
and energy it takes to be an advocate
thank you bro because without you laying
all that groundwork i wouldn't be able
to do
i wouldn't be able to put the [ __ ]
seeds in it that's the greatest way i
could put it
so thank you bro we need you out there
we need more guys like you out there
doing it so
you guys if you are curious on how to be
active how to get involved in the
political side
uh not everybody's a grower not
everybody's a podcaster if you want to
do some behind the scenes work and get
legalization going where you are
get it going contact mike he will help
you out teach you how to do all that
stuff give you some tips and tricks
he's a busy dude but he will respond to
you i do promise that
and you can totally stay anonymous doing
this also
it's harder but in none of my advocacy
has anyone ever checked my id
so you could fully be any sort of pen
name you want as long as it's believable
and letters to the editor have
a lot of weight to them the powers that
be still really like newspapers
and they don't have an ability to check
who's at the end of the email either
so you just submit an email go to
outlook
you can create a new outlook email in
about four seconds
and you can be anybody you want to be
just the more people speaking out the
better it is for everybody
mike is feeding the trolls yeah yeah the
more people the better that's definitely
it we need more
so there are a lot of people that are
sitting around smoking listening to the
show loving the show
uh just send an email if you're if
you're working on some sort of
legalization where you live
send an email all right we've done
enough with the political talking about
sending emails and stuff mike
i want to thank you for hanging out bro
uh i need to go get some more
concentrates out of my concentrate
supply
it is time for us to bro out for a few
minutes and just talk off camera here
you don't get enough time to adult and
hang out so we're going to
abuse some of that privilege thank you
again for hanging out bro
do you want to remind people how to
stalk you on social media just because
they all have 80d and they already
forgot what you said at the start of the
show
um you can find me at twitter at
nemopunk15
you can find me on facebook at pueblo
for sensible cannabis laws
and you can find me on patreon at
patreon.com forward slash
white mike there you go nice and
professionally done
uh ladies and gentlemen boys girls pimps
hoes friends foes smokers growers
activists and dab cavists oh man my
connection is cut out right as i said
that but
i hope i'm still recording all of that
because it was [ __ ] smoothie guys i
hope you heard that
um if you feel like this episode was
educational informative and or
entertaining maybe you'd like to support
my patreon it is patreon.com forward
slash grow from your heart
if you've got questions corrections
comments or concerns the email address
is grow from your heart at hotmail.com
yeah it's old school don't make fun of
me
uh the website of course is
iriegenetics.com all kinds of good [ __ ]
at iregenetics.com check it out support
the brand
i think that is all i've got for you
thank you for listening thanks to mike
for being a guest
i'm going to wrap it up now i'll be back
in a couple of days with fresh new
content
you know i want to give a big shout out
to my buddy stabby mick [ __ ]
stab
dude stab wood shout out stabby and
until next time take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me