yeah welcome to the show podcast world
i'm your host my friends call me ross to
jeff and this
is episode 654 of the grow from your
heart podcast in this episode i'm going
to focus on a breeding question
before we get to that part of the show
let's do a few shout outs to a few of
the kind folks who support the show on
patreon
let's start off with the big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to my friend alabama man let's send a
big thank you shout out to chief leaf
and caribou heart tv
i want to send a big thank you shout out
to my buddy glenn jeroni let's send a
special thank you shout out to all mixed
up
i want to send a big thank you shout out
to mister let's send a thank you shout
out to frankie and trium up
let's send a big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to singlet
and 716 vibes
i want to send a big thank you shout out
to samurai gardens and then let's wrap
it all up with the big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out
to queen city creations big thanks and
big shout out to everybody
who continues to support the show on
patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need is right
there on the screen and of course there
is a link in the show notes and the
video description
to make it nice and easy for all of my
friends
really quickly uh big shout out to my
buddy white mike for pointing out
the patreon link to my patreon in the
video descriptions
uh was wrong when i cut and pasted it
and put some dot dot dots and it didn't
finish the whole link so i gave you a
dead link i apologize my fault
i didn't get any patreon contributions
because of that i know i did get some i
didn't get new ones you didn't have a
link
my fault my bad patreon.com forward
slash girl from your heart the link in
the previous videos
is no good i apologize there's always
one little mistake
that's an easy mistake to fix all right
where do we go from there shout out to
white mike thank you for the update that
i made
a minor slash major mistake i'm sure you
may notice by now if you're watching on
the video format that i'm attempting to
record in a multi-cam format
again thank you for watching the
multicam experiment here i'm learning
this i did realize that in the last
episode
uh there were a couple of hiccups if you
will i don't know what happened dude i'm
learning i'm new at this we'll figure it
out
come along for the ride with me be
patient we'll get it going i still feel
like i put out a quality episode last
time none of the information really got
lost there was one jump cut
where it felt like a couple of seconds
of the video may have disappeared i
don't know what happened if you didn't
notice i didn't notice it was [ __ ]
perfect bro
anyway thank you for coming on this
multi-cam journey with me we're learning
together somebody told me a long time
ago they were worried about all of the
uh technical additions to the show they
didn't want it to take away from the
podcast
i'm not going to let it take away from
the main focus of the show which is
teaching you
uh sharing my knowledge with you on how
to grow quality cannabis how to improve
your garden
uh today we're gonna focus on breeding i
got a great question about breeding
a lot of people ask me about breeding uh
and it's time to talk more about it so
we're gonna do that in just a moment
obviously i'm stoned and rambly today
but i won't let all the new gear
uh distract me from the focus of the
show i write the show
i do all the stuff on the computer on
the paper i do all that then we play
with all the gear
i've just added a step i don't let it
take from the previous steps i just
added more to it
i think it's going to go well it's
always got to keep evolving getting
better or it will get stale
got to keep moving forward you guys
can't stay where we were right move
forward do what you can do
all right i should move forward and quit
talking about the same thing
this episode will come out right after 7
10 7 10
snuck up on me this year there aren't
any major cannabis events going on in my
area that i'm aware of
uh no vending opportunities no major
consumption opportunities we just came
out of a really weird time here in the
world
so nobody really prepared anything for
the 710 event there is a
another non-cannabis related event i
will be attending on 7 10
i'm probably the only dab cadet in there
everybody else will be there for another
thing
uh but yeah 7 10 snuck up on me when you
hear this it will be
post 710. i hope everybody had a
wonderful beautiful 710 i hope you
stocked up on concentrates
uh they will sell out quickly this time
of year the places where you go to get
your dabs may not have dabs because 710
is coming
really quickly if you don't know about
710 we'll just ramble on to that one for
a moment i have done a full podcast
episode
one year ago did a full episode about
i bust out a bunch of equipment i should
probably do that again now that i'm
doing two cameras maybe get another
camera and do that one
but 7 if you flip the number 710 upside
down it actually says the word oil
so 710 is a good time to smoke oil we
take dabs now at 7 10. a lot of people
smoke
flowers or a joint or a blunt or a bong
rip at 4 20.
now 7 10 is when you smoke some dabs 710
is
dab culture it is the new 420 so that's
what i'm talking about when i say 710
happy 710 everybody i'm sorry i didn't
put out a 710 episode i'm sorry i missed
that it snuck up on me this year
like i said lots of stuff going on and
no events so we didn't pay attention to
710 that light right there is making my
eye twitch that was really awkward on
camera
not even going to edit that i hope you
saw it um where do we go from here
i want to give a big shout out to
shikari richardson that's right i'm not
going to delve too far into this topic
this is
everybody's heard about it every
cannabis consumer has heard about what
happened to
the lovely shikari richardson a uh an
olympic
runner has been uh basically stopped
from running not allowed to run in
certain events because
she failed a cannabis drug test that's
right she had weed in her system
the place where she consumed cannabis
cannabis was legal at the time or she
consumed it it was legal there
she was in a place where she could smoke
cannabis she also had a family member
just passed away i believe it may have
been her mom just passed away
i know god i don't even want to think
about that moment but i'm going to smoke
some cannabis when my mom passes i
promise you
ah but uh the person was just doing life
and where they were life was
happening and that was legal and because
they're an olympic athlete because they
did something that was a
was legal where they were now they can't
compete in an event
um that's [ __ ] it's kind of shitty
that somebody can't compete because of
cannabis use
also i have friends who are athletes i
hang out with a couple yeah
i'm not an athlete myself at all but i
do have a diverse group of friends
uh shout out to my friend who had a
conversation with me doesn't want his
name set on my show i'm sure of it
uh shout out to my buddy who had a
conversation with me today he is
an athlete he's competed in uh major
events i think he may have been in an
olympic he was a he's a wrestler the
dude's a wrestler
uh his brother was a ufc fighter uh they
said
that when you are in these types of
events that it's not just a paper
contract you don't just read paper and
you sign [ __ ] and say that's the rules
there's a meeting there's a discussion
people talk to you
and they put it into your head lots of
times there is no
cannabis use while you were under this
contract
yeah cannabis may be legal in colorado
oregon california wherever you want to
go
that it's legal it may be legal there
but if you choose to be
an olympic runner you are forfeiting
that this is your new
thing your new contract this rule
supersedes all of those rules
you can't do it just like if you want
some jobs you have to pass a drug test
you can't do certain jobs if you want to
be a cannabis consumer
the olympics are the same way so there
is kind of a
being a person who wants freedom and
free cannabis and legalized cannabis and
let's all smoke and have a good time and
i feel that athletes need cannabis
just as much if not more than anybody
they're struggling their bodies hurt
they're under
strain mentally and physically all day
long they need something to calm down
make themselves feel better i think it
feels good
when i move heavy stuff after i take a
dab after that i don't feel like i moved
a bunch of heavy stuff
i think athletes should be allowed to
consume i think everybody should be
allowed to consume responsibly
but she did sign a paper she did shake
hands and say i won't do that my job
depends on it so
that's kind of a 50 50 i'm torn between
that how i feel on it was her
responsibility to
not get caught consuming cannabis is
what that was uh
she was gonna do it don't get caught so
um that was her responsibility but
where i'm leading to that i do want to
give a shout out
to one of her sponsors if you know my
personal life if you know me if you pay
attention my social media you know i'm a
big old sneakerhead
quarantine covid the lockdown got me
bored i wasn't allowed to go anywhere
usually i go to a comedy show or a
concert every single weekend if not two
or three of those
a week during covet i wasn't going
anywhere we were sitting here
zooming and being on a zoom video was
not enough for me
i developed a ridiculous sneaker
addiction that's right i've got
we won't go too far into that because it
could be a problem i may need an
intervention
find me up on intervention taking away
my sneakers uh but i wanted to give a
shout out to nike because nike is
shikari richardson's official sponsor
and
nike did not revoke their sponsorship
which i think is kind of cool
in this uh day and age i feel like such
an old guy when i say that
your sponsors bail out if you say
something wrong very quickly your
sponsors cancel you and forget about you
very quickly if you make the wrong move
and for nike to support uh they're in
dorsey i think that's the appropriate
word that just came out smoothly we're
gonna go with it
for nike to support this in dorsey like
that and not drop them not fire them not
pull any ads not take any funding not
take any merch deals
that is really cool so shout out to nike
for doing that a lot of people are gonna
say you're shot not a big old
corporation
they're standing up for a cannabis
consumer which is kind of cool and
they've also uh been putting out some
cannabis
friendly uh shoes and merch so that's
kind of cool
um that's enough uh what is it pop
culture current news current events we
don't need enough of that on that we
don't need much of that on this show
let's focus on cannabis
a lot of people are going to listen to
this episode because this is going to be
the episode
about breeding that's right i've got an
email here about breeding
uh many people listen to the podcast
they may not know
that i am also the founder breeder sole
proprietor
uh i am the one man army of ire genetics
i read genetics premium seeds is a seed
company
i slash we make regular and feminized
seeds
i'm sure most people that listen to the
show know that but i'm sure there's a
few people out there that have no idea
that i even make seeds that's just
something that may have not gotten to
their radar but i make seeds i'm irie
genetics premium seeds
i'm fairly well known for my breeding
technique my breeding methods my methods
are tried and trued i've got
a couple of male plants a few male
plants have passed through my stable
that have been proven to be studs i've
got a very uh
reliable selection of female plants um
and my breeding skills have been proven
uh and i think i'm breeding
with purpose and from a good place so i
feel like i can give you a good little
rundown on breeding and a lot of people
have been asking for it is where i think
i was headed with that
a lot of people have been asking me for
breeding tips and i don't talk about it
a lot on the show honestly because
i wanted to make sure to give all of the
basic grow tips first i mean i need you
you need to be able to grow it's not you
don't need i guess you
it's better if i shouldn't say need
because you can pull off seeds no matter
what if you try
uh it's better if you know how to grow
if you understand the plant before you
start breeding you shouldn't
in my opinion just start breeding right
away have a good relationship with the
plant understand how it grows
understand the functions of the plant
then understand what you're looking for
in breeding build
just have a good foundation so i wanted
you to get that before i started doing
too much about breeding also
my business is breeding that's part of
what that's how i survive so why do i
want to teach everybody else how to
breed but at this point
i'm very insecure with my role in the
breeding community with my role in the
cannabis community i can teach you how
to breed
i'm going to do my thing forever it's
not going to push me out of a job out of
the market or anything like that so i'm
willing to share my knowledge
grow from your heart breed with love
let's uh cut me off of this [ __ ]
ramble fest and let's actually jump into
this email
and we'll set up this part of the show
it goes just like this it says ross to
jeff i'm
not sure if i'm submitting this in the
proper area
but i am a long time listener and i grow
personally for companies and for myself
for over
five years there's a lot there in that
first sentence you did submit it to the
appropriate channel you sent that to
grow from your heart at hotmail.com that
got right to me thank you
uh longtime listener thank you i do
appreciate that long time listener first
time emailer it looks like
uh thanks for the great message because
this one is a good one got me off on a
good ramble
uh says i grow personally and for
companies now that's gonna get my
attention because this is a breeding
question
before i even get to the breeding part
let me ramble about this
if you work for a big company that has
plants that are in flower
and you are breeding at home it is your
responsibility as the grower slash
breeder
slash person with all the plans do not
pollinate that commercial grow if you
grow at work that's a commercial grow
do not contaminate that grow with pollen
they are relying on that crop to pay
your bills your rent comes from that
crop the patients the customers the
consumers don't want that crop seeded
because you decided
to be a a new breeder a pollen chucker
at home if you
successfully breed some seeds without
contaminating that crop at work
we'll call you a breeder if you [ __ ] up
and pollinate that entire crop at work
you're a shitty pollen chucker and you
didn't do your job right so
the first thing you need to do is make
sure in my opinion the first thing you
should do
maybe need to do i try not to use words
like should and need but
this i feel like it's appropriate you
you need to make sure
you should make sure not to pollinate
that big commercial grow people are
relying on that to be seedless
top shelf quality bud don't seed that
[ __ ] up
so now once you're sure you're not gonna
seed up that grow then we can talk more
about breeding
uh there are several ways to make sure
you don't seed that grow up change your
clothes a lot wash your hair
water deactivates pollen anytime you're
around that male plant when he's
pollinating
just squirt yourself down with pollen
change your clothes have
clothes that you go in the grow room
with and your personal grow
then grow clothes that you don't wear in
the grow so you come out of the grill
you change clothes
possibly take a shower between those
clothes if you have time if it's
possible
come out of the grow change clothes put
on fresh clothes then go to work and put
on different clothes at that growth so
you're using
different clothes in that grow different
clothes at home and different clothes in
your home grow
it sounds tedious it sounds ridiculous
but with the experiments you're trying
to play
with and the money you're putting at
risk at that commercial grow it is what
is necessary
everything from the hat to the shoes
need to be different don't take those
same shoes in your grow that you do to
the commercial grow that should be the
rule of thumb anyway you don't want to
move those bugs around and if you're
getting in the car you're leaving work
getting in the car those bugs are riding
home with you you're bringing them into
the house
you should change clothes take a shower
at that point then go into your grow in
different clothes
it's really hard to keep it all separate
but do the best that you can
keep that pollen away from the other
grow
really don't [ __ ] up that grow so i want
to finish this message but
that really stands out when you say i
want to breed at home and i'm working at
a company
that's going to set off a lot of alarms
for a lot of people don't tell anybody
at the commercial grow that you're
breeding at home
because if one seed pops up they're all
going to blame you they're gonna be like
it's that pollen chucker that's breeding
at home he just seeded everything it's
all gonna be your fault
all right there is more of this message
it says now i'm deciding i want to try
out breeding at a personal level at home
is there a previous episode number you
can point me to for the best breeding
guide
i've actually listened to two episodes
about breeding terms but i'm curious
if you have a more of a guide formatted
episode
already thanks again for everything much
love
uh do they say their name they don't say
that they want their name said so they
know who they are they don't need their
name said on this episode
but they've got a great question let's
talk a little bit about breeding i do
not have
a previous episode where i talk
specifically about breeding i do talk
about
pollination times i've talked a couple
of times about male selection which i'll
touch on here
uh but i don't think i've done the
episode that i owe you
for good breeding so i'm gonna take a
sip of my drink here because i'm sure
you could hear it in my throat
after i get a little moisture on the
face here we will talk about breeding
hang out here we go let's talk about
breeding cannabis uh the main thing one
of the main things to think about
is if you're gonna breed do you want to
pollinate all of the plants or just a
couple of plants because
uh pollen is hard to control if you
don't have some experience and a plan
there are ways to control the pollen but
if you're new
if you don't have some some strategy in
place you could really mess up
like i mentioned earlier do not
pollinate your work
grow do not pollinate your friends grow
do not pollinate the grow down the
street think about that sort of stuff be
kind to the people around you
a lot of people are growing cannabis now
and a lot of people are relying on that
for medicine
a lot of people are also growing hemp
all over the place so you've got to
worry about getting pollinated as well
from other sources so i would recommend
only breeding indoors or in a greenhouse
of some sort
i don't really trust outdoor breeding
because if some guy down the street gets
a male he may breed with me on accident
breed with my plants on accident sounds
better that way okay
one of the main things to think about
when breeding is what is your goal do
you have a goal or are you just pollen
chucking if you're just pollen chucking
that is fun too but it's much better
much more fulfilling
much more rewarding and uh much more
successful
if you have a goal how do you even know
if you were successful if you didn't
have a goal if you're just
putting plant a and plant b in a room
together and putting pollen on the
plants and
letting it happen and then growing the
seeds that's fun but
it was their success in it what was your
goal did you have something in mind did
you want to do something
are you making seeds for do you intend
to eventually be
a commercial seed producer will these
seeds be put to market
are you going to make seeds to give to
your friends are you going to sell them
you're going to pass them out at trade
shows are they going to be gifts are
these are they something you intend on
making to give to
disabled veterans who can't afford seeds
or um
i don't know there's some random group i
was trying to think of some random group
with like
a bunch of random names but then it
almost got offensive in my head like
um just random people from a random
place that do random things that enjoy a
certain thing all those together in one
group are you
specifically finding seeds for those
people who can't afford them
whatever you're doing with the seeds
what is your goal or are you just going
to grow them at your house on your own
or in your commercial grow on your own
what's your goal for the seeds
think about what your goal is it's all
about a goal a lot of things
in productivity of any sort it's all
about your goal you can't get to the
destination to the end
without a good goal from the very
beginning so when we're breeding when
we're making seeds
let's have a goal one of the first goals
to think of is
what am i breeding for who are these
seeds going to how big is this going to
get so think about that from the
beginning and kind of be prepared for
that from the start
then your next goal is to improve upon
the cannabis species not just to make
this strain and this strain because you
want to name it the two strains together
would make a really clever name and you
want to make a million dollars off a
cool strain name
the cool strain name will get you so far
but once people grow those seeds and
realize that they suck because you
didn't do any proper selection
then that strain sucks and now you got a
really popular strain name that is known
for putting out shitty plants so that
that's not the way to do it have a goal
improve upon the species
maybe you've got something that tastes
really good but it lacks potency maybe
you've got something that is super
potent that doesn't taste good
maybe you want to improve upon that
thing somehow then you need to find
a prob i guess you're gonna have a
female if you're smoking it then you
need to find a male
that is going to improve upon that
female when they breed if you breed them
together
and you just make something that is
worse or not better than both of the
plants you started with
you didn't really breed successfully in
my opinion unless
your goal was to isolate one trait if
you don't care about
the potency and the way that it grows
you're just looking for straight up that
one
sour mango terp and that's all you're
breeding for you can do that but
i want potency vigor things that people
often forget about
is stuff like pest resistance pathogen
resistance cold resistance drought
resistance
how does it handle temperature swings
diurnal swings humidity swings
does it take stress well because i put a
lot of my plants in a commercial grow
and no disrespect to the ladies and
gentlemen of the commercial grow but
sometimes they're overworked and they're
stressed and they party too hard on the
weekend or whatever is going on and the
plants have a little uh
they don't get taken care of as much as
they could of maybe saturday and sunday
the weekend crew might be hungover or
whatever and the plants deal with some
stress
i need them to survive that stress in
the commercial grow also
i sell seeds commercially people that
have never grown before are getting my
seeds i want them to have great success
and they're going to beat these plants
up
so it's all about selection we need
plants that are going to survive
drought stress problems uh being popped
and twisted and manipulated
a lot of these things are going to be
delivered by the male plan a lot of
these traits come from the male
side of this equation and a lot of
people are only breeding for
flavor aroma we call we call it in the
industry
instagram ability can you post this
plant like is it going to look good is
it going to sell through
instagram but then when you get it in
your garden like i said a minute ago you
grow it
and it just grows like [ __ ] it grows
real skinny and it falls over
and one of the buds at the top is
beautiful it's [ __ ] purple it's got
red leaves coming off of it instagram
goes ape [ __ ]
but it doesn't grow worth the [ __ ] and
when you smoke it the buzz is miserable
and
there's no good flavor to it it just
looks really good it hit a good lab test
because it's got a lot of trichomes on
it but there's nothing good about it
other than paper and instagram so breed
for the right stuff have a goal
improve upon the plant and don't just be
pollen chucking and they're just a
pollen chuck so
uh selection is key i talked about a lot
of the resistance path
uh pest and pathogen we're just gonna
call that peth that's my new word right
now
uh pest and pathogen resistance comes
from the male a lot of that comes from
the male so
a good male is key to a good breeding
project male selection is very important
i've done full episodes on mail
selection
but selecting the mail let's talk about
choosing a male it's all about your goal
do you want to make uh indica or sativa
dominant plants do you want to make
tall skinny plants do you want to make
short squatty plants do you want to make
plants that flower
in 50 days do you want to make plants
that flower in 70 days do you want to
make
plants that flower in 142 days shout out
to my buddy lemur priest for his 140 day
finishers
um what do you want to make you've got
to choose a male
that will contribute those traits to the
mix
of course he's only going to give 50
percent maybe that's something else
we're going to talk about in a moment
he's only going to give about 50 of his
traits to this cross
what is he shaped like what does he
smell like find a male that has
traits that you want to work with this
is kind of like chefing
this male is one of your ingredients but
we've only got two ingredients to work
with
so what does this male bring to the
table are we mixing
uh what are two flavors that are good
together um
chocolate and anything right chocolate
and strawberries would be good together
um what else is good together i'm just
trying to think of random [ __ ] now but
like savory stuff together is always
good but then if you go and mix
two of the wrong things together
sometimes it just doesn't [ __ ] taste
good that's how breeding is also
you got to have the right two
ingredients if you mix the two bad
ingredients together it's just not gonna
work
you can't put ketchup and milk in the
same bottle and expect that to be good
sometimes breeding goes that way
so find a male with the features that
you're looking for
shape structure leaf size leaf shape
colors does that male plant put out
colors are you looking for a plant that
turns
dark colors red colors purple colors
look for a male plant that exhibits
those traits in the leaves
flowering time we don't want i
personally don't want a male
that takes way too long to flower but i
also don't want a male that shows me
flower too early
something i mentioned this is a good
segue into that uh
if a male plant flowers too early in my
opinion
he contributes too much of himself to
the breeding mix
my goal in breeding most of the time is
to find a male and a female that when
they breed together
you can find a perfect balance of the
male and female
in the offspring you'll see offspring
that look just like mommy just like
daddy and then you'll see some that
you'll say
man i see mommy's growth structure in
there it smells just like daddy it does
that stretching thing that mommy does it
does the leaf shape of the daddy plant
that is my goal is to find a male that
doesn't overpower the female
but still puts enough of itself into
that cross to make the females different
and off to make the offspring different
and something new so i don't want a male
plant that flowers right away
if i have if i get a 10 pack most people
buy a 10 pack of seeds if you've got 10
seeds
you're most likely going to find
somewhere between four and six
males in there for the sake of my story
we're gonna say you've got five male
plants the girls are doing their thing
we're gonna talk about the boys
that first male plant to flower is way
too eager
he's like i want a flower here we go i
don't want to breed with him
i think the offspring he makes is going
to be
mostly like him it's going to be shaped
like him it's going to have the leaf
structure
the build and it's going to flower too
quickly if that plant gets root bound if
that plant doesn't get enough light
it's got an uh what's the word
propensity um wow
big words for me today i'm not even sure
if that's the right [ __ ] word but
we're going with it
uh it could flower early because that
male plant that i used was an
early flowering plant if i've got five i
generally choose
the third or fourth male to go into
flower and start
showing me hey i'm a strong male
flowering plant i want to see big
stamens coming off of it i want to see
rapid growth into flower
that fourth or fifth one will be the
winner sometimes that's not
the third or fourth will probably be the
keeper uh that is not
hard and fast but that is kind of a rule
of thumb and i i kind of have an eye
when i'm popping seeds i can see early
early on
early in veg like when they go from
their small like the cup or their small
veg into their large veg pots i have
usually
already decided that right there is my
breeding male
these two over here are the keeper
females i try not to let my
my intuition like that ruin anything i
try to still be open-minded but most of
the time i'm i'm correct already at that
point
and by the time it's dried and cured and
smoked everybody else already agrees
like you were right bro we saw it from
the beginning because
they've been around so much we just
train them and i share my ideas
but um i kind of got myself lost there
on a ramble but i enjoy that
find a good male plant uh that third or
fourth one is going to be your good male
plant
uh the early ones are going to put too
much of themselves into the mix that
third or fourth one is going to be a
good breeder it's going to have
it's going to pass enough of itself onto
the female to show you what it's got to
offer and then
the female is going to be able to
express itself in the breeding project
and like i said a moment ago that's when
you get the offspring
that shows phenotypes that look like
mommy phenotypes that look like daddy
and then phenotypes that you could see
that perfect
chocolate strawberry mix half of it is
chocolate half of it is strawberry it's
perfectly beautiful
you can see that happen if your
selections are proper if that is your
goal
also maybe that's not your goal maybe
you want to just recreate this female
plant you got to find something that
doesn't adulterate it too much but
most of the time the goal is to make a
cross of those two
that is improving the species in my
opinion you don't want to just make a
photocopy or you don't want to move
backwards unless
you've got a specific goal so good male
is
key maybe a male that displays trichomes
if your male plant is showing trichomes
that is a good thing we want plants that
make trichomes if the males and females
both make trichomes that should add up
to
shabang double trichomes right if you
got a mendel chart and you see trichomes
trichomes that's going to be [ __ ]
trichomes with a capital t
right there on your chart baby uh aromas
i like a male plant you're going to
think i'm crazy i say this a lot i say
this often and i mean it
i do a stem rub on the plants uh early
flower i can already tell
about week two week three of flower what
these plants are gonna start smelling
like for me
i just grab the stem and just rub it
with my fingers and smell it
and if it smells like vomit and trash
can
and acrid disgustingness maybe some
funky feet maybe some rotten socks
that is a plant that i want to breed
with i don't choose to breed with the
sweet candies
smelling male males because i've got
those females i like an
acrid funky male plant that's just gross
i also like a plant with a good
structure that's really important to me
it's got to grow with the good
structure it's got to take some abuse i
will put
just like most people do a phenohunt i
don't know how long it's been since i've
talked about a proper final hunt we'll
talk about that that's when you grow
a number of seeds and you find the
winners out of that pack of seeds you
are hunting for the phenotype that you
select
i will do a phenohunt for boy plants
i'll grow
uh it's colorado so i'll grow 12 seeds
at a time and i'll find
uh the females out of there and just
toss them immediately
and now i've got six or five male plants
to work with and i'll watch them grow
and i'll find the best boy out of there
and i'll pull him aside and then now
i've got one plants and i've got 11 more
seeds that i can crack and i'll run 11
and i'll find another boy in there and
compare it to that first one and i've
done that a couple times until i found
stellar males
so run a final hunt until you find the
male plant that you want if you've only
got 10 seeds there's a male in there
that will work for you
if you've got 100 seeds your opportunity
to find a stellar male are much better
how do you know when you found a good
male the only way to
audition your stud plant is to pollinate
in my opinion
multiple female plants with that plant
you could pollinate one plant with it
and see what it makes maybe you just
made one
really awesome cross that's fun if
that's what you want to do but
if you really want to tell if that male
is a good breeder
hit him to several female plants with
different traits all of those plants
need to have
different different traits i've got a
strawberry starburst that smells like
strawberry bubble gum or it's a
strawberry fields from crockett
smells like strawberry bubble gum i've
got a platinum tangy from garden of
wheaton
it smells straight up like oranges so if
i hit
my male plant to the strawberry and my
male plant to the tangie
i could tell i get this strawberry and
something and oranges and something and
i can tell what this male plant is
bringing to the mix i can see that
when i cross it to this one and to this
one that all of the offspring got tall
and made big purple leaves or i can see
commonalities or
outliers through the breeding by doing
multiple female plants i can
if i hit four or five different females
i could tell what that male is going to
offer
if i just hit one i don't know sometimes
if the things that come from that
offspring
were traits from the grandparents they
could have been
so if i use um i'm just going to say
plant a
and plant b it's going to be easier that
way if i use plant a in plant b
and i make offspring and i name that
number one and number one
shows me things that aren't displayed in
plant a and plant b
it could come from the grandpa the
parents of plant a or plant b
plant a's parents or plant b's parents
and i wouldn't know that if i don't know
that plant's parents
so if i use multiple females i know if
i'm seeing
recessive traits or traits from
grandparents or traits from great
grandparents or if i'm seeing stuff that
is displayed from the male
people wonder why seeds are so expensive
you guys to do it properly to do it
correctly to do it sustainably
uh to do it to where you're around for a
while it does take some work some
research some effort
some care some effort that's a lot of it
is effort a lot of people just think
they're gonna put two plants in a room
and let them hump and make some seeds
and make some money
that will work a couple of times but
then people are gonna buy those seeds
and they're gonna grow them out and
they're gonna go yeah these are
not what i was hoping for we're gonna go
find a breeder that's been doing some
testing and read some books and figured
it out
so um find a good selection pollinate
several females with different traits um
know your goal when you're doing this
the first time you're doing it you're
kind of looking to see what the male
plant does
but you've probably got some plants
you've been working with for a while
uh find a male plant that is different
than the girls if you've got a bunch of
crazy sativa females maybe find an
indica heavy male or something unless
you're looking to make even more
sativa heavy females find something that
is going to reach your goal
but it's more fun when the male is
different than the female so that you
can see what the male is doing
to that mix i keep saying stuff like
that but
once you get there and you have the
seeds and you start growing and you see
what you've created
if it all looks the same you're going to
go my mail plant is
really dominating the mix here because
all of these crosses
all smell like foot and i don't get any
strawberries i don't get any oranges i
don't get any blueberries like i
expected from the females i'm just
getting that
bar trash can and puke from the male
plant you know he's too powerful
got to choose a different male for that
that's never a bad thing
this isn't on the notes yet but we're
going to go into this part
as a responsible breeder something
you've got to do
is know when you've made some trash
if you've just made a bunch of seeds and
you grew out a bunch of them and they're
not impressing you
they aren't better than the parent plant
that you started with
don't sell them don't pass them out
don't try to recoup your losses this was
a breeding project where you learned
these plants don't breed well together
you've got to get rid of that
or just grow it yourself or maybe f2 it
or b
c or b exit whichever one you want to
use shout out to my buddy f1p
um work with it yourself those are yours
but maybe if they're not stellar if
they're not impressive don't put them
out don't sell them
that's when you go making a bad name for
yourself if you want to be around to be
in the industry for a while
do things correctly be honest impress us
with your products
the internet is here forever all of the
[ __ ] you do and say now is recorded
documented programmed written down
digitally stored backed up on a hard
drive
[ __ ] stored in a cloud ready to be
used against you in the court of law the
court of the internet
facebook court instagram court whatever
the [ __ ] court it is time for
somebody is ready to blast your [ __ ] so
do things correctly if you want to stick
around in this industry in this scene
right now if you're a seed breeder
if you're a creator of some sort in this
industry you are a pioneer
you can either be remembered for years
to come as a pioneer in this industry or
you can be one of those people that
popped up
made a couple of bucks we realized
you're just trying to [ __ ] us for a
couple of bucks and now you are gone are
you here forever are you part of the
industry or are you here for the cash
grab
now's the time to make a decision if
you're trying to get into the seed
breeding game for the market
all right that was my weird rant for
this episode um
yeah if you didn't make something good
don't share it that is your
responsibility to make that decision so
pollinate a bunch of females grow that
[ __ ] out uh multiple females are going
to show you what the male does to the
mix
see what he does is this male plant
adding value is he adding value to the
crosses or is he just making a bunch of
reproductions of the females or a bunch
of reproductions of himself or is he
making hemp
if hemp is your goal you're reaching
your goal but if that's not your goal
we've got to figure out
what ma which male plant we can use in
the future to reach your goal crack more
seeds find a better male
repeat the process this is why seeds get
expensive i have thrown away male plants
i've thrown away batches of seeds
for every cross i for every 10 crosses
that i released there are probably five
to ten more that didn't even make it
uh it's not that they were terrible but
i only want to put out
nines and tens and elevens there's a lot
of people out there that are okay with
putting out
fours and sixes and that's cool but
that's just not how i operate i'd rather
put out
nines and tens and elevens because i've
got the opportunity i know i can do it
why waste your time and my time with a
six
if you're a six i still love you um
where are we in this podcast i'm having
fun today
shout out to dabs by the way happy 710
everybody i hope you guys have a
had a wonderful 7 10. is that mail plan
adding value right here oh it's the
phone giving me interference i hope you
guys didn't hear that come through the
microphone something just rattled like
chewbacca in my headphones
i was the phone doing interference with
the gear here enough rambles is that
male plant adding value to your cross is
he doing good or is he just making
more hemp seed for you more bird seed
don't be afraid to throw away a breeding
project go back
start over do it all over again that's
how you learn the most it's going to
take a long time
uh this isn't your last breeding project
hopefully i say
a lot of times when people are freaking
out stressing out over their grow
they're not sure what to do i just say
it's not your last grow it's your first
grow it's the first time you're doing
this we're going gonna have so many more
grows to figure all this stuff out go
ahead and ruin the first one mess it up
that way your fifth and sixth one can be
perfect if you [ __ ] up the fifth one i'm
gonna be mad at you if you get the first
one wrong
that's perfect screw up the first time
screw up the third time script the
fourth time
fifth and sixth let's start getting [ __ ]
correctly so all you gotta do is start
over
breed again i know wasted some time
wasted some energy it was worth it it's
a good learning experience it doesn't
really take that much time that long
that much space
uh this isn't on my notes but let's
ramble a lot of people think that
breeding requires a lot of space it
doesn't it requires
very little space you can breed with
very small plants honestly
when i'm making a new cross if it's
something that has never been made
before and i think
that plant and that plant right there i
should put them on a date i should put
them in a room and i should let them do
their thing
and then we'll have some seeds those
plants grow in a six
inch net pot and they're about eight
inches tall maybe ten inches tall when i
flower them i do not top them
i grow them they get eight to ten inches
tall they go into flour
i pollinate them and then we get about
somewhere between 30 and 100 seeds
depending on
the plant some plants take pollen really
well and give you a lot of seeds
some are kind of stingy but some of them
will just throw out seeds either way
i've got enough
to play with i can grow a few of them i
can send a few of them to my tester
friends they can grow them out
then we can see if that new cross is
worth the [ __ ] instead of making
thousands and thousands of seeds at a
big old plant and wasting space
i can put we're in colorado the legal
number to grow here is 12 plants i've
got six
recreationally six on my medical
allowance so that gives me 12 plants
i'll put
six uh 12. let me do math in my head
again i'll put 11. that's the goal
number here
11 female plants in a room and one male
plant in a room
and they'll just pollinate all 11 of
those little tiny six-inch net pots
under one led light
real small plants real small pots grow
them up just a couple of weeks
flour them out pollinate them and then
uh i do the 18
6 trick once i get them good and
pollinated i put the lights back on 18 6
and i actually move
those little tiny plants back to my veg
space they don't even waste any space
now they're just in the corner of the
veg space they're getting what they need
they're on 18-6 they're gonna finish
flowering
in about six to eight maybe nine weeks
hopefully not that long depending on the
strain
i will have somewhere between thirty and
a thousand seeds from each plant to play
with
uh did i say a thousand thirty and a
hundred seeds from each plant to play
with
and that's enough for myself and lemur
and mobius and rosin man and
zozo to run them and see what we've got
and then if i find out they're all good
or if i find out they're all terrible we
move forward from there if they're good
i've still got the clones of the
original plants make a bunch more
this time we'll run it in a seven gallon
pot grow it up a little bit bigger
pollinate it
make enough seeds to last for a minute
so we could stock up all the vendors
but you don't need a lot of space you
need the same things that you need
uh for your regular grow you need a dark
space that you can control the dark on i
like to throw them into either
11 13 or 12 12 for a few weeks get them
into flower
get that pollen on there um so let's
talk about this a little bit more
specific detail
get them into flour around day 23 to 32
depending on the plant is when they want
pollen if you pollinate
early your seeds will be um
they're more likely to be more uniform
and healthier if you pull in a ripe
pollinate right in the middle
you will get more seeds and they'll
still be healthy they'll still be
uniform if you pollinate too late
your seeds will start to get not as
round
you'll get more twins you'll get more
weirdos if you pollinate too late
so it's all about timing that plant some
of my plants want pollen i've talked
about this
uh the platinum tangie is ready for
pollen at like day 23 of flowers she's
like pollinate me i'm ready to go
strawberry fields i gotta wait till like
day 27 or day 30 to give her pollen
if i hit her too early she doesn't make
enough seeds if i hit her too late she
doesn't make
good seeds so it's all about timing when
it comes to breeding
you may need to learn to put strawberry
starburst or strawberry fields into the
room
a week ahead maybe two weeks ahead then
drag the platinum tangy in there two
weeks later
let those flower then drag the male the
male should already be in there so we'll
talk about male timing
but you want to pollinate the plants
around day 23
to 27 maybe 32 depending on the plan
you want those pistols to be big and
bushy and strong looking
now let's talk about timing the male
plane your male plants probably going to
start dropping pollen around day 14
really get going around 17
really dumping by 23 kicking it out by
day 26.
your plants are ready for pollen by now
but uh you may want to get
the females a little bit ahead you may
want to get the male a little bit ahead
it depends on your strategy what you
want to do i've got a separate place for
my male so i can get him ahead
and he's really dumping pollen so he's
probably
a week ahead of the other so he's
putting out good pollen some of that
later pollen is better in my opinion the
early pollen is good
the later pollen seems to be more
productive not super late but like four
five week six pollen is really good
put that on the week three week four
females and it really goes shebang so
get your boy
get him pollinating if you've got one
space
put them all in there at the same time
and do what you've got to do i
understand how it goes it will work
a lot of the things i talk about are
specifics that will dial things in and
give you the best results
this is growing cannabis on a homegrown
level i understand sometimes you just
got to throw some plants in a room and
do what you can do so
if that's what you've got to do do that
so you've got your females in there
they're going to want pollen around day
23 27 30 32 at the latest
uh your boy's going to start dropping
pollen around day 12 14
17 they'll start dropping it like 25 by
day 30.
you can't [ __ ] walk around him
because when you touch the floor you
could see pollen fall off of him
that's the point where i would drag him
over to the females put him right in the
middle of the females and just shake him
just grab him right by the base and give
him a good shake just like if you're
going to whip somebody with him
just whip all those female plants with
them the pollen is going to go flying
it's going to go everywhere at this
point you're achieving full
pollination those plants are getting it
you're going to taste pollen you're
going to have pollen in your teeth in
your nose you're going to breathe pollen
and you're going to sneeze it's going to
suck
you're going to have bright yellow
boogers for a whole day you can't get
rid of it no matter what you do your
eyes are going to feel red and itchy
i think that part of my redness and
weirdness from my eyes today is from
pollen big shout out to
king solomon for making my eyes itchy
it's worth it uh it could be that light
could be solly
uh but pollinate go in there and just
spread that pollen i put the plant right
in front of a fan sometimes
just let the fan [ __ ] blow the pollen
everywhere then i wait a few days
maybe one maybe two maybe three days
then i will pollinate again
now that male plant in my opinion has
done his job he's done
i will cut him down and smack him
against something either the fan or the
lights
just getting all that pollen out into
that room just go sprinkle them all over
the female plants make them actually
make contact i'm trying to make
maximum pollination where every pistol
has been pollinated i want maximum seeds
because you guys buy
every seed that i make and i cannot keep
up with you thank you i love you for
that but i need to make as many seeds as
i can
so you drag them in there pollinate
pollination should happen
females are ready i keep saying it
around day 23 about day 27
30 32 ish your boy's dropping around 17
a little bit later is the best pollen
day 25 is really killer pollen
uh get him in there juice up those girls
let the pollination set
pollinate one more time cut down the boy
clean up the pollen get that boy out of
there
now you're just dealing with seated
females at this point
that's when i put the lights back on 18
6. i've talked about this a lot there
are full episodes about this
in my opinion this works really well to
speed up the finishing process to make
the seeds
finish faster they finish harder they're
fatter they're stronger
excuse me for that they're fatter
they're stronger some of the best seeds
i have ever made have been finished
under the 18
6 finishing cycle the best seeds i have
ever made
were finished under an 18-6 flowering
cycle and they were grown under cannon
leds
i'm going to take a quick drink and
we'll continue the rant about breeding
all right so we've achieved pollination
we've put our lights back on 18
6. now we're gonna feed the plants the
plants in my opinion don't need the
bloom boosters like we normally feed
them because we're not going for flour
uh when you put your plants on eighteen
six let me tell you that this is gonna
happen they're gonna look like [ __ ]
we've gotta give them several weeks for
these seeds to finish up
the plants are going to reveg don't
worry don't stress on that we're not
growing buds
your intention is not to make big pretty
flowers at this point
at this point we are fully focusing on
seeds we are growing a seeded crop you
are now growing seeds before we were
focused on trichomes
and bag of peel flowers now it is just
healthy fat
seeds the plants are going to go back
into a vegetative state because we've
got them on an 18
6 lighting cycle in about 14 17 21 days
you're gonna see little new shoots
coming out of these plants do not freak
out do not panic don't cut them off
don't do any weird [ __ ] let them keep
growing your plants are gonna look weird
and crazy
don't worry you're growing four seeds
take a lot of pictures post it to social
media see what
people think they're gonna freak out
they're gonna tell you cut it down it's
a mutant
they're not gonna know what the [ __ ] is
going on just sit back and laugh like a
mad scientist because it's really fun to
see people freak out
on a seated crop that is fully revenging
if you need clones in a few weeks before
you harvest you will have clones they'll
be popping out right out of the tops of
these
seeded plants you'll have brand new
clones cut those off use them just like
normal clones that is a new mother plant
don't flower that one out let that one
grow out until the leaves get normal
again
then take clones off of that you can
flower those those are your new plants
you can get
seeds and clones off of the same plant
that is a crazy trick that i have done
a couple of times so you've got your
plants they're on 18-6 they're going to
continue to flower
they don't need the bloom boosters like
they normally do because we're
not growing buds they do in my opinion
need enjoy and appreciate a little bit
of amino acids amino acids are great
building blocks to life if you've got a
product with amino some sort of liquid
amino in there
add that to it also they do like a
little extra cal mag
they're also going to appreciate a
little bit of nitrogen
if you're a bottle grower i just
basically don't switch
the veg bottle to the bloom bottle when
my feed schedule says put in the
excuse me let me fix my brain when the
feed schedule says
put in the bloom bottle i just don't
switch from veg to bloom i continue that
veg bottle all the way through the
flowering cycle
i don't do a flush phase like you
normally do
that's because we're not going to smoke
and i want to feed my seeds
so yeah the main nutrient difference is
they want a little bit more calmag they
want some amino acids and i don't switch
to the flowering nutrients i just use
that veg bottle
most other things are basically the same
i don't defoliate as heavily
honestly they don't grow as bushy
because they're spending most of their
energy on making those seeds
so then you got to let them finish
that's where i'm headed we're feeding
them they're gonna grow they're just
gonna keep on growing
um try to don't get it too humid don't
spray
try not to spray because you've got
seeds in there if you get them too wet
too humid
those seeds will germinate inside of
your buds i've seen it before
i've seen little sprouts growing out of
live plants it's really beautiful but
you just ruined your plants and your
seeds and you kind of [ __ ] up
everything unless you're trying to make
some living soil
there's nothing to be used there so let
them grow let them continue to grow
don't let it get too humid you want at
the same conditions as you do a normal
grow environment so you're already doing
that
feed them water them then you will
notice that the seeds are starting to
get hard a lot of people say
how do i know when the seeds are ready
hopefully these plants are really seeded
up
all you have to do is find a branch that
you're okay with just kind of kind of
mangling a little bit
grab a bud and just pinch it and pull
out a seed and then roll it between your
fingers
the butt will fall off the casing will
come off all the calyx and all that part
will fall onto the floor and you'll just
have a seat in your hand pop it right in
your hand and check it out
is it white is it pale is it gray is it
getting tiger striped is it dark
is it black then is it hard give it a
squeeze
if it crushes that's when you can tell a
lot when it crushes does it just go
squish if nothing comes out you're
nowhere near ready if a little
white gooey thing comes out you're
getting close if it's hard and kind of
goes crunch and white gooey [ __ ] comes
out you're getting really close if it's
hard
and when you pinch it it makes a little
indention in your finger then you're
probably ready but go a little bit
longer
it's going to take six to eight maybe
nine weeks for these seeds to harden up
honestly from the time you pollinate
until the time you cut them down is
going to be six to eight maybe nine
weeks it is going to be very
plant specific it's going to be very
environmental specific
there are a lot of things that will come
into play to decide how long
these seeds need to go before you
harvest them i want to read my notes and
make sure i didn't miss anything because
i got stone and i went kind of fast and
i did lose track of where i was at one
point
i want to make sure i don't miss
anything for you select plants
select a female select a male get them
at the right point in flowering
put them in the room let them do their
magic on each other
then switch the light cycle to 18 6 feed
them properly
uh basically give them veg nutrients
all the way through give them aminos
give them calmac give them nitrogen
that should keep them happy don't let
them get root bound don't get them too
humid
um they're on 18-6 let them go long
enough
then i think we can talk about
harvesting
um let's harvest one of the best parts
about growing for seed is you don't
really have to trim
it's all just gonna none of it's gonna
get smoked well unless you're gonna try
i don't do that i don't feel it's useful
i feel like it's a waste of time
um so before harvest while the plants
are still alive still growing still well
still turgid is the word i'm looking for
i will pull off as many leaves as i can
get
just defoliate with my hands maybe
scissors but put on a pair of gloves or
just go pull off all of the leaves
because when i cut the plants down i
don't need that much leaf on there
so i go in i cut off all of the leaves
or pull off all of the leaves as many as
i can get
then the next day i cut the plants down
and i hang them upside down and put a
label on them that way i know that this
plant is for sure this plant
it was the female this i already know
what it was pollinated by because it was
my breeding project
then i just simply let it dry i don't
even put them in a dry and cure room
i just hang them in a basement where the
air is and they just
dry in that natural environment i'm not
curing them i'm not drying them
especially we're not going to smoke them
this is all seeded product a lot of
people think that it's insane or
there's a problem with just seeding this
up and not even attempting to save the
material
by the time i'm done sorting it and
getting the seeds out of it it is so
beat up that it is not worth it any
edibles that you make tastes like crap
it tastes like chlorophyll
any concentrates you may come out green
and terrible because it's so beat up it
is not worth the time energy and effort
uh the material goes into the compost
bin or the bokashi bucket
is honestly what happens to that
material so we
cut down the plants they've been
defoliated heavily we cut them down they
hang
upside down or you can lay them on racks
if you want but the seeds may start
falling out as it dries up
as long as you got something to catch
the seeds and keep them separated keep
them separated
so that you don't get any
cross-contamination or cross-labeling of
seeds
chop the plants down hang them up let
them get this is how i do it i let them
get crispity crispy crunchy dry they're
super butter finger dry
then i will get a container i wish i
would have brought one to the table
it is a sterlite container i believe is
the brand
sterlite makes them rubbermaid makes
them there's a bunch of generic brands
that make them at the big box stores
where they sell you all the plastic [ __ ]
you can get these containers it's
probably 18 inches 16
inches tall deep you might want to call
it it's about three feet wide and it's
about a foot and a half
thick um it's like a big box basically
it's all a big plastic box
i will grab a pair of gloves and i will
put my plant in that box
and i basically grab the plant by the
base of the stalk and i put my hand
around all the buds and run my hand
right up the main stem
and just shuck all the buds right off
the stem it is so dry
that as i run my hand up the stem and
push all these buds off they just fall
right off the stick into the container
so now all the buds are
off the sticks they're all into this
container i've got a couple of methods
for removing
uh the seeds at this point but some of
the easiest ways are just
put on gloves and just grind it all up
with your hands don't smash too hard
you'll know when you're going hard
enough to destroy seeds but if you've
got
all the plant matter in that container
and you just start grinding it up with
your hands
you will hear those seeds hitting that
bin just ding ding ding ding ding ding
ding if you did it right it sounds like
it is raining seeds into that container
it is a very
uh when you grew seeds on purpose and
you hear that it is a very
satisfying feeling another really
effective way of getting these seeds out
of these buds
is to remove all the buds from the
sticks you got to get most of the sticks
out because we're going to put all these
buds
into a one gallon ziploc bag as many as
you can get it into that one gallon
ziploc bag
and then i just kind of roll my hands
around that bag and squeeze it and
crumble it these buds are dusty bone dry
so as i'm doing this i'm just making
dust out of all of that bud
then i personally use a seed sorter i've
got a machine
that i pour the seeds and all the the
other material is called chaff so i pour
the chaff and the seed mixture into this
one part and seeds come out of one end
and the chaff comes out of the other
i've got to run it through a couple of
times to make sure i don't miss any
seeds but once i get the rhythm of the
machine
i can pull out a lot of seeds quite
quickly if you don't have a seed sorter
there are a lot of ways to figure out
how to get the seeds
uh remember that the seeds roll and the
chaff is fluffy and stays at the top you
can do it just like we used to back in
the day get an album
run the seat run the material up the
album and the seeds fall down the
material stays at the top
there are a lot of ways to do it this is
uh
a seed breeder's version of trimming you
guys out there trimming
you always talk about how you want to
put the scissors in your eye and that
you hate trimming
pulling the seeds out is that's the
headache for a breeder if you don't have
the machine if you've got the machines
they will do you very well there is the
easy grow
seed sorter is what i think it's called
the easy seed
seed sorter that is a great machine my
buddy cascadian groan is putting out the
larger models if you need something to
do a few more seeds uh
cascading groans is actually more
affordable so find him on social media
shout out to cascadian grown there you
go brother free plug just because i want
to support the community
also there's another guy i saw damn i
really wish i remember who saw the
uh who made the plastic 3d printed
version it was smaller
uh but still all three great products no
bias no
yeah just three products you could use
they're all three seed sorters another
thing i've seen done
i think i learned this from mr soul i
like to share uh resources so you don't
think i'm a wizard
i do learn [ __ ] from a lot of other
people mr soul
puts his buds he takes the sticks out
he's got just buds in a five gallon
bucket
and he taught us to get a drill and then
at the hardware store they sell a paddle
that is a drill bit so it hooks into
your drill just like a normal drill bit
but it is to stir paint is what i
believe it was originally made for
and you put your drill on like a low
setting so you don't destroy the seeds
and just go into the five gallon bucket
and just give it a few zoo
zip zip you don't want to go in there
and murder it but give it a few zaps
and if the material is dry enough just
give it a zip it'll just
shatter that material and rupture the
material and the seeds just go flying to
the edge of the bucket
it will not break the seeds if you put
it on a low setting and you do it gently
and pay attention if you go in there and
start [ __ ] mashing them on the bottom
and making mashed potatoes out of it
you'll destroy the seeds but
if you're smooth about it and you pay
attention watch what you're doing you
will not destroy the seeds it is a quick
way to get them out
then all of the chaff is at the top all
the seeds are at the bottom
pull out a few handfuls of the chaff
that will help you out start sorting
those seeds much more quickly
seriously pulling the seeds out is uh
the really the challenging part
unless you're making packages i package
seeds by hand every seed that you buy
was packaged by me i touched that seed i
rolled it on the table made it was hard
made sure it was hard that was weird
uh touched that seed made sure it was
hard all right rolled it on the table
made sure it was hard i put all those
seeds into the packaging myself
i like to touch them but counting to 10
and counting to 12 and counting to 6
does get quite tedious
i make sure to put extra seeds in there
for you but that is my version of
trimming that's what i'm just like all
right my eyes are crossed i need a break
so we've gotten all the way to selecting
plants we've gotten all the way up to
harvesting we've gotten to pulling the
seeds out
now you've got to count them it's always
good to count your seeds i know that
sounds tedious and monotonous i've got a
machine that does that i simply drop my
seeds in a machine and i hit go
and it vibrates and it counts the seeds
for me beautiful beautiful machine
hopefully you've got a friend maybe a
lovely girlfriend or somebody that will
sit around and count seeds with you
i just count them out sometimes you can
do it by weight you'll get close enough
if you just want a good idea
sometimes you could tell that this mini
in a baggie is about a thousand seeds
you'll get good at it eventually
count them because you want to know how
many seeds you made because you want to
know how many you make next
time so that you can make if you make
five more next time that's improvement
but you want to just document stuff i
like to make a lot of notes i like to
make
excessive notes that way i know where
progress is i know where i'm slacking i
know where i'm improving
all right now let's talk about the most
rewarding part of this entire project
now it is time to grow
the seeds we have produced did we make
trash did we make the next gems did we
make the newest chem dog did we make the
new gorilla glue
did we make the new popular [ __ ] that's
going to have everybody lined up at the
dispensary or
did we just make a bunch of intersex
mutant plants and nobody wants to grow
the only way to find that out is to
sprout them and grow them the first
thing you want to document is
germination rate
however many seeds you grow write it
down uh how many germinated
write that down that is your germination
rate if you popped
10 seeds and only seven of them sprouted
you've got a 70 germination rate
not really acceptable for commercial
seeds those are good for you you need at
least 80
germination to put them out to market 90
is better
if they don't have 90 germination rate
at least put 13 seeds in that package
when you sell them
do something like that to help the
people out but you need a good
germination rate so test these seeds
germ them out
then see how they grow veg them take
notes as they veg if you've got 10 of
them
you should label them however you want
you can name them you can number them
you can letter them
but just make notes right that plant
number one grows like [ __ ] plant number
two grows amazing plant number three
it's kind of weird plant number four is
the one i want to keep already
make notes because you're not gonna
remember this is gonna be a long process
and you're so excited
all your mental notes are gonna get
foggy so make a lot of notes grow these
out
you can grow them as big as you want you
can grow them as small as you want but
flower them out
do your testing process however you want
to test them do you want to grow them
big and top them and spread them out and
see what they do
i like to run kind of a scientific test
i run them once again in a six
inch net pot untopped uh veg them for
about two or three weeks
get them big enough just to see the
shape of the plant then put it into
flour
then i'll find out very quickly if those
plants show intersex traits if they're
mutants if they're weirdos
i can find what they smell taste look
like i can find production
very quickly i can achieve production
very quickly and find winners and losers
very quickly in less than 100 days if i
do it by just
flowering them out really quickly then
you can dry them cure them smoke them
with the crew take a bunch of pictures
and see what you've got it's about 100
day process
maybe 120 if you veg them for too long
so grow them out see what you've got if
you want to go bigger you can i like a
small test grow
it just makes more sense to me why grow
big ass plants i don't even take a clone
a lot of times on my test grows i've got
a thousand seeds
grown out 10 of them if i find something
cool and there i'll grow more seeds of
that
but just grow them out find what we've
got why do i want to spend a bunch of
time growing something that could be
trash it could be amazing but it also
could be trash and if i waste
soil time electricity nutrients water
real estate in the grow on plants that
were [ __ ] then that's frustrating so
veg them flower them out see what we've
got smoke them yourself smoke them with
your friends
smoke them with if you're a medical
grower smoke them with whoever is
consuming them medically if you are
a uh profit grower smoke them with your
favorite customers give them to them as
a sample be like here's numbers one two
and three let me know what you liked
better
and they're going to love you for that
they're like you let me get you let me
pick which one you're going to grow and
they'll think it's custom for them and
[ __ ] so uh select the best ones
the best one i don't like the word ones
so it's one plural it's weird select the
best one or the plants that work the
best for you
then continue to grow those those all
right my face is wearing out so at this
point you've grown out a bunch of the
plants
uh you've found males females you know
how many males and females come out of a
pack you know your germination rate
you know what kind of terps you're
getting from each cross you can see now
what that male did to each cross did it
over dominate everything did it add a
nice
something to everything did it work the
way that you expected it we said start
this with a goal
did you meet a goal did you exceed your
goal did you forget about the goal did
you do something totally different that
wasn't your goal but still amazing
just document that and then when you do
it again you got some sort of document
some sort of record
so um are the seeds you made
better than the parents did you improve
upon cannabis did you improve upon the
species
if you paid money for these seeds would
you be happy with that
uh is there a reason to grow these seeds
again was this just something you would
have done one time or do you want to
keep growing these because you probably
have a lot of them
are you letting yourself and your ego
get in the way of quality control
did you fall in love with this breeding
project uh you know how your friend
your friend the soundcloud rapper thinks
that every beat he makes is the best
beat ever but it's the same beat he's
been making since
8th grade are you doing that with your
breeding are you saying this is the best
[ __ ] ever bro but it's really just
the same beat you made in 8th grade just
trying to relive it because
your ego is in the way and you really
should just [ __ ] delete that and move
on and try something new
don't let your ego get in the way of
your breeding
um i've done it i've been super proud of
[ __ ] and then been like but but
but and then if i catch myself saying
but but then i already know that
i just need to i but but just move on
that [ __ ] ain't worth but
but but move on you there are so many
plants to work with so many male
plants so many female plants you can
make feminized plants which will be a
whole other podcast we do not have time
for that rabbit hole
there are so many plants to play with
why would you want to waste time with
something
that isn't moving the cannabis species
the plant the industry the community
forward
why do you want to stall it out and
stand still so if your breeding isn't
perfect isn't amazing just abandon the
project let's start over let's do
something different unless you find a
trait in there that you really want to
isolate work with breed again
you'll know it if you see it you'll know
what i'm talking about
all right uh we got all the way through
this i think
yeah i think so there will be a couple
of quick edits but i think we did a good
breeding podcast this should spark a lot
of questions i really hope i get a lot
of feedback a lot of response from this
episode these grow lessons really do get
a lot of notice
thank you we're getting a lot of
traction on the youtube uh the patreon
has been blowing up i appreciate that
but i do look forward to the questions
the email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com
i cannot wait i want questions so that i
could do a second part of this episode
fill in the gaps that i missed let you
know uh any questions that you may have
on breeding
please send them my way we'll do another
episode about this big shout out to my
friend here who sent me this
message i don't think they want their
name said they did not include it in the
message so i'm going to keep you
anonymous
thank you for generating great content
ladies and gentlemen boys girls pimps
hoes friends foes smokers growers
clone cutters pollen chuckers seed
poppers
seed exchangers everybody out there in
the beautiful cannabis community
i want to thank you once again for
listening to episode 654 of the grow
from your heart podcast it blows my mind
every time i say the episode number 654
episodes you guys
uh thank you without you on the other
side of this
i would just be a psychopath with
expensive toys so thank you for
supporting me i do appreciate it
big up big respect if you feel like the
episode was educational informative
entertaining
maybe i made you laugh maybe i saved
your garden maybe you just want to throw
me a couple of bucks for giving you a
couple hours of entertainment every week
my patreon is patreon.com forward slash
grow from your heart
send me some love show me some support
big thank you i do appreciate that again
i did correct the link
in this episode the link in the
description should get you there if
you've been trying to click on it and it
gives you that 404 error
you're right i did [ __ ] up my bad i
fixed the link click on that get us
right there
um i asked for patreon contributions a
lot um
do not feel bad if you can't contribute
to patreon i get it money is expensive
or coming out of a weird time in the
world right now
i don't expect a contr contribution from
everybody if you're listening all i want
you to do is click
like or tell a friend about the show
something like that that stuff is free
click like subscribe smash that like
button is what all the young kids say
do stuff like that if you've got another
friend who is growing thinking about
growing
uh passionate about growing already
maybe you're not happy with the way
they're growing you want to politely
improve their garden
maybe just tell them hey have you heard
about the grow from your heart podcast
word of mouth is a great way to spread a
show
and it is absolutely free it means a lot
to me so those are ways you could
support me for free
um yeah click like click subscribe and
tell your friends
uh what else do we got i think that's
about it uh email address is grow from
your heart hotmail.com the website
iregenetics.com a lot of people just
found out today
that i am a seed breeder they're going
to be very interested in my seeds
my website is iriegenetics.com on that
website you will find a list of breeders
at the top of that list is seeds
herenow.com use coupon code gfyh10 that
will save you 10
at seedshearnow.com you'll find a
wonderful list of breeder of vendors
there
i may have said breeders a moment ago i
meant a list of vendors
those folks all carry my seeds some will
have some stuff in stock some won't have
some stuff in stock some will have five
packs some will have 10 packs
some will have different prices some
will take different cards some will take
different payment methods there will be
variances on the websites
find what works best for you find who's
got what you need in stock find
who takes your payment method find who
ships to you you're gonna have to do a
little bit of research but it's all
there on iregenetics.com
all right i'm gonna wrap this up because
i don't need to ramble for too much
longer
thank you once again for listening i
will be back in just a couple of days
with fresh new content
i want to give a giant shout out to all
of my friends at the embracing organics
podcast
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
you