[Music]
[Applause]
all right here we go take
three welcome back podcast world i'm
your host my friends call me rasta jeff
and this
is episode 656 of the grow from your
heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to answer a
couple of grow emails and questions
before we get to that part of the show
let's do a few shout outs to a few of
those kind of folks who support the
show on patreon let's start off with the
big grow from your heart podcast thank
you shout out to my friend waguan
let's send a big thank you shout out to
godfather kush let's send a big thank
you shout out to nomi by my guacamole
i want to send a big thank you shout out
to a new supporter ruth 305
let's send a big thank you shout out to
a longtime supporter levity loveday
i want to send a big fist bump to my
friend jackie daytona
let's send a big thank you shout out to
learning and vernon and terp burglar
i want to send a big thank you shout out
to kojaks and stone trout bum
let's send a big thank you shout out to
samurai gardens and then let's wrap it
all up with the big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out
to our friend frugalrock big thanks and
big shout out to everybody who continues
to support the show on patreon
if you are not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need is right
there on the screen and i did include a
link in the show notes and the video
description
to make it nice and easy for all of my
friends i say it all the time
if you're driving if you're working
please don't put yourself in any danger
or any trouble to support the patreon
that link will be there when you're safe
patreon.com forward slash
grow from your heart while we're doing
shout outs and saying thanks to people
i want to send a big thank you shout out
today today i went to the p.o box and i
got a great gift in there
the p.o box is often stuffed with great
gifts but this one was pretty cool
something useful
something that will get to put get put
to use on a daily basis i have not had
the opportunity to use it yet but i
promise you i will
it came with a letter it says hey jeff
big fan of the pod
the crow has benefited a lot since
starting to listen that's what it's all
about making the grow look better
it says i thought i would send you a
gfyh grinder as a thank you feel free to
check out the company on the instagram
have a great day from mike custom dank i
want to show you this label before i
show you the grinder they sent me
but big shout out to our friends custom
dank i want to make sure to get that on
one of the cameras i may just have to
pop in
a logo later but make sure you follow
our friends custom dank on instagram
they did send me a beautiful gift they
are great people
uh it is spelled just like you think it
would be custom dank
or if you're dyslexic dank custom will
work as well not making fun of the
dyslexic folks
i may have a touch of this dyslexia
myself if you've never noticed all right
this is the gift that my friends did
send me here it is an awesome grow from
your heart podcast
logo grinder it's got the gf i'm gonna
take this part off just so i don't
dump it on my computer it does have the
gfyh logo i may have to take another
photo of that and insert it in later but
there is the gfyh podcast logo
beautifully um engraved embossed laser
etched i don't know exactly how but it
is beautifully done on the top of this
grinder
they even got the little gradient part
in the middle of the logo it's perfect
it's beautiful
thank you you did a hell of a good job
on the artwork then let's talk about the
grinder the grinder itself is
very well made very well constructed i'm
gonna say this is probably aluminum
i said that word very oddly but who
doesn't say aluminum oddly
uh it's got a nice grinding wheel on the
inside nice teeth in there they look
sharp they look strong then you unscrew
it
so you put your product in here right
give it a good twist chop chop chop chop
then you'd unscrew here then i kind of
like this part once you unscrew it
you kind of set that part to the side
there's a little dish in here
that is removable i like that this
little dish comes out
it's got a little screen on the bottom
of there of course you'd catch your uh
your keef catch down here in the bottom
it's got a little a little scraper for
your keef catch
i really enjoy that beautiful basic
grinder but it's got the logo
on it it's well made i like that little
cup in the middle beautiful
great gift for a cannabis consumer thank
you please do follow my friends
i appreciate good gifts especially stuff
with the gfyh
podcast logo all right big shout out to
our friends make sure you give them a
follow please
and if you want to send more gifs send
me an email let's grow from your heart
at hotmail.com
we'll get you set up with the po box
maybe we'll do one of those episodes
where we just open up a bunch of cool
[ __ ] for the whole show
alright the music ended and it got quiet
so let's focus on
a podcast in a previous episode i did
a uh what is it i did a lesson on
phenotypes i defined the word phenotype
definition was the word i was looking
for that would not come to my brain we
talked a lot about phenotypes i told you
what phenotypes were
how to find phenotypes we talked a lot
about the word phenotypes
uh i got a great follow-up question from
a podcast
listener or viewer i'm not sure if
you're watching or viewing either way
thank you for the interaction and thank
you for the great
uh feedback and update uh this is a very
respectable and respectful letter uh
let's not
run around in too many circles let's get
right to it
it says uh you are the best and you give
back in so many ways
thanks and respect big respect the
respect is mutual here i can tell
uh by the way this is written that you
do disagree with me very respectfully
and that's a great way to have a
conversation
it goes on to say i do disagree with you
on one topic in episode 655 about
phenotypes
where you said that you're backing off
on your phenotype discussions and your
strained descriptions
i disagree that you should do that and
here is why
yes i did say that i feel like i'm
messing up by giving you
uh too much guidance and too much help
on selecting phenotypes
i feel like that is some work that you
should do that is custom work that
should be tailored for you that's why
there are phenotypes that's why they're
a selection to be done
that's part of the the beauty of growing
so i was gonna leave that up to you a
little bit
i feel like i've offered a quality
product why not give you some variation
to choose from
find what you want i've said all of this
on the previous episode
so let me keep going with this message
it says
i had a skunk number one sweet skunk
plant that i wanted to
improve upon which is a great use for
some of my genetics if you want to breed
something and make it a little better
some of my stuff is definitely a good
way to do that
it says i researched regular mail seeds
and i decided on a rise that is a very
good breeding plant
says my goals were to bring up my thc
and increase bud density while retaining
my skunk's bud formation
excuse me the skunk's bud formation
classic red orange light green and so
many
swelled bracts and she looks over seeded
traits so a trait of this plant is red
orange
and light green with swelled bracts that
look like they are over
seeded so it looks like it's got some
swollen bracks on there it's just a
trait of the plant it's not seeded but
it looks like it
that is a trait that is an observable
characteristic of
this plant so he wanted to keep that
trait along with the bud formation
then they wanted to add some density and
a little bit of potency so they
uh selected chose a rise as the breeding
male which is a very good choice
and they knew that because of the things
that i typed on my website we'll talk
about that
it goes on to say i got 10 arise seeds
from seeds herenow.com
i acquired four males i was hoping for a
50 50 fino but
no what i had to choose from was one
golden goat
one stretcher one daybreaker and one
question mark
i know this how you ask because of your
great
arise pheno descriptions so if i hadn't
described that a rise plant and those
phenos to expect
very well so well this listener this
breeder this grower would not have known
that a rise
would be the perfect candidate for
breeding to make his project what he
wanted it to be
so the reliable description that i
gained that gave the in-depth the
detailed description that i gave about
phenotypes
that really helped our grower friend our
breeder friend our listener maybe a
viewer friend
to make the proper selections so maybe
just maybe i do need to keep giving
those detailed descriptions there's more
to this it goes on it says
monkey puke that's a really great name
not something i would have used
something i do love so that's beautiful
i love it when you nail it and get the
name right
and you didn't take something i would
have used nothing wrong with it i love
the name it's just not
uh not on my brand i got to stay on
brand it's off-brand for me it's very on
brand for you probably so that's
beautiful monkey
puke uh if i saw a jar of monkey puke on
the shelf i would want to smell that
what does monkey puke smell like that's
what my brain i just go what does and i
would know it's not
real monkey puke there was not a primate
involved there was no vomiting to be
done
but i think that's what monkey puke is
gonna smell like once i smell the jar
that's what you've done to my brain i
really think i'm smelling monkey puke
weird psychological tricks we play on
people with strain names here let me
continue here monkey puke
f1 which is skunk one to arise is in day
45 and i think i got
exactly what i wanted i love so many
things about this message
uh the respectful argument uh the
respectful disagreement may be my
favorite part
then the you've mentioned so many
details about your breeding your goal
your idea the reason you were doing this
that is so awesome and it looks like you
are hitting your goal your 45 days in
and it appears like you were getting
what you wanted and expected out of that
that's exciting
from one breeder to another that is
really exciting good job big up much
respect
that is super cool i'm excited for you
brother really just from one bro one
breeder to another i know what it's like
when it's like
45 days in and you're going oh i think
i've done it i might have got exactly
what i wanted it's like when the chef
starts smelling the ingredients and
everybody
uh in the kitchen it smells good right
but people in the living room start
peeking their head and going
bro what are you doing in here it smells
[ __ ] good that's where we are
if you're not a grower if you're not a
breeder you don't understand the feeling
that is the feeling when somebody
peeps their head in the kitchen and goes
dude whatever you're cooking
i can't wait for it to be done that's
where we are with this project and it's
exciting i'm excited for you bro if you
can't tell
um it says only time and possibly an
f2 generation will tell i love that
you're even ready
already already ready to take it to f2
we haven't even finished the f1 batch
this guy's excited and eager
these are the types of breeders we need
in this industry um
the point remains that i would have no
idea what i was looking for in a mail
without your arise
strain description and you're selecting
a mail podcast
with 99 of the other breeders work you
have
zero zip nothing to go by you're a one
percenter my friend
don't change what you're doing add more
strain descriptions
i'm gonna interrupt myself here and i'm
going to say my website needs some
attention you guys i've got strain
descriptions and photos for most of my
stuff
up there if you look at the website you
notice there's not a photo there's not a
strain description for something that
you've got experience with
send me a message include that photo
include that strained description
if you've just got some details about a
strain that you think should be on the
website
this one gets super fat at the end of
week nine if you let this one go to week
10 it gets super stinky
whatever you notice send me some details
like that i will send you a thanks i
will give you a shout out
i will make it worth it to you if you've
got some great photos please send me
those photos
maybe i just need to update the website
with your photos maybe your photos are
better than what's there
don't be shy i would like to get the
website updated for the start of the
year
um thank you all right let's get right
back into this
uh so keep adding the strain
descriptions don't change keep what
you're doing add more descriptions
that's where we were in this
uh yes i want to add more descriptions i
want to add more pictures
i want to talk more about phenotypes uh
it is summertime i just realized i've
got an
awesome summer project i wasn't prepared
for um i will do more stuff on the
website i just asked for help for that
and as i grow these strains i do learn
more things about them i have to grow
them i have to
develop the relationship if i don't see
that something uh is factual i don't put
it on the website i don't just ramble
off some [ __ ]
uh like say that it's bright green and
smells like a skunk's ass and it makes
you feel like you just came when you
smoke it like
i could put that on the website about
everything but there's no need to do
that you're going to buy it you're going
to grow it you're going to smoke it then
you're going to call me back and say i
still don't feel like i came after you
smoke it
and no one's going to want to buy that
again so um i have to grow them i have
to get the experience i have to develop
their relationship to be able to talk
about it
uh in that sort of a deep detail so be
patient with me there are
so many limitations i was running a lot
of not running working with and
operating in a lot of commercial
facilities since covid
i've really dialed that back so i'm on
my own personal
space and numbers which really really
limits a breeder so i've got
a lot of test growers out there helping
me out and stuff we're learning a lot
but not as rapidly as we could when we
had the commercial
environments at our fingertips all right
where was i by the way
i got the most beautiful and lemony
plant ever
in the tent with monkey puke she's an
awesome lemon sunrise
what what so there's a beautiful and
lemony plant ever in the tent
she's an awesome lemon sunrise that's a
huge compliment my friend
you are breeding with my genetics you
are growing my genetics
i'm honored that you trust me you trust
my breeding you trust my selections
and then thank you for the respectful
argument
you have convinced me i will continue to
do in-depth phenotype explanations what
i want to do
is help you guys identify the phenos and
know what to expect what i don't want
you to do
is uh make you search too hard for the
phenotypes that i have talked about
i don't want you passing up awesome
phenotypes that would work very well for
you because you heard me talk about a
different
phenotype find the one that is going to
work beautifully for you and work with
that one that's
i don't want to mess you up is really
what i'm trying to avoid
i will help you identify phenos if
you're like hey does this look more like
the mean girl does this look more like
the stretchy girl
i will tell you that stuff also keep in
mind
these phenotypes i'm giving you ideas
and suggestions of kind of guidelines of
what box it may fall
into it could be more of the mean girl
phenotype and the nice girl and the
chunky girl phenotype it could have i
could see all of that in there
and it just doesn't have to be labeled
one of those phenos i'm just saying
those are the common
phenotypes that i have identified and
traits that i have observed
over time from working with these plants
so many times
so i will continue to give in-depth
descriptions of new stuff i will update
the old stuff
i will continue to give you phenotype
ideas of what to expect out of the
phenotypes
i will continue to help you identify
phenotypes if you send me a picture and
you say
uh does this look more goat-leaning or
more arise-leaning i will try to help
you with that
don't get offended if i don't respond
right away i've got um
i'm going to say about 18 000 unread
emails right now it's nothing personal
there's just one of me
and there must be at least 18 000 of you
with the question
and i cannot keep up i don't have an
intern i don't have a secretary it is
all me
i do the grow for the first half of the
day i do the podcast or internet work
for the second half of the day
then the third half of the day is when i
do all the normal life stuff that most
people do
and yeah there are three halves to my
day so my days are different than yours
i'm trying to catch up
um i guess being a small business owner
or a business owner a proprietor
an entrepreneur i guess being overloaded
is a good thing if i catch up that means
i [ __ ] up to tell you the truth so
uh i apologize that i'm behind also i'm
very grateful that i'm behind it's kind
of a double-edged sword also
i used to let it super stress me that my
social media inboxes were overflowed my
email inboxes were overflowed
at this point i have accepted it it is
just something that is going to be
i want to reply to you i want to answer
your messages but
i want to do a lot of [ __ ] also i also
want to take a nap so
uh don't take it personally if i'm not
answering your message
send me send me your questions uh send
me the phenotype questions is what i'm
getting at
let me know which phenotype you need me
to identify i'll do my best but
don't expect it to fall exactly in one
of the boxes it doesn't have to be
golden goat it doesn't have to be a rise
it doesn't have to be the 50 50. maybe
it's the 30 70.
maybe i'm gonna say it looks kind of
golden goat but also has the bud shape
and the leaf structure of the platinum
tangy
you might get different [ __ ] like that
and that is possible
with genetics that's how it works so
thank you for the great feedback this
one came from our friend who calls
themselves
s c dung slinger 79
um i'm guessing that's some organics
with the dung slinger and 79 is probably
the year you're born and sc is probably
south carolina i'm just guessing i am
assuming making an ass of myself but big
shout out to our buddy scdungslinger79
pollen chucked genetics i do appreciate
the
the respectful arguments are great uh
the criticism the feedback i invite
request and accept that sort of stuff if
you have any questions corrections
comments or concerns or feedback i do
love to hear it
the email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com
don't be shy send me some messages all
right the next message that i've got
unfolded here on the table that i'm
trying to pull out from underneath the
computer
comes from our friend pete and it is a
quick one
and it says should i hang a
battery-powered lantern
in the flower and veg tent if my power
will be turn
power will be turned off for eight hours
the electrical company is replacing an
electric
pole um no i think
that eight hours of off time will be
just fine
you can interrupt the daylight cycle and
give them this eight hours of off time
and they will be okay what you cannot do
is interrupt the dark cycle and expect
them to be okay
excuse me i'm trying not to burp into
the microphone here
all right i think i'm better what i
wanted to say was
you can interrupt the daytime cycle if
the plants get extra
dark it is okay they're gonna think it
was a shady day
i was cloudy or something like that they
just weren't getting as much sun as they
should have they're gonna be like oh
it's nice and cloudy it's dreary
uh they're gonna have netflix and chill
that day they're just gonna chill out
take a break you're not gonna get
the photosynthesis and metabolism you're
not gonna get the growth that day that
you normally would have but it's
18 hours uh 24 hours of light that
you're not gonna get not that big of a
deal it's actually just you're
interrupting eight hours
so you can interrupt the daytime with
unexpected darkness i wouldn't do that
all the time
but this one time this one day when
they're doing construction this will not
be a problem
now the other part of this that i want
to make sure to say is you cannot
interrupt the dark cycle when those
plants are in a flowering phase and
you've got them in the dark for 18 or
for 12 hours
do not interrupt that 12 hours of
darkness that is more critical that will
cause you problems
that could lead to issues down the road
so i do not think you need to hang a
battery powered lantern
in the flower or veg tents if they're
only going to be off
for this one day for eight hours that
shouldn't be too big of a deal
you may notice that the tents get a
little bit humid you may need to figure
out
open some doors open some windows get
that humid smell out or humid out of
there but then
you're gonna get that stanky ass smell
it's going to stink because your carbon
filters are not running you're going to
have some things to think about right
now
it's only going to be eight hours the
main thing is don't panic and do
anything stupid to make it worse you may
just want to leave while the power is
out just go somewhere else and say
the plant's got to deal with it i've got
to deal with it the plants will be fine
eight hours will not destroy your garden
should not cause too many big problems
the main thing when you get back home
reset
everything reset all of your timers your
fans your air conditioners just go
check on everything and make sure that
the timers are correct
and get them back on their regularly
scheduled program
as soon as possible just go make sure
that your uh
your veg tent timer your light timer is
on go make sure that your
flower room timer your flower tent timer
is on and set to the time you think it
should be and the off and on time that
you think it should be
just go do a little bit of a check cover
your own ass
if you've got an air conditioner that's
on a timer or has some settings check
those settings go make sure all your
fans and blowers
are reset the way that they should be
then walk around the house
fix the clock on the microwave the clock
on anything that went off most of our
stuff's digital and resets itself now
but
go fix all the clocks go make sure that
they're all synced up get that [ __ ]
corrected
all right so i don't think you need to
hang up a battery powered lantern
um the plants will be fine they're just
going to think it was a shady day
again you guys you can have darkness
during the light cycle that shouldn't
cause you too big of a problem if it is
not
major for too long if you're doing it
for more than 24 hours or so it may
start to
tell your plants it's a good idea to go
into flower but
8 to 12 to 14 20 hours shouldn't be a
big deal
what you cannot do is have light during
the dark cycle
do not think about it just like this
during the day can you take a nap
it would be totally fine right take a
nap be cool make it nice and dark just
lay down get some sneak
some snoozes i was gonna say some snores
and some snoozes at the same time
gonna leave that [ __ ] in there that's
the kind of day it has been
uh make it dark for a few minutes get
nice and stoned and pass out for like an
hour and wake up and feel refreshed you
can do that right
what if i wake you up for an hour in the
middle of the night and expect you to do
[ __ ] you're going to be mad at me
the plants feel the same way they could
take a nap they don't want to get woken
up unexpectedly so that's how the plants
operate
all right my friend pete i want to thank
you for a great message you got me
rambling for quite a bit on that one
you guys my camera flickered at me and
did some weird [ __ ] and i really don't
want to
miss any of this recording so what i'm
going to do i'm going to wrap
up this podcast this may be a short
episode but i don't want to lose this
recording because i don't know what's
happening with that camera um ladies and
gentlemen boys girls pimps hoes friends
foes smokers growers clone cutters paul
and chuckers
all of you beautiful cannabis
enthusiasts out there i want to thank
you again for listening to a quick
episode 656 of the grow from your heart
podcast
let's all hope to job that this makes it
to the internet because that camera
flickered and i don't know what is going
on there
um yeah make sure you check out my
website iriegenetics.com
all the irie genetics updates are there
if you've got any questions corrections
comments or concerns like i said before
the email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com don't be shy
i love the friendly criticism uh
respectful debates and arguments
those are all invited also join the
discord there's a lot going on
on the grow from your heart irie army
iriegeneticsdiscord
uh there will be a link to the discord
in the show notes however you're viewing
or watching
there is a link to the irie genetics
discord
i think all the cool kids say tap in all
right
i'm gonna wrap it up before we lose this
file i don't know what's going on let's
all hope this makes it to the internet
let's give a big shout out to my buddy
fiscals organics and until next time
take a fat dab and give your mom a hug
for me
you