[Music]
um
heidi ho podcast world i'm your host my
friends call me rosta jeff and
this is episode 658
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to focus on a
couple of grow questions before we get
to that part of the show
let's do a few shout outs to a few of
those kind folks who support the show on
patreon
let's start off with the big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to my new friend
uncle rick let's send a big thank you
shout out to my buddy the dad hayes
i want to send a big thank you shout out
to brohan78
i want to send a special thank you shout
out to my buddy lefty's farm
let's send a big thank you shout out to
thomas mcginnis and madewell medicated
i want to send a big fist bump to my
buddy tart and mike let's send a special
thank you shout out to greenvet88224
i want to send a big thank you shout out
to rasufa let's send a big thank you
shout out to josiah w
i want to send a huge thank you shout
out to stash drop 269
let's send a big fist bump to captain
mojo i want to send a big thank you
shout out to groove 2112.
let's send a big thank you shout out to
my buddy zacks and starker and then
let's wrap it all up with the big grow
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out to my new friend matthew drukovich
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon
if you are not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need is right there on the screen and of
course i did include that link
in the show notes and the video
description you guys know the ramble
about the video description the link in
the show notes
this time i'm going to remind you that i
do include a discord
link in the notes and the video
description that's right there is a
discord server
where there are a lot of great people
hanging out right now there's something
going on
on the ire genetics grow from your heart
irie army discord something is happening
right now
billy podunk is hanging out there
posting something dave's not here maybe
posting something cool
our buddy greybeard is doing something
maybe stabby is posting something over
there
make sure you check out the discord it
is in the show description
in the notes follow the link
also before we get too far i do want to
apologize you may hear
the air conditioner rattling in the
background uh it is approximately eight
o'clock as i am recording
and it is approximately 90 degrees
outside it has taken me all day
to get this space cool and comfortable
for recording
i'm not turning off that air i'm going
to let it just keep on going until it is
almost cold until it's uncomfortably
cold and then we'll turn it down a
little bit and let it readjust but
i'm grateful that it has cooled down a
little bit and i'm not turning it off so
if you hear a couple of rattles a couple
of
background noises that's just the air
conditioner don't worry about it
we'll be cool get it we will be cool
that's a dead joke if i ever heard one
all right um what else do i want to say
please like and subscribe on youtube
ladies and gentlemen we've got 7
500 and some random number of
subscribers at this point
i do appreciate love and respect all of
those subscribers however i want
10 000 subscribers once we hit that 10
000 mark that is when the show will pop
up in more
uh algorithms more people will see the
show and that you may like this show or
the recommended shows
will pop up after other people watch the
dude grow show they'll see my show pop
up after that
get the show more exposure so what i'm
asking for is for you
to share the show it is completely free
all you have to do is tell your friends
maybe share a post on social media maybe
just click like click subscribe
leave some comments on the show anything
to click make the show move
move us in the algorithm would be
helpful i would be grateful
big thank you for all that let's get to
10 000 subscribers you guys i think we
should have 10k
let's push let's get it there all right
i don't want to ramble too much
i did say i was going to focus on grow
questions let's get to that
part of the show this one came from my
friend
uh slightly stoned stupid42 on patreon
big shout out to all of the patreon
supporters
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart
this one says hey rosta jeff i have a
question about one of your strains i'm
trying my hand in breeding
and i have a real nice scarlet begonias
female so they're going to breed
they've chosen a scarlet begonias female
as the breeder that is a great plant to
breed with a lot of great opportunities
will come from that
it says i'm breeding with a nice dj
shorts navy cross male and that navy
cross is east coast sour diesel
to the dj short blueberry f4 that is
going to be that's an amazing cross
right there you got the east coast sour
diesel
that straight diesel feel chemicals
nasty funk
almost an aroma that kind of burns your
eyes it's kind of if
somebody's got a bag of that in their
pocket and they get in the car your nose
starts to crinkle you go
man you got that sour diesel on you and
then your eyes start to feel it and then
as soon as i smoke sour diesel flowers
i feel it in my eyes in my head and i
love it
one random note about the sour diesel i
do not enjoy sour diesel concentrates
it just doesn't transfer it doesn't
translate in my opinion something
happens when you make a concentrate
that chemically skunky uh
diesel flavor doesn't come through the
way it should in a concentrate most of
the time that is just my opinion i've
never really enjoyed i love
the flowers i love a good sour diesel
flower
never been a big fan of any sour diesel
concentrates there's just something i've
really noticed along the way
let me get back on track so we've got a
sour diesel east coast sour diesel
crossed to a blueberry f4
that's going to be blueberry diesel
terps that's going to be crazy amazing
delicious good i can imagine only a good
buzz from anything dj short puts out
dj shorts a great breeder let me make a
side note i am honored that you're
choosing to use
one of my strains to breed to one of dj
strains because dj honestly is
uh one of my heroes without dj short
there wouldn't be an irie genetics he is
uh one of the godfathers one of the
pioneers one of the founders of cannabis
breeding
he taught me not directly his books his
teachings his podcast appearances
uh his books mainly a lot of [ __ ] that
he has said in magazines and books
have taught me a lot of things and a lot
of ideas and have been springboards
for ideas and tricks that i've learned
up to where i am now so
without dj i wouldn't be where i am i
read genetics wouldn't exist roster jeff
wouldn't be where we are so
big shout out big salute to dj short and
thank you for choosing to breed my
scarlet to some dj short work that's
[ __ ] awesome now let's get back on
some sort of track here you're going to
breed the scarlet begonias to the dj
shorts navy cross
male then it says now to make the
strains stable
do you keep finding the winners and
inbreeding them
um in short form it's not inbreeding it
is uh filial breeding it's breeding for
the next generation but technically what
you said
is what you want to do yes but when you
say inbreeding that implies that you are
going to take
one of the seeds that you made and breed
it to one of the parent plants and that
would be a back cross
a bc or a bx if you want to make pete's
head explode
that would be a back cross so what you
want to do you're on the right path you
want to
or what is done too stable and what is
your what do you mean
by stable i see a lot of people say that
plant is not stable and they mean that
it's got tendencies to have problems or
it's got this or it does that
stable just means do the plants look
uniform when you grow out a population
of seeds
how uniform do they look are they stable
are the
phenotypes stable that's what we want to
talk about so that's what i think you're
aiming for
how do we make them stable sometimes
that first f1 you're going to get pretty
stable
crosses you're going to identify you'll
be able to identify the phenotypes
you'll see what you've made you'll know
what you're working with um
now you've got that f1 batch of seeds or
actually it's technically a poly hybrid
but we're going to call this an f1 batch
of seeds so you've taken
your scarlet begonias you have
pollinated with the
navy cross you've got a batch of seeds
you want to make them
stable you find a male and a female from
that batch of seeds that are the winners
like you said
that have traits which you are looking
for now here is where we talk about the
breeding part
which i always like to step in with what
is your goal breeding is all about your
goal
these are two great plants to cross i
could see why it would be a good idea
but i can't see the plants which you
have chosen to cross what is the reason
what is the goal what is the desired
outcome
is there something about the scarlet
begonias you love what about the dj
short plant that you really love are you
trying to correct something you trying
to upgrade something are you chasing
a trait from one are you trying to
combine traits to from one
and the other to make one plant what is
your ultimate goal here
document that goal then do the cross
then grow out those seeds find if you've
met your goal do
a certain percentage of the seeds you
made hit the goal you're looking for are
they better
than both parent plants do they look
smell taste grow appear
perform the way you expected anticipated
and hope those plants would
if so you're mostly successful so far if
not then you're not you're not
successful you didn't make a good cross
you may have to just either pick another
male plant out of the pack pick a
different phenotype
uh start all over or just abandon the
project altogether so set a goal what is
your desired goal
what traits are you looking for so grow
out these seeds find a female plant that
holds the traits you are looking for
find a male plant that holds the traits
you are looking for
and cross those again and then guess
what you're going to get seeds out of
those
we're going to do it again find a female
that holds the traits you're looking for
find a male that holds the traits you're
looking for
and cross it again every time you do it
you should be working on stabilization
and uniformity of the progeny of the
offspring of the phenotypes they should
look
similar each time you do this they
should get closer and closer and closer
the first time you do the cross you're
gonna get like probably you'll see
somewhere between three maybe five maybe
seven or eight different phenotypes
depending on the parent plants you use
it just depends on
how their genetics breed together you're
gonna see multiple phenotypes
when you do the f2 you're gonna see we
call it the pandora's box you're gonna
open up
a lot of stuff you're going to see um
plants that are a lot the mommy plants
that are a lot the daddy plants are a
little bit mommy and daddy but then
you're also going to see grandparents on
both sides of that cross
appear in the progeny it's going to be
very fun it's really unique it's a
little bit frustrating sometimes to work
with the f2
uh population so now it's your job
to select the proper male and female out
of that f2 population breed them
together and make the f3
now these are going to be if you've done
your selection properly these will be
more uniform they'll start getting more
stable as the word that you're using
they'll start looking more uniform more
familiar
get your f3s find the seeds that look
beautiful that do what you want the
plants to do what you want
and cross those so that is you're going
to f4 by the time you get to f4 f5
you're really looking at uniform plants
dj stops at four or five
most of the time and he says that is to
give you some room to work with it if
you choose to breed with it
if you breed uh with a plant that is an
f4
or an f5 it's going to be very dominant
in your mix it's going to be like adding
too much hot sauce it's just going to
overpower everything everything will be
spicy at that point
so the easiest way the main way to do
this
is to keep going forward with filial
generations and stabilize
by uh selection by finding the traits
you want and selecting parent plants
that perform and do the things you need
and crossing them so if you
select pot properly on keep going
forward you
will make them stable it's just all
about selection from population
um what becomes challenging with that is
sometimes you see outliers and you want
to play with the outliers do i want to
breed with the one that looks just like
i wanted to play with or do i want to
breed to that [ __ ] weirdo there's
nothing stopping you from pollinating
both of those plants and doing two
separate lines and playing with it
now that i said two separate lines let's
talk about a totally different process
of doing this
i don't know what your goal is but maybe
uh maybe you want the flavor
of the blueberry diesel and maybe you
want the potency of the scarlet begonias
i'm just making up traits and ideas for
the sake of a podcast just to have a
springboard to talk about here
so you want one tree i forgot what i
even said now you want the the potency
of the scarlet begonias
and the flavors and aromas of the sauer
diesel blueberry cross the
navy navy cross so
you could in theory you could keep
crossing
male and female and male and female and
keep hoping you get that potency and
that flavor keep hoping you get those
traits find the female that's got both
of those
and keep crossing and keep crossing
further and further until you've
stabilized it
or here's another idea you can breed two
separate lines you can breed
the same this is the same cross so you
take the scarlet begonias
you take your uh navy cross and you make
seeds
now you find the male and female that
you like that have
the flavor the female's got the flavor
you're looking for
and the male has got it's got the aromas
it's going to work good for breeding and
you cross it to that female
and you make the flavor profile and then
you f2 that for flavor and f3 that
focused on flavor the whole time all the
way up to f4 or f5
and focus on just flavor you need a good
grower you need a good structure you
need a good shape
but the main focus right now is whatever
that flavor you're after
focus in on that i'm going to say
blueberry
diesel i can almost smell what a
blueberry diesel i've smoked blueberry
headband it's probably quite similar
that gassiness with a sweet blueberry to
it with that fake blueberry muffin
flavor on the exhale
i can get that in my mind so we're
searching for that terp
on the blueberry side of the cross now
let's get
a totally different batch of seeds the
same batch of seeds but a different
selection of seeds
and we're pulling out a male and female
that breed for
nothing but potency like they don't
taste super good
they don't yield super fat but it is
potent every time you smoke it
you got to call your mom you got to be
like bro i'm too [ __ ] high i can't
find my keys and the keys are in your
hand
like it's one of those looking for your
sunglasses where you're [ __ ] wearing
them i gotta turn down the music so that
you could see the street signs better
that kind of weed so breed for potency
and then just go f2
potency f3 potency f4 potency
and then by the time you get to f4 f5
you've just bred these plants that every
seed just makes highly ridiculously
potent [ __ ] plants
so now on side a you have still got uh
scarlet begonias cross to navy cross on
the other side you've still got scarlet
begonias crossed a navy cross but
one line is nothing but terps and the
other side is nothing but potency
now guess what we get to do we get to
find the correct progeny from
each line and cross those and then we
get the amazing terps and the amazing
potency and that is when we've got a
true f1 hybrid that is when a true f1
is achieved at that point earlier i said
that we're playing with poly hybrids
that is a good way
to wrap back to the poly hybrid part
until you
work it and stabilize it in such a
manner it is
just a polyhybrid at this point is a
true f1 you've worked the two lines for
desired specific traits with a very
specific goal in mind and then you have
crossed the two
in the end it is really a
long process it could be a lifeline a
lifetime
project but there's no rush there's no
hurry to do this dj short
has been at this since he was a very
young man and he's my senior probably by
i'm gonna give him 10 years on me no no
disrespect dj
uh we respect you because you're our
elder i'm just saying dj's been at it
for a while
you've got your whole life to do it uh
don't try to fast track it
going fast will [ __ ] you up take your
time be patient
grow large numbers if you can a large
population will give you opportunity to
find the plants you're looking for you
can find the uniform plants you can find
the outliers
you'll start being very familiar with
them early
when they start growing if you grow
enough you'll go i don't even want these
plants and you'll just start calling
them you know these aren't for me
this is not for the mix and you'll just
start getting rid of it and then you'll
see it on both sides
you'll be really really good at culling
the plants that do not qualify for your
breeding project
all right so let me make sure i answered
all of that now to make the strain
stable do you keep finding the winners
and inbreeding them
inbreeding isn't the appropriate word
but you've got the right idea yes
you'll have a batch of seeds out of the
seeds find a male find a female
breed them together those will make more
seeds find a male find a female out of
those seeds and breed those together and
just keep going forward
if you want to do two separate breeding
projects to isolate traits and then
bring those together in the future
that is a really beautiful project to
really get a beautiful f1 hybrid
so you did use the word inbreeding which
isn't absolutely correct in this
situation i understand what you were
getting at but i'm just going to talk
about inbreeding briefly here
inbreeding is basically how we make a
back cross inbreeding would be
if we took any of the seeds and bred it
to the parent which it came from
in plant biology it's okay
to uh breed brothers and sisters
together it's okay to breed anything
together but
bringing brothers and sisters together
is more commonplace for moving the
generations forward
uh breeding a parent to one of the
children is actually a back cross and
it's done mainly
to uh stabilize something like the back
cross i would do that if i didn't have
if i wanted to make seeds of something
which i only had a female of and i've
talked about that plenty on other shows
but that is
that is inbreeding if you go uh a seed
back to one of its parents
is actually the inbreeding in cannabis
that can be done a lot of different ways
i just wanted to touch on what
inbreeding actually was since you did
use that word here in the message
all right i think i talked a lot about
that topic i hope i answered your
question
um i really do enjoy talking about
breeding so if you've got any more
breeding questions please do send them
to me
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart is the easiest method or
uh grow from your heart at hotmail.com
will get them to me as well
all right i do have another question
here in front of me also big shout out
to my buddy
slightly stoned stupid 42.
got another question this one came from
our friend red eye and it says i was
also thinking about reversed feminize to
feminized what would we be
expecting so this actually came from a
part of another conversation
i just kind of clipped out this part uh
feels unexplored
okay so basically what they're asking
about is if they crossed a reversed
feminized plant
to a feminized plant what would we be
expecting
basically this is just uh reversing a
female plant and crossing it to a female
plant
you can cross uh feminized plants to
non-feminized plants to regular plants
to
feminize to non however you want to do
it it is possible people ask me a lot of
times
is it okay to breed with feminized
plants yes absolutely
is it okay to keep a feminized plant as
a mother yes absolutely that is the same
thing as a non-femme
plant the only difference was back in
the the pollen stage
we determined that you would not get any
males it was the pollen there was a male
or a female that female pollen had a
female plant made female plants it's all
the same as any other plant except it
was guaranteed a female
a good way to think about it and mr soul
taught me this i'm not taking credit for
this analogy but think
about it when you make feminized seeds
basically we have learned
how to put up a filter and when the
males start shooting pollen we have
learned how to suck out
all of the male pollen out of the air
out of the equation so that only female
pollen
will land onto our female plants that is
not at
all how the process happens but it's a
very good analogy how to explain it the
only difference is the pollen we've
learned how to take
the male pollen out of the equation to
create all female seeds
so crossing reversed feminized to
feminized what would we be expecting
that is basically
uh making a self-plan the things to
think about that would be a variable
here
is are we reversing well it says a
reversed feminized too
feminized is it the same feminized plant
like a golden goat let's just say i grew
let's just say lemon jeffree that's a
better example just for where i want to
go with this
lemon jeffree is a feminized plant it's
not available in regular seeds at all
um let's say we use the painted lady cut
of lemon jeffrey she's got a beautiful
lemon jeffree cut so we take that
painted lady cut of lemon jeffrey
uh i reversed that one because it says a
a reversed feminize so i reverse it
treat it with silver thiosulfate it is
now making
female pollen do i pollinate that same
another cut of the same lemon jeffree at
that point we're just going to expect
more lemon jeffrey we have made an s1
that is a self
version of that lemon jeffree it's going
to make pretty close to copies
stable if you will copies of the
original lemon jeffree there will be
some differences you will see a little
bit of golden goat and some phenotypes
you will see a little bit of
the lemon skunk and some phenos most of
them are gonna look just like the mommy
that i use to recreate it because the
pollen donor and the pollen receiver
basically the mommy and daddy of this
plant were the same plant so it's gonna
look like this plant very much so much
of its genetics
mathematically are this plant you do
like i mentioned have the opportunity to
see that golden goat and to see that
lemon skunk
and also you're going to see weird
outliers that's just how genetics work
you're always going to get some weird
[ __ ] expected that is how genetics work
no matter how hard the breeding just
done
how much work is done nature loves to
throw you some weird [ __ ] and that's
nature's will to survive if we try to
control it too much that's when it
[ __ ] fights back and it's like oh you
think you got the breeding dialed in
watch this and then you get some weird
[ __ ] mutant plants you had no idea
we're gonna come out
so um reversed feminized to
feminized we took that lemon jeffrey we
reversed her we put her on more lemon
jeffrey
we have now made a lemon jeffrey s1
which is probably a little bit different
than just when you do the golden goat to
the lemon skunk you're gonna see
variation there if we take that just the
lemon jeffrey now
and reverse that one and hit the lemon
jeffrey again we're locking in those
lemon jeffree traits we've washed out
the opportunity to see lemon skunk and
golden goat a little bit
giving ourselves even more opportunity
to lock in
that lemon jeffrey trait so if we did
reverse feminize to feminized
what would we be expecting so we've
talked about if we pollinate the same
thing what if we pollinate
a different plant that is when we are
doing what i labeled what i was calling
at some point an
r1 or a reversal i will do an updated
podcast on those labels because i have
received
a lot of feedback on that um and yes
those were kind of terms made up by our
by our industry by somebody in our
industry but it works is why i tried to
go with it
um anyway if you put that reversed lemon
jeffrey pollen on
any other plant you are now making a new
cross and it's going to work just like
if you put any other pollen on
any other plant except it's going to be
all female
and you're going to see let's say i'm
just gonna pick a plant i have to pick a
plant to put this pollen on we're going
to put reversed lemon jeffrey pollen
on uh let's just put it on the chem de
la chem cause that sounds [ __ ]
amazing right lemon jeffrey to kem de la
cam
what it's not happening so don't get too
excited but it sounds [ __ ] beautiful
so now we've got the reversed lemon
jeffrey and we're putting it on
uh chem de la chem pollen or on a chem
daily chem female that wouldn't work
because that one's not
feminized they want to do to a feminized
so let's put that on
something feminized orange gasm let's
throw that on the orange gasm now you've
made
uh orange gasm cross two lemon jeffree
that is a new hybrid that's gonna be
lemon oranges
craziness unfortunately they both have
golden goat in the mix so you're gonna
get a lot of golden goat in the progeny
there but that wasn't that's beside the
point
the point here is that you're just going
to make a new hybrid it will be just
like if you were to put
any other plant in a room and pollinate
any other plant
but since you're using a feminized
starter plant
all of the offspring all the progeny all
of the seeds will be female
i'm gonna say that ah 99.9 percent of
them will be female because like i said
nature does love to [ __ ] with you no
matter how good the breeding is done
it is possible to find a male a full-on
nutty
intersex plant anything wrong i don't
know if i need to edit that word out or
not
um i may if you hear a bleep right there
you know what where to edit it out
because youtube may get on me for that
word
um uh it won't be an
intersex plant it won't have male and
female parts it will be a straight up
full-on male that is an opportunity to
come from feminized seeds
it is one in a million or one in
i'm going to say i don't know 100 000 or
something like that but it is possible
i've seen it happen
i know another breeder who has had it
happen i've seen a breeder
breed with a male that came from
feminized stock
and that makes a lot of females it does
put off
some male plants but most of the
offspring are female so
it is possible no matter how good the
breeding is done those plants are going
to do what they want just like jurassic
park bro
life does find a way
we can't do everything to make the
plants perfect every time we do our best
through selection
so um let's see where were we
crossing reversed to feminize we talked
about that or reverse feminize to
feminized
i wanted to talk about hitting the
reverse pollen to
a the same female to a different female
the same time you're making uh self
plants a second way you're just making
uh r1's reverse plant basically making
new hybrids
i think i answered that one unexplored
had to try it
uh not very unexplored all the breeders
are doing that
um some people don't even realize that
what if you get a clone what if somebody
passes you a clone of lemon jeffrey and
you just decide to breed with it
you probably didn't even think if that
lemon jeffrey came from a feminized seed
stock you just have the clone you
probably don't even think about
if the original plant came from a femme
seed or a regular seed so a lot of
people are doing that
they're just out there breeding with
femme stock with reg stock and they're
not even thinking about it until this
episode now they're going to put thought
into it
they're going to [ __ ] everything up
because now they're aware of it they're
going to stumble over themselves and
trip over their own dicks that's just
how people get
but it's not very unexplored i've been
exploring it i got experience in there
um so crossing reverse feminize to
feminized you're just going to get
great feminized offspring if you do it
right you get great [ __ ]
if you do it to wonky plants that
haven't been tested if they have
problems
uh if they're prone to throw manners i'm
trying to avoid that one word i said a
moment ago the h word because we have a
friend who got their channel flagged for
saying that h word is hate speech
we're actually talking about intersex
plants here please don't flag us
uh but if they're prone to do that the
offspring will do that as well so be
careful with your
selection selection is key all right i
want to send a big thank you to my buddy
red eye thank you for the great question
i hope i answered you because i feel
like i got
super rambly all right i've got another
great email here in front of me
let's not ramble too much let's get
right into this one
oh that's not the one we need for the
show actually here
is it's on the bottom of course here is
the one i wanted to read on
this episode i'm not going to read the
whole message because it is
uh quite long and we can get to the
point kind of quickly here without
reading all of this this one came from
our friend debo
buds this did come from the irie
genetics
website there is a grow help tab on the
ire genetics website if you go to
iregenetics.com
you will see the grow help tab click on
there we ask you a few
a few preliminary questions we ask you
what name you would like to be called on
the podcast in case i do read your
message
big shout out to our buddy deebo buds
getting their message read here we ask
you what strain you're growing why
you're growing it what kind of lights
just a few basic questions to help me
help you so let's get right into it
uh this one is from our buddy debo buds
they're growing a random seed indoor
under
led they're in flower they're five weeks
in
uh they their last feed was a five
gallon res
uh with 19 mils let's see
okay they've broken down every mil of
every nutrient we don't need to read all
that they're feeding
uh botanicare calmag advanced nutrients
sensei bloom
a and b bud blood a quarter scoop of
great white
uh ppm or ec of the last feeding 1200 i
think for
what you're putting in there that seems
a little bit low and for week five a
bloom
that's a little bit low there should be
a couple other things in here the
daytime temps are fine nighttime temps
are fine
no reports on humidity um
so i'm going to read part of this and we
may end up editing this because this is
kind of long we don't need to review all
of this here but it does go on to say
what's up you bad [ __ ] on my
last flower run which was my first
flower
ever during hydroponics i made several
mistakes yes that is going to happen but
owning up to those mistakes is very
important
it says at the time i was doing half
strength of the recommended feeding as i
as it was working well in veg so i
continued that same pattern when
flipping to flower all was well until
week five
so they're doing the recommendation a
lot of times we say
podcasters people who teach you about
growing we say that you only need to use
about half strength of what a nutrient
company recommends on the bottles
because
they do want you to buy more and you can
always add something to your plants but
you can't take nutrients out so start
off at half strength see what the plants
are doing
if they're responding like they're
hungry if they want more of something
you can give it to them
but if they're acting like they're being
burnt or overfed then you know you need
to reduce it
start off weaker work your way up dial
it in figure it out from there
so our friend here was following good
advice going about it the right way they
were feeding
uh have strength nutrients and they were
happy with it the plant seemed happy
until week five it says uh then week
five
i let's see i noticed the ppm of the
runoff was
going up every day like they quit eating
so i added fresh 5.5 ph
water uh that water ph was way too low
you're pissing the plants off
only to top off the res midweek but the
runoff each day continued to climb
so after two days i dumped the res and
started to flush
with ro with ro water with a ph of
5.6 and then for the rest of the week i
just
watered with auro water at a regular
cycle watching the ppm drop back down
from 1200 to 1850 so you were getting a
runoff
of of 18.50
okay i continued this for a week and
never dropped under 1200 i called the
manufacturer okay
now i've got a couple of things to
mention already um
did the plants look okay we didn't talk
about what the plants looked like you
just said
then in week five you notice that the
ppms were way
off um you don't mention that the plants
looked upset
are you growing ph meters are you
growing ec meters or are we growing
plants if the plants looked angry you
didn't include that here so i don't know
but if you're just changing things up
and doing random chaotic [ __ ] to your
plants
because of a meter and the plants didn't
say anything about it
don't do that don't do that the plants
are the boss we're not growing meters
we're not growing monitors we're not
growing programs
we're not trying to make the [ __ ]
charts happy we're trying to make the
plants happy i love all of my toys my
equipment my meters
it makes life easy but those aren't
what i paid the most attention to i pay
attention to
the plants i know what the plants need i
watch the plants do they look happy
then i make a mental note of what
parameters those plants enjoy
i know that these plants like it about
82 degrees they like it about 60
relative humidity they like a little bit
of wind in here they like it when i
water them this often
so then i set up devices that will tell
me when those parameters are being met
or when they are not being met i don't
pay too much attention to the room to
the equipment
to the runoff to the ph coming out of
the plant i watch
the plants and if they're angry they'll
tell me and then i can start
checking my monitors my meters looking
at reports i can see
oh a couple of days ago it got really
hot in here and i can see that today
they're acting a little bit goofy or
a few days ago the runoff on the ph was
a little bit high and now they're acting
goofy now we can react
i don't look at runoff numbers and say
the numbers are wrong we have to change
something
as soon as you start doing that you [ __ ]
up the plants watch the plants they will
tell you
so that is the main thing to start with
um
yeah you don't mention that the plants
were mad you just say that the numbers
were wrong so you changed it then you
said you called the manufacturer in tech
support
and got reprimanded for only using half
of what they recommend
my notes on my page straight up say [ __ ]
that guy if somebody reprimanded you for
using their product the wrong way
[ __ ] that guy and again i've only got to
go by what you said and you said they
reprimanded you so
my if i called a company and i was like
hey i need help with your product and
they reprimanded me
i'd [ __ ] that company i would never give
them another dollar
of my hard-earned money they wouldn't
even hear from me they wouldn't even
i wouldn't even take the energy to talk
[ __ ] about them on a podcast they i
would just forget they even existed
and the brand you're talking about until
you brought them up i basically forgot
they existed anyway
let's keep moving so dude don't let a
nutrient company reprimand you for doing
anything wrong if they had good quality
customer service
they would they what they should do is
take you by your hand and guide you
through it and do it the proper way that
is their job if they want to call
themselves customer service that is the
way to do it
what they did was a dick move that
wasn't cool at all that is not customer
service that's
uh that's an ego problem uh that's
that's yeah it's
being a control freak and having an ego
problem if you want somebody to
use your product you don't reprimand
them i don't think you should reprimand
them if i wanted if you were
called me and you're like dude this
product isn't working i'd say well let's
figure it out and i'd have a phone call
with you and we talk about what did you
do well here's where you went wrong
here's how you can fix it
call me in a week we'll see how it's
going i wouldn't reprimand you
like that's not the way [ __ ] works so i
hope you don't give them any more of
your money abandon ship with those guys
is my uh
vote with your dollars is what scotty
real would tell us so it goes on
uh but man i think i've answered most of
your questions really dude i'm gonna
read a little bit more of this but
honestly
uh one of your mistakes was adjusting
due to numbers don't adjust due to
numbers the bottom line is the plants
are the boss in this whole situation not
the investors
not the owner of the facility not the
irs guy
not city planning and zoning not the
consultant not the lead grower not the
grow tech not the trimmer
not the uh the compliance person none of
those people are the boss they all like
to think they are we all like to think
we are the plants are the boss the
plants dictate
everything in that place uh you should
make a schedule for the plants and you
should have some
some stuff like that they can't write
the rules and the schedules and they
can't go get food
but they are the boss so let them be the
boss i do want to read more of this
uh but when you said you got reprimanded
dude that's frustrating don't ever let a
manufacturer reprimand you you should
call them back and tell them that rosta
jeff said to go [ __ ] yourself
uh then since i didn't think it was
right either but i'm not gonna argue
with them i'm still learning okay so
they did tell you to use it full
strength
i'm learning i didn't know better than
them uh then the ppm stayed high
then they started to drop again and the
plants are now showing sign of flushing
well yeah you've been doing so much to
them now that those plants are just
going to be angry you're in
if you're in any sort of hydro like that
they they do uh they
show you results very quickly and you've
done a lot to them so they've been beat
up
um i'm already let's see figured i'd
switch
ppm to ec on the next run oh yeah using
a different scale may i mess you all up
too when i check the trichomes during
all this time they turn from clear to
some milky and some seem to have stalled
out
your plants are confused yes i'm going
to read more of this to myself really
quickly and we'll see if we can help you
out anymore or if we've covered the
important parts harvested
time to move on sometimes that's the
best way to do it dude
cut it down and take note of what you
did and learn from it and know what to
do and what not to do next time
a lot of learning is learning what not
to do next time you
if you get everything right every time
think about it like if you're a
skateboarder or if you're doing some
extreme sport you're out there on a
[ __ ] freestyle bike or a motorcycle
if you nail the trick the first time
every time you're never gonna learn
anything you're gonna get a big head
you're gonna get a big ego
and then when it comes time to perform
in the x games you're going to get
nervous and you're not going to be able
to do the basic tricks because you've
been out there doing stalefish 360s
can't even [ __ ] kick flip right so um
yeah learn you got to learn from your
mistakes crash and burn and hurt
yourself is where i was trying to head
uh fall down get some road rash break a
couple bones and then you'll learn
i don't need to do that [ __ ] again and
you'll learn that i gotta put my foot
here i gotta put my foot here and you'll
start landing your tricks that's where i
was trying to go with all that nonsense
um there's a lot to this message but
you've harvested
uh this message came in a while back um
my main point of this dude is uh don't
grow meters
don't adjust too much to the meters and
then don't ever let a nutrient company
representative talk down to you
i don't know who you are uh but nobody
should ever reprimand you nobody maybe
your mama or daddy but that's the only
person's
um maybe you're married too sorry uh
let's see
oh i don't have page two of this anyway
there was a second page to this but i
feel like i have answered most of this
question this one actually came to us
quite a while ago so
uh that crop has been harvested i did
want to make sure to read that because
when you said you were reprimanded by
the representative of that grow company
it definitely uh
it made me frustrated so i want to come
on here and just make sure that you uh
stand up for yourself next time
and my main point is don't grow meters
we're not growing meters we're not
growing ec meters we're not growing i
love all my toys don't get me wrong i
always talk about that i know my friends
that give me meters and make programs
and stuff they're going come on use the
meters
i do but they're not the boss the plants
are the boss the meters are what i use
to uh as markers and indicators if i've
got a problem then i go to the meters
the plants say
something's wrong i look at them i can
usually identify a problem but i can use
the meters
the programs the notes to kind of back
up my claims if i have to go to
a facility owner and say hey i think
this is happening we need to spend money
on this
they say prove it and i go the plants
show this the
status shows this reports show this and
this piece of equipment shows this
i've isolated the problem to this they
go that's good work we'll order the
product you think i don't just go
hey the plants are looking like this we
gotta add calmag and they go oh
how do you know that and i go because
they're showing the little rusty spots
dude
they go no let's look at the reports
let's look at some [ __ ] and let's
[ __ ] back that claim up with
something
then we adjust the calmac all right i
did want to make sure to get that one
answered because it did come in quite a
ways
ago i feel like i rambled through that
one quite a bit but
one of your problems is that you're
mixing brands it looks like you were
doubling up on your base nutrients in
this also
um use a more reputable brand use a
brand that didn't reprimand you
i would recommend using new millennium
bottled nutrients they don't pay me to
say that but they're good people they've
got great customer service
uh and a lot of my teachings are based
on using their products so if you're
using them you can follow along very
easily with me it's very easy to
understand that way
but don't let anyone reprimand you and
uh
grow from your heart watch the plants
don't worry so much about the meters
all right ladies and gentlemen boys
girls pimps hoes friends foes
smokers growers clone cutters paul and
chuckers all you beautiful cannabis
enthusiasts out there that is all i've
got for you for this episode
of the show i want to thank you again
for hanging out if you have any
questions corrections comments or
concerns you know that i would love to
hear from you
the email address of course is grow from
your heart at hotmail.com
please don't be shy reach out let me
know what you think if you've got any
updates if you want me to talk about
something on the show
let me know i love generating listener
created
content also don't forget to check us
out on discord the link is in the show
notes and
in the video description also don't
forget about the patreon
at patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all right it is time for me
to wrap up this show you know i'll be
back in a couple of days with fresh new
content
i want to give a giant shout out to my
friend jinx proof and until next time
take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you