[Music]
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rasta jeff and this
is episode 659 of the grow from your
heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to talk a
little bit about watering our plants
then i'll talk a little bit about a
seeded plant before we get to that part
of the show
let's do a few shout outs to a few of
the kind folks who support the show
on patreon let's start off with the big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to my friend girls grow too
let's send a big thank you shout out to
my buddy north north terps
let's follow that up with a big thank
you shout out of course to mrs
north north turp arena turpington let's
send a big thank you shout out to my
buddy big sexy dank
i want to send a big thank you shout out
to black hippie and new old guy
let's send a thank you shout out to g7
and pack northwest dan
i want to send a big thank you shout out
to my friend adhd grower
let's send a thank you shout out to
shakoba i want to send a big thank you
shout out to rosta green thumb
let's send a big thank you shout out to
my buddy kes burton i want to send a
special thank you shout out to a
longtime friend jesse gross
then let's wrap it all up with the big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out
to my friend and a great test grower
let's send a thank you shout out to my
buddy mobius groves
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon
if you are not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need is right
there on the screen and of course there
is a link in the show notes
and in the video description
again i do want to invite you to join me
on discord i do have a great discord
server
there are a lot of wonderful people
hanging out on discord right now while
we're hanging out watching the podcast
they are probably watching the show and
hanging out on discord talking about it
doing like a a grow companion sort of a
hangout sort of a show if you know what
i'm talking about
so they are over there on discord i
invite you to join us on discord there
is a link
in the show notes and the video
description right next to that patreon
link
join us on discord big shout out to my
whole crew over there on discord they
said they don't need love and shout outs
but
love you guys want to give you a shout
out so i won't list you individually
they know who they are big shout out to
the gang holding it down over there on
discord
i've been hanging out there more than
making more time to be more active on
the social media
i was overwhelmed with work stuff you
guys don't care about that but
i've been making an effort to be more
active on the social media and my
discord channel is a place i've really
been making an effort to be more present
it's got my name on it it's got my face
on it it's my crew it's my army
i should be there so i've been trying to
be there be more present hang out with
the crew pop in
share some love give some gifts away do
some
some things you never know what could
happen over there on the ire
genetics irie army grow from your heart
discord channel there is a link in the
video and show notes description
make it nice and easy for you to get
there it's a long weird link for me to
type
all right let's move forward what else
do i want to say oh also make sure you
please do like and subscribe to this
video in the previous episode i did ask
that we get the show
to 10 000 subscribers uh we're almost to
8 000 at the time i'm recording this
uh probably 7.7 i did not look uh very
recently but we were pretty close to 7.7
000 so thank you for the big push a lot
of my friends did post to social media
saying hey let's get rosta jeff to 10k i
do appreciate all of the support from
the community
all the love for my friends trying to
get us up to ten thousand big love big
respect thank you guys for that support
if you haven't already done it please
press that subscribe button
click like on the video maybe type in
some comments let us know what you think
about the show if you're watching on
youtube
all right let's do move forward i did
say that i had some grow
lessons we were going to talk a little
bit about watering plants
um i've been working with a couple of
other people i may be teaching people
how to water some plants we don't need
to go into too many details about that
but as i was teaching people to water
these plants
basically what i did was i went to their
grow and i just stood around and watched
them do their thing
i kind of acted aloof a little bit i
looked like i was on my phone i looked
like i was distracted that was an
appearance that i gave on purpose
they got comfortable in their grow
environment and they did their day in
the grow
and i just kind of watched and they
didn't know i was watching in such
detail but i took a few notes on the
phone wrote down some ideas
thought of ways we can improve their
grow that's what i was there for so one
of the things i really noticed that
these people were doing
that they could improve upon i noticed
right away is they are watering the very
center of their plants it doesn't matter
what size container you've got if you've
got 1 gallon 2 gallon
3 gallons 50 gallons it doesn't matter
what size your container is
it is not ideal to water just the center
part of that plant maybe when that plant
is a baby when it's new
when it's just getting established and
doesn't have a big root system
it's okay to water that inner inner uh
circle there but once the plant grows
then we're going to water want to water
the outer
part of that plant the roots are only
going to grow where there is water it's
going to look they're going to look for
water
but if they don't find water they're
just going to die and those ends are
that's where the roots end is where the
water doesn't go
so if we do water these plants at the
outer edge a little bit more the roots
will grow out that way we will get
bigger
bigger roots bigger healthier roots in
some ways do translate to bigger
healthier fruits that is
kind of a good catchphrase it's not a
hundred percent accurate because i can
grow you
big ass plants in tiny pots and a hydro
system but if you do have big fat
healthy roots
your plants will be more healthy they
can eat better they could cycle better
uh you can get a longer wet and dry time
so if you want to go away for the
weekend you can water them down you can
leave
anyway you want a bigger root system you
want to water uh
instead of just watering right in the
middle because i was watching these
people walk up to their pot they'd get
their watering container and just pour
it right in the middle
and i was like you maybe hit like 30 of
the root zone of that plant the water's
going right down the middle of that pot
it's not spreading out maybe it is
through gravity in the way that it flows
but it would have been more ideal
to water the whole top part of that
plant and let it soak all the way down
do apologize for the raspy voice i
promise that didn't happen until i
pressed record today and then i got the
raspiness
we're gonna fight right through that so
uh water the outer part of the plant not
just the newer plant
as the plants are growing if they're
brand new absolutely you do just have to
water that inner
part that's where the plant is but if
you've got the appropriate pot size for
your plant and for its roots
you should be watering most of that root
zone most of that soil zone
so don't just water the center water the
outside if you think about it the plants
are
shaped like an umbrella so if you think
about it the rain would come down
and the leaves would hit the rain would
hit the top leaves and it would spread
it out wider and then it would go down
and spread it out wider and go down and
spread it out wider that's how the
leaves are shaped they kind of taper
outward
in a tier system just like we build a
roof just the way we put the shingles on
the roof the water has to flow a certain
way
the leaves are already doing that that's
probably where we got the idea of how to
lay the shingles
so the plant the rain will hit the water
the water will drip
outward and then if you look at the
ground where it rains there will be a
big circle of water around your plant
right under the plant
didn't even get watered because unless
water flowed into there but it was
protected from
the plant it didn't get hit underneath
but all around it is all wet and all
that root zone in that big circle is
getting wet so
if you think about it the plants do want
water at that outer edge they're shaped
like an umbrella
so let's get water to that outer edge
then here are some things that will
happen
your plant will branch out more it won't
think it's in a little tiny
zone and it will branch out more it'll
get more branching it'll get more
activity it will get more
growth also i noticed that these people
had their plants in too small
of a pot uh those plants weren't going
to grow very big and they weren't
they probably were in the right size pot
because they weren't watering enough
uh to get them to fill the pot but i
would recommend a larger pot than what
they were using because their plants are
going to get root bound which is another
thing that was causing their plants to
get tall
and lanky their plants were very tall
and skinny so if we water
more space to water more space for roots
those plants are going to grow wider if
you've got
the root base tucked into a little tiny
coffee can they're going to get tall and
skinny if you put into a bigger pot
they're going to get wider they'll have
more root space
they'll feel more comfortable getting
larger um
also their plants were too close
together which wasn't too big of a deal
because they were tall and lanky
uh they had a bunch of fish and pole
plants going on um
they were too pressed together too tall
and lanky and in too small of a pot
they were starting to autoflower because
they were so upset
they were too close together some of the
lower stuff wasn't getting light they
didn't clean up any of the bottoms that
stuff was starting to autoflower
they were pressed so close together the
light wasn't getting down
uh into the canopy but having those
plants pressed so closely together
and not cleaning up the bottoms of them
was making them go into flour and the
roots haven't even filled these
containers yet so it's way early to
flower these plants and it was way early
for them to be so tall so uh these
plants were going into flour
uh they were not ready to flower they
were not healthy they were too tall
so the things we can start with is water
that outer edge then another thing we
can do is make sure
to have our plants far enough apart
where they can grow and get some
branching on them
then another thing we should do is make
sure to up pot at the right time
uh to prevent that early flowering
because once they do get
uh root bound they can go into flower
early on you all right i've got a lot of
notes in front of me i'm gonna make sure
i covered them
i feel like i covered that section quite
quickly i hit all the bullet points i've
got here let's move on
to a grow question that came from my
friend brohan
78 on patreon again that is patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart
this one says hey ross to jeff i was
wondering something i recently grew your
golden goat fans
oh you're a very lucky person those
golden goat feminist seeds are sold out
i have and will be sold out for a short
time they will be back but right now
you're a lucky person to have those it
says they came out beautifully by the
way
ah thank you and that's a good work to
you i made good seeds
you had to grow them took you nine
probably 12 weeks to get that whole
project completed maybe more
good job you did all the hard work so it
says i found one perfect looking seed
and a bud
there were no males around at all would
this seed even be viable
thank you all right so i've said this
several times on several shows before
i'm not blaming you nothing for not
hearing it but this is my theory on how
this works
uh plants are a lot like jurassic park
nature
finds a way the number one goal for our
plants
ah we have a lot of ideas and a lot of
goals for them we want to grow them and
pop and twist them and defoliate them we
want to smoke them and we want them to
get us high and we want to turn it into
concentrates or baked goods or whatever
this plant has one main goal in its own
mind and that is to reproduce
to make seeds for the next season that
is your plant's whole goal if it's a
female plant
it wants to get seeded if it's a male
plant it wants to do some pollinating
so that is the main goal of this plant
these plants will
find a way to survive so it is not
uncommon
for these plants to kind of just throw
one or two random seeds some people will
call it a stress seed some people will
call it a herm seed
if you don't see any intersex flowers on
that plant then it's nothing to worry
about
sometimes a plant will make a seed
because it is striving to survive
oftentimes this is because the plant
went a little bit longer than it should
have but if you've got one
fully developed perfect looking seed
that seed happened early in the
flowering process
and that that bud just that plant just
knew i'm really good bud and we have to
continue so it made a seed it is natural
life does find a way
uh it's the jurassic park theory is what
i call it and i think i borrowed that
from james bean so shout out to my buddy
james bean if that is where i learned
the jurassic park theory
so what is happening here is basically
uh life will find a way there are a few
things that could cause this it could
have been stress
uh it could have been some intersex
trait it could have just been
uh life finding a way there's another
thing known as i'm going to say it wrong
because i didn't google the word before
rotalization road i think it's
rotalization
anyway what it is is uh growing the
plant longer than it needed to flower
and then that will make the plant make
seeds uh it doesn't sound like you did
that because you probably didn't know
the seed was in there you probably just
harvested your normal buds and you're
grinding up a bowl one day and heard
tink tink in the grinder and went oh
dude i got a seed in here
um so we call that a gift that is a gift
that is a free bc the follow-up is
uh there were no males around at all
yeah uh that's just the life will find a
way the will to survive then it says
would this seed even be
viable thanks for your help hey my
friend brohan 78 thank you for the great
question this is a good springboard for
some rambling here this seed if it looks
perfect
uh the only way to find out if it is
viable is to grow it
does it sprout let's see what happens
then veg it up
take a clone of it because you may have
the next
champion plant this could be something
amazing this could be better than the
original golden goat this could blow
golden goat out of the water
or this could be complete trash this
could just be
something with nanners on it this could
just be a totally freaky mutant plant
that you want to throw away
but it could be amazing this is how a
lot of famous strains were created we're
going to talk about that in a minute but
get a clone of this plant flower it out
see what it does
smoke it with your friends maybe you
don't even need to smoke it with that
maybe you're
halfway through growing it you're going
to say look it's nothing but trichomes
it's just a trichome tree maybe that's
what you've got maybe it's charlie
brown's christmas tree
and you'll know three weeks into flower
that it's a winner or a loser
but grow it out finish it up see what it
does um
what you technically have would be
labeled bag seed don't call it golden
goat
just say it's golden goat bag seed that
means it came from a bag of golden goat
and it is a seed
that we don't know why that seed
happened we know it came from golden
goat buds
so we know the female was golden goat
but we don't know why that seed happened
so we can't label it
with a full-on name that's not an
a-grade seed because we don't know the
full pedigree of that
so you've got a bag seed it could be
anything it could be
amazing it could be trash let's talk
about a few strains that i
feel happened this way or in a similar
manner
i feel the original golden goat actually
was an accident it was not supposed to
be bread
a guy had a male plant and he had a
female plant and they actually it wasn't
me i did not breed the original golden
goat by the way let me clear that up
that was made by mr dank in topeka
kansas
but uh mr dank's male plant got away
from him it pollinated his female plant
he found some seeds in there when he was
smoking it or i don't know if he was
smoking or what but he found the seeds
that became the golden goat that was an
accident
so that was technically bag seed that's
the same scenario
which you've got accidental seed it
became golden go which is
world renowned it's a famous [ __ ]
strain that see those seeds sell out
every seed i make sells out immediately
so that's a very famous strain and it
was made by
accident gorilla glue was made by
accident it's another one of the world's
most famous strains
it's sought after all of the seeds of
gorilla glue get
sold people claim to have gorilla glue
crosses that they don't have it's clone
only
just like the golden goat until we made
it into femme seeds
uh but anyway i digress that one is
another accident
we've got the cookies the girl scout
cookies i suspect i cannot prove
but i don't think girl scout cookies was
really made with anything on purpose or
we would know what it was people would
somebody would come forward and say it
was this
cross to this i did it in this basement
somebody would say that
instead it shrouded with mystery which
makes me think it was an accidental bag
seed that somebody found and they grew
and they found a gem just like you
possibly have in there
let's talk about something else we
should mention all of the chem dog line
everything that came from chem dog
genetics started
with bag seed i always talk a little bit
about
chem dog and the legend of the 13 beans
i'm not going to go too deep into it
i don't have any notes i just decided
right now that i would kind of update
you on the chem dog story there was a
guy
he wasn't known as kim dog yet we're not
going to say his name um
he went to some grateful dead shows and
he met up with some guys
named aj and peabud and aj and peabud
were growing some weed
that they called dog bud they called it
dog bud because when you smoked on it
you smoked it
uh you rolled over on your back like a
dog they called it the dog bud
some of their friends were calling it
the chem wheat because it smelled like
chemicals they were asking what kind of
chemicals they grew it with this is the
best of my recollection of this story
so peabud and joe were growing
we're getting i don't know if they were
growing it or getting it i don't know
that part they were getting the dog bud
they uh were calling it dog bud because
it would make you stone like a dog you
lay on you roll over on your back like a
dog or they were calling it the chem
weed because their friend said it
smelled like chemicals
that kind of spawns the name chemdog
right there they were not putting a w
in it it was chem dog with an o so all
of us that are using the w
we're doing it wrong old school chem dog
with an o not with a w
so uh these guys run into a guy
uh whose name will be left out of the
story at a grateful dead concert at deer
creek so
he buys some weed from him he realizes
this weed's [ __ ] fire
they exchange numbers uh grateful dead
tour ends
uh peabud and joe go back to colorado
allegedly breckenridge is where i think
this where they were from
um the guy who later becomes kem dog
goes back to his place
he contacts them later says i want some
herb ah
they teleported them some wheat now they
[ __ ] mailed it to him allegedly
probably i don't know exactly how that
happened they got him
uh so the boys in colorado allegedly got
the man who later became kem dog they
got him some product
uh there was allegedly i've heard two
different stories i heard there were
three ounces i heard there were four
ounces
um if anybody wants to chime in
somewhere and let me know that
i'm all about it i want to get this
story right and i just now decided to
tell you so i'm trying to remember the
best i can from memory
so these guys get herb to the man who
becomes chem dog
chem dog finds 13 seeds in this bag of
weed in the
all three ounces or four ounces however
many he got
there were 13 seeds he sprouted some of
them
some of them were males they got removed
i've heard him talk on future podcasts
uh no i can't hear him talk on future
podcasts
but after this story i heard him talk on
podcast that was
i knew what i meant you knew what i
meant i heard him talk on podcasts where
he said i wish i knew what i was doing
with those males because now i kick
myself for calling those males
yeah bro me too those males were
probably [ __ ] amazing so the kim dog
males got tossed there were
all the females that he found he kept i
think he may have more seeds according
to the legend of kim dog in the 13 beans
of those 13 beans we got the chem 91
i'm going to guess he popped that in 91
we got the chem d
which had a lot of i'm not exactly sure
why it got called kim d but it had a lot
of that
tennis ball uh chemical sort of a smell
to it
uh the chem 91 was skunkier in my
opinion that's my favorite is the skunky
one
the chem d is kind of gassier in tennis
balls uh then there's the kem's sister
and there are other chems that came from
that i should have done research but the
top three that you'll know
are the chem 91 uh the chem d and the
kim's sister i don't know if there was
one that was just straight called chem
dog
but that is chem dog is the guy who
found those seeds in a bag of weed and
he grew them
now we're calling the weed chem dog and
there's a guy known as chem dog from
some seeds that came from bags of weed
what you've got is bag seed you could
have the next chem dog you could be
the guy of legend of the golden goat s1
and the one bean that could be you
right now or you could have trash that
you should throw away at week four
but that is my recollection of randomly
decidingly
deciding to tell you the legend of kem
dog in the 13 beans there were two guys
in colorado
they had some herb they were calling it
the dog weed uh they met a guy at a
grateful dead show
they became friends later on they got
him some of the herb he found 13 seeds
those 13 seeds netted us some of the
most
uh prolific influential cannabis in our
uh catalog in our gene pool in our
[ __ ] culture everybody knows what kem
dog is
everybody knows about chem d everybody's
smoked chem
chem dog you hear about it it's
legendary so that is where it came from
it was
bag seed uh recently i had a friend say
dude have you shopped at this dispensary
and i was like no i don't really shop
there and he's like they have a shelf
that
it's all seeded but the wheat is super
good but it's got a few seeds in it and
i was like how many seeds are in he's
like you get like one or two seeds in
eighth
and i did the math i got how much is an
ounce and he told me i go bro just go
buy an ounce and hope you get 10 seeds
in there that's like buying a [ __ ]
pack of killer seeds if you grow that
you're gonna find fire in there and he's
like really bro
and i was like those are free seeds bro
go get those most people are gonna be
mad but go buy an ounce and
hope you get a 12 pack of free seeds
it'll be worth it
that's what the out the price of an
ounce is what a 10 or 12 pack of seeds
would cost you on the market
and then basically he's getting an ounce
of shitty weed to go with it that's the
way i thought about it
told him go get an ounce of that weed
anyway
i digress i'm rambling i'm not sure how
long i've been going but
let's do it this way i've got a lot of
editing to do i've been learning a
couple of tricks of final cut pro
by the way thank you for all the
compliments uh the feedback
all of that good stuff on the last
couple of episodes i've been working
hard on making creative intros
i've been working hard on just doing
some details to make the show
better i do appreciate you for watching
i want to keep your attention i want to
be a top notch podcast
i feel like the content coming from this
section
the notes the show that part is good in
my opinion i could be wrong it's my show
but i feel like the next step is
production so thank you for the
compliments the words of encouragement
the words of wisdom some people have
sent me some feedback and stuff and some
advice also thank you for all of that
thank you for growing with me and being
patient while i grow this is going to be
probably
kind of a short episode because i do
need to get to editing i need to figure
some stuff out
uh also working on color correcting is
the next move i am never the right color
in these videos
we're going to figure that [ __ ] out one
of these days color correction is fun
anyway i am rambling i got super stoned
before this episode i've had a good long
day finally cooling down a little bit
wasn't melting uh thank you guys for
hanging out thank you for joining me for
another episode of the grow from your
heart podcast you guys 659 episodes that
is madness
madness thank you i do appreciate it um
if you've got any questions corrections
comments or concerns you know that i
would love to hear from you
the email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com don't be shy
send me some updates questions
corrections comments concerns
constructive criticism don't worry about
my pride i need to know what you're
thinking that's the only way we can
improve the show
also don't forget about the website
iregenetics.com lots of great stuff on
iriegenetics.com
if you scroll halfway down there is a
stay up to date tab where you can put in
your email address and you will receive
a newsletter approximately once a month
that will let you know what is going on
with ire genetics maybe you'll get
coupon codes
for vendors maybe you'll get a coupon
code for the web store where you can get
some fresh t-shirts or different gear
that we may have coming up
you'll get the first notifications when
those things go on the website
uh maybe you'll get coupon codes all the
stuff that we're doing maybe some event
details that are coming up we will be at
the indo expo in denver
the denver expo there are multiple
denver indo expos i'm a hometown hero
doing the denver show
so look forward to seeing you there that
will be uh those details will be on the
website fairly soon
also the discord i do invite you once
again to join us on discord discord is a
good time
there's a spot to post pictures there's
a spot to ask questions
there's a place to get seeds there's a
place to hang out and do a video chat
sometimes i pop in the video chat hang
out
i say i'm going to go in the video chat
on discord for an hour and take a dab
with my friends and then guess what it's
[ __ ] four in the morning i'm still in
there dabbing
thank you guys for entertaining me
thanks for hanging out you're invited
you never know when i might be in there
you might pop in and i might be taking
dabs we'll chat we'll [ __ ]
do a dab together all that good stuff
all right uh the email the website the
discord and of course don't forget about
cannabis and please if you're watching
this on youtube now is the time
to like and subscribe we're trying to
get the show up to 10 000 subscribers
it's free all you got to do is click the
subscribe button all right ladies and
gentlemen boys girls pimps hoes friends
foes smokers growers clone cutters paul
and chuckers
all of you beautiful cannabis
enthusiasts out there i really do want
to thank you once again for listening to
another fun-filled episode of the grow
from your heart podcast you know
i will be back in just a couple of days
with fresh new content
i want to give a giant shout out to the
captain and commander of the irie army
let's send a big thank you shout out to
my good friend lemur priest
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
you