[Music]
yeah welcome to the show podcast world
i'm your host my friends call me rasta
jeff
and this is episode 660
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to answer a
couple of grow questions
before we get to those grow questions
let's do a few shout outs to a few of
the kind folks
who support the show on patreon let's
start off with the big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out
to my friend scooters3g send a big thank
you shout out to jessica k
i want to send a thank you to dank
groves i want to send a big thank you
shout out to my friend crazyhandgroves
let's send a thank you shout out to my
new friend justin clauser i want to send
a thank you shout out to elder's garden
and stoner dave
let's send a big thank you shout out to
716 vibes and james butterson
i want to send a special thank you shout
out to my friend the painted lady
then let's wrap it all up with the big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out
to my friend chicago dabber big thanks
and big shout out to everybody
who continues to support the show on
patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need is right there on the screen and of
course i did include a link
in the show notes and the video
description to make it super easy for
all of my friends if you've been
watching the past couple of episodes
you know this is the part of the show
where i invite you to join us on the
discord channel
that's right there's an irie army
discord where all the irie genetics crew
the grow from your heart podcast crew
are hanging out on the discord right now
there's a live chat happening
somebody's posting pictures dave's doing
an auction or a raffle or something of
that nature up there
join us on the discord channel there is
a link in the show notes and
in the video description all right
i do want to start the show by uh saying
uh that a few of my friends have
mentioned something that i think is
funny
i have decided that when you overflow
the reservoir at a new grow
you have simply baptized the place with
your new presence that is now
your new grow it's like i licked it it's
mine or i peed on it it is mine
that is what happens when you overflow
the reservoir at a grow
the first time you do it that is your
new place the second time you do it
uh we got to figure out an excuse for
that the third time set a [ __ ] timer
and quit taking so many dabs on your
break but the first time you overflowed
that reservoir
welcome to your new grow that is a
christening uh that is a rite of passage
it's funny the first time
it's a real [ __ ] the second time but
the third time it gets embarrassing
i wanted to give a shout out to a friend
who overflowed his reservoir
uh you're not gonna get your name said
but bro big shout out much respect
welcome to the crew we have all done it
it's gonna happen again overflow gang
all right
where do i go from there i've got a good
question so
many people might not be aware but i am
not only the grow from your heart
podcast not only do they know me as
rosta jeff but also i am the
uh head breeder the only breeder the
founder sole proprietor of irie genetics
premium seeds that's right i make irie
genetics premium seeds that is all me
i do have a nice test crew that helps me
out i do have some friends helping me
with the project this summer
but 99.99 of irie genetics is all me
there's a web guy shout out to the web
guy shout out to the testing
crew but the breeding the selection all
of that stuff happens
by me i do offer a product
called table seeds um they're not
available on a website or anything if
you get seeds
through some avenues through some
auctions or some raffles or perhaps a
waffle
they do offer table seeds as a bonus
let me take a moment to describe what
table seeds are before we get into this
message
table seeds are just exactly what they
sound like
let's say hypothetically i was sitting
at this table and i was packing up
a bunch of seed packages and i put a
package of whatever seeds into a bowl
and then i dispersed those seeds from a
bowl into ten packs or into five packs
sometimes when i'm done as i'm cleaning
up i discover
seeds on the table guess what those get
labeled those are now what are known as
table seeds
unknown soldiers if i've worked with a
couple of strains over the course of the
day
and we clean up at the end of the day i
may find 10 or 12 seeds and i don't know
which bag they came from
i do not give them a name i'm not that
kind of guy i don't just
assign them a name i don't just pick a
bag for them to go into
i don't just fake it for you i actually
set them aside they go into another bowl
that is labeled table seeds just all the
random seeds i clean up off the table
maybe i found it
tucked under the side of the computer
maybe it rolled off that way
maybe i just don't know which bag it
came out of instead of trying to fake it
like i said earlier
i don't lie to you i don't cheat you i
don't rip you off it gets assigned the
word
table seeds then when you buy seeds at a
waffle or an action
yes we do be careful with some of the
words we say it's just jokes there
when you do buy stuff in a waffle or an
action i do send you extra table seeds
as a bonus as a thank you
that's just my way of giving you more
[ __ ] you do get bonus packs every time
you shop with me but
i will send you extra table seeds if
i've got them uh they're low right now
so i stop doing it
once they pile back up and i've got more
to make it worth our time and energy i
will put the table seeds back in the mix
now that you know what table seeds are
oh the beauty about table seeds let's
talk about
how magical table seeds are they could
be
anything in my lineup it could be
anything i've ever
released it could be anything i've never
released it could be stuff you've heard
of a thousand times
it could be [ __ ] you have never heard of
anything any seed that has ever crossed
this table
has the potential to end up as a table
seed if i drop
if i've got a congo to arise or uh jack
the ripper to
oh let's not say too many things right
jack the ripper to lemon skunk maybe i
dropped one of those seeds and it rolled
off somewhere and i found it later
that's in the table seed mix and i don't
even know what it is they could be rags
they could be fems it's kinda
irie genetics bag seed is close to what
that is you know it's from me
but you don't know if it which male or
female was involved in that mix
in any way so those are table seeds they
could be anything from my lineup it
could be a feminized cross it could be a
king solomon cross it could be a jack
the ripper cross it could be an old
daybreaker cross it could be a king chem
grape stomper cross it could be
anything out of my lineup i think i made
enough
stress on that so this question stems
from the table seeds
this one came from our friend grow can
advocate it looks like this one came
over
patreon i do think big you big thank you
for the patreon support
it does go on it says rasta jeff i can't
thank you enough for the wisdom
you impart to the cannabis community
through your videos and podcasts
ah thank you those compliments those
words of encouragement mean a lot to me
so thank you it says we're we are a
better
community because of you i don't know
that i'm making a better community but
if you say so
that's humbling that is awesome i'm
going to politely take the compliment
but i don't know that i mean maybe i did
make the whole community better there's
a really cool chill vibe in the discord
so go hang on go see the community we
did create you're right bro i'll quit
fighting with you
it goes on though it says here is my
question as a patreon supporter i've
tried to hang out on the discord channel
and learn from all of the fine folks in
the irie army and i've even had the
chance to win
one of the seed auctions a few months
back yes allegedly possibly
there may be some seed auctions over on
the discord we got to be careful what we
say on youtube
but allegedly that could be a thing it
says i'm currently growing iri genetics
blue raspberry truffle
and in the package i got a handful of 10
or fifth notes is 15 or 20
table seeds which is funny because they
come in packs of 10
and you got 15 or 20 which means i was
generous with your table seeds i just
like to give you extra [ __ ]
money is expensive and when you guys
choose to spend your hard-earned money
especially during the past year and a
half two years we've had
when we're not absolutely sure where the
next nickel and dime could come from
money is extra expensive and when you
chose to spend your hard-earned money
your scarce money with my company on my
brand i appreciate it so i make sure to
show you that i love you
that i appreciate you i know there are
thousands of other breeders out there
there are thousands of other breeders on
the same website where you buy my [ __ ]
so taking the uh the just buying my
brand and supporting my brand it means a
lot to me so i want to make sure you get
more than what you paid for um that's if
you get what you paid for
you feel good if you don't get what you
paid for you feel kind of angry but if
you get extra you're like damn i'm gonna
go back there again it's just inviting
it's encouraging and i want to show you
that
i'm appreciative for it um i don't know
i've i've been given a gift
i don't talk about spirituality and
stuff but uh i'm rich
spiritually and all that [ __ ] so i'm i'm
ready to give you more when you spend
your money with you with me that's what
i want to do make sure you feel the
customer service
so you got 15 or 20 table seeds in your
10 pack is where that ramble stemmed
from
goes on to say here is my question since
the table seeds are unknown strains but
otherwise good genetics i was going to
run
all of them at once and do a fino hunt
that's a really good strategy but then i
got to thinking
is there anything wrong or unethical
about breeding with them
i'm in prohibition land so i'm
personally not in it to make a bunch of
seeds and sell them
as a breeder how would you feel if
somebody took your table seeds and kept
the genetics going by breeding them
maybe even finding something pretty cool
oh you'll find something pretty [ __ ]
cool in there uh
what's the right thing to do with naming
anything that comes out of this i can
see this from both sides
as a breeder i wouldn't want my name on
stuff that i couldn't control the
outcomes
but on the flip side if it comes from
stock that i've put my heart and soul
into
i'd want to make sure it's legit so if
you tell me to [ __ ] off
bro i would never tell anybody to [ __ ]
off uh this is i've got full respect
no matter what your idea is i'll sit
down and have a conversation with you so
never [ __ ] off always approach me with a
smile and be ready for a friendly
uh conversation maybe we'll smoke a dab
however we gotta do it we'll find a
resolution that is friendly that we can
both agree on
never gonna tell you to [ __ ] off no
matter who you are out there unless you
need to [ __ ] off
uh it says i just wanna grow this [ __ ]
and smoke it i'm good with oh if you
want me to tell me to [ __ ] off and just
grow this [ __ ] and smoke and i'm good
with that thanks again for all you do
much love from canna no grow can
advocate all right this is a very good
question it gives me the opportunity to
talk about a couple things here
this person is asking if they can breed
with the table seeds first
question the first question is can i
breed with your seeds is basically what
they're asking
yes i encourage support
promote uh endorse you breeding with my
seeds if i made the seeds
and you acquired them through a
reasonable ethical
moral method if you didn't steal them
rip somebody off or lie to get them
i encourage you to breed with them have
a good time those are your
seeds ah you paid money for them
somebody's got money for them either
myself or the vendor that sold them to
you or the bro that sold them to you
somebody made some money once they left
my hands i have no say-so no control
ah no real i i care that you have a
successful outcome but other than that i
can't really care too much about what
you do with them i can't stay attached
to them
uh once i accepted money they're yours i
can't make rules on [ __ ] people
paid me money for uh that's when you
tell me to [ __ ] off when i take your
money and give you rules that's when i
[ __ ] off that's
that's how that should go so i encourage
it i promote it i endorse it i support
it please do breed with the seeds that
you get from me
that is cool i bred with seeds i got
from other growers i bred with seeds and
clones that came from other breeders
i did not invent cannabis i didn't just
meditate one day and manifest
a batch of seeds i had to start with
seeds or clones that came from another
grower another gardener which was
another breeder
so i didn't invent seeds i didn't invent
cannabis and i
feel no way territorial or uh protective
of the plant or of
i do feel protective of the plant but
not of the breeding you should be able
to play freely just like i do there are
seeds there are grow lights have a good
time you've got my blessings
um yeah i didn't invent this plant so i
can't stop you i want you to breed maybe
you'll make better [ __ ] than me that
would be
awesome i would be really delighted and
proud to see you
use one of my packs of seeds and make
something better than anything i've ever
done that would make me happy
as a teacher as a breeder i'm not going
to be around forever i don't expect to
[ __ ] live forever i need people to be
a good grower better breeders i have to
pass this torch eventually
there were breeders that taught me how
to do this i hope to teach you
the same way also i hope to teach you
good ethics and good morals within
breeding so let's talk about that part
now
you can use my stuff you've got my full
permission when you do
that it would be cool and this is a
special case because these are table
seeds if you use any of my seeds that
you know what they are
just say that was strawberry starburst
cross to whatever you used just put give
credit to it just
be honest don't lie and say that secret
strain a to secret stream b
first of all the community doesn't trust
you doesn't want that but second of all
that's a dick move give
us credit if you notice my packages of
seeds it always says
this crossed to this i want you to know
that that was
sub cools jack the ripper across to my
arise or
however it went crockett's uh strawberry
fields to my
daybreaker whatever i did i want you to
know that way i'm not lying to anybody
misleading anybody
uh they're also i'm giving credit to the
people who i'm using their work that's
important also
medical smokers are looking for relief
and they know certain strains help them
so if they see that
maybe og kush is something that works
great for a person and then strawberry
something if it's got strawberry in it
maybe it works really good for a person
if they can look through the genetic
history and see this has og cushion
strawberry on one side and og cushion
the terps on the other side
it may they know how to map out their
medicine a little bit that way it gives
them a hint it gives them a clue at what
to select for their medical consumption
so i think it's important for several
reasons that we label these plants
properly correctly with the crosses and
honor
the original breeders that made those
plants i feel that anything you learn
it's very important to honor the source
we aren't [ __ ] wizards most of us
learn from google
so you'll hear me say a lot of times
things like i learned that from mr soul
or i read this in soma's book i feel
like it's important to teach
those sources that way you guys have the
opportunity as well to say oh you
learned it from mr soul then you go
research mr soul
and then you find out more you learn
where i'm learning and then you get a
deeper understanding and then we can
learn together
i think it's important so um i do feel
that it is okay to breed with my seeds i
encourage it i didn't invent them
uh the ethics would be to uh put
normally you would just put the strain
name but these are table seeds so you're
gonna have to put
um i regi just put table seeds by
iriegenetics in the description you know
what i mean
and then i always write a nice story
about my strain so it would just say i
acquired some table seeds from my buddy
irie genetics or
roster jeff at iregenetics i found a
keeper in there with these traits and
described the traits
maybe just maybe i can identify what
you've got i'm not gonna
100 percent say that i can but once it's
in flower maybe
through visual descriptions through some
aroma descriptions we can identify what
you've got i'm very familiar with my
lineup
but you can honor it by saying it is a
table seed from ross to jeff from ire
genetics i crossed it to this and this
is what i'm doing
and then the really cool thing to do
would be send me a 10 pack but you know
that's not required
i don't have space to grow it right now
but you know if you find something fire
and you breed it and you send it back to
me and then i grow that and i breed it
to something
i promise you i send seeds back to you
so that's how that that works out
i do keep my friends in mind when i'm
working with the stuff they send me
wow that was a lot of rambling so where
do we go from here um
what's the right thing to do with naming
anything that comes out of this bro name
it whatever you want you've got my
blessing my honor
name it something that is cool to you
don't uh if you want to honor my line
and my work you can put something in
there that would sort of
give a hint of where it came from you
could give pay homage to it through the
name i sort of try to do that with some
stuff
also blueberry butcher is
jack the ripper it's got jack the ripper
in there that's why the word butcher
ended up in there it just sounds like
blueberry killing you
jack the ripper and it's got blueberry
cookies on one side uh blueberry butcher
so i honored the jack the ripper in
there um
arise got called a rise because
it has got daybreaker as the male and
daybreaker comes from gage green
genetics and they name
a lot of their stuff one word like
uplifting positive words and i just kept
with the theme i didn't steal a word
they were using arise was actually
submitted by a social media fan they
said arise would be a cool strain name
and i was like i'm going to use it
so we used a rise it pays tribute to the
original breeder that bred one of the
strains
it honors that it continues that
tradition but it's also my own
thing so that's where the name arise
came from i don't know if you ever knew
that
um yeah so honor me maybe by putting
something with my or just name it
something whatever you want
uh if you're into transformers name it
after a [ __ ] transformer if you're
into electronic stuff name it after some
electronic [ __ ]
uh your grow can advocate do name it
something
after your cannabis activism or
something i don't know man have fun with
the name creation you get to name it
whatever
you want that is part of the beauty of
naming strains
i really like to have fun with my naming
schemes sometimes i drive myself crazy
because i've got the perfect name for a
strain but i still insist that it isn't
perfect
it doesn't sound like you're trying to
make seeds for a market so the name
won't be
as critical sometimes i feel like a name
the name of a strain can dictate the
success or
failure of that strain it can be fire
and if it's got a bad name it just won't
sell for some reason
sometimes things on the market don't
have the they're not the best product
but they've got a good name and they
just sell because of the name so
i always struggle with the perfect name
i like to crowdsource names a little bit
see what people think i try to come up
with my own stuff but they let the crowd
kind of weigh in a little bit because
they're the ones buying it
but come up with a name that means
something to you
something that you smile or you grin or
you giggle or you feel some sort of
pride every time you say that name
and then if you're not gonna put it out
to market it doesn't have to be
something catchy that's gonna
catch the market you can name it
whatever you want it's just yours
so name the strain whatever feels good
to you whatever is fun to you
uh maybe if you got a family or
something or somebody helping you grow
it maybe they've got a name suggestion
maybe you guys can
compile your names combine your names
together come up with something cool
it's like making up a band name
uh this is always fun for me i love this
kind of stuff so i think i covered the
basics of
your question you do have the uh the
blessing to breed with my stuff
um just put that it's an irie genetics
table seed in there or an irie genetics
however you want to label it
technically if you're not going to sell
it or do anything with it you don't have
to really
worry about that honestly but it's just
a irie genetics table seed crossed to
whatever you choose to cross it with
name it whatever you want have fun if
you want some strained name ideas let me
know what you're working with also let's
try to identify this plant
i don't know how to send pictures on
cannabi or on patreon yet
it doesn't let me attach pictures but
send them to me through my email
grow from your heart at hotmail.com uh
maybe as it's early in flower later in
flower i may be able to help you
identify
exactly what you're growing maybe uh i
can hear some
descriptions of the aromas we'll see
what you're working with we'll be able
to tell by how long it takes to flower
the leaf shape the colors
some aromas we may be able to at least
narrow down
some options of what you may have in
your garden grow can advocate
i rambled for a long time about that i
really hope i answered your question bro
breed with my stuff
everybody out there have fun breeding
uh even if you've got a seed company
breed with some of my stuff don't uh
don't just straight take a male and
start a seed company
take a male take a female breed
something select a male from that use
your own male that's been worked
then make a seed company out of that
would be cool but you've got my
blessings
um i'm not worried about it i'm honored
that you choose to work with my stuff
there's some good breeding stock in
there
so don't be shy all right i feel like i
do have more messages how long have we
been going we do have time for another
one this may be a long episode which is
cool i owe you guys a long one this time
where are we this one comes from our
friend they want their name said their
name is not listed so we're gonna skip
that and keep them anonymous big shout
out to my friend you'll know who you are
it says hey jeff i love this show i
asked a question during the premiere
and you asked me to email it to you i do
remember this i was watching the
premiere on youtube the show does
premiere on
on youtube at 12 o'clock mountain time
it's midnight
uh mountain time it is going from
wednesday to thursday so it's
um it's technically 11 59
wednesday into 12 thursday at midnight
uh mountain time is when these shows
come out i do the premiere on youtube
i do wednesday and monday so it'll be
wednesday and monday sorry it's sunday
into monday and wednesday into thursday
is when the premieres come out at
midnight
i hang out quite often in the premiere
in the chat with my friends and i watch
the chat
and i talk with the guys and gals that
are there and we [ __ ] a little bit
during that chat our friend did ask us
this question
there was no way for me to remember it
or capture it there in the chat so i
said please email it
this is what we got it says could you do
a segment
or an episode on um and i have to be
careful with the words i use because i
mentioned this before we did have
a friend whose channel got flagged
because they used an inappropriate word
which is really funny because they're
using it appropriately but
algorithms will get you in trouble um
can we talk about intersex plants and
finding nanners on plants those aren't
the words on the paper here but i'm
trying to be careful
uh do you know how long until nanners
develop pollen or can you explain if
there's a difference on when nanners
show up
during week three or when they show up
on week five etc
do you keep them or do you chop based on
these circumstances so this is a very
good question
uh when you're working with some of the
new common varietals out there
it is not uncommon to discover intersex
plants that is a plant that
appears to be female and then at some
point in that plant's life it throws out
male
flowers when that plant throws out male
flowers you've got a decision to make
and that's what this question is all
about
how do we handle these plants that
suddenly tell us that they are
intersex plants we thought we had female
plants a lot of og cush and chem stuff
will have
a tendency to throw some nanners on you
because that comes from
somewhere down the line in the chems and
the og cushes
there is an intersex gene that trait is
in there somewhere
um we've done a lot of breeding with
them to try to wash that out and remove
it but it is always going to be present
it's going to pop up sometimes it can
happen from a lot of different things
um temperature swings early latent veg
early in flower
temperature swings temperature stress
too high or too low of one way
or the other can definitely uh what's
word influence
uh intersex traits in our plants uh
stress of any sort early in flower or
laden flower
can trigger intersex traits in our
plants
over feeding uh certain things can cause
intersex traits to appear within our
plants uh
light problems light leaks like
interruptions can cause
intersex traits within our plants now
let me interrupt myself i keep saying
can cause intersex traits within our
plants these traits
are already in the plant people say this
plant turned intersex on me and i always
say no it was always intersex
you just gave it the opportunity to show
you um
that plant was always an [ __ ] you
just gave it the option
to show you it was an [ __ ] it was
always an [ __ ] it always had that
intersex straight you just never gave it
the environment to express that
phenotypical expression
just like purple is a trait just like
trichomes
are a trait just like aroma is a trait
uh
just like the buzz is a trait of a plant
so is intersex that is a trait that is
carried within that plant
if you breed to that plant it will move
that trait along the breeding the
chances of getting it depend on
just the genetic mapping does this male
wash that out with this female or does
this female carry that trait how do we
breed it out
how do you miss it i wouldn't even mess
with it honestly as a breeder
with so many options and opportunities
for plants i don't mess with anything
that gives me
too much or much intersex trait i don't
mess with that
a lot of people have chosen to do that
so
um the trait is already there what is
happening is we are triggering that
trait to express itself in certain
environments
so sometimes the plants will show you
they have intersex traits early they'll
go right into flower and then you'll see
female parts and then you'll see male
parts like 15 days in that is an early
expressing intersex plant i would remove
that there's no need to keep that that
is an
early intersex that is going to be a
struggle for nine weeks
that is going to be a problem the entire
grow and the prob the main problem is
that male part and the female part are
timed up perfectly to where if pollen
does come out the females are timed
perfectly
to receive the pollen and there's no way
to keep that plant from pollinating
itself and the plants around it
so that early intersex sign i would not
even [ __ ] with that that one goes
bye-bye quite quickly
uh no no need for a struggle set
yourself up for success get that
problematic plant the [ __ ] out of there
replace it with something good or use
that space for one of the plants that's
in there just grow a little bit longer
let's talk about a week three intersex
plant now that's about that's about
where we are that's about day 15
uh day 17 day 20 you'll start seeing
those early intersex
plants right as things go into flower
get rid of that there's no reason to
keep that if you've got replacement
plants better seeds
other opportunities get rid of that
intersex plant don't breed with it don't
grow it don't waste your time
there's no need to have that in the
garden with all the options for good
seeds good plants
why why [ __ ] with it like that's like
going on a first date
and finding out that you're totally not
compatible and still trying to stick it
out for nine [ __ ] weeks let's not do
that to ourselves
call that [ __ ] intersex plant move
forward let's move later
let's talk about like week five or week
six
if i'm seeing intersex pop up around
week five or week six
i've got a decision to make is this
plant hot fire
is this something i've grown before is
this my first run with it
if it's my first run and i'm seeing
intersex at week five or six
this plant better have other traits that
make it highly desirable
is it throwing one or two nanners i may
keep her around
if she throws four or five five or six
i'm getting freaked out i'm getting
stressed out
i have to keep an eye on those nanners
and see
uh if they develop into if they start
making what looks like could open into a
sack i have to watch how big it's
getting
do i pluck them out do i cut those nugs
off the plant do i cut the plant down
entirely
that depends on other traits of the
plant how's the shape of the plant how's
the structure what's the leaf size
what's the aroma
what does it look like overall other
than those couple of nanners in the
plant
if there are enough there five six seven
i'm gonna get worried it's gonna bother
me i won't be able to sleep at night
every time i close my eyes i'm gonna go
my crop's getting seeded by an intersex
plant that i'm too stubborn to remove
then i'm gonna have to wake up and
[ __ ] get rid of it if it's got like
nine [ __ ] nanners on it
if it's got two or three we may keep an
eye on it and see what it does
we're gonna watch those nanners they may
be sterile
they may never do anything they may be
filled with pollen
it's my job to keep an eye on it and see
what they do and make a decision
if they're gonna fill with pollen and
cause me a problem i'm gonna get rid of
them
if those are sterile nanners let it grow
let it grow let it grow there's no
reason to cut down
sterile manners they're not gonna do
anything they're ugly
there is a slight herm trait within that
plant maybe not breed with it
keep an eye on it uh see if certain
things are triggering those nanners but
if they just pop up
regularly i've worked with a couple of
plants that like at week eight it'll
just pop a couple of nanners
so let's move right into that ah later
later in flower popping nanners
week eight week nine i'm not concerned
really
because my plants are nine weeks into
flower eight weeks into flower
the pistols on the plants the parts that
would receive the pollen are withered
and dry and dusty they're not gonna get
any pollen at this point they will not
pollinate my plants
all right so if we're getting manners
around week eight or week nine i don't
worry too much
because those plants are too far into
their life cycle to become pollinated
the thing i am concerned with is if i'm
running a perpetual grow which i often
do
which would mean that i've got plants
coming in as plants are going out
so i may have some plants right at peak
pollination time
while these plants at week eight or week
nine possibly are producing manners
which may contain
pollen now we got a couple things to
think about
do we pick out those nanners do we chop
off the buds with the nanners it's
usually the top so do you want to do
that
are those nanners going to produce
pollen or are they sterile
most of the time in my experience a
plant that expresses an
intersex trait around week 8 or week 9
generally produces sterile flowers they
do not have any pollen in them they do
not create
any pollination they don't cause any
problems
that is most of my experience i have
seen the opposite
but probably ninety percent of the time
those late
flower intersex male flowers are not
threatening to my crop
those are uh let's talk about a previous
episode those are
the plant trying to find a way to
survive
sometimes those plants may pollinate but
most of the time those nanos that pop up
late
do not contain any pollen so they
usually do not stress me
again if there are one or two two or
three once we get up to like five or
seven again i start going what is with
that plan
and it's already done we're at week
eight or week nine i'll let it finish up
i may grow it one more time and maybe
not push it so hard at the end or maybe
push it harder at the end
usually i push the plants pretty [ __ ]
hard that is probably what caused it
to show me intersex traits so during the
next grow i would simply reduce my feed
be a little bit more careful with my
light cycle pay a little bit more
attention
and see if i can make that plant not
show me intersex
traits on the second run if it does it
again i've got a decision to make am i
going to get rid of it is it worth
keeping it
so that is a late flowering plant it's
doing that
in late flower because it wants to
survive it's doing what we were calling
the jurassic park effect in a previous
episode
these plants have the will to survive
life does find
a way so that is why they're showing you
intersex in week 9 or week 10 some later
flowering plants will do it if you've
got a 10 or 11 12 week flowering plant
it may do it in the last two weeks
right before harvest time naturally in
the environment
that plant would have been destroyed by
something a goat would have eaten it
something the wind would have taken it
down nature would have knocked it over
the wind the weather the rain
something would have knocked it down it
never would have gotten that far in
nature and if it did it would have said
i don't know what to do why didn't i get
pollinated yet because like i've spoken
about before
these plants main goal is to reproduce
they want to survive
so there can be more plants for next
year and if we don't give them the
opportunity
to mate they'll find a way in that plant
just goes hey you didn't pollinate me
i've been putting all of my energy into
making babies you never gave me that
opportunity i'm gonna figure it out
and there's something in these plants
that says i can make my own male parts
and just start spitting out flowers
we have selected hopefully through
breeding through selective breeding
through several generations hopefully
we've removed most of those intersex
traits but it is still there it's still
an opportunity it's going to pop
up it's not removed from the cannabis
gene pool by any means
it's all about selection so i went on a
really good ramble there but
uh early uh showing intersex plants they
go
mid flower like week five or week six
you've got some things to think about
late flowering plants that show intersex
traits if they're fire
keep them around let them have a couple
of nanners at the end you probably won't
cause any problems
and if they do pollinate uh use those
seeds grow them yourself you've got some
really cool bag seeds don't share them
with your friends don't make any money
off of them but grow them because you
may have some really cool [ __ ]
if that plant was cool enough to keep
around until week nine or week ten even
though it made some intersex flowers
it's probably good
smoke maybe whatever you accidentally
bred that to
is going to be better or equally good
smoke with different traits either way
it's a fun project you've got some free
bag seeds to work with if you're a new
grower you're new at germinating seeds
there's some seeds you could try to
germinate they were free
practice seeds are never a bad thing so
let me make sure i answered
uh the majority of your question here
because i do feel like i got rambly
uh do an episode or segment on nanners
um
i like to use the word intersex we're
going to avoid the h word
i definitely don't like the shortened
version of the h word
um that just sounds childish to me when
you say it
uh h and then e at the end of it h e it
just sounds like a
third grade word uh just say just herman
or something like that if you're going
to
do it say short for herman don't say
harmony
we're just going to end up with a
youtube [ __ ] strike here intersex is
the word we want to use guys
intersex is the appropriate word for
what we're talking about
um do a show on intersex yes week three
cut it week five or six you got
decisions to make
late flowering uh late showing intersex
they're probably sterile probably not
too big of a deal unless maybe you've
got a perpetual
and maybe that's not a sterile ah male
flower popping up
most of the time intersex is from uh it
is in there it's not something that you
did it is
in there and then it just expressed
itself it's just a trait that was always
in the plant waiting to show you had to
trigger it give it the right environment
and a lot of that is just from breeding
selection we have to choose better
plants
uh stress test the plants before you
breed with them test the progeny before
you sell them
that is my short ramble on intersex
plants you guys um
i think i covered a lot of ground in
this episode i want to thank everybody
again for listening to episode 660 of
the grow from your heart podcast
when i say the numbers at the start of
the show it puts a big smile on my face
and it blows my mind
every time 660 episodes and many of you
have been along for the entire journey
a lot of you jumped on right when we
came into youtube some people are just
jumping in
each and every one of you truly thank
you big salute i appreciate you
please hang out i only in only plan and
intend
i was on a roll there for a minute it's
just gonna get better that's what i'm
trying to say you guys stick around
thank you i owe it to you to make the
show better i've got the other camera
i'm learning [ __ ] more tricks with
the editing trying to make it a great
show for you trying to keep the quality
content going
that's enough of that stuff all right i
think that's all we've got for this
episode i covered a couple of good
topics covered a lot of ground here
if you've got any questions corrections
comments or concerns you know i would
love to hear from you
the email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com don't be shy
uh send me your questions corrections
comments
concerns constructive criticism words of
wisdom i am ready
don't be shy also make sure to check out
the website at iregenetics.com
uh and of course join us on discord i do
look forward to seeing you on discord
if you're watching on youtube please now
is the time to click
like and subscribe to the channel all
right that is all i've got for this
episode you know i'll be back in a
couple of days with fresh new content
i want to give a giant shout out to my
friend brian c and until next time take
a fat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]