[Music]
yeah welcome back podcast world i'm your
host my friends call me rasta jeff and
this is episode 662
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to talk a little
bit about that dog butt again
before we get to that part of the show
let's do a few shout outs to a few of
the kind
folks who support the show on patreon
let's start off with the big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to my friend
alabama man i want to sit a big thank
you shout out to mr mean
green let's send a special thank you
shout out to stone trout bomb
i want to send a big thank you shout out
to chief chiefly420
let's send a thank you shout out to
scooters3g and caribou heart tv
let's send a big thank you shout out to
a longtime supporter glenn geroni
brian p and froggle rock
i want to send a big fist bump to a
great photographer and a good tester all
mixed up
let's send a big thank you shout out to
another great tester mobius grows
i want to send a thank you shout out to
roll this nug and then let's wrap it all
up with the big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out
to my friend elder's garden big thanks
and big shout out to everybody
who continues to support the show on
patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
all of the information you need is right
there on the screen and of course there
is a link
in the show notes and in the video
description to make it nice
and easy for all of my friends by the
time this episode comes out
we will have reached 1 000 members on
the discord channel
thank you to everybody who supports the
discord channel i do appreciate it
1 000 members that means a lot to me
i'll be there more often
i'll be hanging out i'll be giving away
some prizes showing some love
saying thanks join me on discord all
right i do have a lot of great stuff to
talk about
i'm coming to you on a rainy cold
colorado evening i'm a little bit
excited to be cold i had to turn off the
air conditioner
uh my arms are a little cold it's kind
of poking a hole in my shirt over here
and i am so excited to be cold it has
been a long
hot summer i am really excited for the
cold however
it is now what i call powdery mildew
season we have gone from super hot to
super cold
uh sometimes it is uh 60 something at
night and 90 something during the day
we're having some jumps uh we're heading
into the fall time of year here almost a
couple of weird uh temperature swings in
colorado
we will get some rain we'll get some
hail storms we'll have some 90 degree
days
that is the perfect environment for
powdery mildew
do you have a strategy do you have a
plan have you thought about what you're
going to do
when you see the powdery mildew are you
looking for it are you scouting for
powdery mildew i'm mainly talking about
outdoors but this will apply indoors as
well
are you looking for powdery mildew
outdoors do you know how to identify it
do all of the people working in your
grow know how to identify powdery mildew
do you know what to do if it is spotted
in your grow
because outdoors it is now powdery
mildew season
in the grow houses have a strategy in
place be ready
i know what products you are willing to
use know what willing products it is too
late to use know what products you can
use together
get a strategy in place now is le time
all right i did say i was going to talk
about that dog butt again
talking about the dog bud the chem dog
and chem dog
and the sauer diesel resulted in several
emails i'm sure they will keep going
they'll keep coming as more people
listen to the episode
but i do have a great one here in front
of me i want to talk about
this one came from patreon patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart
it says hey ross to jeff thank you for
replying and then it says i guess it's
hard to put this into words but i will
try you do a wonderful job my friend
i've read this message it says
i guess the background is that i learned
to self-medicate in the early 90s
welcome to the crew bro
uh growing up i was a smart kid it was
called lazy by teachers
and family for years because i wasn't
trying or applying myself bro me too i
was just bored with the freaking
curriculum
teach me some [ __ ] i care about and i am
passionate keep teaching me about the
same [ __ ] over and over again in school
and i already learned it i don't care i
get obnoxious i know what you mean
it says as a young adult experimenting i
found that i could focus and be
successful with the help of cannabis
rastafari i know exactly what you mean
brother sometimes i wake up
my thoughts are going seven different
directions i don't know what needs to
get done today
i don't know what i want to eat for
breakfast i don't know what shoes i'm
going to wear today i take a couple of
dabs and everything just goes
you want to have this for breakfast
you're going to wear these shoes and
then at nine o'clock you have to go to
this place and it all just falls right
into place just
smoke a little bit and the the pieces of
the puzzle kind of come back together so
i know what you mean my friend
um now i am the head of i don't know if
i should read this part we're going to
leave some of this out because it may
reveal too much of who you are and if
anybody from work reads this
anyway our friend is the head of a
global company we're going to leave out
some details there
so they are very successful they're a
cannabis consumer they've been smoking
since the 90s they're probably
close to my age and they are successful
so this
uh states first of all that people can
smoke cannabis and they can
self-medicate with it
and they can become very very successful
people and we shouldn't judge anybody
for the way they choose to medicate
themselves
i am rambling it says now um
chem dog was not only the guy to find
the seeds at that time
okay kemdog was not the only guy to find
seeds at that time with the grateful
dead and fish tours so it sounds like my
friend here
may have stumbled across some of those
chem dog seeds or those dog bud seeds
we found plenty and many northern
vermont and northern new york people
grew it too
yeah it's not unlikely if somebody found
if one person found 13 seeds in an ounce
um the weed was going around grateful
dead shows and fish shows there was more
of that herb going around
not just that one ounce had seeds in it
which is funny because the guys that
were selling it were hoping to find
seeds and they never
did to the best of my knowledge but it
sounds like they were in a couple of
eighths some of the custies got some of
those seeds
so people in vermont and new york were
growing it too
big up to the new york and vermont fish
family i cannot wait to boogie down
in a couple of weeks if all things go
well uh now that i try different chem
dogs or chem 91 crosses i realize
how much a grower's style personality
and talent play a part yes that's
absolutely accurate
i always say that if i give 10 people a
clone of the same exact plant we're
going to get 10
different finished products they're
going to grow it differently their room
is differently the environment is
different
their nutrients are different ah they're
pruning their technique will be a little
bit different
then of course the dry and cure process
is going to be drastically different so
we're going to get
some similar familiar aromas flavors the
buzz will be similar but there will be
subtle differences amongst
every grow maybe some of the buds will
be more dense maybe some of the buds
will be fluffier
ah maybe some if the aromas lean certain
ways like with the chem 91 we get some
sweetness and some
foot and then some just weird funk maybe
some guys are going to bring out more
foot some guys are going to bring out
more funks some guys are going to bring
out the sweetness
that has a lot to do with the nutrients
the environment and then of course the
drying and curing process are going to
play
a huge role in the finished product so
it's a lot like a song
if uh if you get 10 bands that are all
professional bands and they play
the same song it's gonna sound a little
bit different they'll play the same
notes
but it's gonna have a little bit
different flavor to it i'm trying to
think of two bands we could compare that
are going to be anywhere near fair that
people may
i'm all right let's just say if we took
metallica
and then we took a reggae band and we
did the wait you know take a load off
annie
right you're going to hear take a load
off and it's going to be screaming with
metallica he's going to do
yeah and then in the reggae it's going
to be boom
take a load it's going to be real slow
it's the same song it's going to be the
same song played correctly
but done with different flavors and
different styles because it is very
artist
dependent i hope you followed along with
that we just compared
metallica and reggae to cannabis growing
on this podcast you never know what
we're going to do next
um so yes it does play a big part then
it goes on there is more
to this wonderful message it says since
what i'm looking for is not realistic i
was hoping you would have a strain in
your repertoire that might be inspired
by the mid
90s fish scene but with a rasta
jeff twist um
man you could probably find some of that
if you are from the vermont new york
area
somebody's probably got some of those
dog bud seeds that you were looking for
but you're looking for something
from the rasta jeff repertoire the irie
genetics catalog
that is chem 91 with a rosted jeff twist
you are in luck
my friend i have a couple of things i
would recommend for you the first one
i'm going to suggest will be the morning
do
morning dew is a cross of the grateful
dog to my arise
there's going to be a lot of chem in
there the grateful dog
is kim d2 or it's chem 91 i apologize
chem 91
to sfvog it is a deadhead
og uh kind of a feminized back crossed
inbreeding project i wasn't sure
what i was doing at the time when i made
that i didn't know i was doing something
strange
but i did get some grateful dead some
deadhead og seeds which is chem 91
and sf the san fernando valley og kush
f4
they were crossed to make the deadhead
og i did some feminizing and reversing
of that i crossed
uh phenotype the same phenotype i selfed
it then i took the
seed that came out of that and
pollinated that with the original
mom that i used so i kind of did some
inbreeding i pollinated one of the
offspring with the original mom to make
a super femme plant
um that is the grateful dog that has
been crossed
to the uh the arise which has
the chem d and the grandparents you're
going to see the chem d pop up a little
bit
you're going to see the chem 91 that
morning dew is very it's got the
that sour sweetness that chem 91 had i
know that
if you smoked it there's a sour
sweetness it's not the dominant flavor
but that's what
kind of gives it a little bit of a funk
to it that sour sweetness but it's also
got the fuel
and the cushy aromas that you expect
from a good chem
so i think the morning dew is probably
the closest you're gonna get
for a chem 91 with my sort of a twist on
it the next thing that i think you would
really enjoy
is a new cross that does not have a name
um it is in the works it will need a
great name
i'm not even sure that i want to reveal
the cross yet do we do it here on the
show
yeah we do it why not i am in the works
of crossing the p91
to the arise that will have some amazing
uh gassy funky smells it will smell a
lot like that old school stuff and it
should have a lot of that good buzz to
it
i haven't done it yet it's in the
process they're in the room together
it's almost time for the magic to happen
but the p91 to arise will be
something that will make you very happy
all right i think i answered that
question it was good uh
connecting with somebody who was very
has a very similar story to myself
uh very passionately curious i love
learning
i just wasn't interested in school
because they taught me all that i feel
like
everything i learned in school i learned
probably in like third or fourth grade
and then fifth and sixth grade was just
a repeat of that [ __ ] and then ninth and
tenth grades were repeats of all this
[ __ ] all over again and they just
repeated it and i didn't write what they
just kept teaching
the same dumb [ __ ] they didn't go much
further i felt like i learned much more
in life
uh and became successful as a cannabis
consumer after school yeah so
uh we have a lot in common we both love
that fish tour grateful dead stuff and
the chem
i hope answered your question bro and i
do hope to see you uh at a fish show or
a
uh wherever we end up a dead and company
show maybe a dark star orchestra show
let's hang out bro smoke some some good
dog weeds some morning dew or something
all right i am awful rambly i got good
and stoned at the start of this episode
i have no idea how long i've been
recording by the way so this will be
long and fun
i do have another episode here in front
of me another one that does reference
the chem dog and it says
rasta jeff i love it when they start
like that i was just listening to your
podcast
and you referenced the kim dog and the
13 beans yes i'm getting a lot of
responses because of that episode and i
love it
says man talk about some lineage that
shaped the east coast
cannabis scene yeah some of my favorite
strains come
from the chem 91 some of my favorite
stuff has chem 91 in it some of my
favorite
crosses that i've made have chem and
other chem
lines in there so yeah it really shaped
the east coast and i think it shaped all
of the cannabis scene to tell you the
truth bro not just on the east but yeah
it started there and
trickled out this way it says anyway i
went camping this year
i'm not sure if i should say exactly
yeah i went camping this year in bethel
for a spartan race and took a trip over
to the woodstock museum i got lucky
chatting with an old head who offered me
a quarter of his slightly stupid or
slightly seated
but stupid stony cookies and kim so this
herb was slightly seeded
and stupid stony cookies and kim so you
got some girl scout cookies
and then you got some chem in there it
could be kmd it could be chem dog it
could be a lot of things but cookies and
cam
um that's also known as the gmo
uh gmo is also known as chem cookies or
garlic cookies so you could have
something like that in there
that's a great cross but uh he says
maybe it was just the scenery and the
atmosphere or whatever but i'm telling
you it was some of the best herb
herb i have ever touched in my life
um it was the atmosphere the environment
the surprise of finding
some new head at a really cool place
smoking you out
um and also it was like a change if you
i feel like if i smoke the same herb all
the time herb that i grew
uh herb from the same grovers around
here if i smoke the same concentrates
all the time the same jar
i feel like the buzz gets boring i don't
get as
buzzed medicated i don't feel the effect
as much if i smoke uh
one gram of the same concentrate all day
by the end of the day i gotta switch
jars and smoke something different and
then i'll get a better buzz so part of
it was you switching up
uh your intake your medicine you ate at
a different restaurant so it just tasted
better
uh it's gonna be like that all the time
but i think that contributed it
contributed
contributed did to it that's what i
meant to say i promise you
uh that really contributed to the the
experiences where you were
the new uh person but then of course
that new product was totally different
your body was like well these are
different terps and different
cannabinoids that i'm not familiar with
and different ratios this is kind of
nice
and you were just out there loving life
feeling irie so it was a definitely a
good different buzz
now let's get to the fun part i found
eight seeds one of which
doesn't look viable but i kept it just
in case i got them stashed away for safe
keeping but man
i can't wait for the day i get that itch
to pop these seeds
so if you found eight of them and one
looks unviable you've got
seven seeds and i think they say seven
is a lucky number
so you've got seven lucky seeds from
your friend
uh from the woodstock museum i cannot
believe
those seeds are not already germinated
if i had gotten those seeds from that
head in that situation i would
be they would be in dirt you'd already
be getting tests of what they grew like
from me
that's just how that would go um what a
great story
and i'm glad that the chem dog reference
and the kim dog story brought
that up and then i'm glad that that just
happened that uh some old head at the
woodstock museum of all places
had some slightly seeded but uh what did
the what's the word here stupid stoney
cookies and chem whatever you paid for
that bag of weed
unless what'd you get you got a quarter
uh you got eight seeds in there if you
paid around like 70 80 bucks
you definitely got a [ __ ] good deal
if you paid 50 bucks you got a magical
deal because those eight seeds in my
opinion
are worth probably 50 bucks i that that
would have been worth 50 bucks or so to
me anyway so
um yeah the weed was free the seeds are
what you definitely paid for so big come
up on that
uh this came from our friend poop grows
on patreon
um excellent name poop does grow no [ __ ]
but
uh bro grow those beans and send me
pictures of them
or or even better send me some beans bro
no but grow them you grow them yourself
i'm excited to see what you've got
you've got some chem and cookies uh
who knows what pollinated that that
could be an s1 that could be
that could be anything it could be
magical you may have the next chem dog
in your jar that may be the next magical
strain
we've talked about where these strains
come from and then we discovered on a
previous episode that even the sour d
allegedly
possibly was a mistake a bag seat if you
will
all right that is enough about the chem
stuff
i'm sure there are more emails in my
patreon more emails in the inbox that i
have not discovered
uh the inboxes are full the patreon is
loading up i do check the patreon first
then i head to the inboxes
uh don't be shy send me more messages
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart
the email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com
send me updates send me questions i do
love it keep the conversation going
uh there is more to this episode how
long have i been recording i really have
no clue i did not press the timer on
this device
so we're just gonna go and tell i run
out of voice i guess this one came from
our friend brian
you can call me brian and it says hey
ross to jeff first of all let me thank
you
so much for all the knowledge and
experience you
share hey thank you you are very welcome
i feel like i've been given a gift
and if i didn't share my gift i may
spontaneously combust i feel like if i
don't record a podcast if i don't play
my drums if i don't do a few key things
in life
life doesn't go the way it should so uh
thank you for noticing that i do put
some effort and share some knowledge
into here
this is what i was put here for i've got
to do this this is my duty
thank you for noticing i'm gonna go on
with the message it says
you maintain a high standard which makes
an excellent model for us to base
ourselves
off of also you hold me to a high
standard i'm not allowed to [ __ ] up take
a day off get lazy
slip up anymore because i know that the
irie army the grow from your heart team
the whole crew is out there cheering me
on looking forward to me coming out and
encouraging you educating you
uh you guys keep me on my game you keep
me sharp as well you expect a lot
from me which it makes me expect a lot
from me which makes you expect
it's just inspiring me every day so
thank you guys for the encouragement the
motivation
uh because without you guys on the other
end of this it would
i would just be a complete psychopath
i'd be a guy with too many cameras too
many toys
and this would look [ __ ] weird so
thank you for all the support
it does go on it says i think that's a
huge compliment also thank you
um it says my question is when you breed
a male and female together you get
certain results
uh yes then it says would the results be
completely different if you switched the
male
female order and bred those plants would
there be similarities also what if
we were using two females rather than a
male female
would there be different results and
then they break down some examples
i absolutely understand the question
here let's jump into answering this
all right just to make this question
nice and clear what this person is
asking
we want to do some breeding and we've
got plant a and plant b
to start the scenario plant a is the
male
and plant b is the female they want to
breed it that way
then they want to flip the male female
around to where the opposite plant is
the male and the opposite
plant is the female i honestly don't
remember how i started
but the second round is the opposite of
whatever i said the first time
will there be a difference in the
outcome in the progeny of that breeding
project
if we flip them will we see differences
if we were to hypothetically
get i'm going to say uh og kush and
golden goat if we used an og kush male
and a golden goat female and bred them
and then did an og kush female and a
golden goat male and bred them
would we see differences depending on
your phenotypical selection for your
starting plants
most likely yes you will see differences
um the male in my opinion adds a lot to
the structure the shape of the plant the
potency of the plant
the mildew resistance the pathogen
resistance those sort of things i feel
like come from the pollen donor side of
the plant
so you may see and also it depends on
how
dominant each plant is in the mix
um so
let's just say they're even let's just
say we've got even dominance on
everything we've selected that they're
going to breed evenly that's really just
not common with anything in life but
um if we breed them so you're gonna see
uh you may see more of
the dad's tallness in each side you may
get the
the height of the dad in each of them
you may get the pest resistance from the
dad in each of them so if you're
oh gee so og kush og kush likes to get a
little bit drier golden goat gets really
thirsty
whichever dad you used i think you're
going to see that trait more dominant in
that cross if you use the golden goat
dad your offspring are going to be more
thirsty if you use the og kush dad
your offspring will be less thirsty
uh either way you do that cross so if
you if you use these two same plants
just flipping the dad
i think will have an effect on the
amount of thirst
in those plants and this is hypothetical
because i know that golden goat drinks
and eats like crazy and i know that the
og kush plants
uh they don't drink very much you can
almost starve them and not give them
water for a really long time they'll do
better you can't
you're more likely to kill an og kush
plant by over watering than under
watering so that's what i'm trying to
get with there
i hope that makes sense i'm going to
give another example
another good example is if we crossed
the grateful dog
to the golden goat this has been done uh
one way it is called the golden road the
other way it is called
the heart of gold right now my brain's
playing tricks on me because i'm talking
and trying to talk about these two
strains and don't have notes on it in
front of me
but grateful dog and golden goat have
been crossed
each way to where the grateful dog has
been the pollen donor and the grateful
dog has been the pollen receiver
when the golden goat is the pollen donor
the progeny makes sweeter um
pointier buds they're sweeter in flavor
they've got more of that tropical flavor
and they're pointier that's uh they're
jagged the leaves are more serrated the
buds are
uh maybe a little bit fox taily but they
just look meaner the silhouette is just
more sharp and jagged that's why a lot
of phenotypes
i call it the mean girl phenotype of
stuff that i cross with golden goat
you can just see it in there now the
cross that the
grateful dog is the pollen donor those
come out with more of a rounded pinecone
shaped bud
they aren't as jaggedy they don't have
as many uh maybe it's almost fox tailing
maybe it's fingery
but when i use the grateful dog as the
pollen donor it's tighter
it looks more like a tight silver pine
cone it gets this silver hue to it
a silver tent maybe a velvety sort of a
texture a little bit of purple to it
so that's what happens when the grateful
dog is the pollen donor so yes you will
see differences
uh based on flipping the male and the
female you'll see differences
and it just depends on which male and
you're going to find some males that
when you breed with them they're really
dominant in the mix and you'll find some
males that just
mix really well with the female and
you'll find some that you're just making
reproductions of the females
so it's kind of about the dominance of
the male in your mix and that's really
going to have a huge effect on it but
you will see a difference in which way
you do
the cross so like i was saying with the
grateful dog to golden goat
when the golden goat is the reversal
that flavor of the golden goat comes
through a little bit better
the flowering time of the golden goat
comes through but when i use the
grateful dog as the pollen donor the
flowering time of the grateful dog
the leaf shape and size of the grateful
dog seem to dominate
that mix so yes there absolutely is a
difference it does make a huge
difference
now the last part also what if you were
using two females rather than a male
female would there be different results
that's kind of what i was going with
just now because i didn't even realize i
was talking about two feminized crosses
but yes you will see the differences
there absolutely it's going to work just
like the boy girl
maybe easier to see because you have
seen
the females in full flower as their
female butt expression so you can
identify the traits which are coming
from each side very accurately because
you know what the females look like when
you're using the boy
you just know what the female looks like
and you're guessing the other traits
came from the boy's side
not uh traits from the history on the
mom's side
so i think i answer that i think it
makes sense they wrap it up with i hope
you understand the questions i totally
understand
i hope you understood my long and rambly
answer thank you for the great question
uh that came from my friend you can call
me brian big up to my friend you call me
brian
uh thank you for the great message if
you have any more questions or a
follow-up
please do reach out you do know how to
find me alright ladies and gentlemen
boys girls pimps hoes friends foes
smokers growers clone cutters and paul
and chuckers
all of you beautiful cannabis
enthusiasts out there i want to thank
you once again for listening to another
episode of the grow from your heart
podcast if you have any questions
corrections comments or concerns
you know i would love to hear from you
the email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com don't be shy reach
out
also if you feel like the episode was
educational informative or entertaining
and you'd like to support the show all
you have to do is visit www.patreon
forward slash grow from your heart don't
be shy
also check out the website
iriegenetics.com
that is all i've got for you for this
episode i'll be back in a couple of days
with fresh new content
i want to give a big shout out to my
friend uncle gigi and until next time
take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you