[Music]
yeah welcome back podcast world i'm your
host my friends call me rasta jeff and
this is episode 665
of the grow from your heart podcast
before i get too far if you're not old
enough to watch this video or if
cultivating or consuming cannabis is
illegal in your location don't do it and
if you do it you cannot blame me if you
get caught alright in this episode we
are going to focus on flushing our
plants before i get to that part of the
show let's do a few shout outs to a few
of the kind folks who support the show
on patreon let's start off with the big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to my friend stashdrop269
let's send a big thank you shout out to
jackie daytona and shakoba i want to
send a big thank you shout out to my
buddy adhd grower let's send a big thank
you shout out to quasi and grow bandit
let's send a big thank you shout out to
kojak and dank groves let's send a big
fist bump in a thank you shout out to a
longtime supporter of my buddy mister
let's send a big thank you shout out to
g7 and then let's wrap it all up with
the big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out to my buddy magic
mike
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need is right there on the screen and
you know i did include that link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it nice and easy for all of my
friends you may have noticed that
recently my instagram account was
deactivated i did get that account back
it is back if you're not already
following me on instagram it's irie
underscore genetics on instagram don't
forget about the monday night live show
that's right on instagram every monday
approximately 7 10 p.m mountain time i
do go live on instagram i fire up the
live feed we take a couple of dabs we
listen to some music and i answer
cultivation and cannabis culture
questions live on the fly throw up your
grow questions throw up your grow ideas
i will answer your questions make some
comments and let you know what i think
so join me monday approximately 7 10 p.m
mountain time on the instagram live feed
you may not get a notification we may be
shadow banded this time on instagram so
you'll have to give me a follow then
around 7 10 p.m mountain time open up
the instagram app look up at the top
you'll see my little icon of my name
with a red circle around it
if it's got a red or a green circle
around it that means i may be live click
on that check out the live feed hang out
with us leave some comments i'll answer
your comments there in the live feed i
am going to rely less on uh instagram
and other social media platforms they
are attacking and banning cannabis
related content so i don't want to
support them if they're not going to
support us what i am going to do is
focus my energy more on the discord
server and more on the cannabis
application cannabis definitely supports
cannabis friendly content they're all
about cannabis content join me on
cannabis it's a free app you can
download for your phone uh download it
just like any other app create an
account just like all the other apps log
in post your cannabis friendly photos
your dab videos your bong rip videos
your duck face smoking videos all your
cool cannabis photography is invited and
promoted and
encouraged on the cannabis application
so join us there the other place you
will find me more frequently is on my
discord server that's right there's an
irie genetics irie army grow from your
heart podcast discord server there are a
lot of great people hanging out there
right now big shout out to all of them
they've built me a wonderful community
over there on discord i will be on the
discord more we've reached over a
thousand members i recently gave away a
few prize packages i will be giving away
more prize packages i'll be hanging out
in the live chat the video chat the
voice chat more often so join us over on
the discord channel the discord server
and big thanks to everybody who has
signed up there are over a thousand
members on discord now that is awesome
we recently added a page a discord page
for every irie genetic strain now you
can go and post pictures of strain
specific strains under those tabs if
you're curious about growing a strain or
have questions you can go there and
interact with all of the people on the
discord and see their experiences their
photos you can ask them questions
have strain specific conversations on
the discord channel we are constantly
working on on improving it big shout out
to the gang over there join us there
will be a link in the description
you may have noticed i did take a little
bit of a social media break i was a
little bit overwhelmed with a lot of
stuff there was a lot of email happening
there was a lot of social media
interaction i'm on six or seven
different apps i produce a couple of
different podcast episodes every week i
do a live show i try to hang out with
friends and family and have a real life
outside of all this irie genetic stuff
i did kind of take a little bit of a
break from social media i had to just
for uh not just for mental health
reasons but for real life reasons there
was other [ __ ] that had to be done right
now it is outdoor growth season there
may be some things happening outside
there may be some other things happening
since it's summertime
we're allowed to go outside and go to
events again i'm going to do as much of
that as i can but i am trying to get
back into the social media a little bit
more if you've been waiting for a
message reply if you've been waiting to
see me post or something it will be
happening more frequently may not be on
instagram it may not be on facebook but
you will see me more active on social
media again sometimes you got to step
back that's not even real
it's just everybody's just creating a
bubble on there that doesn't even really
exist so don't let it overwhelm you
don't let it get to you don't make it
become part of a job it is supposed to
be fun supposed to enjoy that i wasn't
enjoying it it was too much work it was
overwhelming uh when it got that
overwhelming i just gave up and signed
out when my account got deleted it was
almost relieving but i missed all my
friends in my dms so i had to go find
all my friends again glad i found you
guys all right i am chattery i am rambly
um take good care of yourself when
you're uh working with social media
don't let it get to your head that
shit's not real most of it is not even
real 90 of the time those people
wouldn't say half of what they're saying
if they were in a room with people but
we just get weird with phones and
computers in front of us all right i am
rambling let's get to another very
important topic i've got something very
important i want to address somebody
drew this for me right here there's
going to be a logo popping up they don't
know that they drew it they designed
this for me and they sent it to me and
it is beautiful i really like this logo
i've been using it in a few places and i
owe you
a prize a gift a thank you and i can't
find you most of the time i save the
artist's name in the file name when i
save the file
this file's been moved from computer to
computer from drive to drive and i
failed at saving the file name with the
person's name in it so i need your help
if you know who made this if you made
this please
send me your email address your mailing
address uh maybe your shirt size and i
am going to uh pay you back for making
this artwork right here i need to quit
doing that because every time i do it i
have to put the image back in and that's
more editing all right uh thank you for
the great artwork and you folks that did
submit art like i said i took kind of a
break i got overwhelmed i'm going back
through all the emails i'm going back
through the file folders and when i'm
using your art you will get gifts for
your submissions i'm making sure to
catch up uh get everybody caught up make
sure that you know that i do appreciate
your work uh even if i didn't use your
art if i find it in a folder i'm going
to try to send you something because you
did put work in so thank you and don't
be shy to send more music and artwork to
the show i do like it you may notice i'm
using different artwork making different
intros stuff like that let's focus on
cannabis i did say i was going to talk
about flushing our plants i had a friend
say that he thought he messed up his
crop because he did not flush between
the veg phase and the flowering phase
and i was like there's no need to flush
then and he's like oh my friends tell me
that i have to flush and i think he
means the internet
the internet says that he has to flush
between the veg phase and the flower
phase and i said if you didn't do
anything wrong brother there's no reason
to flush during that phase and then he
said that he was taught that he should
flush often to fix problems and i think
that from what i have noticed in most
cases unless you've got a major major
major problem flushing usually just
causes more problems and we're going to
talk a little bit about flushing at the
end of the growth cycle flushing
pre-harvest a little bit but let's talk
a little bit about a mid grow flush and
a flush to solve problems i don't think
it's necessary
i think if you've got a problem so what
am i talking about let me kind of recap
what i'm even talking about if you see a
problem in your plants people will say
that they've got a problem we'll say
maybe a nutrient lockout or a nutrient
burn or an under some sort of problem
that they can't completely identify a
lot of people their first move is to
flush they will get a container of water
they will put the ph at whatever ph
they're used to using and they will just
over water the plant in an attempt to
wash everything out of the root zone and
start fresh
that's a good idea but
wouldn't it be a better idea in my
opinion
instead of rinsing out that root zone so
let's think about it the plants got a
problem then you're gonna just over
water it to where now it's over watered
now you got two problems and now your
third problem that you're going to
create is that it doesn't have any
nutrients in its root zone so now it's
got problem number one that we haven't
identified and we just panic flushed
number two now it's over water problem
number three now there's no nutrients in
there now whatever it was overdone or
deficient on that's definitely [ __ ]
because we just completely rinsed out
everything there's nothing in there it's
hungry it's freaking out so people
always say it had this problem i flushed
and now they're doing this i rarely hear
people say i had this problem i flushed
and i fixed it i don't hear that i get
more calls of saying dude i flushed them
they look like [ __ ] now now what do i do
and i say just let them dry out and feed
them properly and then they'll be back
on track so i think if you're going to
do a panic flush
why not mix up a solid feed i call it
like a a triage feed or just a solid
diet or a good meal plan like if you
went to the if you went to the doctor
and you're like sick and you got some
problems first thing they're gonna do is
stick an iv in you and get you some
vitamins to get you hydrated let's do
that for the plant let's mix up a good
batch of nutrients what is your basic
feed what are you normally feeding this
plant you have nitrogen phosphorous
potassium do you have your calcium
magnesium do you have your basic
nutrients that these plants need do you
have some fulvic acid in there to help
them uptake do you have uh some carbs in
there uh do you have some microbes in
there do you have things in there to put
this plant in its top performance
whatever phase you're in if you're in
veg if you're in flower ah mix up a
really nice mix some base nutrients some
calmag
some microbes i mentioned a bunch of
things get a good solid mix in there get
the ph adjusted perfectly and then water
that to run off now what you're going to
do you're going to rinse out all the old
[ __ ] that's in there it's going to fall
right out of the bottom as the plants
get run off and you're going to put a
brand new meal in there it's like
delivering [ __ ] soup in a sandwich to
a sick friend they've been eating
[ __ ] energy bars and drinking
gatorades all day because they've just
been sick and struggling that's what
your plant's been doing it's like i'm
[ __ ] i don't know what to do and you
just gave it soup and a sandwich and a
hug and that's really probably the best
you could do for it in my opinion so i
think like a mid grow or a mid cycle
flush is probably more detrimental than
it is uh helpful to our plants in most
cases now if you do have like a major
major major lockout or something maybe
you might want to flush and then at that
point uh just do plain water or maybe do
something there are plenty of flushing
products in there those are useful the
sugars in there do help unbind the salt
is what's happening in there that may
work but
unless you've got major major issues i
don't think that flushing during the
growth cycle is a good idea a necessary
idea i think it's going to cause you
more problems you're going to over water
you're going to make the plants thirsty
and they already had one problem to
start with so you're just compounding
problems why not mix up something that
we know is good for the plants like when
people are sick you don't just give them
a bunch of water and hope that they just
pee everything out you got to give them
nutrients in a meal also like i said
bring them soup in a sandwich maybe a
multivitamin maybe a kombucha to get
some probiotics in them you got to take
care of them the plants are the same way
we got to take care of the plants so um
i keep repeating myself that mid-cycle
flush might be kind of silly most of
what i've been talking about so far
applies to a soilless mix type of a grow
maybe you're using fox farms or some
soil like that that's what this would
apply to something with bottled
nutrients that type of environment let's
talk a little bit about hydro and
flushing now i don't think it's
necessary to flush
your grow mid grow your plants mid grow
with a hydroponic system i think that is
a missed opportunity for a feed if
you've got a big problem if you see
something is completely off in any case
the first case of the first step the
first thing to do is identify the
deficiency or the over feed or the
toxicity or whatever the problem is your
first step is to identify that then like
i said before mix up that proper feed if
you know what's off correct that if you
know what you're giving too much of
don't feed it that this time if you've
given it too little of something add
some of that this time but adjust your
nutrients and then get that in the
reservoir and get it fed to the plants i
don't like to run a lot of plain water
through a hydro system and not feed the
plants the reason we're doing
hydroponics is to get as many feeds as
possible to kind of beef up those plants
and get as many nutrients into it so
we're missing an opportunity to feed
them we should just mix up the feed that
they need and get it to them every time
instead of doing just plain water so the
first step in any case to solving a
nutrient issue whether it's over or
under feed is to identify the problem
what nutrient are we missing and a lot
of times it is two nutrients working
together or against each other you'll
notice if you over feed one thing you'll
see a problem with another if you under
feed one thing you'll see a problem with
a different nutrient they work in
balance together so pay close attention
keep good notes of everything that you
fed keep good notes of your ph keep good
notes of your ec you may even want to
measure the ec and ph going in and
coming out of your plants if you've got
that ability that will help us diagnose
a problem and then adjust to make
corrections especially in a hydroponic
system it's a little bit harder in a
soilless mix because you got all that
soilless stuff in there you're going to
get a lot of ppms of different things
but we know exactly what we're putting
in in a hydroponic mix let me read my
notes and see where i am
um identify the problem mix up a good
feed um yeah why would you starve the
plants you could just water them but why
would you do that now you're gonna make
them hungry also that's like telling a
sick person like starve for a day and
then i'll try to figure out what's wrong
with you and then we'll diagnose it and
then we'll [ __ ] fix you
no no don't make them feed
mix up a solid feed with the appropriate
things uh just at the appropriate ph for
your time in the grow and what your
garden is used to make sure the ph is
right also make sure that your ph pen is
correct i saw somebody that has been
adjusting their ph with the pen that has
been miscalibrated for quite a while so
everything looked like [ __ ] we thought
the ph was correct the pen was off so it
was not everything was way off make sure
your pins are good then reset that soil
with the good feed when you just water
everything into that soil with that good
nutrient mix with the good ph balance
you just kind of reset that soil those
plants will start drinking all of that
they'll get more active and they'll
start recovering you're not going to see
the burn and stuff is not going to go
away if you've got crispy leaves and
crinkled up [ __ ] like that it's not
going to go away but the new growth
won't be as terrible and beat up but
you're not going to get rid of some of
that don't be afraid to pull off some of
those crispy bad dead funky ugly leaves
those do invite more problems
the bugs kind of see those yellow leaves
as weakness the spider mites that's why
we use the yellow sticky traps because
the bugs like spider mites and things
like that see the yellow and they say
that plant should be green but it's
yellow so that means that little
protective layer on the outside is
probably good and weak i can get in
there and start munching and get the
plant juices out of this so get those
yellow funky ugly crinkly crusty dry
leaves out of there if you've got them
try to keep all the green healthy
foliage around save that rescue that
focus on the new stuff coming
now let's talk about something
a little bit controversial that honestly
this is all bro science i do not have
any science behind this i'm going to
tell you the honest truth i am debating
and readjusting and rethinking my stance
on flushing our cannabis plants i don't
have enough real scientific data i don't
have the scientific machines to do this
all i can tell you is by uh burning it
by smoking it by consuming it by
extracting it by enjoying it or not
enjoying it that's the only testing that
i've got and that's kind of what matters
because um yeah i've never had some lab
equipment tell me that my weed was good
or bad so um
let's talk about flushing flushing and
this is the end of harvest or the end of
the cycle pre-harvest flushing we've
been feeding our plants for nine weeks
we're gonna cut down i used to preach
the flush for 10 to 14 days is that
necessary i don't know there's a lot of
debate in that my question is what do we
think we're flushing out like there's a
plant and there are buds and nutrients
have been put into that plant and
they've been photosynthesized or
metabolized and turned into plant they
are fibers and terpenes and there's a
bunch of different components to that
plant now there plant waxes and esters
and uh all the different components of a
plant they became a plant there's not
like
little
nutrients and they are but they're the
building blocks of the plant what are we
gonna flush out i don't know like
when you pee do you like do you think
you pee so
i i don't know what we're gonna flush
out i really don't know because i pee
out waste but the building blocks of the
food that i ate still created me i like
my waste comes out but the the things
that i ate and consumed that created me
are still here you're not gonna flush a
lot of that out so if you were to
consume me
you would only you would the
the waste is all that's coming out of me
so i think even when we flush i i see
that's and i don't have enough science
behind it that's my thought process on
it uh i'm open to feedback i would love
to hear your uh opinions your bro
science i'd love to read your paperwork
on it again i have grown for a lot of
time in a lot of environments with a lot
of different mediums sometimes i've had
the opportunity to flush for two weeks
sometimes we've had emergencies where
plants didn't get to get flushed as much
sometimes i notice a difference
sometimes i don't sometimes i also
notice that the dry and cure really had
a lot to do with it so i am not sure um
is that white ash really telling me that
it was flushed properly is the flush the
right thing i do notice that if we over
feed the stuff doesn't burn right
sometimes if you over feed certain
things it doesn't burn right but is
flushing real i really don't know i'm
still adjusting my approach to that
whole thought process but i want to know
what are we flushing out like what do we
actually think is coming out of the
plant
i don't know ladies and gentlemen boys
girls pimps hoes friends foes smokers
growers clone cutters paul and chuckers
all of you beautiful cannabis
enthusiasts out there i think that is
all i've got for you for this episode
this may be a quick show i'm not sure
how long we've been going either way it
is quality over quantity right i could
ramble on and make this show longer but
we got a quick talk about flushing we
got to talk about uh the discord and
stuff at the top of the show i want to
thank you again for listening to another
great episode of the girl from your
heart podcast i did have fun recording
this one i do enjoy doing this show i'm
in my own little bubble here i got my
headphones on can't hear the doorbell
can't hear nothing around me couldn't
hear the phone ring if it did i like it
i enjoy being in the zone here i love
knowing that i'm helping people out so
thank you for giving me the opportunity
to teach you stuff some some stuff today
i do look forward to your feedback about
flushing if you've got questions
corrections comments concerns feedback
of any sort is invited the email address
for the podcast is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com please don't be shy
let's have a conversation i'll talk more
about it on future episodes you teach me
so i can teach you i do appreciate the
uh the relationship uh make sure you
check out the uh the patreon at
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart also don't forget about the
discord channel join us on the discord
server the link is in the video
description the link is in the show
notes if the show notes are not showing
up on whatever audio service you are
listening on i do apologize for that i'm
still learning we rebuilt the website
there's some hitches and glitches i'm
figuring out uh please do be patient but
the link will be on youtube if you need
to go to the youtube channel uh the link
will be in the most recent video just
click on that it'll be the top link
i do apologize for not being able to get
it in all of the show notes everywhere
i'm still learning some tricks
also check out the website
iriegenetics.com
if you scroll halfway down on the irie
genetics website there is a news letter
spot where you can type in your email
address and you'll be signed up for a
newsletter approximately once a month i
do send out a newsletter i let you know
about sales on the website i let you
know about new merge drops new seed
drops they let you know about coupon
codes random updates will happen if you
join the irie genetics newsletter on the
ire genetics website at iregenetics.com
did i mention the patreon at patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart
alright that is all i've got for you for
this episode for some reason camera
number two turned off i'm not exactly
sure why that happened so we're gonna
get some editing done do some problem
solving then we'll be back in a couple
of days with fresh new content i want to
give a giant shout out to my buddy queen
city creations and until next time take
a fat dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you