[Music]
all right here we go welcome back
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rasta jeff and this is episode
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to answer a
couple of emails before we get to that
part of the show let's do a few shout
outs to a few of the great folks who
support the show on patreon let's start
off with the big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to my friend
girls grow too let's send a big thank
you shout out to pacific northwest dan i
want to send a big thank you shout out
to kanna organic illinois let's send a
big fist bump to my buddy blackhawks fan
i want to send a special thank you shout
out to groove 2112. i want to send a big
fist bump to my buddy thecanocrat let's
send a special thank you shout out to
learnin and burnin i want to send a big
thank you shout out to nick a and
frankie let's send a big fist bump to
brendan groves then let's wrap it all up
with the big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to my
friends alex and adam from fiscals
organics big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need is right there on the screen and of
course i do include a link in the show
notes and in the video description to
make it nice and easy for all of my
friends you know the story if you're
driving if you're trimming if you've got
the kids don't reach into your pocket
and grab your phone now that link will
be there when you're ready patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart i do
again want to invite you to join my
discord server that's right the ivory
genetics irie army grow from your heart
podcast discord server has over 1 000
members it would be great to see you
there join the party we do a lot of fun
things there are probably people hanging
out right now in the discord server
chatting talking about growing talking
about life talking about music having
random conversations if you've got grow
questions questions about just about
anything i read genetics somebody is
there to answer that question for you
even when i am not there qualified
people are there to help you out that
sounds like i got a 1-800 number or
something now that's pretty cool join
the club the irie genetics discord again
there is a link in the show notes and in
the video description hang out join the
army it is a good time i look forward to
seeing you there i do pop into the live
chat occasionally i've been trying to
hang out there more i keep saying it's
got my face on it i should be more
involved so i do go to the irie army
discord i hang out take dabs in the live
chat chat with the folks that hang out
there try to be involved uh show some
appreciation i do uh chat in the chat
rooms quite a bit i post pictures
there's a strain specific section now in
the discord if you want to know anything
about any irie genetic strain there is
probably a post about it in the discord
it's got its own strain specific section
if you want to read about a rise click
on a rise i posted a photo there a bunch
of people have posted grow reports you
can learn a lot on the discord join us
also i did post some new merchandise to
the web store everybody on the discord
and on the patreon got the first
notifications about that new merchandise
you're hearing about it here on the
podcast there are some new items in the
store make sure you check out the irie
genetics store go to
iriegenetics.com click on the store uh
that will take you right to my web store
where you will see the new merchandise
there are several new items you may
enjoy go take a look uh if you're a part
of the patreon or part of the discord
you got an early notification so maybe
sign up there and you will get early
notices when new things are released
alright that's the main chatter for the
top of the show let's move our way into
the main topics i did say i was going to
talk about some emails um i've got a
couple of great emails here in front of
me i don't have them in any particular
order i'm just gonna grab one right off
the top of the stack this one comes from
our friend adam and it goes a lot like
this it says hey ross to jeff i like it
when they start off like that says i
apologize in advance if this email gets
a bit long it's kinda long but i will
edit it uh to the best of my ability and
then we will get right to the point in
answering a good question
it says i will try to make sure to keep
it as short and to the point as possible
first off my name is adam and if this
makes it to the podcast you can use my
name what's up adam good to meet you i'm
rosta jeff thank you for the great
message it goes on it says i listen to a
lot of podcasts about growing and i am a
patron to several of them uh they we do
all appreciate that uh then it says he's
wondering why he doesn't contribute to
mine yeah bro why don't you not a big
deal i'm doing just fine keep supporting
the shows which you are supporting there
are a lot of people out there supporting
me right now i'm very grateful and
appreciative for them i know that money
is expensive so do what you can i'm
getting enough support there's probably
somewhere else uh if you're not
supporting me and you are supporting
somebody that's fine that's what i'm
trying to say somebody else needs your
support that's cool um it goes on it
says you're the only podcast that i
actually trust to teach me something
useful uh useful advice that i know if i
do what you say word for word i will be
successful so thank you for the amazing
enlightening content ah dude that's a
huge compliment i don't know if you
realize how much of a compliment that is
i
do try to keep in mind that you're going
to follow my word hopefully step by step
word for word when i give instructions i
forget how much trust you put in me how
much faith you have in me i try to keep
that in mind but i try also not to let
it affect me i just try to deliver the
show i try not to let it get too
stressful and too heavy because it's
going to freak me out and mess it all up
so i'm glad that you are
noticing the the attention to detail and
i'm glad that you feel that you can just
trust me and follow along and that
things are going to go right just by
following my guidance i appreciate that
man thank you and i'm glad that i'm
making your garden better
excuse the throat clearing i did take
some fat fat dabs a moment ago this will
go away
all right got to keep reading it says
uh where were we it says useful advice
then it says uh that being said i have a
different breeding question for you
we've been talking a lot about breeding
on the podcast lately i've really been
enjoying these breeding questions so
this one is a fun question for me it
goes on it says i've learned enough from
you to do my own breeding i've been
making my own seeds for years uh
i do appreciate that you feel like
you've learned enough from me about
breeding i hope you're reading some
other books read some mel frank some
greg green there are lots of other
breeding books a lot of other breeding
books that i would recommend you read
learn about mendel charts read
everything from gregor mendel learn
about alieal charts
learn all of that stuff then when it
actually comes time to breed forget you
learned all of that and do it all from
intuition but i think it's important to
learn all of that it goes on there's
more um
i have been breeding and making my own
seeds for years
i've been managed to do pheno hunting
testing and pollination which is hard
for me to actually express this question
i have okay i'm gonna do my best to
filter out your question
it says every time i've run across
i don't get a lot of seeds maybe a few
maybe 50 to 100 seeds
that's okay that's enough seeds to work
with to play with to learn a lot of
things about those plants and you just
need
possibly bigger plants and better timed
pollination which we can talk about
later if you want to it says you seem to
be a very smart businessman so i guess
my question is how would one go about
starting a seed company that is a very
deep and detailed question that i could
talk for days about so i will touch on
that and we'll try to get all of your
points here covered
one of the main questions he asks is how
do you keep genetics around i mean i
don't really care about plant counts but
i have to do phenohunts and make sure i
still have meds to get by
um yeah that's the hard part is being a
breeder making seeds and also having
enough non-seeded medicine to supply
yourself that's kind of
when i started transitioning from doing
seeds to not seeds that was something i
would struggle with
if you're not producing seeds on a
commercial level yet your small grow
space
if you make a little bit your doesn't
sound like you're getting a lot of seeds
now if we improve the size of the plants
the pollination times we can produce
many many more seeds in your grow space
whatever space you're using for your
personal production we can dedicate one
crop
per year in that space to make enough
seeds for a long time for you to work
with and play with maybe enough to send
out some testers to see if what you've
developed is
if it qualifies for the market so you
can make a lot of seeds i would i would
just dedicate one crop to seeds per year
if that's what you've got to do just go
in there and pollinate one time and then
clean it all up and then grow a bunch of
meds for the rest of the year hopefully
um then we got to teach you some tricks
to make the other crops fill in the gap
for that one crop that you took out for
that part of the year that's probably
another good thing to learn so we've
just got to pollinate one crop and then
recover for that one crop that you
didn't grow for your medicine this means
we got to increase production by
whatever that one crop is we got to
cover that by the next four or five
crops over the year
you understand what i'm saying
how do i have enough uh pollinate
pollinate plants and still have meds to
get by
it's all about finding more space you
said you don't care about plant counts
so more space more lights more plants
dude but try to keep the best you can
keep that pollen away from your
non-seeded stuff just learn how to have
veg and flower cycles off of each other
out of rhythm where you don't have plant
room a and flower while room b is in
flowers you could pollinate finish up
and then flower the other room right
away don't have them going in flower at
the same time and you won't pollinate
both rooms
i do apologize for all the throat
clearing in this episode it is quite
distracting but i'm gonna kind of a flow
so we're gonna keep going here
um one of the other questions how do you
keep genetics around i keep mother
plants just like a basic mother plant i
do have male and female plants i've got
the king solomon male plant i've got the
jack the ripper male plant that i keep
around big ups to sub cool shout out
missy buddy rest in peace big love but i
keep those plants just like a mother
plant they veg perpetually i keep them
in a large pot under
under a long light time cycle they stand
under a 19-5 cycle honestly i keep my
moms under 19-5
so they're on for 19 hours a day off for
five hours a day i keep them under uh
really powerful led lights right now
actually they're under canon leds big up
to uh black sail market check out black
sail market and i think you can use
coupon code rasta jeff might save you a
few bucks anyway i keep the mother
plants the father plants just in a
perpetual vegetative state and then when
i need them for breeding or whatever i'm
gonna do in the room i just cut a bunch
of clones and then veg those out and put
those in the room together and let them
have a party and that's how the breeding
happens
uh occasionally every
depending on the strain and the plant
and the vigor of the plant and how much
light that plant needs and how many
clones of that plant i take how
frequently sometimes i do what i call
re-momming a plant every three six nine
months like uh let's say strawberry
starburst let's talk about momming
strawberry starburst that plant grows
very fast very vigorous it's one of my
most productive plants it needs to be
remomed about every three to six months
which means the pot which is it which it
is in it becomes root bound if i put it
in a five or a seven i don't have room
for any bigger than a seven if i put it
in a five or a seven it will become root
bound in three to six months very
tightly root bound so it gets slow it
stops producing enough shoots it gets
kind of sad and shitty looking i've got
to cut a bunch of clones off of it
before it gets to that point ideally and
then uh either flower out that old one
outdoors or just toss that big one or
something and then use all those fresh
clones they will be part of them will be
a production run and then one of them
will be kept behind as the new mother
so that one gets remomed every probably
every four or five months honestly about
every four months let's talk about
remombing the mac the mac vegges quite
slowly she doesn't give me a lot of
clones uh so i veg that one in a smaller
pot and just let it veg for a really
long time i top it and then i take that
top and i make another plant out of it
and i let it grow right next to the
other one and then when i need clones i
actually cut clones off of both of those
so that i've got enough clones for my
project with the mac
because i need extra cuts because it
doesn't grow very well
but i use two plants as clone donors for
that because it doesn't give me a lot of
cuts i don't have to remom the mac every
every six months every eight months nine
months or something like that because
the roots don't go too crazy in that
plant it grows very slowly so i just
keep that one aside and let it keep
vegging all the others get up potted
that one doesn't get up potted i cut a
clone off of it grow it up cut a clone
off of that grow that one up so i've got
like three or four small mac plants that
are growing i can get clones off of all
of them when it's time to use them keep
one behind is the keeper plant i think
i've described keeping mother and father
plants properly
i think that is how i keep genetics
around
mother them father them
perpetually veg them and then when
they're getting too big cut clones off
them and start over a lot of times i try
to time it right to where i can go from
the three gallon to either the five or
the seven get clones off of it move that
into the flower room and then keep the
clones i just cut as my new mother so i
can keep it going forever so i'm vegging
using my mom plant as my new flowering
plant get a clone off of that kind of
keeps it going that way you'll learn a
rhythm of how to do that all right so
you said you don't really care about
plant count that is fun because the next
thing you said is phenohunts
if you're going to start a seed company
you're going to have to search out a lot
of things
um you've got breeding stuff right how
do you know it's any good you need to do
some feet need to do some pheno hunts
run a bunch of those seeds see what
you've got
pick one or two lines you said you've
read a few things pick one or two of
your favorites
run as many of them as you think you can
manage do them small they don't need to
be big pots put them in a one gallon pot
put them in a two gallon pot veg them
until they're just starting to show
their shape what they're going to be
shaped like then flower them out now you
know what you've got you can see if it's
crap or if it's amazing or if it's
somewhere in the middle you can see if
it's mutants if it's intersex
you know what you're working with now
now pick a bunch of those seeds out
package them up and send them out to
testers let them grow them do this do
the testers experience positive or
negative results with those seeds that's
how you're going to find out if you've
got good stuff so pheno hunting is going
to be a fun project especially when you
said you're not worried about plant
counts uh get good at identifying the
traits you're looking for get good at
identifying desirable traits what is the
product what does the market want
i don't follow trends like right now
everybody wants uh and no offense to the
market that's just not where i'm headed
people want uh cake and dessert flavored
stuff right now that seems to be the
trend i don't do that but what i do is i
watch and see like what are they after
is it but what if my stuff works they
want bud density they want flavor
what is working is it uh powdery mildew
resistant what are the things people are
after for their grow right now and then
i just make sure my stuff has those
traits and then if they like my flavors
and aromas that's what they're gonna buy
it for so i should get myself back on
track and jump back into the message
here it does say but king solomon for
example how do you keep that genetic
around for so long i think i talked a
little bit about that just keep it as a
mother plant grow it cut clones off of
it use the clones
put the big one in the room let him make
pollen then i've got clones kept behind
um it says i had a beautiful arise mail
that i just collected pollen from but
now he is gone
uh yeah you could have taken clothes
from him just like you do a female plant
and then uh you would have had him
around and then he could have done it
again and again and again
then it goes on to say i hope you can
kind of figure out what i'm asking
because i cannot figure out how to put
it into words thanks for any advice and
any response you may give and thank you
again for all the amazing content you
share with the world and of course happy
growing hey my friend adam thank you i
do have a few more notes to talk about
on this i just wanted to make sure to
cover the few questions that you did
specifically ask so
um you want to start a seed company we
talked about how to keep the plants
around how to make a few more seeds uh
you don't care about plant counts so
pheno hunting is going to be great get
testers out uh you still got to produce
your own medicine just maybe
use one room over there for meds and one
room over there for seeds and
just make sure not to get pollen over
there or time them just veg this one
flower this one at the right time you
won't pollinate both rooms i covered
that
now let's talk about some other stuff
starting a seed company
my number one question i like to ask
people when they have any idea is why
why do you want to start a seed company
and i'm not doubting you i'm not
disrespecting you i just want you to say
out loud to the world why do you want to
start a seed company there doesn't have
to be any witnesses around nobody needs
to be in the room when you say it i just
want you to hear the words come out of
your mouth and understand why you want
to start a seed company have you thought
about in depth why so a lot of times
when i say why people go
because and they gotta actually think
about it like they have to take like we
get cool ideas i want to do a lot of
things i want to go places and i want to
see people and buy things but why i
don't know do i just want to because i
saw it on the internet do i just want to
because it sounds like a fun idea or is
it something i really want to do do i
think i want to do it or do i want to do
it so why do you want to start a seed
company what's your goal what's your
purpose what's your mission what are you
going to bring to the industry the
cannabis industry the seed industry what
are you going to provide that is not
already here what are you going to do
that's not already being done what can
you offer us that's not already being
offered how are you going to stand out
what is your mission your purpose what's
your pride where's your passion why are
you doing this what's your purpose all
right so that's my main question all
right another note that i wrote down was
to not learn how to be a seed breeder
while you're starting a company learn
seed breeding learn the ins and outs of
seed breeding
learn the basics before you launch your
company if you put your brand and your
logo on some stuff and you send out some
stuff before you're ready and you
realize i don't know all the ins and
outs and i haven't thought this through
yet and you send out some problematic
seeds or your shipping isn't on time or
things go wrong and you start off wrong
you won't get far in this industry the
cannabis industry the seed breeding
industry the growers
the patients they're all on the internet
they all have a very tight-knit
community everybody knows everybody
every brand gets a very quick reputation
if you kind of suck at the beginning the
community is gonna say hey this new seed
company they failed at the very
beginning they didn't do me right they
didn't treat me right their product
wasn't good it didn't work for me you'll
never get very far after that because
word spreads like wildfire and this
industry we do take people's word for a
lot of what we're doing we use a lot of
recommendations and a lot of reviews
from the internet so that's going to
matter a lot so don't learn on your
customers get established learn what
you're doing then get a customer base
that's going to go a long way for you
because i see a lot of breeders on
social media doing it backwards they're
making seeds and trying to figure it out
and using their customers as their
tester base and as their uh their
education don't do that educate yourself
then sell seeds to your customers and
they'll be much more happy with you
you'll feel more pride and then they'll
you'll stick around and they'll come
back and buy more seeds i've got a lot
of stuff on my paper here um if you're
going to start a seed company oh
something that's going to say consumers
are very educated uh consumers are very
connected and they are not afraid to go
on the internet and either give you big
praise you can see like like you sent
here ross to jeff you did amazingly uh
there's also the opposite if you don't
do well you'll get the great thing about
the internet if you do a good job you'll
get one email if you do a bad job you'll
get about a hundred of them so if you
mess up
they're gonna they're you're gonna get
lit up really quickly and the consumers
are very very educated right now
they could listen to my show they could
listen to the dude gross show they could
listen to adam dunn they can listen to
tad hussy uh they can listen to danny
danko and mike they can listen to so
many shows out there to become very
educated consumers and then they all go
online they join my discord they join
everybody's discord every breeder out
there by now probably has a cool discord
and they all go get very very educated
they talk amongst each other we love
teaching each other we're all very
passionate so the consumers are very
educated right now and if you make some
mistakes they will see through it and
they'll call you out they'll point it
out uh they'll expose you is what the
internet likes to say now so um yeah do
what you're gonna do but do it correctly
come correct is what i think they say
now because the consumers are very
educated
if you are going to start a seed company
from somebody who
has been in it for a while who is deep
in it now this is my life dude i i
there's no way out and that's cool i am
dedicated this is what i wanted i didn't
know this is what i was starting when i
started it but this is what i want
um there's no halfway in if you're
starting a seed company if you're all in
you're all in if you're not all in you
know it and don't even start if you've
got a backup plan if you say i'm going
to start this seed company but if it
fails you're already not in it you've
got to say i'm going to start this seed
company and then i'm going to do this
with the seed company and then in five
years i'll do this then in 10 years i'll
do this then we'll expand to this if
that's your thought process you've got a
chance of winning if you've got a backup
plan already if you've got an exit
strategy you are not meant to be in the
seed game this is a huge commitment this
is a huge lifestyle this isn't just a
business this isn't just um it's not
just work this is my lifestyle i have to
wake up and take care of plants before i
go to bed i am checking on plants i
spend the first part of my day answering
emails i know people are going no he
doesn't he doesn't reply to me dude i
try i get a lot of emails there's social
media to be done there's merchandise to
be ordered there's packaging to be
ordered uh once the packaging gets here
you got to put the seeds in the
packaging you got to put the labels on
the packaging i do all of that stuff i
do get some help with some of the things
i like to do all the seed touching and
stuff myself
some of the other stuff i do let some
people help with but 99 of it is me
there's a web guy there's an accounting
team there's stuff oh then you got to go
talk to the lawyers you got to go talk
to the accountants you got to go do bank
stuff there's so much being involved so
if you want to do this
be all in it will be stressful in so
many ways but it's rewarding in so many
ways i wake up and i don't have to
answer to a boss the boss is myself and
the most i and i'm okay with that that's
what i want for my life there's nobody
bitching at me nobody telling me i'm
late nobody telling me that i suck that
i gotta work harder only me i'm the only
one that says that to me and that's okay
um
but it's it's a lifestyle it's a strain
on relationships because uh when you own
a business
it's hard to decide when to take a day
off you guys don't even want to know
what time it is right now when i'm
recording it's darkest [__] out i'm the
only one up in the neighborhood
everybody can probably hear me talking
right now but that is entrepreneur life
if you're going to start a seed company
you become an entrepreneur you're you're
breeding you're taking care of the
garden you're taking care of the seeds
then you're marketing you're getting
merchandise you're meeting with people
you're worried about security you're
worried about financial things uh then
you're marketing again then there's
social media then you got to get up and
do it all again tomorrow when do you
take a break it's going to put a strain
on relationships it's going to put a
strain on a lot of things you have to
learn a lot of balance
but if you love it like i do uh it's
very very rewarding i think that the
interactions i've built with my audience
the irie army uh the grow from your
heart crew uh that is very rewarding
that refills all of the stress that this
company gives me it's not even that
stressful it's it's just it's it could
be so much more stressful but the
the things i have to handle the army the
crew replenish me i go hang out in the
chat i hang out on monday and you guys
uh give me praise and send me digital
fist bumps that stuff really does
recharge me of course the patreon and
the seed sales they do feel good as well
but all that stuff from the crowd the
army does recharge me so there is a lot
of work to be done it's going to put a
strain on your life your relationships
don't let it affect your health
learn some balance so if you've got an
exit strategy you're not in you've got
to be all in because uh this is an
all-in thing and it's getting
very competitive every year it gets more
competitive
speaking of every year i didn't think
about uh going to events once you've
started a seed brand where are you going
to sell your seeds
it's great to sell them on the internet
that feels really nice but the key is to
go to the places and meet the people and
shake their hands that's where you build
relationships that's where you build
long lasting clientele some of my
favorite people i meet at the events
they stand in front of my booth and wait
30 minutes to get in line to see me and
shake my hand but when they get there i
take my time with them i shake their
hand i look them in the eye and i'm like
bro i saw the pictures of the last girl
you did it looked amazing uh your new
baby is beautiful like conversations
like that you know who you are bro and
ma'am uh but uh yeah i like to meet the
people shake their hands give them hugs
high-five them take pictures with them
that's a huge huge part of being a seed
breeder you got to build a booth you
have to build a team that can work the
booth with you
then while you're at the booth at the
indo expo for the weekend who's taking
care of the garden at home who's taking
care of the seeds who's taking care of
the internet the website the orders
there are a lot of things to think about
logistics to deal with when it comes to
owning a legitimate seed company but if
you build a nice team and you got some
support it is very easy um the market is
getting more competitive the market is
getting much more competitive and more
fast pace all of the websites where i
vend if they had 10
breeders when i started now they've got
30. if they had 20 when i started now
they've got a hundred these websites are
building quickly of course i'm expanding
to more vendors i've got more outlets
but every website i go to they've got
more and more breeders which is more
competition which means that you've got
to do what i said earlier how do you
stand out how do you set apart what
makes you special why do i want to buy
your seeds why would i pick your brand
over the 700 other brands that are
available on the market right now so
you're gonna have to come up somehow
you're gonna have to stand out you're
gonna have to win some awards or put out
a strain that gets noticed
if you want longitudinally do something
real don't just use some shitty sales
tactics that a lot of other brands that
came and went tried to use
all right there's more there is more no
backup plan that's what i've got written
if you got a backup plan you're not in
it to win it uh one of the things i
struggled with and i keep kind of
mentioning this
letting others help with my company is
really hard for me i do have a web guy
because i have no idea what i'm doing
when it comes to building a website i
rely on him and trust him greatly i've
got a graphic design group i've got a
few people that do graphic designs for
me they've learned my style i got one
guy i can say hey bro uh i want to make
a sticker for a strain called blue
raspberry truffle and he goes say no
more fam and 30 minutes later i get a
design for blue raspberry truffle and
it's what i was thinking i didn't have
to send him my image or my idea he goes
i already know what you're going to do
bro here you go and he just sends it
it's perfect so
shout out to kevin you know who you are
bro
he hooks me up with great art i do stuff
like that i let people help me out with
stuff like that but letting people uh
design some of the merch and do some of
that kind of stuff it took me a minute
to let go of some of that control i
still don't let anybody package seeds
every seed is packaged by hand by me
they come in a little round disc with a
little foam a protective insert all of
the seeds come out of a little uh it's a
ritual they get put into a little like a
just a cereal bowl a small cereal bowl
i roll them on the bottom of the bowl to
make sure they're nice and hard with
this finger and i make sure the seeds
nice and solid i set a few of them at
the edge of the bowl and then i try to
find 10 or 12 of them that look like
they would be friends to go in a
container together maybe that's crazy
but i package every seed by myself
they're irie genetics hand selected
premium seeds and i think that doing
that it says it on the package that's
what i talk about i need to follow that
and that's why i stand out because i
touched those seats and i made sure that
they're quality i don't trust anybody
else to do that
learning to
learning to delegate and letting anybody
do anything else with my company took a
long time it took a very long time until
i realized i simply cannot do all of
this stuff if i want to give you a long
talkative podcast like this i've been
going for quite a while today and i'm
enjoying it i want to give you long
shows like this i've got to learn how to
let other people help me with other
things so shout out to guys like dave
dave does uh waffles and actions if
you're on the internet you know what
waffles and actions are shout out to the
artist crew uh shout out to handmade
apparel adam hand for making uh shirts
for me shout out to kevin for doing
artwork uh there are other people
black thumb grower
gets a shout out too but those people
helped me out quite a bit i feel like
there was somebody i really wanted to
give a shout out i was going to give a
shout out to uh dp710 for his blueberry
butcher artwork you guys will see
stickers and shirts of that when the
seeds are restocked shout out to dave
for helping design some merchandise uh
shout out to all the people that helped
me out uh shout out to uh riven waters
for a bunch of great artwork as well uh
that those people make my life much
easier a lot of people have sent me
great artwork now i'm in a hole i can't
remember everybody but all those people
that send me artwork and things like
that that help me out they do make my
life easier it was hard hard hard hard
to let people have a little bit of
control in this company because it was
my vision it's my baby so learn how to
delegate learn what you're comfortable
letting other people do so once the
seeds go into the container and that
part is sealed up sometimes i do let
other people fold the card and put a
sticker on it and put that into a baggie
and heat seal it but that's like the
only part i really let other people do
for me because that's kind of i can
watch them do it and i give them 100
packs 100 bubbles with 100 cards and 100
stickers and they kind of can't screw it
up they kind of have to try to [__] that
up so i do let other people do that part
sometimes but most of the time it's just
me doing the seed packaging
so learning to let other people help is
a challenge know when to ask for help um
so then you've got to
just do it man just do it and then learn
how to adjust and adapt to the market
things are going to happen things are
going to go wrong things won't go as
expected
i've been booked for events and had the
car loaded up and was about to get in
the car and then got an email or a text
message saying hey they just came and
said you can't sell seeds here and i'm
like well i paid you a lot of money for
that booth and i'd like to go sell seeds
there and they're like no you can't even
sell seeds i wouldn't even show up if i
were you i'll give you back your money
or or you might not even get your money
back those are often options at events
um so learn to adjust and adapt recently
uh my instagram page got [__] taken
uh luckily i've got a good team we got
that back quite quickly but that's a
great marketing tool and without that i
was not reaching over 30 000 people when
i post uh over 500 people would see my
stories every time i post them that was
500 people that were not seeing my
content potential uh those are we call
those leads in the business industry so
it took a minute to get the instagram
back there's always going to be stepping
stones and stuff like that learn to
adjust and adapt shit's not going to go
smoothly for the first two years and
then you're going to get busy and it's
going to feel like you're never going to
catch up which is a good thing if you
feel like you're catching up in a
business that means you don't have
enough to do it means you're failing you
got to find more [__] to do um so i'm
rambling on that let's see then there's
marketing networking and being involved
uh you've got to market your brand how
are people going to know that you exist
social media will get you so far but
then you've got to get out there be seen
make flyers merchandise stickers be on
shows get known
networking
when you're new
i'm not trying to it's hard to afford a
booth and advertising and all of the
requirements to get up where you need to
be as a new breeder so networking will
help you out maybe you'll make friends
with myself or another breeder who is
new to the game maybe i'll say hey bro
i'll give you two hours at my booth on
sunday if you want to come hang out at
my booth on sunday i'll give you two
hours where you can come set up shop at
my booth you can tweet and say hey my
brand will be at iregenetics's booth at
the indo expo for two hours you can sit
next to me and sell seeds for two hours
i'll give you a chance like that so do
some networking and make some friends
um or find another breeder who is right
at your level and split the booth with
them or maybe two or three other
breeders and get like four or five other
breeders who are just enter entering
the game all of you can go and network
together you can all use your social
media powers together power in numbers
more people will come to the booth then
when somebody comes to the booth to buy
your friends seeds they'll say oh you
made a cross of that and that i want
those seeds also and now you've made a
new client a new customer a new lead and
then you cross advertise with each other
like that i don't feel competition in
the breeding game so i'm all about
teaching my friends how to get into this
and helping you do it just know uh it's
over saturated and a lot of us are uh
it's already taken up dude the pie is
already getting eaten up but i'm not
afraid to teach you guys how to get into
it because i feel it's like
um
it's like food and music i make a
certain kind of thing and you might not
be into my certain kind of thing and
that is okay with me because there are
plenty of people that are into it
i'm into
fish the banned fish and i'm into the
grateful dead and i love reggae music
that's my little box my genre of stuff i
really really enjoy so let's just
hypothetically say that my seeds are
that kind of music well say i put out
fish and reiki and grateful dead vibes
with my seeds
if you've got norwegian death metal
seeds that's not gonna be my favorite
i'm not against it i got no problem with
it that's just not my favorite but
there's gonna be somebody at the
convention that is looking and has been
looking their whole life for norwegian
death metal seeds maybe you're into
country music there's a breeder that
breeds seeds that are aimed toward the
country music vibe i'm just being i'm
just giving you analogies here trying to
compare some [__] but i don't feel any
competition because i make a certain
type of product and other breeders out
there make a certain type of product and
a lot of the times uh people in the
community have already decided what
they're into if you're into a certain
thing like if a lot of people have
already decided when they go to the
event i want to go find mr soul or i
want to go find ire genetics or i want
to go find capulator everybody goes and
gets in caps line so we already know
we've already kind of found the band
that we're looking for it's like when
you go to the festival can't wait for
six o'clock i gotta go see fish at the
main stage or whatever band you're into
you already know it the industry gets
like that i feel no competition no uh no
weird vibes or anything like that toward
any of the industry so i think i covered
most of my notes i did write a lot of
stuff down that was a really good
question got me really really rambly
which i do enjoy
i do need a drink and i do think that
i'm going to wrap up this episode
because my next question is going to be
a long one so on the next episode we're
going to have another long question that
talks about commercial cultivation cover
a couple of commercial cultivations in
the next episode uh my buddy adam thank
you that was a great question dude you
got me talking for quite a long time not
a lot of editing to do which makes my
life easy so thanks again for that
ladies and gentlemen boys girls pimps
hoes friends foes smokers growers clone
cutters pollen chuckers
bmx riders skateboarders surfer kids and
fruit booters i want to thank each and
every one of you again for listening to
episode
665 of the grow from your heart podcast
every time i read the episode numbers on
my screen it makes me make this weird
smile it's kind of a weird pride thing
it's also like holy [__] we did
665 episodes it's pride it's also a
giddy feeling um couldn't have done it
wouldn't have done it without you so
thank you guys for watching listening
supporting i do appreciate it
if you have any questions corrections
comments or concerns you know i would
love to hear from you the email address
is grow from your heart at hotmail.com
don't be shy send me some messages let
me know what's up uh also the discord i
mentioned the discord earlier in the
show the discord server there is a link
in the show notes and the video
description over a thousand members on
the discord channel when i get done here
uh as the files load from the cameras
into the computer i actually go hang out
on discord and take a couple of dabs
drink some water and get my voice back
so that's where we'll be for a couple of
minutes here uh patreon patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart show
love give love thank you for all of the
love uh now is the time to click like
and subscribe if you have not already
clicked like on this video i did slur a
little bit but that's okay if you have
not already clicked like on this video
now is a good time also make sure to
subscribe also there's a little
notification bell if you click on that
notification bell every time i put out a
new episode you'll get a little ding on
your phone you'll know there's a fresh
episode of the grow from your heart
podcast you could jump in watch the
premieres hang out with us i'm often in
the chat in the premiere of the show so
i'm hanging out watching the chat
chatting with the crew join us like and
subscribe
all right that's all i've got for you
for this episode you know i'll be back
in a couple of days with fresh new
content
i want to send a big shout out to my
buddy john at lollipop farms and until
next time take a fat dab and give your
mom a hug for me
[Music]
you