[Music]
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rosta jeff and this is episode
666 of the grow from your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to talk about
integrated pest management before we get
to that part of the show let's do a few
shout outs to a few of the kind folks
who support the show on patreon let's
start off with the big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out to my
friend ivan munoz let's send a big thank
you shout out to red eyed optimist and
canadareaper413
let's send a big thank you shout out to
madewell medicated and thomas mcginnis
let's send a big fist bump and a thank
you shout out to captain mojo and
zachsen starker let's send a big thank
you shout out to spherical glassworks
and 716 grows let's send a big fist bump
to a long time supporter and a good
friend jesse groves then let's wrap up
the shout outs with the big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
and a fist bump to the dad hayes big
thanks and big shout out to everybody
who continues to support the show if you
are not already supporting the show on
patreon and you would like to learn how
to do so all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need is right there on the screen and
you know i did put a link in the show
notes and in the video description to
make it nice and easy for all of my
friends once again patreon.com forward
slash grow from your heart again i would
like to invite you to join the irie
genetics grow from your heart podcast
discord server we've reached
approximately 1100 members of the
discord server it has been a good time i
hang out in the live chat i do some
video chats take some dabs talk about
growing answer a bunch of questions over
there
sometimes if i'm packing up seeds or
getting orders together i just hang out
in the chat and hang out with the
friends it's like having some company or
someone to hang out with join me you
never know when i could be in the chat
also if you've got any questions about
anything i read genetics the discord
server is a great place to go for
information there are people there right
now that are ready to help you willing
to give you advice guidance details they
will fill you in
so once again i do cordially invite you
to join us on the discord server and of
course there is a link in the show notes
and in the video description all right i
did say this episode was going to be
about integrated pest management this
could take a while so i don't want to
ramble too much here at the start of the
show try to use my voice for the lesson
here so let's get right into it
integrated pest management i got a
question from patreon that said can you
do a series on integrated pest
management there is so much to cover and
i replied with there is so much to cover
so this may be a long episode i'm not
going to get into details on uh each
specific pest we're going to talk about
basic integrated pest management let's
get right into it what is the first step
to making sure we don't get a we're
going to get let me start by saying this
you're going to experience bugs in your
garden [ __ ] does happen we can't stop
everything uh sometimes the best way to
learn how to prevent a pest is to get a
pest the best way to learn how to
eradicate a pest is to get that pest you
never learn about a problem until you
have to face it so you're going to get
problems in the group bugs are going to
show up powdery mildew is going to show
up things are going to happen that is
how life goes in a grow environment
whether it's indoors outdoors greenhouse
whatever you're doing there's the huge
opportunity very high likelihood for
bugs especially if you're growing in an
area where i grow where i live it's
legal here everybody grows everybody
works in a commercial facility or a
dispensary or their boyfriend or cousin
or roommate or somebody is involved in a
growth somewhere so we're all trading
bugs we go to a house to go play video
games or smoke with a friend you sit on
the couch and you're just passing spider
mites back and forth you go to your
other friend's house you take the mites
there or you get thermites that's just
how it works when everybody works in a
gross we've got to stay on top of it
you're gonna get bugs don't let the bugs
discourage you don't let them scare you
if we know what to do and how to
identify bugs before the time comes we
don't panic as much so i try to be
prepared try to read about what's coming
try to know what to expect try to google
research things i'm going to do a little
bit of that work for you
so you're going to get bugs no matter
how well you set up your grow how well
you design your things things may happen
so don't feel like uh like you've done
something wrong don't feel like you've
got shame or something you've got
something to hide if you've got bugs
it's a good learning opportunity and the
pride will come when you defeat the
problem and have a successful crop even
though you did have some fears in the
beginning or middle of the cycle all
right so
um that is my kind of disclaimer my what
is that a preface there so we you're
gonna get bugs and don't feel like it
like you failed or anything it's very
common especially in my area in my
industry so uh the number one way to
prevent uh problems is to
have a plan in place before problems
ever even start prevention is key like i
said a moment ago learn how to identify
bugs have a strategy where are you
growing i just said that i'm in i'm in
colorado it's legal to grow here i can
have six plants in my home everybody's
got six plants in their home anybody my
age in my age range uh if you're 21 to
45 maybe 60 you've probably got six
plants in your home if you've got a
medical marijuana recommendation you can
have six more so you may have up to 12
plants in your home
that means there's probably one house on
every block growing in my opinion in my
experience honestly it's about that
average
so where are you growing i know that
here in colorado everybody like i said
has got spider mites powdery mildew
fungus gnats thrips we've got all the
basic bugs because we're just trading it
from commercial facilities what bugs pop
up where you live if you're growing
indoors outdoors greenhouse environment
what kind of bugs are known to be
present in gardens where you live if
you're outdoors you can do a quick
little google search and find out what
kind of bugs are going to show up in an
outdoor garden and you can be prepared
to battle those bugs know what they look
like know what their eggs look like know
what kind of signs they leave on the
plant what do they do do you see their
poop do they make bite marks uh do you
see eggs lots of things will indicate
that bugs are there know what you're
looking for know how to find them and
have a plan of attack before you even
get the bugs and it will help you out
tremendously a little bit of training
ahead of time and you'll know how to
react without going into panic mode
panic mode
panic mode in the garden causes more
problems than it ever fixes i see people
just decide to do random crazy [ __ ]
because they had a problem that was a
level two and they're like well then i
sprayed i defoliated i over watered i
changed the light cycle and then i fed
it completely different nutrients and
i'm like well you just took that level
two problem and made it a level seven by
doing too many damn things to the plants
if you know what you're doing know how
to not panic you've got a much more
likelihood of a successful rescue or an
eradication of a problem so know what
problems are coming know what to expect
what kind of bugs are in your area most
common bugs for every grow you're going
to see spider mites fungus gnats thrips
i'm sure there's other stuff that we'll
talk about aphids are common especially
if you're growing outdoors everybody
gets worms and caterpillars outdoors
know what is coming prepare for those
things
then the next step is to think uh how
nuclear or organic do you want to go to
treat your garden for pest prevention
are you going to spray heavy pesticides
are you going to spray heavy fungicides
or are you only going to go with organic
pesticides and fungicides or are you not
going to spray at all are you going to
use predator predator bugs in your
garden there are many very useful
insects that we can order
we can purchase them online or locally
from insectiaries if you have one near
you you can get live bugs delivered to
your grow and you can disperse those
live insects in your grow and they will
eat the problem bugs they will stick
around if you buy the right insects
they'll make babies and they'll keep
breeding in your garden those bugs are
beneficial they don't eat your plants
they don't cause any problems and they
work as security guards for the other
bugs if some spider might show up they
eat them
if you do decide to use sprays as your
plan of attack for pests and fungus
how harsh or gentle of a chemical will
you allow yourself to use in your garden
do you want to use something that is
crazy from uh some monsanto product or
do you just want to use some hippie uh
oil sprays where is your boundary where
is your uh your threshold there what
will and will you not use start thinking
about that now start researching the
products and find out what you are
comfortable with i don't like um
neem oil neem oil will make if you're
going to use your your finished product
for concentrates or any i don't like
neem oil neem oil will stick around in
the flavor of your product most of those
botanical oils and essential oils are
not good for growing cannabis in my
opinion because they stick around and
you will taste it in the finished
product if you use it too much so let me
find my notes again and see where i am
are you going to spray are you going to
use predator bugs i do have a note here
that says in my opinion ladybugs are
basically useless i know a lot of people
are going to throw their arms up in the
air and go what i love ladybugs
in my opinion for their price they are
not cost effective they're not hungry
enough they're not aggressive enough
they don't stick around long enough they
fly away
you release a [ __ ] ton of ladybugs
however many however many ladybugs you
release tomorrow you're only going to
have half of them if it's indoors
outdoors greenhouse whatever half of
them are going to fly into the lights
half of them are going to fly into the
blowers half of them are just going to
die because they don't have any food or
they don't know what they're doing it's
just overpopulated with ladybugs
suddenly they just die
then by halfway through that day you've
only got a third by the end of that day
you've probably got a quarter this is my
experience with ladybugs you let a bunch
of them go you end up sweeping them up
shop backing them up they stink you end
up crunching them on the floor now you
got to mop up the floor because you've
got scattered splattered ladybugs
everywhere i don't prefer ladybugs i see
people talk about it all the time on
social media
ladybugs are amateur hour there are much
more aggressive and qualified bugs out
there to do the job for you
swarskis persimilis hypoaspis miles
green lace wings i know i'm going fast
but you can do some research and you can
find those bugs that will work for you
which predators work in your environment
when you go shopping for predator
insects you can do a lot of research on
the website hopefully the website you
were looking at will tell you this
predator bug prefers this temperature
range and this humidity range the bugs
do have a vpd which they prefer also if
you don't have that type of a vpd then
you may want to get a different bug or
your insects that you just bought your
troopers your army your soldiers they
may come for a little while and hang out
and eat a couple of bugs and they'll go
you know what it's way too hot in here
bro they're gonna find an escape rod and
they're gonna go somewhere else and
they're gonna go to a garden where it's
a more appropriate temperature or
they'll just die off they'll quit
breeding they'll quit eating and they
will die off so find out the appropriate
predators for your environment a lot of
the good companies you can call them and
they will give you advice and guidance
you can say this is my greenhouse my
indoor my outdoor production
maybe be vague about cannabis but just
they don't care what plants you're
growing talk about canopy size and bug
infestation and bug pressure is what
they will be more worried about they're
going to want to know canopy size
temperature humidity environment
environmental swings things like that
then they're going to want to know what
pest are you trying to eradicate so get
a good idea of which insects you need
for your environment and also be
prepared for which insects are coming to
your grow very commonly you're going to
get spider mites thrips fungus gnats
aphids
if you're outdoors you're going to get
those moths that lay eggs in there and
those moths turn into worms and they
become caterpillars and they become
butterflies i don't know what they are
in colorado we get a lot of melon worms
here in southern colorado they're orange
worms that grow in the buds
they'll really wreak havoc on your
plants quite quickly so which insects do
you think you're going to use uh find
out if they're cost effective for your
area can you afford those insects
learn how you're going to disperse them
some of them have to be hung up on each
individual plant some come in a
container and you just take off the lid
and they start climbing out you just got
to move them around a little bit
depending on the size of your grow it
may have may require a little bit of
manpower to spread out those
sachets or however they are delivered to
you
let me see where i'm in my notes i did
get lost uh which predators are you
going to use which bugs are you going to
battle
now let's talk about spraying are you
capable of spraying i don't know how
physically capable you are you may have
to mix up a 5 gallon 10 maybe a 20
gallon container of water with
pesticides mixed into it with fungicides
mixed into that and then you may have to
spray a large area i don't know your
physical limitations i try to keep in
mind some people aren't completely
physically able like some people are so
maybe you need to get predator bugs and
let them out maybe you have to spray
because you can't disperse the predator
bugs what's gonna work best for you what
can you physically manage do you have a
crew do you have a staff do you have a
helper do you have a couple strapping
young lads out there that can just be in
the heat all day putting out bugs or
maybe a guy that can suit up in the
middle of the day don't spray during the
day can't turn off the lights if you're
in the greenhouse but if you're outside
or whatever do you have a guy that can
spray when the sun goes down or before
the sun comes up do you have somebody
capable of spraying so think about that
sort of stuff are you going to be able
to stick to a routine and a cycle you
can get the bugs delivered on a schedule
if you set up a deal with the places
that deliver the bugs they can come once
a week every two weeks twice a week
however you want to set up a routine and
they'll know what's best for you
depending on the
infestation the pest pressure the
beneficial insect you're buying and the
environment in which you're putting it
in the insectaries will have great
recommendations on frequency
and maybe they will try to sell you
extra but it is always better to have
extra security guards than not enough
you want more on your team so the other
team can't take over
if your gang is bigger you got a better
chance of winning um let me keep going
to figure out how where i am
okay let's talk about spraying now if
you're spraying indoors that is a good
option i am hesitant of spraying
outdoors because in my opinion
i don't want to
disrupt the balance outdoors i don't do
a lot of outdoor growing i may have a
greenhouse project happening this year
that i haven't talked about but i don't
do a lot of outdoor growing if i were to
grow outdoors i would use beneficial
insects and predator bugs as my way of
taking care of pest pressure
my reasoning for not wanting to spray
outside is i feel it disrupts the
outside outside is already doing its
thing it's great outside if we don't
mess with it outside is perfect it's
perfectly sustainable humans are what
mess up outside we put our plants out
there we're going to get a bug out there
uh something most likely is going to eat
that bug then that bug is either going
to move on or try to make home in our
plants then in most cases another bug
will come get rid of that
we do have to draw the line somewhere we
can't just have a bug battle happening
in our plants every day and there are
some things like i've seen spider mites
build webs and take over gardens really
quickly without any interaction or
prevention but i think that outside if
we mess around too much we do cause more
problems so my opinion
my preference would be to use the
beneficial insects for the outdoor grow
that way we're not spraying things we're
not destroying the environment that
patch of land you're growing on may be
yours it may not be it could be somebody
else's land you just snuck on don't be a
dick but either way treat that land with
respect that that 10 by 10 patch of land
may be yours everything around it is
ours somebody out there owns it somebody
next door to you owns it the environment
that it is actually a part of is all of
ours and please respect it and take good
care of it i don't know where your
sprays are going i don't know what
you're doing to the earth the
environment the air all of that stuff
we're sharing it keep that in mind
please i'm sure that most people
listening to my show
are gonna be very gentle and very
courteous and very mindful but still
keep in mind that that patch of land
that you're [ __ ] up for this one grow
season to have a successful crop that's
also our land that's also our
environment you won't be here forever
hopefully that land outlives you and
there are other generations that have to
live on that land let's not make it have
to live on that land let's make it they
get to live on that land that you did
not destroy contaminate uh
what's the word i'm looking for make it
infertile let's not do that to the land
around us let's have respect all right
that's enough of my hippie ramble but
really you guys keep that stuff in mind
when you're spraying you're spraying
your area but where's the drift going
where's the pesticide going what are the
long-term effects you were doing to that
plot of land what are you doing to the
ecosystem the balance the environment
and now you're gonna say yeah but you're
gonna release a bunch of beneficial
insects yeah uh they're beneficial
insects they're gonna help the garden
they're not gonna there's not chemical
stuff it's not gonna change the earth
for a long time and they're gonna help
out my fellow neighbor growers by eating
their pests as well all right let me
find my notes and get back where i am
now i know i did mention this already
but think about your strategy before it
is time to attack i know we don't want
bugs i know we don't want to have to get
in there or go out there and attack a
bunch of bugs and try to fix a problem
but have a plan in place what are you
going to do you know i keep talking
about greenhouse environments indoor
outdoor environments here is a huge
piece of advice we have built if you
have built a nice indoor environment
you've hung up your lights you've put up
the reflective coating on the wall
you've cleaned up the flooring real well
you went and bought a bunch of brand new
gear we ran ducting we've got a carbon
filter in there if you're growing plants
indoors please
don't take them outside i know you're
going to want to take them outside it's
like taking them for a walk you're going
to go get them some fresh air some
sunshine go expose them to the
environment but you're also going to
expose them to all of the bugs that are
outside and then you're gonna bring that
precious plant with its new uh
passengers its stowaways into your
beautiful grow now in your grow you are
creating the most perfect environment
hopefully you've got the most ideal
environment for that plant but also
that's the most ideal beautiful perfect
environment for whatever bugs you just
brought in on that plant to thrive
they're going to have a party they're
going to say dude it is 77 degrees in
here it is the perfect humidity in here
there's not too much wind in here the
light cycle is the same constantly
there's no pest pressure there's no rain
there's no do in the morning there's no
problem we could just have a party in
here it is the island of jamaica for the
pests they're just gonna start partying
and then they're gonna start breeding in
there and then within a couple of days
you're gonna go oh i really [ __ ] up
putting that plant outside and bringing
it back in here because there's nothing
to stop that uh that party they're gonna
breed and they're gonna eat and they're
gonna breed and they're gonna eat and
they're just gonna take over your garden
so i really recommend not taking your
plants outside and bringing them back in
if you've got indoor plants they should
be indoor plants if you've got outdoor
plants those are outdoor plants if you
got greenhouse plants those are
greenhouse plants
really i wouldn't recommend bringing i
see it all the time on social media put
the plants outside today for a couple of
hours and i'm like oh you're gonna take
them indoors and contaminate the entire
grow space then you got to reclaim that
whole grow space yeah you've created
that beautiful indoor grow environment
let's just leave them in there they will
they will appreciate it now let's talk
about pest management
we have talked about prevention
we've talked about thinking about what
we might use
let's talk about identifying our bugs
learn to identify bugs how about now
maybe you don't have an infestation now
right how about now while you're
listening to me maybe just google spider
mites two spotted spider mites ah russet
mites google all of the common spider
mites that could be found in your area
that way you know what they look like
then let's start looking for what does
spider mite damage look like it looks
like somebody just took your leaves and
just started poking it with a little
little needle and all the juices came
out of that leaf where you poked it and
it just starts getting dry and they call
it stip stipule stipule i think that's
the word we learned in art class i
forgot the word it looks like somebody
just was just poking at that leaf and
just trying to just poke it and make a
little it'll look gradient it'll be
green and then it'll kind of gradient to
like a dead yellowy color and that's
where the spider mites are just having
lunch and they're probably on the
underside of the leaf so pull off that
leaf and take a look at it
right along the main vein of the leaves
the long main vein they'll be tucked up
there under the edge trying to hide
laying eggs
maybe you need a microscope or some sort
of magnification but pull off a leaf and
take a look you're going to find them
right there at the bottom so learn to
identify the bugs which we are expecting
to encounter
learn to identify spider mites uh learn
to identify
who the devil in my opinion one of the
worst insects to face i'm not afraid of
most
i can battle and conquer almost any
infestation you'll get in a grow whether
it's a home grow a commercial
environment a greenhouse outdoor i'm not
the expert but most other places we will
conquer all problems my biggest fear my
biggest adversary would be
the russet might those things are the
[ __ ] devil learn how to identify them
learn how to identify the signs of their
presence in your garden they will trick
you they will make you think you've got
nutrient problems they'll make you think
you've got watering problems they'll
make you think the plants are just doing
weird [ __ ] and then you'll realize
oh i've got russet mites russet mites
are the devil that's the biggest problem
in the garden i do know how to get rid
of them but it does take a little bit of
uh some strategy and some persistence
you got to be on top of that [ __ ] so
learn to identify those bugs spotted
mites spider mites uh russet mites
aphids aphids are easy because
aphids have uh tailpipes if you look
they look like a little volkswagen
beetle with tailpipes two exhaust pipes
coming out of them aphids always have
exhaust pipes uh and they come in all
colors i've been seeing new colors of
aphids which i've never seen before in
colorado it's like every year we get a
new color of aphid so if you got a
little green bug a little white bug a
little it could be purple brown yellow
i've seen them of all colors i haven't
seen a blue aphid yet um have i no i
haven't seen purple or blue aphids but
anyway aphids can be all colors so those
weird looking little
shiny
volkswagen beetle looking things that
are climbing around uh those are
possibly aphids in your grow thrips you
probably won't see the thrips they're
tiny what you will see is uh honeydew it
looks like they just looks like they
blew their nose or something blew your
nose bullet's nose on your lower leaves
it'll be on the bottom leaves of the
plant because the thrips likes to go
hang out in the soil and they come up at
night and they [ __ ] all over your leaves
so
that's called honeydew thrips are super
easy to get rid of people panic when
they see thrips those are easy easy to
get rid of white flies white flies uh
you may confuse a thrip or a fungus gnat
let me [ __ ] try to say that again i'm
not even going to edit that
white flies you may confuse a white fly
with an aphid if it flies away when you
tap the plant that's a white fly
sometimes you'll be watering and you'll
bump the plant just gently just like i
did this mic stand and you'll just see
little ashy bugs come flying out those
[ __ ] are white flies they are very
easy to eradicate uh those are more uh
of an annoyance than a problem they can
be a vector and lead to further issues
but really they're more just annoying
and obnoxious than anything else and
they [ __ ] up your pictures they get in
your face
those suck
just like fungus gnats fungus gnats are
obnoxious and they fly around as well if
you tap the pot and these little black
flies come out those little [ __ ] are
fungus gnats that's probably from over
watering if you don't over water as
frequently let the soil dry up a little
bit you'll have less likelihood for
fungus gnats
something i've learned if you run
canon led lighting from black sail
market big shout out to my buddy keith
at blacksail if you run the canon leds
the diode is about the size of a 50 cent
piece and i think the fungus gnats are
attracted to it they fly right into that
50 cent piece of a light and they fall
directly down onto the plant that is
right below that so you could just go
scoop them up off of that plant and
you'll be able to identify your fungus
gnats you'll know it's like a little
indicator a little marker you'll know
they're there because that led light is
just nuking them they can't resist it
they fly right into it and they hit it
and they go oh that's too hot and then
they cook and they just fall right onto
the plants below
all right i did mention that outdoors
you're going to get caterpillars and
melon beetles those are not the easiest
to get rid of you're going to have to
treat with some probably some spray
products i'm not sure what predators are
large enough maybe a praying mantis
maybe a giant lacewing
maybe big enough to eat some of those
caterpillars and melon beetles
those are things you're going to see
outdoors possibly in the greenhouse i
hope you don't get those in the
greenhouse
more stuff you might see powdery mildew
powdery mildew is very common i keep
saying it's powdery mildew season here
in colorado
temperature swings humidity swings
diurnal swings will definitely lead to
powdery mildew here in colorado over
foliation
over leafy plants
low circulation things like that will
definitely lead to powdery mildew
powdery mildew is definitely something
you'll run into in a greenhouse
environment very commonly we get it here
in colorado because we have a lot of
drastic temperature changes uh powdery
mildew is not very hard to get rid of
it's also very easy to prevent you can
spray a few products on your plants
there are some organic products that you
could spray that will work as a
preventative i wasn't going to talk a
lot about stuff like that but i like
for a preventative and a corrective
product in a
powdery mildew situation i like the
products cease i haven't used it but
i've seen a lot of great success with
green cure and then if it really gets
nasty
xerotal 2.0 is not organic but it is a
good product we've got a lot of options
but if you spray it with the c su or a
combination of the two you'll prevent a
nice protective layer those are
beneficial bacterias that eat the
powdery mildew or one of them eats the
powdery mildew one creates a surface uh
ph on the leaf surface that makes it
undesirable for powdery mildew to
colonize so those are a couple of ways
to help you prevent powdery mildew
prevention there from a fungus you can
do that indoors outdoors greenhouse
environments uh cease is organic it's a
little bit expensive but it's cheaper
than powdery mildew
now another thing that is very important
when it comes to integrated pest
management is scouting and indicators do
you know what you're looking for do you
know the signs of pests i've talked
about a couple of things to look for
spider mites you're gonna see stipuling
little pokeys you're gonna see little
crawly bugs on the bottom of the leaves
if you see webbing you've got spider
mites and you have not been paying
attention it's time to get in there and
get rid of those [ __ ] things uh the
aphids you're gonna see little skittles
crawling around your plants thrips
you're gonna see the honeydew white
flies you'll see the ashes flying around
fungus gnats are little black things
flying around
caterpillars and melon beetles and
orange worms those are going to be
obvious uh powdery mildew looks like
you're starting to put powdered sugar on
the plants it looks like you were eating
a powdered donut and just dribbled it
right onto the plant that's what that
looks like so uh do you know what you're
looking for know the signs of bugs and
powdery mildew also pay attention for
bud rot but that's a little bit later in
the season when you've got buds if the
inside of that bud looks brown and
squishy and shitty you've got bud rot
i'm sorry that happened to you um
scouting and indicators uh does the
whole crew if you're working with a crew
more people than just yourself do they
all know what they're looking for do you
have a specific person scouting every
day yes every day you should look at
every plant every single day if you're
looking for pests there should be one
person or a team of people trained to
identify and scout four pests what are
your indicators a lot of people use
yellow sticky traps in their garden
unfortunately they're thinking that that
is a pest eradicator that is not a way
to get rid of pests that is simply there
to tell you you have got pests you look
at the yellow sticky trap every day
maybe twice a day maybe take a peek at
it before you leave the grow take a peek
when you come back and see how many bugs
are sticking to that yellow sticky trap
you're gonna get a few bugs just because
life has bugs there are bugs wherever
you are you may get a fly i'm sure you
saw the little gnat flying around here
may get some mosquitoes or something
stuck to it but do you have a bunch of
white flies or a bunch of fungus gnats
or a bunch of something unidentifiable
stuck to those sticky cards pay
attention let them be indicators as soon
as you see that number getting towards
concerning it's time to step up your
prevention maybe start doing an
eradication maybe start putting more
beneficial insects into the room it's
time to start rethinking your strategy
if you're seeing the numbers on the
cards get too high do scouting don't be
afraid
i talk a lot about defoliating when
you're defoliating don't be afraid to
take off a few leaves and flip them
upside down and take a moment to see
what you've got going on on the bottom
of those leaves are there bugs are there
eggs take some time enjoy your plants
spend a minute with them inspect them
scout them now let's talk about plant
damage and other signs of trouble do you
see signs of trouble do you see plant
damage i've told you what to look for
are you in there every day looking for
it the problem the problem plant i can
already tell you it's the one in the
back corner that you don't [ __ ] with
enough that's the one that's got the
bugs on it get back there and look at it
love that plant give it kisses why are
you annoying why are you avoiding that
one plant what did it do to you there's
always that one in the grow it's always
just back there or back there in the
corner that's the one with bugs and
those bugs are gonna move on pretty soon
and they're gonna be in the whole grow
so uh look for signs of damage do you
know what you're looking for do you know
what kind of bugs are doing that damage
now do you know how to react properly
with intent and purpose just because you
see bug damage doesn't mean you need to
go get pesticide a and heavily spray
pesticide a what if the pesticide you
just got is for spider mites and the
bugs that you've got are thrips is it
going to work is it going to do anything
or did you just spray the plants with
some stressful [ __ ] spend some money
spend some time spend some energy on the
wrong thing let's identify the pest do
some research on the appropriate product
or beneficial insect to eradicate that
pest and apply with intent and purpose
have a strategy have a schedule how
often do you need to apply this product
um how many days apart do i need to wait
to apply this product what other
products can i apply with this and what
other products can i not apply with this
some things you can't mix some things
you can mix some things you shouldn't
spray maybe five to seven days apart
from each other you may want to wait uh
if you treat with any sulfur products
don't treat with any oils for five to
seven days before or after and the
opposite sulfurs and oils shouldn't mix
it's going to give you huge problems on
your plants so
be ready to react properly with intent
and purpose have
a good idea is to have multiple modes of
attack if you've got uh swarovskis and
persimilis and hypoasmus miles and
lacewings in there you've got multiple
modes of attack three different bugs
going in there you can't run and hide
from three or four different bugs but if
you've got a tank mix with multiple
ingredients you can spray multiple
things in the garden at one time that
way you hit with multiple modes of
attack some pesticides simply make the
plants undesirable for the bugs the bugs
are like oh that's sticky and stinky i
don't want to go there other pesticides
will infect your bugs with a mushroom or
a fungus that grows inside of them and
then explodes them other pesticides will
simply make the bugs forget to eat and
then they just don't eat and they die
some pesticides will make the bugs
unable to breed so they'll just keep
going but they can't make any more so
multiple modes of attack what if i hit
you with the pesticide that makes you
not want to breed and forget to eat and
now you're just not eating and you're
not breeding you're just walking around
going i don't have a purpose and then
you die and you don't come back and the
bugs are gone so if you hit with
multiple modes of attack you can
definitely eradicate your problems more
quickly
here is something to keep in mind i'm
talking about multiple modes of attack
and multiple products in a tank mix
bugs will get what is known as
resistance to a pesticide just think
about if you walk in the room every day
and i punch you right in the jaw every
day day one is gonna [ __ ] hurt day
two it's gonna hurt day three it's gonna
suck day four
all right i got punched in the jog and
day five yup day six right in the jaw by
day 12 you're just going to walk out the
door and you're going to put your jaw up
there and take it and keep doing your
thing if you keep spraying the bugs the
same thing over and over and over again
they're going to start drinking it up
like kool-aid and it's not going to do
anything to them it doesn't take very
long for some of these new bugs we've
we've evolved these bugs so quickly by
doing this they've developed such quick
resistance to pesticides that we've got
to rotate and use multiple modes of
attack so rotate your pesticides to
prevent resistance
one thing that the bug lady suzanne says
you cannot build a resistance to being
eaten so if you want to use those
predator bugs they will always win
because you cannot build a resistance to
being eaten there's no resistance
especially if you power in numbers if
you overdo it with those uh predator
insects you will definitely win
let's see
i've already said that i don't like neem
oil i don't like oils with a lot of
fragrances especially like spearmint
oils peppermint oils
any of that
sticky oil that you spray on the plants
that you can see it kind of stick and
leave a shine onto the plant i don't
like spraying that sort of stuff because
i make a lot of concentrates out of my
products i want to smoke a concentrate
that is oil free when you make
concentrates from products that have
been sprayed with oils you can see an
experienced concentrate maker
consumer i'm not even an experienced
maker and i can see it i can see the
oils float to the top of the
concentrates when you're putting oils
and weird sprays and [ __ ] in the plants
we can see it some people know how to
remove it i don't know how to do that
part that's not my area of expertise but
i can see it i can identify it on the
top of the concentrate it's a little
oily sheen just like if you mix oil and
water together you can watch the oil
float i can see that i can see the
pesticides when the products are being
processed so i don't like a lot of crazy
hippie oils i would rather just go with
a pesticide or insects than some of
those
lower level
hippie oils they sell at the store you
know which brands i'm talking about i
skip all of that stuff
now um spray properly whatever you're
going to spray spray properly do you
need to spray the top of the leaf do you
need to spray the underside of the leaf
some products like to be sprayed what is
called two runoff so you spray the
plants until they're just [ __ ]
dripping to where you got a puddle of
pesticide or offspray around the bottom
of the plant some plants do some
pesticides do not want to be sprayed to
run off so they just want you to spray
the plant with enough just to get enough
of it on there and it stays there and
then some of them you got to spray the
underside of the leaf extreme like if
you got spider mites you need to spray
the underside of the leaves because
that's where the bugs are if you're
spraying for powdery mildew you need to
spray the top because that's where the
powdery mildew is going to go so
understand how to spray properly also
understand the pesticides you are using
all this is something i probably should
have started with but every bottle that
you're going to use has a booklet on the
front open up that booklet and read
about the re-entry interval what when
you spray a pesticide there's a amount
of time you should leave your grow and
not enter that because it is
those pesticides are fresh and flying
around you just sprayed bubbles in there
and you got wet pesticide in there you
don't want to be rubbing up against it
you don't want that in your lungs and
your skin there is something called the
re-entry interval written on that
booklet inside of your on your
pesticides read that book there is so
much information in there there are
dosage recommendations there is a part
that tells you what personal protective
equipment to wear always where the
appropriate personal protective
equipment when applying any type of
pesticide if you're just spraying water
if you're making small enough bubbles i
like to wear a mask or a respirator i
don't want to inhale micronized bubbles
of anything into my lungs that doesn't
sound like a good idea we got enough
[ __ ] to deal with right now with our
lungs let's try to not poison
contaminate and injure ourselves while
trying to take care of our plants so
proper personal protective equipment at
all times it will be listed inside of
the pesticide book right on the front of
the bottle you just pull out this one
little book all the info you need is
right there just read the book it's only
going to take you a couple of minutes
and it may really really help you out
use all of the recommended personal
protective equipment always use gloves i
recommend like a paper tyvek suit if you
can't invest in that get a long sleeve
shirt wear that get some long pants
always wear shoes and socks in the grove
that cover up your feet the bottoms of
your feet are one of the most absorbent
parts for contaminants and pesticides so
think about
spray a pesticide drips off the plant
lands on the floor you're barefoot you
step on that [ __ ] you're going to get
maximum pesticide absorption and
exposure that you could possibly get
through the bottoms of your feet there
are a couple other spots
of course your genitals because you got
that thin soft skin armpits face but the
bottoms of your feet are a prime spot
for you to accidentally contaminate
yourself so please wear the appropriate
personal protective equipment and read
the bottles learn about the equipment
the re-entry intervals and learn about
the toxicity levels of those products
you're using does it say like warning
hazard danger poison it's gonna have
words like that on there know what
you're working with
also
maybe have the msds sheets available
maybe have a spray log available if
you're in a commercial environment those
are required if you're in a personal
grow you can get crazy and willy-nilly
with all that [ __ ] but still it would be
a good idea to have a binder with an
msds log for all of your products that's
simply find every product you've got and
go to the internet go to the website
type in whatever product um i'm just
gonna i don't have any liquid products
near me i've got i can see a bottle of
cease so cease biological pesticide or
fungicide whatever it says on there uh
seize product msds sheet and you'll find
it every product has an msds sheet
available they have to print it uh i
make i buy these little it's like a
little laminate folder that you'd keep
like for a presentation and a folder and
i just print them off and i slide them
all into there and make a notebook out
of them that way if anything does go
wrong if i do end up sick if i do ingest
something i can grab that folder i can
grab my pesticide log and i can go to
the hospital i can say there's probably
clues in here and then they can help me
out or maybe somebody can take that [ __ ]
for me if i'm not able to do it
just good ideas to protect yourself
that may be a different strategy if you
were in what is known as a red state
maybe you don't that's all evidence at
this point in a red state so be careful
with that decision but i do like to have
uh the msds sheets a spray log try to
have all that stuff available in case
you never know what could go wrong and i
was trained by the department of
agriculture the colorado department of
agriculture to keep those types of
records in a commercial environment it's
required you have to have all that stuff
for i think uh three to five years it
all has to be kept on file uh the
compliance officer knows how many years
she keeps it all for us but shout out to
your compliance officer wherever you are
i am super off topic now where are we
keep those books keep all that stuff
documented and then uh i was saying i'm
uh trained by the department of
agriculture i guess maybe it would be a
good time to drop my credentials in here
since i'm talking about pesticides
applications all this safety and stuff
you're going well who the hell are you
bro uh that's a good question i have got
a training from the colorado department
of agriculture and the colorado state
university i was trained by a very great
lady named theo walker i took like a
it's either a six or eight hour class in
a cool building in denver with uh there
were very few people in that class but
it was a good time and she taught us in
great detail about pesticides pesticide
handling pesticide application pesticide
exposure she taught us a great class i
am what is called train the trainer
certified i can go to commercial groves
and the state of colorado and i can
teach them how to be pesticide compliant
i can train other people to train the
staff how to be pesticide compliant so
that is my credential i'm train the
trainer certified which means i can
train other trainers i go to the grow
and i train the lead grower and he
teaches the staff or i just do a big
meeting teach the whole class all at one
time teach up the whole uh the whole
gang so those are my credentials i do
have a little bit of training with
pesticides pesticide application
handling and safety i'm not just talking
out of my ass on this episode the others
use your best judgment um
all right where am i i've got a lot of
notes here i try to just freestyle
because it feels better i feel like i'm
getting a good flow the notes make me
feel too robotic
uh spray properly do you need to spray
the top the bottom uh run off or not
then the next part is soil drench a lot
of our pests live on the leaves and hang
out in the plants but a lot of them
retreat to the soil
for safety we can shake the plants we
can disrupt things they just go hide
down in the dirt because a lot of things
can't get to them so for those pests
that's when i would recommend what is
known as a soil dredge or a soil drench
there are many great products you can
use to get rid of many common pests in
your soil most commonly you're going to
find uh fungus gnats in your soil you
may find root aphids in your soil those
are all easy to defeat with a root
drench
a root drench or a spray any kind of
pesticide treatment needs to be done on
a good solid schedule i spray in a
commercial environment if we don't have
any issues i spray every monday if i see
one sign of issues we spray every monday
and every thursday if i see something in
the soil we'll do a soil drench on
monday and then we'll do another soil
drinch on the next monday if i feel like
there's still an issue we'll hit the
soil again on thursday along with those
sprays so we're spraying up top and
we're soaking the soil we're really
trying to attack from all angles with
multiple modes of attack so a soil
dredge is not a problem never be afraid
to soil dredge those plants if you've
got a soil borne insect something like a
fungus gnat something like a root aphid
uh really easy product to soil drench
with is evergreen maybe 15 to 30 ml of
evergreen is that correct i don't want
to steer you wrong that came out really
naturally
15 to 30 millimeter milliliters of
evergreen per gallon of water a nice
soil dread start off with the 15 see if
that helps you out the plants are going
to kind of react uh soil dredge till you
get some runoff that should help get rid
of your bugs i'm going to do research
and make sure i set the right numbers
when i edit um so we got a soil dredge
for soil borne pests if you're hitting
the soil and you're hitting the foliage
and the plants and the room is right
you're definitely going to be on the
right path to getting rid of all of
those problem bugs but keep in mind if
you're using predators we can't go
spraying some things we can't spray most
things and we definitely can't use most
of these soil dredges they will destroy
your predator so that's going to be some
strategery to work on there the most
important part to all of this is to have
a routine and a plan and a strategy if
you just go in there on monday and spray
and think i got rid of it all no you
didn't you killed the live bugs or you
killed the eggs but the opposite is
still there there's still a small
population that you missed you've got to
be on top of it that's why i spray every
monday and every thursday if i see any
issues get in there monday with one or
two pesticides then get in there on
thursday with one or two different
pesticides then go back monday with one
of the products i used on monday one of
the products i used on thursday then on
thursday i'll use the other two products
and we'll just keep rotating maybe add
some new [ __ ]
then i just keep rotating maybe add a
product maybe take a product out but i
really do try to attack those bugs with
all [ __ ] options
all right another important part is to
have boundaries and ethics don't spray
[ __ ] laid into flour
don't spray the wrong things in flour at
all don't spray [ __ ] that you would not
admit spraying if you wouldn't write it
down and say hey i sprayed 30
millimeters of this
milliliters sorry i keep saying
millimeters for some reason uh if you're
not proud of it if you wouldn't admit it
if you wouldn't smoke it with me don't
[ __ ] spray it on your plants that is
really the ethics of all of it if you
wouldn't smoke it please don't spray it
if you wouldn't tell us about it and be
honest about it just don't do it you
know
you know and you got to feel it imagine
if you spray some [ __ ] on your plants
and you sell it to me or give it to me
because you you're like bro thank you
for the lessons and you give me an ounce
of weed and i smoke it and like i start
going man my lungs feel weird and like
two weeks later i'm like my lung is all
burning and like a week later i'm like i
gotta go to the hospital my lung is
[ __ ] on fire and four weeks later
like i had to pull my right lung out
because i got some disease from a
pesticide and you're like oh that could
have been from the [ __ ] that i sold him
like imagine how you're going to feel i
don't want anybody to feel that way so
use some ethics when it comes to the
pesticides and things you were spraying
onto your plants any sort of foliar
product anything you're feeding your
plants anything you're doing should be
treated with all of that sort of ethics
what would rasta jeff do think about
that as you're doing [ __ ] in your garden
that may be a new merch product all
right i'm going to go over these notes
real quick and then we may start
wrapping up this podcast all right
ladies and gentlemen boys girls pimps
hoes friends foes smokers growers clone
cutters pollen chuckers
beneficial insect users and pesticide
spray applicators i want to thank you
again for listening to another episode
of the grow from your heart podcast i do
want to stress that the most important
part of this is that you read the
bottles and use all of the personal
protective equipment and do understand
those re-entry intervals something i
should add i didn't mention on the
re-entry interval part those products
are meant to be sprayed outdoors all of
those products the re-entry interval
written on those bottles is for outdoors
add two to four hours if you were in an
indoor environment i know that sounds
crazy but they're used to having wind
and sun to break down those products you
don't have that in your indoor grow so i
would add two to four hours to your
re-entry interval for your sprayed
applications all right i think that is
all i've got for you really i hope you
did learn a lot from this episode i hope
this inspired a lot of questions
corrections comments and concerns if
you've got those my email address is
grow from your heart at hotmail.com i do
look forward to hearing from you don't
forget to join the discord server it's a
party don't miss us also don't forget
about patreon patreon.com forward slash
grow from your heart now is the time to
like and subscribe and also hit that
little notification bell every time i
put out a new video you will get a
notification that's right if you're
watching on youtube now is the time
please do click like subscribe and click
the notification bell alright that's all
i've got for you you know i'll be back
in just a couple of days with fresh new
content i want to give a big shout out
to my buddy billy podunk and until next
time take a fat dab and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]
you