[Music]
what here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rasta jeff and this is episode
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to read a couple
of patreon messages before we get to
that part of the show let's do a few
shout outs to a few of the great folks
who support the show on patreon let's
start off with the big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out to 716
vibes let's send a big fist bump and a
thank you shout out to smoke what let's
send a special thank you shout out to
uncle gigi i want to send a big thank
you shout out to queen city creations
let's send a big thank you to yannick
buchi and grim bull the druid let's send
a big fist bump to sunny and backtopia
let's send a big thank you shout out to
nick p and jake b i want to send a big
shout out to darren smith and then let's
wrap it all up with the big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to my friend rozin ryan
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need is right there on the screen and
you know i do include a link in the show
notes and in the video description to
make it nice and easy for all of my
friends here is my disclaimer if you're
driving if you're working if you're
trimming don't get yourself in a wreck
don't get in trouble that link will be
there when you're free
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart this is the part of the show where
i invite you to join the irie genetics
discord channel that's right there is a
discord channel where all of the irie
genetics crew hangs out i pop in the
chat sometimes join the live chat join
the crew we hang out take some dabs talk
about life talk about growing talk about
whatever may be going on a couple of
nights ago i had some friends help me
make some decisions on some merchandise
so there's a lot of cool stuff happening
on the discord channel sometimes i do
exclusive drops i let people know that
things are coming up on the discord
channel so that is another avenue to
find some exclusive drops exclusive
information uh so make sure you do check
out the discord uh the link will be in
the show notes and in the video
description and i will try to remember
to put the link right here on the screen
when i am editing so check us out on
discord i was at a greenhouse today and
those plants are taking off i'm
recording on august 27 and today
the plants are going crazy most of the
plants are kicking into the flowering
phase they're starting to make big fuzzy
pistols look like they got dandelions on
them beautiful plants
most of them are kicking off there were
a couple of strains however that are
lagging a little bit they're just
stretching like crazy right now i'm sure
they'll catch up but it is an exciting
time for the greenhouse grow it was fun
to be out there getting my shoes dirty
getting a sunburn great time loving the
greenhouse life that was a lot of fun
let's keep moving uh some people were
asking me to do some episodes about
things that i have already done the
outdoor season is happening uh every
outdoor season i get asked for a couple
of outdoor episodes and then toward the
end of the season i get asked for a
couple of very specific episodes i've
already done those episodes that i have
in my mind a couple of them i've only
done an audio form i haven't done them
in the new video format but a lot of old
episodes are available on the youtube
channel and in the server wherever
you're listening or watching this
podcast from uh two however you do that
listen to watch it uh you know what i
meant to say however you're enjoying
this podcast there are a lot of old
episodes that may include some of the
grow advice and grow lessons and answers
to questions which you are looking for
don't forget about the old episodes is
what i'm trying to say we're at 668
right now that means there are 667 other
episodes that may have some answers that
you haven't heard yet
and even though i have done a lot of
episodes that i haven't converted to
video format yet or redone in the video
format i will get to those i was trying
not to repeat myself too much but it is
time i've got to kind of re-loop around
and do some of those old episodes over
again i've learned a lot technology
technology has changed uh the growing
has evolved so it may be time to update
some of those older episodes but don't
forget to check the feed uh do a quick
google search you may find an episode
about the question you've got in mind so
don't forget about that old stuff let's
move forward i do have a screenshot on
my phone somebody sent me a question i
just took a quick screenshot was the
most efficient way to do it this
question came from our friend i don't
know if they want their name said we're
gonna skip that the question says what's
up rasta jeff i've got a quick question
in your opinion is the hella dank seed
company a legit seed bank do they carry
legit irie genetics the answer to that
is yes the hella dank seed company is a
legitimate vendor for ire genetics that
is a great seed vendor a great seed bank
a great seed company
they get stuff out to you quite quickly
they've got a good selection a good
variety and good fair pricing i do
support them endorse them
promote them they are part of the team
most of the time you can verify a vendor
by checking my website
i usually have most of the vendors
updated on the website sometimes
i'm still auditioning a vendor so i may
not add them right away
but once they do uh they do sell a few
packs and make a couple of orders and
they show me that they have good quality
customer service and they don't
embarrass me in any way or frustrate my
customers then i do add them to the
website there are probably one or two
maybe three that need to be added to the
website right now uh i just haven't uh
sent them to the web guy to do it as
soon as i send him an email he'll
probably get them up there
we've got to get the canadian link up
there and a couple of others really soon
i've just got to make that happen there
is an official canadian distributor and
there are probably seven uh official
vendors on the website now what i'm
getting at is uh if you ever want to
know if a vendor is an official vendor
of irie genetics all you've got to do is
hit my website and on the website there
is a list of vendors and most of them
are listed there uh the company you
asked about is listed there in the top
three they're one of the top three or
top five vendors of my seed so they are
a legitimate seed vendor they are
official uh check the website and most
of the brands are the vendors will be
updated uh pretty quickly i'll send the
email to get them all on there because
they do approve and we're gonna add them
um the canada link will have a lot of
people excited all right so hella dang
seed company is official yes uh don't
forget to check out
seedshearnow.com check out the golden
ticket seed company heritage seed bank
el fuego seeds shy town seeds i know i'm
skipping one and i apologize i can't
think of it right now i just did that
off the top of my head
if i missed your seed brand i'm sorry
big shout out um where are we going from
there i have got some patreon messages
that's what i said we were gonna do i've
got a couple of great messages here in
front of me let's jump right into that
part that's what you guys showed up for
the question portion
this one came from my friend kyle this
one came from patreon it says hey ross
to jeff what's up kyle good to meet you
bro says i can't thank you enough for
all of the knowledge you are very
welcome brother keep listening and keep
supporting on patreon i'll keep it
coming it says i heard about you from
the dgc and i've really enjoyed your
podcast
big shout out to the dgc make sure you
make sure you support the dude grows
show big shout out to the dude big shout
out to scotty real big up to guru and
then a big special fist bump to
everybody behind the scenes you guys get
forgotten i'm a producer i'm an editor i
know it how it is i know how it goes big
fist bump to everybody i'm doing all
that stuff by myself so awesome for
making it easy for those guys
let's keep going because obviously i'm
stone and rambly it says i listen to the
podcast in a loop throughout the day and
soak in the info even when i already
know it ah that's a great thing
sometimes you may catch a weird detail
or something you didn't hear the first
time and i enjoy the clicks you're
making my numbers go up making my stats
climb so i appreciate that and uh you're
just filling your head with great
knowledge so that's a good thing it says
i'm 42 years old and i'm growing my own
plants here in va do i want to say that
out loud because i think they are
illegal now yeah so he's grown his
plants in virginia he's 42 years old he
says it's hard to believe that i can
legally grow and just three years ago
not far from me this door was kicked in
and i was taken to jail isn't it weird
how just like just one rule or one
scribble of a paper or one click of
approval can change everything yeah i
know what it feels like to have a chain
put on the door and the door just flies
off and a bunch of noise and commotions
happen you have no idea what's going on
and the dog's running down the street
there's no front door on the house and
suddenly you're on the [ __ ] floor in
handcuffs and all your friends are
looking at you like what the [ __ ] just
happened uh but then like a week later
they signed papers that say we won't do
that anymore you guys can smoke and grow
all the weed you want it's [ __ ] weird
how paper works i love it let's keep
going obviously i'm stoned it says
anyway i have fallen in love with the
plant the plant culture and how to grow
it dude welcome to my world
i am passionate about cannabis uh it
keeps me smiling it keeps me medicated
it keeps me feeling good it builds a
good community i've built a business and
a lifestyle around it so i completely
know how you feel brother welcome to the
club thanks for joining us uh it says uh
it is therapeutic for me it is the most
therapeutic uh growing it is more
therapeutic than smoking cannabis in my
opinion it says my question is a little
different and i like different questions
it says how do you manage the personal
aspect of this process i mean socially
when you meet somebody new how do you
introduce this into the conversation it
is legal for me and i have 10 of your
strains and i'm debating which one to
pop in my next run that's a ramble but
if it's a commitment to grow this plant
properly and i don't want but it is a
commitment to grow the plant properly
and i don't want to have to constantly
come up with excuses i'm just curious
what your thoughts may
be
well
there's a couple of ways to go about
that it seems like the question is how
do you bring up cannabis in your uh
conversations in your social circle and
then also how do you bring up that you
grow cannabis in your social circle
right now
the best bet is to just not talk about
it keep your mouth shut uh feel it feel
things out check the temperature see how
people are see what the climate's like
where you are um
maybe ask some baited questions don't be
too obvious don't get yourself set up
for anything but maybe when you're in
your social circle when you're in your
group be like you see they legalized
weed and you're gonna get answers from
people that's all you have to do is
bring it up or just be somewhere and let
them bring it up if you don't want to
spark that conversation that's funny
spark that conversation that was not on
purpose if you don't want to spark that
conversation let them bring it up
they'll talk about it potheads love to
talk about pot you love to talk about
pot so much you're emailing me to talk
about pot to ask about how to talk about
pot so someone's going to bring it up
dude don't worry somebody will bring it
up
maybe you don't want to be that guy
you're
growing you're producing you've got some
stuff to lose don't tell people that you
don't know trust and probably love don't
even tell people that you're growing
there's no need for people to know that
you're growing even if it is legal it's
still a profitable profitable commodity
it's still a lot of work
people may want to steal it from you
people may want to just [ __ ] with you
just because maybe they don't like you
from high school still and now they know
you grow weed they want to make [ __ ] go
wrong because they don't like you and
they don't like weed now you're a target
be careful don't tell anybody that you
don't need to tell if they don't know
it's there they don't know it's there uh
yeah if that's the bottom line if they
don't know it's there they don't know
it's there if they don't know what's up
they can't do anything about it so
there's gonna be two different
boundaries here who are you going to
talk about uh there may be three
different boundaries who do we talk
about cannabis with who do we get
political and have fun conversations and
make them part of the team and be like
hey i want to talk about weed and weed
politics find some of those people then
we're going to have another layer of
people who do we actually smoke with
like because that's going to come up
once they start saying hey do you see
there's legal weed one person in that
group is gonna go [ __ ] yeah i'm so glad
it's legal i've been wanting to smoke
and that conversation is gonna happen
don't don't say around everybody like
we'll go smoke later bro save that wait
until you break off into your own little
groups or something and those people
that don't smoke or they were not with
the right ideas with you when they walk
away then stick around and be like hey
bro let's let's burn one tomorrow after
work or whatever you guys will figure it
out weed heads unite that's why you're
here you've already found us so don't
tell anybody that doesn't need to know
now you're going to find your social
circle to talk about it you're going to
find your smoking circle then who are
you going to share the grow with uh
everybody knows i grow because of who i
am and where i am and how uh what i've
been for this community that sounded
really egotistical what i've been for
this community uh how outspoken i have
been for this community i had uh i was
involved in the first dispensary in my
city i've been on the news smoking weed
news cameras have been at the [ __ ]
house where we smoked and [ __ ] uh people
know who i am and what i do that's why
i've got to follow the damn rules so
closely now but uh i kind of wish i
wasn't under the spotlight so much
sometimes uh under the magnifying glass
because
i will be a very good example if i need
to be so i've got to follow the rules
very carefully
so don't make it known that you're
growing unless you need to
don't tell i don't know if you're
married single got kids if you got a dog
my advice right now is just tell the dog
the dog's the only one that needs to
know you and the dog that's that's such
the greatest secret that you've got
maybe you're gonna make friends with
somebody who's really super cool and one
day you'll feel like it's time to share
that garden but
let that be like your secret zen thing
that you've got that's your new your new
secret just your new little zone in
there when i was growing illegally
before growing was fully legal it was
kind of like my little thing like i was
like yeah i'm in here doing this and
nobody can know about it's kind of fun
to have a little private project a
little secret thing um
if you have to make excuses
uh who are you making excuses to are you
making excuses to go burn one are you
making excuses because you've got to go
water that's one of the struggles of
being a grower is having to sneak away
like i got to go check on my [ __ ]
plants like here in colorado we look at
our phone and we say oh my pulse monitor
went off excuse me i've got to go take
care of my plants that's my way out of a
conversation or out of a boring
situation you're gonna have to find the
opposite you're like oh [ __ ] my plants
have an issue i gotta figure out how to
get out of here you're like my dog just
called me i gotta go take care of my dog
um excuses are gonna be harder to find
but be creative try to take care of the
plants uh early in the morning before
everybody else is up before work so you
can get in there take care of those
plants nobody will interrupt you uh
nobody's trying to get your attention
you're not uh cutting out of other time
when people think you should be
somewhere else uh but if you got to do
too much sneaky [ __ ] that's when you got
to kind of think about what you're doing
also
so
coming up with excuses mainly just keep
your mouth shut bro there's no need to
tell everybody about it not even your
girlfriend not your best friends what
happens if you and that girl break up
and she knows that girl is there she may
cause some problems for you
that could be a big deal what if you
tell your bro and one day he decides
he's not your bro anymore
like [ __ ] goes wrong man so be careful
um you're my age you got some years on
you i'm 42 as well uh so maybe hopefully
you got some wisdom by now hopefully you
got a good group of friends maybe a
trusty friend circle but still
these types of things change circles and
it's a new market where you are there so
be very very careful be very careful um
man and maybe uh you maybe want to get
in on the ground floor of these new
businesses you sound like a smart person
and you're growing and you need people
to talk to i just got the idea open up a
social smoking club or a dispensary
that's for you brother that's where you
meet all kinds of people to talk to and
that's also how you make a business out
of something you love and then it gets
legal and then you don't even have to
explain it to people they'll go that's
the guy with the dispensary downtown and
they'll be providing a service that
makes you feel good that you're
passionate about and that's what life is
all about that came to me at the end of
that message i'm glad i let that one
come through me all right uh bro thank
you for the great message i hope i
answered that question uh how do i
handle the social aspect of this uh let
it evolve naturally and mostly to keep
your mouth shut don't tell too many
people because um it's fun to smoke with
other people but it sounds like you've
been smoking by yourself for a long time
and that you can keep doing that bro and
tell somebody until somebody else admits
that they're a smoker then bring them in
uh kyle thank you brother it's a great
message i look forward to uh taking a
fat dab with you someday all right man
let's move on to the next message this
one came from a friend who is calling
themselves trike man i don't know that
if i ever that i've ever met trikeman
before sounds like a super cool
superhero name uh big shout out to trike
man i'm trying to picture your superhero
costume it's definitely sticky
it gets amber as you get [ __ ] angry
or super powered starts off clear and
your power builds up and starts getting
amber that's what trike man would do in
my mind i told you i took some dabs and
i'm high all right let's read this
message it says i hope all is well buddy
obviously things are well bro it's a
little bit warm other than that things
are ivory it says big ups to the irie
army it's trikeman here and i got a
little question about stabilizing
genetics with reversing females
that is a great topic sounds like a big
mouthful but it's really not that much
to think about uh stabilizing genetics
uh basically the goal i think when you
are talking about stabilizing is growing
a population of seeds and hoping that
they come out uniform they look the same
that's what i think you're saying when
you say stabilizing genetics and then
with reversing females so that is taking
a female plant and using silver
thiosulfate or
colloidal silver to induce that plant to
create pollen sacs and then pollinating
female plants with that which i do like
the idea that is a very good way to
stabilize and lock in traits without
opening up pandora's box
says so here's a little example of what
i am curious about say i start by making
my cross with a male and a female all
right we've got a plant uh next i search
for what my goal in that breeding
project was all right so we've got the
phenotype that was our goal that's
beautiful then from there i want to
reverse that female that i selected and
breed that to itself
that so now we've made a plant that is
beautiful this is a very common thing we
made some seeds we found a plant that's
beautiful now our friend wants to
take two clones of this plant so we're
basically going to cut a branch here and
a branch here and we got two cuts of the
same plant we're going to reverse one
using the reversal method that i've
talked about in previous episodes either
silver thiosulfate or colloidal silver
then we're going to put the pollen that
comes from that plant onto the other
plant so we've just reversed one
pollinated one we have now made an s1 or
maybe a feminized f1 some people may say
we're going to talk about that in depth
in the future here maybe get some other
folks on the show but i digress so um
i'm going to catch up in the message
search for what my goal was uh from
there i want to reverse that female and
breed it to itself makes perfect sense
so far my question is do i breed the
next generation to the first generation
i reverse the first time or do i reverse
the next generation and cross it to a
clone of itself again and keep doing
that or keep reading the next generation
to the first female i selected and
reversed uh thank you for everything you
do buddy i hope you feel irie about the
rest of your days respect from trikeman
big respect bro this is a great question
i've got a couple of good answers my
first answer is
yes
do all that [ __ ] do all of it um
that's how you're gonna find what works
the best is do all of that now i do have
some more in-depth answers to this
because i know you want more details
uh you want to
you want to continue breeding with this
now
excuse all the thrill clearing i've been
talking about those dabs now we're at
the phase where they [ __ ] up my throat
so what you've got is a feminized f1 or
it's an s1 because it's been self uh
that is going to be fairly uniform or
fairly stable in my experience
if you've selected good plants or a good
plant is what this would be
you're probably going to get
approximately 50 to 70 percent of your
plants that look like your starter plant
and then
probably
50 is a possibility but 50 to 30 of
those plants are going to look a little
bit like the mother that was used to
make that plant and the father that was
used to make that plant so you're gonna
have a pretty good lock in already on
your first cross when we uh start doing
the next cross is when we kind of unlock
weird [ __ ] sometimes we get um
f2 variation is when you start seeing
weird things when you do breeding so you
do the f1 you get that hybrid vigor uh
you do the f2 sometimes you'll find uh
plants that outperform the original
cross you find good parent stock from f2
and make the f3 and that's when you
really start locking in those uh the
stability those traits that you're
looking for uh the uniformity is what
the word i think i was looking for so
you may open up pandora's box and make
[ __ ] go weird by doing more breeding to
this uh reversed f1 or this s1 that
you've got so you do have two very
useful very viable options uh that you
could have great success with you could
either take uh two of those s ones or
it's an f1 yeah it's a self f1 uh we're
still debating on the names of and the
lettering and labeling of all this uh so
you could take a batch of those seeds
and grow them and find a male and a
female or i guess find an ideal female
in there or you could find an idea of
two females and you could cross that
however you'd like you could find one
and resell fit or you can find
two and cross those together and make
the next generation however you'd like
or you can do that back cross you can
take
something from the second generation and
put it back to that first generation you
made or back to one of those parents now
here is something that i don't talk
about a lot but here's something i
discovered on accident i took a plant
and it was a beautiful plant it was
amazing i loved it it was everything i
was looking for in a plant
i reversed it i made feminized uh f1s or
s1s out of that plant so i've got my
feminized seed stock and i did sort of
what you're thinking about doing i found
the winner out of that number nine was
the keeper
i took number nine
and then i took the original pollen from
the first making of that seed and i
pollinated number nine with the pollen
from its mom so that reversed pollen
went on number nine it was basically the
mom went on to the daughter essentially
and the offspring that came from that
were labeled number 77 uh the good one
my favorite one that came out of that
was labeled number 77 i was calling the
whole batch the 77s uh that was related
to some other stuff is why i got that
number
and if you know why big shout out hey
now um
so number 77 would not reverse so
depending on what your goal is if you
want to keep moving forward you may be
stuck because i can't breed i couldn't
breed with 77 for a long time because it
wouldn't turn around i could not reverse
it to make pollen from it so i feel like
i trapped myself i cut off my breeding
project right there the way that i did
that i'll repeat that process because i
probably got your attention more now
i made the feminized cross just like you
did i took a plant took two clones uh
pollen and pollen receiver that made
seeds i took a seed from that batch and
i found a stellar keeper that looked a
lot like the original plant i started
with i took the pollen from the original
mom and put that onto the daughter plant
and the offspring the granddaughters
that came out that'd be mommy daughter
granddaughter at that point right the
granddaughters don't reverse i can't
flip them they don't if i spray them
with silver thiosulfate they don't react
the way that most plants react i feel
like i really locked in the uh feminized
side of that plant to where i can't even
get it to reverse now that's how
stubbornly feminized that plan is so be
careful you may
trap yourself you may end your breeding
right there you'll have to go backwards
you'll say well i can't reverse this
thing it won't flip uh you can you can
do all of these ways that you want to do
it it depends on the traits that you're
searching for um are the traits that
you're looking for so you've made the s1
or the feminized f1 are the traits
you're looking for showing uh very
commonly are they prominent are they
dominant are they popping up a lot so
deciding the next move is all about
where are the traits that you're looking
for do you see the trait you're looking
for in a lot of the seeds you've got
do you see the trait you're looking for
and the mother plant that you started
with do you see the traits you're
looking for maybe in the father plant
that was the original pollen donor in
the original non-feminized cross
what where is the trait what are you
looking for get that trait get that
ingredient and then breathe that
direction i wish i had a better uh more
solid answer but i don't know
which plants look the best and which
plants have your goal but that is the
plant you need um
you are on the right track you've got a
lot of good ideas and i know i said it
earlier the answer is yes and the answer
is to do all of this
it's really hard to decide what to do
sometimes i'm going to read it again and
see if i can give you a better
definitive answer but without looking at
the plants and without saying
this one's got that strawberry terp that
i'm after or this one's got that purple
color that i'm after it's hard to pick
for you but go for the plants that have
the traits which you were looking for
and then keep locking in that trait uh
and then deciding so yeah if you want to
move forward with the feminized
generations or go back to another plant
it where are the ingredients that you
need are they forward are they back
there somewhere do the seeds show you
what you want or do you need to put
another ingredient in there the only way
to figure it out really honestly is to
breed it and grow them i'm going to scan
over the message real quick and make
sure that i got the answer to this all
right i think i more than covered the
answer to this question
it's all about finding where the traits
are that you want to lock in and then
use those plants to create the results
that you want i think you'd find great
results in the s2 generation i also
think you'd find great results in the uh
it would be a reversed back cross i
think you'd find great results in both
of those it's all about your goal uh
play with both of them if you can
honestly you're going to have great
results with that very first feminized
cross that's when you're going to see
great results it's not going to be
wonky or problematic or anything like
that you're not going to find a bunch of
mutants unless unless your starting
plants were wonky and mutants but i
think uh you sound like a smart guy
it sounds like you probably did good
selection it sounds like you're thinking
ahead which is very great because a lot
of breeders don't do that but i think
you're on the right path
and i think uh it's just the plants are
gonna tell you man i wish i had a better
answer i wish i could tell you do uh
three shakes of this ingredient three
shakes of this and it'll work but it's
all about seeing those plants which way
do you need to go what are the plants
showing you what are the parents showing
you grow it all out see what you've got
get very familiar with all of the plants
and then you'll know what they're going
to do you'll just be able to tell like
if you grow this this female plant so
many times and this female plant so many
times and you cross this one to this one
and this one to this one and that one to
that one you'll start knowing what this
plant contributes to crosses and you'll
start being able to predict it it's
almost it almost becomes uh predictable
once you've bred with a bunch of plants
so many times all right uh my friend
trikeman thank you for the great
question bro i do look forward to the
response from this if you've got any
more follow-up questions please do ask i
feel like i got kind of carried away and
rambly
so i hope i was clear again i do look
forward to the reply the email address
of course you know it is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com
ladies gentlemen boys girls pimps hoes
friends foes smokers growers clone
cutters and pollen chuckers it is time
for me to wrap up this episode i want to
thank everybody once again for listening
to episode
668 of the grow from your heart podcast
it blows my mind every time i write down
a number like 668.
it's crazy to me that we've gotten this
far thank you for all of the support
once again if you have any questions
corrections comments or concerns you
know i would love to hear from you the
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com don't be shy i've been
enjoying the listener interaction it has
been a great time speaking of
interaction join us on discord when i
get done recording here i've gotta wait
for this camera and that camera to load
up to the computer it takes a little
while for them to load into the computer
before i can even begin to edit while
they load up i'm gonna go hang out in
discord take a couple of dabs check in
with the crew
show them some new merch designs that
i've got going so they're gonna see the
merch while i'm on the live feed hanging
out they'll get to approve uh disapprove
some things give me some feedback so
that's where i will be joining me on the
discord i may be there right now when
you're watching this check it out i
might be hanging out also make sure you
check out the patreon at patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart i
think that is all i've got for you make
sure you click like make sure you
subscribe click on that little
notification bell that way every time i
put out an episode you do get a
notification the episodes do come out at
midnight monday and at midnight thursday
that's uh 1201 monday and 1201 thursday
so check us out uh we will be on youtube
doing premieres i do hang out in the
chat on youtube sometimes i'm in the
chat on youtube chatting with the
friends watching the video happen and
i'm also in discord taking dabs with
those guys i'm also in another chat
hanging out so i try to be as
interactive as i can when i'm available
summer has had me busy not complaining i
love it comedy and concerts are back
look at my smile all right i'm getting
rambly once again big shout out to dabs
uh that is all i've got for this episode
you know i'll be back in a couple of
days with fresh new content i want to
give a big shout out to my friend girls
grow too and until next time take a fat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you