[Music]
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rosta jeff and this is episode
669 of the grow from your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to read a
couple of viewer emails before we get to
that part of the show let's do a few
shout outs to a few of the great folks
who support the show on patreon let's
start off with the big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out to
maroney let's send a big thank you shout
out to alan h and chandler w let's send
a big fist bump and a thank you shout
out to sensei mia let's send a thank you
to a new supporter growing tennessee
let's also send another thank you to
another new supporter sam heads dgc
let's send a big fist bump and a thank
you shout out to a longtime supporter my
friend riven waters let's send a big
fist bump to another friend and a
longtime supporter crazy hand grows then
let's wrap it all up with a big grow
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out to my buddy billy podonk big thanks
and big shout out to everybody who
continues to support the show on patreon
if you are not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need is right there on the screen and
you know i do include a link in the show
notes to make it nice and easy for all
of my friends
this is the part of the show where i do
invite you to the discord server that's
right there is an irie genetics grow
from your heart podcast discord server
and you are invited i would love to have
you there there's a link in the show
notes and the video description and we
recently added a link on the website
that's right if you go to the irie
genetics website at iregenetics.com
on the top of the website you will see a
link that says discord simply click on
that link and guess what you'll go right
to the discord server we do invite you
we do encourage you to join us and i
look forward to seeing you on the irie
genetics grow from your heart podcast
discord server i do want to send a big
thank you shout out to my buddy mobius
grows what's up bro big shout out and
big thank you for the great tester
update report video that's right my
buddy mobius is testing some seeds for
me he's got some new seeds he's running
a test grow and today i received a great
email with a detailed video he walks
around the grove and he says this is one
phenotype this is another these are some
traits each phenotype has these are
commonalities these are differences this
is what i'm feeding this is what i've
done this is what the room is like it
was like i was hanging out with my own
plants in his grow hanging out with my
babies in his grow hanging out with his
babies in his grow it was a great
experience that is great work from a
tester i do appreciate that i love that
sort of stuff so if you're testing for
me
please do send videos it was like a
facetime video with my kids or something
it's like here's the babies and i got to
see the kids at play playing in the
playground with each other looking
beautiful put a smile on my face so
mobius good work bro big fist bump i
wish more testers would be like you i'll
let's segue right into this part i will
need more testers very soon so if you've
been sending me uh tester applications
don't worry those are saved in a folder
i did not delete those throw those away
they're all in a folder
on the desktop so whenever i need some
testers just go right to the email open
up that folder and i can find all the
applicants in there go through find some
good candidates that i think may be a
tester if you have not already applied
to be a tester uh there's a full episode
about being a tester make sure you
listen to that episode then apply
following the instructions within that
episode i did talk recently about
genetics i do need to make an update uh
daz the guy that i knew that i had a
friendship with from mephistogenetics
has now started what is known as night
owl genetics make sure you check out
night owl genetics for your auto
flowering seeds needs i do support daz
great guy so make sure you check them
out if you're into the auto flowers
all right i do have a question uh here
in front of me
that i do want to address this is uh
comes from a previous episode in a
previous episode i read a question about
a commercial grow whose plants were
getting too tall they weren't finishing
on time uh people wanted to send me a
lot of suggestions a lot of ideas on
what to do with this grow we did receive
a lot of great input a lot of great
ideas however
there were a lot of small adjustments
and small details that weren't going to
make a big enough impact overall in this
commercial growth to make it worth the
time
uh energy
money and effort to make those changes
in this grow this is a commercial
environment think about uh if we're
gonna make a small adjustment in your
growth think about the time energy and
cost it takes to make it in your grow
and then think if we're going to do that
in a commercial environment it costs
100 times the cost to do that because
we're doing it if you're doing it to one
light we're doing it to a hundred we've
got to repeat the process a hundred
times we have to buy the equipment a
hundred times we have to take the
manpower or woman power to install or
adjust or adapt that new equipment we
have to test the equipment we have to
learn the equipment it takes a lot of
time to have people come in there a lot
of money a lot of energy and then in the
long run if you've got your personal
grow with two four one however many
small lights you've got going i'm not
downplaying your grumps and your
personal grow is a small grow that's
your girl in a commercial environment
we're doing things on an exponential
scale compared to what you've got going
at home in most cases and in a
commercial environment we're getting
very little return on our investment
after staffing after payroll after the
rent on the building the electricity on
the building licensing taxes packaging
transportation fees uh workmen's comp
lawyers the lawyer the accountant all of
that stuff eats into all of our profit
and hopefully it's just you uh your
trimming partner and hopefully the
lawyer is all that you've got to pay
hopefully you got that lawyer on
retainer take care of that if you're
growing everybody growing should have a
lawyer no matter what you're doing i
should have a lawyer anyway but my point
is that at a home grow
your return on investment is much
greater and our return on investment in
a commercial growth is much smaller
because we have much more expenses many
more expenses so making small
adjustments like that are much uh more
costly than it would be in a small
environment we've got to repeat it a
hundred times if we have a hundred
lights there were some great
recommendations uh things like changing
the light spectrum and
changing the temperature in the night
things like that that would help but not
uh to the uh the degree which we need
help in this commercial environment
those plants were obviously being
flowered
being veg for two or three weeks too
long they were getting too big they just
needed to be done sooner uh we couldn't
it was a commercial environment people
said raise the fans raise the lights
it's a commercial grow bro we probably
got three foot tall tables 12 foot
lights 18-foot ceilings we've maxed out
with what we can do we can't just raise
the lights
we can't go around and put blue lights
up everywhere uh the commer then then
where's the profit if you got a
commercial girl then where did the
profit go there are 100 lights you gotta
replace half of them with blue bulbs
that's 50 bulbs you got to buy they're
100 each you do the math on there that's
500 i know that's not a real number i'm
hoping you're paying attention all right
so there were a lot of great ideas but
most of them are not feasible the main
solution to that is better scheduling
the plants were too big we know they're
too big they're repeatedly too big
they're growing into the lights they're
going into the fans the easy logical
solution is flower earlier have smaller
plants don't grow them so damn big
they're more manageable they're healthy
less time on the road is less time for a
crash also if those plants are only in
the room for a total of like four weeks
of veg and [ __ ] nine weeks of flower
that's two or three weeks less
opportunity for powdery mildew spider
mites thrips fungus gnats over watering
ph lockout power failures other weird
[ __ ] to go on because in a commercial
environment
all things that can go wrong will until
you get the facility dialed in and
everything is perfect things will go and
then things will continue to go wrong
because pumps will go out power will
fail like air conditioners will fail
weird shit's going to happen all the
time you've got to adjust and adapt i've
talked about that enough
so that's a good setup for this one
message that i did get i've been talking
quite a bit uh this one says rosta jeff
question on what you said on not being
able to shorten the flowering phase yes
on that episode i did say that we can't
shorten the flowering phase the plants
have to flower for their nine or ten
weeks until they're finished and that we
should shorten the veg phase because
then you make you just start with
smaller plants you don't grow them as
big and they don't finish as big it
makes sense to me but this one was a
great question it says isn't that what
new millennium winter frost claims to do
on the dude grow show i think jaren the
new millennium guy said you can get
different strains to finish at the same
time
um yes the new millennium product uh the
winter frost product from new millennium
will cause the plants to go into their
finishing stage a little more quickly
they will start ripening they will go
into senescence a little bit sooner when
you feed them that product they will be
triggered uh there's something in there
that tells them hey it's the end it's
time to go uh to the end phase
but would you rather have a room that's
proper or would you rather have to feed
a product that is going to trigger the
finishing like a you could put a
band-aid on it and spend all kinds of
money on this product or you could fix
the schedule and do it right and also
this product isn't going to cut two or
three weeks off this may cut five maybe
seven days maybe ten at the most but
it's not going to cut that many days off
your full cycle and the grow we were
talking about it sounded like they
needed two maybe three full weeks cut
off of their process so that's a great
idea to use the new millennium winter
frost but it's not going to be a drastic
enough change now speaking of drastic
changes here's another great thing we
can talk about diurnal temperature
swings if we narrow down that swing if
we don't have more than five degrees
between our day and night swing and
maybe five or ten percent humidity
between our day and night swing that
will help with the stretch that initial
stretch into the flowering phase that
may help that may be a way to do it
popping and twisting the stems
cracking the branches that may be one
way to do it but overall the ultimate
solution as a as the consultant who sees
the overall problem as an experienced
grower who's been in these commercial
facilities the answer to that was just
flower earlier why are you going to grow
10 foot tall plants if you've only got a
14 foot ceiling grow
5 foot tall plants flower them out
they'll be 10 feet tall you've got 4
feet of extra space think ahead plan
ahead we talked about that before be
successful all right let me hit my notes
here recap myself get myself back on
track make sure we're doing this right
um yes question about winterfrost we
covered that okay now i do have more
emails in front of me do i want to give
this person a shout out do they want
their name said this one if they did not
leave their name
um but big shout out you know who you
are thank you for sparking great content
i do want to keep moving i'm awful
rambly today so i do need to keep myself
on track
all right i'm not sure if this message
is trolling me or if this was 100
serious i'm going to read it anyway if
you're trolling me uh good job and if
you're not trolling me uh listen this
time it goes on it says hey ross to jeff
i'm growing a few of your strains and
i'm just curious when to start counting
flowering days do i start at light
switch of 1212 or when i start seeing
pre-flowers then it goes on here's the
best part i heard on an episode that you
said you start counting at the light
switch
that's what i said bro you i start
counting at the light switch is this
correct or should i add some weeks keep
up the good work and i will continue to
work with you and your company
um my friend saul you heard me right i'm
gonna say it again i always start
counting flowering days on an indoor
grow the day i flip the lights to 1212.
all right i'm going to look into this
camera say it at another angle
i always and i recommend you always
start counting flowering days in an
indoor grow from the day you flip the
lights to 12 12. if you do a unique
creative fancy flowering light cycle
like maybe 11 13 or something like that
start counting the day you change that
timer to 12 12 or 11 13 that is day one
of flower don't adjust that don't play
with that that is day one
why would we
put
63 days of flowering and then you start
flowering on this day but then subtract
14 days or add 14 days i didn't put a
math problem on the package it says nine
weeks of flowering so the day you start
flowering is day one at the end of nine
weeks not at the start of nine weeks
either people say i've gone eight full
weeks i'm gonna chop down tomorrow i say
you've got the ninth week to go and they
say week nine is tomorrow and i go hey
you still got to you've got to finish
that week you've got to finish the ninth
week if it says nine to ten weeks let it
go 10 completed weeks 70 days so you've
got to let it finish
so the plants are going to take 9 to 10
weeks from the day you flip that timer
to 12 12. when you go in there and you
change the timer from 9 pm on to 9 a.m
off you are not 12 hours off 12 hours on
in your 24 hour day
that is day one of flowering write it
down take a screenshot on your phone
make some sort of a note that says day
one of flowering is today this day maybe
get a piece of duct tape and write that
date on the piece of duct tape and stick
that duct tape on the door or possibly
on the pot of the plant that you were
flowering keep that note somewhere that
you will find it that you will not
forget i've got weird ocd i like to
flower on the first that way i know that
in two months the next first on that
third month will be when i'm harvesting
so if i start flowering january first we
got all of january we got all of
february march 1st i got a crop so that
means that a little bit before march 1st
i need to get my next crop coming up
just planning thinking like that so um
i've been going on for a long time about
this i don't know how many times i can
say it i don't know how else to stress
it um
flowering day one starts the day that
you flip the timer to 12 12. if you're
outdoors that's a different environment
that's a different thing we don't know
when we change the timer to 12 12 then
pay attention your trichomes pay
attention to the plants it's all about
watching the plants most of the time
anyway i was going to segue into that so
that's a great way to do it
the calendar is a great thing my
recommendation on the seed package is a
great thing but there will be variables
like always in life there will be
variables you've got to pay attention to
your trichomes the trichomes on your
plant are what indicate ripeness when
those trichomes are turning amber some
people like different ratios
i'm going to say somewhere between 20
and 30 amber trichomes on your plant
that is that is when it is a good time
to harvest the trichomes are the thing
that contain the active ingredient the
active compounds which give us a buzz
that make us stoned that contain thc cbd
cbn cbg all of the other wonderful
cannabinoids we're seeking those are all
in our trichome let's get the trichome
right that's what we're after we are
trichome farmers a lot of people think
they're growing big beautiful plants
that's what you're growing the main
thing you are working on is beautiful
trichomes we want those trichomes now
since i'm on this path this rant ah
pistols or you guys call them hairs the
hairs do not have anything with
indication of ripeness those hairs those
pistols are the breeding parts of the
plant those things can change colors a
lot of people will say when the hairs
turn brown or when the pistols turn
brown that's when the plants are
finished that is false that is wrong
that is inaccurate those parts are for
breeding those parts of the plant can be
damaged destroyed withered
ruined from all kinds of things a spray
will make your pistols can make your
pistols of your plants turn brown and
wither up
wind can do it your skin oil touching it
can do it that plant just passing up its
point of peak pollination can do it
those plants only want pollen for so
long into their life they're just like
people they have a time when they can
reproduce and then that time expires and
when that time expires on a plant the
pistols turn brown and dry up and wither
up and shrink in
some people will say at that point this
plant is ready for harvest
those people would be wrong those
pistols those hairs do not have any
indicator any indication anything to do
with the ripeness of your plant we are
trichome farmers we want ripe trichomes
unless you're breeding for seeds
trichomes are all you should be
measuring ripeness by if you're breeding
for seeds then of course measure by the
hardness and ripeness of the seeds
inside of that plant so
that was a good rant for the same
question i've been asked a lot of times
this one pops up at least once a month
i'm hoping uh and this person has
already heard it this is the gonna be
the third time that they've heard me say
that you set your timer to 12 12 and
that is day one of flowering that's when
you start counting flowering days if i
wrote 10 weeks on the seed package that
means you've got to let it finish week
10 don't let it go to week 10 and cut it
down let it go through week 10 and cut
it down possibly for funsies let it go a
little bit longer
all right now since we're on this uh
sort of a path this topic here here's
something funny that i see on social
media all the time and i understand why
you're doing it i understand what
inspires
this sort of a thought process but i
think that this is funny a lot of times
on social media i will see something
that says something like uh i'm only two
weeks away from week nine which means
you are in week seven so just say i'm in
week seven don't like i'm only two weeks
away from week nine yeah i get it that
you want to make it sound like you're
further for your mind you're tricking
yourself to think i am only this far
away but just be realistic with yourself
just say
i am in the end of week six a lot of
people are saying i'm two weeks away
from week nine and they're technically
in the end of week six be realistic with
yourself
uh that way you have realistic
expectations you know your timeline i
get it it's like little kids saying uh
it's only one month till christmas i'm
i'm only 24 days away till christmas i
get it i get it but but let's not get
too excited for christmas let's be
patient let's look at it realistically
that just makes me giggle on social
media when i see that sort of stuff
nothing personal uh no hatred just makes
me laugh uh let's see what the next
message is that message did come from
our friend saul big thanks to saul ah
dude 12 12 is the day you flip that
timer or day one is the day
you flip that timer to 12 12. i will get
refocused here and work on the next
message
this one comes from another friend who
calls themselves heaven and hell
and their question says hey hey hey
master rasta jeff the man with the magic
breath i didn't know that that was a
thing but that is a great way to start a
message what's up bro good to meet you
that is one hell of an intro it says i
was wondering what nutrient line you
would recommend for your top three
brands please that is a great question
that is an ever evolving ever-changing
question for me because i do
get to try a lot of different products i
get scent free things i get sent samples
i get asked to try things my friends
give me a lot of input and a lot of
feedback on products they're using uh
when i was working in a lot of
commercial environments i had a lot of
space and places to experiment with new
stuff
i keep going back to a few of the same
things so let's talk about the top three
that i would recommend for a very long
time i was having great success with the
botanic hairline i was using botanicaire
pureblend pro liquid karma the calmag
uh the silica blast the hydra guard or
hydroplex maybe both
um
there's another one then a couple other
great products there's a bloom booster
that i can't think of the name of right
now they had a few other products that
they were adding to their mix then i
would add a couple other key things of
course i always add a couple of stuff
whenever i get a a brand i like to add a
couple of things but i was having great
success with botanicare
um unfortunately there were some
political reasons why i chose to kind of
sway away from botanica it was mainly
political reasons and i was seeing great
success with another brand let's talk
about the other brand the other brand i
switched to that i have great success
with and i still use on a regular basis
is new millennium bottled nutrients i
think new millennium is great uh the way
it's formulated the way it's uh just the
way it's measured out it's easy to work
with
it makes the plants grow with great
vigor they come out good potency they
taste good they finish on time they've
got products that help us finish they've
got products that help them root
the way the nutrients are broken down
and the bottles are broken down makes a
lot of sense their nutrient calculator
and schedule is easy to follow uh jiren
and neil are good people they've got
good customer service and honestly
nobody pays me uh to talk about this i
don't have big jugs of new millennium
bottles sitting around or anything like
that i'll actually bump into jiren at a
couple of concerts this weekend and
we'll say what's up and give each other
a fist bump and won't talk about
business at all so they do not pay me to
advertise their brand they don't give me
free stuff they did give me a free hat
and i've gotten a few free bottles but
it's not uh it's there's nothing they
don't pay me to advertise i'm saying
it's good [ __ ] i have to buy it and i
still go buy it at the groce store most
of the time so
new millennium good [ __ ] uh it's easy to
understand also
botanicare is a good product i switched
using it because mainly for political
reasons if you aren't too worried about
uh dollars and ethics and political
stuff botanicare makes a great product
just think about where your money's
going maybe pay attention to that sort
of stuff on the botanicare website they
have a great nutrient calculator you can
type in which bottles you've got how
many weeks of veg you expect to do how
many weeks of flour you expect and it
will tell you every week what to feed
those plants and that makes it very easy
so there are two brands that i really
enjoyed using that was botanicare and
new millennium i also had good
experience with vegbloom from hydroponic
research they make a lot of good
products i think that is a great product
for a commercial grow environment i've
talked a lot about veg bloom and
commercial grow environments really good
stuff i know you asked for three but i
also want to recommend biobiz biobiz
makes an affordable product very easy to
use and the product that your finished
flowers will taste so good with biobiz
good [ __ ]
now with all of that being said let me
make a couple of recommendations
you may be very limited with what is
available to you in your area i don't
know if you're shopping online i don't
know if you're shopping at a local
hydroponic store or a gardening center
or whatever is available where you are
if you're going to the store to get what
is available i recommend you shop around
and get what is there on the shelf so
you don't have to pay extra for shipping
shipping costs are expensive sending
bottles of water across the country can
get ridiculous maybe find something at
the local grow store that will suit your
needs
maybe do some research on brands i was
talking earlier that one brand i really
enjoyed i switch because of political
and other reasons maybe read about who
is attached to who who are the parent
companies who are the umbrella companies
to that company if that matters to you
pay attention to that sort of stuff it
may be easier for you to find products
locally they may be more reliable it may
be easier for you to build your arsenal
up that way slowly over time locally
than it would be to have stuff shipped
maybe you can't have grow products
shipped straight to your house sometimes
if you order bottles of grow nutrients
it will come just as that bottle of grow
nutrients with plastic wrap wrapped
around it and then some sort of security
tape around the the lid so it doesn't
come popped open so the whole
neighborhood knows you just got a bottle
of whatever pureblend pro organic tea
sitting on the front porch until you got
home from work it just sat out there all
day who knows who drove by who knows who
was walking the dogs and saw that who
knows how many other neighborhood kids
walked by and they grow weed too and
they know what the [ __ ] you got now they
know that you grow weed so that's
something to think about where are you
going to source your products where are
they going to come from can you get it
at your local groce store
there was something else i wanted to add
to that the nutrient calculators go look
at all of the nutrient calculators and
nutrient schedules on line check out the
website for the brand that you intend to
use
try to stick with if you're picking a
brand i say that i like adding stuff try
to start with the brand and like if
you're going to use let's just say that
you're going to use new millennium
new millennium actually sells a great
starter pack
get that starter pack and use their
website for their nutrient calculator
and feed it like it says on the nutrient
calculator if you can't get all of the
stuff
on your wish list start with the basics
that you need now you need like a base
are you in veg or in bloom get your
bases for that then get your cal mag
then get your rooting supplements then
get your bloom boosters and just add
them over time and then after you
harvest maybe if your next run get a
couple of more bottles if you didn't run
out think of it as every time you go to
the store you can get one or two more
bottles like when you were a kid you're
just trying to expand your lego sets or
whatever you're doing get another game
for the playstation think of it like
that now just invest in new bottles
every time you go then find a brand that
you like if you decide you don't like it
it's okay to switch there's no problem
with brand loyalty in this industry you
can switch brands you can switch
mid-grow if you really want to the
plants don't care as long as they're
getting fed and getting what they need
the plants may be happier if you switch
if you went from a shitty product to a
better product they're eating better
they may be happier but learn a product
see if you like it run a crop or two
with that run a crop or two with other
stuff maybe if you can afford the space
and the products and the time and the
energy maybe do two side-by-sides maybe
do a new millennium run and uh whatever
a botanical run and maybe um a bio biz
run and then some other brand that's
local at your store that's available do
those runs all together and see what
works best for you i know you asked for
three i'm going to say
new millennium bottle nutrients
botanicare and
hydroponic research is veg bloom
products that's probably my top three
favorites the veg bloom is my favorite
for commercial growing if i wasn't doing
commercial growing i'd probably swap
that one out with biobiz for my third
reply all right i think i've been
rambling on for long enough it feels
like i need a drink so i'm going to
start wrapping up this show i want to
thank my buddy heaven hell for the great
message you have any questions
corrections comments or concerns you
know i would love to hear from you the
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com don't be shy send me your
feedback send me your questions let me
know what you think you know i love
creating listener generated content if
you've got a question out there send it
to me i'll answer it on the show that
means i'm at least helping you i'm
probably helping a few other people if
you have got that question don't forget
about the patreon
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart
all the information is right there on
the screen of course there is a website
at
iregenetics.com on that website there
now is a link to the official irie
genetics grow from your heart discord
join the discord hangout tap in is what
i think the cool kids say all right
ladies and gentlemen boys girls pimps
hoes friends foes smokers growers clone
cutters pollen chuckers all of you
beautiful cannabis enthusiasts out there
i want to thank you once again for
listening to episode
669 of the grow from your heart podcast
you know i'll be back in a couple of
days with fresh fresh new content let's
send a big shout out to my buddy
greybeard and until next time take a fat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you