[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis Community
it's time for episode number 67 of the
grow from your heart podcast your source
for Cannabis News education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower if you're professional grower
if you're a new smoker or a hardcore
Dabber if you're a cannabis activist or
even someone who's just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you thanks
for joining me I'm your host roster Jeff
as always I need to send a huge thank
you shout out to the Mystic Roots band
for letting me use their music on the
show big thanks to cat CP and the entire
Mystic Roots crew what's up guys I'm
sitting at the table with my good buddy
Clint how you doing Clint I'm doing good
Jeff what's up brother I'm hanging out
man I'm going to turn down that music
that's kind of loud in the headphones
there yeah we're we're good man we're
good dude I love the ree real loud in
the ear if it's too loud you're too old
y'all yeah you can turn down the volume
on your
phone I don't know yeah yeah there you
go uh let's read some ads real quick so
we can get that out of the way uh this
podcast is brought to you by my friends
at Hy gr indoor growing supplies H gr
indoor growing supplies has two
locations to serve Colorado visit the
Denver store 6271 Beach Street or check
out the peblo location on 618 East 4th
Street in beautiful peblo Colorado check
out High gr for competitive pricing and
a great selection of indoor grow
supplies get your favorite nutrients at
high grow indoor growing supplies big
shout out to burn and Jesse when you're
uh at H gr make sure you let them know
you listen to The Grow from your heart
podcast and they will give you
commercial pricing on your entire
purchase that's a sweet hookup uh the
organic portions of this podcast are
brought to you by my friends at the
Rocky Mountain worm company visit the
Rocky Mountain worm company in Colorado
Springs for fresh worm castings African
nightcrawlers red wigglers and all of
your organic soil amendments the Rocky
Mountain worm company has dragonfly
Earth medicine products in stock right
now uh the Rocky Mountain worm company
will ship to your door you can get the
same worm castings that I use in my
garden and many of the same amendments
that I use through www. rockymountainmc
company.com check that out today and if
you visit the store it's at 411 Tiana
Street in Colorado Springs Colorado make
sure you tell them you heard about them
through the podcast big shout out to Jay
also a big shout out to Nature's green
remedies.com thanks for their support
all the time I don't have a coupon code
for you this month uh much respect to
all the sponsors that make the show
possible if one of you are interested in
sponsoring the podcast send me an email
it's grow fromyou heart hotmail.com I'll
get you all the information that you
need so Clint's back at the table he got
himself some water he got me some water
I appreciate it um Clint and I had the
pleasure to uh go to a couple of comedy
shows over the past week you said this
is coming out in a couple weeks yes this
one we'll put it out on a Wednesday this
will be like the 1st or the 29th or
something of May I feel it hey everybody
uh just so you know Mother's Day May
10th there you go don't [ __ ] forget
it's your mom you love her yes take a
fat dad give your mom a hug for me and
Mother's Day buy the [ __ ] some flowers
that's right I'm just thinking ahead yes
I'm I'm helping out every single one of
us Stoner boys it's like oh [ __ ] I would
have forgot I'm trying to at least maybe
you guys already have it good heads up
dude this will be out before Mother's
Day you guys don't forget don't [ __ ] it
up love your mom that's where you came
from that's my one that's my sponsor is
your mom like that's that's who I'm
trying to get to promote not my mom your
mom nope everybody's mom just like hey
mother earth there you go all right uh
that's already an awkward story so May
10 May 10th is Mother's Day and we get
to brag do you know what we're doing May
10th bro I do know what we're doing May
10th Clint and I will be seeing Doug
Benson uh hosting his podcast Doug Loves
Movies at Comedy Works my favorite
comedy club on the damn Planet the only
comedy club that's worth a [ __ ] unless
unless you're going to a different one
yeah unless unless the next one we go to
will be worth a [ __ ] and then we'll talk
no I love the Denver Improv so I have to
back that place up that place was
[ __ ] sweet but Comedy Works is my
favorite comedy club on the planet that
I've ever been to it's awesome it's
amazing we get to see Doug Benson there
May 10th recording his podcast Doug
Loves Movies Doug Loves Movies yes if
you guys are into Doug binon check that
out um I do need to give you a quick
apology sorry about the Growers meeting
uh I had very short notice that that was
not going to happen uh The Growers
meeting didn't happen if you guys showed
up um I'm in my house right now it's the
time of the meeting we're here recording
taking dabs it's about 710 yeah yeah
this is when the meeting should be
happening but I got a free time some
free time so we came here and recorded a
podcast I apologize um I don't work for
hyro I was just simply trying to help
them out I was advertising I don't know
what happened I don't know why they
couldn't do it I hope everything is cool
with those guys I love them big shout
out to burn everybody at hygro burn and
Jesse I apologize we'll get another
meeting together it will happen I won't
do this to you guys again um so let's
get on with what we were saying Doug
Benson we get to see him May 10th uh I'm
going to start it off by saying this I
really hope he does a better show than
he did when we saw him Monday night yeah
dude that was um we we went up uh I took
a buddy of mine Jeff uh came up as well
and then uh so shout out to my buddy
Drew uh cuz he'll be listening dude
shout out to my friend Danielle that's
right uh I ended up uh realizing I had a
plus one available for the comedy show
and I called her about two and a half
hours before the show and I said if you
can get your cute little ass to Denver
in the next from peblo from peblo uh to
the restaurant where we're all going to
eat I will order you food and have a
plate of food waiting for you by the
time you get there you can grub down and
we got to get to the show and I told her
please be here by this time and she made
it 5 minutes early dude yeah uh shout
out to a girl that got ready got herself
beautiful and drove to Denver in two and
a half hours ladies it's possible you
can do it I'm proud of you so big shout
out to Danielle thanks for doing that I
appreciate it I'm glad you got to come
to the show with us so uh and also shout
out to your friend that you brought with
us man drew the first time I got to meet
him and he seems like a fun guy we have
common friends so we're definitely going
to hang out and Tak dad oh yeah yeah you
guys were talking about him that was
cool you know some some cannabis people
that's peblo too but it's the same thing
as like uh I just we're one degree of
separation from everybody one degree of
Kevin Bacon from every single person the
truth that's the truth so shout out to
Drew is good meeting you bro glad to
meet you we're definitely going to hang
out and take some dabs together uh I saw
the picture of Drew's car right home it
looks like you took a little nappy poo
bro well fortunately it was after the
show we got to the car uh but Drew you
did pass the [ __ ] out and it was
hilarious to watch like well he kept he
kept like trying to like lay over on to
me as I'm driving I kept having to like
of him back like Get over either that or
finish the job you started there you go
suck my dick your your front your car
has got those big couch seats so I'm
sure he was just thinking he's cuddled
up on the couch with you that's that it
is the the most comfortable seats you've
ever ridden out I don't know about that
it's pretty comfortable buddy his car is
a boat you guys it's you could go on a
cruise in Clint's car that's right
everybody coming out for the cruise
we'll be going uh May 10th Mother's Day
I don't know um no there's no Cruise
anyways so we got to see Doug and and we
were um um front row we were front row I
want to give a shout out to the Mellow
Mushroom and Kelo Marley that's right
we've made friends with this lovely
waitress at the Mellow Mushroom she is a
fellow grower she is an extract artist
she has a [ __ ] cool dog named Zephyr
yeah uh so shout out to Kelo shout out
to shout out to Zephyr hope you guys are
doing great I hope you listening are
listening to this episode they told me
she told me that they listen to the
podcast so I hope they're checking it
out uh she's she's not only an awesome
waitress but she's a cool uh lady I've
been talking to her on Instagram and
what not she seems like a great chick so
yeah check out that Mellow Mushroom too
that place is delicious yeah Clint's a
carnivore carnivorous meat eaten freak
over there um uhhuh and I am a scrawny
[ __ ] hippie vegetarian you can agree
with that bro I'm not saying nothing
brother and uh they have a meal on that
menu for everybody yep I'm I'm
completely satisfied Clinton is
satisfied we sit across the table from
each other and belittle each other's
food we really do too look at all the
grease coming off here your your meat
pizza you carnivore piece of [ __ ] this
is all the [ __ ] that you should feed my
food yeah so huge shout out to the
mushroom those guys are great so now we
can go on to the Doug Benson part um we
owe a shout out to Baker Baker and
Comedy Works also yeah um I happen to
have some VIP preferred seating status
at Comedy Works as long as I let them
know I'm coming in advance they will get
me some VIP seats so we saw Doug Benson
we were front [ __ ] Row for Doug
Benson yeah it was great got to see him
record his uh comedy special it was the
third time they had done that show that
night so we'll get on with that in a
second um the show opened with graham
Elwood how' you feel about Graham Elwood
dude Graham Elwood was one of the
funniest guys I've seen in a long time
now I was really [ __ ] high of course
so I don't remember a lot of what he
said and I would zone out like he'd go
on some rant and I'd just start zoning
out [ __ ] high as [ __ ] just like man
it would be cool to see like what the
inside of a rainbow looks
like you know what I mean like I was
just and he was he was still talking
about something like like his kid or
something like that something happy and
I I just went to the extra happy place I
guess I looked over a couple times and I
can tell you were zoned out oh yeah uh
so Graham Elwood's hilarious you guys um
he's got a fake band known as the
whistling Baines uh he's on a lot of
podcasts if you listen to that Doug
Benson podcast you will hear some Graham
Elwood he's also got his own podcast
called the comedy film nerds
um Graham actually invited me to the LA
podfest in Los Angeles and he told me
that there is a big room where you can
set up and everybody records their
podcast out there and he said that if I
come he would be on my show and he shook
my hand so if I make it to La podfest
podfest you guys will hear Graham Elwood
on the podcast that would be [ __ ]
cool he was he was really nice guy um I
know that I can't keep it in check
tonight I've said the f bomb probably 15
times already yeah um
anyway he said it so quietly [ __ ]
yeah um but he but Graham amazed me
because he was funny and he was clean
which is hard to do so like uh just more
props to him he was really funny if if
he would ever listen to this I hope he
would hear us say that uh he was the
best part of that night because Doug
Benson came on after him and Doug first
thing he said he goes uh I woke up this
morning I started smoking this was on
420 yeah this was on 420 so let's yeah
let's remind the people that but yeah so
he woke up he started smoking he did a
420 show up till he was he was smoking
up until then he just kept smoking all
day and that was the first thing he said
is like he did all he could do to make
it to where he couldn't make it to that
last show yeah his goal was to be too
high to record that show I I think he
succeeded you know I've seen I've gotten
Doug Benson High several times and I've
never seen him that high I got high and
this sounds like bragging but I'm kind
of I'm not Bros with Doug but I'm
internet buddies with Doug I'm Twitter
friends with Doug we talk and [ __ ] and
some of the comedians Know Who I Am by
now because I've gone to enough shows so
he relies on rosta Jeff to get him high
before the show he knows I've got some
dank weed and I'm not psycho so he hits
me up he hit me up to get him high one
time I got him high and he told me from
the stage he [ __ ] up a joke and looked
at me and said you got me too high bro
yeah uh that night he was three or four
times beyond that level of highness he
was he was so [ __ ] skinny eyed
[ __ ] you could not see one eye was
skinny one eye was weird oh jeez I think
one eye was working kind of but it was
it was [ __ ] I I don't know dude he
was so baked that he
just he it just wasn't even that much
fun he kept putting his head on the
microphone you guys heard this sound a
lot and that was his head hitting the
microphone so that he could take a
little break he was I mean he was
laughing at his own jokes and there was
some really hilarious [ __ ] that he said
he spent 30 minutes reading [ __ ]
tweets thank you the first 30 minutes of
his show he read tweets which he usually
spends but the problem was that 30
minutes was only divided up by like five
tweets yes it wasn't like a whole bunch
of tweets it was like five people that
were uh audacious enough to pull their
phone out in a comedy show and send him
a shout out or and and tweet at him
right then yeah that's we're up front
row I can't do that no that looks he
would Graham was staring at me cuz my
phone was on my lap because it's too big
for my pocket I got this iPhone 6 plus
my phone was on my lap and Graham kept
looking at it I felt like Graham Elwood
looked at my phone twice like he's got
his [ __ ] phone out but I maybe if it
was on your lap he was looking at
something else was he looking at my
package bro you think Graham was
checking it out he was trying to see if
he got any seeds down there oh I got
plenty of seeds buddy this is team IR
regenetics all right so uh I saw Doug
Benson literally yawn he had to move the
mic from his face and yawn on stage
performing his comedy special so he
actually said uh this is is my third
time recording this and what I want to
do is make sure to get the jokes that I
didn't get perfect the last couple of
times now now don't don't let me uh say
anything other than I respect him for
being honest but I just didn't pay to go
see a guy just kind of muddle through
something right do you know what I mean
yeah when I go to see a concert I don't
want to watch Metallica do soundcheck
five times I don't know why I picked
Metallica out of all [ __ ] band that
would be well I mean
maybe I want to watch them nail inner
Sandman I don't want to watch them try
to do some song they haven't done right
in a couple of weeks we haven't we hav
played this song properly we're going to
try it in front of you like yeah three
times yeah or I mean Doug only did
things I guess he did things three times
that day though yeah and he did a couple
of the bits twice because he forgot he
did one when he was doing a bit for us
oh yeah well it's because he broke it
off early in the first part he didn't
tell like the the same part of the story
did he I I don't remember how high were
we part of that was because he had a
pocket full of notes that were
disheveled it looked like um it looked
like your grandpa had gone to Lowe's you
know when Grandpa comes home from going
out all day he's got a pocket full of
receipts and a couple of breath mints
and a [ __ ] toothpick and like did too
a shopping list and now Grandpa's got a
joint in there yeah yeah well he had
there's like four or five different
colors of pieces of paper in there there
was a receipt for Barnes &amp; Noble in
there that I could see like he I don't
know if he had scribbled on all of it
but that's what that's where his notes
were was in that handful of Grandpa and
he kept staring at handful of Grandpa is
also the name of my new metal
[Laughter]
band can we write that down because I
have I have a use for the name handful
of
Grandpa all right another project needs
a name and if you're not going to use it
oh oh no buddy we're we're going to make
something out of this guys make sure you
listen to my other podcast it's called
handful of Grandpa it hasn't been put
out yet but first guest yes that may
just be an episode but still this that
needs to be written down and I'm sorry
if I'm wasting time writing down this
phrase handful if you guys have made it
this far into this podcast we salute you
uh second of all um you know we're
probably not going to be talking too
much about growing not on this one but
uh the next episode we're growing as
people
though all right now I now I remember
why I forget to bring comedians on the
show every so often it's just me bro
this is the [ __ ] that happens no I love
it I love the chaos I hope the listeners
like it uh it doesn't always have to be
grow lessons Danielle you could put your
notebook away there will be nothing to
write down this time other than the
phrase handful of Grandpa we
win anyway so but um so we had those
disheveled notes right and then that's
where we were there yeah and then uh he
just and I think he needs glasses to go
with the notes oh dude he definitely
needed to open his eyes a little bit
because they were [ __ ] closed yeah
yeah they were closed he was [ __ ] up
somebody threw a joint on stage and it
took him two minutes to find it and pick
it up he almost stepped on it
he was wa and and if you've ever seen
The Comedy Works like stage it's well
lit and it's maybe the size of your
kitchen table yes like it's it's not a
big thing like by and there was nothing
on the stage it's like a blue carpet
what did somebody say the floor looked
like somebody tweeted and said the floor
looked like a a nail or a salon floor a
spa a day spa floor I thought that was
weird but it was it was vacuumed
beautifully it was perfect anyway no but
it was just like 30 minutes on five
tweets which was kind of boring got into
some other stuff and then he tried to do
like other tweets or something like
later in the show didn't he wasn't he
doing tweet relief oh yeah uh he did a
thing it's called watch This Not That is
a game that he plays on his show where
he lets the audience members select
movies and then he decides which one to
watch but he was too high to keep track
of what the other audience members were
saying I Think Jesus I don't remember
man well it was the thing's called
promotional tool and uh we we definitely
felt like we got used like a tool like
it just it did it felt a little like uh
like you know what guys it sucks to be
you but this is what's happening and
maybe that's the way it has to be I
didn't want to say that when car when we
all were talking about it later I was
like so would you guys think and I was
just waiting for someone to be like that
was kind of [ __ ] whack for my 20
bucks well you went and hung out with
Doug and then me and uh my boy Drew took
off yeah we were all in stupidly enough
there were three carloads of people from
pleo with one or two people in each car
because we didn't plan that I had come
from the Cannabis Cup you came up on
your own and then I invited Danielle
right after you left I was already in
Monument by the time she hit me up so
well she made it so I'm proud of her
super proud she made that but yeah so we
all had to get in separate cars so once
we linked up and talked about it it was
like yeah I felt like we kind of were
his guinea pigs or his test audience or
something uh shout out to Graham Elwood
he saved the [ __ ] show uh Doug I'm
not being disrespectful to you bro I
just feel like that third show man you
were too high and if I wasn't I'm like a
loyal Doug fan so it was kind of neat
for me to see that like I've seen enough
Doug that's why I'm watching my friend
do comedy Now whatever and I get VIP
seats and [ __ ] but if I was a normal
civilian listener I might not have been
impressed with that show well like I
told you the only interaction I've had
with him is just listening to Doug Loves
movies and so that's not a whole lot of
Doug that's a lot of everybody else
right I haven't watched Doug specials
before that was my first chance of
seeing Doug Benson and I was not
impressed I've said it on the podcast
before that I think maybe Doug's uh
excess cannabis use may be slowing down
his comedy and his career and I think
that our experience uh solidifies my
theory yeah yeah and that sucks because
cannabis shouldn't be used as a slowing
down it should be used as a way to move
yourself forward well and then um real
quick and and we didn't bring this up
before but when when there was that he
said we're all going to go smoke outside
and I was like all right cool so we'll
go smoke and there was what like 100
people L there was like 100 people in
that Alleyway I don't know if you guys
have ever seen The Comedy Works Alleyway
but it's proba probably 30 ft wide maybe
you know about 10 yards well I'm just
trying to give it a little bit of room
because car and a person on either side
of the car you know I'm going to say
it's 10t wide I feel it well I don't
know if a car goes down there we all got
to squeeze against the side yeah I guess
all right so so we'll say 10t wide yeah
maybe 15 just but there was there was
like 75 to 100 people there A lot of
people in there um and and it started
feeling real broy while while Doug was
smoking Doug could take a hit of a joint
and everybody would cheer for it as
though he was like some hero like coming
home from war and this was his first
like step on American soil it was
[ __ ] it was just like yeah that's
that's it like we we're doing it we're
outside in Colorado we're doing it and
it was just like no this is this isn't
the attitude I want to have around weed
yeah yeah it kind of wasn't it seemed uh
like we were taking tequila shots and
everybody was high-fiving over the
tequila shots yeah it got that way yeah
that's how I felt about it I'm glad that
I didn't I I didn't stick around I had
to get home I was tired actually Doug
usually hangs out and smokes with
everybody but he uh he smoked with a few
people and then he knows me so he
actually turned to me and he said hey
Rost Jeff how are you man and how was
your drive because he knows I drive far
and when the crowd saw him heard him
address me they [ __ ] separated and
let him and I kind of hang out and take
some pictures and chill for a minute and
he shook my hand and left he just
wandered off that was it yeah there were
still a lot of people there and he left
uh so I saw Ango at that point uh Ango
beum you guys if you know Ango check him
out it's at his name is a hardest spell
it's NG G A IO 420 n n420 check him out
on Twitter um he's a cannabis activist
he is a podcaster he's a um he's a
comedian he's a jack of all trades but
he's definitely a pot smoker and a pot
connoisseur so I bumped into Eno we've
been Twitter friends and whatnot and
we've been in the same area same
industry for a long time but I finally
bumped into the dude and made friends
with him uh he followed me on Twitter he
followed uh our friend on Twitter and
then
uh I thought that was the end of my
meeting with Eno I thought we had met
and shook hands and [ __ ] so everybody
went our separate ways Clint drove home
like he said because he was tired
obviously Drew needed a nap um he made
it 30 minutes I made sure Danielle got
to her car safely and we all headed back
south to the lovely city of Pueblo uh
Tuesday I had to drive almost all the
way back I drove up to the North End of
Springs to meet up with some friends for
some food that were leaving back to Cali
um I got to introduce
um our friend Danielle to our friend my
friend Jay they've been Twitter and uh
Instagram friends for a long time and
they finally got to meet up so I put
them two chicks in a parking lot let
them hula hoop together for a minute and
it was great yeah we got to make some
friends out of those too shout out to
them two ladies so that was my Tuesday
then Wednesday Clint met me at my house
uh right around 4:20 is and then we
boogied up to go see um Mr Greg poops y
record the world's smartest podcast uh
check that one out out it may lose some
of you guys some of you guys may like it
uh Clint I could tell that uh Clint was
a little bit lost during the show yeah
it was either lost or it was
just I don't know he gets a little ranty
you know how it is well yeah that's he
calls that the boring preachy part of
his show he definitely he he sure has
that's a good portion of his show
apparently Cu uh there was a lot of
preachy Parts there was some joke Parts
at the start they just take a little
while he's got like a lot of references
and stuff that just it just takes a
while to get to things I'm more of a you
know let me hit you with the left and a
right like well his comedy he's he's
doing uh no he's a smart guy and I like
the guy and he's funny like some of the
jokes he had were really funny it just
takes a little while to get there but
he's I'm pretty sure he's like improving
all of that all of that was improv
Wednesday was the Podcast Thursday
Friday and Saturday he's doing standup
which will be completely different than
what you saw that's the thing is like
improv is a different thing to me you
know what I mean like uh I do standup I
don't do improv and it's nothing against
improv I just don't do Do It um so I
don't know those skills like those guys
are better uh at many many things but I
think just getting to the joke and
keeping people laughing that's where
standup Reigns and keeping you engaged
and stuff like that now improv is kind
of like well let let's try to figure out
how do we get back to this like neutral
points or whatever so that way we can
make it funny and but those guys that's
a challenge and a half but the audience
is a little bit more uh gives you more
leeway with that oh yeah you know what I
mean so maybe you guys knowing the
podcast were giving him more leeway than
I was well I am I'm not there just for
the funny I'm expecting to be um
enlightened a little by Greg educated
slightly offended at some points um I
know he's a thinking man's comedian you
have to and he calls himself the world's
smartest man it's not it's that's a joke
that's just a but it's he's a smart dude
though he's a smart sucker and he's been
doing improv we you asked him how long
you've been doing comedy and he just
shook his head at you like I think he
just wanted to say like longer than
you've been alive and that but I was but
but and and I wasn't trying to say it
like oh how long you been I I was just
wanting to ask him like well how long
you know this this is like a goal of
mine to be you and and he kind of did
kind of just dismiss me as though I was
saying it like an [ __ ] but what I
meant like was all respect like dude
like I just I just want to know that
there is the possibility that in like
you've been doing this for 30 years
that's what it takes to get to you cool
man I'd love to yeah he's that's where I
want to be and you guys he's the one
from Whose Line Is It Anyway is name of
the show right Who's Line yeah Whose
Line Is It Anyways one of the that's one
of the shows that this guy is on he's uh
no offense to Greg but he's probably the
one that you call the gay one yeah he's
not he's got a beautiful wife named
Jennifer and he is completely straight
and he stands up for women's rights so
he just got like a little bit of a high
uh irritating voice you know what I mean
like I don't mean like super irritating
but it's just like I probably wouldn't
want to marry that guy well I'm glad you
feel that way I think I think I'm all
right with that his voice made it to
where I didn't want to marry him nothing
else about that situation uh he wears a
suit all of the time uh he had a suit
with an uh kind of an uh it's a bluish
jacket with a purple shirt underneath it
and he had a purple hanky in one pocket
and at one point he pulled out a hanky
out of his jacket pocket to do a joke
and the hanky out of his pocket was
perfectly pressed and it was purple and
it had gold pinstriping on it dude his
pocket hanky was [ __ ] stylish like
this dude is stylish from head to toe
his shoes were sharp the only thing that
shocked me about the man was uh so we
saw the com we saw him record his show
while he's recording the show I look to
the right and I see Ango sitting
backstage at Comedy Works so I was like
we're going to hang out with and guo and
Greg watch this so after the show uh we
get bustled out and uh after a couple of
times of me looking over at Clinton he's
looking like he's going to fall asleep
also shout out to our friend Joe our
friend Joe met up with us yeah what's
and joined us we almost left Joe out
sorry about that Joe joined us for the
comedy show Joe had a great time Joe was
a huge poops fan so uh I looked over and
Greg's kind of uh Clint's kind of fallen
asleep a couple of times and then after
the show we're looking for the guys and
we can't find them and a friend of mine
is like dude they're down here in this
area smoking just walk back there and I
walk back there and I could hear Ango
from a block away he's got a very
recognizable voice so we walk down the
stairs and they're just hanging out
smoking so uh and guo greets me and knew
my name and then I introduce myself to
Greg PRS he sticks out his hand we shake
hands I asked if we're interrupting they
said no I lit a joint yep that's just
what I felt like needed to happen so
then we started hanging out with the
these guys for we hung out for an hour
yeah about an hour one of the things I
was going to say what I led on to was
the thing that shocked me about Greg he
smokes cigarettes I never would have
guessed Greg PRS smoked cigarettes I
don't know why you would have thought
that he was smarter than that is that
what you're saying I think so yes
nothing against you cigarette smokers I
know cuz I I've just recently finally
got I I quit my EIG too nice I quit all
that nicotine [ __ ] very cool I'm just
doing weed now which you know hit and
miss that's that's a good thing or a bad
thing you know no that's better for you
well it's better for me but it could
also get me fired for my job oh yeah
this this guy's name is not Clint this
is Bobby McGee here welcome to the grow
from your heart podcast my name is Bob
and a anyway um no I understand cutting
cigarettes out is hard and uh but Greg
PRS doing it it just it was like wow
that's that that was weird and it stunk
too that's kind of it was so weird that
like I could smell his cigarette worse
than I could smell all the dankness
around us uh shout out to Ango he pulled
out some Tangi from C that had some
stink and some flavor to it that Tangi
was delicious I didn't get a chance to
try I smelt it I was already Too High by
the time he had pulled that out I smelt
it though I think my platinum OG uh
trumped it the Platinum o he was I gave
him the last of my platinum OG that I
had with me and he looked quite
impressed with it he was uh he and he
was a nice guy too so and gu's a great
dude that is true we smoked with these
guys for like an hour and they were
talking to us not at us not about us
like we were just hanging out with
normal people at one point Point Greg
proops was telling a baseball story go
figure if you know anything about PRS
you know he's a huge baseball fan and he
was talking about a uh player leading
off of first BL base in a celebration
and then the Umpire yelled play ball and
the guy just stayed way off of first BL
base and so the first baseman reaches
over with the ball and tags him out and
as he talks about tagging him out he Dam
near punched me in the titty yeah did
like because he tagged me out as like a
physical act to show what happened but
he was being cool no he was just hanging
out and that story was uh the the Kansas
City Royals own George Brett for all the
uh Stoner [ __ ] baseball that was the
story you were that we were being told
3,000th hit look it up on YouTube yeah
yeah that's exactly it is he was
celebrating his 3,000th hit but so when
PRS was acting out the smack he smacked
me and looked at me like I was his buddy
and I tried not to light up like a
school girl because I was stupid excited
but I thought it was pretty awesome Greg
proops is one of my heroes he's I'm a
comedy nerd and he's a comedy Legend and
I'm a a podcaster and he's got a great
podcast so uh something about and he's
articulate and uh he makes me speak and
write better he actually makes me more
conscious of my my vocabulary and my
mouth when I'm trying when I'm not super
dabbed out he's uh he was really funny
you know there was some really funny
parts to Doug too though you know but
you know between the shows I I had a
rough weekend because I say you know but
Graham Elliott that was my favorite
lwood lwood Graham Elwood gram Elwood
yes as I said yes just like you said it
wasn't recorded or anything was it no
nobody else hear that anyway uh Graham
Graham was my favorite of the the little
Excursion we Clint is kind of OD a
comedy show you've got comedy blue balls
right now I'd assume it's
[ __ ] need a little comedy tug yeah uh
May 10th that'll be funny May 10th it'll
be funny May 10th will be fun maybe when
will come back you know that would be
nice that'd be cool it' be cool to see
him i' I'd love to know who was going to
be on that but I'm going to have my T or
my name tag ready there you go uh I
don't know if I want to take my old I've
got a name tag made guys if you don't
know what we're talking about when you
go see Doug binon do Doug love movies
Doug Loves Movies you got to take a name
tag with you I don't know if I want to
take my old name tag or if I want to
print up a new one the Old One's I'll
take your old one there you go be like
you be me God you're the laziest
[ __ ] so we've got uh Doug Loves
Movies on May 10th uh Joey Diaz coming
up after that yeah and that's June in
June and then what else do we have
coming up a Brian Ken show Brian Ken I I
think it sounds like I'm going to see
Brian Ken guys I got to start listening
to more of Brian K you don't have to I
can take somebody else I'm all I'm all
well you know I'm all about seeing some
Brian K that's fighter and the kid right
yeah dude no it's it it's it's going to
be fun dude that's the thing is it's
just fun going you know that that's the
thing is like I'm not going to complain
about this like these couple of days CU
they were fun days and and it's funny
that I can still be a little bit like uh
H it wasn't that great but we hung out
with poops in NGO for a [ __ ] hour
yeah for an hour and just smok like Bros
yeah yeah so I don't know what the hell
I'm complaining about and I could have
probably smoked with Doug I just didn't
feel like hopping in that crowd yeah
that was a big crowd but we're going to
see Doug here in like two weeks so yeah
everything's good man Mother's Day guys
have we mentioned that Mother's Day is
Good how high are we uh remember that
opener that cold open [ __ ] from Clint
30 minutes ago all right we've been
going for 30 minutes that's pretty good
you got anything else you want to add
about the uh the comedy shows before we
start wrapping it up and moving on to
different subjects no um the again uh
Comedy Works is one of the best clubs if
if you haven't been there please go
check it out it doesn't matter who you
go see it's going to be fun um it's we
have great service there all the time
they got waitresses running all over the
place um and with us you know we're
doing uh every Thursday down here in PUO
so if you want to see open mic comedy
we're still doing that every Thursday at
the rainbow at the Rainbow on Santa Fe
and guys I know I keep talking about
being VIP at Comedy Works and they treat
me like a pin pimp they will treat you
like a pimp as well they treat everybody
like a rockar there uh I'm just 65 with
dreadlocks and they recognize my high
ass every time so they remember me and
I've made friends oh and we're coming
back kind of you know frequently yeah
fairly frequently and I bring dank dank
weed and I might smoke out in the back
every time and they recognize me that
might happen they might smell you coming
before they see your [ __ ] 65 rosta
[ __ ] you know it's fun when you take
uh take a date with you who's never
really hung out with you out in public a
lot and you take her to a comedy show
and everybody at The Comedy Works 125
miles from your house high fives you and
knows you by name that's [ __ ] The
Comedians know you by name like that's
that's a way to take a chick out and she
was like what that was pretty neat dude
I I do want to go to the can cup with
you next year though I don't know if you
do because uh oh I ain't smoking a whole
bunch no I'm just saying every 10 feet
it's uh I get stopped and start a new
conversation every 10 ft every 10 ft so
put a bag over your head that's what you
got I'll throw some dreadlocks on
they'll think that I am you we're about
the same height we are close to the same
height dude you could be my brother my
brother from another this will work and
I'll just I'll just uh kind of be like
yeah man like I no I'm just really high
and I just won't even open my eyes you
still have sunglasses anyway if you're
being me see here we go man we're on it
right I just need an IR region X shirt
I'm going to send around a drone of me
so that I can go kick
it he's still he's still running around
just somewhere else he's we take breaks
we're on and off on ships yeah you get
to be me for five hours you get the
morning shift I'm no good in the
mornings there you go there's no people
out there in the mornings I'll take that
shift plenty of people out there in the
mornings it was crazy this this time in
the mornings well I guess you said that
on the last podcast you talked about it
on the last one yeah yeah just how busy
it is how busy yeah how many people are
running around there were thousands of
people there I never uh looked for the
official ticket sales to see how many
people were there thousands there were
people that I know I'm good on that one
but thanks uh there were people that I
did not get to see he just tried to pass
me a bowl of flowers and I turned it
down because Flowers really give me
stupid bad cotton mouth on the show I'll
take a dab though I'm going to take a
dab um so you said Thursdays at the
Rainbow Bar Thursday at the Rainbow Bar
9900 p.m. uh come check it out you know
wild cousins just trying to keep uh keep
going you know it's tough cuz we're not
in the the big city doing the the big
boy shows and stuff now my boy John
Bueno is starting to to take off he's
going to he's really giv a % to it good
I I really think that he's going to be
one of the first guys out of peblo to
really cuz he's funny he's a good guy
and uh he's he wants it I saw his post
about doing uh some show where he's
hosting it so I was proud of him for
that I think he's going up to Longmont
to host some I don't remember who it was
either is there a cover charge for your
show on Thursdays at the rainbow the
rainbow is free every THS free come see
some free comedy guys it's open micers
but oh we might get some weird [ __ ] here
we should be cool everything should have
worked I think everything's cool still
happening yeah uh yeah so uh those shows
are going to be free open MERS yeah they
didn't miss [ __ ] hopefully we're going
to have to go back and look because
that's got me sketched out so yeah I
hope all that recorded
guys welcome to part two CU we just
recorded part one it's missing it looks
like everything worked but uh I could
tell that garage band was pissed off at
me for a second there there was an
update on the computer and everything's
still kind of wonky but uh so yeah I'm
about to take this dab is what I was
going to do um the free shows you'll see
some open micers there what type of who
will we see at these Open Mic events on
a Thursday who do you think will show up
uh you know we got a lot of guys uh
myself I'm going to get back after it I
took a little bit of a break but I got
to get back after it and then uh my boy
Paul Rosalez he's uh he's there every
Thursday really funny guy if you guys
listen to the episode 62 wild cousins he
was the the funny one yeah he was the
funny one that's looking for a dude to
hook up with d dude I [ __ ] that [ __ ]
was funny oh we had a good time he's
he's really funny um uh John bueno's
like I said really really funny we got
other guys coming through um sometimes
it's brand new guys if you're a brand
new guy and you want to try comedy
there's no better place in the rain new
G or yeah please I'm sorry I meant when
I say dude I I mean guy and gal and when
I say it's all unisex guy I just mean
anybody I really don't mean it as like
only guys can do whatever right no I
wish more ladies had come out they don't
they don't want to do it anyway maybe
I'm intimidating I'm
6'5 4ft
dreadlocks yeah you should see Clint's
creds they're in not really come on they
don't get no dread cred anyway all right
uh do you have any other shows coming up
any specific dates no not right now uh
just uh Mother's Day that's it Mother's
Day yes he's taking your mom out no I
don't mean that you take your mom out
take your own Mother's out take them to
dinner or do it on the 9th I don't know
make sure you guys follow Clint on
Instagram and Twitter it's tall Clint
tall Clint uh he hasn't been posting a
lot lately but he's getting back into it
he took kind of a Hiatus to get a [ __ ]
together we respect that [ __ ] yeah the
social media takes a lot of your damn
time I've noticed like I post a lot and
then I catch myself like oh I've been on
here for 30 minutes I gotta wipe and get
out of
here I didn't see that coming either did
I either did I it came oh you propsed it
all right we are going to wrap up this
show you guys dude thank you for coming
to the podcast yeah Budd uh thanks for
hanging out with me at comedy shows uh
thanks for all the shows we have planned
together in the future we've been having
fun dude we have a lot of fun the
audience yeah team tall guy thanks to
the audience yeah that's I think so yeah
tweet at us let us know what you think
this one was a little rambly I apologize
it was a lot of rambly but uh sometimes
you got to cut loose and have a comedy
show instead of all about uptight weed
I'm pretty sure you guys are getting a
lot of weed anyway and if you made it
this far good job yeah yeah um make sure
you clean the filters and your air
conditioners and calibrate your PA H
meters there you go that was some weed
advice for the show you did it yeah we
got some in there oh man also uh make
sure uh that they don't have centipedes
because those are scary there you go you
heard it from Clint centipedes Are scary
all right guys thanks for listening I'm
going to be back in a few days with
another episode I'm not sure if it'll be
uh I'm not sure if this came out on a
Wednesday or Monday so not sure how this
is going to go we'll see how it works uh
don't forget to check out the sponsors
Rocky Mountain worm company High gr
indoor growing supplies and Nature's
green remedies.com
try to come down to peblo check out the
comedy shows at the Rainbow Bar on
Thursdays they're funny they're free and
they serve booze so if it's not funny
just drink more go outside and smoke a
fat joint and then it'll be funny it'll
be great uh if you want to sponsor the
podcast or if you have a product you'd
like me to review send me an email it's
SC from meart hotmail.com I'll get you
all the information you need uh don't
forget that the show is available on
iTunes Stitcher and every single episode
will always and forever be archived on
iy gentics color.com also don't forget
about the donation button um on top of
the iry genetics.com webbsite there's a
grow from your heart podcast tab at the
top right there's a PayPal button click
right on there and you can make a
donation I'll never charge you anything
for the podcast it's always going to be
free because I love you but if you feel
like making a contribution I would
appreciate it and I'll say thank you on
the show um what else do I want to say
find me on social media make sure you
follow me on Instagram it's IR gentics
um once again congrats and a big shout
out to my ninja Spence thanks again for
listening until next time take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me with a
handful of
Grandpa