[Music]
all right here we go welcome back
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rosta jeff and this is episode
number 671
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to talk about bud
washing before we get to that part of
the show let's do a few shout outs to a
few of those great folks who support the
show on patreon let's start off with the
big grow from your heart podcast thank
you shout out to my buddy alabama man
let's send a special thank you shout out
to chiefly420 i want to send a fist bump
and a thank you shout out to scooter
let's send a big thank you shout out to
a longtime supporter my buddy quasi
let's send a thank you shout out to a
fellow podcaster caribou heart tv i want
to send a special thank you shout out to
a long time supporter and a good friend
my buddy glenn jeroni let's send a thank
you shout out to guido and frugal rock
let's send a thank you shout out to
another longtime supporter my buddy all
mixed up let's send a special thank you
shout out to roll this nug and then
let's wrap up the shout outs with a big
thank you shout out to my buddy stoned
trout bomb
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need is right there on the screen and
you know i do include that link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it super easy for all of my
friends you know the rules if you're
driving if you're working don't pull out
the phone don't get yourself in any
danger right now the link will be there
when you've got time patreon.com forward
slash grow from your heart this is the
part of the podcast where i do cordially
invite you to join the discord server
that's right there is a link to the
discord server in the show notes and the
video description i'm also putting the
link right here so you could see that
type that in manually if that's
something you want to do but join us on
the discord server again if you're
driving if you've got the kids if you're
trimming don't get yourself in trouble
don't put yourself in danger the discord
link will be there when you've got time
but i do invite you to join us on
discord jump into the discord server
meet my friend rastabot and join the
party there's a lot of cool stuff
happening on the discord server there
are a lot of cool people there uh
there's a live video chat where people
are hanging out right now uh canadian
weednerd is probably there billy podunk
is probably there hanging out talking
about growing cannabis talking about
life right now there's a grow chat
section there's a strain chat section
there's even a section to go talk about
fish or reggae music so if you need
something to do someone to hang out with
want to talk about cannabis want to
learn about ire genetics or just want to
hang out with the crew we cordially
invite you to come hang out on the
discord server once again there is a
link in the show notes and in the video
description really quickly i do want to
apologize that the last episode was
shorter than normal i did cut out a good
chunk of that episode i don't don't know
if you noticed
my magical editing skills i removed a
good portion of that show that i felt i
got way off track and i was basically
talking uh to and for myself and i
didn't want to punish you by leaving
that in the show so i cut it out so i
apologize for the short show sometimes a
short quick episode is better than a
long bullshitted episode it's easier
just to come in and say here's the point
here's the lesson here's how you do it
wishes success i'm out have a good day
uh there's no need for me just to sit
here and extend [ __ ] just to make the
episode look longer on youtube uh
quality over quantity and i've got 80d
you've got 80d maybe that short episode
was exactly what we needed if you need a
longer episode listen to two or i've got
plenty of friends out there doing
podcasts that you will enjoy as well but
i do apologize for the short show try to
keep it good try to keep it tight i felt
like i had to cut out some [ __ ] that
was for all of our benefit all right
where do we go from here i want to give
a big thank you shout out fist bump hug
high five smile uh spread some vibes to
all of the friends and family that i saw
at the fish concerts in denver over the
weekend that's right i try not to brag
boast too much about the amazing [ __ ]
that i get to do in my life but if you
know me if we're friends and if not
here's a little insight into my life
fish is my favorite band i've got a few
bands that i really enjoy fish with a ph
ph ish if you never heard of them check
them out fish is my favorite band
there's nothing like it uh no two shows
will ever be the same every show is
different they never play the same songs
within like a week so if they played
your favorite song friday you won't hear
it again until next friday if you're
lucky
i went i got to go see i went saw fish
for three nights in a row at dick's
sporting goods the big soccer field in
denver and commerce city and i had the
time of my freaking life
we've been on this weird uh i don't even
like to talk about quarantine and all
the weird [ __ ] we've been going through
for the past two years we've been locked
down it's been nice to get out and dance
and boogie and see some [ __ ] music it
was such a good time you guys i feel so
good about it uh but part of the fun
fish is a big part of the fun fish is
why we go the band fish puts on a great
show they play great music in my opinion
they put me in a great mindset that's
only a portion of the event a big
portion of that event is going and
seeing old friends catching up with old
friends there are some people i only see
at fish shows there are some people that
i see often but we definitely know we'll
see each other at fish shows and then
there are people that i meet for the
first time at fish shows and it is a
wonderful experience doing all of the
above seeing the old crew meeting the
new crew and then just seeing the fish
crew is always a beautiful experience so
i want to send a big shout out a big
thank you a big hug a high five a funky
dance move to all of the people that i
bumped into at fish if we spent the
weekend grooving in a section together
big shout out to section 107 big up you
guys held it down uh everybody in 107 if
we hung out and got down together big
fist bump i'm not going to even try to
remember all the names but even the
people who thought i'd forget their
names pete and leandro i remember bro
but i got all your names in my head big
shout out to all those great folks i got
your business cards we will be in touch
uh if we were brand new friends that was
a great time if you walked by and gave
me a high five a fist bump a nod a hug
just tap me on the shoulder and give me
a thumbs up if you walked by and said
great podcast
however you did it thank you i
appreciate it
uh i was having a good ass time i was
dancing to fish and i was having a good
time i was trying not to uh interrupt
the fish experience to talk to people
but the people i did talk with uh
between sets and during set break
beautiful time thank you and again shout
out to everybody for the fist bumps the
high fives the hugs the handshakes the
stickers uh the treats the snacks the
food i was given gifts and food and
drinks and people just they saw what i
was drinking and they saw that my
beverage was low and they came out of
nowhere with a fresh beverage for me and
i was like you're [ __ ] people are
amazing at fish shows so it's a really
good time i met some new people uh
people from all over the place i got to
see a friend who has lived in
like thailand and vietnam and [ __ ] for
the past few years i don't think i've
seen him since probably 10 years ago at
a fish show so i got to bump into that
guy we gave each other a hug we talked
for a few minutes talked about some
future endeavors and he skedaddled off
to go back into the fish show and do his
thing so he's out there having a good
time i met some great folks from hawaii
uh some folks from indiana some folks
from pa uh there's folks from everywhere
we had a good time i'm gonna quit
gushing about the fish show obviously
guys i had an amazing [ __ ] time i
wanted to talk about i'd like to share
with you guys what i do but i owe a
bunch of people fist bumps high fives
thank yous and shout outs um if we just
made eye contact and you knew who i was
and he gave me the nod because you
didn't want to interrupt respect i saw
you we had a good time thank you if you
came up and you're like bro are you
roster jeff that was me bro we had a
good time it was great meeting you it
felt so good i made some new friends and
we're hanging out in a little group and
every few minutes somebody would walk by
and they'd be like ross to jeff and they
just high-five me or give me a hug or
somebody just like love the podcast bro
and somebody just walks by and goes
arise and i was like well that was
awkward but then eventually the people
that i was with are like hey why do they
keep saying that [ __ ] to you and so i
had to explain i was like oh i have a
weed podcast and all that good stuff
that was entertainingly fun had a good
time uh everybody that was there
see you next year can't wait for next
year to party let's get it on all right
big fist bumps big shout outs big hugs
pigs high fives uh big vibes big weird
dance moves to all of you folks now
let's move on to the main topic of this
podcast i know i get rambly at the start
of the show sometimes people do complain
about in the comments that i get rambly
at the start of the show it takes five
minutes to get into it but guess what
it's a podcast uh it's free and i do get
a little rambling i'm trying to find a
rhythm i'm finding my space i'm finding
my zone ah i think it feels better than
just going one two three here we go
talking about bud washing i try to get
comfortable bring you in some people
want to hang out if not bro hit that
fast forward button get to the part or
don't whatever anyway uh see that's the
kind of stuff i cut out of the last
episode i'm not going to cut that out of
this one the main topic of today's
episode is bud washing and that's bud
washing with a d washing your bud that's
right you should already be washing
everything else today we're going to
learn about bud washing i'm discovering
that a lot of people are experiencing
problems in their outdoor grow early
this year i did predict a lot of powdery
mildew happening in outdoor grows
because if we've had really drastic
changes here in colorado we've had hot
days cold nights and lots of rain and
that does add up to powdery mildew
situations powdery mildew environments
i've seen a lot of people on social
media posting about their powdery mildew
laden buds and they're asking how do i
get rid of this then perfectly timed i
got this email on the irie genetics
website where there is the grow help tab
really quickly we'll talk about that if
you go to iregenetics.com
there is a grow help tab you can click
on that and it gives you about 12
preliminary questions asking about your
garden those few questions help me
diagnose your grow then we give you the
opportunity to type in what's wrong with
your grow then you send that to me and i
will find that in my email and i will
read it and we'll solve your problem
here on the show so go to the website
iregenetics.com go to the grow health
tab that's where this came from this one
came from name to use on the podcast is
enda kala
or indicaya if it's spanish we'll say
it's indica they're growing some aphisto
sour stomper and creme de la cam and
gnome automatics a lot of this is
unnecessary to read all this info here
we're gonna jump right to it said i love
your show i'm a new grower and you've
helped me figure out how to do this and
i appreciate it big respect bro thank
you for listening i hope i'm able to
help you out with your first interaction
here it says i know it's a ton of work
and i just wanted to let you know i
appreciate your effort thank you there
is a point to this question it says i
don't have a grow problem as much as a
general question i get why bud washing
makes sense on outdoor grows and it's
logical that outdoor buds can be covered
in stuff we don't want to put into our
bodies my question for you is and this
is a very good question it says what is
your take on bud washing on indoor grows
i've seen some claim even indoor buds
are improved by washing i've read okay
so we're going to talk about bud washing
and this person is asking about bud
washing indoors and then it says you
would be surprised how much grime comes
off the buds even in seemingly
controlled environments uh yes i do
agree we uh i do agree that we gather a
lot of funky stuff on those buds you
never know what could be on there there
could be bugs there could be bug poop
we're going to talk about that in a
moment but i do agree that sometimes it
is beneficial to wash indoor buds what
i'm going to talk about will be
applicable to indoor and or outdoor
products so keep that in mind so this
next comment i found on youtube and it
was done right after i did the pest
management episode and it's referring to
using uh predatory pests so if you've
got if you've got a pest problem and you
use another pest to attack that bug the
obvious question was don't all things
that eat poop so the question is are
those predatory pests going to poop out
the carcasses of the bug that they ate
into my plants which is a very good
question
it says who wants to smoke half eaten
bugs and the poop so ah that is a very
good question and that is a very uh good
reason to do blood washing so that is
part of what inspired this episode was
two great emails and a bunch of social
media chatter about bud washing so now
that i've set it up let's get right to
it bud washing what do i mean by bud
washing sometimes your buds will be
infested with powdery mildew
unfortunately it does happen sometimes
we just want to clean off the buds and
get that powdery mildew off of there and
the buds will be safe to consume some
people are going to argue with me now
some people are going to have varying
opinions in my opinion if that bud has
if the floured plant has a little bit of
powdery mildew on those leaves i think
we can wash that powdery mildew off with
bud washing it is not something that i
would like to do that i would rely on
that i would do on a regular basis but
in some emergency cases especially this
year's outdoor crop this may be
necessary also this may be beneficial to
people who grow for extraction if you
want your extractions to be as clean as
they can be why not wash off the product
that you're going to extract before you
put it through the extraction process if
you don't put dirt grime dust bug [ __ ]
bug poop into your extraction machines
you don't have to take that out of the
process you don't have to clean it up
and take that out of the final product
so
uh bud washing sometimes you get powdery
mildew often there are bugs on your
plants often there are bug eggs like
this person said anything that is laying
eggs or eating another bug is also going
to take a [ __ ] so you got some bug [ __ ]
to go into your plants now uh oftentimes
outdoors you will discover bird poop on
your plants there's not much you can do
about that unless you've got a
greenhouse birds are going to fly over
they're going to drop a turd and
sometimes it's going to land right on
your plants i've got a good way to wash
that off this is very effective for that
sometimes you get spider webs outside
sometimes a spider says hey i see [ __ ]
flying around here there's a lot of
plants attracting a lot of things i'm
going to build a web from this plant to
this plant everything that flies through
[ __ ] dinner for the next couple of
weeks until they harvest
you'll get spider webs
then you will get dust and dirt now's a
good time for me to make a quick
disclaimer if you hear the weirdness in
my nose
that uh sorry for that that was really
rude but if you hear the weird nasally
sound in my voice that is because i
spent three days on a dirt parking lot
sucking up dirt and dust and i have got
a little nasal thing happening i feel
fine i feel good but there's a lot of
dirt in my nose and it kind of wrecked
me so there's a lot of dirt and dust on
the grow in the plants and they're
sticky they're trichomes so the powdery
mildew the bugs the bug eggs the bug
poop the bird poop spiderwebs dust and
dirt and then who knows what else who
knows what else maybe who even knows
what else is stuck to those plants it
could be anything outdoors right you see
weird [ __ ] cocoons and [ __ ] bug eggs
and weird larvae and things could be
stuck to those whatever the wind blew by
could be stuck to your plants so why not
wash that stuff off it would be a really
good idea if you're going to smoke it
eat it consume it make extracts off of
it we would wash our fruits and
vegetables right if i handed you a
tomato or a cucumber or an avocado
whatever it was going to be you'd wash
it before you cut it and eat it right we
should possibly maybe consider doing
that with our products especially if
they've got
powdery mildew bug eggs poop bird poop
spider webs dust and dirt something like
that on it why not clean it up
now let's get to the we know why and we
know uh the reasons to do it let's get
to how to do it
uh we would harvest just like normal all
right harvest your plants just like
normal you got your plant it's cut down
your normal harvest process
then you've got to cut the buds into
manageable pieces i like to cut the
plant down to where i've got a bud and a
stick and then at the end of that stick
i leave a hook so essentially what i'm
doing is i'm taking the main stock of
the plant and cutting it above the node
so there would be the main stock goes up
and a node would come off at an angle
and then if you cut right below where
that node comes off you've just left
yourself a hanger so when it's time to
hang that butt up you can use that
little v section as a natural hanger for
your plant you'll see this when it comes
time to cut your plant cut below the
node you'll leave a little hanger you
can just leave the main stock will
become the the short piece of the hanger
and the branch with the buds will become
the the branch with the butt it will all
make sense so i cut them into manageable
pieces
for me i'm going to use a 5 gallon
bucket for my bud washing i need pieces
that are shorter than a 5 gallon bucket
so i can dunk them all the way in there
my goal is to get all the bud matter all
the bud material into the five gallon
bucket so i'm going to harvest like
normal i'm probably going to before
harvest i would normally go and pull off
a majority of the large powdery mildew
laden fan leaves all the big leaves with
the pedial before harvest you could just
go in and strip as many leaves off as
you can get go take off the leaves don't
get aggressive and [ __ ] up the buds take
off all the leaves strip them destroy
those leaves they've got powdery mildew
get them out of there maybe wear a mask
while you're doing this definitely wear
gloves stay safe get in there and
defoliate cut down your plants cut them
into manageable pieces leave sticks so
you can hang them after they are dunked
then this is where when we're going to
actually start cleaning up the buds
one more thing i should mention gloves
uh we're going to use a five gallon
bucket
filled with water uh you can use regular
tap water ro water that doesn't matter
too much to me we're going to add 25 to
50 milliliters of 30
hydrogen peroxide to 5 gallons of water
let me repeat that that is 25 to 50
milliliters per 5 gallons you can go
harder if you want but i would start
light see if it's washing off the pm see
if it's solving the problem if not go
harder go harder until you see it start
doing some damage to a couple branches
then dilute as necessary usually 25 to
50 mils of 30 hydrogen peroxide not the
cheap [ __ ] you need the good stuff the
30 the medical grade the good [ __ ]
25 to 30 mils and a 5 gallon bucket of
water
ah wear your protective equipment when
you're mixing this wear goggles when
you're handling all of this wear gloves
because that 30 hydrogen peroxide will
mess your skin up it is very caustic if
it gets in your eye it's going to be one
of the most painful things you will ever
experience so please when you are using
the hydrogen peroxide please use at
least the gloves and i recommend some
goggles when you're pouring it i
understand a lot of people aren't going
to go get goggles just to pour some [ __ ]
enter at your own risk rasta jeff is
making a disclaimer don't [ __ ] sue me
because you're dumb all right enough
said there
uh 5 gallon bucket 25 to 50 mls of
hydrogen peroxide the good [ __ ] 30 you
can go harder if you want but don't
blame me if that [ __ ] up your buds
start low and then work your way up if
it's not taking off the mildew add more
when it starts bleaching your buds
you've gone too far dilute you'll figure
it out only take one or two branches and
you'll notice all right so we've got our
five gallon bucket filled with our
solution you don't have to use the
hydrogen peroxide but that is what i
recommend if we're going to do this that
is something i would recommend i don't
think it will damage your plants i don't
think it will mess anything up i've
applied hydrogen peroxide as a foliar
spray before to combat powdery mildew
and in my opinion it works very very
well it leaves the growth smelling clean
and fresh and the next day you don't
even notice it happened
except there's no powdery mildew and the
plants are happier and it smells amazing
like ganja in that room so we've got our
five gallon bucket we've got our
hydrogen peroxide in there we've got our
gloves on maybe some of you are wearing
eye gear probably not we're going to cut
our plant into manageable sections
probably 10 to 12 inch sections
something like that is probably
manageable for most people before we
even start dunking these buds have a
place where they are going to hang where
are they going to go once you dunk these
buds you're going to dunk them into
water you're going to swirl them around
we're going to take them out we've got
to hang them somewhere for them to drip
dry they're going to have a lot of water
in there depending on how spongy and
dense your buds are and how much bud is
on that stick there's going to be quite
a bit of water left in there it will
come out don't worry don't squeeze it
don't do anything [ __ ] crazy to it
let it drip out let it just come out
naturally okay
so have that space in mind have it
planned have it ready maybe already know
exactly how much space you need to hang
these plants before you even get to this
point because i don't want you to have
wet buds and a struggle that's when
you're going to cause problems if you
don't [ __ ] it up this will go very well
but if you don't have a proper strategy
and a place to put the buds before you
dunk them [ __ ] will go wrong i promise
we can't stack up wet buds they've got
to be hung with space uh with care so uh
have a place for them to go have the
product your solution ready have your
protective equipment on cut the buds
into manageable pieces now here's where
we're gonna get crazy you got a five
gallon bucket right take your piece of
bud your branch your stock however much
product you've got and just submerge it
right into the water i know this sounds
brave i know this sounds crazy you just
put months into this product but i have
done entire harvests in commercial
facilities this way i've paid guys to
spend all day washing buds with hydrogen
peroxide because we couldn't rescue this
facility that was coated in powdery
mildew and that was our solution it all
got made into extracts it was all tested
it was all safe it all worked i trust
this method so
we're going to dunk our buds directly
into the five gallon bucket with our
hydrogen peroxide solution
while it's in there
jostle it the word that i want to use is
jostle stir the buds around don't get in
there and [ __ ] sh
we're not trying to shake the trichomes
off we're trying to jostle the powdery
mildew off we don't want to disrupt the
plant i just want to rinse it just not
vigorous but not not lily dipping but
you want to get in there and kind of
just in and out and swish it around a
little bit
just get that just get some movement
gets a little bit of friction in there
just wash that powdery mildew off then
take that plant out and give it a visual
assessment look at it do you see more
problems
did bug poop come off of it did the
spider web come off of it did the bird
[ __ ] come off did the powdery mill do
wash off did you do a good enough job if
not dunk that [ __ ] back in there give
it another wiggle another jiggle another
another jostle do what you need to do
until it's clean hang it up
repeat as necessary
maybe do a portion of the crop at this
point maybe just do some of it and see
how you like this method check on those
plants check on them in an hour check on
them in two four six every few hours
just check on them see what is happening
before you do the whole crop check on
them see if you like how it is going see
if you dunk them enough is there still
stuff on there you want to wash off if
there is you can
but it is very important that you dunk
them and wash them before the plants
begin to dry do not
do not take a dry plant and try to dunk
it and remoisten it and do this you will
destroy everything you'll [ __ ] it all up
you'll be so mad so that's a quick
disclaimer a quick reminder a quick
notice
do not try to remoisten and do this to a
dried plant you can't do that that's
going to be a total failure so take your
wet plant dunk it shake it jostle it
around hang it up if you like how that
one came out in a couple of hours do the
rest of the plants dunk them all dunk
them jostle them give them a little
swish watch the powdery mildew come on
up now eventually that water is going to
start looking a little bit funky at your
own discretion dump that [ __ ] out start
fresh the hydrogen peroxide is not super
expensive
you've gotten this far with it hopefully
it's working for you and it is cost
effective but feel free to dump that
[ __ ] out and start fresh
let me check my notes make sure i'm on
pace
uh replace the water as necessary you'll
start seeing powdery mildew on the top
or you'll start seeing it'll get crimey
and gross you'll know you'll feel you'll
just have a feeling that's gross i
should change it change it don't be
afraid um
hang the buds so hang them where they
can drip dry i would hang them um
somewhere with an ambient environment i
know that wherever like just ambient no
you don't need extreme heat extreme cold
normal ambient environment somewhere
between 65 and 75 degrees would be cool
uh would be ideal but right now i'm
gonna give you up to 82 ish degrees
because it's hotter than [ __ ] everywhere
and it's going to be hard to find a cool
space like that so if you get a cool dry
space that would be ideal let them drip
dry
there's going to be a lot of water
falling out of these buds onto the floor
be prepared for that maybe do it outside
maybe do it in the garage then once
they're done dripping and they're no
longer dripping then you can move them
to your regular drying space and you can
begin your drying process as normal
for the normal drying space
ah that's when i would have 55 to 65
humidity maybe 50 humidity since the
plants are so wet uh maybe start off at
50 and then let it go up over the next
day up to 55 to 65 but 50 to 65 humidity
then 65 to 75 degrees in that room if
you can manage that i understand it's
hot as [ __ ] uh right now i'd probably
have to have an 80 degree drying space
just because that's how it is uh but we
can't always always have all the perfect
[ __ ]
have a fan in there have fans moving the
air so none of the air is stagnant but
don't have fans directly blowing onto
the plants speed drying them so if you
can have an oscillating fan that just
goes across the plants occasionally
that's okay have air movement in the
room but don't blow onto the plants
because that'll cause dryness that we
don't want that'll dry one section fast
and the others won't be dry evenly
that'll start causing you problems
so at this point
basically uh dry your plants like you
normally would proceed with caution uh
keep an eye on the plants uh don't let
the room get too humid you may need to
step up your humid uh your dehumidifier
or your extraction fan
however your drying and curing spaces
set up don't let it get too humid in
there that's something that is very
important at this time
have that room dialed in have a way to
get rid of the excess humidity because
we did soak these buds in water and then
we put them
hopefully let them drip long enough but
there's a lot of water in there so a lot
of that water has to come out expect a
couple of extra days on your dry time
but that is not a problem in my opinion
letting cannabis dry longer is a good
thing some of you guys want it to dry
super fast it's better when it dries
slower a better thing happens there's a
conversion happening there's a
conversion that happens during the
drying and cure process that happens
better if it goes more slowly so take
your time with the drying and curing
process
uh i will work on an updated drying and
curing episode i know i haven't done
that updated episode there's a uh just
an audio only version we'll get a video
version of that coming up those episodes
take a lot of focus and a lot of work a
lot of time to record a lot of
perfection in the editing but we'll get
it right we'll get it out for you but
at this point i feel like i have gotten
you through
bud washing it's not as scary as it
sounds it's not as intimidating as it
sounds it's not as nasty as it sounds
you're taking a bucket with some
hydrogen peroxide you can use h2o2 if
you've got that available once again be
just as careful if not more careful with
the h2o2 it's just as caustic it'll burn
it'll [ __ ] you up it's dangerous use
your personal protective equipment don't
sue me if you [ __ ] up
also if you get caught doing anything
illegal uh involving this plant this
culture this scene i will not be held
responsible rosta jeff is a fictional
character and this is a show for
entertainment purposes but ah mix up
your solution dunk that [ __ ] in there
give it a swirl hang it up and don't let
it get moldy because it's too wet and
don't speed dry it that is the gist of
bud washing think about why you're doing
it
a lot of extractors have started bud
washing even if there is not a problem
in the grow they find that the grow
spaces are dusty where i live uh this
town experience there's a documentary
called the dust bowl this town was part
of the dust bowl this town where i live
gets dusty uh there's desert that way
there's desert that way there's a steel
mill that way that produces all kinds of
weird dusty [ __ ] so we have to dust here
constantly if you dust the shelves you
dust monday you're probably dusting
again thursday and if you don't it
builds up a funky gunk of dust it is
dusty here all that shit's on our plants
as well my table is not very sticky it's
kind of sticky because i take some dabs
here
but the table is not naturally really
sticky and it gets dusty and funky or
cannabis plants if you're doing it right
they're sticky as [ __ ] especially
outside so you're going to get all of
that dust from the desert that we've got
all of that weird [ __ ] floating around
from the wind all of that stuff from the
steel mill all the brake dust if you
live by the interstate and you got to
grow by the interstate there's a lot of
brake dust in the air all of that [ __ ]
will be stuck to your plants we don't
think about that so that's a very good
logical rational reason to do a little
bit of bud washing and then when you
start rinsing those plants and you see
what's left in the water you'll be a
little bit disgusted that you haven't
thought about doing it before we're
making extracts we're making food we're
smoking these products imagine it would
you want to smoke a bunch of dirt would
you want to smoke a nice hit of bird
[ __ ] you down bro hey bro i got a big
bag of bird turd you want to take a hit
off of this that doesn't sound appealing
to me don't be afraid don't be scared to
wash your buds don't be ashamed of it
either
we put a lot of work and a lot of energy
into our grow sometimes you have to have
something to show for it a lot of you
this is your medicine for the year this
is what is going to get you by this is
what's going to make you not
super sick from whatever ails you i
don't want to pin you with some sort of
condition but this may be what is saving
your life for the next year let's do
what we can to save it let's be proud
about it let's be safe let's be as clean
and conscious as about it as we can as
well
uh keep in mind prevention is key but
right now uh at the outdoor season that
i saw there was a lot of powdery mildew
and there were not a lot of ways to
prevent it because we cannot control the
vpd outdoors you can apply a few things
i do like cease i like zero tall
i like double nickel uh what's the one
from
marone bioinnovations the uh they've got
a couple maybe it's grand devo there's a
lot of great products that we can spray
that work as a preventative or a uh it
will help remove the pan eradicator of
the powdery mildew but i understand
sometimes [ __ ] gets away from you so uh
if you're just fighting the powdery
mildew now you can spray with c so you
could spray with double nickel and then
when it comes time to harvest do that
dunk in either zero tall or hydrogen
peroxide also heavy defoliation will
help you with powdery mildew all right
ladies and gentlemen boys girls pimps
hoes friends foes smokers growers clone
cutters pollen chuckers uh
spinners guys that stand there chompers
and tapers i want to thank each and
every one of you for hanging out
listening to another episode of the of
the grow from your heart podcast i
forgot the name on my own show for a
moment there this was a good time i had
a great time i hope you had as much fun
as i did i hope i helped you out i hope
i rescued your outdoor harvest i really
hope you don't have a powdery mildew
problem but if you do maybe we'll get
you through it we'll get through it
together again don't be ashamed don't be
embarrassed [ __ ] happens especially
outdoors you guys that is gonna happen
if it's indoors we've got to correct
some issues
ah that's a whole another conversation a
whole another podcast but
don't ever be ashamed don't be fearful
don't be scared that you have
had or have a problem in your grow
that's how we learn the most if they
went perfect every time just be perfect
every time when a problem came up you
wouldn't know what to do with it guess
what now we know what to do with powdery
mildew all right i've been rambling for
a long time thanks again for hanging out
you guys uh if you have any questions
corrections comments or concerns you
know how to reach me the email address
is grow from your heart at hotmail.com
don't be shy send me some questions
corrections comments concerns updates i
do love the harassment i look forward to
it speaking of harassment find us on
discord there's a link in the show notes
and the video description and if i'm
paying attention enough when i edit the
link is right here as well you won't be
able to click it but you can read it and
you can type it right on it it's right
there yeah discord gg some other stuff
it goes right here we'll put it there
alright um also the website uh
everything is at the website everything
i read genetics everything ire army
everything grow from your heart is at
the website contact information uh a
link to the discord if you don't want to
type in all those links go to the irie
genetics website there's a link to the
discord there's a link to the etsy store
where you can get some fresh new gear
that's right there's a new coffee mug up
with my face on it uh there will be new
shirts going up soon there are some
brand new merchandise that arrive today
then when i do get a moment i will put
that on the etsy store stay tuned keep
checking because there's new [ __ ] coming
also on that website there is a tab that
says uh stay up to date if you type in
your email address you will get a
newsletter approximately once a month
maybe every two weeks and lets you know
what's going on with iregenetics it will
let you know about that new merchandise
i talked about it'll let you know about
coupon codes it'll let you know about
seed drops and restocks events and
updates uh we will have an update on an
event here in the next episode so do
stay tuned for that but make sure you
check out the irie genetics website and
sign up for the newsletter so i can send
you a newsletter once a month that is
all i've got for you for this episode
i'll be back in a couple of days with
fresh new content let's send a big shout
out to my buddy rosta green thumb and
until next time take a fat dab and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you