[Music]
all right here we go welcome back
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rosta jeff and this is episode
of the grow from your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to read a
couple of patreon questions before we
get to that part of the show let's do a
few shout outs to a few of those great
folks who support the show on patreon
let's start off with the big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to my friend justa smokin let's send a
big thank you shout out to route 305 and
elders garden let's send a grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to big sexy dank in 716 grows i want to
send a thank you shout out to a longtime
supporter know me by my guacamole let's
send a big fist bump and a thank you
shout out to jackie daytona i want to
send a special thank you shout out to
stash drop 269. let's send a big fist
bump to my buddy mister then let's wrap
it all up with the big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out to
terp burglar big thanks and big shout
out to everybody who continues to
support the show on patreon if you are
not already supporting the show and you
would like to learn how to do so all you
have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need is right there on the screen and
you know i do include a link in the show
notes and the video description to make
it nice and easy for all of my friends i
do want to send a special thank you
shout out to all 200 of my patreon
supporters we've been hovering right
around 200 patrons lately i do
appreciate it that means a lot to me it
does not go unnoticed i enjoy it i
appreciate it sometimes it's a bit
overwhelming but big salute big fist
bump thank you for all of that support
now this is the part where i do invite
you to join us on discord that's right
the discord server has reached over 1400
members in the last episode i said we
hit 1200 we are already to 1400 members
on the discord server there are a lot of
great things happening over on discord i
always say there's a video chat where
people are hanging out they've added a
sports chat channel if you're watching
sports if you're watching basketball
hockey football golf whatever's on your
tv if you're smoking a bowl and watching
sports and you want someone to hang out
with go to the ivory genetics discord
look for the sports chat server click on
there you can hang out you can just be
in the voice chat or you can be on the
video chat hang out smoke with the crew
there are a lot of cool people hanging
out over there especially on game day
during a big game rooting for their team
it's all friendly go root for your team
in the discord server the last time i
jumped in the discord server i let the
crew help me design new merchandise i
was working on a couple of designs for
some new merch that i'll talk about in a
future episode but i wanted some
feedback and some input so i went to the
discord i posted a picture of the
merchandise that i had in mind and i
said give me feedback give me info give
me details give me updates i got a lot
of great feedback and i compiled some of
the crowd's input and feedback into a
beautiful design so there'll be some
great merchandise that was partially
designed by the discord crew so if
you're hanging out in the discord you
may get the opportunity to help us
design new merchandise name new strains
you can be involved in a lot of great
[ __ ] if you join us on the discord
server of course there is a link in the
show notes and the video description and
i'll type the link right here you can't
click on it but you can at least read
that type that into your url join us on
the discord server once again big thanks
to everybody who's hanging out on the
discord server i did mention that we
designed some new merchandise on the
website
iriegenetics.com there is a store to the
uh there's a link to the ire store click
on that link that will take you to the
ire store where the irie genetics
merchandise is available for the podcast
listeners i have created the coupon code
podcast 10. that coupon code is good at
the ire merch store where you can get
the shirts the stickers the coffee cups
there are grinders there there are
rolling trays there there are a few
other pieces of merchandise that are
coming but kovit has a slowed down a
little bit when those items do arrive
i'll send out the mailchimp newsletter
let you know they're there i'll add them
to the store right away make them
available for the crew but don't miss it
on iriegenetics.com click on the store
link to use coupon code podcast 10 that
will save you 10 off everything in the
web store
all right i do have some real topics
here that we want to get into i have
been doing i don't talk about it a lot
because
i try to keep some projects secret until
i see a little bit of success i feel
like if i talk about things a little bit
too early it gives me the opportunity to
fail and then i've got to talk about
failures which is never fun but maybe i
should mention even though i'm a
professional grower that has done a lot
of [ __ ] sometimes i still fail and it's
okay to [ __ ] up and fail let it humble
you but let's get myself back on track i
am talking about an outdoor garden that
i've been playing in i did some outdoor
breeding i had some help it was not just
me i don't want to take all of the
credit big shout out to the team that
worked outdoors this year they know who
they are they may not want their name
set here on the show at this time we'll
talk about them and introduce them in
the future if they want that but uh big
shout out thank you for the help and for
the work and for the space but we've got
some outdoor space going it's actually a
beautiful greenhouse
i took a few plants to the greenhouse
and i may have taken king solomon out
there and he may have done some work
that's right i did some outdoor breeding
or some greenhouse breeding and
something i learned that those seeds
developed quickly outdoor breeding
happens really fast i was not expecting
it um it's a good thing the seeds will
be done earlier than anticipated the
pollination happened much earlier than
anticipated and i learned a lot this
year and i'm very excited to have added
outdoor breeding to my list of skills
that i feel comfortable doing uh this
year was our inaugural run but i had a
good uh support team i had friends that
i could message and say hey bro i'm
gonna breed outside any advice big shout
out to jesse he sent me a paragraph of
uh oddly spelled uh weirdly punctuated
[ __ ] and taught me how to grow outdoors
and breed outdoors jesse i'm just
picking on your brother nothing but love
he can build a house you guys
but jesse gave me some great advice and
with uh jesse's advice my lead and our
crew's hard work and effort uh we have
got some seeds that will be ready here
uh hopefully they'll be done by they'll
be dying i'm gonna give myself a
deadline but around the halloween time
we'll be cleaning up seeds making
packages getting that stuff ready for
possibly the endo expo i did mention
that the endo expo
is kind of up in the air at this point
it's been a week since i've recorded and
i have not oh excuse me for that
it has been a week since i recorded and
i have not received any updates on the
endo expo once again as soon as i do
receive an update on that i will let you
know but there will be a bunch of fresh
seeds and new crosses that you've never
heard of stuff i've never talked about
will be available that came out of this
greenhouse okay i feel like i'm rambling
because i'm very excited about the
greenhouse my point was that things are
happening much more quickly in the
greenhouse the buds uh it looked like i
said oh this is where the buds are i was
teaching somebody new i said these are
where the buds are going to happen this
is how it's going to go the next day i
was like well there are all the buds
holy [ __ ] and then i showed them this is
where we pollinated here's the start of
buds and the next day i was like holy
[ __ ] they're all the seeds it went
really quickly outdoors i was amazed i'm
excited for next year i'm already
planning for the next year's outdoor
breeding program got ideas and things i
want to do i get in over my head
sometimes all right let's focus now on
some of these patreon questions i do
have a couple of patreon questions that
came from the patreon audience obviously
the first patreon question in this
episode comes from our friend zachary u
it is a good outdoor growing question i
feel like it's very applicable at this
time of year and it goes a lot like this
i have eight plants four of them are the
same strains started at the same time
that makes sense then there are two
pairs of different strains started at
the same time one pair being scarlet
begonias and another pair uh it doesn't
say what the others are then it says
five plants that consist of three ogs
one scarlet begonia wow it's a sweet
cherry pie are in one area that is
pretty heavy with sunlight consistently
they are behind the other three at
another spot in regards to flowering
speed but the three of the same strain
and the same area are flowering at
different rates can this be summed up to
being simple as different phenotypes or
something i cannot even think of so the
question here is he's got several plants
and they're acting different outdoors
he's got some in one area and some in
another area the plants in the same area
are showing different expressions
they're the same strain they all came
from the same package of seeds but
they're showing different stuff yes my
friend that is a perfect example of
phenotypical expression
just think about it if uh somebody had
let's talk about two parents i'm gonna
pick anybody's parents maybe yours maybe
not if you don't want it to be let's
talk about two parents two breeding
parents they made three babies let's
talk about a family with three kids you
may have one tall skinny kid that would
be me you may have one short chunkier
kid that might not be me then you may
have one that is kind of weirdly shaped
in the middle one kid may be really
athletic one kid may not be athletic at
all one may be really aggressive one may
be really passive but you came from the
same parents and you grew up in the same
exact environment those are just
phenotypical expressions the plants do
very similar things so you're going to
see that variation that expression in
the plants i would be very interesting
on a totally different experiment to
take clones and put a clone of the same
plant in your two different grow
locations and see what they do there so
what i definitely think is happening is
that you are seeing phenotypical
variation if you've got a pack of seeds
and you put you've got four of the same
plant in one area they look different i
do believe that it's just phenotypical
variation i'm going to read the question
here make sure i answer that correctly
so there is another part that i do want
to touch on you said that they are
behind in flowering uh compared to
plants the same type of plants in
another area uh that is another part of
phenotypical expression maybe that one
area is getting more light maybe it's
getting less light
longer light maybe something is blocking
the light maybe it's shaded
maybe the temperature is just a little
bit different over there maybe the soil
is a little bit different but that shows
us how just a little bit of difference
in environment can change the plants
drastically they're further behind each
other or further ahead each other in
flower just because of the environment
in which they are in that is a very good
example so most of what you are seeing
here is phenotypical expression i guess
all of it is phenotypical expression
even if it is the environment making it
happen because that's what phenotypical
expression is it's showing different
traits based on your environment
expressing different things so that's
what you've got going on there uh good
uh good foresight good prediction good
hypothesis and i do agree with you buddy
that is just basic phenotypical
expression big shout out to my buddy
zachary you for the great message uh
keep them growing bro and since you said
you've got some irie genetics outdoors
where are my photos bro pictures or it
didn't happen if you guys are growing i
read genetics i would love to see your
photos send me
photos of my strains at any stage of
growth veg flower
big buds little buds anything you want
to share anything you think i might want
to post to social media anything you
want me to share to social media send it
to me the email address is grow from
your heart hotmail.com or just forward
it right over to me on instagram it's
irie underscore genetics on instagram i
r i e underscore genetics i hope you can
spell genetics irie underscore genetics
on instagram just shoot me your photos
excuse me
just shoot me your photos if you want
them shared let me know you want them
shared if you want credit let me know
you want credit if you don't want credit
let me know because most of the time i
just automatically will give you credit
be like here's a picture of scarlet
begonias grown by zachary u post it up
put in my stories save it to the
highlights it'll be up there for a long
time let me know also we need some
photos for the website so don't be
afraid to send me photos i enjoy photos
all right let me get myself back on
track get back in a little bit of focus
here because i do have another great
message in front of me this one comes
from our friend rastabot we mentioned
rastabot last week when we were talking
about discord rastabot big thank you for
all the dedication on the discord server
the discord gang always tells me bro we
don't need shout outs we don't need love
we don't need high fives but you guys do
so much work i cannot believe the
dedication and commitment to the discord
server by the discord team big shout out
thank you guys i appreciate it there are
1400 people hanging out because a few
people decided they would build a
discord for me thank you i it blows my
mind you guys the support that i get
from the irie army for this podcast for
the seed brand it still blows my mind
it's humbling it makes me feel great it
makes me feel nervous it's overwhelming
in the best way i love it it's inspiring
it's motivating uh makes me feel like a
superhero it gives me a lot of great
feelings there's a lot of pride but also
i got there's a lot of people that i
cannot let down which is a great yet
scary feeling in a good way don't ever
stop doing what you're doing guys i do
love it all right from rastabot this one
says hey rasta jeff i've been loving the
breeding talk you've been doing lately
thank you bro i like talking about
breeding if you have specific breeding
questions please do send them i like
specific questions it gets me more
focused on my rambles because i do get
rambly if you haven't noticed on this
episode it goes on to say my mind was
wandering dear during your latest
episode thanks bro mine probably was too
says i thought of a couple related
questions when you breed how often do
you re-test your seeds that is a very
good question being a person who breeds
uh for commercial purposes my seeds are
on the market through several different
avenues it is a good idea that i do keep
up my quality control standards uh so
that is a very good question i do
appreciate you uh checking me on that a
lot of people go unchecked and they
forget to check so thank you for
checking on me
so it goes on it says if you make a
thousand seeds and that batch passes the
test do you retest the next time you
make a batch
so we'll make a lot of seeds we'll make
a thousand seeds we'll test them you
guys get to see you guys get to see most
of the testing i try to keep it fairly
transparent i have a lot of testers who
are on social media but i also have
testers who are not on social media you
see the folks who are uh you see zozo j
post every moment of the grow you get to
see from the sprout all the way up in
[ __ ] time lapse video uh who else
does a great job uh all mixed up does a
good job rosin man does a good job
mobius grows does a great job they post
all that stuff to social media big shout
out to all the testers who i didn't
mention that was enough sorry i don't
want the list to just keep going it's
not an award show we're not going to
shout out everybody in the gang but all
the testers post their stuff up on
social media and you guys get to see it
so you get to see that initial testing
how does it look like is the structure
good what are the leaf shape like what
is the bud shaped like are there any
cool colors a lot of times we see if
there are any problems through those
testers they'll show us were there any
issues luckily most of the time there
are no issues but like all things [ __ ]
does happen so get a lot of testers
going they send me test reports then we
decide if we want to release it we
release it then right before it's sold
out or sometimes unfortunately just
after it sells out i decide i need to
make more and restock that strain so
here's where your question really comes
into play do i test this next batch i'll
do the pollen chucking i'll make the
male plant in the female plant do their
magic i'll get the seeds out of there i
generally will do a solid germination
test i get uh i don't even know how many
seeds fit in the palm of my hand it's
probably about 40 or 50 seeds and i just
do the paper towel germination test fold
up a paper towel a lot like i do this
piece of paper
fold it up soak it with water throw the
seeds right in the middle there leave
them on the table they don't get any
special treatment but i do make sure
they're wet i do check on them every few
hours then i open it up to see how many
of those seeds germinated that is one of
my main concerns at this point if they
are germinating there are healthy seeds
they've went they flowered long enough
they finished most of the time i could
tell that by squeezing them i push them
on the table they're hard if it hurts my
finger it makes a dent the seeds are
ready um so i germinate them i make sure
they sprout if they're sprouting i'm
mostly confident in them then we'll send
a few of those out as freebies to the
friends and they'll grow them and
they'll know what they've got to be like
hey run these real quick and they'll
just run them and we can see what
they've got i don't really do honestly
rigorous vigorous retesting as long as
those mother plants and father plant
weren't ruined destroyed uh compromised
as the word i'm seeking in my head as
long as there was no compromisation of
the parent plants i feel like the
genetics are exactly the same the
breeding will happen exactly the same
the phenotypes are going to be the same
i didn't put any other there's no other
ingredients in my recipe so there should
not be any variation again if my parent
plants will remain
remain uncompromised if there was no
compromised health no stress
no light weirdness no nutrient problems
anything like that then it should be the
same there's no scientific biological
reason why i would get variation
maybe some epigenetics or something like
that may cost something but i think it
would take much longer than what i'm
able to do with these plants i haven't
had them for hundreds of years so um i
don't do rigorous vigorous retesting of
the crosses too deeply i do retest for
germination rates i test every batch of
seeds for germ rates we want to know
that every batch of seeds is good so if
i make a batch there's a thousand seeds
in there 50 to 100 of them just go
strictly just to germination
we'll pull a few of those out if we've
got room to keep them and grow those
most of the time that's how it works you
germ like 50 of them i pick [ __ ] 25
of them grow those uh find 10 or 12
females in there take pictures all those
have good documentation that's how it
usually goes but the second time around
i don't really do vigorous testing i
send them out to the crew i say hey
rosin man hey mobius hey somebody uh
these are a remake can you give me a
quick run or i grow them myself i'll
just grow a few and i can tell quickly
uh they're my kids i could tell quite
quickly if they're gonna be worth a [ __ ]
or not
then it wraps up with not looking to
have you do a quality control test on
the air just more wondering how
different breeding is between the same
cuts over time and years
in my experience i have not noticed any
change in the breeding i'm pretty good
at identifying uh the offspring the
phenotypes from my crosses and i don't
see any difference any uh any shift any
degradation any weird evolution in my
breeding i think it all looks just the
same
um i think i'd have to have the plants
for quite a bit longer i think i'd have
to be doing it for quite a bit longer
for the plants to build up any memory uh
unless i started breeding with sick
plants or something which at that point
i don't do if the plants don't sustain
health if i can't keep them healthy
there's no need for them to stay in the
garden because i can keep a plant basic
health is [ __ ] i'm really good at
that they look green and healthy all the
time so yeah if they're not staying
green and migrate they go bye-bye
because they're pain in the ass i think
i wrapped up your question let me give
it a quick skim there's not a lot to it
uh how often do you retest uh strict
germination testing uh strict first
level testing second batch not serious
on the the re-testing that much but i do
do germ tests i think that covers it all
before i wrap up this message i do have
one cool topic i can talk about pretty
soon i'm going to do some different
testing i just mentioned it a minute ago
that i'm doing some breeding outdoors i
have made some of the same crosses
outdoors that i've made indoors and i
have not ever tested the outdoor grow
yet so i don't know what the outdoor
progeny is going to look like i need a
couple of friends a couple of testers
that will run a batch of seeds made
indoors and a batch of seeds made
outdoors i think i said that correctly
take the indoor seeds and outdoor seeds
label them correctly like plant a
indoors plant b outdoors and run them
all next to each other and see if there
is any difference in there i want to run
a bunch i want some friends to run a
bunch uh the experiments are fun when i
do them but i need more feedback as well
i'm going to see stuff but uh under the
whichever lights i choose to use in the
summertime i use one kind of light in
the winter i use another how do they
respond under my lights but also how do
they react in your grow and in dave's
grow and in john's grow and in jacks
grow and jill's grow and bills grow and
everybody's growing i want to see what
they do so pretty soon we're going to
get to test stuff that was made indoors
right next to stuff that was made
outdoors because i recently bred some of
the same stuff uh some of it's coming
down from the indoor grow and it's
almost ready in the outdoor grow just
ironically did the same stuff at the
same time and we'll get to test those
side by side that is something i'm very
curious about new testing that will get
to be done so that was a good rant that
was a good side subject to get me going
on i do appreciate that i'm really
excited about the outdoor greenhouse
grow this year and i super cannot wait
to grow the seeds that come from that
and see are they more vigorous are they
any different is there any difference at
all i just know that we made a lot more
seeds outdoors than we would have
indoors so that was the super cool part
and it seemed to happen super quickly
all right i am off on a good ramble
again let's reel me back in and get back
on a podcast my buddy rastabot dude
thank you for a great patreon message
thank you once again for all of the
discord work cannot wait to hang out
with you on discord when i get done
recording here it does take quite a few
minutes to load all the files from the
computer onto the drive as that happens
i go take a couple of dabs and hang out
with the crew on discord hope you're
there brother if not we'll catch you
next time all right ladies and gentlemen
boys and girls pimps and hoes friends
and foes smokers growers clone cutters
and paul and chuckers all of you
beautiful cannabis enthusiasts out there
i'm going to wrap up this podcast now
this will be a quick thursday episode i
want to do thank you once again i do
want to thank you i don't even know what
my brain said right there but you know
what i mean i want to thank you once
again for listening to episode
673 of the grow from your heart podcast
if you have any questions corrections
comments or concerns you know i would
love to hear from you the email address
for the podcast is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com don't be shy send me your
feedback send me your details also send
me your irie genetics grow pictures i
would love to see what you're growing
see how you're doing maybe we can give
you some advice maybe we could share
some of your picks if you want them
shared here on the podcast let me know i
can start sharing your irie genetics
here on the show that would be a fun
addition to the podcast thank you for
the idea i'm glad you came up with that
that was really cool of you uh what else
do i got for you this is the time of the
podcast where i ask you to like and
subscribe go to youtube if you're
watching if you're listening on an audio
server i do invite you to watch the
videos on youtube there's a high quality
4k multi-cam video happening on youtube
right now that you may want to check out
go to youtube click subscribe click on
the notification bell that way every
time i put out a new episode you do get
a notification you never miss any of the
content sometimes sometimes the audio
servers seem to be a little bit delayed
sometimes they miss some episodes i have
to repost them i'm not making excuses i
am not super tech savvy i don't know
what happens we're working on fixing all
of the glitches on all of the audio
feeds but i do my best to make sure that
youtube is updated every monday uh it's
actually sunday night into monday at
midnight and every thursday i know it's
wednesday into thursday at midnight i
make sure to have the youtube video
posted that has been the priority
because honestly i edit down the youtube
video then i pull the audio out of that
so i've got to do the video first so it
gets up there on youtube then while it's
posting i do the audio video welcome a
little bit behind the scenes all right
so like and subscribe on youtube that
was the point don't forget about the
discord server and everything else is on
the irie genetics website at
iregenetics.com all right that's all
i've got for you i feel like you've been
rambling on for quite a bit uh you know
i'll be back in a couple of days with
fresh new content i want to give a big
shout out to my buddy jesse gross and
until next time take a fat dab and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]
bye