[Music]
welcome back podcast world i'm your host
my friends call me rosta jeff and this
is episode 674
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to talk about a
couple of seasonal grow room adjustments
before we get to that part of the show
let's do a few shout outs to a few of
the great folks who support the show on
patreon let's start off with a big grow
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out to my new friend polo paul let's
send a thank you shout out to grow
bandit and ko jax let's send a thank you
shout out to my friend kes burton i want
to send a big thank you shout out and a
fist bump to sam heads let's send a
thank you shout out to spherical
glassworks i want to send a thank you
shout out to g7 and greenvet 88225.
let's send a special thank you shout out
to a new old guy i want to send a thank
you shout out to josiah w then let's
wrap it all up with the big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to my friends at fiscal's organics big
thanks and big shout out to everybody
who continues to support the show on
patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit www dot patreon
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need is right
there on the screen and you know i do
put a link in the show notes and the
video description to make it nice and
easy for all of my friends this is the
part of the podcast where i cordially
invite you to the discord server that's
right we've got approximately 1400
people hanging out on the discord server
i talk about it on every episode it's a
good time it's a great place to be once
again i invite you to join us on the
grow from your heart podcast irie
genetics discord server again there's a
link in the show notes and the video
description and i will pop the link up
on the screen right here that link won't
count you can't click on it but you can
read that type that into your browser
join us on discord i think you'll have a
good time there big shout out to all of
my friends over there on the discord
server right now all right let's jump
right into it ladies and gentlemen i did
say we were going to talk about some
seasonal adjustments here i am in
southern colorado it's not quite cold
yet but i do know that hoodie season is
soon approaching that's right it's going
to be fall here very soon i'm surprised
i haven't busted out the hoodie yet but
i want to be prepared so we're going to
talk about this episode right now we
need to get ahead of the game we don't
need to have our equipment in the garage
dusty dirty under a tarp maybe you need
to order it from amazon maybe need to
figure that [ __ ] out we don't need to be
delayed on having equipment we need to
be ahead of the game for seasonal
changes that is something that is very
important
the bigger the grow gets the more
important that is it's very easy to
change the environment adjust the
conditions in a smaller room once you
start going 4 6 15 20 50 100 lights it
gets increasingly more challenging to
control the room control the space
adjust to the outside environment last
year in colorado we had a day where it
was
negative 17 degrees it's one of the
coldest weekends i've ever experienced
that i can remember in my adult life
absolutely one of the coldest
experiences i can remember in my growing
career i do think i saw a negative 24 at
one point in my life that negative 17
really put some stress on my grow space
so we need to be prepared for things
like negative 17 coming up pretty soon
here the conditions the environment the
temperature changes rapidly so i in
colorado need to get my [ __ ] together
and need to get my gear prepared get a
strategy in place start thinking about
what i'm going to do what type of
seasonal changes are coming in your
location you may be listening anywhere
on the planet big shout out wherever you
are but think about the changes that are
coming is it going to get colder is it
going to get hotter will it be more
humid will it get drier what do you need
to do to adjust your growth to set
yourself up for success that's one of my
main goals of this podcast my goal is to
help you set yourself up for success
i've had a lot of trial and error i've
had a lot of experience i want to take a
lot of that experience and cut out a lot
of [ __ ]
get you right to the point set you up
for success tell you a lot of things
will fail try to show you the best way
to do it that is my main goal here so
let's focus in on a few of the
adjustments that i feel like i need to
make for my grow environment i am
currently going from a warm summer
environment here in colorado we had 104
degree days we had 108s there might have
been 112 in there we had some super hot
days here over the summer so i have got
led lighting in my main flowering space
right now that's right i've been using
uh canon lighting from black sail market
big shout out to black cell market so
over the summer time and over the spring
time i had great success with the canon
lighting from black sail market however
i know that in the winter time those
lights will not keep my grow space warm
enough those lights are great for when
it is hot outside and i don't need
warmth in my grow but it is about to get
really cold and i'm going to use my grow
lights to heat my grow environment also
i'll use my grow lights to sort of heat
part of my living space as well the heat
will get ducted into my living area i
will be heating up the grow space with
the lights exhausting that extra heat
into my living room and that way i don't
have to turn on the heater as much i'll
try to use that electricity that i'm
already running for the grow lights to
efficiently heat my house so that's one
adjustment i will make
when it gets just a touch cooler when i
have a weekend available i am going to
take down all of my led lighting and
re-hang my hps lighting that's right it
will have high pressure sodium lights
for flower over the winter time that's
one thing that i definitely will change
uh there's nothing wrong with the canon
lights those canon leds are amazing
lights they make beautiful plants the
plants grow with great vigor in fact i
will leave the cannons in one area in a
veg space because that area stays warmer
just naturally and where the grow space
is but the flowering room does need to
get changed it's up against the exterior
wall of the house i will get much colder
there we're going to swap that out for
hbss nothing wrong with the cannons
other than they don't make enough heat
for the winter so i'm going to hang a
light that will make enough heat for the
winter and use that gear to my advantage
why would i put up a heater when i've
got hps lights i can just throw those
right up that is my theory if you have a
heater if you want to do it do that but
i'm going to use the hps lights because
i've got them and then i conduct that
heat that comes from those to another
room as well heat up part of the living
space that's the first major adjustment
i will make because i will use the hps
lights to heat up part of the house and
the grow space so the way my grow is set
up once i change those lights i will
need to change my ducting that will also
change the way i set up my carbon filter
so we have caused a chain reaction of
things to set up and change in the grow
that's a beautiful process i think that
resetting things up and rebuilding
things gives me a good opportunity to
clean things that i may not have cleaned
maintenance things that may not have
gotten the maintenance they needed
things are coming off of the ceiling
they'll be down on the floor i can clean
every inch of it before it goes back up
it'll go into summer storage i'll wrap
it up in plastic i will clean it then
wrap it up into plastic put it in summer
storage that way next summer when i need
it or when the winter went whichever
when i need that gear again it's clean
it's ready to rock it's been cleaned up
i don't have to go polishing it but now
is a good time to clean everything up
give everything a good once over i will
probably repaint the walls while i'm in
the process of rebuilding everything but
i will definitely do the different
lighting and redo the ducting which is
going to lead me to redoing the exiting
of the room where the air the ducting
goes out which is going to lead to me
repainting the entire room which will
probably lead to me redoing the flooring
in the entire room that sounds like a
task but i love it and it's like it's
like a trigger for good work to happen a
lot of these things probably needed to
be done anyway so this is a good time to
do it the seasonal change will trigger
this
now things to think about i said i'm
going to change my ducting something to
think about is the air that you were
bringing into your grow i don't know
where the air is coming in from i don't
know if you've got an air conditioner i
don't know if you have a passive intake
and active intake if we are bringing
frosty cold air into our warm grow
environment where we've got grow lights
going and it's nice and warm in there
we're bringing basically icicles into
the room that creates condensation
moisture what that really creates is
opportunities for powdery mildew we've
already had enough powdery mildew and
the warm season in the spring and summer
season let's get away from that for the
winter we've got such dry conditions
let's avoid powdery mildew and use those
dry conditions to our advantage you can
bring that outside air into your grow
but let's warm it up before it hits the
grow environment maybe bring it into
another room warm it up then shoot it
into your grow space something like that
but let's not shoot that frosty cold air
directly into the grow directly over the
plants if it's got to go directly into
the room if you don't have any other way
to do it run some ducting to where it
goes somewhere else further from the
plants then it warms up a little bit
before it actually makes it to the
plants that's a good thing to think
about
is the water which you are feeding these
plants where does the water come from is
it super cold if i turn on the water
outside in the middle of winter that
water is super cold i wouldn't want to
put that water on my plants if i get
water from one spot in my house it is
super cold if i get water from the
kitchen it's nice and room temperature
don't feed your plants really cold water
think of it like this if you wouldn't
put your feet in there don't feed it to
your plants your plants can't walk away
your plants can't pull their feet out
the plants can't say ah [ __ ] that's cold
i need to get out of the water they're
stuck there you're torturing them don't
do that don't feed them super cold water
get that water warmed up at least 69 70
degrees should be ideal for a soilless
soil coco sort of a grow if you're
growing hydro whole another ball game do
your thing you guys like to adjust your
temperatures accordingly to avoid the
mildew i'm not an expert in that area
i'm talking about something with soil
soilless mix cocoa something like that
so
don't feed too cold of water it will
shock your roots be cool with that
especially if it gets real cold outside
all right another thing that people
often overlook when it gets cold how
cold is the floor in your grow space i
talked a minute ago about putting cold
water on your feet can you walk around
in the grow space barefoot and your feet
not be too cold it's not a good idea to
walk around the grow space barefoot
let's talk about why i've got one solid
reason why i think it's not a good idea
to walk around the grow space barefoot
if and when we apply pesticides i apply
pesticides on a routine basis in my
garden
i apply spray pesticides i also spray
foliar feeds which we may talk about
more on this episode i apply a lot of
things to that grow i feed the plants a
lot of [ __ ] ends up on that floor
pesticides grow nutrients a lot of stuff
is on that floor i do my best to keep it
clean i mop it i clean it i sweep it but
there is stuff on that floor you
shouldn't be in there barefoot because
the bottoms of your feet are part of the
one of the most absorbent parts of your
body for chemicals toxins contaminants
you can suck up pesticides through the
bottoms of your feet quite quickly so
technically maybe you shouldn't be in
there barefoot also protect your toes uh
what kind of hippie are you in there
barefoot anyway if that's your style
be that way bro but uh it's risky it's
dangerous so um
walk around see if the floor is cold
that's the main point is it cold on your
feet if it's cold on your feet get the
plants up off of the floor it's okay to
have a cold grow room floor but raise
the plants up off of it maybe just put
them on a cinder block maybe a very
affordable way to get the plants up off
the floor is to flip another pot upside
down and set the pot right on that pot
just you got one upside down another pot
on another pot now you're that pot
height taller and off the ground
sometimes that's not the best because it
gets you too close to the light
sometimes if i got a plant that's not
growing tall enough that's how i get the
[ __ ] closer to the light and adjust
that plant to match the rest of the
canopy but
get them up off the floor flip a pot
upside down
use some cinder blocks build a table get
those plants off the floor because it is
probably quite cold so think about the
air coming in think about the cold water
and think about that cold intake cold
floor cold water cold intake it is all
going to happen very soon um we don't
want to freeze out these plants try to
use that cold air to your advantage
but not don't blast the plants don't
cause any frostbite set yourself up for
success you guys this time of the year
is coming
maybe time to turn off some things turn
on some other things i don't know your
full grow environment i don't have your
pulse monitor i don't know what your uh
minder unit is telling you pay attention
to that and make the adjustments but i'm
giving you a heads up the best i can now
is the time to start thinking about the
equipment for the seasonal changes set
yourself up for success don't say i can
go buy that in two weeks because
everybody's gonna go to the groce store
and buy that in two weeks and it's gonna
be gone sold out especially during these
weird times it takes a really long time
for [ __ ] to get replenished reshipped
and restocked get ahead of the game go
get that [ __ ] now especially if it's in
the budget if it's in the budget why are
you [ __ ] around go get it uh go get
it before it goes in demand because once
it goes in high demand they'll raise the
price on you it's not going to go on
sale when people need more of it that is
not the way this industry works come on
go get the [ __ ] you need now be prepared
uh do all of the [ __ ] today that you can
do today if there is work that can
happen in the grow room this is a side
rant this is uh
just some rasta jeff advice here
if there's work that can be done in the
grow room today or tomorrow and you've
got time energy equipment and
electricity still to do it if the lights
are on and uh if you're not getting too
much overtime and the boss isn't gonna
get on your ass get in there and do that
stuff because tomorrow there's gonna be
more [ __ ] to do there may be some new
[ __ ] to do that you didn't know there's
especially in a commercial environment
you guys i am very experienced in
working in large commercial grows the
thing i train people when i teach them
how to operate in a new grow i say the
first thing we do is we walk in and we
find out what went wrong last night
because in 100 in a hundred flowering
light environment you've got 100
flowering lights somewhere between 30
and 60 vegetative lights you've got
clones clone trays hydro pumps fans air
conditioners uh co2 machines computers
all kinds of [ __ ] in a big facility the
first thing we need to do when we walk
in is find out what went wrong last
night so if there's some stuff that you
can get done today go ahead and do that
stuff because i don't know what your
surprises are going to be tomorrow you
could have a five-minute surprise you
could and i hope this doesn't happen you
could kick over a bucket take you 15 20
minutes to mop that bucket up you got to
go smoke a dab get your [ __ ] back
together and regroup uh maybe that's a
30 minute [ __ ] waste of your day that
you didn't see coming or maybe just
maybe i don't even want to jinx you
maybe something catastrophic goes wrong
in the grove and you don't get any of
your side work done you don't get any of
your main work done now your side work
main work and tomorrow's work is already
[ __ ] up set yourself up for success
get as much done today as you can i
understand we've got families we've got
kids we got dogs we want to run around
with uh we got reggae shows we want to
go see you guys i saw the most amazing
reggae show tonight today earlier today
it was so good it was tonight it's kind
of late now that i'm recording but the
vibes were high i had to do something uh
we got stuff we want to do in our lives
but try to knock out those garden chores
if you've got a small grow it really
can't take that long if you've got a big
grow
then you ask for it get in there and do
the work i know what my job is i know
how long it should take i know how much
to allow myself and i also know that
[ __ ] happens surprises come up things go
wrong uh it's murphy's law what can go
wrong [ __ ] will and be prepared for
that it's how you react respond and
adjust to those things that make you a
good grower but if you're
prepared those things are much easier to
deal with alright i'm [ __ ] rambling
set yourself up for success you guys
that's the bottom line here i want you
to succeed as much as you want to be
successful i really want you to be
successful i don't want you to go buy
all this gear set up all this stuff uh
send me money on patreon buy expensive
seeds and then not have a fruitful
harvest that's going to make me feel bad
especially if you bought my seeds and
listened to my show and still didn't
succeed i feel like i kind of guided you
and you didn't get there so i want us to
get there together i want you to feel
that pride that i feel when i harvest
some plants all right
stone and rambly i'm telling you the
reggae vibes are high tonight um i do
have a patreon question here in front of
me let's get this one patreon question
go in this one came from my buddy
cynthia nasty what's up bro thank you
for the great message i sent me a lot of
great stuff on patreon finally one of
them has made it to the podcast this one
from my buddy scentsy goes a lot like
this uh it says your silver thiosulfate
blend is working bland i said bland it
doesn't say bland here it says let me
try on this camera maybe this camera
will get it right your silver
thiosulfate blend is working amazingly
on my autoflower project so a few
episodes back quite a few episodes back
i gave an explanation on how to make
silver thiosulfate to use for reversing
plants to make feminized seeds our
friend cynthia nasty here has used my
recipe to make some autoflower feminized
seeds which is a great thing i don't
make autoflowers so i'm glad somebody
else is out there doing it it said i
have followed your instructions to a tea
and i'm getting a pretty decent amount
of pollen that is great to hear because
sometimes the recipe will take some
adjustment the first time you make that
mix it might not be strong enough to
reverse the plant it might be so strong
it burns the plant uh the spray schedule
may need to be more frequently less
frequently it might burn it might not do
anything to the plant there are
adjustments to be made per plant here so
i'm glad that it worked for you on the
first try
that gives me confidence that my mixture
is working it's very universal versatile
and it worked on your stuff that feels
good so it says big up for sharing that
it saved us a ton of money and i'm not
even close to using up the first batch
yes silver thiosulfate or at least the
components to make such are very
affordable when i see people selling
products to reverse plants and i see
companies selling silver thiosulfate for
exorbitant amounts it drives me a little
bit crazy because you can make hundreds
of gallons for like 30 bucks hundreds of
gallons for maybe 30 bucks and most of
that 30 is probably going to be shipping
uh the two products you need are very
affordable uh 10 bucks per bottle 10
bucks for shipping and then you need a
gallon of distilled water every time you
do it and that'll make enough to reverse
a plan and you got it covered that's
really affordable in my opinion uh so
when i see the people charging too much
it drives me crazy that's just price
gouging that's stabbing at the community
that that shouldn't be a thing we should
be able to have access to the products
which we need so there you go make your
own silver sulfate much more cost
effective
there is more it says ah this is kind of
a breeding and market question this is
sort of a sales question a business
question i really do like this as i'm a
great person to ask this i would say it
says knowing that the market is driving
fem and autoflower seeds as a breeder
trying to serve the market does it make
sense to search for elite females more
than trying out different males
so there's a couple things to talk about
in that one sentence there in that one
statement
knowing that the market is driving on
fems and autos yes
the market loves feminized seeds more
than half of what i sell would be femme
seeds if i could make more fems i can't
keep up i don't make enough fems i make
a lot of regular seeds uh we're going to
talk about that in a minute they're
honestly easier you get more pollen from
a regular plant you don't have to
reverse it reversing is science you have
to learn each plant
takes a little more effort time energy
space work
um so the market is after femmes and
autos that is very true but there are a
lot of people
who will not grow feminized seeds there
are a lot of people who will not grow
autoflower seeds there are large
portions of the cannabis community who
are opposed to both of those i'm not
bashing those products i have no nothing
against autoflowers
especially against feminized seeds but a
lot of people will not grow them a lot
of people feel that feminized seeds are
doing something wrong to the gene pool
uh a lot of people um just simply won't
grow those seeds i was gonna talk about
a certain group and why but we don't
need to go down that path today let's
keep me a little bit focused a lot of
people do want the reg seeds a lot of
people want the fems a lot of people
want the autoflowers i see that there's
a market for all of that let me follow
up it says as a breeder trying to serve
the market does it make more sense to
search for elite females more than
trying out different males um you have
to do both as a breeder who wants to be
uh what's the word um
relevant in the market that wants to be
on top of the market that wants
customers you have to do both you have
to have solid a solid male plant at
least the male plant is kind of what
sets you apart everybody's got the
females everybody's growing the females
the entire community is growing the
females we see those in large numbers
it's the breeders who are seeking out
the elite males that do the work to make
new things so we've got to find both
we've got to find the males that will
contribute to the gene pool and move the
cannabis plants forward for our purpose
whether my purpose is usually uh
producing high yielding plants with a
lot of terps and very high thc potency
that is my thing that's because that's
what i enjoy and i feel like since i
make a product that i enjoy i am
successful because i'm doing it with my
heart for myself and other people like
it it's like a good musician
if your favorite musician wrote songs
for some girl those songs are gonna suck
but if your favorite musician writes
songs for themselves they're gonna be
great songs and that girl will love it
and so will you i think that's why my
brand works i make a product that i feel
is up to my standards up to what i like
and you guys happen to like it also
because i've got high standards and i
know what to uh what people want what to
expect and what to look for in quality
cannabis
so um a lot of it is finding that mail a
lot of it is finding the boy a lot of my
company is based on king solomon you
mentioned solomon later in this message
solomon is the stud it took me a lot of
searching a lot of hunting to find
solomon first i had the plant i had to
find the plant that fit the criteria
which i was looking for i had a list i'm
kind of an ocd guy i write lists on
paper it had to have all of these traits
and once i found to plant a few plants
with all of those traits we bred with
them then we grew out those seeds and we
had to see what that male plant was
doing to the seeds so that's how i found
solomon that's why solomon stands out
that's why my company stands out because
of that elite male now the other half
the equation you do have to have those
elite females having a stud and a bunch
of half-assed females to breed with
won't do it you have to make solid
female selections now i said before the
entire community has got females they're
all pheno hunting female plants so we've
got the beautiful advantage of i can
grow the plants and i can find my own
females or we've got a squad of people
out there buying seeds getting free
seeds growing seeds trading seeds and
they find good keepers and somehow they
end up back in my garden and i can breed
with those elite females as well so the
question is uh does it make sense to
search for elite females more than
trying out different males as a breeder
who makes a lot of regular seeds i need
to have solid males in my garden and i
have to have a revolving stable of
quality females i try to keep a couple
i'm limited on numbers so i keep a
percentage of my numbers for a male
plant a percentage for solid keeper
females and then a percentage of my
numbers go for rotating plants something
that's going to come and go like i
usually have a list of this many and
when i get a new plant i go where does
it fit in the list who's got to go and
the one on the bottom of the list that
plant gets kicked out and the new ones
come in
so uh if i were to only make feminized
seeds
then i wouldn't even worry about boys
and we would be searching for the best
females all the time and i would just
breed stuff and find i would grow it
first which i normally do and i would
find the winners out of there and then i
would send out the seeds and let you
guys grow it next but i would be one or
two steps ahead of you breeding with the
new [ __ ] that you don't have yet so that
i'm ahead of everybody just a couple of
steps which is honestly kind of what i
do with my own line anyway
uh but if i were only to make femmes
yeah we would be searching out a bunch
of badass females and then just breed
each female to every female if i had a
list of six girls i take number one and
pollinate everybody else with it and
then we take number two and pollinate
everybody else and take number three
pollinate everybody else just reverse
that plant pollinate everybody with it
is what we would have to do
but i like making red seeds i really
like
i like breeding i like watching what the
boy does to the plants to the mix to the
recipe i kind of like that part so i
like the boys and the mix i love
feminized seeds also but there's just
something about a male female cross
being a breeder being somebody who's
deeply curious and passionate about
genetics and breeding that boy plant
means a lot to me so you have to have
both
uh the males are what separate us from
each other we are male as kind of like
our style it's like our calling card
it's our flavor uh it's our catchphrase
or whatever you want to say uh it's what
yeah that's the male is what does it uh
and one male can do a lot of work just
like a reversed female can do a lot of
work but if you've got nine females in
the room pollinate all nine of those
females from that one male and make nine
crosses from one dude uh sometimes
that's how i do it with king solomon
i'll put him in the room
with just the whole stable of ladies and
let him go buck wild he may be in a
greenhouse right now getting frisky with
like 12 beautiful ladies so he's got a
hot hot [ __ ] weekend all right let me
keep moving because i am kind of
rambling
where are we
um
it goes on i have to find my place
furthermore it says furthermore knowing
that the market doesn't want male plants
or most of the market would it make
sense for breeders to start charging
more not less for regular seed
production um it is common i said
comment i'm going to put the bunch of
c's across the screen again it is common
that
feminized seeds are usually double the
price of regular seeds if you look at my
website if you look at most of my seed
vendors a regular pack of seeds is 80
bucks a feminized pack of seeds is 80
bucks in the regular seeds it's a 10
pack and the femme seeds it's a six pack
they're almost double the price so
um that is because i said earlier it
takes more work much more work in my
opinion and in my experience to make a
feminized seed you've got to treat that
donor the pollen donor plant you've got
to treat it it's got to be treated with
a specific way for about three or four
weeks before you're going to make it a
plant that will give you pollen then
once it does reverse sometimes they
don't make very much pollen depending on
how your recipe was you've got to adjust
the recipe perfect that dial that in if
you didn't get it right you may have
just done a full run and not produced
enough pollen you got a bunch of buds
with very minimal seeds kind of wasted a
whole run there so
you got to dial it in you got to get it
right that's why femme seeds are more
expensive and regular seeds are
generally half the price and then on top
of that
regular seeds are one price
fem seeds are double and then autoflower
fem seeds are double that price so
you're paying a lot more for your
autoflowers let me keep reading because
there is more to this it says it is an
interesting thing to think about that i
see how much your discord server loves
king solomon clearly he is a beast yes
with king solomon in the stable it does
make it hard to do any other work like i
just want to work with solomon why not
put solomon pollen on every female
cannabis plant in the world uh solomon
is a stud everything he touches turns to
[ __ ] gold it's amazing so it makes it
hard to do other projects i did find a
jack the ripper male that does amazing
work so i've been playing with him and
you know i do love to cross a few i
reverse a few of those females i've got
but yes uh solomon is a beast he's a
true stud he's a winner um i put a lot
of work dedication time energy and
effort into finding that dude so i'm
glad it paid off
i had to name him solomon if you
understand anything about solomon and
why he's named solomon big up maybe
he'll do some research now there's a
reason for that name then it says what
do you think uh man i gave a lot of
insight i hope you know what i think by
now then it says lastly i think you
should redo and re-release a lot of your
early grow instructions there are a
bunch of new people and way more podcast
competition than he mentions his
mentions i said mentions is he mentions
some of my podcast competition let me
say this
i don't feel that anybody out there
podcasting is competition we're all
friends we're all bros we're all doing
the same thing we've got the same exact
goal our goal is to make you a better
grower to give you better knowledge to
make you more comfortable in the grow
room more comfortable with your plants i
don't feel it uh competitive any
competition i see that word um twice in
this sentence here so
no competition dude it's all love it's
all respect but yes there are so many
more podcasts out there um
now let's revisit the point of that
sentence redoing and re-releasing a lot
of the old episodes i would love to do
that i will work on doing that but i get
so many messages and questions that
redoing stuff uh sometimes is uh it's on
the back burner keeping up with the
current content the current questions
that is important staying on top of the
patreon questions those people do pay me
to answer their questions i feel like
that is priority i always print out the
patreon questions bang those out first
then i work my way to older questions
stuff that's just on my mind that i want
to ramble about stuff like that so um i
will redo those episodes over time i did
the cloning episode
i did the bottom and lollipopping
episode those were just kind of redos of
episodes as well another thing you can
do if you don't want to wait for the
redos you can always go back and listen
to the old episodes if you're an old
listener a new listener if you've just
discovered the podcast please do feel
free to dive into the old catalog of
episodes there's a lot of great
knowledge uh go check out the way that
the podcast has changed uh just grown
over time first it was really scripted i
wrote down
most of what i was gonna say was on
paper and i would just read it and just
[ __ ] do the show like that and then
it got more comfortable and then i hit
my head there's a chunk of episodes
where i've got i'm recovering and
dealing with a traumatic brain injury
and a lot of weirdness those episodes
are really interesting to listen to uh
and then just over time things change
and then we had a pandemic which taught
me a lot about podcasting and that's
when i went to video so go listen to the
old stuff that's what i'm saying a lot
of the lessons you're looking for a lot
of questions you guys might have may be
hidden in those old episodes and i will
over time redo them i'm slowly they're
slowly organically re-happening the
winter stuff i just talked about i'm
sure i've said a lot of that in an old
episode before so a lot of it will get
repeated recycled i felt kind of weird
about doing repeats and recycled
episodes but a lot of people have asked
the same questions and i'm realizing
that a lot of podcast listeners you
either do or you do not go listen to old
episodes if you listen to old episodes
you start at number one and you listen
all the way up to the current or you
just start where you are that's kind of
how podcast viewers and listeners are
two types of podcast viewers i love you
both i got no judgment but uh they
either go all the way back or they don't
so we got to redo a lot of stuff again i
do invite you to go to listen to that
old [ __ ]
bro i am stoned and rambly let me wrap
up this podcast while it still sounds
good uh cincy nasty cincy thank you for
the great message let me make sure i
covered all the notes because i did
abandon this one quite quickly yeah bro
we covered all of this point all of
these points uh you gotta have a male
and good females um if you're just gonna
make fem seeds then you don't have to
worry about the boy but you gotta be
certain that your paul and donors are
tried true tested and reliable um i
think i covered all that i wanna thank
you for a great question dude thank you
for the continued patreon support you've
been a patreon supporter for a long time
you've sent me a lot of great content a
lot of great questions a lot of good
info i do look forward to meeting you
one day shaking your hand and getting
you so high you are uncomfortable
alright ladies and gentlemen boys girls
pimps hoes friends foes smokers growers
clone cutters pollen chuckers all of you
beautiful people out there i want to
thank you once again for watching
another episode of the grow from your
heart podcast if you have any questions
corrections comments or concerns you
know i would love to hear from you the
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com don't be shy send me some
feedback i will read that maybe i'll use
it on the show create some content out
of that sort of stuff don't forget about
the patreon channel at patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart
everything else you want to know is on
the website at
iriegenetics.com that's right all things
grow from your heart all things roster
jeff all things i read genetics it is
all right there at iregenetics.com
now is the time when i ask you please
like and subscribe click like click
subscribe to the podcast click on that
little notification bell every time i
put out an episode you'll get a
notification never miss an episode i'm
trying to get the channel to 10 000
subscribers we're getting close big
thanks to everybody who subscribes to
the youtube channel all right everybody
that is all i've got for you for this
episode you know i'll be back in a few
days with fresh new content i want to
give a giant shout out to my buddy lemur
priest and until next time take a fat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you