[Music]
yeah welcome back podcast world i'm your
host my friends call me rasta jeff and
this is episode 675
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to read a couple
of patreon questions before we get to
that part of the show let's do a few
shout outs to a few of those great folks
who support the show on patreon let's
start off with the big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out to my
friend girls grow too let's send a thank
you shout out to kanno organic illinois
let's send a big thank you shout out and
a fist bump to magic mike let's send a
special thank you shout out to a
longtime supporter of my friend the
candycrat let's send a thank you shout
out to levity loveday let's send a big
high five and a fist bump to eric i want
to send a thank you shout out to
groove2112
let's send a girl from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to another
longtime supporter gramps memel let's
send a thank you shout out to my buddy
eric ross i want to send a big fist bump
and a thank you shout out to single t
let's send a thank you shout out to
brohan 76 then let's wrap it all up with
a big grow from your heart podcast thank
you shout out to my buddy matthew t
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need is right there on the screen and
you know i do put a link in the show
notes and in the video description to
make it nice and easy for all of my
friends this is of course the part of
the show where i do invite you to join
us on the discord server the discord
server is approaching 1500 members by
the time this podcast episode comes out
we might have 1500 members on the
discord server
big salute shout out thank you for all
of the support on discord it's a good
time over there i'm having a great time
hanging out with people i try to jump in
the chat i just posted some questions
and actually a secret strain release
idea asking for strained names bunch of
stuff happens over there on the discord
so please do join us on the discord
there is a link of course in the show
notes and in the video description it
has been a long time since i've talked
about what strain i'm smoking on the
podcast
i need to mention what strain i'm
smoking because it feels like
i've got bricks on my head or
excuse me maybe like i've got some kind
of belt around my brain i feel slow
motion i took a big fat dab of some blue
fruit live rosin from green dot labs
nobody pays me to talk about it nobody
gives me the concentrate so i went to
the local dispensary and i bought it i
brought it home set up the equipment
thought i should take a dab before i
record and that stuff put me in slow
motion so if you catch me going a little
bit slow looking feeling a little bit
confused you're right it's from the blue
fruit and i am enjoying it so big shout
out to our friends at green dot
green.labs honestly they do not pay me
they don't sponsor the show i just
enjoyed the dab that i just took so much
that i thought you might notice and i
should mention how good it was all right
let's keep things moving the next order
of business i want to talk about is i
want to send a big thank you shout out
to all of the people that i ran into at
the colorado cool vibes reggae festival
at the levitt pavilion in denver
colorado there was a reggae festival it
was the first year of the reggae
festival and with the outcome that i saw
i guarantee we will have that festival
again i hope a lot of the same bands
return uh it was let me talk about some
of the bands that we got to see we got
to see when i showed up mighty mystic
was playing if you're a reggae fan you
probably know mighty mystic after the
mighty mystic i think we got to see
jamiri morgan big up to my buddy jamiri
morgan uh jamiri is the son of gramps
morgan who of course is a member of
morgan heritage who is one of uh
probably my top three top five reggae
bands of all time um i might maybe have
gotten to hang out with uh jamerry
morgan and morgan heritage a little bit
not going to talk too much about that
you could tell with a smile on my face
how much fun i had there
we got to see mighty mystic jamiri
morgan after jamiri morgan a band called
through the roots came on stage they're
the band that sings uh sorry for my
bloodshot eyes if you listen to reggae
if you listen to reggae radio any reggae
channel you've heard that song got to
see those guys
then we got to see the beautiful lovely
and amazing
natalie rise uh that was pretty awesome
i talked about going to a reggae show a
few nights ago i went to another reggae
show since then i haven't missed a show
on the tour yet and it's just kind of a
joke there's only been two shows on the
tour so far you guys but i haven't
missed a show on the tour uh but it's
been a good time hanging out with all
the reggae artists on
saturday at the reggae festival i kind
of got to hang out with everybody and
got spoiled also a lot of the cannabis
community was present at that festival a
lot of the reggae community was present
at that festival uh it was a good time a
lot of people came and gave me hugs high
fives fist bumps uh love and respect big
shout out to everybody who gave me any
sort of love respect high five fist bump
if you took a minute to compliment my
dreadlocks or my shoes thank you it was
a great day uh i was
just beaming with good vibes and big
energy because a reggae show is like my
favorite place to be i was specially
invited by one of my favorite performers
i got to hang out with some of my
favorite reggae artists and see some of
my favorite uh favorite people some of
the older rosters that i look up to were
there for the colorado locals that have
been putting on reggae shows for years
and have been in reggae bands here for
years i got to hang out with them hang
out with some popular reggae bands that
was a good time you could tell still
vibing from it so big up to everybody
who showed me some love at the reggae
festival you guys are not here to talk
about a reggae fest you guys are here to
talk about
growing ganja so let's focus a little
bit on that thanks for letting me rant
about reggae music for a minute caught
myself chattering i'm high we'll get
back on track here um i do have some
great patreon questions that's what
we're going to talk about that's what we
are going to talk about and i'm going to
edit that one uh we are going to talk
about some patreon questions once again
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart we will jump right into it we're
gonna go with this one first
this one came from my friend it looks
like what name do they want me to use
we're gonna say this came from our
friend warwick and it goes a lot like
this it says what's up ross to jeff i
have some seeds from a source who has
some sort of wizard of oz
and they call it killer green bud and i
was looking at crossing that with some
of your genetics
which would you suggest cheers from
warwick p.s i love the podcast uh
warwick big shout out great compliment
for loving the podcast even better
compliment wanting to breed with my
genetics that is a very good question
so you've got some seeds
that i don't know what those seeds are
the wizard of oz i don't know what that
is i don't know where they came from i
could have done some research but
honestly that wouldn't help me out too
much with my advice i would give you the
same exact advice probably
um you've got seeds so
do you want to use a male from my plants
or a male from that pack of seeds like
have you decided which side is going to
be which like which side who you're
going to use the male from who you're
going to use the female from have you
done any commitment
or deciding or any uh dedication to um
which side is which have you thought
about that so you've got some seeds uh
who has some wizard of oz you're gonna
have to grow the wizard of oz then
you're gonna have to grow some of my
seeds and we'll talk about which ones uh
later on
uh grow that wizard of oz do you find a
good boy do you find a good female is
there something you like in there what
stands out about that plant that makes
you want to breed with it that's what i
want to know why what is your goal it
all boils down to where i'm headed with
this is what is your goal when you're
breeding cannabis plants one of your
main objectives one of your main things
to think about is what is the goal
what's your purpose here why are you
breeding these plants
i appreciate that you want to breed with
my stuff because you like something
about my brand makes you want to breed
with it i appreciate that but what makes
you want to breed with these particular
plants there's got to be a goal in mind
when you're breeding i could be i want
to make some hot fire cool that's a
great idea but what traits
make hot fire in your opinion what is a
good pie what's a good cake in your
opinion because you are being a chef now
you're the one mixing [ __ ] up what is
your goal what are you trying to bake if
you're trying to make pizza then we
don't need to order uh if we if you're
making pizza we need to order cheese and
pizza sauce if you're making cakes we
need to order totally different show we
don't need any cheese and pizza sauce in
our cake so it's all about your goal
what do you want so i would say grow
start off grow some of these uh what are
they called wizard of oz kill a green
blood seeds and see what you get do you
find a stellar male do you find a
stellar female is there a plant in there
that talks to you that just says i am a
standout breeding plant i see that as a
breeder
as a passionate cannabis grower or
somebody's that somebody that's been
around these plants and seen them
express themselves so many different
ways i see plants and i go that right
there is something you should breed with
and that intuition will kick in so learn
about mendel charts learn about alieal
charts learn all of that stuff then
build some intuition on which plants to
breed with then grow these seeds find a
male or female that gets your attention
keep them have a clone of that keep a
mother plant of that grow it several
times build a relationship with that
plant so you understand how it reacts in
response to different feedings different
conditions different stresses learn it
very well
then
think about what your goal is
what does that plant have that it would
mix well with what is that plant missing
that you want to maybe correct what
could you improve upon with that plant
what terps are going to mix well with
that plant
what structure will combine well with
think about things like that now what is
your goal is something i keep saying i
don't know what the flavors uh the
aromas the structure the potency i don't
know anything about the plant that
you're starting with that's why you've
got to grow it test it find the keeper
that you like then we'll breed with that
then what is your goal do you want to
make something really tall and skinny
that takes 77 to 85 days to flower or do
you want the opposite do you want
something short and squatty that
finishes in 55 to 63 days do you want
something that will rip your brain apart
the first time you smoke it you take two
rips off of it and it feels like your
head just exploded and beams of light
came out of it you're [ __ ] panicking
and paranoid or do you want to take two
fat rips and just melt into the couch
and be part of the couch it's all about
your goal so it's really hard for me to
tell you what to breed with because i
don't know your goal i don't know if
you're trying to make pizzas i don't
know if you're trying to make apple pie
so i'm not sure what ingredients to send
for you from the store uh do you want
something i can really kind of guide you
through is terps do you want strawberry
terps do you want orange chirps do you
want funky blueberry skittly kind of
terps what other chirp should i write
down do you just want pure gas and funky
stank i can steer you in directions with
that
of course i've got strains that are kind
of obviously labeled for that kind of
project if you want strawberries
strawberry starburst would be the way to
go if you want orangey orange terps sun
kiss would be the way to go if you can
get it orange gasm would be the way to
go now if you get orange gasm you're
locked into either using the orange gasm
as the female side of the cross because
it's a feminized seed or you've got to
find a good orange gasm reverse it use
that as your pollen donor so that's puts
you on a track for your breeding that
does kind of make some decisions there
for you when you use a feminized cross
on one side side rant it is totally fine
it's okay i do it all the time you can
breed to a feminized seed if you've got
a seed it was feminized
it works just like any other plant you
could breed to it you can mother plant
that bad [ __ ] it works just like the
other plants people have some weird
rumors myths misconceptions
it's whack it's not real it works just
like other plants the only difference
was it was female for sure all right so
if you're looking for certain flavors
certain terps i can help you with that
like i said there's orange there's
strawberry there's blueberry funkiness
i've got garlic stuff i've got like
skunky gassy dirty feet kind of [ __ ]
that i can recommend you breed with that
would be the double dose if you want the
garlicky stuff use the dark hollow
a lot of my stuff is very uh the names
kind of give you a good hint of what the
flavors are going to be like strawberry
there's blueberry butcher is going to
taste like blueberry so their lemon
jeffrey is going to taste like lemons
there's stuff like that lemon sunrise
tastes like lemons i give you pretty
strong hints with my terp profiles so
are you looking for
super high thc because a lot of my stuff
will give you super high thc but i'd
probably recommend using like an arise
or a sonic boom male to get that really
high thc or anything with the jack the
ripper crosses would contribute to super
high thc but along with that will come a
longer flowering time so those are
things you have to negotiate with when
it comes to breeding uh and then you
will find outliers in the phenotypes and
then find an outlier find one that came
from sativa dominant heavy genetics that
were bred together find one that flowers
in a short time and breed to that one
again and breed to that one and keep
finding short flowers and you get that
sativa dominant short flowering thing
which is kind of what i think they did
with golden goat anyway i'm on a ramble
there are you looking for more of a
sativa or indica outcome in your cross
if you want more sativa stuff
i would say go with like the jack the
ripper crosses or straight up a rise if
you want more indica stuff i would say
use a morning dew a dark hollow or maybe
a double dose as a female or maybe even
a male in one of your crosses it's
really all about your goal
i said earlier do you want a longer or
shorter flowering project do you want
them to finish in 55 63 or do you want
those 80 day flower plants uh if you
want to go longer
i would say use something to jack the
ripper stuff i've said that before that
jack the ripper stuff goes for a while
the morning dude the prana the sun kiss
those finish a little bit earlier if you
want some quicker finishing stuff that's
what i would recommend but overall
it's hard for me to recommend what to
breed to your wizard of oz because first
off i don't know what the wizard of oz
is i don't know what it looks like
smells like and even if i had a good
written description of it if it said
here that it smells like pine trees and
grows like this how do i know that
that's the phenotype you're going to get
maybe you selected a phenotype that
smells like bubble gum and gets real
tall and skinny and i don't know that so
it's hard to decide what to tell you to
cross it with and then you're going to
get different phenotypes from my crosses
as well some things will get if you
cross something that's real strawberry
and something that's real gassy some
phenotypes are going to lean real
strawberries some phenotypes are going
to lean real gas and guess what some be
strawberry gas perfect up the middle
you're going to get others that are
totally random [ __ ] you'll get bubble
gum and turpentine out of some of them
but that's just outliers because that's
how genetics in nature works there's
nothing stopping you from breeding with
multiple female plants at one time you
can get one dude and as long as that one
dude makes enough pollen you can
pollinate as many females that are in
the room
i allegedly have a greenhouse going
right now with king solomon sitting
right in the middle uh he's actually he
served his purpose he did his job he uh
he made a [ __ ] mess everybody's
pregnant uh how would tracy morgan do he
got everyone pregnant are they pregnant
i can't do a good tracy morgan on the
spot i wasn't prepared but you know what
i'm saying he got everyone got pregnant
tonight uh shout out to tracy morgan he
got everybody pre not tracy morgan king
solomon got everybody pregnant in that
greenhouse uh and he got one two i think
he pollinated 12 other he pollinated 12
female plants so there are 12 outdoor
plants got pollinated by one plant when
i go indoors i usually do
one male per one or two lights so i've
got a light of female plants and one
male plant per light maybe sometimes two
depending on how big the overall plants
are how big the dude is but i'll put
several females to king solomon most of
the time or several females to jack the
ripper or several females to a reversed
golden goat that way you can make
multiple things and then that way you
run those multiple so you put let's for
example say we put your let's just take
the wizard of oz mail and we'll
pollinate strawberry starburst we'll
pollinate sun kiss and then we'll also
pollinate jack the ripper and we'll grow
seeds from all of those and we've grown
the strawberry starburst the sun kiss
and the jack the ripper times enough to
where we know what they do when you grow
them they know how they respond and
react to different environments feedings
conditions abuses stresses we know what
they're resistant to we know what
they're really susceptible to we know
how long they take to flower so we know
those plants very well right we've got a
relationship with those then we cross
them with
your male wizard of oz then you grow the
seeds that come from those plants and
then we get to see what the male is
doing to each different cross so if we
see that normally the strawberry
starburst was tall and had skinny leaves
and long lanky buds and smells like
strawberries and the sun kisses kinda
it's not as tall but it's got that
rounder structure and the wide plant
structure and smells like oranges then
we grow out the progeny that came from
those crosses and we see that they both
have a spicy apple flavor we know that
your wizard of oz is contributing
a spicy apple terp to everything that's
kind of one of his traits what we know
he does that's how you test out a male
plant that's the only real way to test
out a boy is to pollinate a bunch of
things grow them and then find
commonalities amongst those different
crosses to find out what he's doing
that's how i know so well what my king
solomon plant does to other plants when
i cross it it's very predictable for me
um
8 out of 10 times by now i can say if we
hit that plant with king solomon it's
going to do this and i can predict it
i'll write it down on paper and i'll say
bro we're going to get this out of it
and then we'll do it whoever i'll
pollinate the plants i'll give seeds to
people and i'll say expect this watch
out for this and they'll message me back
they'll be like bro i thought you said
it's a tester i never you never grew it
how'd you know what it would was going
to do and if i know both the parents so
well that i know that strawberry
starburst grows tall she gets skinny
around week six she starts yellowing up
real bad you want to give her extra
nutrients but don't because you'll burn
her she just kind of yellows out that's
what she does and then i know that this
other plant over here uh around week
nine it really starts beefing up so that
i know that the offspring around week
seven are probably gonna get yellow and
beef up that's just the kind of math
that my brain understands how to do with
these plants they're my kids i know them
i know that that one is gonna be an
honoree [ __ ] one night and that one's
gonna be really a pain in the ass in the
mornings but saturday morning they're
gonna get along it's gonna be cool just
[ __ ] like that you know it that's how
the plants are telling them what the
plants they talk to me they tell me
all right i feel like i've been rambling
for a very long time about this one but
honestly breeding is all about your
purpose and your goal breed with intent
breed with purpose have a goal do what i
do challenge yourself
no matter which plants you use just get
a piece of paper and write down
i'm going to cross and i'm just being
hypothetical you can use any plants in
your garden that you choose to work with
and you've got my permission my blessing
um my honor to breed with my seeds all
of you guys out there gals out there
anybody uh that wants to play with my
seeds and do some pollen chucking please
do if you make a seed company out of it
give me some credit give me a shout out
say learn some [ __ ] from ross to jeff
but i encourage you to breed with my
stuff the main thing is that you've got
a goal all right i told you i took some
fat dabs but i finally remember what the
[ __ ] i was saying i just had to ramble
it out i may have cut some of the
rambling out uh that's the magic of
editing uh and i better say it before i
[ __ ] forget what i was saying again
here's a challenge when you're going to
do some breeding and you've got the
blessings to breed with my plants your
plants whatever plants you want to
choose nobody uh should say you can't
breed with their seeds once you buy them
they're yours that's my opinion do your
thing ah but
write down i'm going to breed my wizard
of oz to strawberry starburst i'm going
to breed wizard of oz to cindy 99 i'm
gonna breed wizard of oz to uh something
from colin and something from miss jill
just read it to a bunch of different
things but write down your expected
outcome i think that's called your
hypothesis write down uh your your
predictions what you think so like i'm
gonna put this wizard of oz to
strawberry starburst i'm hoping i get
high potency strawberry terps and then
think of what like may kind of not be
the super coolest trait everything's
going to have like a negative trait to
it like what's the downside to all these
bonus traits see where that is just see
what you can predict and then every time
you breed again keep writing down your
predictions and you'll start seeing what
you can do and what you can predict and
what you can rely on and what the plants
do repeatedly over and over when you
breed with them and then you'll learn
this dude is great to breed with this
girl plant is good to breed with then
you'll start playing with different male
plants and you'll start seeing what
different
boy and girl combinations do to each
other and you'll realize this male and
this female work real well together but
when i breed this male and this female
together it doesn't work worth a [ __ ]
for some reason you'll find combos that
are magic and some that are mediocre
and some that you wish you never made
because you end up throwing away big
baggies filled with seeds you feed them
to the birds you flush them down the
toilet
don't give those to your friends all
right i think i've rambled on for extra
time that i needed to on this one ah my
buddy what is your name in this one i
already [ __ ] lost your name in this
one warwick my friend my bro uh thank
you for the great message and uh if
you've got any follow-up questions i
would love to talk more about this send
me some more details and maybe we can
steer you on the right path get you down
the right track uh but man just follow
your heart grow from your heart and
breed with love brother that's what i
really think you should you should and
need to do uh breed these grow these
plants out see what speaks to you and
then you're like uh you're like the
matchmaker you're the guy on the dating
game you just gotta set them up and hope
they get along you are the new plant
tinder now i do have one more message in
front of me that i'm gonna read on this
episode this this message right here
comes from my friend squirrel master
what up squirrel master good to see you
brother hope you are well thank you for
being a part of the irie army it's good
to have you on team ire genetics this
message from my buddy squirrel master
goes a little bit i like this it says
i'm sorry if i've asked this before i
can't remember
dude i've done 600 this is episode 675.
uh i don't remember either so if you
already did hopefully everybody forgot
because i did so did you
hopefully everybody's smoking as much as
we are anywho anyhow anyway it goes like
this this is squirrel master uh you
should get that tattooed on your
forearms put your arms like this
together and then get this is squirrel
master tattooed down your forearms that
would be [ __ ] gnarly um big up
squirrel master it says i was wondering
about light leaks and interrupter
interruptions in the vegetative phase
will this affect a vegging plant to the
point where it causes herming or other
things when the plants are
flowering
um light interruptions during veg won't
be major and catastrophic if you do it
on purpose multiple times the plant may
start tripping out on you and may show
you some
frustration some hormonal problems but
you can basically manipulate that light
pretty well
a couple of times in veg uh maybe you
want to go from like maybe just want to
completely change the schedule yeah do
it one time they won't notice like what
the [ __ ] was that then they'll just keep
growing uh if you do it like today and
then again in three days and again in a
few days they may start getting weird
shaped leaves because they're they're
just not sure what to do they'll react
just like you bro
once or twice they'll be like what the
[ __ ] was that and they'll get right back
on track but if you do it a few times
they're going to want to talk to the
manager they're like what the [ __ ] is
going on why do you keep waking me up
why am i sleeping then why are the
lights back on and why is it sun shiny
at three in the morning what's happening
but if you do it a couple times
mess with them a little bit and veg they
will be okay try to get them back on a
good day night cycle a good rhythm
before you put them into flower so that
they know like oh i've been on 18-6 and
they kind of have an idea and then when
you switch to 12 12 they'll notice
they'll be like oh now it's actually 12
12. because if you have a chaotic
schedule chaos chaos then you go to 12
12 they're going to be confused it'll
take a little bit longer i would expect
for them to realize oh that's really 12
12. i really should go into bloom
so i would give them minimal
interruptions as close to flower as
possible but i don't think that it will
cause major problems major concerns now
in the flowering phase i would really
try to avoid light leaks at all costs i
don't want light leaks light
interruptions schedule changes i really
try to keep that locked in once i'm in
the flowering phase
that is where you will see issues you
possibly will lead to intersex
expressions of your plants you'll start
seeing possible reveg start seeing
possible twisty coily leaves maybe slow
uh the real word is [ __ ] growth
don't flag me for that one that's the
real word the pla the growth of the
plant will be [ __ ] because the light
schedule is interrupted i won't look
like it's blooming the way that it
should you'll think you're in a
flowering stage but since you're getting
a light leak the plant just won't go
into flower it's like no it's still
light there's a little bit of light so
i'm supposed to stay in the vegetative
stage so make sure you've got full
darkness and flower but in the
vegetative stage you will be okay as
long as you're not out there [ __ ]
with the breaker just making sure
they're off and on don't turn it into a
rave let's not have a party in the grow
room but a couple of interruptions and i
think you will be just fine all right
let me scroll through make sure i've
covered my notes yes i feel like i have
covered the major part of the show i
wanted to get through now it is time to
wrap up this podcast ladies and
gentlemen boys girls pimps hoes friends
foes smokers growers clone cutters
pollen chuckers uh who else is out there
everybody out there all of you beautiful
cannabis people thank you for joining me
for another episode of the grow from
your heart podcast that blue fruit had
me high and rambly so i hope you enjoyed
this show as much as i did this was a
good time for me if you feel like the
episode was educational informative or
entertaining and you'd like to support
the show all you have to do is visit
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart all of the information you need is
right there on the screen if you have
any questions corrections comments or
concerns of course you can send me an
email the email address is grow from
your heart at hotmail.com
all of the other info you need is on the
website at
iregenetics.com please do check out the
website lots of cool stuff on there uh
there's a newsletter tab you can type in
your email address we'll link you up
with the newsletter you'll get updates
on new seed drops new website
information new vendors new merch uh if
i'm going to be at an event or something
i'll try to let you know i do have
another cool announcement that i'm going
to share pretty soon um so check out the
website also there is a place uh where
you can ask grow questions there's a
grow help tab on the website click on
the grow help tab it'll ask you a few
preliminary questions then there's a
spot for you to type in your grow
problem type it in send me your question
i will help you out probably read it
right here on the podcast so check out
the website
iriegenetics.com i'm sure you could tell
my voice is burning out it is time for
me to wrap up this podcast once again
everybody thank you for hanging out 675
episodes that's amazing to me every time
i say a high number like that i get a
weird uh little flutter inside and a
smile on my face it makes me feel great
so thank you guys for hanging out for so
many episodes this is the time where i
ask you to click like click subscribe
most of you of course are already
subscribed if you're not already
subscribed to the show please do
subscribe on youtube if you're listening
on an audio format i appreciate you i
love you for listening if you're hanging
out right now on apple podcast stitcher
radio
spotify wherever else you may be
listening please do go to youtube just
subscribe to the channel type in grow
from your heart podcast click subscribe
trying to get to 10 000 subscribers big
thanks to everybody who subscribes to
the show right that's all i've got for
you you know i'll be back in a couple of
days with fresh new content i want to
send a giant shout out to my buddy the
larf knight rises and until next time
take a fat dab and give your mom a hug
for me
[Music]
bye
you